thank you
[Music]
welcome to breeder Syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene Through The Eyes of the folks who
lived in I'm Matthew owner of Riot seeds
I'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not soja breeder and grower from
Mendocino
welcome to the underground
so tonight
I thought we would go over a little bit
because last week a lot of you remember
um
we didn't get a lot of questions when it
came to the the hot slate and viroid uh
stuff so we wanted to get to a lot of
interactive uh questions for that I
guess that's I don't even know how to
word it but yeah well yeah I mean we for
for various reasons we had to kill the
comments last time so we didn't end up
seeing a bunch of people's stuff and so
I don't think the viroid is is probably
like unless I really pontificate a lot I
don't think the virus is a whole show
um but if people have questions if
people have general questions that they
want to ask uh tonight would be a good
time to uh lay them out there yeah you
know I thought um like one of the things
that I I really took away from the
viroid
um topic and I think this is the first
thing that jumped out we were talking
about you know the different uh I mean
different techniques people use for
cloning and if you have an edge that's
cut where it's a wound as she called it
um
I mean you can't use
arrow cloners with different strains you
know if you're if that's what you're
doing it really kind of wipes out that
whole situation from being a viable
product in this market I mean there was
there there's an aspect of that and then
there's like there's actually
um there's actually some new tech that
coming out for uh or not new tech but
there's there's new to cannabis Tech
that's kind of being pushed right now
for cloning which I think is pretty cool
and I actually uh belief or I believe I
should say uh is a big addition
um so I've seen I've seen some people
try to get around it but they're people
have been asking about like uh cloning
Tech uh and safe practices and then
there's also been a bunch of people that
have been asking about
um you know
and this kind of sucks too but they've
been asking you about like drying and
curing and how to get better weed uh
which you know to be honest like it's
it's actually one of the few things I'm
like hesitant to talk about because
I uh
um you know most corporate people grow
shitty weed yeah and they don't realize
what Corners to cut but then I don't
necessarily want to deny like a bunch of
like home Growers and stuff like that
better technique either so it's like a
weird animals aren't watching this [ __ ]
anyway until it turned out to be a long
time ago it's a weird it's a weird
conundrum so if if people want to hear
about drying and curing Tech and a way
to get better tasting weed uh you could
start start throwing it up in the
comments
um you know so
another another thing she addressed and
and a lot of people like I said were
arguing about before the uh show and
even after was the relevance to Hops
Leighton
showing up in the progeny of seed now I
I thought about it all weekend you know
a bunch about different clones that have
been used that we know pretty sure have
uh obso Latin one that I know for sure
had it when I got it back in the day and
we didn't know what it was at the time
was jesel diesel is well known to have
some kind of sickness and later on it
got tested it does have hlv
Jesus has been used in a lot of a lot a
lot a lot of stuff and we've never seen
any progeny from any diesel anything
show any of the dudding traits on their
own now is it in there
maybe but I mean
the progeny doesn't come up for it in
the test so I that eight percent number
seems awfully High I mean well one thing
is one thing we should probably mention
that's important and I think we brought
it up on the previous show is that most
of the stuff she was talking about and
this is where people get mad at science
especially like to use the covid thing
or whatever is because
if uh if science gets proven incorrect
they think it's all [ __ ] right
but that's how science is
um it's correct until somebody can prove
that it's it's incorrect or there's a
different technique and that doesn't
mean that like you know I mean it's
obviously like what we know at the time
yeah right and most of what there's what
most of what she was trying to express
to us about Hobb latent because cannabis
is not very well studied are other
viroids similar to hop latent
uh and other studies done it's there's
not a lot of work done specifically on
hoplate in cannabis yeah exactly so she
was trying to give us her best
explanation on what was ongoing
currently yeah
um and I think that's educated guesses
based on available information in other
cultivars or not not even just called
for other uh
I don't know species yeah and you know
and there's an aspect where people are
asking about false positives I think
with any kind of test there can there
there's a there's a there's a decent
percentage for false positives that can
exist and then I also think that just
because you get a negative test once
doesn't mean you're exactly in the clear
either yeah
um you know so I think there's that and
um you know sadly
um with the proliferation of cuttings
now these days and the lack of
cleanliness and stuff like that I can
safely say that like I mean maybe you
can map to speak on this before but
um in the early days of like clone
training and stuff like that nobody
nobody worried about this stuff at all
not stuff like that no no I mean in the
early days of Clone trading when I first
presentering in
um the term dud had barely just started
to even be I think it was even years
later a few years later that even like
hey this thing might be a dud I don't
know you know there's been for a long
time
um you know that's one one of the things
I think dudding dudding is a term we use
in cannabis to basically describe a
plant that's acting unhealthy yeah and I
don't I think that that um hop Slaton
can be a cause of dudding
um but uh you know I also think that um
there's a variety of other diseases and
probably unknown viruses yeah uh and
things like that that could also come up
later
um that are going to get spread around
you know
um so
you know um I think she was fair and
that what she told us was best knowledge
sure I think there's a lot of unknowns
and I think that a lot of like the basic
cleanliness and maintenance techniques
which are not common in cannabis need to
start getting applied
that's for sure
um yeah all that all that is good
technique I've been trying to get people
to do that with germinating seeds for a
long time using as as sterile technique
as they can because it does matter
you know um a lot of people do the the
old like well if a plant nature drops
you know the seeds in the ground
naturally they pop up you know I can
wait you know I can do whatever and put
whatever and you don't have to be clean
to pop seeds but really it does matter
if if you're if you're spending a good
amount of money on seeds it it really
does matter that's the highest rational
point right if you buy a two dollar pack
of tomato seeds and you don't get that
great of a germination rate uh nobody
cares
yeah if you give Matt Riot 300 and you
don't have good Tech and four of them
don't pop and now you're pissed yes so
because cannabis seeds our tendons have
a tendency to be expensive
um you know you probably want to take
the small extra steps needed to like get
as much success as you human as possible
yeah you know yeah
um
you know uh so you know there's an
aspect where as she was saying on the on
the show before you know I do believe
that there's a potential for people to
clone out of it
um you know you know I don't think
that's an impossibility but like she
made a very good point in that the
viroid is extremely tiny and all it
takes is one little bit of it to be able
to replicate itself and slowly come back
you know
um so what I actually think is uh
um is you know what people should
probably do is you know uh is have a
quarantine situation
um and people put plants into quarantine
to check for you know russets or or
broad mites or or other pests or things
like that
um it's probably advisable to maybe get
a cheap test a couple of times
um on an important plan yeah you know
and hopefully
um we'll have a situation like I was
mentioning before where like eventually
they'll make nurseries
um you know have a clean bill of health
you know I don't think so and yeah we've
seen we've seen any number of of clones
of private clone sellers have to
temporarily shut down their clone
selling because you know customers have
been buying expensive plants and then
it's ends up positive
um so
that's an interesting question about the
Superdog go ahead um well
um you know uh I would say that did I
there was a lot of uh when people
someone just asked for people that
aren't seeing it when I was we were
doing all of our super dog seeds did we
find sour Finos
uh and I would say yes we did
um not so much in look more in nose
you know
um there's definitely uh there's
definitely you know the the pathway we
took to sour to to Superdog is a little
different than what happened with sour
diesel
um but I think that when you cross skunk
and chem uh in certain ways you're gonna
get certain things that come up if you
look through be careful with that
terminology remember most people are
going to think you're talking about
skunk one when you see yeah you know we
actually
um we we actually considered today uh to
[ __ ] for a second we actually
considered doing a a whole show on skunk
one
um because it is such a it's got such a
long history
um and it's got so much misconceptions
these days but it does seem like Sam
skunk man might be giving a rendition of
his opinion
um and so maybe we can follow that uh
because it's always it's always good to
get the you know and and and then you
know we'll have an idea of like what
because lots of lots has been said yeah
you know he's been he's been invited on
the show so he knows that he has a
standing invitation to come on and talk
about anything he wants to too
um but but some people are clear
um you know because Matt you know Matt's
right is that
um you know Sam intentionally bred all
skunky Aroma out of skunk one for a long
time that was a claim yes
um and he's made that claim consistently
over a very long period of time and it
does seem like the first plants of skunk
that he brought over to Holland had a
little bit more skunkiness in them than
the later ones
um but uh you know there's an immense
amount of people that have been looking
through skunk one for skunk and not
finding it
um it seems like the skunk that got used
in sour
um was a blend of different skunks and
then blended into Super Skunk uh and
then some other accidents so it's kind
of it's it's not it's not a clear path
when you say a blend of different skunks
are you seeing a blend of different
skunk ones or are you using a different
term
um you know uh
so it's it Matt and I have Matt and I
have have some connections to the uh the
gentleman who uh bred that clone right
and he's given us
um unfortunately like a lot of these
Old-Timers from the 80s uh you would
like a well-written out lineage uh with
exacts
yeah and it was mostly he bought things
from sssc and from Neville that had
skunk in it and Blended them together
for two or three years and then crossed
something of that into Super Skunk
and then we got the skunk that became
famous
okay again are you you say skunk very
freely are you seeing skunk one I would
assume I would assume so because he said
he was buying think skunky things from
Neville and and and and and uh super
City the seed Club
right so he was he was buying hybrids
and he was blending them together for
two or three years I believe he even
referred to that line as skunky skunk
right skunky's Coke yeah yeah and and
then and then he took that line and the
first year that that Neville actually
released the super skunk okay which is
sort of the line that puts skunk back
into skunk as it were
um so if if if he's correct and he's
telling us the truth which I don't have
any reason to doubt it seems like half
of the thing that became very famous is
a blend of Neville's and super City the
seed Club work and half of it is super
skunk itself
from the first year of uh
um from 1990 yeah right and then from
that on there was some hermaphroditic
accidents and there was this and that
and it gets even more convoluted so it's
uh you know in order for in order for
Neville to find skunk he had to take the
skunkiest thing of skunk one that he
could find and cross it to a totally
unrelated genetic Maple Leaf yes
um and so you know
um
you know for for whatever for whatever
that work that is worth yeah um and yeah
someone just asked yeah there was there
it is it is from Virginia
um there was a gentleman that was uh you
know older than us and involved in dead
tour
um and he he did you know they did some
breeding but like a lot of a lot of 80s
breeding
um he didn't have a bunch of notes
and he didn't come out with this was
step one this was step two this was step
three
it's much more General it's like when we
interviewed when you when you and Kanza
interviewed Greg yeah it was a few
specifics and a lot of uh mysterious you
know yeah there wasn't a lot of detail
on the NLS as far as specifics there was
a couple things yeah
um you know so
um be that as it may like we're not
gonna actually do uh
um We're Not Gonna actually do a big
skunk one thing but in the it is
probably worthwhile to go over it at
some point but maybe we'll pick up where
you know we'll fill in gaps and comment
on what Sam is saying soon
yeah
um but anyway uh
I have just like such a much different
take on skunk one and everything that it
has to do with it like it's just it's a
different take because I wasn't around
like during those early eras to have
bought skunk one from like the first
year it was produced or ever or even
smoked anything like that my only skunk
was uh
stuff started much later you know in the
in the 2000s so my experience with it is
only
the Clones that we have left the old
clones that I've run of skunk one like
the cheese and other stuff like that
um and other stuff with heavy skunk one
influences that I learned over time were
very similar to what I am seeing out of
out of skunk one seed lines like the
pure from Flying Dutchman we got to run
but I didn't see anything capable of
producing anything like
the Terps we would see in super or not
terms but it's the same thing you can
see in super skunk and even looking at
everything that skunk one touches and
breeds outwards you just never seeing
anything like that in any of it well
it's interesting is
um Matt and I got to interview Corel
from Super sativa seed club and one of
the questions I can't remember if it was
when you asked him or with my section of
it but I can't remember that
um he did mention that the skunk that
got brought over in 8485
um
you know
um was different
than later open pollinations and later
breedings and and that type of stuff it
was a little raw yeah and I think even
Sam said that there maybe was a small
there was a small possibility you could
find something like that in there but
then later on it was it was basically
out
yeah and a lot of the the recent scams
that have been going on in the last five
or six years are turning on that hope
that oh my skunk is old enough that
you're gonna find in there this this
thing that Sam hadn't bred out yet you
know yeah and so I see some pretty cool
comments in the in here
um there's a uh people were talking
about pot of gold which uh product I
love pot of gold uh which is uh Hindu by
Skunk one and there's there was another
thing
um uh you know that was from the Flying
Dutchman and if I'm correct I believe
the Flying Dutchman was basically a I
don't want to say a front for Sam but
they seems like they bought most of
their wholesale seed stock from Sam yeah
um because Sam was willing to sell
wholesale within Holland which was legal
and not willing to sell retail
you know uh and
um you know there's another guy that
just asked if silver Pearl we both
describe silver Pearl differently yeah
uh and you know that people have been
building the same grows of the same Bud
too people have different
interpretations of the same thing you
know people have different uh people
have different um you know they get
different noses off things they can get
different effects off things you know
yeah uh and silver Pearl is actually an
early poly hybrid
yeah two so there can be different
Expressions off it
yeah yeah you know in that regardless
it's it's because I believe it's it's
early Pearl by
um Northern Lights by Skunk well yeah
yeah and early Pearl is early girl like
I mean it's it's a it's a hybrid of
a whole bit it's got a whole bunch of
different stuff it's crazy that it was
so consistent too like as far as its
Expressions being that much of a poly
hybrid it makes me wonder how much work
went into it beforehand for it to be so
consistent like with its Expressions
that it throws
you know there's another there's a
gentleman in the in the thing that was
saying that
um now we're getting a little off topic
but he was saying that Maple Leaf Indica
is probably the last thing that Scentsy
has that is original
after the Dutch raids
I don't believe that to be honest
um and I know and maybe a little bit of
history is is required there so uh Maple
Leaf was given to Neville by a character
named Jim Ortega
um and Neville sold it
um raw as you as it were uh at the seed
bank for about three years and then when
he got busted and he sold his company to
Scentsy seeds it disappeared off the
menu I think Matt for what it was like
about eight years it was a long time it
was about eight years
um and then it reappeared probably about
1999 it reappeared on scentsy's catalog
three or four years after Neville had
left and so as near as we can determine
that was no longer the original Maple
Leaf it was a hodgepodge of a few
different Maple Leaf phinos crossed the
skunk one yeah that Neville had uh made
it's made it Scentsy but was unreleased
so it's not pure Maple Leaf anymore
um and then on top of that after the
bust
um at some point Scentsy outsourced most
almost all of its breeding to Spain
so I I would I would love for there to
be some Aboriginal things from Scentsy
left I just don't put any Trust
into
um
you know I don't put any trust into it
I've seen stuff from Scentsy that came
out post you know 2000s and stuff like
that that looked like super skunk they
actually looked like it but none of it
it was all very simple one dominant type
uh sense though yeah yeah and I mean you
know skunk one sadly it's it's uh you
know it's got skunk in the name so
people really want to associate it with
that you know but uh it'll forever be
done every few years by the next Yahoo
that comes in and declares I've got
skunk I got the original skunk one it's
brand new you know I'm uh I'm a little
bit more people are talking in the
comments again so maybe we'll just kind
of ramble for a bit but people were
talking the comments I thought Scott and
Neville did a lot together
um that doesn't seem to be too terribly
true yeah
um I I I'm a little bit more of a shanty
backer than most in in our crew I would
say but what it does seem is that
um you know
Neville partnered with Shanti and
Greenhouse after Scentsy
and then Neville had a partnership a bit
with Shanti at um at uh Mr Nice seeds
and Neville did sell some of his old
collection of seeds to Shanti but it
doesn't seem that they were heavily
involved together for a lot of years in
actual breeding projects
was that the sense that you got talking
to Neville as well that's the sense I
got and I said I sensed a lot of um
yeah well a lot of you know there's you
know so anyway it it Shanty legitimately
uh by Neville's own Owen admittance
bought uh Neville's own club old
collection of seeds and they certainly
partnered together both at uh greenhouse
seeds with Arjun and at Mr Nice for a
while but in terms of them both being in
the same breeding room together doing a
lot of work over a number of years
it seems like as time goes on that seems
less likely than it was before that
would be the wildest ego battle I've
ever seen
that would be you know a a Star Wars uh
level ego battle that'd be cool but but
be that as it may maybe we could maybe
we could scroll back a little bit now uh
because we got we got way off topic
there a little bit but
um you know when it comes to like hop
latent or just clean practices in
general
um there's a there's a new you know um
I've seen people like get like uh um you
know you know like like the restaurant
style like you know like red ketchup
containers and they squirt a little bit
of gel into each plug and stuff like
that you know so you don't because one
of the big things is that all of a
sudden we're learning you don't want to
dip a raw cut
into a liquid or a gel that then you dip
another Raw it's basically like an open
wound yeah so if you don't want to
spread the viroid you probably don't
want to like share the same liquid with
hundreds of different open wounds it
would be nice if they just had a little
squeeze bottle with a little [ __ ]
thing
remember though one company used to do
that
people are doing that and that seems
cool but there is this thing that's
going on there's this gentleman I don't
usually give shouts out to people but
um
um but I'll say there's a guy on IG
called slow nickel
okay okay and he's an agronomist right
uh and he mostly does stuff with um you
know he's he mostly seems like he works
in the South and Central America growing
a lot of different kind of crops and
vegetables but he makes this really
interesting point um which divides with
me really strongly in which he does this
thing that's incredibly
counter-intuitive to me which is that
when you take your Rockwell pube or your
Rooter rapid Rooter plug or whatever
you're using right yeah he dips just the
tip of the actual cut itself into some
kind of rooting hormone yeah and then he
sticks that clone so that the actual cut
itself is not in the cube
okay so it's actually sticking out of
the cube right okay and the reason for
that is he said that what you want is
that you want that open wound to form a
hard callus yeah right and then once it
forms a callous then the roots shoot out
from there and the reason why it makes
so much sense to me is he says if you
leave this raw open wound and you stick
it in a Rockwell Cube or you stick it
into a rapid Rooter or something it'll
shoot out a bunch of roots but it's too
moist for it to form that hard callus
and then essentially you have an open
wound that allows a lot of opportunity
for fungal or virus or other various
things to get in there right which makes
a lot of sense yeah you know and he's
shown a lot of examples
um and a lot of people seem to be really
jiving on to his method yeah right and
it does make sense because if you think
of like human skin you know like it's a
big barrier against disease yeah right
and so you know the callus is
essentially a scab
yeah you form a hard scab and then the
roots start growing out of the you know
and then so that's pretty new uh for
people most people are just using to
stick the cutting into a rockable cube
or stick it into a rapid root or
whatever and it goes from there yeah
right
um and I actually having seen his Tech
and looking at it and reading about it I
actually I absolutely totally agree with
them yeah um I've been experimenting
with it for a while and
um it makes perfect sense to me and it's
changed how I do things now you know one
of the things that you have to do is
like a lot of times you'll have like an
insert that you'll stick into a tray
yeah and then you'll stick your rockwool
Cube or your rapid Rooter so that
actually the the stem that's sticking
out is a little elevated
yeah you see what I'm saying so it's not
just like touching flat against the the
tray itself
um I don't you know what the [ __ ] you're
talking about when it comes to hanging
out of the pla like how are you gonna
have it hanging an inch above the plug
when it doesn't float in the air so no
it's more like this so imagine I mean
this is this is gonna look a little
salacious or whatever but imagine this
is your plug yeah right and most people
would just stick it and leave it inside
but what he's saying is that have the
actual end about the bottom penetrate
the bottom side gotcha pop out the
bottom and then if that little callus
stick if that sticks out the bottom then
the actual cut end will Alice over hard
because yeah and honestly like if you
guys like if if you're if I'm not
describing it well you can look up slow
nickel on hygiene he has a really good
he has some good tutorials on a lot of
pictures on it
um but what it basically what is basic
technique is is just dip the rooting
hormone a little bit in that cut have
that cut callous or seal off like a like
a scab yeah and then it roots from there
and then it doesn't allow this big open
pathway Highway for you know fusarium or
disease to get up into your plant and
cause issues how about air embolisms
like that used to be the big thing like
everybody was don't get the [ __ ] and
I you know what's funny is back in the
day I remember Boney showed me this this
clone someone showed me this clone tech
for for put
Ting I just want to say for the crew
when I when I did the when I did my
little visual right there it did feel
slightly fifth gradish but here we are
you know so and for the people on audio
that didn't get to see he bent over and
it was real weird oh man there we go so
but yeah if you I don't usually plug
people but if you if you want to go look
up slow nickel he has a bunch of
examples and pictures on his page of the
tech that you can go and make and make a
lot of sense of and it does make sense
to seal the wound
to not have an open wound that allows
fungal matter and different stuff like
that to get in there yeah right so the
problem with that is that if you're
going to do that thing like you were
saying where you're going to inject a
bunch of gel into a rapid Rooter or into
a thing
um you know that's that's that's that's
sticking the plant into the cube again
yeah
you know
um so because
and you know like you were saying before
um in terms of slowing down hop latent
um it makes area flows shitty technology
yeah you really better make sure that
the Clones you're putting in an area
flow are 100 clean yeah because you
absolutely will spread it to every other
clone in that area flow yeah or in that
in that you know aerial cloner or you
know whatever whatever brand you're
you're familiar with it's just a bunch
of raw wound cuttings getting sprayed by
the same liquid over and over and over
and over again so it's a breeding house
for disease yeah I never liked those
things because I just could never keep
it consistently clean like all it took
is one little
pathogen vector and that was it and it
would be in the motor it would be
everywhere in those damn things
yeah I mean if you if the biggest issue
with those is that you want to keep your
water temperature in the mid 60s yeah um
that's where you get the most oxygen huh
yeah a chiller is kind of nice yeah and
then and then on top of that even if you
have fungal diseases like say pithium in
your water
um pythium can't actually reproduce
below 68 degrees oh interesting it
absolutely can't right which is why like
in in rivers and streams or ponds or
whatever if you see cold water it's
usually clear yeah and warm water is
usually not
interesting in that regard yeah um and
so you know they're uh
um
you know I all of a sudden my my uh I
apologize everyone my my comments paused
and now they just unpause and now
there's a million things going on but
but anyway
um you know cloning Tech he it does seem
like
um he is showing cloning Tech that makes
a lot of sense and just as a general as
a general Vibe
um sealing sealing off the wound
you know and not allowing and not
allowing Rock going on there is a big
deal yeah you know
um and so you know people might have to
change I mean I used to I used to dip
all of my cuttings in the same solution
so it really in order to slow down the
Hop latent or slow down other diseases
now that we're worried about you really
kind of have to look at like your whole
process
um and look at every step because you
can't do all you can't do most of the
steps right and then have a centralized
thing where you're screwing it all up
yeah I knew a lot of people who would
keep moms and use Aero cloners to you
know reinvigorate their moms you know
keep their rooms going and that might be
a technique of the past the big the big
problem that I used to run I used to run
aerial cloners when I ran water culture
the big issue that I had with them when
you're running them in soil or something
else is that if you use a rapid Rooter
you use a rockwool plug or anything like
that it just gives the the Clone itself
an anchor yeah you can have like a you
can have a rooted cutting with beautiful
Roots all coming off it and then you
transplant it into some soil or whatever
else and if you don't stabilize it the
right way there's nothing really it's
just a stick with some rooms and it has
a tendency to move around a bunch yeah
you know
so um but really what it is is that he's
shown it a bunch of times a lot of times
uh root rot or fusarium or pythium or
whatever else can go right up into your
plant
and a lot of times your plant can
recover but those plants end up yielding
less than others or being weaker yeah
and it seems like it was just an
unrealized weak point in a lot of
people's cloning method
which is cool because now that one of
the there's not been that many benefits
of legal weed
um in my opinion yeah um but one of them
might be that some actual agronomists
and actual people can bring some
different techniques that you know might
might improve uh you know cannabis
culture
um and how we do things
now before I before I forget I want to
say some things um I didn't told you yet
but uh land race genetics I think in the
coming week or so and this is going to
be on their time over in Afghanistan
or Pakistan I can't remember which part
he's in right now but he's going to take
us through a field
as they're harvesting
over there live oh wow I know isn't that
[ __ ] cool so he's gonna try to set it
up with the farmers there so we can go
live from the fields uh in the Mideast
essentially to watch some of the
harvesting go down some of the technique
and maybe help us talk to some of the
farmers and translate for us so it'll it
might be at 2 A.M or 3 A.M or 4 a.m but
I'm gonna wake up and do it whatever
time it is because that will be freaking
amazing it's the other side of the Earth
Somebody commented I seen a pic of that
nl5 tell us about it I don't know what
you're talking about with that uh I put
up a pic of nl5 today
and it was good
um yeah we have a whole episode on
Northern Lights with Seattle Greg so
please go go watch that if you want to
learn about Northern Lights we have most
of our episodes catch something on
something Northern Lights at some point
you know yeah Valley thank you it's one
of the building blocks yeah um and
because it's so ancient there's a lot of
there's a lot of funny claims popping up
now
um about
um you know ancient nl5 lines recently
rediscovered you know this and that pure
Neville this that all that um yeah how
would y'all rate ml5 Haze on a one to
ten I still gotta read some more stuff
too real quick before we jump into all
that oh sorry yeah it's all right um uh
no don't go away go ahead I think uh I
think nl5 Hayes is the most successful
publicly released hybrid in marijuana
history yeah and I think there's
probably more high quality uh um clones
from from that line that are still alive
today and circulated than probably any
other line yeah
realistically speaking that's actually
why I rate it so highly it's not just
personal preference it's that there's
literally like usually we're lucky if
there's one or or two at most
um you know cultivars that have survived
from their original era that we know are
are it is what it is
um and with nl5 Haze there's probably
like over 10. yeah which is pretty
incredible for something that was
basically from 85 88 89 to uh
um you know 95 or 96 or something I
think it would probably be fair to say
cookies bad Steve stumped the [ __ ] out
of nl5as as far as Cuts distributed now
nowadays
um you know what I mean like I think
that one probably swept the market
unfortunately I don't know about all
that yeah
I mean but but what else what I'll say
is that proof will be in the pudding so
you know um a lot of these nl5 Haze
cuttings that are still around and
capped are 25 to 30 years old right
we'll give we'll give cookie another 15
or 20 years and we'll see how many of
these original clones are held onto and
hoarded by Future Generations yeah um
because that's really the key to staying
power you can have all the hype you want
um but you know it really better be good
to have people keep coming back to it so
time will tell you know
um it you know one of the one of the
things about cookie is that it's so much
more modern than nl5 Haze you would
think just by the law of averages there
would be way more of it
um that would survive
yeah but the only reason why the only
reason why it's going to survive that
long or you're going to have that many
cookie Cuts survive for that long is If
people really love it and really
appreciate the smoke yeah
in my opinion I think so yeah I I think
you're right Cookie's probably we'll see
if it'll stand the test but you know I I
will say that that's not exactly a fair
comparison because what I was basically
doing is comparing things to like
actually released seed lines
you know where cookies was more like it
got famous as a cut and then bag seeds
occurred and then various hybrids
occurred where you know um it's not like
AK-47 or nl5 Haze or silver Pearl or
something where you could buy seeds of
it yeah for a number of years from a
company
yeah you know
um and then no 5 Hayes never actually
really ruled the market uh our buddy
crybaby is is uh is commenting on that
it's true Super Skunk outsold it a lot
Neville said there was other things that
were a lot more popular I'm just saying
that I don't think any cut I don't think
any seat mine has as many different
females that have survived as long
yeah I think that that might be fair to
say you know I mean because there's
there's a number of them in Europe and
there's a number of them in America and
you start adding all those ones up and
all of a sudden you're at you know 10 or
12 clones that are 25 to 35 years each I
have a theory and I think crybaby
probably has a similar Theory based on
what we've seen I know we've talked
about it is that super skunk might have
a similar history but we just don't know
enough about the cuts that are out there
that are super skunk Cuts yet that's
what I think well one of the things
that's that is uh that really sucks from
a historian perspective is that
Americans especially are very good about
giving counterculture nicknames to their
weed
um and so a lot of a lot of the original
genetics that came over in the 80s and
90s are obscured because they got some
they got a name yeah and then we don't
know what they are anymore
um so we know that there was an enormous
amount of Super Skunk that was sold
but it was probably given nicknames yes
exactly like we believe that we believe
that the that it's likely that the puck
is a hash plant from Neville yeah but it
got the nickname the puck with one crew
and then it got the nickname the Skelly
from another crew yeah
you know I mean the snow I've talked
about that before the snow was called
skunk five in Florida yeah and then it
was called Eugene snow in glassblower
circles in Eugene it was called Humboldt
snow when our buddy Caleb got a hold of
it in the late 90s
you know uh people talking about the dog
[ __ ] the dog [ __ ] was called Electric
Boogaloo
um Matt and I Matt and I and friends of
ours have been like debating whether or
not we think what we think that is
um but a lot of plants got nicknames and
um those nicknames obscure you know what
origin it might have come from
and so far because philos is a liar and
other groups are liars we haven't I mean
it would be amazing if we had like a a
genetic ability to test things and that
Corel and Neville and and Sirius and
these various groups had their original
[ __ ] and you could just they could just
put that up into a database and then you
could map out what came out of it yeah I
have um I also have a conversation soon
that I was telling you about with um
uh Mrs I want to pronounce her name
right Vergara I want to say from
um
um Cornell University their their
cannabis reading program and I'm very
interested in talking with her and she's
interested in talking with us because
the scientific Community is having a
hard time understanding why the Clones
that they have now currently are not
lining up with what they're seeing in
the actual genetic data and when I was
talking with her I was like well there's
a lot of reasons why because what you're
given is these Legacy clones that you
guys think you have probably aren't what
they say they are or aren't what Leafly
because they're they're relying a lot on
things like Leafly for their genetic
data like looking at oh Leafly says it
is XYZ so it must be XYZ let's enter it
into our little database and that's
where the problem is always going to be
with with uh Academia versus traditional
Farmers because there's a pretty small
group of people that know and it's even
harder to know that you have the legit
cut and then even for historians like
Matt and I and Caleb and others and
stuff sometimes like the information
that we think we know gets turned on its
head yeah a little bit I mean Matt and I
if you want to talk about the dog [ __ ]
for a minute
um and just so everybody knows this is
like absolute speculation on my part but
a lot of people have thought that the
dog [ __ ] is an old nl5 Hayes Fino
right yeah
um I have
I have thought perhaps that it is a old
silver Pearl by Hayes Fino which was
called that in Neville's catalog and
then later it was just called silver
haze from Scentsy yeah um and that would
explain why it's prettier
that's what I would explain because it
doesn't really actually look like the
cough or the A5
and it's not as wild as that it's
actually a much prettier hybrid but it
has the haze effect and it certainly has
that Neville's you know that Neville's
like feeling to it
um but it looks like it has something
else in it and that that strain was
available from about 88 on
um and was available from Neville's
catalog and from Scentsy
um and uh you know that's total
speculation but there's not very many
things that came from all we know is
that it came out of Minneapolis
Minnesota area in the early 90s
and came West
and the rest of it is just observational
I was thinking nl5 skunk one Haze
because I've seen a lot of pretty nl5
skunk one Haze
um like from from Delta 9 labs they did
their fruit of the Gods and that was an
nl5 skunk one Haze or like a uh that's a
perfect example but think about it right
now so silver Pearl times Haze
would be early Pearl nl5 skunk one
exactly it's it's really close so you
just basically described many hairs yeah
you know um and I'm not I don't that's
just complete speculation on my part due
to the timing of the seeds available
what the plant is telling me the fact
that the plant is prettier and quicker
than most of the other straight nl5 Haze
f1s
um but it's just a guess yeah but it's a
guess and I think it's fair because you
can look at it and see
if I'm looking at dog [ __ ] it has the it
has a lot of resin production for it
like an nl5 Haze if it were Nano 5 Haze
it has really good resin production and
it goes to the edges and tips of the
leaves even on some of the um not
families but bigger leaves uh water
leaves that aren't families and I
remember Neville telling me that trait
specifically was from skunk ones so we
know it has skunk one in it somewhere
I think based on what Neville said so
that I think your your your uh silver
Pearl is very very interesting uh
synopsis I mean yeah so you know could
it be it could be you know I don't know
it certainly like I said the seed the
seed was available during the time that
it popped up in Minnesota
um you know there wasn't honestly barely
any Haze hybrids available on the market
then I've grown personally a lot of
skunk one Haze uh from Sam yeah it
definitely isn't that
yeah it's got other things in it you
know and so but you know it also could
be uh something unknown that turns us on
its head you know yeah could be
uh oh boy you know people ask me about
stem rubs uh you know stem rubs are I
there there are some Terps occasionally
that come off stems
um you I would put myself in the in the
classification of in Veg it's the rare
plant that I get much off of stem rub
and vegetative growth yeah
I mean I can smell stuff but it rarely
does it transfer to flour for it to mean
anything to me other than this plant
smells like this in veg I mean
interestingly I lost it in the fires but
that old tan Joe cut I had that was from
the early 80s yeah you could be carrying
a tray of of you know of one gallon pots
or something and you would get whiffs of
citrus yeah even in veg but it's pretty
rare yeah I mean I always tell people
like if you want to smell roadkill skunk
go get like the poodle nuts cut or even
an Urkle in veg take a cut sniff it I
mean but but it does it transfer to
[ __ ] flour unfortunately like Urkel's
grape it's a very grapey it has some
skunky tones in it but mostly grapey and
sweet so yeah I mean it it not
everything transfers unfortunately a lot
of people like I've seen breeders be
like yeah this [ __ ] [ __ ] roots and
veg yes donkey and it's like oh yeah
they give you what I mean they give you
like a someoneiere list of smells and
Aromas and maybe their schnoz is just a
lot better than mine uh and their brains
on a different level but I am always
amazed at some of the depth that people
can get off a basic stem rub I'm not
saying it's impossible I have had some
plants that definitely gave me some
Terps that were identifiable in veg I'm
just saying for me personally it's a
little it's it's more rare
um you know and so you know and it's
usually something simple to me like
citrus yeah it's not like oh it smells
like leather with hints of raw cherries
and a backbone of coffee it's it's yeah
I don't get a lot of complexity it's
usually something simple shining through
you know on that level
um and uh you know one thing I never
hear is is I smell chlorophyll okay
that's one thing I definitely smell and
veg when I run something is a shitload
of chlorophyll and people were asking me
what do I think about the you know I I
did get a couple of uh Caleb selections
from Matt and Caleb's uh
um nl5 outgrow that they did when they
you know they grew a bunch of plants but
I in my part of California it is
extremely hot and nasty especially this
summer in summer uh and so I was waiting
for more opportune weather to give those
a shot
um real quick I'm going to talk about we
have the therighteats.com sale right now
I want to see how many people actually
listen to this buy stuff so it the the
coupon code's invisible 40 it's gonna
work for this weekend 40 off anybody who
uses it so if if you use it I'll know
you watch the show and you get to save
40 and that's pretty cool we put up some
Red Menace which is the Bubba uh flow
hybrid the Blueberry Scone which is the
wedding cake Bluebonnet uh the blue
cream which is the uh we were talking
about silver Pearl tonight that's the
the perfect Pearl from pipsweed uh which
is a silver Pearl S1 cross to the blue
bonnet so all those are up there those
haven't been dropped before I don't
think except for the wedding cake one
early on and invisible four to get you
40 off so enjoy there we go people keep
commenting on my beard you know I uh I
do a lot I work outside a lot in summer
and so it helps with uh SPF
yeah it helps protect me from aging
you know faster than I already am yeah
yeah I don't know it's handsome the salt
and pepper I've only got a little bit I
need some of that I don't know about
salt and pepper it's getting a little
whiter on that level yeah a little more
salt a little more a little a little
more salt a little less pepper you know
yeah
um but uh but yeah you know uh
you know they uh we'll we'll see you
know I think Matt and Caleb they're
gonna do they're gonna do some further
work with that nl5 you know line hybrid
whatever it might be
um picking out females that they like
and seeing what's going on so we have we
actually have some um we have some
really big big projects coming up um not
just me with um CSI but the whole group
um so there's a few things we'll be able
to talk about soon but I'm really
[ __ ] stoked we got some big
collaborations coming up with CSI on
many levels so uh yeah I mean the homie
what's good about the homie is that he
uh not only does he do stuff that
interests him in terms of what he thinks
might be like um you know modern
cultivars and stuff like that and modern
hybrids but he also does reproduction of
old seed stock
um he's very willing to take uh dubious
seeds with a story and run a bunch of
them and see you know he'll let the
seeds he'll let the plants tell him what
he thinks of it later on yeah you know
because uh sometimes good seed stock
comes from scandalous characters yeah uh
you know and all that and so you know he
does Femme seeds regular seeds
experimental projects that type of thing
so you know uh in a Land of like let's
smash together all the most popular Cuts
today
um doing some of that other kind of work
that doesn't really you know might not
fly off the shelves as fast but it's
still valuable is really is really
important one one I was he was telling
me about the other day and I was like
because I always give him [ __ ] like
he'll make stuff and he'll put it on his
site sometimes and not announce it
anywhere not a [ __ ] word he'll be
like yeah no one was really interested
in that and I'm like bro did you even
tell anyone did you tell them because I
didn't know that you put it out he was
talking about a Mendo perps
um cross to I think it was a Blackberry
Widow from JoJo Rizzo and it was a um it
was else I think it was elselayer who
made it originally and Caleb took it to
F3 and if if people remember Blackberry
widow
um it's very magenta red pretty
um and Meadow perps can spit that too
and he bred this in that red Direction
and he's got an F3
seed run that he did ages ago like eight
years ago it's just been kept in the
freezer you know and still got perfect
germ rates but you never really sold
them you know things like that blow my
mind even uh multi-stage breeding of any
kind uh in today's economic environment
is rare yeah so it should be supported
um because like most breeding projects
you don't get what you want in one step
yeah um Buckshot yeah the Hawaiian life
was doing great in um Bakersfield heat
Outdoors too it was it was played really
well shockingly because we were getting
up into the 118's 120s this year six
days of over a hundred
we uh we had California had one of the
worst heat waves in modern memory
uh just this last in the you know after
Labor Day which was really unfortunate
you know
um it took my a lot of my friends told
me up in Mendo and stuff like that that
they're uh they don't think their weed
is nice
oh I believe it because the heat wave
yeah yeah yeah well that's weird because
when some other breeders saying that the
more heat the more skunky it is I
believe so that's funny
you know I mean I you know they're
I when it gets to that extreme heat it's
just damaging nothing's happy you know
you don't want to be 115 118 and then 80
or 90 degrees at night you know yeah
that's just that's just not going to
make anything happy and I do think that
like one of the things that makes Mendo
and Southern Humboldt Trinity and things
like that one of the really nice places
is to grow outdoor cannabis is that you
get a nice cool stretch at night it
might be 100 degrees in the daytime but
it gets into the 50s at night and that
temperature differential I think brings
out the crystal content the Terps some
of the development I think that make
like I always notice that like people in
like Grass Valley or people that were
more Inland in California they would get
these ginormous plants from the same
strings but I didn't think they were
quite as not people from there probably
getting mad at me but I didn't think
that they developed I didn't think that
their region developed it's fair you
know I just think that you know if he
hits 55 or 60 degrees at night or 48 or
something like that it brings out
something in the Cannabis that if it
only gets down to the 80s it doesn't
yeah
so you know um and I think too it's like
those cold snaps uh or you know it gives
the plant it's just like humans like
they say that like one of the biggest
dangers with heat waves is when it gets
really warm at night
um your body doesn't have a chance to
recover from the day yeah and so one of
the biggest dangers is is extremely warm
nights for humans yeah and I think the
same thing to be true for cannabis like
the cool nights gives the plant an
ability to recover from a really hot day
yeah and if it's 88 degrees at 11
o'clock at night
um boy
yeah there were there were many nights
here where it wouldn't get under a
hundred all night it was [ __ ] unreal
yeah so you know so I from uh multiple
friends have told me that they did not
think that they don't think their plants
are quite as which sucks for the current
uh the current market and the current uh
economics of things but uh it was it was
a poorly timed Heat Wave yeah and
unusually late you know and usually and
yeah unusually brutal for sure
so
um
yeah I don't know
I
um but you know there's there's an
aspect of of uh that's one of the things
about climate change if you were
um that uh is really interesting in the
sense that a lot of times in not just in
cannabis but in other agriculture you
pick spots that tend to suit what you're
doing
yeah and if the climate shifts it might
not it might not suit what you're doing
as much
yeah you know as an indoor grower
um I didn't really take into account how
much uh the weather in Bakersfield would
affect even indoor growing like it's
when it gets to a certain point it's so
brutal that that it does affect indoor
growing even you know like trying to
keep the house cool while you're running
[ __ ] x amount of Lights it's gnarly
it's not I mean it's hot there's a
there's an old ass term we used to use
in the height of the indoor days summer
bud
yeah summer Bud was not as nice
yeah and you know there's a lot of other
types and honestly like I uh you know
where I live in Mendo like granted I get
to use the outside which is nice but a
lot of people would shut down in summer
yeah um because they wouldn't grow as
nice herb yeah and back in the day you
could get away with like a little bit
lesser indoor
uh but right now the market is just ugly
so
um you know summer run bud can be you
know there there's uh I don't even know
what to talk about when it comes to the
market uh it's ever it's ever changing
and very painful and has a bunch of
people very nervous and
um you know so yeah I think we've delved
into that depressive [ __ ] talk enough
yeah where everybody's filming that that
is is deeply involved in the weed scene
where it's not just a hobby and even
people that it's just a hobby look at
the electric bills look at it look at
how everything's going especially in
California even hobby Growers are
starting to not be able to afford to
grow
yeah I mean California sadly
um you know its power is just through
the roof yeah you know so even just
keeping yourself cool like the human
part of your family cool uh can be a lot
of money
yeah my mom will live in like 100 degree
weather inside her house because she's
an old Miser but um and if she hears the
sorry Mom but um
her electric bill this last month was
like six hundred dollars which was
outrageous for her she's never had
anything even that [ __ ] close because
she will live and eat without any kind
of AC just because she's cheap and that
blew her [ __ ] mind the 600 electric
bill hit her so I would imagine
everybody's having a rough time with
that
yeah and you know and then obviously
like you know in California especially
PG e got got made liable for a number of
these uh incredible fires
and so yeah I mean they you know what
are they going to do declare bankruptcy
and got a business and you don't have
power yeah no it's a monopoly too is
there a reason we're allowed to have
Monopoly for an electric company
it's it's not necessarily a monopoly
because I don't you don't have PG e down
there it's all the only thing we have
the only thing you have is PG e
interesting
um you know the option it's the only
option I mean it's hard to have a bunch
of competition because who owns all the
transmission lines yeah who's
responsible for maintaining all the
polls and all the power and all of this
and all that it's not something like you
can just be like oh well T-Mobile versus
a T versus this versus that it's it's a
little there's a lot of infrastructure
involved yeah the water companies here
are the same way you don't have a choice
on that you don't have a choice on
garbage and you don't have a choice on
an electric company
you know so
um it uh it's you know I mean when um
you know when I first moved to Mendo uh
all the all the diesel grows in the
woods or whatever you know diesel was a
dollar
yeah now it's super expensive yes you
know
um before you know I I this is gonna
date me but like before I was I had an
eight lighter before
um before the Enron fake scandal in 2000
2001 where they they lied about how much
how like that California had a power
crisis oh that [ __ ] yeah yeah and you
know my eight lighter was never more
than 350 bucks a month yeah and then
they raised the rates right after that
and it was 12 to 1500 a month yeah
crazily yep
um
there's a great documentary on that
called Enron the smartest guys in the
room if anybody wants to watch anything
on it it explains it in detail how how
they played they played us in California
and they actually got us to lock into
Super long-term extremely high power
rates because the governor was worried
they was going to get even worse yeah
and even though they went down for fraud
and a bunch of the bunch of the top
Executives did long prison terms we
petitioned the federal government to
break the contracts because they were
signed with a company fraudulently
cheating California yeah and the Bush
Administration didn't let us out of the
didn't let us out of it
shocking so it's just been it's been
unfortunately for California uh growing
indoor has been increasingly expensive
yeah definitely prohibitively expensive
prohibitively expensive and uh you know
sadly the you know the price of indoor
is also is not heading and and you know
it's not like going up with the cost of
doing business yeah no it's crazy it's
only soft so um it's really pinched a
lot of people unfortunately yeah you
know in that regard so
um
yeah I mean it uh
there are certain places like I think
there's certain places in in like in in
Trinity and there's other areas that tie
into like hydroelectric power right
where the power is a lot cheaper but
everywhere that people like to live in
California for the most part like is
expensive yeah yeah even like I said
Bakersfield used to be like one of the
last cheap little bastions for for
cheapness in California to be able to
afford a home but that's done that's
long gone now so yeah
being poor doesn't really work in
California too well anymore a fork
um you know Trinity the problem with
Trinity is just it's like you might as
well live Swiss Family Robinson
you know it's remote is it ever been up
there yeah yeah my buddy was just
Siskiyou County a Southern Oregon power
and it's cheaper
there's some hydroelectric that comes
out of Oregon so there's certain
counties in Far Northern California that
have way way nicer power than
um any of the population centers where
most of us live I actually want to bring
rings on for a show I think he'd be
awesome awesome awesome both of you two
shooting the [ __ ] yeah if I could
convince him he would be good one day
he's a super weed nerd he's been
breeding for a long time he has his own
take on weed
he's pretty he's pretty sarcastic yeah
yeah he is you know him and I have done
a number of different projects together
and we have a lot of similarities in
terms of like our approach to things and
stuff so yeah
um you know yeah it uh um
you know there's not
um there's not you know there's uh you
know people that that crack seeds every
year and grow different seeds every year
outside and do breeding projects every
year that's
I don't want to call them a Dying Breed
necessarily but they're rarer than they
used to be definitely did I tell you I'm
doing a new UFO podcast Tuesday
you did not I I am gonna do my friend
Nick and it's be called invisible
residence and Tuesday we're going to
have our first recording of us talking
for the first time like trying to figure
it out so yes I didn't know if you'd
want to do it but I entered UFOs aren't
necessarily your thing but yeah we're
gonna give it a go and see if anybody
gives a [ __ ] but it would be interesting
especially from a skeptical point of
view on UFOs
I bet yeah he um I will say one thing
about my buddy Rings is that he comes up
with a series of very inappropriate seed
line names and hashish names that sounds
familiar he does I I would actually have
to say that he might he he might have
the most inappropriate that I'm aware of
yeah really which one is it can you can
you say this name can I say it can I can
I pump him out sure
um do uh uh he has one called uh your
sister's innocence laughs
yep
um I love it there's another one there's
another one called butt stuff yeah butt
stuff's a great one that's how me and
him first started talking about if you
cross butt stuff to your sisters in a
sense you really start getting places
yeah you sure do he had a he had a
hashish line for a minute that you
remember Heaven's Gate yes because those
that's probably right up your alley with
all the UFO weirdos so yeah remember how
they all had like the Adidas suits and
like the shoes the Nike yeah right so
there he he had this image of like two
Nike shoes pointing up and then the
Adidas jump shoot and it ends at the
knees and then like and then like a
spaceship
you know
um the clubs had a hard time
uh promoting the uh the head the heavens
gate uh the yeah the heavens gate
hashish line it was uh it was a little
through risque perhaps a little too a
little too morbid the humor was so black
it was ultraviolet
yes yeah
that's Rings humor humor so black it's
ultraviolet yeah uh and then there's and
then there's ones that are um that are
worse than that that didn't even make
the public cut so oh wow yeah I love it
you know but yeah I would have to say
there's other ones there's other ones I
won't say but one of my favorite is
yours I mean how do you get more your
sister's innocence you know oh that's
too good that's too good
um
you know but I mean he's he's actually
been in Mendo longer than I have um I
moved here in in 98 he moved here in
like 94. yeah which is definitely a
different time and so he's been here
through a lot of different eras and we
have been talking a bunch actually about
how you know we watched an enormous
amount of people pour into our community
yeah um as the green Rush happened
and now that the prices crashed we're
watching all these people pour out Mass
Exodus yeah yeah there was a lot of
people that came here for different
reasons a lot of money
and as that has gotten tighter they fled
maybe I need to move up now when it's
when the getting's good and everybody's
gone
yeah I mean it uh it uh where can I find
your sister's innocence
um you know your sister's innocence is a
fleeting thing it's only there for so
long and then once it's gone it's gone
you know I mean it's gone it's pretty
hard to get it back you know check your
muscle rest up once it's uh once once
it's gone it's gone you know it's it's a
it's a brief period of time yeah you
know it's a brief period of time
so but yeah but you know Mendo Mendo is
probably going to go back to somewhat
depopulated and weird
yeah because there was a lot of rich
kids that moved up here and and faked
being hippies or whatever in order to
grow weed and I have spending money and
there was a lot of people that moved
here for different reasons there's a lot
of people that came up here and bought
property
um and grew for a few years and then
farmed it out to friends and went and
lived in the bay or went and lived in LA
or went in Santa Rosa or whatever and
you know got and they just like you know
took a skim off the lifestyle to do
whatever they wanted yeah and the
economics of that are all trashed so
it's very likely that um in the next
four or five years a lot of uh Mountain
properties are going to start popping up
so yeah makes sense
um you know and and you know Mendo Still
Remains one of the better places to grow
weed yeah it's just a matter about you
know survival and whether or not you
like to live in the country
whether you or not you like to turn up
in weird Fields with your soul missing
with your soul missing yeah yeah oh no
that's that's that's uh what was that
show called Murder Mountain that's
humbled isn't it that's humble yeah and
that's that's that's obviously
um it's exaggerated to some degree of
course but it's also no but it actually
is it's also true the area that they're
talking about is this place called Alder
Point Road outside of Garberville yeah
and one of the things that made Alder
Point Road pretty famous is that there's
a lot of places in Humboldt Mendo that
are big Parcels say like 40 80 160.
that's kind of how they got divvied up
uh legally yeah um and aldera Point Road
had a bunch of you know four acre six
acre ten acre 12 acre right so it meant
a lot of weirdos got more tightly packed
together yeah and it was a cheap place
to land
in Humble blow it up for a bit and then
try to get out somewhere better
you know so you get a bunch of weirdos
all on top of each other living too
close to each other if you're all on uh
if you're if you if you've got a bunch
of 160 acre Parcels or a bunch of 80
acre personals you have some distance
from people yeah if you have a bunch of
three acres six acre Four Acre eight
acre little Parcels then you're all kind
of stacked up on one another yeah and
then you know there's more interaction
there's more weirdos
yeah definitely uh the heels them heal
weirdos
so so have you confirmed with your your
buddy Tom Hill if he's going to do the
show or not
you know
um speaking of Hill weirdos I don't
think it would be insulting uh we are
hopeful we are hopeful to soon have Tom
Hill on the show uh I don't think it's
going to be Live It Won't Be Live um it
will be it'll only be audio he's
probably only going to be audio I'm
probably going to have to go honestly
visit him yeah um at his spot
um but he has lived on one of the most
notorious areas in Mendocino County
since the mid 80s yeah uh and so that in
itself is an enormous load of stories
he's got an immense amount of wheat
history in there and then how he sort of
got famous outside of Mendo and our
little circles is he became active on
the forums in the early days
and uh Matt can speak to this too
um you know but he was along with Vic
High uh and a number of other people he
was kind of a giant on the early forums
in a way uh he created Tom Hills Hayes
um he's credited with deep chunk which
some people huh x18 ptk yeah all kinds
of [ __ ] he he's been around a lot of the
old school growing families and a lot of
the old school growing techniques he's
seen all the different eras from the
camp and the 80s into the 90s into 215
um uh you know uh deep chunk I didn't
actually hear it called Deep chunk
because in Mendo we called it monkey
balls yeah
um some people called it deep chunk some
people called it um uh Hindu death
cabbage uh it had a number of different
names but it probably is the closest
thing to an actual like I see a lot of
times uh the chemist is different but
the chemist is also still alive uh and
someone that Tom could speak on
extensively so I'm actually really
excited
um
to maybe to maybe chat with him
uh and he's he's definitely a little bit
reclusive but we're hopeful to be able
to do sort of like a private recorded
thing that we could put up later yeah
yeah
um and he is uh to both mad and myself I
would say uh he's sort of uh an elder
a hero someone that both of us looked up
to uh while
um you know while we were learning how
to how to breed I still do I mean he
talked [ __ ] with the best of them too
like and I don't know growing up reading
his [ __ ] talk like the [ __ ] he would say
I'd be like damn I want to be like that
dude he doesn't [ __ ] take no [ __ ] no
he was pretty famous for being caustic
online and on on one of the lives
um I called him a cantankerous old man
uh and he reached out to me to say that
he's mellowed
um which is pretty funny
um but uh yeah but but I think I think
very highly of him and he's really he's
like people throw this this term around
lightly uh or you know too lightly in my
opinion but Tom is a legitimate cannabis
OG yeah I agree he's a he has he has
created a bunch of uh really cool lines
uh he's been around for an enormous
amount of History he's a super character
uh he was important in the forums
um a lot of people have bred with his
work uh he is he's a badass so every
serious reader I know has been inspired
by uh Tom Hill in some way in his word
every serious breeder I know uh yeah
he's an adult he he at this point he's
an elder in the in the breeding
Community
um and his work speaks for itself and he
I'm not going to name where it is but
with the some of the some of the areas
that he's lived in for a long time are
what I consider to be the Beating Heart
of the Mendocino cannabis scene
um from way back in the day uh so it
would be super cool and everybody that's
listening tonight
um you know hopefully
um he's someone to listen to he's
someone to look up to uh and it's not
easy to be a cannabis lifer no no no no
um it is not uh yeah and not and coming
from his era too like I said I say this
all the time like it was it was just as
dangerous back then to deal wheat as it
was anything else so a lot of people had
to [ __ ] with a lot of stuff and it was a
different time you know different kinds
of characters are involved so what's
cool about that perhaps is that the I
don't I can't predict exactly where the
conversation will go I'm supposed to go
up there and barbecue with them perhaps
and maybe I'll you know have a wide
ranging conversation but
um it could you could you he could talk
extensively just about the history of
where he's at
you could talk extensively about a bunch
of his own breeding he could talk
extensively about the strains and the
type of things that were around in the
various eras
um there's a lot of different directions
you could probably have a series of
talks with him about certain subjects
and really get some places so
um hopefully it happens soon he's
expressed interest
um he likes what Matt and I are doing
which is extremely humbling
yeah you know yeah I I generally didn't
even think he knew who the [ __ ] I was
like that's that's where it's at you
know like different era different
everything so yeah it was cool yeah
super cool you know so we'll see can I
can't predict when or how soon or
whatever but there's been some interest
and so when that [ __ ] happens people
should really listen because
um you know he's been in it to win it
for a long time and he does have another
interview out so Phil I think it's
coming out soon so definitely keep your
ears poke for that check it out yeah
because he does he does and regardless
of what platform it's on he's worth
listening to absolutely um we're both
you know I don't actually listen to a
lot of other weed podcasts because they
kind of drive me nuts
um but I will be listening to that one
because of who it who he is yeah I'm
gonna listen to the podcast for that one
I'll even give it the plug yeah I mean I
I might even I might even listen to the
uh to the the [ __ ] Gypsy one but I
wouldn't go that far
yeah I don't really I don't have any
interest in hearing [ __ ] I'm just I'm
just curious what what spin he spins
yeah I mean you know I wouldn't
interview that guy
even though he's a Eve but you know but
I I'm curious I am a little bit curious
um but you know we'll see I doubt that
that guy will ask him the right
questions yeah yeah okay you can only
that's the thing though like if you've
if you're new to breeding what are you
gonna ask Tom Hill
what would you know to ask him
um what forums are left for you to
peruse to to go look you know what I
mean like it's it's it's hard it's a
hard thing to do so it'll be different
um but I'm excited either way there's so
much I I I've been trying to research
the chemist for many years and have
gotten like absolutely [ __ ] nowhere
except for like little hints of people
who met him once and like said you know
XYZ but I can say I'm very interested in
that I can say this uh the chemist is
alive
yeah he's in his 70s and I thought he
was not with us I'll leave it at that
um someone just asked he did not create
Urkel
um but
um you know uh Tom has his his view of
how Urkel happened
um and it's an interesting one so if I
get if I get a chance to go and hang out
and we get a chance to talk that will
probably be on the list because it's
probably something that people would be
interesting in hearing
and to our good friends listening right
now keep your calendar clear for
December at the emerald ball it sounds
like we may be doing another can
Illuminati thing which is private it'll
probably be small but for our very good
friends who go every year and listen to
this
um keep your calendars clear
yeah we we were met Matt and I and some
other close friends of ours we kind of
threw a party for a few years for weed
enthusiasts breeders heads various
things like that it was pretty
successful it was a really nice time for
people to get together and smoke a bunch
of weed and shoot the [ __ ] in person uh
it got [ __ ] by covid uh for a number
of years but now that it seems like
that's receding and times are a little
different we're going to try to bring it
back yeah and uh so that means I gotta
get on uh you know having some samples
yeah get your [ __ ] ready son yeah so
yeah you know
um so yeah I mean people can reach out
about that one I'm not sure we're not
trying to get inundated in invites if
you're not a close friend that hasn't
gone to one it's probably going to be
smaller than the last ones even so even
people that went to the last one
probably won't be heading to this one
but but there you know there's it's it's
who knows it's not the the the size and
who's coming and all that and everything
like that not to leave anybody out but
like we it's we're hoping it's gonna
happen yes so sounds like it that's the
plans
you know maybe we can even do some
content from not like live but maybe we
could even like you know oh yeah get
some people that year but we had too
much fun yeah we had it was it was uh it
was it was it would be hard to it's it's
cool to not have to think there yeah in
that regard just to be able to hang out
and chill and
um put any info on what cut of sour I
have my God I don't know dude I have a
lot of people that um want to
confidently tell me stories about my
headband and my sour and what they think
it is
um but you know I just think that
there's people that want to like have
certainty where there's uncertainty
in my opinion it's hard you know um and
with the recent batch of popularity with
sour and headbands everyone wants to
fill in the blanks on a bunch of
different stuff you know
so you know we'll have to see how that
goes what are your train wreck
experiences
I was just looking at my list here your
my train wreck experiences yeah yeah
since you were I mean you're up in that
region did you have any train wreck
experiences what I what I'll say what's
interesting about train wreck is that
the first public thing I did as [ __ ]
not so I guess was I showed my face
because uh Caleb had a a cannabis event
um that he threw and he asked me to be
on the panel
um and so I was up there with him and
um you know a number of different people
um Kevin Jody uh you know uh just very
various folks and
um one of the interesting things that he
mentioned was that because Humboldt was
such a seed-based place
train wreck was one of the first named
Cuts up there that became popular yeah
right
um and one of the things that became
popular about it was that it was Frosty
yielded a ton and indoors it made people
a bunch of money yeah
and no one bitched about no one bitched
about the potency either on it it was
before it was before it was basically
before Jack Herrera
like not I don't know about before Jack
career but it was before Jack Greer was
common enough that people called things
Jack like when people say yeah when
people say Jack Terps
um uh previously it was train wreck
Terps yes even though they didn't use
train wreck terp back then but they
called it that train wreck no yes
it was train wreck was probably one of
the first Super popular Cuts in Northern
California that had that strong
terpenolin knows and there's a lot of
mystery to it too it does not seem that
um there seems to be a number of
different train wreck cuts that float
around yeah there seems to be debate on
on who had what train wreck when
um our buddy pack is doing has been
doing some stuff with some old school
train wreck
um you know yeah he's made some killer
crosses uh there's the the GMO Mac he's
done some some new school crosses like
the GMO map stuff but he's also like
that blue dream train wreck one is
[ __ ] Stellar like it it was it's hard
to find the the old uh SD caterpillar
dream like a lot of people some people
just said the arcade at e32 e32 was a
reference to like they thought it was
like 32 General I mean there was there
was just a bunch of different rumors
about train wreck uh train wreck is an
interesting one and then it's a little
bit like Urkel in the sense that despite
its fame
um it doesn't have a clear storyline
yeah
to me yeah you know
um yeah I agree yeah and I think um CSI
said the same because I've definitely
picked his brain on it as one of my
favorite old old school California
strains I picked his brain on it quite a
bit
um yeah some people some people are like
dude that shit's too strong too racy too
speedy and for me it's one of the ones
that gives me anti-anxiety high it's
[ __ ] weird and then people are asking
various things about Sour I don't know
anything I don't actually like you know
I've known JJ a long time
I don't know what sour he has yeah you
know uh I think JJ mostly breeds for
seed
um I haven't smoked any of JJ's actual
flour from any of his clones he uses in
a long time
so I can't I can't really comment on
that you know
um you know yeah and you know there's
aspects someone's just saying saw a
couple people saying they made crosses
with my cuts
um that's nice in the sense that it
appears that the podcast that Matt and I
are doing is is gaining popularity a bit
you know uh that people are saying that
they're using my cut even though I have
no idea who they are and so they didn't
get it from me but they're pretty sure
they must have what I have
um and then I'm not obviously
um selling any clones or anything like
that or selling any seeds right now so
um if people are jumping into the um
people seem to be jumping into the The
Name Game unfortunately yeah which
irritates the piss out of Matt but
um and then someone just asked any info
on original diesel uh original diesel in
my opinion is a very misleading term
there's an original diesel out there uh
that a guy has uh that'll remain
nameless that basically just it was the
first diesel he got so he called it
original
um Matt has a nice that I have it
actually Matt has a nice cut of original
diesel
um also called day wrecker which it may
not even be the original cut called day
record also called day record may not
even be the original cut called day
wrecker
um and and uh there's a lot you know and
Diesel also in you know I have some good
buddies from New York and diesel in the
mid 90s was slang for uh Fireweed yeah
and and don't forget archives uh uses
his original diesel which is the shrubi
diesel the Amish and also referred to as
original Diesel and I think his actually
probably came before the day wrecker as
far as any kind of provenance goes or
Providence goes on uh
I actually uh I actually don't think
that Jack is renamed train wreck no um
no I don't I I disagree I do think they
very strongly have a similar terpene
profile
um but the bud structure the high the
way they look the way they grow uh
there's significant differences there
yeah someone asked me to list the new
stuff on the site uh we have the train
wreck Trinity Blue Bonnet
um that I think we've called that copper
Berry because it has a lot of copyright
terms the we put up some more of the
pure kush Lube on it the blue bonnet bx1
I found somewhere the triangle choke
which we never sold we gave a bunch away
which is the diesel uh I'm sorry
triangle diesel blue bonnet and then the
ones I named earlier so re-watch the
episode
um some I still have to add and there's
some Hawaiian light specific directional
open pollination breedings meaning uh me
and Caleb's Select Cuts hit by all the
males we isolated some of that from the
open pollination just to keep those
separate and um I'll have some of those
up too
and there's a bunch of stuff that people
man there's a lot of comments coming
Fast and Furious
um people just asked how do you get rid
of variegation on the chem and headband
crosses uh sometimes you can't depending
on the cross I suppose but uh chems and
headbands tend to be very heavy feeders
and they tend to be heavy calcium
feeders too so you could try that but
when I say calcium I don't mean Cal Mag
a lot of times they don't need nearly as
much magnesium as they need calcium so
if you're going to try try to give it
more calcium and try to get a product
that does not have a bunch of Mag as
well
because you can overload uh I got a
question for you
what when
what is your definition of a headband
like like when you think of a headband
traditionally I know there's the can of
Bible definition or whatever that it was
like a normal lights hybrid of some sort
but when you think of headband what's
the first thing that comes to mind scent
wise or maybe high-wise or expression
wise I mean not that this this might not
be fair or accurate but when I think of
headband I think of the first cut I got
as headband which is my La
um I think of a a diesel type plant I
think of a skunky type plant
um
you know and it turns out now that Manny
and swell and Bondo and others
have been talking more it does seem like
the very first cut that was called
headband was the was the plant that the
seeds of the first Sour Diesel were
found in
interesting
and that they all claim that that's the
case that they had a cut they called
diesel two and
um there was a per there was a friend of
theirs in New York that called it
headband and
um there was a one of their friends
Manny found some seeds in that diesel 2
headband
um and out of those seeds came the first
uh Sour Diesel
um there's a bunch of other headbands
and there's a couple lumpas headband and
the 56 day which we both consider to be
like renamed cushes
um you know uh and then there's day
wrecker and there's other things that
have all kind of headband was one of
those ones that the story wasn't well
known for a long time so it allowed a
lot of people to claim
the name yeah and there's probably about
four or five different cuts that all
claim to be original New York City
headband yeah and some of those have
been discounted
yes by the people that had headband
which people probably don't like yeah
I'm sure you know uh people talking
about yes Jack is an is I wouldn't say
Jack is an unworked Super Silver Haze I
would say that that Jack is in
um uh uh you know a stop along the way
of that breeding project and Neville
didn't feel it was done and so he
reworked it for a bit and Super Silver
Haze and mango Haze for that matter came
out of that later breeding project yeah
um you know and then people are talking
about you know
um
you know sours and Karma sour and res
sour according to according to you know
them alone or whatever you know res got
his sour from chemdog I think an 07 or
06 or something like that so I've seen I
see people quoting [ __ ] clop and and
stuff you can't take that to the bank
there our podcast he's done one was
almost a week after the other they're
completely conflicted with everything
he's ever said about Sour I don't think
it's up anymore but it was for years so
you really have to be careful what
you're taking in his info and
immediately repeating his facts because
there's been a lot of research done on
that [ __ ] somebody's asked if I wear
glasses I do wear glasses but I'm
nearsighted so I can't read the comments
on uh if I have them on yeah um so
that's why maybe I sit a little close
and you might see me like staring or
whatever someone just asked about the
Cal 106 that slow nickel is pushing I've
never tried it yet but I did pump him uh
as far as being an agronomist and
helping with some of the cloning
techniques people seem to be really
liking it
um and that you know there's a product
by a good friend of mine uh who owns
Cutting Edge Edge that's called plant
amp that's calcium chloride and it's
organic
calcium separated from magnesium in my
opinion is a better option for most
plants than calmac
most calmag is Created from calcium
nitrate which I don't like as much as
calcium carbonate or calcium carbonate
and the Cannabis seems to need a lot
more calcium than it needs magnesium so
over dosing it hard enough with calcium
can overdose it in magnesium and so I
like I like those two uh
um I like those two products separated
ideally
in fact maybe I should maybe I should
nerd out for a second and say that um
when they were doing uh nutrients and
they were doing NPK as like the three
macro elements yeah um scientists
considered calcium so important they
actually considered it adding making a
top four
yeah so calcium missed out being up
there with nitrogen phosphorus and
potassium
um as they decided to make it a
micronutrient but they made it a sort of
a macro micro it's probably the most
important of the micronutrients in terms
of how much plants how much plants like
and I think that's I think it's Boron as
far as what plants like but I think one
of the most important ones is boron and
I can't remember why but I remember
hearing that so I'm just going to throw
it in there but I mean there's there's
there are there's all of them are
important and if they're not present in
sufficient quantities the plant I mean
the plant needs all of them right uh
boron in small amounts is incredibly
important but in large amounts it
toxifies things and makes it important
anything anything does that um and
actually in my my neck of the woods in
Mendo there's a lot there's regions of
Mendo that have excessive boron in the
water and a lot of people would have a
great first year and okay second year
and a horrible third year and end up
trying to filter Boron out of their mix
really badly because it persists yeah
um
before you get going on anything else do
you know much about uh uh power flower
yeah
talk a little bit about that because it
used to be a staple up there and I know
a lot of people used it and had some of
their best harvests with it and then all
of a sudden it was gone and why it was
gone I love power flower I wish it still
existed
um power flower was a it came in a brown
bag
it was designed to be gorilla style so
you could plant directly in the bag you
could throw the bag on the ground and
make an X and plant your plant in it and
poke some holes right yeah or you could
put it into beds or put it into pots or
whatever obviously uh it had enough food
in it for about three months
um so in that era when you were doing
gorilla and stuff like that um and
you're just wanting to water your plant
but really what made Power flowers
special was that they they were digging
some of the mix of it came out of this
ancient bog
yeah and feet bump yeah there was a peat
bog and that pea fog long ago when there
was basically like we know people
weren't Brewing teas very much back then
there wasn't any of these like
um biological fungal bacterial products
on the market like there's a plethora of
now and so that ancient biology really
tended to eat the organic food contained
within power flower and it made it a lot
more available than other mixes yeah and
eventually they dug they they had issues
with the state and local and this and
that and they dug out the bog too much
and it was sort of a
um it was environmental [ __ ] yeah they
it just it just wasn't what it was
anymore it was a it was a snapshot in
time you know the green Rush the the
people started using it people got
really popular people started using it
more and more they started selling more
and more of it that led to more people
that led to more more use and that led
to the state getting involved and then
eventually that bog ran out
yeah I the reason I bring it up is
because when I was talking to CSI last
he had mentioned that the best Sour Girl
he's ever smoked because he's not a sour
fan he always talks about it but he also
says that the some of the best wheat
he's ever smoked with sour yeah
he has terrible taste in the weed yeah
[ __ ] his case all my favorites he's like
yeah I like it I breed with it yeah on
this one he said Shabbat grew the best
the best sour he's ever grown but he
would use flower power and he said he's
never seen lemon and stuff like that
come out of sour before in these grows
because it just never was able to get
flower power again and grow with it but
he also said it was an amazing product I
will say that the diesel family in
general is very sensitive to
environmental factors everything from
soil to nutrient to whatever else you
can grow sour diesel and living soil or
whatever and have it come out very sweet
yeah getting it to actually be sour
getting it to actually be skunky uh is
kind of complex
um the diesel plants can come out like
they're usually good and the high is
usually there but the flavor profiles
and all that and how they grow and how
the buds form uh they're very sensitive
okay no they're very sensitive
um I I've I was trying to say about
someone about this today and I've
started taking to calling them diesels
instead of sours and that's only because
I've noticed that a lot of people still
that haven't grown like old sour cuts
that aren't familiar with sour still
think of like the citric acid Warhead
type thing and apply that to what they
expect when they smoke a sour because
people talk about a mouth coating thing
with sour and we know what that is
having smoked sour but when people think
about that and then they think of the
word sour mouth coat and then the citric
acid type sourness comes to mind I've
noticed a lot of people look for that in
their what they think would be sours and
that's not necessarily what
yeah what the name means I mean and sour
is one of those things where I'm not
going to sit here and call anybody a
liar or anything like that because I
wasn't there so who am I to say that but
it does seem like of the people involved
there's a couple of different stories
and you kind of end up having to choose
who you want to believe yeah
um and there's some certainty about
certain things but it does seem like it
was a multi-stage accident
for lack of a better way to put it and
then it became so famous that there's
some people that wanted to put a little
bit more certainty
yeah on to that you know and so
um I uh it sounds better if you intended
to do it you know it makes you sound
cooler if you meant to do [ __ ] yeah you
know and so I don't I you know but
diesel in general uh diesel Cuts
headband cuts that whole family it's one
of my favorite families it's some of my
favorite smoke they are highly variable
uh most of them are pretty good which is
nice
um but they are and especially right now
with the Resurgence in popularity
there's a lot of false Stories being
told and a lot of like very certain
Tales yeah
um you know and I mean you know it'll
probably I'll probably say this and
regret it or whatever
um but there's a lot of there's a lot of
people that are like oh my sour traces
all the way back to 95. yeah but then
according to the sour people the sour
was actually found in the spring of 96.
that would make it hard so it's uh so
some people sour predates real Sour by
spy by almost a year and that's why the
term free free was born oh yeah the
pre-pre you know it's like how what's
the earliest I can do it let's go six
months earlier I know a guy
yep you know and I I people are talking
about various things I don't use this
term very much
I really dislike IBL in cannabis if you
see the term IBL and cannabis you should
be extremely suspicious IBL is bait the
only thing that I could even think that
I would consider to be close to an IBL
is Tom Hill's deep chunk same yeah I I
you see Sour Diesel I'll be IBL I [ __ ]
on that yeah no that's a joke I mean
even even res would be like hey here's
my sour Divo here's all the Fino's you
can get
right under it yeah I mean you know you
can think about you can think about
inbred line and it's like oh I invited a
couple Generations it's an IDL an actual
IBL has almost no
it doesn't have phenos yeah it doesn't
have pheno phenotypical it is a Fino
basically
it has it has a very very very narrow
band of expressions
so I don't even like ibls because
there's nowhere to go you get what you
get
yes
you know weasel couldn't have had it
before 96 no so there's I I don't really
want to get into the whole sour story
because it's extremely long
um and we have an episode on it and we
have various things on it and all that
but
um very quickly uh there was you know
there was weed that was being bought
there was bag seeds found out of that
weed there was a couple plants that were
called diesel one and diesel two
um that were grown out of those bag
seeds something harmed onto the diesel
two they sold some weed of diesel two to
Manny Manny found some seeds in diesel
too he grew those up and called them
Sour Diesel yeah
and also like someone this is the if you
it should never be in anyone's head that
x amount of generations equals IBL the
generation has nothing to do with it
other than the fact that you can't find
them in early Generations because that
would mean that's not how it works so an
IBL means you've achieved uniformity you
can do that in any generation
but a bad breeder can take something to
F14 and never achieve it already I'll
say it a different way okay and maybe
maybe maybe you can [ __ ] on this or not
but to me
if you get a true breeding line a true
breeding cannabis line means that it
breeds true for at least one
characteristic one trait it might breed
true for multiple characteristics right
but it has to breed true for at least
one consistent characteristic to me a
cannabis IBL means that it breeds true
for basically all the characteristics
several yeah you know it's it's it has
very little variation within the lines
what you see is what you get
yeah you could probably plant out
hundreds of them and the variation
within the line would be less than five
percent yeah so it's not even desirable
for the most part to have an IBL because
you're really cutting off Pathways for
people to do different things with a
line it really feel like a a hemp Farm
wanting to do a seed pop for Vigor and
you want
a uniformity without having to do all
the cloning that's like where idls shine
and so most people these days they're
like oh well I have an inbred line I
took it two or three or four generations
so now it's in bread
yeah that's not an IBL an ideal infused
line bread with inbreeding and like a
line bread a line that's been line bred
can be variant and still have work put
into it and be a line that's line bread
but it doesn't mean it's an inbred line
uh proper and the hard part about it is
is that
um you know all the we can we can and
this you know it's like IBL it's like
what are you even trying to get out of
it are you trying to get something that
like you know the only reason why an IBL
would even be desirable would be if you
were trying to grow a whole bunch of
consistent plants in a field or
something from seed or Greenhouse or
whatever and you wanted to grow from
seed and you wanted it to all be very
very close to each other in height
weight branching THC this that whatever
else yeah but in cannabis we like things
to be a little bit variable so people
have different choices of where they're
going
right and the term IBL is 99 of the time
misused really bad yeah I used to rage
about it for years and then I just
stopped because it just didn't matter
people are going to use it anyways yeah
it just it just doesn't exist but if you
look up the definition almost nobody
like like I said I maybe there's a
couple other things that are besides
deep chunk deep chunks really the only
one that comes to mind
uh this Christmas tree Bud from from
Caleb's pretty consistent and that's it
it's it's so far and few between though
that it's like two three things I could
think of and inbred does not mean IBL
yeah inbred just you know people have
been asking about recombinant IBL
recombinant has to do with recombining
the genetics and it's usually a GMO term
so is someone saying they're doing
recombinant IBL work they're not using
the term correctly I have no clue what
they're talking about
you know Rob Clark's book says F7 is ivl
no it's not you know no and Rob Clark
also did good breeding understood
breeding to him he might have been able
to take something to IBL at an F7 that
would make sense because he understood
the term he understood all that
F7 does not equal IBL though you could
take something that's incredibly
different like something from Bodhi
that's like a wild Cambodian and cross
it with some Afghan and take it seven
generations and it wouldn't even be
close to IBL yeah like there's no
there's no set amount of generations
that gets there you either get there or
you don't yes
it's it's crazy because it seems like
wow that's a really easy way to describe
it is like it's just as simple as that
is it uniform no not ideal that's all
you ever have to know about it and then
the other thing about it is is that like
when people are doing like f gens in
regular breeding the size of the
generation is so much larger
you know and the population they're
picking at each F gen is so much larger
than most small-scale hobbyist cannabis
breeding that doing an ideal doing an
IBL project is just is just outside the
purview of most people's spacing
and another term that gets used of
course in cannabis and I do it all the
time this is F1 the actual term F1
because most cannabis now that we work
with unless we're working with like
[ __ ] land races or old heirloom lines
they're going to be modern lines that
are hybrids or poly hybrids or poly
polypoli hybrids you know and trying to
in in the definition of F1 it's
combining two distinctly different
genotypes well a lot of these are not
distinctly different a lot of these are
you know basically Afghani type
Expressions to the extreme you know and
um if you're Crossing two light types
that's not an F1 but we don't really
have specific terms in cannabis because
it's such a a wildly unique
um crop so I don't know if there's any
correct terms for stuff like like
polyhybrid X polyhybrid it's not quite
an F1 you know I mean people someone
just asked what's the point of going so
many generations in general
I will say that in general most breeding
these days is one step only
yeah um to be old school breeding and to
use these terms that get thrown around
in cannabis
um you know to do a bunch of stages of
breeding you would have to have a goal
of what you're trying to achieve and
then however many generations it takes
you until you feel like you've hit that
goal yeah that's really what it's about
you know
um and there's no set amount of you
could hit that generation in F3 or F4 or
it could take you to F7 or f8 or it
could take you to F10
or whatever you know yeah
um it it very much depends on your goals
and what you're trying to stabilize
within the line and then the other thing
is that like I said you can have a true
breeding
you can have a true breeding line that's
only true breeding for one trait
right the more traits that you try to
make true breeding within the same line
the harder it is
yes yes so you know you try to make
something that's extreme like like uh
skunk one can is is true breeding for
the most part for a few things yes right
it's got great calyx to Leaf ratio
you know uh you know it's it's got a few
different things but it's got got the
resin trait that Neville talked about
that's very visible it's got the resin
trait you know it's got It's got a
certain what people call skunkoid type
you know bud structure a lot right yeah
um but you know it has a range of
terpene profiles
yeah you know it has a range of other
aspects it's not true breeding in every
aspect it's true breeding in a few
traits that tended to be useful so it
tended to be bred to a lot of different
things so the more true breeding traits
you try to add in the harder your
project becomes
yeah I've noticed that DJ despite DJ's
uh work with blueberry being very odd
doing constant different
constant F ones of every filial
generation meaning two different types
inside the line which is not usually
done despite that a lot of the blueberry
stuff I found can be really good at
breeding true for certain traits if the
lines worked a little bit more like
reading true for purple breeding true
for the blueberry turfs breeding true
for XYZ
um oddly enough that's one of those ones
that you can actually get good good true
reading traits a lot like window curbs
even has a lot of certain traits that
can be true for type and you know maybe
maybe we can take it back because we
were talking about nl5as before when um
when Neville was when Neville was
looking through his nl5 hay seeds
he was basically looking for a few
traits in that he that he was that he
was after he was looking for something
that was 16 weeks or less
because he thought longer than that was
a huge pain in the ass so any even if it
was amazing weed if it took 20 weeks he
[ __ ] canned it he was looking for things
with decent yields and he was looking
for things that had the high
yeah he wasn't looking for looks
he wasn't necessarily looking for flavor
profile
he was looking for time of finish
bud structure and effect
yeah you know Guild was super important
too right yeah yeah yeah time to finish
get bud structure that's kind of what I
meant by budget yeah yeah but structure
yeah you know he was good looking for
things that threw bats and and yielded
fairly solid compared to like a bunch of
wispy calyxes and stuff like that and so
he had three things he was basically
looking for time to finish the high and
you know making it making it yield
enough that it would bud structure and
yield so it was worth taking it that
four months yeah so he might have found
some amazingly phenomenal stuff but he
was like oh it's 21 weeks screw that
yeah and the more traits you start to
add to look for those things the harder
it's going to be to find it in a single
plant
yep you know that's why I avoid or I try
to avoid using uh males that are super
polyhybrid types with a lot of
Expressions to to narrow what I'm doing
so if I have projects I can use it as a
tool as opposed to wondering what's
going to happen and somebody who wants
to talk somebody wants to talk about
flow yeah I think that's a good idea I
mean we could talk about flow without
doing all the blueberry top sure
um I'll talk about flow and then Matt
can talk about flow because I probably
have our own different takes on Flow
yeah blow interested me
because it was incredibly beautiful
looking
and DJ whack waxed poetic about how it
was almost a pure sativa but it was done
in that seven weeks yeah who doesn't
want amazing cannabis that's done in 49
or 50 days right yeah um so it had the
had the look it's supposed to have a
very up energetic High
all that type of stuff
um and when we did the I was at the like
I mentioned before I helped Jason King
in one of the Cana Bible books uh get a
lot of people so he could get a lot of
pictures and and helped with a bunch of
the print projects and stuff and so at
the cannon Bible party I bought like 450
seeds or something like that direct from
DJ
um probably o3ish or two-ish uh yeah and
one of them was flow so I got about 100
flow seats
um and I grew so I grew out a lot of
flow
I was pretty disappointed there was
especially pre-cookie I got a lot of
Pinks a lot of Blues a lot of purples
lavenders very pretty very feathery not
a lot of flavor not a lot of high
I was kind of disappointed so that's my
experience with flow
yeah I could I can understand some of
that
um I fell in love with Flo because you
know like uh a lot of other people I was
I was falling in love with purples and
at the time Flo was one of those base
purples that people use to to inject
beautiful colors into their work I've
thrown flow from DJ's stock modern DJ
stock something I I purchased from him
in the past few years I've run stock
from uh alkaline man I believe it was
who did the um the rose float which is
some of the stuff I added to the site
tonight and that was very different the
Old Dutch Passion release of flow is
very different from the modern DJ flow I
found and
um
yeah I mean it's a beautiful plant it
can breed breed true for a lot of traits
it's very floral perfumey smelling from
what my experience is with it but the
the rose flow from um blind man was like
Rosie perfumey but way more heavy on the
NOG chompa incense which you can also
find in modern flow too stuff like that
um some flow is very cushy looking
almost with the the nuggetry structure
but with those big you know the the
widespan What DJ called a stretch Indica
you know this long node spacing
um it's a gorgeous plant but it really
I've never really met anyone goes [ __ ] I
love smoke and flow I've never met
anyone
love just smoking Pure Flow I've never
met anyone for me I wasn't a fan of the
Colorado flow at all I thought I do not
like that turp said It reminds me of
like a a much more pronounced turned up
Mach One
um so I'm not a big fan of that dirt
profile yeah it's that Floral perfumey
but it's very beautiful the Colorado
flow is super beautiful one of the
prettiest flow Cuts uh Greenworks was
talking about DJ's flow cut that's
another really pretty nice one
um but yeah I I have a lot of experience
with the Dutch Passion flow and alkaline
man's work with it and that's what we
put in the um what do we call it Red
Menace that crossed above it because
bubble wood
I kind of wanted to make another I I've
crossed an organ purple tie to Bubba and
I've now across the float above it to
see what would a different Afghani type
that wasn't used in blueberry or in DJ's
work would would you cross to something
like flow to see what direction it goes
so yeah
yeah I
um you know I I'm not I'm not trying to
diss DJ sometimes you can find amazing
stuff in a in in every in a single pack
sometimes you can go through a bunch of
seeds and find nothing that you're
looking for I will say that um you know
when I was uh growing those those lines
especially five six years before cookie
even popped up uh there was a lot of
colors that were quite rare in cannabis
back then
um I just never found the Terps and the
high in the same plant
you know if you could have found an
extremely attractive plant that had nice
flavor and I the way I wanted it to
I would have liked that better I just
never was able to find something yeah I
thought uh
a lot like a lot like blueberry I think
um Flo does best in hybrids you know
yeah I think that's where it shines I
think uh I think when when you were
interviewing red and uh Chimera uh
Chimera made a pretty good point which
is that he sort of considers all of DJ's
work to be one line yeah you know um one
family and what's nice about it is that
um it's it's inbred to the point where
um you know it he didn't add a bunch of
other stuff to it so it sort of is what
it is yeah um and I think DJ took the
breeding perception of oh I see these
phenos in it well now if I take these
phenos and I breed them together I have
flow and if I take these phenos and I
breed them I get this and if I take
these phenos and I breathe them they get
that but they're all from the same
General stock just taken in different
directions and so sometimes that works
better than others you know
um but it seems like DJ's work is much
better suited to outcrossing to
something very different than itself
then within itself yeah it seems like it
shines more in hybrids than it does as a
as far as my personal preference I'm not
gonna like maybe like his son's gonna go
JD's gonna get all [ __ ] mad at me and
[ __ ] scream around his daughters his
daughter gets real mad all the time you
know but uh whatever the case may be
so I had a good question for you would
you mind saying if more of the cuts you
keep are from someone else gifting or
you hunting seeds that's a good question
most of them are are our Cuts I've
acquired
you know my collection is pretty weird
in the sense that it's basically
entirely suited around my tastes
um I didn't collect it for any other
reason that I liked the weed
um it's only now because most people
didn't collect cuts and didn't hold on
to cuts and there's been a Resurgence
and a desire for some of these old
famous things that all of a sudden these
things have been sought after so there's
certain things that I have a lot of
depth in in my collection and there's
other things that I don't prefer that
much that I don't have very much of at
all
um because it wasn't collected to have
some kind of like comprehensive database
of all weed
it was personal
what's a what's a a sense profile that
you would like to see in cannabis that
you have not yet
you know
um
maybe maybe I'll cheat
yeah cheat uh there is a scent profile
in cannabis that um uh I like a lot and
I have not and I would love to see a
plant that translated it into flavor
I would love a real bubble gum
I think the bubble gum that's out there
I there are plants that I think smell
very strongly of bubble gum yeah I don't
recall smoking things that make me lip
smack like I just I had some Big League
Chew yeah you know or something along
those lines I mean there's there's some
aspects of I've you know there's some
maybe some juicy fruit bubble gum maybe
there's some like there's some flavorful
profiles a little bit like that but your
straight classic pink bubble gum flavor
um I don't get that yeah I got that from
the um the 95 Century starfino that was
bubble gum because it was super Panic oh
yeah bubble gum and it would come
through super like you know what your
paneling does just [ __ ] amplifies
everything it was it was really nice I
think that's what uh the Indiana bubble
gum needed so I I did grab a bunch of
the Durban bubble gum from Caleb for
that reason
um if there's questions going on Matt
won't let me answer how many moms I have
uh for uh opposite offices I'll say you
you guys there are limited to plant
counts why the [ __ ] would you want him
documenting anything about plant couch
stop it but I will but but I will say
that when it comes to important Cuts I
don't like having only one mom of
certain things and and the most
important things to me not only do I not
like having one mom but I do like having
them backed up with friends
um oh God people want a [ __ ] rare
dankness I don't want to talk about
right this really obviously he wants us
to talk Scott you know reach was
involved in early clone trading
um he's been around forever uh he has a
lot of respect from a lot of different
people so I'm sure he's a great guy I
don't interact with him so I don't know
I didn't really grow anywhere dating
this stuff at the time because I was
making stuff similar
um I heard people love that flow OG
cross I heard people I don't know who
made it for them if that was something
Scott from Erin Agnes made or something
Fletcher made from archive I know
there's some head butting that went on
there so I don't want to speculate but
yeah
yeah and so there's there's an aspect of
I will say that
um most of the reason why people don't
keep moms more than what they're
currently growing for for you know
modern times
is because it's expensive it's time
consuming and it's a huge pain in the
ass
yeah you know I wish more people did it
but um uh we could have an episode on
long-term mom Health
um and you know I know we mentioned it
at the beginning of the thing people
have been bugging about it all thing
it's too late now
um we are going to run a little over
than we normally do because people have
been chatting a bunch but I'm not going
to talk about dry Tech today simply
because it's too deep it's too detailed
of a topic you can do that for one of
your solo things that I've been trying
to get you to record forever so there's
an aspect actually where there is a
bunch of solo content about some
historical stuff that's about to come
out
um I know I promised it and uh it's
right in the middle of my growing season
um so of course like it's it's awesome
for me to like be like oh I'll come out
with all this new stuff right in the
middle of like I got plants everywhere
so
um but uh there will be some historical
stuff coming out and what we're going to
do with it is I am going to talk for
five or ten minutes about some specific
histories or specific strains and it's
very likely that I'm also going to make
like an IG post with possibly some
pictures and some more information and a
brief description and then people can go
on our our our podcast and see like a
little short and and listen it'll
probably be mostly uh uh audio
uh to back up the post it won't be like
video chat like this is right here but
um it will you know we're going to do
some historical stuff like that so it
will be coming soon I'm just right in
the middle of growth season and so uh
it's a you know and Matt can tell you
where to find he does the pitch on all
yeah
might as well start busting it out so
um
first off uh like again I had it pinned
up here the whole time but for the audio
listeners uh this weekend
um I don't remember what the date is I
think it's like the 16th of
September so this weekend the 16th of
September uh coupon code invisible 40.
uh we'll get you 40 off through the
weekend on riotsiege.com we have my
spray that's 40 off too for this weekend
so take advantage of it while you can
um we have the copper Berry which is the
Trainwreck Trinity Blue Bonnet the pure
blue pure kush Bluebonnet Bluebonnet bx1
triangle choke blue cream Blueberry
Scone Red Menace some of the Hawaiian
light stuff up uh some of it I still
need to add we have the Santa Cruz goat
farm stuff which is the the train wreck
Femme uh fam hybrids
um I got my podcast coming up next
Tuesday about alien [ __ ] so if you want
to watch that it's the invisible right
maybe I'll throw in there he just
mentioned it real quick but we got a
buddy that's on our Discord that we chat
with all the time pack and he was just
mentioning the pack goat farm stuff
um pack has been releasing some uh train
wreck and some other lines that he's
held close for a long time and he's been
breeding in my opinion which is one of
the best ways to breed which is with
stuff he likes a lot
um and so Matt has some of that so uh
look up for that for sure I just wanted
to plug that a little bit more than yeah
um but he's a good homie he's on our
Discord he's another person you can ask
questions about and Matt's got some of
his stuff that we've been selling so uh
he's a good dude yeah that's an
excellent plug
um and we have our patreon where you can
come kick it with us watch [ __ ]
movies uh shoot the [ __ ] we do giveaways
I was going to do a giveaway here but
I'll probably actually since we ran over
time I'll probably just go do it on the
patreon and and do a giveaway for the
patreon folks
um uh uh so yeah go to patreon search
breeder Syndicate that's how you find us
go Google it um preacher Syndicate 2.0
you can find us on iTunes for the audio
YouTube you can find the audio and video
after the show
um I'll probably have this up within two
hours so yeah check it out we're on all
the podcast software on YouTube
um
that's it thank you everyone for showing
up not so you want anything else you
want to get in no just uh we will I I
will have some we will have some solo
content and some different stuff coming
out very soon uh it's been a little
slower than we thought but
um always thank you for your Friday
night thank you for your time always
good to listen to everyone
thanks everyone peace want more breeder
Syndicate be sure to check out our
patreon by going to Google and searching
breeders syndicate patreon
we have a secret Discord where we are
available at most times in interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsseeds.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray from making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
foreign