welcome welcome welcome
i've been sort of pukey all day so
hopefully uh
hopefully this will go smooth
um i think natsu made it safe to
oregon last night but he's not back yet
or maybe he is maybe he's gonna pop in i
don't know i haven't talked to him today
well maybe he'll pop up hopefully he
will
but soon we will have chimera
from chimera seeds um
legend of the bc scene
so yeah i'm just getting everything
ready
what's a good site let's see let me just
try um
let's see
i want to try to find a good site for
for tests to go over and i brought my
tablet out just to do that but
i have no [ __ ] clue where the
internet
even is on this tablet there it is
what do you guys think is a good site
like uh
sc labs or something
i'm trying to think of a few different
ones
let's see
oh kite mirror one though let me see if
we can find him yet
if you're in here come here just uh
raise your hand
he's not here yet okay
wait a little bit more
my nose recover from yesterday what i do
yesterday
oh the scent stuff i had a headache for
a while the whole house smelled like um
like artificial grape all night
yeah that was fun though it was very
interesting and and informative
did any of you guys pick up a kit after
to try it i really want to do another
episode where a bunch of us have kits
and we can all do it so you guys can all
type in here like what's going on with
your smelling etc
and get a good handle on it
how much are they the kids seriously
having a look
whatever they are they're probably worth
it you know because they're they're
pretty
fun yeah we could do a group workshop
over on um
discord as well
not so in travel mode as far as i know i
haven't talked to him he may pop up for
all i know but i i i haven't heard from
him to know
hey bitter is is not so home yet do you
know
175 for the advanced kid yeah that's
about right makes sense
the site was um
it's a long long site
um paraphernalia social.com so you have
to know how to spell paraphernalia but
social.com
hmm
okay i'm gonna start out no actually i
already did it yesterday
i gotta read this thing again
once uh chimera gets here so i can be
profesh you guys like my profess
[ __ ]
mode with the 2.0
who would win in a cage match me or
hannah come on
come on come on come on don't be silly
don't be silly
i don't go beating up on chads i don't
do that [ __ ]
that's mean
i don't even dislike in-house that much
i just i don't like how that situation
went
i really don't i don't have any respect
for him for it
the terms which terms
the terms the terps the terms
sorry we're just waiting i want to get
the the crowd up a little bit i know
saturdays are weird for us
sorry didn't watch the fights earlier
too i was sick i didn't even realize
they were on so early but it was a
london show
looks like patty pimlet
[ __ ] choked that dude out
and gustafson lost which sucks
i like us
who's the guy that commented and had you
change the trademark i don't remember
the name dude it was in an old or you
could probably find the post still
on instagram because it was done unless
it's gotten reported because all my [ __ ]
got reported for a while
but um
yeah
i can't remember the name the dude did
end up being nice like at the end of the
conversation and along the thread we
were laughing at each other but
yeah started out a little contentious
let's see
nothing yet nothing yet
nothing yet
i'm sure you guys love staring at my
ugly [ __ ] head right now that's what
we all want to see
what's up you guys got any questions in
the meantime till we get started so we
can uh kill some time
any comments questions
concerns questions about ufos questions
about [ __ ] serial killers
questions about whatever i don't know
anything you guys got questions about
i'll take them
well thank you i try to have the most
beautiful noggin possible but
you know
i get sick of staring at my [ __ ] head
[Music]
i'm staying sober for this one too
because
chimera talks
way over my head the guy is brilliant
and when it comes to
science
it's really hard to find anyone who is
as confident with
science and breeding science when it
comes to that as him so i'm trying to
try to keep my [ __ ] together today
i have not tested out the purple pro yet
um i know i know csi got one but i don't
know i don't think he's had even time to
touch it or use it or not do anything
with it yet
is the s or c silent word in the word
sent
god that's a good one
all the bb stuff you've done anything
without cast cut from nugs and jug days
i have not no one ever passed it um
why didn't you stick your pink yellow
when you sip your tea this is coffee
it's actually half calf coffee
because yesterday i drink full calf
coffee it was up all night
steep hill labs do can of annoying terp
testing
i don't know much about any of the labs
which is a reason why we're doing the
show
hopefully
primary members it's on this account and
not the other one um let me see if i can
send an
invitation to him somehow
let's see breeding
cannabis
damn
okay
make sure i got him on the right one
there he is
mr america
oh wait no he's not from america
so welcome hold on and get it going
from chimera seeds in a few minutes
there he is mr not from america
[Laughter]
how you doing dude not bad how are you
guys man all right it's good to see you
um not so mayor may not show up at some
point but we're going to get started
without him all good
all right so i got to read this i'm
trying to make it more professional
because uh we're doing the 2.0 of reader
syndicate and everything so
i have to read this theme and then uh
we'll get jamming
gotcha
welcome to breach of syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
lived it i'm matt the owner of riot
seeds this is chimera
owner of chimera seeds
uh
yeah
welcome to the underground that is so
professional yeah you like that yeah i
really really like the game
do we have some uh is there a good place
to look up the labs aspect
like different labs that i could put i
have my tablet right here yeah
i'm wondering the best way to do this
you know what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna
send you a text message with a sample
okay um a report that for a report
format that i have a little bit to do
with
um the
designing the way it is but really
we can use anything right the important
thing is that we go through a lab report
lab report and show people
what are the things to look at
what can you like obviously in a lab
report there's all this built-in
information right
so how can you take that information and
essentially infer things about the
results or see if you can identify
problems
with what the lab has done yeah right
and so you know what you sent me the
other day and i think you got those
posted on your ig or something yeah yeah
they're posted on the ig yeah so people
can check those out either now or later
but
you know
like i said one of the things i said to
you back then was that um
it wasn't really
like that was those were results that
somebody had cut and pasted into a
spreadsheet yes yeah so that's an
opportunity for like anybody manipulate
them yeah yeah anybody can [ __ ] with it
at that point yeah in an excel
spreadsheet eventually
like a legal document in a way
yeah well they are they are legal
documents oh they are legal documents
yeah
i didn't know that
especially when it comes to like you
know obviously there's all this
environmental testing that needs to be
done but yes in the context of
regulations like these are these are
legal documents that certify something
for the purpose of regulations that's
right yeah so that makes sense it's gone
to like a good standard right yeah
um i don't i don't know why i'm not
having any luck suddenly sending this
thing over
let me just do it this way
all right so that'll bring up a picture
and
you might want to actually go in and
copy the link from the picture
but um
this lab report is called the phytofax
and some artifacts were developed by
napro it's actually it's an image search
i don't know what comes up for you but
it's the top left picture
on that on that okay one sec i gotta
switch off here because it it'll it'll
pause me for a second one sec
there we go
you looked really crazy when you were
frozen like you had this really bizarre
look there we go
i don't know if it'll even let me show
pictures on here now
you might just have to copy and paste
the link in or you know what we'll put
it up on our ig after some people yeah
let's put it up on that g after
um
yeah so
essentially like
look when you get back when most places
give you back a lab report i mean we're
looking at
even even if we're just talking
cannabinoids
you're looking at like
minimum 12 chemicals okay
because like i guess it's probably
important to talk a little bit about lab
testing there's various ways there's
different assays that you can do so
there's different tests that you can run
to try and determine the cannabinoid
content of a sample
right yeah
if you put it into a gc a gc's got
something it called um
what is it called the injection port on
a gt it's like putting what you do is
you take up you take
think about you like you got your bud
you put it in some alcohol or some
methanol or something that's going to
extract to catch me
you more or less shake it up and then
you take like one microliter
of the liquid that has now dissolved so
you got your ethanol but now you've got
all the stuff that came off the plant
yes right in that liquid and so what we
want to do is we take
we take a small sample of that liquid
i'll call it like a thousandth of a
milli milliliter
and that gets injected into this
injection port
of the of the gas chromatic okay and so
what that does is it takes the liquid
that we have with all of our stuff
inside it and it makes it into a vapor
that that injection port is heated like
300 degrees
yeah they are 350 degrees celsius or
whatever so
the point is is when you put that [ __ ]
in
in the liquid or sorry that liquid into
the injector and it becomes a vapor it
automatically decarboxylates yeah
right so you don't you no longer have
because the cannabis plant doesn't make
thc it makes thc acid yeah
we really want to be able to detect the
compounds as they were in
the in the plant
right yeah
because what happens is when stuff gets
decarboxylated a certain percentage of
it
like gets destroyed in the conversion
process it just yeah
right so it's like if you start with
like 100 of thc acid or 100 molecules of
thc acid and say you lose 20 of those
molecules as it gets converted into thc
yeah
when you get a report at the end that
shows 80 milligrams of you know thc or
80 units of thc that's not what was
actually in the sample right our testing
method has destroyed part of the sample
and so if you go back and look at like
all the cannabinoid testing that's been
done
you know in the scientific literature
60s 70s 80s most of it was done on dc
right so the numbers that we see
are going to be lower than really what
was in the plant and so
call it like that's interesting roughly
after 2000 sometime it might have been
like late 90s
people started realizing hey now we need
to do this in what's called an hplc or a
high pressure liquid chromatograph
chromatograph
and okay the liquid chromatograph
doesn't do that initial
decarboxylation step right because your
sample it gets rather going into
ejection in an injection port your micro
microliter of liquid sample that we use
to extract you know our extraction
buffer from the plant yeah that gets
injected into like a stream of other
liquid
that runs through the machine at like 25
27 30 degrees right maybe 40
so that's not a big deal that's not
decarboxylating anything so the
chemicals that are in that
uh in the hplc and the liquid
chromatograph they don't change right so
what we're getting if we use that method
is an accurate representation of what's
in the
uh what's in the sample okay wow okay
and so it's a much better technique for
using for cannabinoids is that what they
use now
not all labs are the same right so this
is kind of the way here here's the thing
is the last the the regulations usually
say
you have to develop a test that will
accurately quantify cannabinoids yeah
and that test must be
what's called validated and validated
just means like you run a set of
experiments using your
your your protocol to show that your
protocol is
actually measuring what you say it's
measuring yeah right it's like it's like
calibrating your ruler it's like proving
that your ruler is calibrated yeah yeah
right it makes sense like you're not
saying stuff's 12 inches when really
it's like you know eight and a half
inches or whatever right it's the same
kind of thing yeah that's what
validation is
and so the regulations say you have to
develop a validated method but they
don't tell you you have to use this
exact method with this machine and this
column and this solvent and this
extraction buffer right and so yeah what
ends up happening is every lab develops
and you'll see if you go and ask them
about their methods a lot of them will
come back and say well that's
proprietary we can't disclose to you the
way we do that
right and that's a bit of a red flag
like if i'm yeah
you know like i'm not a one-off
we do it in-house because it gets too
expensive but you need to do it as a
third party but if i am working with a
third-party lab we're not just running
one or two tests like we're gonna be
running hundreds of tests right
so we're essentially paying them to
generate data for us right so
i need to be sure
that the test that you guys are running
actually measures what it says so i'll
go in to a lab and say show me all your
validation document yeah right
they won't let you photocopy them take
them with you but you can certainly sit
down in their office and read through
their method
right and we've done this
like when i was working at napo we did
this with multiple different labs
because
napo was a research lab and we had
dispensary clients that were
so
you know growers that we represented
would grow the samples we would analyze
the results they'd go off to the lab or
they go off the dispensary but the
dispensary would be using like
one or two or three of the biggest labs
in california for the same samples right
and so we had our data
that we knew was
damn solid and we published the method
so anybody can go and check out why it's
solid
but it's like we had real confidence in
that our results were right but we would
what would happen is because our client
would send off the same sample that we
had data for to multiple labs
we would get back
that are essentially duplicate copies of
the same
results yeah but with somebody else's
lap right so it was generated by
something else and you'd see
oh this lab can identify
terpenoline or this lab is confusing cbd
and cbg
oh wow right and like those are pretty
big deals right yeah that's a big deal
well yeah again like
99.9 of the samples they see are thc
only so it doesn't really matter whether
that tiny little blip is cbd or cbg but
yeah you know
again like if we're saying that this is
a legal document that supports the
regulations that uh that have been
created to protect cannabis like it's
kind of an important thing yeah yeah you
think so
so yeah
and so in the in the gas chromatography
when they do that kind of sample with
ethanol is that little tiny one
milliliter that they or point whatever
milliliters is that homogeneous enough
when they pull it to be a great average
of the sample that they're taking is
that is it
is that how that works yeah and it's
like that's a very good question so the
sampling of the one microliter
thing like you can you can imagine that
like
every step along that process from
taking the flower it actually goes back
it's like it starts with the sampling
procedure
how did you get the bud out of the bag
that it was grown in or out of the lot
that it was grown in okay and so
very often what happens
is this is
like
listen everybody's found all sorts of
ways to game the system because the
consumer is so thc driven yeah
everybody is trying to work every single
snap angle right so for example growers
will go and cherry pick all the biggest
nicest beautiful buds out of the thing
the biggest bugs are the top of the
plant they get of course they're going
to have chemical content
right and so if you want a real number
of the batch
we developed a sampling method where you
know you take one bud this big and one
bud this big and then one bud this big
and they all get combined together or
you know so many grams of each the whole
thing gets blended up
and and homogenized and then you use
that homogenized sample to do your
extraction from right
people don't do it like if you're
showing up at fc labs and you're trying
to like get a feed company you're trying
to sell a million seeds
they go and they chop off the top is
nice big buds and they trim all the like
the grainy leafy parts off so there's
like absolutely nothing but resin yeah
and then those pristine beautiful baby
labs go off the samples go off to the
left yeah you're gonna get a [ __ ]
higher number
right that's that should be obvious but
these are the games that end up getting
played because
the more thc you got in your sample the
better the distributors and the
retailers and everybody is you know
anybody that's thc focus they're gonna
get
bamboozled from that kind of stuff right
yeah and so like you said there's
there's that's just sampling the flower
now it goes to the lab like maybe the
labs like getting paid a decent fee and
they like put like an extra you know
point five or five percent extra flour
in the scale when they go to do the
extraction buffer like there's there's a
million ways between
the plants and getting
you know that injection going into the
injection port ways to manipulate the
sample yeah forget like intentionally
manipulating it there's also like
natural variation and like experimental
error that happens yeah that is going to
allow that is going to have on a loud
variation and so one thing we were
talking about the other day is that like
for example in canada
the regulation says
that the thc content in the flower
um
must be whatever's labeled on the on the
bag or the box however it's labeled for
thc content yeah that has to be within
plus or minus 15 percent
of the actual amount well so that's like
if it's 20 and it's actual 20
15 20 is three so that means
that like 23 to 17 or 17 to 23 is
actually like that plus or minus 15
percent window on either side of 20
right
so
like it's important for people to
understand that like
with a loud error that's to be expected
there's really no difference between 17
and 23
and then and again that would apply like
between 30 and 24 right like
well yeah as you go up like yeah up to
30 now
you know about 50 of 30 is four and a
half percent right so you've got like 34
percent down to like what is it 26 five
and a half right 25.5 yeah yeah so like
that's a huge [ __ ] rate yeah as you
get higher it gets quieter
yeah
and listen
that is cannabinoids cannabinoids are
typically regulated by regulation like
the regulator whoever makes the rules
for the you know to set up a legal
program says hey can havenoid lab test
have to be
with plus or minus within plus or minus
15 that's what that's going to be our
allowed range so your
your assay that or that protocol that
your lab designs to generate this thing
it has to hit between these two goat
balls well terpenes like for example
terps aren't regulated in canada
right so they're
considered cannabinoids
no they're not catalyzed okay
yeah
their cannabinoids are a specific class
that bind to the cannabinoid receptor
and it's arguably like only
beta-carotene binds to one of them
so
but they're they're a different chemical
class but like you know all of us all
the producers
and retailers they want that terpene
info on the label right because it is
somewhat informative to the consumer so
it's another way that you can
differentiate your product say hey
mine's different because this is the
chemical well
yeah terpenoids or terpenes aren't
regulated in the system like there is no
requirement to analyze and disclose the
amount of terpene content on a flower
it's like it's purely an extra thing
yeah
so because they're not regulated
molecules there's no [ __ ] regulations
that says
hey it has to be within
15 allowable range
so in canada
and i'm sure it's i don't know exactly
what it is it probably varies by
district in the state but at least
because they're not
regulated labs set their own allowable
acceptable rate so
i validated one labs method
and i was reading through their
described allowable range is 30 plus or
minus jesus
so
you've got like let's call it like
well let's call it six percent terps
yeah right
a third is like two out of those six so
that's essentially saying like
you know two percent on either side of
six that's like from four to eight
percent range yeah that the lab can't
really differentiate between the
difference between those two things
right yeah
um like that's a bomb that's a huge
bummer i don't think people understand
that because you know when some of these
labs publish the results they're like oh
you have like three point four seven
nine
uh milligrams of are
3.579
um
percent mircine yeah right well it's
like dude if it's 30
off
why the hell are we measuring it down to
three decimals yeah that's true that's
wild yeah it's it's intense
right it's like you just it's so dumb
but again
you have to realize there's a difference
between accurately leaving labeling the
information on a product
versus how can you stick information on
a label of a product to sway a
consumer's buying preference right
um
and clearly those aren't the same thing
no right so not at all it's kind of i
think it's really
well
for anybody watching like if you're just
basing things on thc numbers you're
getting fooled like you're getting
bamboozled right yeah um
you're getting you're having your
marketing emotions played with right and
this is this is what companies do
um
so understanding that all in context
maybe let's think about going back and
looking at like a lab report right and
so
in the numbers that you sent me one of
the things i found really interesting
was you know whenever i look at a lab
report my first thing is
i don't even like everybody goes to
straight to tac or straight to terpene
content or whatever i don't know i go
who who's the lab
yeah right who's the lab are these guys
trustworthy or not and after like a
thousand lab reports or 2000 lab reports
you start to say
hey these guys always have like you know
like all of their roosevelts are like 33
to 38 thc like yeah
really yeah i apply that same logic
right things or to seed companies you
know like i see them working with things
like 40 different things that have been
non-existent for 40 years and i'm like
okay well full of [ __ ] you know yeah
yeah yeah and it's marketing right and
the thing is too like the other thing
you got to keep in mind too it's like
when we see these hchc scores like 30
plus percent thc acid
that's a huge amount yeah it really is
like a [ __ ] massive amount for a
plant to produce that was one flower on
one run right that's really what was set
sampled
if you follow that cultivar
back through five ten cycles like you'll
see twenty eight twenty six
sure but the one that always appears on
the seed bank
package says it's 34 oh yeah yeah right
so like
people got to realize that like when
you're being fed one of these numbers
especially if it doesn't come on
that certified letterhead legal document
and they're fine at the bottom like if
you go down and look at it it's signed
by the laboratory manager right because
again that's part of this
chain of custody thing that happens with
regulated ship right yeah
so
um yeah so check out the lab okay yeah
secondly
look before even looking at the numbers
like i i was like you know i always want
to say
before i can put any confidence in these
numbers i need to try and figure out how
those numbers were generated yes right
and so a lab report should say
cannabinoids were were analyzed by hplc
so they had a laboratory back and it
says cannabinoids are analyzed by gc
it's like right there i'm like okay well
the cannabinoid numbers could be off by
yeah right because we've done those
experiments and you can burn up to 30 or
30 of the total cannabinoid content in
an injection port of a gc
inject like gcs are not a great
instrument for measuring cannabinoids
even though all the analysis like up to
the mid 90s was done that way
right yeah
but for terpenes for example it's
actually a great way to do it
and so
a lot of very good labs what they'll do
is they'll do it you'll do your you know
you put your bud grind it up
homogenize it take your sample put in
your ethanol or methanol or whatever
your extraction buffer is
strip out the contents separate out the
solid material now you've got your
little liquid
yeah with all your goodies in it right
that often gets split into two different
samples or you will sample two different
one microliter amounts from there one
goes gets injected into an hplc
for cannabinoid a separate one goes into
uh an hpls or sorry a gc4 terpenoid or
terpene okay okay
we actually used to do two different
things when we sent the one off to
uh
the the hplc we would take
your sample out
and then we would take one raw sample
out of that subsample and the other
would get diluted by a factor of 10.
so you have nine parts nine microliters
of of the solvent mixed in so now what
you do is you have
um a diluted sample and a concentrated
sample
and so the concentrated sample is good
for
all the very small
components that exist like you know cbc
the cbg
whatever the little blip cannabinoids
are essentially you've got one that's
like really
it's like being able to do that on those
with a magnifying glass yeah
your diluted sample for the molecules
that are there in abundance
right because if you try to often if you
try to cram those like thc like a type
one plant that's full of thc you cram
that through your hplc and it just it
overloads the detector okay so you
wanted to so
as you can see all these places are
opportunity for error
yeah if you do them very very carefully
you can actually get incredibly um
incredibly accurate results now if
you're like running
a thousand two thousand samples a week
that come into your commercial
laboratory in california
dude that's like three throughput
yeah right so it's like you're you're
essentially breaking down how many can i
do in a day
okay well if i'm doing that many a day
maybe i don't have the ability to do it
quite as accurately yeah right and so
these are the decisions that get made in
the lab that no one's thinking about
everybody just thinks you drop down your
120 bucks or 150 bucks and you get a
bunch of numbers back in it's proof of
them yeah you just toss it in the
machine bam
yeah it's not like that right
so
it's just important for people to
understand the context right so
do um did you want to go over the
standard what the standard is how it
works
yeah so chemicals so any machine has to
be calibrated right
um
and
how's the best way to explain it when we
take you so you got your butt okay you
get your butt call us our extraction
buffer you put a flower in there you put
in your ethanol and shake it around blah
blah blah
send out the flower oops say about the
flower i just throw a sample all over
the ground
you said about the flower and you got
your
your your left over what we've got is
ethanol or methanol whatever it doesn't
matter your solvent
with all the chemicals that we were able
to strip out of the cannabis plant
material so you got turf you've got all
the different cannabinoids
a standard like but we don't know how
much of everything is in that
sample like it's an unknown amount of
unknown chemicals in the sample right
and what we need to do is compare it to
a known sample
and so
you can actually order pure thc from a
lab synthesis company and these
synthesis companies that are allowed to
have you know they get a dea license so
that like the cops can have and they'll
they'll sell
they'll be the dea license so they can
synthesize thc and make
what are what are known as like a
chemical standard which is usually one
milligram of thc
into one milliliter of methanol yeah
well methanol is an alcohol but it's not
like ethanol it's poisonous go blind so
the idea is people won't consume it
so it's
so weird that anybody would like
consider the idea to go get thc standard
ethanol like [ __ ] shoot it or
whatever they're doing and do with it
it's wild yeah but this is what the dea
is the the context of the da's thinking
in progress right like yeah of course
thc and someone's gonna try and get high
a milligram like dude really yeah you
know like even like a 20 bud is like 200
milligrams yeah right so it's like you
really you're gonna try to anyway
of course you don't but that's the
theory behind it but
one milligram
in one milliliter of ethanol is legal
yeah it's legal people can buy and trade
it without having licenses
so
now you have your one milligram
milliliter you can essentially treat
that like your extraction buffer
extracted cannabis plant you can take
like one microliter out of that
milliliter inject it into your hplc and
you get a peak of a known amount and you
can say okay this peak is i know that
it's this known amount we're putting in
boom
you know now i can when i run
another sample and it has a peak of the
same size i know that it had the
equivalent amount of thc so it's a way
that you can calibrate your machines
okay got it and good labs will do what
are called check standards like you run
your calibration curve you get the
machine all calibrated and then like
call it every three or five or maybe 10
runs
rather than running a sample you run
your standard through or your standard
mix of terpene standards and cannabinoid
standards and what that should do is
that like
now you have throughout your day you've
got your 100 samples that are going
through the lab say every 10
you've got like a snapshot of the
machine in calibration yeah
and if it's out you can see oh hey we
caught it while it was getting out of
calibration let's recalibrate it right
that makes sense it's an important it's
for any analytical
uh endeavor where you're trying to
figure out like hey what's this exact
amount of compound in a plant or in a
substance you want to have the ability
to compound or to
to validate that number confirm that the
amount that you're measuring is actually
what you're measuring right
yeah um
so it's a great question because like
when our my friend arnold has
a dutch research scientist that was
involved in setting up the dutch system
and he's a real plant nerd guy and he
started doing all this research and he
wanted to to check to see if the
standards from the chemical company are
or are what they were you know they're
supposed to be
one milligram per milliliter well he did
a whole bunch of tests and showed that
the standard was actually 88 or 0.88
milligrams oh yeah
so the the the substance that the guys
are selling to all the labs
wasn't properly calibrated that means
everybody in the industry is off right
or everybody yeah that's from those guys
wrong
like this is we're talking you know
i think it was like 20 2009
but two years ago in canada the same
thing happened right like somebody
identified that hey you know the restek
sample or that was restek is a supplier
for standards the res tech samples that
everybody uses to calibrate or but half
the industry uses calibrate they've been
wrong for eight months man they kept
that quiet
it comes up in the circles but it
doesn't like yeah it does come up if you
if you're
it listen when that happens they have to
like they're legally to send that
requirement but again you're the support
industry for a regulated system
yeah you [ __ ] up that's affecting
everybody how they're complying with the
regulations it's like they are closed
right so it does it does become known to
much lab but again it's the type of
thing that like
the labs might
they're not required to disclose to the
public
yeah yeah right they they probably
should disclose to their clients but
often they don't right yeah
um or it can happen that they don't so
anyway like
yeah that's a chemical standard and you
buy a chemical essentially if you're
calibrating for cannabinoids like you
know i was just on the sc lab website
reading over through some of their stuff
they they test for 39 terpenes and
terpenoids so they've even
they they either have a standard mix
that a chemical supplier supplies or
they buy individually all of those
individual terpenes and
create their own standard mix that they
use to to calibrate the machine so
you're not only calibrating for thc
you're calibrating for terps if you're
running the test you're currently every
individual terpene yeah wow
yeah and like i said some now they've
gotten to the point where
like uh you know
say
res tech or someone one of these terpe
or these supply chemical supply
companies that services the medical
cannabis industry
they might say hey we've done the mix
for you here's 15 terpenes you know all
the majors or whatever yeah the pioneers
termine blah blah blah and you'll buy a
pre-mixed
one of those so that you don't have to
individually go and create the standard
to put it to calibrate your dc
yeah um but again anytime you're buying
a compound that you're not making and
you're not quantifying your say itself
is a potential source of error
yeah absolutely
so
yeah it's a bit of a deal
so wow so when we started looking at
your results i started going through
them i realized
whoever was generating those results for
one
like again it was data pasted into uh an
excel spreadsheet yeah it wasn't even a
lab report so it's like one like right
off the bat it's like how much i'm not
saying it was the numbers were wrong but
if somebody gave it no yeah my red flags
would be like okay
something could be up here yeah the
second thing i went through and i
started looking at what's the ratio of
thc um in the plant versus thc acid in
the plant as you probably know cannabis
doesn't produce thc it produces the
natural form thc acid
and so
if right right
right away if you get a live report back
and there's junk thc in there like i'm
talking more than really a percent
yeah
it's probably been run through a gc
so it's like okay
if the thc numbers are coming out like
you know 20 thc 25 whatever that's yeah
you should see 25 percent thc acid
yeah you couldn't see 25 thc so
right here
like just by that one number you can see
oh they measure the whether or not they
measure the cannabinoids through plc or
through gc if it's through gc the number
is probably wrong yeah because again we
know that a bunch of it gets destroyed
in the injector right so
there's things that you can like right
off the top look at you know most people
are looking at the they grab the lab
report they go straight to the thc
number and they're like 32 i'm the best
yeah right and it's like that's you
shouldn't be doing that right yeah
looking at the context of what that
number means
is all the information in this lab
report consistent
right and internally consistent like
this between each other
yeah like the queen itself doesn't make
sense and so that was one of the things
that's that tweaked me a little bit when
i first saw yours it was like
they had clearly run in hplc
and gc
which is fine i mean like i said if
you're using it for the terps the gc is
fine but they were probably it looked
like they were collecting that
cannabinoid data as they were doing the
terpene run as well
ah okay so it's like you know in my mind
i'm like looking at him like ignore that
yeah don't even look at that don't even
put any credence into it because it's
just
it's weird well and
with me like when i see something off
like that and like when it comes to
terps and lab reports the reason i sent
it to you of course when we talked i was
like i don't know like i have no fun
including you can read this what is it
but like
yeah i i
i i'm like anybody else you know like i
i see that and i'm like wow thc number
wow cool high terp numbers what's this
somebody asked me about a year ago ryan
when you start getting
uh skeptical about a lab report and i
said when somebody says to me i have a
lab report for you to see
right you should already be skeptical of
the results and that's okay like it's
not like you're trying to hate on
somebody's report card no but you should
be yeah you have to be right like you
that is the mentality that you have to
have are these numbers that i'm looking
at really real yeah right
yes
because like again like you know you
hear i hear for a while in washington
they were calling them thc stores it's
not a [ __ ] score
like you didn't win a race
this is an analysis of what's in the
flower that you grew yeah
and like yeah you played a role in that
but it's mostly genetics right like
you know anyway it's just funny like you
you know in this world that we're in
like there's so much grower's ego right
where it's like oh yeah you know and
it's like i really like let's try to
tease those two things apart
right with how awesome you are from the
weed that you grew i'm like all for
telling people that they grow great meat
you go great flower i mean i'm always
impressed i don't care who it is yeah
right it's like if you're truly
producing the finest that's great like
people like that in my opinion helping
the world
right but if you're just growing
like looking for lab of course you can
run around the world telling how
everybody how cool you are it's like you
know yeah it doesn't impress me like
i've seen enough live boards that like i
don't it's like who cares great you got
it yeah you got a big one it's like
great you know what i mean like yeah we
if you grow enough plants especially
from seed you're going to find some big
ones yeah right big big big plants and
big big high numbers so
anyway that's like a good thing to look
at look at the cannabinoids are you know
are you seeing neutral cannabinoids or
acidic cannabinoids or bones right
you want to be seen both
and you want your neutrals like thc cbd
cbg you want those numbers to be really
low yeah um because that's an indicator
that your lab report is good and now you
sent me like for example so you sent me
ones and one had like i think there was
like three and a three and a four
percent or terp-wise yes they're both
like i mean those are
we have a we had what we called the
schwag flag
and it's really like under one percent
so we would just discard anything that
was under one percent terpene content
yeah because they're they're not like
they're 80s weed it's not that they're
bad
yeah it's just not the oiliest dankest
like super drippy oily wheat right
um
and so we would just automatically
anything under it doesn't even get
considered for the
for you know quality and then
we started you know this is a few years
ago but we were you know getting into
the four or five percent range
and through breeding the highest
terpenoid producing plants we were able
to get some like outliers that were up
to like even seven percent or even eight
which is like ridiculously oily yeah
um
so you know you can do that but
again like you really want to have
confidence in the lab that you're doing
exactly and
as a
as a breeder like a home breeder it gets
really [ __ ] expensive to use thirty
party third-party laps because it does
you're growing a hundred plants
like that's like a ten thousand dollar
analytical bill yeah yeah crazy in most
cases like even if you were to turn
around and sell every gram of that crop
you're not getting enough like yeah
you know unless you're growing huge
plants you're not getting that 10 grand
back yeah right so
um
doing that kind of breeding has to be
funded by people with pockets or
somebody that has an understanding that
hey i'm going to make an investment in
this and the result that comes out of
the end is going to have value
yeah right and and so nowadays like
you'll see those plants that are like up
into the five percent like five percent
i'm not gonna say it's a maxima in the
market but like yeah when i see someone
with a five percenter
even when i consider it might be thirty
percent inflated i'm like my good job
you agree that well yeah um
when i see eights i'm really skeptical
again they're not possible i know
they're possible because we've made them
yeah but
when it's such an anomaly got like six
lines and all of them are eight
percenters yeah that's kind of like oh
yeah you won like five billion dollar
lotteries in a row like the probability
of that is really [ __ ] low right and
so when the probability is really low
something shifty is probably going on
right yeah right like this isn't about
calling anybody out or saying whatever
your [ __ ] stuff sugar yeah yeah like you
know somebody showed me a 38
labs flower 38
total cannabinoids
um which is like exceptionally high and
it was enough to be lab important i
called up josh you know i know josh and
uh
and alec from there they're two of the
owners and i called up alec and i said
dude like
what's up with this number like people
are showing this all over ig and sending
it to me
tell me what's going on with this sample
and he's like yeah he says when we get a
number over you know i think it was 32
or whatever
but when they when they have a number
that hits a certain thing it's go back
to the sample
start from the beginning again and yeah
the whole process reanalyze it they call
it a represent run a reprep on that
sample
and they do and it came back like you
know within the same
small window that it was like yeah it's
a real number wow so you can have like
these massive [ __ ] numbers where it's
like
all the stars aligned and the plants
treated perfectly and it's the most
banging genetic and
the the dry and everything is done
perfectly and you preserve that
beautiful specimen and get it yeah
um
so when you when you show me your
samples and you have that one that was
higher yeah and all i can tell you is
it seems high it doesn't mean it's wrong
yeah but
it's one to look at
it's anomalous
yeah exactly and there's two anomalies
in those three samples
well yeah so so so even if it was just
based on the numbers i would be like
that doesn't mean that they're wrong
yeah
no lab report no signature
it's not even on a lab report you know
yeah no i don't know the lab never saw
it missing it's like all those things
combined it's like red flag red flag red
flag rag flag
right so absolutely yeah
and like i said you know
the only way to really know these things
is to run that sample that that plant
through five different grows and analyze
that that yeah and kind of see what's
the range of what that plant does
um
yeah i mean i guess it could be an
anomalous
it could be an anomalous anomalously
good grow just that one round and
that's that
only time you'll ever see it yeah and i
think like i think that we can still say
that like
nobody
really knows all the secret little
switches and bells and whistles which is
to give a plant to make it produce
at its optimum optimum production every
single time like sure you know you hit
it or you don't and sometimes like
there's a lot of clouds or sometimes
it's shitty weather and you get you know
like whatever it is like yeah
nothing goes perfectly the air
conditioner goes down who knows right
yeah there's a ton of things that can go
wrong
um
so
again in the context of like the thing i
like consumers to know is that like it's
just to understand that context just
because it's like you know like i'm out
in the market you're out in the market
we're trying to sell seeds we're trying
to provide good products from people and
you've got some jump that's been growing
for like seven years
and they've got an instagram page with
like their crosses and like
everything's you know i i you know my
results range from like 32 to 40 thc and
it's just yeah
the reason i want to have these
conversations in public is so that like
the consumers that are watching us they
can become informed and then when they
see the used car sales and seed pushers
that like are everywhere in this [ __ ]
market every left turn like every second
account that follows me is something
genetics or something labs yeah right
it's like oh you're a lab are you you've
got like a tent
yeah
um
it's all about
it's it's all about marketing it's all
about trying to [ __ ] nick buck right
yeah and
you know i'd like making a living out of
a cannabis would be nice for everybody
but
you know i really
have
taken this to like a stupid level of
passion
yeah in depthness that it's like when i
have to stand beside like joe blow
that's like
it's about nonsense it's like i just you
know and i'm
not competing not even competing for an
audience but it's like i'm at a
conference i'm speaking on a panel
besides some dude
that's like spouting nonsense near this
point jesus christ man
yeah it's hard it's hard when you love
something that much and you fit that
many that many years into it and and
just to watch you get bastardized super
fast around you well yeah
and the only way to do that is to like
you know is to try to explain to people
why your shit's different right
like what do you see like all this time
and energy that i put into learning and
understanding all this stuff like why it
makes a difference in our our seeds
yeah
and
you know it's it's demoralizing
that it's demoralizing to have to
to sit there and do that and the but the
only way to really have people recognize
is to like educate all of our consumers
right yeah so that people can be
informed and people can like not get
caught in the carnival
of co get caught up with the carnival
parkers
yeah right so
yeah it's abundant
well they're everywhere it's like you
know it's like trying to walk across a
field like avoiding cow patties
yeah it really is
there's a loose bunch of stuff on labs i
don't know what other stuff we want you
want to cover or what if there's
questions from the audience or stuff
that you want yeah
someone someone asked are inaccurate
percentages fabricated by via false
standards when using the gc
uh which is what you mean a standard
like so if you know yeah
like
i think the answer is yes lab results
can be falsified they can also be
there are all the time as we've
explained with that 15 thing if you
didn't understand and see that go back
and watch it
there is an inherent amount of normal
variation and acceptable
laboratory error that influences the
end results right so like
when you put in the flower
and you get back that lab report that
didn't come from god
right yeah like i don't believe god that
didn't somebody didn't hand that down to
the divine and say this is the divine
ultimate truth right like yeah yeah it's
like hey we measured your [ __ ] this is
the this is the measurement that we got
here's the number and by the way what
you should understand is that that
number is like has an acceptable
variation
right
on the other side of the question do
people
manipulate these laboratories
yes absolutely
in every district there have been
laboratories that have had their bombs
bank because
like it's like you take like you know
there was somebody they in a leafly
article somebody did this
and laid out like a thousand lab reports
they took all the statistical averages
of
all these different labs and every lab's
statistical average went on on a graph
with a different color curve right oh
wow you see like everybody is all lined
over this one specific area and then you
got one lab that's like shifted to the
right
their whole curve is like shifted to the
right and it's like okay well what the
[ __ ] are these guys doing wrong yeah
right and the truth is
it happens in every district
higher lab results
get more sales of course therefore
there's an incentive for labs to give
higher results because they're a profit
for-profit service yeah and
there's
a benefit for growers to seek those labs
out
and maybe pay a little bit more for a
higher number
right
and so
i think that's a bad design yeah i think
the answer you can't go back to that
question
do do labs manipulate let's not say all
labs but say a percentage of labs do
manipulate
and that can be done intentionally or
unintentionally
yeah the the way it's set up is right
for corruption if if one wants to be
corrupt
it's
you have to it again it's about this
passion thing that we were talking about
what are you seeking
are you speaking to market a product or
are you seeking the ultimate truth yeah
are you seeing any answers cannabis
understanding right and like
if you're not controlling that agenda
you're getting played by it right so if
you're a consumer that's true unless you
know like say for example like
you know you i go through all the stuff
and you say to me you know dude i really
want to be like high integrity seed bank
we're going to do everything the right
way and you show up you're doing it the
right way
i'm going to have more faith than you
yeah
um and then if like i resonate with that
kind of thing and i say hey matt's doing
all the thing look he's demonstrating
that like hey i got this lab report but
maybe it was a little high i don't know
like something's questionable that shows
that you got integrity if i'm a customer
i'm gonna support that yeah right
um but these are again that's like a
value judgment of something that i value
other than i might not value those
things right like because as you can see
like a lot of other people are like well
[ __ ] that the jungle boys is the hottest
[ __ ] i'm gonna go grab whatever they got
you know what i mean yeah they don't the
value system is not the same so anyway
next question
and the education system's not the same
i mean like that what we've been trying
to do with the whole breeder syndicate
thing has been it's been tough because
we decided a long time ago the only way
to combat
disinformation and misinformation is to
educate but you can't force people to
want to educate themselves
no you can't all you can do is
lay it out for the people that want to
know
yeah and
i've been pushing this uphill for a long
time
um
more people are getting to the point
where they want to know
yeah
right
um
and it's changing right i mean just it's
changing over time but yeah it takes
time and you know it's like everything
it's like
you know what you and i consider good
music that ain't what's on the top 40.
right and the cannabis industry is going
to be no different like there's going to
be people that really understand they're
really passionate and they really want
that's a compared beautiful things
and then there's like
the 90 that are gonna listen to justin
bieber
yeah right and smoke bieber butt
so
i have some i have some questions i want
to run through
it it refers to testing but it refers to
genetic testing
uh are you cool with that yeah sure okay
um
this is kind of i don't know i mean i
don't know if there's an answer to it
necessarily but do you know how far we
are in mapping the cannabis genome as
far as are we able to tell
real genetic relation as far as like s1
variation and and parental lines father
cousin sister is that even something in
cannabis that you can do
yeah you can do it
i can't go and like seek that
information out so one of the weird
things with the filos
was going on you know they were doing
the run around trying to get samples and
they obviously approached me at one
point in time and i was like not
interested
yeah but what i will do is i said hey
i've got all these
self populations
why don't i help why don't we look at
like 50 individuals from the self
population and then explore the
variations so then now we've got like
we've we've shown hey here's like the
parental clone here's the
heterozygosity by sequencing
yeah growing 100 offspring of themselves
do the same thing to each other they
didn't want to do that [ __ ] yeah
um
it seemed like that was the most
like what people went to philos for was
that information more so than anything
else
they were just weird they had the pitch
was great it was like
collect your star on the galaxy
yeah right like and it was like it's
kind of like that whole like
we can show you your name it'll be up in
lights yeah you know like it's [ __ ]
nonsense but that's it people fall and
fall for that [ __ ] right yeah so um
when we when i don't mean we but i mean
when
humanity first
did the human genome project it was like
oh my god we're going to know everything
we've got the whole genomes and that
would be able to treat disease and it's
like wait a second
it's like you've got one white guy
yeah right like do you think that that
encompasses the genetic variation that
exists in like the jewish or the or the
afghan or the african population of like
the north yeah yeah
south africa or like asia versus you
know like wherever
right and so
the next evolution that came out of that
was called the thousand genomes project
right and it's like once you got a
thousand genomes now you can start
looking at all the different genes and
seeing okay here's kind of like a
catalog of the in the genomic variation
that exists in the species
or
like at least it gives us a look at hey
there's way more varieties right and so
we're not at the point with cannabis
yeah so there are you know
folks like medicinal genomics and some
other groups i think medicinal genomics
probably have like i would say they've
been doing it i think they've been doing
it like more or less the longest
and they so they've started to get like
yeah you can go in and if you're one of
their clients and you paid out your [ __ ]
sequence you can compare
you know your snips versus other
essentially snip sir
genetics misspelling isn't a word
right yeah
you can and because these things are
repeated over time if you have like a
genetic
misspelling that happens in skunk and
then you cross it into skunk northern
lights and skunk caves and found
like you have a probability of finding
that
misspelling in all of those different
lines right yeah so over time you can
use those to build like a family tree
um
but what we haven't really done a good
job of at this point yet is saying
this
small genetic change results in x
right okay so like we've got a bunch of
dna letters and we can see there's
variation in these dna letters but it's
like okay what does that correlate to in
a plant we don't know
yeah right and that's the hard work is
correlating the phenotypic data with the
genetic data that makes sense and that
is going to take time yeah that's got to
be years away yeah but it's going to
it's always going to be an ongoing
process right yeah and with corn they've
done it they've got a pretty good job of
it now and like listen we've got like
we've got what's called an annotated
genome which means
you can look up hey you want to look up
like the uh
fatty acid desaturates gene that is
involved in like you know cell plant
cells what happens when plants get
really cold they increase the oil
content and the cell membranes then
there's a gene involved in that right so
yeah like i can look up that gene and
actually now go and find out exactly
where it is in the canopy you know
because they've said hey this small
suction of the the chromosome matches up
with this gene and all of the plants
this is the gene that does this in
cannabis
right so but like again it's like you
know that that gene that segment of dna
signals there
do we know what every variant that
exists for that gene
and the result of those variants are no
we don't know that
very interesting so we're starting to
build that knowledge like one of the
things you know recurrent medicinal
genomics recurrence no dummy
you know he looked he was like oh we're
going to start looking at the
cannabinoid synthase genes like that's
going to be one of the first things so
you know they sequence the whole genome
but the first thing that they do they
take the microscope up it's not a
microscope or a magnifying glass but
it's an analogy you take the magnifying
glass out and you go and you look at
that region of the genome that has those
genes involved in cannabinoid production
hey this one's got a break in the gene
or this one has two copies of the gene
right and so
they're starting to tease it apart for
like
some of the major genes of interest
yeah but because they don't grow plants
and they don't do those correlational
studies between genetic data and
phenotypes
they can't generate that kind of data
yeah right it was it was slow build
it was interesting going back and forth
with filos at the very end before they
shut their doors
and
giving them known parents
and the known children cuts and watching
them come back and say there is no
relation it was really interesting
watching that and they they put their
their whole reputation on the line to do
it on top of that well it makes you
wonder what's going on because i mean
you know they are so it's like did they
[ __ ] up the samples lab are they not
just not running them and taking your
money and telling you
right like that could be yeah too right
you have no way of knowing
you have no way of knowing and and when
we pointed it out they shut the doors so
i guess i i don't know i i'd like to see
how long their data stays up online
their data sets because knowing that it
i i would think that if the more that
gets out the more likely people are to
start asking questions
i
i had like listen when they first
started coming out with their things and
i talked to you know i was they offered
me a job at one point in time yeah when
i left napo and came back to canada they
were like well come work with us nigro
and just or at the
philos and you know just give us give me
like two of your cbg seeds
yeah no
i was you know i
legalization was happening in canada i
was over living out of [ __ ] hotels in
the states
yeah and uh
yeah i just i didn't
i didn't value it i didn't i there was
too many red flags yeah right
and um
so
like
the way that they were going and
collecting their data
was wrong
right and just because of
you know not who i am but because of
like the position i was in with knowing
a lot of people on the internet yeah
yeah and having access to like you know
all the known stuff i was like guys like
i'll just get you all the [ __ ]
yeah
and then it's verified cuts and you know
when you're doing a catatonic that it
came from the guy that read cam chronic
right like yeah yeah exactly you know
and they were like well we don't want to
do that
they didn't want we got real legacy
strength you know we got fearless like
well why not it's like oh you want to
take people's money to give them an
answer
right because they were running a test
their cost was 30 100 bucks or whatever
it was and they're charging people
hundreds of dollars right so
yeah
they're just turning and burning
um and in the meantime they're learning
all this stuff because they see
everybody's samples or like the guy that
pays the test you only see your sample
right yeah it's like you understand your
genetic
data
to whatever degree
you can say oh look there's my star on
the galaxy
yeah right it's kind of like buying an
anchor on the moon
right yeah like you can see with the
telescope who cares it's like [ __ ]
useless
yeah dude
um
so but anyway you know
anyway it's one of those things where
it's like i don't know if you're thought
to read tom sawyer but it's like there's
a certain point in time he has to paint
whitewash the stupid fats and
everybody's like yeah yeah hey tom can i
give you my like apple if you let me
whitewash some of your fence that's kind
of what phylos was doing with the
cannabis industry right everybody was
lining up like suckers to be remembered
it all turned like because of i did that
breeding work from napro then there was
the patent that came from it like a lot
of people all bent out of shape and it
was like you're [ __ ] filos you're
working with filos and patenting all
this stuff and i was like wait a second
all you dumbasses fell into the [ __ ]
philos trap
you actively paid to give away your
[ __ ] information to some big genetics
company
and you're pissed off at me like why
don't you ask me mad at me like you fell
into the trap dude
right
um
so i don't know the cannabis is
you know community is funny with that
stuff because it's like yeah like the
patents already freaked out about the
patents and now everybody wants a patent
right yeah
literally everyone
yeah
and
like
i think if you truly bred something and
you created something new then you can
get intellectual property protection by
way of a patent like a plant patent in
the states [ __ ] get on with your bad
self now now why not now it's got to now
it's got to the point of where you
almost have to if you want to stay
competitive because the legal market's
coming and if you don't patent it
someone else will it's just it's going
to happen well they can't nobody can
so somebody can't come along patent your
[ __ ]
um
they can patent something that is the
same as your [ __ ] if you didn't get to
it in time yeah sure
but yeah
really like what a patent is saying hey
this this unique thing that i developed
is mine
and yeah this gives you a stamp that
says hey that you actually developed
that because you have to demonstrate
how you made it
okay
like you have to say to people i crossed
this and this we did these selections
and there's all things like role
descriptions right do you have to have
actual proof that you crossed x y z and
the proof of all this like video like do
you know how it works it has to stand up
in court
right because it can be challenged at
any point in time so if you don't do a
good enough job like you might get it
past the uspto you met you might get
past the patent examiner and he says
yeah this thing appears
whatever but if somebody comes along and
and challenges it later and they can
demonstrate later
that that hey
you didn't
document well enough and there's these
things that call what you said into
question that's up in front of the judge
yeah who's going to make a ruling on
whether you actually the patent is valid
a patent is a claim right it doesn't
mean that you wouldn't hit it to claim
that you own something
right whether you really own it is a
matter for the cards
yeah right and so like any patent can be
challenged
um and so if you're going to go through
a patent and all the effort and expense
of getting a patent for something that
you've created you should probably do a
good job of describing everything like
all your homework every last step yeah
because you want to lay out the whole
story
so some because the story is what gets
published in the patent if somebody
comes along and says yeah this doesn't
make sense in your story that's ground
for a challenge yeah and so
that's why when you see like you know
i'm not talking about plant patents but
if you read some of these patents on
like genes
you know it's like
or for example in a chemotype so it'll
be like
we're patenting every plant in
terpenoline dominance with uh type three
or type two you know cannabinoid profile
meaning cbd and cbg and that means
everything from one percent two percent
three percent four percent five percent
six yeah and you'll literally see them
[ __ ] list out like you know one
through forty percent
right yeah for clarity that they say
this patent claims every plant that is
one percent two percent three percent
four percent yeah
and it's like you document it as tightly
controlled as possible and the idea
for that patent attorneys do is like
you want to write patents that are
defensible in the future
so you try to close every loophole that
you can think of
right
is and patents are different than
trademarks i know archive trademarks
yeah trademarks are some there's a trick
yeah
trademark is how you sell a product
okay okay look
when we start talking about intellectual
property on plants
it's
who wherever the person is watching this
in the world like if you're in europe or
in your canada or you're in the united
states or you're in china
totally different okay yeah
there's something in in the
this there's a system that is like
accepted all over the world
called um upof and upon essentially the
union for the protection of plant
varieties and and they're the guys that
created this overarching system that
said
these are the ways that we evaluate to
see who owns or develops a new plant
variety
yeah but it's an international treaty
made by an international organization
all the countries come together most of
the countries in the world come together
and have signed this treaty but like for
example
you know
they call it like new zealand say they
signed on in like the 1974 edition of
the treaty and the united states signed
on in like a later version call it 1991
right
made up numbers and dates sure you're
only beholden to the version of the
treaty to which you signed
yeah okay so and then
[Music]
you sign the treaty all these like for
example they go home you know so there's
this international treaty the united
states signs on the international trade
hey we're gonna be part of this thing
now they go back to the united states
and they write a set of legislation that
backs up the treaty
yeah well that legislation is totally
unique to the united states
right like you follow the overarching
principles of the
the umbrella organization that top level
org
but
really every country is a silo with
their own system
yeah
and so
patents plant patents per se
only exist in the united states in
australia
okay like that makes sense there is no
such thing
plant patent in canada or europe yeah
we use
um breeders rights the breeder's right
system that's overthinking by upon
um
one of the major differences between
those two is that a patent
you don't have to disclose or make
available so for example
when we talk about international
registration of plant varieties or plant
cultivars
what that does is so so i develop
whatever call it like a blueberry sweets
it's called a blueberry sweet skunk
plant i find a blueberry sweet snail
plant it's totally different i register
it i declare the parents i do the whole
spiel
yeah but he says okay ryan this plant is
yours we recognize that you're the
developer of this plant this one plant
that you selected out of this population
we're going to give you a cultivar
registration
recognition so it's a registered
cultivar
what you get out of that is the rice you
don't get the plant
yeah so it's like now that plant that i
have that i that
anybody that wants to grow that plant
anywhere else in the world
they can kill that plant but i get the
royalties or you know
like i have the rights to the royalties
or whatever profits come from
the development section of that plant
what you don't get to say is nobody else
can use this plan in fact one of the
conditions that you have to do
is make your plant available to other
breeders
oh interesting yeah and the the reason
is is like hey
the reasoning from the top level org is
hey we recognize that you develop that
plant and it's special it's awesome and
it's unique and we're going to give you
17 years of economic
exclusivity around that plant
plant genetic resources are not yours
yes the entire globe has the right
everybody on the planet has the right to
that plant
for use in the betterment of all plants
for humanity
therefore the plant that you have the
certification on
we recognize it as yours but you have to
share it with everybody else yeah right
and so other people can take my [ __ ] and
breed it and improve it
yeah if i have a patent i don't have to
give it out to anybody
uh okay i got you right you can control
who gets it right because it truly is
your piece of property it's your you
have ownership over that thing
gotcha um that makes that's that's yeah
that makes a lot of sense it's kind of a
weird like unique thing that happens in
the states because you guys have these
patents
they're recognized in australia they're
not recognized anywhere else in the
world
not even canada no that's funny yeah
yeah
yeah so that's one form of patents
there's other forms of patents like
there's utility patents and there's all
this other [ __ ] so
but i think
you know rather than doing a show on
patents it's just good to recognize that
that's kind of the way it is so yeah get
yourself a plan you can also do cultivar
and variety registrations in
the united states i think with patents
around why would you
yeah right the thing about being part of
the international variety registration
is that
you you don't only have record like for
you if you're only growing and your
clients are only in the states fine it
doesn't matter get your patent in the
states you're protected you you're
you've
you're protected in the space take that
plant to
europe
nobody recognizes your ip
yeah so
you know you might want if you're going
to be doing business internationally you
might want to get
a form of intellectual property
protection that is recognized
internationally
okay
so we've got a question for you i want
to hear chimera talk about kitazan
jasmonic acid and salicylic acid is this
something that you
know a lot about
i know i mean i know a little bit about
them i'm not like a plant physiology guy
and i have that stuff on the top of my
on the top of my head i mean they're
they're signaling chemicals right yeah
so chi doesn't kitazan's not kitazan is
an additive is that it's like what's
that's the molecule that's in
uh the shells of crustaceans right yeah
so there's
some evidence that it does stuff and
plants and that's not my area of
specialty
so i want to talk to you about what is
chimera
excited about genetically that's around
right now something you're working on or
something that maybe you saw recently
that you're really stoked on that's
novel
my list not i get off on the variation
so i like new stuff i like i like
i like when our understanding grows
right so it's like you can use it
because for me in genetics
it's like i you know we talked about a
little bit with caleb on the shango show
the other day but yeah like when you're
solving a plan it's not just about
looking through the population and
saying hey oh this plant's great because
of whatever i want to understand all the
traits and the plant and how they're
inherited right and how it's breeding
it's kind of like being able to take a
part machine
once you can take it apart and put it
back together
then you can reassemble it in new ways
yes right and so
that's really what get you know like
when for example the file story came out
right in the the skunk compound yeah
yeah
super interesting
i want to now be able to go into a
breeding program
take a plant with styles self it
and see how does the
like what happens in the distribution of
that thiol expression in the offspring
yeah right because when you analyze that
then you can kind of get to understand
then you can develop a hypothesis about
how
that trade is inherited
yeah once you know how that trade is
inherited then you can bring it into any
other breeding program sure right so
that's like kind of what i nerd on it's
not probably that's very exciting to
people no i mean it's like yeah yeah
that's the kind of stuff that i like so
you know i don't really
like
that there's i have favorites but
you know when i look at cannabis i don't
really look at it in that almost call it
like a prejudicial way
where we're segregating plants on
quality and i only like one type
you know what i mean like
i've got my favorite dogs but for
cannabis
i see the very i see the inherent value
in all of it
yeah right you know that makes sense
funky like rudorah stuff with the
autoflowering i mean that was like i
collect that stuff you know yeah like
when i'm in morocco when i was in
morocco i found these plants there
there's a there's a hemp variety called
panorama and essentially
that the plant grows like a globe
so like all the branches are completely
equal so it makes like this round bush
oh wow right and this half breeder in
him even bosch years ago he developed a
variety of it for
um like as an ornamental variety it was
like it was at the time it was the only
ornamental cannabis variety that had
been bred yeah and he thought oh yeah
people planted their garden yeah with
these little weird glove balls
um anyway i found a plant like that in
morocco and i was like [ __ ] you like
take some seeds out of that sucker and
take it home yeah right
it's an oddity
yeah it's an oddity it's not in the
current cannabis massive gene pool as
far as what's being worked with you
never know what it's going to offer
different like i like the difference
like i really do get off on the
variation that you see in the species
yeah um because i don't think anybody's
done a very good job at like
characterizing the variation that exists
on any given set of trades right well in
april we did we started doing a pretty
good job on terps
and then once we you know what we did
terps at first and then we were like you
know you end up with a plant that has
the same terpene terpene profile and
you've got two plants that are identical
that's that look identical by lab report
but you smell them they're totally
different you're like okay
this is clearly not the whole story we
need to look at other chemicals so you
pull out the gcms and you start looking
for
regions between your peaks it's like
what else is in there that we're
like just driving over right we're
passing in the analysis
and then you start looking at that and
then you find oh there's other scent
molecules that are involved in other
molecules with scent that are involved
in our perception perception of smell
because again it's like i've used this
analogy before but it's like
it's kind of like going to the orchestra
and then and then turn to the guy that's
never heard orchestra music and saying
hey did you hear the oboe
yeah right it's like yeah yeah he he
perceives that in the overall sound of
what he's perceiving is the sound of the
orchestra but he hasn't trained himself
to be able to like identify that one
note right
yeah um and scent is an orchestra
yeah it is molecules right and when we
smell those molecules we get them all at
once that we perceive it as one thing
but really
it's one thing it's like it's kind of
like looking at the mona lisa it's like
you can say yeah it's one painting well
yeah it's one painting but it's like
look at all the intricacy that exists in
it right all the brush details yeah
yeah and that's really the difference
between
that's what happens when you you know i
did i missed the thing last night but i
imagine it's the kind of stuff that you
guys were talking about last night right
like yeah we went through his kit and i
i i went through and smelled each
individual one like the terpenes they're
all in different percentages and whatnot
but yeah it was fascinating there were
certain ones that i was smelling like
lemonade and a few others that i just it
totally wasn't what i thought it would
be like i like it smells like oranges
doesn't it it's like yeah yeah there's
there's a few different limonines in
there but yeah it was it was wild man
uh he he wants to send you one of the
full kits too if you ever want it cool
i'll check it out for sure yeah um he he
wanted to know crybaby uh i'm curious
how soma clonal variants fit into the
whole plant patents or whole patent
sphere
soma clonal variants okay so semicolon
variation is
like let's call it it's usually referred
to as the genetic variation that comes
out of
tissue culture but you can yeah really
so
a somatic cell is like any cell in your
body that is not destined to become like
sperm or egg
okay right so like yeah
uh
audio cut for a second
oh we dropped
sorry so here we go you're good arms are
just going to keep going off um
so some tone of variation is like the
variation that exists as a result of the
plant
growing
so like the somatic cell is like any
cell in your body like i was saying it
doesn't become a germline cell it
doesn't become again it's not going to
become a gamete
yeah okay
in plants we talk about it from what we
see the variation that exists when
plants come out of tissue culture like
there's a variant that we recognize as a
phenotypic variant which we're noticing
a change in morphology
yeah
um
probably what's happened is the hormones
that we've been using in the tissue
culture processes have caused a genetic
mutation that is the result of that
variation
right so i guess
i'm just trying to like repurpose the
question to say like
what's the degree of natural variation
that exists in the cannabis plant right
yeah there was a paper that was just
done on this
and i think there are some flaws in the
paper but they they actually sequenced
all these different plate like they took
samples from a big mother plant called
like you know it was like five or six
feet tall it was actually not in the
healthiest condition which
you know yeah it was like i was like
maybe that's that should have been
documented in the study but bottom line
is they took a whole bunch of
samples of different shoot tips bottom
of the plant top and plant medium middle
part of the plant and lo and behold
there's all this genetic mutation that
exists even with just a mother plant
forget tissue culture
just within a mother plant now
whether that is a a factor of them doing
a bad analysis or not let's forget that
and just assume that it happens
okay
plants and we've seen this in trees
mutations happen as plants grow right so
if you got like a plant that throws off
two shoots right so this is the main one
here you got two shoots coming off here
when this guy has a mutation every cell
that develops from that
cell with a mutation is going to carry
that mutation
yeah right and so we've literally got
two branches on a tree
that are going off in different ways
that have different genotypes if that
genotype happens in a gene if that
mutation happens in a gene that's
important
you know an important trait for cannabis
that could lead to like a change in the
planet
yeah right and so yeah i don't know
you're probably heard like someone's
asking like a sport that's that is a
sport but a sport is like a shoot with a
mutation right and so for example i was
just going to mention like every maybe
people have heard about like pinot
pinot noir is a grape variety he's been
around for hundreds of years
we actually have these new grapes that
are called pinot noir or pinot blanc
which means you know white and pinot um
pinot gris
pinot gris actually kind of a pinky
grape pinky it's actually a sport that
they found on like somebody was walking
through a a
vineyard of pinot noir and noticed that
one branch
on a plant had gray grapes not purple
grapes like there was a mutation that
happened
yeah in the color gene
right and maybe some other genes as well
but the point is you snip off that
that sport or that cutting
that plant is actually different enough
from the registered pinot noir variety
that you can actually take pinot that
new short the the new sport pinot gris
or peanut butter and and well maybe not
patented but you can register it for
life i don't know yet
patents is a little bit different
because the way they unlock the way they
they kind of characterize them is a
little bit different
okay
um but yeah it's it's
like you know when you do your plant
registration it's like oh yeah the
grapes are purple well if like you go
back and it's like you've got this one
where the grapes aren't purple it's
obviously not the same variety
yeah right or the same cultivar so you
can get named as a new cultivar
so
um
yeah truth is like
these things happen
they happen in plants the degree to
which they happen in cannabis i'm i'm
sure we know that they know we know that
it happens
i think the degree to which we know that
it happens is probably still up in the
air
yeah so i don't know if that answers the
question but uh
maybe there's a little context for it
yeah
that's interesting
um
can you talk about and now we're going
to
some of your strains that you've done in
the past can you talk about what my
favorite strain i know we've probably
gone over it before
but since this is a new episode mental
floss like that that was one that
touched me i'm a i'm a [ __ ] for purples
and it was one of it was made during an
era where purples were pretty obscure at
the time like the the purple craze had
gone not many people were breeding with
purples but mental floss always had this
beautiful purple senescence during
flower yeah can you talk about a little
bit when it turns at the end it's a
beautiful one like when
it does one of those things i guess it's
got a bunch of carotenoids in it the
carotenoids like when you look at for
example i don't know you you probably
don't have maple trees down where you
are you might have seen them in the fall
they go from like green and then when
the green the plant you know when the
plants going in the fall and they're
about to shed their leaves they pull as
much resources back out of the leaves
into the trunk yes right so they can
save those those building blocks for
next year and what's left what happens
is so the plants go the leaves go from
green to either red or yellow the reason
they're red or yellow is because they've
got
um
molecules in the leaf called carotenoids
and carotenoids just comes from that
yellow orangey pigment color that's why
they're called that like kind of like
carrots right
but
those carotenoids kind of hide behind
the
chlorophyll and so with metal floss
again when you when you give it a good
flush at the end yeah and the plant you
know cannibalizes all that
that chlorophyll you end up with these
beautiful kind of rainbow
yellow and purple leaves on the back
that plant is also like
it makes some of my favorite hash of any
cannabis that i've ever come across
um super flavorful it's strong it melts
like [ __ ] hell when you uh someone's
saying [ __ ] carrots yeah [ __ ] carrots
when you eat when you it melts like
crazy and it's also very up like i would
smoke that stuff thinking i'm gonna have
another puff and go to bed and you know
i got to come here two hours later type
it away you know yeah yeah like it just
it gets you going
and he heals like a [ __ ]
so it's like it's just a great plant
right uh where did you source your uh
stuff for the incense haze
that the incidence haze one of the
parents is sweet skin the other one is a
seed that came from this dude in new
york state that or that said he got out
of the piff
so um
i don't know if it is or not
is his name was prank so i called it
frank's incense haze yeah right because
it really smelt like incense um when you
grew it
like it was the reason i paired that one
with the sweet skunk is because the two
terp like
very oft not very often not very often
you'll come across two plants
that are so close to each other they
could be the same plant
yeah um
and so
sweet skunk in this plant were like in
almost every sense identical to the part
where like you'd walk into a room like
you like when you got when you know if
you have plans for like 10 15 years in
your room yeah you get to learn like a
little in you know idiosyncratic sorry
idiosyncrasy with the leaf and the way
that like
you know the way that the leaves come
off the main front or the serration
pattern or whatever it is yeah you get
to know them like a parent can identify
twins right like one of the twins and so
it's the same thing like
and
these plants would get confused right
the people would conduct them all the
time because they're so close together
um
anyway yeah it was so when those two
came together so i didn't keep saying i
was selling the sweet skin because i
wanted to understand the inheritance
pattern of some of the rare volatiles
that are in it
and
the self
although it's pure it's a little bit
smaller
you got a wider range of like because
it's expressing all the all the the
hidden variation that exists within one
genome right or those that self
population
but when i cross those two sister
planets together when i when i do a um
what i do across using a reversal i'll
always hit the plant to itself because
usually you're trying to get that pure
line but i also always while the
pollen's flying i will just make a bunch
of other crosses at the same time yeah
so it's you have them so it's like when
you're going down a program it's like oh
hey i lost a trade or this line doesn't
have a trait that i want you go back to
the line with the trait you've already
got a hybrid that's 50
within the line you're working in right
so
some guy dude uh but anyway
so when you cross those two things
together this this the incense haze
which was simply irresistible i mean
they came out much bigger and better
um
and very consistent to type
you know um
so it kind of was the best of both
worlds so when people ask me if like you
know when they're when they're sniffing
around that thing i always say hey
get both of them you know get the self
for breeding so you got the pure stock
it's a little little more homozygous or
a greater chance of being homozygous
but
the the hybrid performs the other one
right in terms of like a grower's
performance right oh sure you know it
really depends on what what the customer
is looking for
i
want to have time i really like to take
my time to do it like a proper consult
with someone because i'll come up and be
like hey somebody grew this stuff that
you know the lemon floss that's great i
want to grow it and that's like what
what are you doing it for like what are
you using it for
right because i don't want you to apply
the seeds that you think you want i want
you to have the seeds that are going to
be the best for what you're doing
right
yeah so yeah
is there a strain that you can think of
that you have been looking for for many
years or strain you'd like to encounter
from the past that you haven't
i mean
yeah
again we had a straight discussion i
think of it in terms of plants
right like are there rare phenotypes
that i've seen in the past that i don't
that i'd love to see again sure i mean
of course
it's kind of one of those things that
it's like
if it comes by it passes without you
grabbing a copy and then solving it like
it may have gone to the wind
yeah right so you got to recognize that
it is but you know you're always looking
for those things in the future
we decided to plant when i was
relatively young and it was called the
scooty sweetie there's an island off of
uh texas british columbia and the
straight there
yeah called lustian it's no power it's
essentially a hippie commune and
you know they grow a lot of dope up
there um yeah and they this one like it
was before i had ever i'd never even
heard of the island at that point in
time i was quite young living on the
other side of the country and a friend
of mine a friend of mine
someone's asking what do we think of
breeder's team yeah your questions are
funny dude um anyway
this this flower ended up back with me
and it was amazing it was like
incredibly electric super strong really
up
and unfortunately other than the name
was gd sweetie
i
i never knew anything you know
yeah i never knew what it was so it's
like yeah for sure i'd love to come
across those things
um
but it's like the beautiful girl that
you dated in high school you might not
find another one like it so marry her
while you can
yeah
yeah okay
well we need to get your genetics here
in the states you know i know there's a
lot of people who really want to grab
chimera's stuff is there anywhere
available in the states right now that
people no i can't i can't sell any of
the
states unfortunately
oh um there is that it's definitely like
i said when i work down there
part of you know becoming a landed
immigrant is having your fingerprints
scanned
right so it's like me me sending seeds
into the states ain't really a great
idea
yeah it's probably probably not but yeah
maybe someone can um work on doing some
chimera genetics out here that'd be cool
yeah yeah in this case we have breeders
retail is going to come up and get going
again but they're a uk bank good so it's
you know with them having done brexit
it's a like it's a bit of a [ __ ] show
right yeah not this it's not as easy to
the business out of the uk it was but
it's perfectly legal for us to do yeah
so people that want to do that can you
know get contact with me and we can hook
you up to the uk
um
but unfortunately the way the laws are
and with that whole
fingerprint and having worked for the
man thing it's like yeah
it's not yeah
that always
though
yeah
that's where we're at
um crybaby made a comment on your
limoncello he said i thought the
limoncello was very consistent was an
excellent breeder i know he's done some
stuff with it too yeah that's right
right that's the that's the sweet skin
itself it is pretty consistent smell
wise there's a little bit of variation i
find still in like in morphology if you
grow enough plants of the flower
morphology
and so that's just what i meant from
that context like the smoking they're
more or less someone said they're more
or less the same but they're very close
they're within
that type
um yeah but
you know i wouldn't lay down if i was
going to grow an indoor set of tables i
wouldn't lay see down seed from those
because there's just
if you're trying to sell the flower
there's a little for me there's a little
bit too much inconsistency
yeah yeah
well is there anything else you want to
cover before we uh
locals up with seeds
all of these new region x knees suck hey
man there's seeds are available
yes seeds are there yeah everybody
listen everybody's you know what it's
like everybody's gone for the cali stuff
all right the cali kelly world owns the
world
it's you know spain on the worlds 10
years ago bcu in the world 10 years
before that it'll vary it'll move around
the work right they're doing the work
down there there's a lot of people
they're growing seeds
um yeah and listen that's the only way
that we're going to come up with new
better canvas keep growing seeds just
[ __ ] keep growing seeds as much as
it's appealing and you have to grow
clones for your business model
you know just keep those seeds because
if you don't grow these we're never
gonna find anything new
and we're always gonna be stuck with the
same [ __ ] that we had five years ago
that's how it goes yeah
yeah
right and listen sometimes it's stuff
from my you know it's like i i see i say
i call it cannabis fashion right it's
like i like to i like to hold on to old
cuts because it's like they go out of
favor but you bring them back like five
ten years later and people are like i
love that [ __ ]
you know yeah like dude it's the mini
skirt or the bell bottoms like they keep
it it is back right
so yeah
i never thought i'd see skunk one make a
comeback and it did you know a few years
ago like what the [ __ ]
part of the live laughing at the skunk
one if somebody actually actually asked
me to sit in and help use genetics to
help referee this stuff because it's
like you got like five guys in
california they were like i've got the
original skunk one that's like oh you do
do you it's like yeah
you're original you've never heard of
sam you've heard of dave
though no okay well then you don't have
the original
yeah right it's like it's funny again
it's that whole ego thing that like
people want to get together
and you know and be like hey i got the
original i'm the man
right yeah
like you know
drunk [ __ ] wonderful it's an
interesting plant but it's one of those
things that like you know it was one of
the first right the first relatively
creating lines and
dave started selling in holland and then
every proceed company was like well
selling we got to sell the skunk
yes so it's like that dutch passion's
got it and since he's got a copy of it
and then everybody's got a copy of it
every [ __ ] seed bank in the world
more or less
has a copy of it are they all original
how much are they any like you know it'd
be really interesting to have like an
acre and have all of them and grow them
all side by side and just see and see
what they're like they're probably not
they probably like not even you know
they're probably not even alike
yeah i'm sure they're not and this dude
that bought the seeds back in like you
know 96 or whatever when he got them
you probably didn't get them from the
original guy
right so yeah probably not is your stuff
original
you know yeah it's just it's a funny
it's a funny thing i i
i
i was actually quite amused to see
one of the most spread around scene
varieties that existed in the last 50
years
have a bunch of new people pop up and be
like yo i've got the original like yeah
and then and throw down big dollars even
though it's never been gone
you know yeah like it's always been
available and what like what is the
original like yeah right like the
original was a seed it was a named
population it wasn't like
you know it's not like today it's like
oh gee kush or cookies or [ __ ] runs
or whatever like these start as cuttings
right it always makes me laugh it's like
you know for example blue dream when
blue dream came around
it was it was one cut
right more or less like there ended up
being a couple that were very similar
but
there was one cut and then people would
come along and be like i got this blue
dream santa cruz blue dream thing and
then they'll like spank white widow on
it or some og or whatever some random
pollen yeah and then they sell the seeds
as blue dreams blue dream and now people
grow those seeds in a different market
where they don't know what the original
blue dream is they pick a mom they say
it's blue dream and now you've got two
plants
that are being passed around the world
as if they're both the original and one
of them is not even the same chemical
profile as the blue drink yeah right
it's not even close most likely yeah
so
uh crab babies asking how much the
ancestral skunk did we get to see a fair
amount like we grow a chunk
it's it's interesting i mean there's
some stuff in there the ancestral the
people i don't know people know about
ancestral scots yeah talk about it those
were seeds that dave when dave was
moving over to holland uh in like early
80s he brought obviously a bunch of
stuff over he brought like a case of
seeds over
and you know did various things with him
and didn't work with him various things
he met a hemp researcher that that knew
um
he met a hemp researcher that was
essentially like
he was a he was in a european country
i'm not going to say which one
but he was
the he grew like he was known as the
half guy right like redhead their their
country sold hemp seed around the world
and when
when the
uh police would like they'd come across
a cannabis bust they'd go and get him
and bring him to the site and be like is
this drug cannabis or not is this hemp
yeah right yeah i know black bar
um
and um
sorry someone's asking that question
that's all right and uh anyway
sam arranged for this guy to grow on his
research field a hectare of skunk
yeah
and and open populate it so essentially
like you know sam brought those seeds
over and they all went into greenhouses
they did various things things with them
had a big bunch of
the skunk left enough to plant like a
hectare
and so they took them to this european
company
country and planted in hector in
isolation
and he and rob went through the
uh what the field and rogued all the
males and the off-types and the and the
the females that were not skunk-like
yeah but the rest of it just got like an
open pocket open pollinated that is what
the ancestral skunk is
okay okay so it's like it's the closest
thing a population could be
to what was produced in california
yes all the other families that came out
of that population were like you know
they were family lines somebody went in
and found two plants and they crossed
them together yeah so what came out of
that from those one-to-one cross is not
the same as what was preserved in the
overall open population right so that's
what the op that's what the skunk was as
i said sam was like there's all these
people are you know
crying and whatever about having access
to
what's up plastagram
um
[Music]
let's give them access to this so we did
right and that and they have they got a
low germination rate i mean they
germinate yeah like that like 25 or
maybe even a little bit less now i
haven't tested them recently well
they're pretty old right
yeah i mean they must have been
reproduced like
25 30 years ago yeah
that's why
a couple years ago
sam was looking at selling his
collection and i actually helped him
re-catalog the entire thing
and so we got to go you know we went
through everything and
we did a whole bunch of germination
tests and we pulled stuff out that was
like 25 year old seed that had been
stored at like
you know four degrees celsius for
20 plus years 25 years and sometimes
germinated at like 80 90
so seeds if they're stored properly and
consistently they can last a long time
and it's like i got like i got a ton of
those blueberry seeds still left from
from the dj projects and people like
yeah but they're all seeds but dude i
can pull [ __ ] the grapefruit sweet
skunk out and pop 10 of them and i'll
pan in them
right like doesn't matter how old the
[ __ ] seed is if it germinates right
yeah exactly
obviously some people think differently
but
was there any skunk two in that
population of uh stuff that he had saved
skunk ii wasn't from sam
oh it wasn't no you know where was that
from i don't know somebody else came
along and made it up i don't think he
ever produced one called skunk too he um
i remember there was some kind of quote
somewhere about him talking about how
skunk 2 was the
the skunkier version
he didn't work the skunkier version
that's the thing he was like i don't
like it i'm watching that
yeah
yeah i wonder where i read that i'll
have to go back and look there's a lot
of stuff that gets attributed to sam i
mean it's like again the whole thing
about him in the dea like all this [ __ ]
is attributed to him that's just not
even true there's little specks of like
roots of truth
somebody took and blew up into this big
weird story and you know
misinterpreted it um it's because he's
mr mystery i think you know like he's
like he's an enigma you're not wrong
that doesn't help but again like i think
after like i think if you were treated
the way that he's been treated in the
cannabis community
look i mean it's like the same thing
that happened with me in the my brain
for that work that ended up being
patented it's like everybody [ __ ]
turns on you
yeah right um
and you know people like i said
everywhere everywhere he went it was
like the you know the whole dutch scene
the reason that people started calling
him dea
was that he was able to come into a
country that wasn't his he's not [ __ ]
dutch he went to holland as an american
expat
and was able was able to get
um
no i didn't say rooting hormone i said
hormones for plant tissue culture so
rooting hormones not the same
um some of the [ __ ] that they use for
plant tissue culture can cause mutations
but that's yeah
um but anyway sam was able to go into
holland set up set up business get a
license to grow cannabis from the
government nobody else could do it
yeah and so of course all the dutch
dudes were [ __ ] choked right they
were like how is this not this isn't
fair this guy's got all this [ __ ] right
yeah absolutely he must have some
context that we don't have what the [ __ ]
like the dea is an american organization
why the hell would the dea
go to the government of a different
country and say hey you got to let this
america grow weed in your country that
doesn't make any [ __ ] sense like
that's a stupid [ __ ] assumption right
that's the story that some dutch
reporter guy came up with and he used to
have a written cannabis radio show and
he spared them all over the airwaves and
now it's [ __ ] true for half the world
right wow is that where it came from is
that where all this started yeah
well it started
as a rumor but that's when it like got
popularized yeah never never remember
meeting scott at one point in time
shanti baba and he was like oh yeah dave
watson blah blah blah and i was like
dude you've been [ __ ] fed uh
you you've been saying [ __ ] i was my
natural lies by [ __ ] neville and all
these other guys right we're jealous and
haters right
neville i mean neville told me directly
that he
knew sam's dea handler everybody knew
his handler you not [ __ ] know what
you're talking about you just spent
nonsense and you came in late like i'm
just gonna ignore your [ __ ] questions
so let's move on
um
yeah like whatever dude like
yeah it's it's it just told you this
factuality that's like people want to
[ __ ] question you without even
knowing like an iota of the [ __ ]
truth yeah bro but didn't you know it
was going to be patented i actually
didn't i was [ __ ] making medicine for
patients dumbass okay
and that's what my intentions are the
[ __ ] company that i was working with
at the time that i was employed by that
were allowing me to [ __ ] like have my
dream cannabis job and build a [ __ ]
multi-million dollar laboratory to play
in
right like yeah it's a job but it's also
a job that i wanted to do one of the
consequences that these guys came out
and patented a bunch of uh
a
a class of plants that didn't exist
before i made them
yeah so it's like how the hell people
like you can complain
is ridiculous like you you obviously
have no idea what you're talking about
and are spouting an opinion
of like from a place of complete
ignorance so like yeah i do have to
laugh and the reason i'm emotional about
it and i'm clearly irritated is because
i [ __ ] got death threats from people
like you yeah i know right yeah
i went after you i went after you
after me right i did yeah
yeah i didn't have the full i didn't
have the full picture and no one did and
that's that's the problem you know
no one had the full picture we just went
off of uh oh my god patent this guy's
[ __ ] with the man
listen our community was bred to believe
that right yeah yeah they'd be very
conspiratorial they're bad like dude i
knew research scientists that worked at
gw pharmaceuticals like doing petri dish
work and experimental design and like
these guys would have the same
experiences that you and i would have
taking care of mary's nephew with
epilepsy down the street right they
would have personal relationships with
like these kids that couldn't get access
to cannabis and they would come in
and because of gw pharmaceuticals that
was doing the work with cannabis they
were allowed they were able to get
access to the medicine they needed to
change their life right so i like big
pharma or not i can't [ __ ] have i
don't have a problem with that like if
you're helping people
in like a context again they're
operating in the context of prohibition
where like these medicines can't get to
the people i made a post today about
marinol
right yeah somebody's chirping me about
marijuana like oh no it's made by in a
laboratory dude a molecule as a molecule
is a molecule like
if you're [ __ ] starving for water you
don't care whether that water was made
from like burning fossil fuels or mixing
hydrogen
and oxygen in a laboratory or purifying
it out of [ __ ] [ __ ] sewer water like
once it comes out at the end and it's
pure [ __ ] water it's water
right so it's the same with thc and it's
the same with cbd
right like if those medicines can go to
someone that can benefit from those
medicines that they couldn't access
otherwise
why the hell do you have a problem with
it
right like yeah i don't get it
right and i know that it comes because
they're not in the place where it's like
you feel like oh the government's not
letting you you you do your art and and
grow the crop that you want to grow you
know what the result is dude go change
the laws and like we've been fighting
for that
hard for [ __ ] 30 40 plus years
right but i've been involved for 30
years
right and um
i founded a political party in canada i
was a farming member of the the
the federal marijuana party in canada
right i didn't know that that's pretty
cool like
to effectuate change so it's like i get
that you're pissed off
and you're scared of big pharma but you
have to [ __ ] direct that anger in a
channel that's going to change things
not just sit there and [ __ ] about big
business because it's boring
right it's like it's boring
and big business is going to happen
whether we like it or not we're seeing
that in the cannabis world regardless
it's going to happen it happens i want
to change cannabis in the few years that
i have left on this [ __ ] floating
rock okay yeah so if you think i'm not
going to take a job where someone pays
me a decent salary and gives me like a
multi-million dollar budget to [ __ ]
grow and make class that the world has
never seen before yeah i'm gonna do it
okay yeah you don't like it too [ __ ]
bad
yeah right
i like seeing the passionate side yeah
like i mean i get offended by it right
because it's like oh yeah of course you
have people that don't know what the
hell they're talking about
and it's like they're spouting that off
as if their ignorant perspective
is like
like one valuable but like too supremely
valuable like they think that they're
right it's like dude yeah go look up the
dunning-kruger effect okay
yeah yeah you know a little bit you know
a little bit and think that you know
everything right try learning a lot and
then things like you know you know
anyway whatever there's too much of that
in the cannabis industry and you know
i'm i'm all up for raising everybody up
i would love to
and that's why we do these things we
share perspective we teach people
because we want you all to be better so
that you all can go and raise the
[ __ ] game and when we all raise the
game the cannabis is better the products
are better the products are safer and
we're all dabbing out on the dankest
[ __ ] [ __ ] right like that's what
exactly
that's why i i i find it a an honor when
anybody anybody uses my stuff
because it means that it was good enough
in their eyes
to take forward and make better and and
the resulting factor that is if they
make something better than i made i
don't let that intimidate me i want to
go work with that like that's what and
that's exciting they truly are making it
better but the thing i don't like is
when people like they actually hack
apart your work and then they tell
everybody it's better it's like and then
they sell it as whatever your strain is
and then that's that i did today contact
and he's like hey man i want like uh i'm
interested in this kind of high and i'm
looking at your
highland mexican blueberry
um
and i'm like i want to buy a hundred
seeds i was like oh you only buy a
hundred seeds i'm not excited because
he's buying a hundred seeds and it's
like yeah because he wants to pop a
bunch i want him it was like it's like
dude if you're gonna put in 100 grow
effort or 100 seed effort into
improving the line let me help you right
yeah and it's like i would die this line
and i would you know and i'm going to
throw in this line extra so that you've
got it
so that as you're in breeding this one
you should put a little bit of this back
into it so that you know
you don't you don't suffer inbreeding
depression and they've got the same
traits and it's got some nice flavor
stuff so
you know in the end you'll be you'll be
able to
build it better i love that i'm stoked
on that right yes absolutely in a five
pack and then knocking off open
pollination of five seeds to me
because it's like you're not i went to a
lot of work to create that population
and now you've essentially put it
through bottleneck and you're selling at
the same thing that's [ __ ] up right
like yeah so please do
take my [ __ ] make better
like you make better i will support you
if you take my yes and you [ __ ] knock
it into crap then i'm not going to be
happy
yeah right like that's kind of the way i
feel about it it's like i look at them
like my kids you know what you mean
yeah of course you know
you you want your babies to go off to
good homes
right
um and have happy marriages and all that
kind of [ __ ]
so
yeah i totally agree on that can you
tell us a little bit about the highland
mexican too since we just brought that
up these were old seeds that came to me
through rabbit legends actually someone
shipped them to him
and it was some old dude that was like
yeah i'm old i've been growing for years
and years i collected these things in
the 60s and 70s
and i don't
know you know i don't know what's gonna
i don't i don't i know i don't have the
ability to do something with them can
you please give them something that did
so we got some and i grew a whole bunch
and found a really interesting plan
yeah and i put well i had one i was like
i'm gonna take this one plant and put it
in the flowering room
and it was you know it was like a real
equatorial right so yeah you put it in
it gets to like a foot tall and you're
like oh this thing is going to really
stretch so you cut it down and make four
or four shoots
and yeah this thing dude it was like
twice as tall and wide as any other
plant in the room and it must have
produced like
i don't know it wasn't they were in like
the many thousands of these like it was
like you know probably i bet
because the whole thing just like the
whole it was these long
you know the old kind of like long spear
flowers that you'd see in the 70s not
too thick but like really yeah long
running
it was like that just chopped full of
seeds
uh it had a nice high effect it was like
i we weren't analyzing turps back then
but i in memory i would say that it's
probably like a lyman interpreter lyman
pining plant which is interesting it's
kind of rare in today's profile world
yeah i think that's what was really
associated with a lot of the old hazes
and interesting
it was just nice but it was nice classic
non
like it was not popular but so when i
released those dj joint projects
yeah i put some of those out there
and i don't think we sold a pack for
like 18 months
because they were like oh you know
everybody wanted the grapefruit
blueberry and the mental floss and all
the the plants that were like
getting yield
and then finally somebody decided to
grow a couple of those like in an
equatorial climate and ordered some of
those and grew them
and they were just
i mean they're
they have the ugliest phenotype flower
female oh i'm sure yeah
like long spindly weird like
you know like buds that have like they
look like they've got like five or six
fox tails coming out of them just two
calories
right and they'd look it would look like
a finger it wouldn't look like a hand
with a bunch of things i remember seeing
them yeah
yeah and you could take them like just
rip off calyx and essentially fold the
paper around that right
right but it was a great nice effect
um in doing those crosses and actually
growing dj stuff i
i don't i'm not
i don't have proof that this is the way
it is but it's definitely my very strong
feeling
is that all those introspective and like
i don't say uh but like
cerebral kind of highs that you get from
thc and this is largely from running all
dj stuff through that really expensive
lab that we built
like in population
most of it's in the 8 to 12 percent
range
yeah right it's not [ __ ] 25 but
yeah exactly low cannabinoid production
what we would call today low can have a
life correction plan
yeah but
when you whack up 30 to like 28 25 28 30
percent thc
you start to really get that stoned kind
of lethargic kind of dull effect where
it's like
all the sheen has been taken off of like
a high and you just kind of feel it in
your head and you're just
like kind of whacked and stoned that's
yeah dhc
right and if you take a marinol pill you
actually feel the same way i bet right
it kind of feels like somebody flooded
you in the head with something you know
like wacky yeah
um
and you don't get that from
those 12 percenters or those 10
percenters now you can kind of get a
nice floaty buzz but it's like it's
enough that you're affected but you're
just kind of in a different headspace
and yeah i i think they're headed high
well and for you know like the folks in
rob's generation dave's generation
that's i'm not saying rob and dave in
particular but like
people of that age that's what cannabis
was when they were growing up and what
they had access to right that was like
he didn't come across like a cookies
back in the 70s it didn't exist no no of
course now
so
um
you'd be but you'd be buzzed right but
it's a different headspace and so that
whole generation not that whole
generation but the majority of that
generation fell in love with that
experience and then sure
indica and 20 plus percent cannabis came
along it was too much for them because
it didn't do that same thing that they
wanted
right and i you know when someone was
talking about when the basket's full
stuff with thca
you're you're kind of right but it's
like you know dj for example like music
with lsd
right
and so
maybe the basket's not full with you
don't want to fill the basket with thc
because when you're putting lsd and thc
in it together
in moderate amounts like it's a more
pleasant effect at least for him
yeah this is all about perception so
um
it's just you know i it's an interesting
thing because essentially what's
happened now
is that like market with a 10 or a 12
flower good [ __ ] luck
yeah the market consumers retailers
distributors are all going to laugh at
you yeah totally arguably there's a
whole class of people out there
that would like that
oh for sure right for sure it's kind of
like saying hey we're gonna have liquor
stores we're only gonna sell things that
are like 25 and above percent alcohol it
gets rid of all beer all wine
all
you know like coolers and all that kind
of stuff that's a huge amount of like
alcohol consumers or the people that
like those products that they don't want
to sit down with a bottle of whiskey and
like do shots or chugs or get exactly
right
so in a way
we're doing the market in the service
and we're doing consumers uh the service
what's up vessel
um
yeah so i don't know like i don't you
know twenty people like up to ten
percent twelve percent but this guy
likes twelve percent budwood [ __ ] you
know yeah hey man like
not everybody's like you like some
people wanna drink light beer
right yeah i don't like getting baked
stoned at all
i just don't i like to be able to if i
have to react to something i want to be
able to react as fast as possible you
know what i mean at any point
yeah
yeah well people are saying it's like
you know every not everybody wants that
some people don't want older weed older
people usually and it's true
but maybe like you know we could teach
people how to use cannabis in a way that
some people might not want
uh like even if you're a teenager right
and dude i've seen it with friends like
i've seen them friends that like they
start smoking a little weed and then
they're like yeah it's fun and then they
get into it and they start smoking more
and they're [ __ ] way too bad right
and it
doesn't like it impacts their life in a
negative way
yeah right so and so i want more people
using cannabis
if they got to smoke something that's
like you know half cbd and half thc or
even just mostly with a little bit of
thc in it like you know five percent tfc
i don't care like i think that we should
make cannabis for all people
um i do too market when we've got the
market that is this way it just it's not
a good thing for the for it's not a good
thing for consumers
you know there there are
scientific studies that show like mass
consumption of thc for at least some
people is not a good thing
yeah and so what do we say oh sorry you
guys you don't get to just you just
you're not allowed to benefit from this
plan
yeah
right it's like well hey how about i can
make you something that does matter
about a variety that i developed out of
napro for the with the beta carotene and
the cbdv
right it was like i was like
that plant had no recreational potential
at all like it was not fun for anybody
right but it was going to make a
difference in some three-year-old's life
right
and his mom isn't going to be able to
like give him this [ __ ] and he's not
going to have like 10 seizures a day
that felt really [ __ ] good dude right
being able to make that plant it felt
really really really good like i can't
tell you
the way i can imagine i was more proud
of that plant in a way
than any high thc plant that i've ever
made that like has like a thousand more
people using it or yeah like 10 000
people smoking it right
um
so yeah i'm all about making all types
of cannabis for all types of people
and uh just because it's the one that
like the majority of people doesn't like
that doesn't mean that it's not an
amazing thing right
so yeah we gotta we gotta make those
plans right which is yeah that's what
somebody was saying about like oh go
work for this company big bad company
man
i'm not trying to help [ __ ] rich
people get richer
right i'm gonna [ __ ] make medicines
for patients or provide plants for for
patients to change people's lives
yeah you either get it or you don't
right
but that's the way i look at it and
everybody's gonna you know your people
are gonna look at what i'm saying from
another perspective and say maybe it's
[ __ ] so whatever all i can tell you
is my truth
yeah
well i just want to thank you because
you know you're you guys like you red dj
are all major
major factors in in the path of my
career as a seed maker and the few
breedings i've done you know so thank
you guys for for establishing that that
path you know before me to try to try to
push the boundaries with blueberry and
and i still love your guys stuff it
still holds its own today
even with all the stuff around that was
popular in the market but i mean i grew
some of that [ __ ] out recently it's
every bit as good as a lot of the other
stuff
i could give a [ __ ] about the market i
mean
especially right now i mean the the seed
markets crashed uh cannabis markets
crashed like right now the people that
are gonna stick through it are the
people that were always gonna stick
through it whether they were making
money or not so
i'm looking forward to that at least
shaking out some of the [ __ ] [ __ ] and
that's about all the good that's gonna
come from it but well i gotta leave
something that dave said you know dave
watson sam says it's like we all stand
on the shoulders of giants
right
um all of us everybody that works with
cannabis we all got those seeds from
somewhere except for greatest people he
invited cannabis so
that's the difference
yeah we got to respect the people that
we got things from and you know
all all of us in our germ pleasant that
we have in our hands it all comes from
somewhere
right and sure maybe maybe we refined it
a little bit maybe we found some better
plants and we propagated and changed
around
but all of us are
beholden to the people that came before
us
absolutely absolutely
well i want to thank you for stopping by
thank you for eliminating us on uh the
testing stuff i've learned a lot myself
like i that is something i've been very
ignorant in is when it comes to testing
and lab testing and stuff so i i really
appreciate your time and thank you and i
can't wait to have you back on my
pleasure thanks for having me and and
listen if there's more questions that we
didn't answer about lab testing hit up
matter hit up myself and we'll address
it on ig or we'll do it again or yeah
we'll do it again and clutch it up so
is there anything um you want to you
want to say before we go like as far as
where to get your seeds for people in
canada anything like that breeders
retail well unfortunately even canada is
a [ __ ] show for seeds because the
legalization so breeders retail you want
our seeds
reach out to me and i'll hook you up
with the breeders retail boys and we'll
get you taken care of
and uh yeah keep growing seeds
support people like matt support the
real ones in the industry
you know we
we gotta eat too right yeah
yeah and it's like it's not like i'm
choosing new leather for the lamborghini
you know anything like really like the
seed industry is not what it was
everybody in the same business is uh is
hurting in a way that i don't think
people really understand so definitely
support those dudes that you can
someone's asking on cunning folk company
i sold mc's they've not seen for me so
they're good folks
good deal and their stock is powered
and let's throw a shout out to red
because that guy's [ __ ] amazing i
love that dude listen red is one of the
realest [ __ ] people i've ever met in
my life he is for 20 years
and he is one of the most high integrity
individuals that i've ever met in my
life
and he is absolutely a real one so
uh yeah he's got a new project out of uh
victoria british columbia on the island
and they got to grow there and so
i think they're gonna hopefully they'll
be doing some of your stuff
yeah yeah and uh yeah we got some good
things lined up for them so
listen anybody in the industry that's
one of the good guys support them it's
like you know we run businesses
i i think i'm sure there's some people
driving lamborghinis but the truth is
that the vast majority of us aren't
yeah it's like we're you know we're just
trying to get by like everybody else so
definitely please grow seeds and support
the people in the industry that you
uh
that you like their content and that you
know you respect their ethic
so and i got to tell you one thing
that's live is like you know matt
mentioned that uh
we had a little bit of a falling out or
a rough patch over the patent thing i
respect matt you know
we he came to me i explained to him my
position on the whole thing
and he recognized that
you know he didn't have the story right
and he's been like more than uh
forthcoming about that
and
to me like that's all you can do like
look we're humans we're going to make
mistakes everybody's going to make
mistakes recognizing the mistakes and
coming and saying hey i did the wrong
thing to me that means everything and
he's a he's a broke life because of it
right so
yeah same here now yeah
yeah thanks for having me
absolute pleasure i'll talk to you soon
and thank you for stopping by yeah much
love to your viewers you guys all have a
good evening
peace
cheers guys