welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate what's up everyone welcome to
R Syndicate I'm Matthew and this is my
near and dear friend Chucky pollins
blowing it up what's up guys gals so
this is second attempt we thought we
were live when it started it didn't
really work out so well trying not to to
cuss super fast so we'll see how that
goes what's
up so tell me about tell me about your
weekend or your week well I wanted to
say thanks for everybody tuning in last
episode it's pretty cool being on the
show and finally getting some you know
credit for what credits do I wanted to
ask you before we get started because
you didn't give me opportunity before we
started uh are you are you sending me a
check for last episode or I I we'll talk
about it after this but we'll talk about
it after this yeah yeah you do need
obviously need paid for your hard work
yeah I was just want to say thanks for
all the support got a lot of haters in
my DMs too talking about I don't know
what the hell I'm talking about I'm a
bum and all this crap and to all y'all I
love y'all very much but we didn't cover
the q&amp;as last time the whole point of
the show last time Matt was was the
questions and answers so if you're we're
live guys gals if you got questions drop
them in the little the chat I can't see
the chat for some reason Matt but drop
them for Matt in the chat and we're
gonna go over some questions from the
Discord as well that we didn't cover
last time and we got some new ones as
well
today so all right well you know I was
wondering did you get any naughty
pictures I got a couple mainly dude's
balls ball okay here here's the thing
guys you gonna send me the ball picks
lift the sack so I could see the the the
you know the the TPA my I used to work
with this guy he called Everything well
maybe we shouldn't say that on YouTube
actually well yeah yeah I digress but
got butthole pictures got some guys
wanting to do some collabos you know
yeah and it's great because I'm trying
to break in and and drop my seed drops
on you guys you know and it's great and
uh I got some big projects in the works
you know uh stuff like that uh you know
uh but mainly yeah a lot of lot of ball
pictures stuff like that but uh you know
do you appreciate those are you a fan
of I me that's the mo over this
weekend's the most balls and and butth
holes I've seen since being locked up so
it's it took me back to a place maybe
that really isn't a positive state of
mind you know mom's always telling me
like keep your head high just like you
did bro before I went in jail that's
right stay positive you know you know me
I get honed in on that [ __ ] that ADHD
[ __ ] like oh [ __ ] I get in on it and I
get on Instagrams and I start making
posts like like non-stop post and [ __ ]
bro like when I when I when [ __ ] ain't
going my way like when you when you say
[ __ ] to me sometimes like you know I get
wild on Instagram but you know I'm just
I'm just want I just want to say praise
God you know I'm holding my head up and
yeah just I'm glad to be here Matt I'm
glad to to you know be here on the show
praise His name praise His name hell
yeaha so I see this hat you have on what
what is this hat well I had a lot of
haters in my chat last time saying I
don't know dly [ __ ] about nothing but I
figure you know I'm one of you guys I'm
trying to I'm one of y'all Matt I'm here
to shine the light on the game where the
light needs to be shined on you see what
I'm saying we got we got three stages
bro anyways but yeah that's ni you let's
get into some of these questions enough
about me I think people you know had
enough of me last week ranting let's get
in these questions man like I said if
you got some questions drop them in the
mother can we cuss Now Matt I I mean
yeah I think so I think we're gonna
probably get blocked no matter what just
because of you [ __ ] all right let's
getting these questions if you got some
questions drop them in the chat we'll
try to hit them as we go but first let's
start off with little cabin in the hood
he says if you could pick one for the
rest of your life what would it be Kim
Sour OG typer or H OG tyer um
I'll let you answer first on this what
what would you pick I mean it seems
obvious to Me
Maybe Kim bro what the I mean that
wouldn't expect any less I mean what the
[ __ ] kind of waste our times with these
question no but you go ahead Matt what
would you pick I'd probably go OG typer
OG typer because I can go back and get
some Bubba out of it if I uh S1
it get whatever want hell yeah I like
the typers you know I would probably
pick OG typers this second I gotta rock
out for the Kim yeah hope you're having
a chilling chillaxing Friday Piner says
I hope y'all are
too straight out of Michigan Chucky the
[ __ ] pins okay let's move on squirrel
says when you got the real dog the real
d a real high flower Haze W pop
seeds good question you know I think at
the end of the day if you're growing and
you
know I think it's a really important to
always pop seeds if you got the space
for it I mean me personally I like to
find the the new stuff when I can or I'm
looking for that new thing uh you know
it does get boring cropping out the same
[ __ ] over and over let's be real I mean
it's fun for a couple Cycles maybe but
you know it's like a treasure hunt man
you know you look out over that
beautiful Horizon you think like like is
the grass greener over there you know
what I'm saying like always yeah what if
I pop these seeds you know some of the
best [ __ ] in the world was created by
accident so I think to myself like if I
pop these seeds maybe you know I find
something cool I think it's also you
know when you're talking about like the
breeder Syndicate some of these guys
they make seeds so being able to pop
some of their work you know be some of
the first people to check that out some
of these people like H&amp;L and and pop and
you know goat farm seeds and stuff like
that you know they they really know
their [ __ ] they have a lot of experience
in making seeds and working with
genetics and and have a lot of cuts and
let's be real like I'm Chucky the [ __ ]
pollins I don't know what the [ __ ] I'm
doing so I really you know I look to
them guys to kind of guide my hand in it
where I'm going maybe not my to my
destination but just uh you know you
know it's fun to pop seeds who don't
like the pop seeds what the [ __ ] what
kind of question is yeah I mean you know
we could you could also talk about
sharing clothes and sometimes it's like
trying to share your
cousin you can get those diseases that
pass back and forth between you and your
friends real fast yeah viruses STDs
viruses yeah what have you I got cold
sords out the yin gang I don't need no
more [ __ ] exactly yeah that shit's rough
man um yeah no really it's a it's a real
thing so you you're you're likely to
find you know the Hops slat and vroid in
seed pops um we don't really know the
seed transmission rate but it is a lot
less than playing with clones so yeah
there is that yeah I mean there's that I
mean that we I mean you know just as
well as me Matt I mean just in the last
few months I've seen a few cases of of
diseases and viruses and stuff like that
so it's like it ain't a joke you guys
don't [ __ ] around with these clones
dropping 300 400 00,000 on a [ __ ]
clone and then you get germs bro bugs
stuff like that I try to tell people if
you know if someone's selling you clones
it's very likely they're not in the
position to have the Clones that they're
selling or they would be kicked out of a
lot of these trade circles where those
clones exist um so if someone's doing
that it's usually like a last ditch
effort they're all out of money and
that's scary sending money to someone
who's all out of money because you never
know what their the Jam's going to be
y yeah it's just a lot of people making
false scarcity on their Elite selections
and usually there's Elite selections are
a seed pop of three maximum yeah there's
always that it's it's like you tell me
Matt and you give great advice you said
there's only like a handful of people to
have access to most of the Clones out
there bro so it's
like are you really do you really got
what you think you got or do you just
get scammed you know what I mean like
yeah you know it's math bro you probably
got scammed yeah there were a lot of
people buying the jel cut off of a an
individual and um I got so many messages
about that and it was it was bummer
because every single time I'd have to be
like bro I hate to break it to you and I
was always the bearer of bad news you
know so I don't like doing that so don't
be don't be spending stupid money on
clones go pop some seeds yeah again they
are very rare clones it's very rare a
clone is like dog [ __ ] where everybody
that smokes it kind of universal degrees
they dig it it's very very rare and
that's why I could pull that out of the
air because I mean even jel there's a
lot of people who don't like jel because
it Herms and it's a pain in the ass so
you know just because I like it don't
mean you will right yeah I mean dude
just pop seeds that's all it is there
you go anyway and and to put you know to
put a put a period on that there's so
many good there's not so many I should
say there's there's a solid core of
people especially like in the Discord
that that are making cool [ __ ] so it's
like I don't know why not pop their
stuff dude and they're working with a
lot of the Clones that people are hyped
about anyway so it's like yeah [ __ ] I
want to see some new cool [ __ ] anyways
get them from someone vetted yeah say
the least uh PX
says uh also or he says what is the can
Illuminati anyways oh [ __ ] I guess for
new people watching they don't know what
the that you they hear you saying can
Illuminati be a part of it sit at the
table and they don't even know what can
Illuminati might be yeah I I
I I only thing they need to know about
the can Illuminati is that the Don is
Denali that's it it's all they need to
know yeah it's like Fight Club bro yeah
you know what what is Fight Club I don't
know yeah clue never heard of it he says
also says I'm assuming he's talking to
me possibly you he says tell us how you
feel about meeting your Heroes yeah it
wouldn't be me
My
Heroes uh you got to meet some you got
to go on one of the trips this the
secret trips I got to go secret I got to
go on a secret trip all my jelly little
haters out there probably wish it was
him but it was me and I'm sorry so don't
shed no tears for me it'll be all right
I'll Pat you on the back and hold you
real tight kiss you on the forehead tell
you everything's gonna be all right no
uh you know I appreciate uh you know
through some let's just say some good
luck I was able to get on one of the
little can Illuminati trips little
secret meetups was super cool shout out
to the people that got me on there they
know who they are they're really the
dudes that keep the Discord and the
breeder Syndicate together and they
invited me on this trip where I got to
meet I think it was like eight other
dudes seven I can't count bro I was [ __ ]
I was [ __ ] up the whole trip but I
can't share a lot but I will say that uh
Rob Clark was there the man the legend
uh got to meet him party out with him a
little bit dude he rocks out he he could
party just like a young cat that was
cool I mean dude just getting us spend
time with people that have more
experience than me you know and and and
a you know I've been locked up in the
majority of my life so it's like I can't
call myself a real grower or anything
Bro Other than maybe a Smuggler you know
so be around these guys was a dream come
true and little fanboyish maybe but hey
I suck dick I don't care you know right
[ __ ] I'm not afraid to admit it but
anyways yeah it was awesome dude getting
to try some good buds grown by the the
the hand that made the buds the genetics
I mean it was awesome dude you couldn't
ask for a better trip I mean we got to
fish we got to smoke Good Good Buds I
got to try a bunch of hazes I got to lay
in bed for three [ __ ] hours a night
wondering like where my life is it
because I smoke too much Band-Aid Haze
and I'm like everything's flashing I
can't get to sleep smoked some of uh
hnls electric mango Haze or whatever man
that [ __ ] has same effect got me I had
some Rank Stranger off camera right here
Matt seen it so he knows I ain't [ __ ]
lying I was gonna show it but he says
you know that's what gets these shows
banned so we we're on the mush pot we're
on a thin rope right now let's just say
that
we [ __ ] ropes
yeah you want the show to continue don't
be asking for the menu anyways but yeah
it was a great trip bro got them you
know felt super corny getting them uh
robbed aside my my books but I got him
to sign my books yeah that's corny
pretty corny he gave us some sweet uh
artwork from like labels from the lbs
back in the day dude pretty cool um yeah
man it was a great trip dude once in a
lifetime opportunity
it's
great yeah uh meeting my heroes I think
um I think in the weed world it's been
rather lackluster um some people like
hyen Lon first time I met him I mean he
was already a good friend by that time
but um getting to meet him was special
there there are several people that have
been quite quite amazing when we get to
meet him and uh not disappointments but
guys like DJ Short um he told me that I
didn't even own my own company he's like
oh I think someone else owns your
company I'm pretty sure and it was a
nice dude that he was referring to but I
was like no that's uh that's that's mine
pretty sure pretty sure the only one
that
um pry sure I'm the only one that uh
owns this a horrible company so yeah I
don't think people would take credit for
it but yeah you know and trying to talk
to him about his strains it became
evident that he wasn't at least at that
day that time he wasn't too into talking
about anything having to do with his own
strains and I thought you know if
someone knows your lines this well would
see they put in the time and effort to
ask good questions you would respond but
yeah no he wasn't into it um did that
let you down at all bro I can't let me
down I was like dude I get to meet talk
to DJ Short spend time he's at my booth
and uh yeah no it was it was absolutely
horrible I got to meet NCGA North C GRS
Association he's a old school head for
back in the day and um he was cool
really cool shared he was the first
person to share a boo space with me at
Emerald cup so um there are times when
it's cool and there are times when it
really sucks so maybe you don't want to
say their name but what what's what's
one time maybe that you had an
impression of somebody in the game and
it ended up being the complete opposite
that you were like the coolest cat you
ever met in
life the coolest cat I ever met
um okay so
CSI right the first time I met him in
person we had already been at kind of I
don't want to say at odds but we didn't
talk to each other we weren't tight
that's for Hampshire and um I didn't my
impression of him was that he was
probably a conceited dick and you know
it was too cool for school so I walked
up to him I he was at the booth next to
me and I walked up to him just shook his
hand introduced myself and left and
after that we were best friends it was
uh it was weird yeah he ended up being
the coolest guy on Earth and not not a
conceeded dick at all quite the opposite
that's that's really cool bro he seems a
really cool I I'll be honest if it
wasn't for him I probably wouldn't even
know about like the breeder Syndicate
for real because he you know I've seen
him on a panel like years ago and kind
of when I got out of jail or whatever
and I just like i' had been locked up
for a minute or whatever a little bit
and uh you know I didn't I hadn't really
[ __ ] [ __ ] looked at the internet for
a while so I got on YouTube and I was
looking up weed stuff because you know
trying to trying to gain some knowledge
in the game trying to find you know shed
the light on on everybody know but I was
trying to figure out what was going on
and I seen in my little podcast and like
for some reason when I clicked his video
like the next time I got on YouTube your
[ __ ] face was right there I said
who's this dick and I started watching
you and that one guy which
one oh yeah yeah I'm not even 20 years
ago or whatever and uh no I just said
who
no but yeah I mean dude just like
getting out of jail and then seeing
like that's an aspect getting out of
jail seeing you guys [ __ ] talking
about [ __ ] that I grew up smoking and
smuggling and dabbling and and Kims and
sour and OG tyers and hazes I said [ __ ]
I think it's this bro I'm not good with
Mom these headphones suck dick what did
she get you I don't even know bro she
said she went to the dollar store and
got some [ __ ] of course it ain't
working right can y'all hear me
okay yeah now we can hear you the
headphones
suck she don't ever listen need to get a
better mom have you talked to any new
women in your life any new women in your
life Bro Other than them I mean some
girls they try to holler at me all the
time bro I'm a good guy yeah you know
what I'm saying they I mean bro they see
the gold gem shirt on and [ __ ] they know
what it's game time they know
Michigan like where you're at bro they
got gold I well I used to live in
California bro like like not on base but
like close to Camp Pendleton out there
bro like like really out there my my dad
was in a marine and uh he was out there
and he met my mom out there in the Navy
bro at a vending machine yeah yeah it's
so I used to live out there bro I don't
remember it but I was out there until I
was like three did your mom get a along
with the women in your
life not really bro I'll be honest I
wouldn't think so I wouldn't think so
keep on DL
bro get beat up around here women run
around anyways but yeah uh anyways we're
getting off crazy topics here bro you on
a rant well this is a weed podcast let's
let reeler back in a little bit let back
in okay uh let's see going through some
of these questions here uh guys you
putting on here some [ __ ] up questions
I wish I could read these on on
YouTubes do you think think weed will go
legal next year federally [ __ ]
no yeah I I doubt it it depends on who's
President and even then I doubt it until
they have it all lined up so they could
take it from the Mom and Pops that's how
I feel yeah they gota get both of them
yeah they gotta get their money first
bro both let's see how much dog guys I
can't even y'all are [ __ ] with me
right now I can't read all these dumb
questions on here y'all trying to get us
as canell they're in here saying
dirty um it says Uh George Jetson says
untopped or topped plants preference for
cropping versus breeding uh the plant
that got away oh I guess that's one
thing untp or top plants preference for
cropping versus breeding depends if it's
a squat little Afghan you don't top it
um
otherwise I mean for breeding you want
to have as many sites as you can get so
you can fill up uh all those nice little
bracks with seeds yeah so it just
depends uh and then the second part was
the plant that Got Away La the original
still what La what the LA a it was an
old Afghani one cut um from the LA Moon
posi tribe which was like uh electronic
DJ
crew um they were always he was the Ed
with it it came via them but it was a
old Afghani number one according to what
they said and it was just really dank it
was uh almost like ammonia so like when
you smell it it burn your nose hairs you
know um yeah it was one of my favorite
I'd like to see it people still uh pass
around to bubba cut that they call La
afy now but this was much different than
that that's cool man I guess
uh why are you see favorite blueberry
cross from appy Hills grower oh from the
crosses I guess the one you recently
dropped oh no you know what there's one
that I'm really looking forward to that
bidder just put out and it's going to be
probably in the in the patreon Discord
$50 tier packs when those go out next
probably two months I think um it's
going to be the Strawberry Cough blue
and cross I'm very looking forward to
that one only because you know
Strawberry Cough has a heavy Berry nose
to it too and uh different than
blueberry uh different genetic and
blueberry so I'm really excited about
that going to have some going myself
soon but those are going to be in the 50
tier for the people who are a part of
that yeah and maybe if there's new
people watching what's the 50 tier uh 50
tier that's when you're in the $50 a
month you get a pack a month for each
month that you're a part of it and
usually every three months we send out
the packages since yeah it's expensive
to send out [ __ ] 50 plus packages a
month yeah uh and also exclusive drops
and [ __ ] like that usually like if one
of the Breeders are in the Discord like
Pac or H&amp;L are working on stuff
sometimes they'll put their new stuff
you know or whatever y as well and you
get to see it before everyone else the
TGA stuff with CSI just uh was dropped
last time last round or it's like with
the competitions and [ __ ] that we're
working on uh with H&amp;L the the the ones
that we've been doing it's like he
released the k91 to the mango haes and
he he said he's probably not ever going
[ __ ] drop it ever bro so it's like
it's just cool [ __ ] like that if you
want to be in on the early stuff I guess
uh let's see here we got a couple of
ones here from biscuit flipper he says
origin story SLB background on the
sharing cut of white
widow maybe do you want me to keep
reading the rest of it because he's got
a bunch of stuff here he says I I I read
it was from lonar and it was and was was
wondering when it came about have a
buddy who's trying to track it down and
is wondering if it's the one he had up
near Dallas back in the mid 90s he might
just pay 500 for the cut if so okay so
first off I will say there's been some
debate about someone selling the cut I
won't say the the gentleman and gentle
woman's name but be careful who you buy
that [ __ ] from there is one for sale
that you can buy and it looks like a
[ __ ] Bubba cush cut that's not
[ __ ] Sharon Widow Sharon is really
[ __ ] ugly um really really hard to
grow you get the Leaf curl it's just
never [ __ ] happy big huge colas it's
not a short squat little Afghan not
super Frosty not really resinous um came
from Lone Star originally and you know
mid 2000s early early to mid 2000s out
of Texas I don't know what White Widow
cut what I don't think uh Lone Star was
passing that cut around openly so I
doubt it was just some cut someone got
as White Widow in Texas
very much doubt that um right now the
only person I know with it for sure is
crazy composer um he's got great
pictures of it up so if you want to see
the real Sharon Widow go check out his
Instagram um but yeah other than that
like I don't really know anybody passing
it around or selling it so don't go
buying cuts of Sharon Widow unless you
get it directly from composer or
something like that kind like we talked
about earlier bro yeah and then you
could fall back on the hlv stuff you
don't know what has what who's keeping
their rooms like separated who can
identify hlv in the first place so
yeah oh yeah I mean be careful guys keep
your sticks on the [ __ ] ice bro gosh
yeah anyways uh also this is from Chakra
Zula Zulu uh also when you guys speak on
I don't know why I said also un let
something also when you guys speak on
the open pollenating do you use one male
or multiple ones and if you use multiple
how do you go about moving forward or
back Crossing when you don't know who
the daddy is also speak on reversing of
males to
females okay so open pollinating means
you're taking every seed you have
hitting every so every male with every
female that's that's open and
pollinating um it's a good question like
uh how do you know when what Daddy was
it if you want to take it forward you
don't you go by traits um you won't know
what Daddy hit what so it's not like
saving clones of each one is advisable
uh of the males when you're doing an
open pollination because you can't just
think oh [ __ ] that was that made some
heat you know because you just won't
know um you could
do an open pollination and then also
take be very careful with the pollen
from each male and uh hit a clone of
each female if you want to go that way
that's also directional um yeah if you
want to work it forward you just work it
Forward by traits you don't work it
Forward by U what potential male hit
what potential female it's all about
trait work at that point um what was the
other question male male reversals onto
females
yeah um so people people have this weird
idea of reversals uh males don't if you
reverse a male it's not going to just
turn into an allout female like that
that's not really going to happen that's
not what it looks like it looks like uh
um a few BRS on a male like female on a
mail um making seeds with it it's a
novel fun idea but like there's I don't
really know anybody's ever found
anything in a male reversal usually
you're doing that just to check out any
traits any any visual or scent traits
from the male side so when you run the
progyny um of anything from that plant
uh in a not reversed portion you can see
the traits come through and you be like
okay this is from the mail because I saw
that in the turfs but it doesn't always
mean that those traits are going to pop
up just because you can identify them or
uh or you've witnessed them at one point
cool all right uh we got another one
from stone or stone Farm okay oh man the
[ __ ] pizza rolls mom made me killing
me bro how can I really tell the
difference between pistols Browning due
to pollination versus pistols Browning
sorry I'm a new grower if this is a dumb
question it's not a dumb question um I
mean it's just all depends on timing
right like if it's a week after you've
hit all the plants then you hope that
that's going to be from pollinating but
yeah they pistols Brown they die off
that they die off and yeah I think it's
actually stigmas not pistols but um yeah
I mean that's it's it's that and then
you know if it's pollinated you'll see
the bra slowly start to swell then
you'll know for sure yeah I mean you're
not pollinating at the end of a a a
plant's life cycle right when you're
going to be seeing brown browning hairs
or whatever anyways you're if you're
gonna be hitting something with pollen
you're usually doing it within you know
a week anywhere from depending on what
you're growing anywhere from like two to
like week four maybe even longer if
you're [ __ ] with other [ __ ] hazes and
longer flowering types but I mean you're
not there's so majority of the time all
the hairs are white so when you hit them
usually within a couple days depending
some some take a week some some are two
days you start seeing some kind of
coloration or or I'm dying back or what
or I guess a little bit but yeah it's
it's yeah
but uh all right yeah uh scrw we can't
answer or we can't we're trying to keep
this a good show bro we're trying we're
try not to get banned here bro or
whatever did Dan ask I I shouldn't ask
probably that's right guys drop some
likes drop some supports we appreciate
it there you go yeah we're live ask
questions too yeah ask questions if you
want you know whatever ask Matt you got
Matt here it's a rare opportunity also
while we're talking about these some of
these questions we've have been asked
before and I know some people tuning in
our big time [ __ ] big wiener experts
and are thinking these are little newbie
questions but guys we got new people
coming in every day we got to help them
on their on their Journey right so at
the end of the day I would recommend
though to new people go back and watch
the old episodes because you know a lot
of these questions are on the old
episodes guys just watch watch them it's
good that's a weird question I've never
heard this
term have you used doe design of
experiments to choose your males for
example have you have you have five
females and two males you hit each male
to complete set of females take Serious
pollen control yeah I don't play with
that I don't play with multiple male
unless I'm doing an open pollination and
that's only then I don't use more than
one male because yes takes serious
pollen control and pollen contamination
is it just doesn't take much so no I
only do one male to to females but then
again like there's there's one thing
that none of us ever really talk about
and it is what happens when a plant
Herms in a room in a room that you've uh
you know dusted with a male that that's
a question I got right so yeah here so
you're a breeder right you got you're
doing your little Chuck or whatever
reversal or whatever you're doing you
got a Herman there you realize after you
made all this seed at the end of the day
say you got a whole room full right you
realize at the end of the day as you're
going through these buds stuff you're
seeing maybe some little plant in the
corner that you didn't notice and she
hmed out and it's the pin's fertile
right at this point you don't know what
the [ __ ] you got money invested in I
know a lot most people are probably just
gonna send it right but like have you
ever experienced where you had to throw
it all away I mean maybe you're not
throwing away you're keeping it for
yourself and running it and just
checking and just see if you pick up
traits you know I guess and then at that
point you just carry it further to work
it or what would you do what do you how
do you handle that kind of stuff um you
know like I experienced that with the
[ __ ] Aussie bastard that little some
[ __ ] stuck in and it's so obvious
because those leaves are so obvious and
if it it's in the first round you know
it was from a Herm essentially because
it wouldn't show up if it was from the
uh you know I mean it's only if it was a
male um yeah those I just kind of pretty
much gave away or put on deep sale like
$20 a pack and let people know hey there
is pollen contamination that's about the
best you can do a [ __ ] like that or or
toss it one or the other um I would
imagine most people that make seeds
would just send it out because you know
you're going to get unless it's a
totally different line it'll be super
obvious which I've seen many times um
where those plants like a Girl Scout
cookies will end up in a pollination of
you know Bubba cross to OG or that's
kind of bad um like Bubba and blueberry
and all of a sudden you see some Girl
Scout cookies popping up you know
someone had a Girl Scout cookies Herman
there and just let it go you know but um
yeah ideally you'd hope they wouldn't
and that they would make it known but
that's not always what we see right yeah
I mean I goes both ways I guess I guess
from a new uh breeders perspective on
you know trying to get into the game or
whatever you want to call it the
industry you know if you it is your
ideally you've kind of built up to this
point but my I was just thinking yeah
like what if you are new and you are
trying to get into it and you do have a
a [ __ ] up how do you handle that you
know I guess maybe like you said just be
transparent as possible and let people
let them [ __ ] know what's up because
some of us are going to see that [ __ ]
and we're going to know we're gonna go
we know what that [ __ ] is you know bro I
I come from the game I'm just trying to
figure out how it works no uh I'm
smoking dude I got some of this Irene S1
from uh CSI bro I'm smoking it's [ __ ]
nice bro it's not like the craziest
potency in the world or nothing but the
turs everything are on point bro Irene's
nice it's a very nice Cut Great gu I
like it uh another
olds oh yeah yeah he says is a is SDS or
colloidal silver better for creating
reversals I don't use colloidal silver
that's an old technique um I don't know
anybody who uses it effectively for um
yeah I just don't know anybody who uses
Cal silver anymore it was an old
technique on the forums people would
talk about mostly um there's been
science papers where they use STS and
put it against clal silver it's found to
not be as effective and so we just went
straight for STDs with my spray which
you can find on sale right now on
riot.com I was gonna plug Ito boom you
see that yeah that's good bro yep um
there I'm assuming there's other stuff
people have used in in the past too and
maybe even currently uh to to maybe
cause the reverse reversal is there
anything else you could kind of talk
about yeah um um um um um cobalt
chloride is another one um that's been
used by
Hyde um yeah I guess that's a secret I
don't [ __ ] it know um yeah cobal
chloride are using just silver without
the th without the Tho sufate th sulfate
helps a lot with um what's it called
light toxicity I'll just say that
because I'm not gonna [ __ ] use a big
word right here um yeah cool yeah the
Cobalt chlorid is another good one hell
yeah burn the [ __ ] out your plants
though so if you need a plant there's
some plants like like TK that you almost
have to kill to reverse to get it to
drop pollen um whereas a lot of other
plants you want them at Peak health and
don't want them to be burned so yeah his
is in Chlor yeah no his his Cobalt green
Cobalt green if I remember correctly
that's what we ended up uh running with
but yeah cobalt chloride is another one
that you can use I just buy my mat Riot
spray and I'm done dude done done Farm
got a spray too
got and farmer Dan too shout out get him
selling it yeah yeah hell yeah dude uh
that's cool man uh we move on to aie
Dragon he says or they say she says
whatever thems maybe I don't know hell
uh did you ever get any of those Alaskan
blueberry Rob mention in the video and
if so are you planning on breeding with
them I didn't
I don't know that Rob still has access
to that but we have um there's another
cut that's made it back in the circle
that's the Dabney blueberry that I
really want to work with again cool hey
do you ever sit on a [ __ ] bro and
you're just sitting there thinking I
know you you've been talking about
moving on from maybe a blueberry lines
and stuff a little bit but do you ever
sit on the [ __ ] or and you're
thinking like what if there is one more
out there that I didn't know I didn't
get to try or one more out there maybe I
can constantly constantly constantly
dude constantly
hey I mean that's cool dude I I I I
appreciate that you so into blueberry
lines that we have to have somebody that
is you know what I'm saying because if
it was like you gotta carry the torch
bro I think it's cool DJ Short you know
kind of he brought the the blueberry to
the table I think there might have been
other blueberries before him right um
but there for a lot of people including
myself there was a lot of disappointment
in buying a really expensive pack of
seeds called blueberry to not find one
thing that was blue blueberry like T
twise or taste um yeah I mean you know
like I I think most people had that
experience um but then there was some
great BC blueberries um from the BC era
guys working with blue
um yeah I don't know I mean I've crossed
it to a lot of stuff but like I could
always run more of each of the things
that I've crossed it to and there's a
few more that I'd like to go through I
just found another pack of poodle nuts
today which is I thought i' had given
the very last of those to um
little Hill and he popped him and he was
stoked on it and I was like oh [ __ ] that
does look amazing he's like yeah this is
the best out of the poodle nuts but I
didn't save any Cuts so now I'm like oh
[ __ ] but I did find I found the very
last pack so I'm like I think it's the
last pack who [ __ ] knows but um yeah
you got like that's how I am dude I find
like random packs just like that I
thought I didn't have any more of or or
whatever I I dude something I wanted to
before I forget I'm [ __ ] scatter
brain right now bro uh something is cool
we talking about earlier about clones
and [ __ ] and it made me think like why
the [ __ ] what uncertain stuff especially
uh you know trying your ex out it made
me realize like man I don't need no cut
of this when I could just have it in a
regular form bro a regular SE form it's
so cool like that I only popped the one
pack and every female that I I got was
some form of blue or blueberry or or
blueberry jam or blueberry candy or some
kind of mix of that and uh like like I
said said the other day going like two
months in bro and it still smells just
like the blueberry bro it smells great I
got them in the jar right here bro
that's awesome yeah I mean the idea with
the the incross line was
consistency um to have consistency in a
in a seed pop like ideally I think even
as new seed buyers we think you know
we're going to go buy a pack of seeds it
says it's like this specific thing they
always say oh yeah it's exactly like
this we pop those seeds and we don't get
that I mean that's pretty you know uh
and yeah like that as a seed buyer from
when I started to now the goal has
always been consistency being able to
say it's like this high is gonna be like
this for me I don't know if it'd be like
that for everyone else but the turps are
like XYZ you know it looks like XYZ and
uh being able to provide that was uh
very important so yeah yeah that was the
most important thing I could have done
in my career was make something
consistent several years they really are
too even the way they grow and I had a
question for you about them bro yeah did
they did you ever at one point I mean
you're breeding them for consistency
right and a lot of these a lot of them
you're working with our shorter plants
but did do you ever see a tall blueberry
ex or any kind of blueberry that will
run a little bit taller because like all
the ones I had no they perform like what
they're supposed to you know short and
more of a squat squat Afghan dominant
types for the most part yeah yeah and
and the the CH profile was stuck in that
like you would you really weren't
finding that that shirt profile at least
in in the in Cross lines and the Bonnet
you weren't finding any of these Broad
Leaf types or um narrow Leaf types
shooting out huge blueberry turbs you
know I did make one cross with a blue
satellite that kind of took it in that
direction more narrow Leaf bigger Cola
taller lankier but um for the most part
yeah it's it's it's kept in the
Afghan that's cool yeah that's cool bro
I really enjoy growing man easy grow
pretty quick flower everything man
I got I made seeds with them I want to
run some and find you know a better
expression bro that's the main thing and
you're bringing out the blue when you
when you outcross it because it's a true
be a true breeding line in that sense so
yeah that's [ __ ] awesome more more
more have you have you figured out where
you're going I know I ask you this every
week bro but have you figured out which
direction you gonna go next I'm biting
it a bit to know bro I mean you know
like I wanted to do more gel work right
but me and CSI did some of that in fem
lines and he he crossed it to more [ __ ]
than I could have ever imagined right um
the strawberry stuff I got rid of most
of my strawberry stuff so trying to go
back and rework my strawberry stuff I
don't have much of the strawberry stuff
anymore I've kind of passed it on um the
p91 stuff I passed on to other people
who are doing work with the p91 stuff
now it's and people seem to dig it and
that's rad but um yeah I don't quite
know what I would do next like I really
need to sit down with my big [ __ ] bag
of collection stuff and like the only
thing that really appeals to me like
there's the Maduro which was an Oregan
purple thae line which is just more
blueberry parentage kind of um [ __ ] I
don't I don't really know I don't want
to do more
sour I don't want to do more Super Skunk
stuff because I think I've done all I
can do with super skunk um it's hard to
say I've got to do fem workor though
because that's all it sells anymore so
yeah so I mean going back and being
redundant on blueberry and doing like a
feminized blue incross now that would
bring out so many recessives and mutants
that I'm not sure that's even a good
idea like it in theory it sounds great
but yeah I don't know how it would uh
present speaking on that Maduro I ran
those uh I think it was I always forget
the name bro it's [ __ ] was it black
cherry black cherry Maduro White Rhino
to anyways I ran those out I just called
it the Maduro just because it was easy I
ha I [ __ ] can barely read them right
bro you know anyways I I yeah ended up
with two females out of like the six
seeds the real old seeds you sent out
with the patron [ __ ] I popped them bro I
got two females out of them uh the one
was just a little I don't know she just
was kind of didn't really I ended up
chopping her so I ran the one and when I
first tried it dude I was like this is
all right bro and it's that classic case
of like I let it cure for like a month
and I had smoked other [ __ ] I was
smoking the skank dog and all the other
stuff and I go back and smoke it bro and
it was [ __ ] pretty nice dude like
yeah I can't at the end of the day I
threw it away so it sucks but I ended up
growing them out dude and were nice but
I didn't get a mail so I was just like
[ __ ] I I just ended up chucking it bro
there's a lot in that parentage of those
seeds which is the only reason I never
ran them like I want to just find the
Maduro stuff like that that was already
a special line now the the Maduro stuff
if I remember came from the same dudes
that the the rose Flow came from and um
yeah is it alkaline man or elevator man
I don't one of the two I don't know I
always get the two confused but yeah
it's interesting [ __ ] uh roslow is one
of the hardest grows I've ever had in a
plant it was never [ __ ] happy and it
wasn't a good line in itself but when
you outcrossed it it made amazing uh f1s
yeah that's that's the thing I'm
learning bro out of getting out of the
jail and [ __ ] like [ __ ] all these new
lines and [ __ ] man you don't you realize
like not all lines are the same bro like
some [ __ ] or not all everything some
[ __ ] [ __ ] grow great for you in one
way and you put some else in their same
way don't grow the [ __ ] man [ __ ] my mom
grows better than I do I think sometimes
dude yeah there's here's an Instagram
comment I think what is better is to
breed with official pollen from
Plants it's a good point official pollen
from plants what's official I'm trying
to don't [ __ ] know whatever it is I
want to be a part of that of that [ __ ]
[ __ ] PID
Dude official official it's Kevin toy
here I'm
official my bad I forgot we're doing a
Q&amp;A again bro yeah it doesn't matter
okay herbs SD says uh is p haes going to
take over the world
P ha Con coming soon you know I don't
know I mean see people seem to like p91
now um there I didn't make a ton of the
s1s there's still a few left that uh
some people have gotten a hold of but um
bitter did Bittersweet did amazing work
to to pull out the best the be better
than what I saw just in the s1's um he
found some really really cool
expressions and made what we call the
sweet pee and other people have used
seeds from the sweet pee and crossed it
to like uh little Lo crossed it to
bandaid Haze I want to say to make the P
Haze bandid Haze number seven yeah so
yeah that's gonna be out there that's
cool um yeah I got a 10 but right here I
would show y'all but we'll get banned
bro yeah we get banned again yeah I got
some of that going right now uh I don't
know like n anyways it's going this is
going yeah but um you know when the the
p91 first came out no nobody gave a [ __ ]
about p91 except San Diego people and
there was a few of them and bitter was
one so out I gotta say anything that
I've smoked that has the pee in it bro
is is good bro
like you know how we were talking about
last episode where we're we're off some
tangent on Autos versus uh traditional
stuff but we're talking about how you
know you grow out a pack and maybe like
one you're not really doing yourself
just as growing out one pack if you're
really trying to [ __ ] with that plant
yeah find something good but the you
know uh [ __ ] Bro the Irene hit me man I
forgot what I oh I was gonna
say I was gonna say [ __ ] just blanked
out bro but uh you know anything with
the p in it like you run that I've ran
crosswise or it's been crossed into it
bro every pack that every plant in there
is pretty good of some you know it might
be not maybe one don't have a stru the
right structure whatever but the actual
smoke the flavor the turbs anything with
p smoke comes out pretty good bro like
legit I don't know
yeah I think it's it's the name it's the
name it's p like I mean I think it's at
the end of the day like we like it and
it's it's in our group it's cool but
like to like random people it it's you
know maybe I think it just comes down to
probably the name bro yeah um Gregor
Smith asked did I grow up in nordal if
so how was it yes um
I had some Herm issues early on with the
nordal but it's one I'd like to go back
and touch on it's one of the few um
afghanis that Shany Baba put out that I
would mess with um at least that I would
try to grow now um a lot of the afghanis
from him I did not like but at the same
time he has some of the best uh narrow
leaf type plants like the the mango hay
you know um super silver Hayes uh
there's more you know you know you know
what he
has yeah see I'm looking here through
some more questions uh shyy says how do
you choose which plant to reverse in a
femin feminized
cross whatever one reverses easier and
more consistently yeah that's how yeah
stagger guys stagger your [ __ ] plants
don't be in there yoloing it with one
thinking you g make like god dude put
stagger it's yeah anyways go watch the
old episodes breeding there you talk
about this guys come on come on uh sorry
some people putting joke questions in
here so I got SK J like we're funny yeah
like we're funny like playing like this
is a game or something
like let's see uh PK asked where will
thousandfold be joining tonight
obviously not no he's too too cool for
us right now but he will be back
eventually he's coming back guys don't
he's got actual work to do he doesn't
want to play while he's working
we're bums you know I I can't I can't
hold a job I can't even apply for a job
I don't have an IDE I can't do [ __ ] so I
just sit around with moms all day K you
know kicking it whatever yeah [ __ ] like
that watching prices right and [ __ ] yeah
yep when she not around I get on like
pornh Hub and stuff
but see uh I think we ran through most
of these questions here oh we got you go
got a couple more here if you uh as Sean
says
if you could go back to one line you
made and start a new project from it
what would it be the strawberry switch
blade that would be it it was a I you
know what to be honest I can't even
remember what was in that son of a [ __ ]
it was East Coast s diesel strawberry
cream and I think it was the double
black DOA which was also a poly hybrid
but it just made for this really uh
magenta looking very strawberry scented
Afghani type plant it's gorgeous
consistent and super strawberry yeah
that would probably be one for
sure I don't know I had a this this goes
to jab question was my favorite Bubba
hybrid I've ever smoked there was
a um a Bubba hybrid with killer queen
like the original bcga Killer Queen
seeds that I popped that one was fire
that was fire I like that one a
lot cool serf boy 47 says can you tell
us about dog [ __ ] also what sour was
used with Gil in your and csi's collab
I'm growing the dog [ __ ] uh t uh X time
sour
xman they are beautiful plants cheers
man sorry I can't [ __ ] read though
yeah um dog [ __ ] like I've only run it a
few times so I don't really wouldn't
really speak on it like well you know I
don't know what it is I don't know the
history on it there's other people who
know that it was you know some glass
blowers from some where doing something
bringing it around to somewhere um as
far as the sour that was the
sour that came from mure um who was on
another episode you can go back and
check it out um as far as I mean I don't
know the history on it like he has he
had it a long time ago
yeah can we kill the dog [ __ ] name
electric bugaloo you know only because
it would annoy the [ __ ] out of someone
that I don't like I'm going to keep
calling it dog [ __ ]
you know just because of that right I
got Matt I got a little beef with you
bro oh yeah last episode my mom was me
and Mom were kicking and and when you
hit me up earli like asking if I could
you know jump on this podcast real
whatever real quick I was like yeah
that's cool but I talking to Mom about I
was like man my mom like real excited
like you get me back on he's getting mad
good guy he's finally coming through for
me and she's like yeah but did you see
last episode on the [ __ ] video thing
he spelled Kim dog with the [ __ ] W
bro and I was like no I didn't so I get
on there and looking at it and I'm
thinking Matt [ __ ] ass over here
trying to play me or something I just
want him to get it clear to all y'all
out there that I don't spell no [ __ ]
Kim dogs no goddamn W's I do fix AC
units part-time I don't do it because I
need to do the money or nothing like
that I do it because I like to fix AC
units and [ __ ] I could I could make
money from the game and [ __ ] but I
really care about the home pent grow you
guys you know what I'm say got save our
five acre farm that we call a farm that
is actually not a farm but we for our
kids [ __ ] like this you know the
industry genomic projects and stuff like
that uh anyways I will say that the
first person to spell it ewg was peab
Bud who was one of the people he was a
you know a golf jockey or something I
don't know what the [ __ ] he was but he
was one of the people that was there
when Joe brand sold the pounds or weight
I don't know ounces I don't know what
the [ __ ] he sold he sold something and
he spelled it dawg so as far as I'm
concerned Kim dog is spelled Kim D AWG
dog that's that's [ __ ] I don't know I
don't [ __ ] with that [ __ ] I don't know
it should have a z at the end if I if I
had my
say I this me and you after this podcast
we gonna get it straight bro we're gonna
figure it out but uh do you trust me
he's not your homie bro get the [ __ ] out
of
here [ __ ] ck6 says do you plan to
remake any blue crosses with thex
instead of the blue bonnet that's a good
question uh and do you have any tips for
getting the best flavor and smells from
the blue
crosses um yeah I mean make sure you
cure it other than that you'll get it
throw it right um
what the
[ __ ] hold on hold on I just I'm just
enjoying the guy with the
facts he thinks he knows some [ __ ] um
yeah uh the blue incross I would like to
eventually I mean it's I still have more
of the original Bonnet seats to pop
though and go through so that always
interests me um yeah that's cool man uh
and then his other question was oh you
answered both of them my bad yeah I mean
just slow down the Cure bro I mean as
far as like bringing out the blue turps
I mean you see the blue turps even on
crosses I mean I think it was at the I
mean of course it's called the Blue hype
the great blue hype had it in there and
you see now after growing uh thex you
can find really great blue turts in
almost any of Matt's work that had you
know that has the Bonnet in it it's not
too far from
thex I mean it's [ __ ] pretty spot on
dude like did y'all did a great job
doing it bro that's nice
yeah uh let's see uh I think we kind of
ran through all of our questions guys
all of them all of them done are we done
I think so is this [ __ ] [ __ ] let me
double check I want make sure we're
sharing everybody's questions and
showing love to everybody oh we got one
more good one a fresh one heirloom
Afghan remake feminized
afghanis yeah I don't know like it had
its long round and then people got mad
because it I didn't make a lot of them
and I sold them for a lot because
everybody wanted them so I don't
know I don't know I I don't know maybe I
have some left could could do could do I
really like the
um I don't know crosses with it that I
liked but yeah no I mean it's just a an
old Super Skunk type so I think there's
even better super skunks than that um it
was skunky it was nice nice but yeah it
was also highly variant which which
isn't something I love I think that's my
biggest um my biggest annoyance is
variance in in lines uh poly
hybrids yep I got a remember them Afghan
90s we talked
about yeah I got some of those going
dude and uh couple of man when you rub
the stems dude I know it's not always a
tail sign of everything but they have
really like kind of similar to the ex a
bit but a little different more of a
Sharp sharpness to the nose on it but
that's this real like two of them had
this like almost like blueberry kind of
berry smells really interesting actually
I haven't I haven't started flowering
them or nothing yet but they're really
interesting if I remember correctly it
was positronics Afghan in those and then
they had um you can go to the real Seed
Co if you want to check those out real
Seed Company um quick seeds kwi
seeds.com the homie Angus runs it some
amazing amazing stuff on the real Seed
Company a lot of you that want to find
good land races um the dude's been in
the game forever he has good sourcing on
his [ __ ] um yeah yep
yep um I was gonna say something else
about him or about about them it is in
EU bro it's you gotta make sure some
when I ordered them bro like I think it
was more than what I thought it was
going to be because the the transfer or
whatever the money bro I [ __ ] up right
I can't
talk I've been drinking beer I've
beened you know but no uh anyways yeah
where's basically it guys any more
questions throw them in chat real quick
if not yeah give a few minutes for it
someone asked uh if I smoke skunk 6 no I
don't know anybody who's uh currently
smoking skunk 6 that's been dead for a
long time it's the same cut as the VA
Super Skunk that came out of va which
was from the breeder from the breeder's
mouth what was it nl5 Haze um super
skunk F2 selection so yeah that's been
dead a long time so I don't know what
the [ __ ] JJ's yapping about [ __ ]
skunk six he he didn't have skunk six
either so what the [ __ ] he talking about
but then again someone hands him a clone
named skunk 6 he's always said I'll I I
keep the name whatever someone gave it
to me as and then he'll sell the seeds
of it
so gotta love that that hard work and
integrity so he says it publicly though
that he doesn't give a f you know yeah
here's a question uh no no where is it
where is it I just saw it there we go
about to read you you on Discord about
my question last week's show about sub
Rob matal Reach Out reach out right now
what you trying to ask bro I'm smoking
skank dog right now yep he got some
skank dog
uh love I me if you dude honestly out of
what I've grown the last few months is
probably my favorite thing so far I I
mean pretty good the particular one I
mean uh I mean they all kind of smell
similar the ones I ran the one that I
really like if you really that care that
much there's some pictures I think
somewhere in the Discord just look up
skank dog but uh it's just kind of a
rancid like coffee smell that it's uh
yeah coffee skunky like not really like
spearm mint but like a slight little bit
of that that kind of mint mint tinge to
it and yeah just like a bitter smell to
it bro I don't know how to explain it
it's just really pungent like really
nice on the and that's what you taste
too that's what I like about it is you
taste that you know how sometimes you
put weed in a a blunt or joint or bong
whatever and it doesn't taste like what
you're smelling bro that that's what I
like about this is it tastes tastes what
I smell and I I don't
know yeah for people asking about skunk
six it was some people in Colorado had
it as skunk 6 it was passed around as
skunk 6 back then it is dead so if
people are trying to sell seeds of it
they're selling you a [ __ ] a myth and
a
dream it's been people have been doing
that with [ __ ] mass mass Super Skunk
that wasn't Mass Super Skunk for ever
since I've been around and no one's
produced it the VA Super Skunk we know
what it looks like um the closest thing
that was used with it would be sour you
know sour was used with it and that's
where you're going to see the progy of
any skunk 6 or uh VA Super Skunk AKA
Mass Super Skunk number one and since it
was the first one that they renamed a
mass super skunk and later they popped
sensey Super Skunk seeds called that
mass Super Skunk 2 because why not um
yeah they didn't call it number two they
just called it Mass Super Skunk as well
because that's how them cam Doggers do
right hey Kim I do that's it mother no
was that some old Greg old
Greg I got the shiny bits down
below downstairs mix up you know I think
I've been thinking about this while I'm
taking shits and stuff dude you gotta
drop some stuff maybe like modern [ __ ]
ain't for Matt Riot modern stuff ain't
for a lot of people I get it but there's
got to be something out there we could
we could you can make a cross of bro
that gets more because I think we need
younger people in the space bro we need
not younger people to lead us but we
need the Next Generation bro we're dying
out you know whether we like it or not
we're dying out bro there not many of us
left you know people talking about Cuts
there ain't even people that really got
the cuts when them [ __ ] are gone then
where are we gonna be this gonna be myar
cookies all that dumb [ __ ] you know we
gotta get the people hyped bro you know
yeah positivity guys Love Is Love Love
Is Love there's you know there's only a
few uh younger cats that I've I've met
that I'm like okay this dude could carry
some [ __ ] you know like they care enough
and to get it right because I mean once
once a few of us are gone and you know
it's gonna be nobody's really gonna give
a [ __ ] about what's what who had what
all that shit's just gonna be drowned
yeah well even if you don't give a [ __ ]
about Matt or or blueberry like fact is
that no hold on goddamn it the fact is
you're keystoned a corner piece of our
community and the broader community in a
lot of ways I think bro you brought so
much if anything you bring everybody
together and you give us you know like d
and a couple other guys y'all bring us
together and I think if we could just
stop arguing about how important your
color of your [ __ ] ashes bro and
focus
on important topics or whether I'm f one
or smoking weed out of your [ __ ]
butthole glass
style uh let's you know we need to focus
on the bigger issues bro yeah yeah I
don't know I think that butthole glass
style might be painful back back to my
question what are we what are we working
with in the future we gotta get
something you gotta come up with
something man we gotta get these people
do I gotta come up with something that
that I'm gonna work with do I have to
work with anything do I just quit start
growing Auto flowers done Auto flowers y
there you go game over that's the
ultimate mat if Matt start throwing Auto
flowers y'all know it's game
over yeah that's it if I do it again if
I do it again for a second time yes I
have done it you made them great the
first time you can come back and make
them great again make them great again
white wiow don't was on that auto flower
sh [ __ ] way
before tell them yeah and everybody said
what are you doing with that [ __ ] I got
I got one here you go uh
okay where is it at it was on here hn
asked it
uh did Matt smoke all the auto flour I
gave
him you know I'll have to look I don't
think I smoked all of
it I didn't smoke all it wasn't the
worst smoke I've had though it was it
was a tricker he sent me a tricker
didn't tell me what it was and said
smoke it so I did because it's H&amp;L and
it was it was a trigger it wasn't
terrible
I mean it had a high to it which is more
than I expect from [ __ ] auto flower
and people that call [ __ ] normal
plants photo period godd damn it well
I'm here to shed the light on the
game I'm G say this when I went to that
meet up I just said move bro so all the
all my stash I lived in a let's just say
I lived in a place where well I just
didn't want to carry all the [ __ ] across
lines State Border Lines or whatever bro
because some of these states had crazy
pen so I gave all my my stashes away so
for like a few months I was smoking
wreck weed up here like a little weirdo
feeling like depressed I couldn't even
look myself in the mirror and make love
to my [ __ ] wife dude but my point is
you got a wife what I got I got a few
wife I'm G PL okay that's what I thought
that's weird okay I'm out here doing it
big you know trying to yeah anyways uh
man you got me off topic talking about
random [ __ ] bro I've been smoking what
was I talking
about I couldn't tell you I don't know
where that was going I don't know we got
a question yeah here it is Gang of green
horns he says I have a question I'm
interested in preserving Big Bang slash
making a strain out of it I have a big
bang times diesel as an S1 clone what
would you use to breed it back to Big
Bang and then it's got skunk number one
ll1
nl1 and then El
Nino there is never a day I would try to
preserve a Greenhouse seed
string you don't believe in
aan what
a no I don't mean to be a dick yeah me
and my for my liking there's nothing I
would buy from greenhouse seeds because
they sold many things as big bang so
what you're getting it's not necessarily
skunk one nl1 and El Nino um it may have
been skunk one nl1 hay it could have
been any number of things that was sold
as big bang because they would buy from
places like Buddha seeds not big Buddha
seeds Buddha seeds Spain and buy bulk
and use that for whatever lines they had
and just be like these [ __ ] won't
know so there's no point in um
preserving stuff that you don't know
what it is unless you really really like
it for yourself as far as preserving a
strain for like the
future that's one of those those tough
ones um it's a tough one
y I mean if you it comes back to if you
like it keep it yeah yeah um as far as
preserving it for the future you'd be
preserving something that we just don't
know what it
is yeah that's that's the thing when
you're working with with any of this
[ __ ] lines or whatever or you're making
seeds or whatever like if you don't know
what the [ __ ] it is like I don't even
want to work with it bro just because
it's I mean it is you don't know you're
shooting yourself in the foot from the
get-go in a way or it feels like at
least you know as far as starting some
kind of breeding project
yeah I mean and and not to even just say
that it's Greenhouse even though they're
horrible um at doing this you know
Barney's Farm Nirvana whoa whoa every
one of them all did it gota be careful
what we say I forget get knocked off
[ __ ] YouTube I know
right d I know who is doing the breeding
there's no one doing breeding compound
genetics he's buying seeds from other
white label seed makers I know some of
the people he buys them from uh early on
I even put this up on the [ __ ] screen
early on um
my buddy y yeast was making the seeds
for him until he stole from y yeast
we're talking about Chris compound AKA
tiger trees um yeah that schmuck doesn't
know [ __ ] about [ __ ] go listen to his
podcast and you'll see it for yourself
like that's what he does I hate to burst
people's bubbles out there but making
seeds is easy guys I've done it I did it
from jail I did it in a [ __ ] bathroom
from jail dude for real
p in he smuggled P sent me [ __ ] in in
there one of my Kim 15 like he made some
crosses with that [ __ ] and dude it's
easy bro anybody can do it yeah just go
buy some seeds put them in a mile art
bag and sell them that's the M surpris
I'm surprised more people don't talk
about compounding the scams B it's
because if they're scared of getting
sued or they're definitely not scared of
him if they've ever met him so
yeah yeah I don't I don't know some of
them dudes are so out of my [ __ ]
spectrum of like
I should have never known this [ __ ] I I
was in Michigan we
got someone was gonna hire us to work
with them both of us and this is when
why East still a part of it and I got to
spend a weekend and then later on
another weekend with uh those guys and I
really like y East I have nothing bad to
say about him at all he's a great guy um
he did good work with compound when he
was doing it uh he has y swarms now go
check that out um but yeah Chris
compound's a [ __ ] I'll happily say that
publicly over and over and
over Matt dunking on the game all right
guys if anybody you got anything else
for him
Matt um I don't know you want to do the
outro yeah we can we get that [ __ ] you
pulled it off once are you two Stone no
I got it
okay guys gals it comes a life wait guys
gals there Comes A Time in everyone's
life when you have to make a
decision are you going to vote with your
dollar and buy the right genetics for
your garden are you going to make a
mistake and spend
$200 on a [ __ ] dream you've been sold
hell no with my help with your help with
Matt's help with the breeder Syndicate
help join the Discord it is a Discord
it's a great place it's a community
don't forget we got r a month $5 a month
that's like a coffee nowadays less than
a coffee at Starbucks you dude you can't
even buy a [ __ ] pack of gum for that
so great info years of information
strain talking about strains all this
stuff Community you know all that fun
stuff guys don't forget you can go to
Riot seeds.com and pick up all the
latest genetics greatest [ __ ] from Matt
H&amp;L Pock and crew there's all kinds of
[ __ ] up there stuff we talked about
today's up there new stuff from Jill I
got the new stuff from Jill add I got
some of I I just realized I never put up
the Santa Cruz wreck from pack so those
are up right now too we have the raffle
going on right now in the Discord that's
going on waffle whatever we call it um
there you go there's that
too well we got of course like you said
Miss jills we got don't forget to go
check out all the other guys' websites I
can't remember them all lft
genetics.com go check out uh krono I
always forget his ack.com I don't know
dude all that go check it all out it is
like literally AIC ack.com I think I
can't spell it a
i leg l.com that that's it but yeah and
then we got ger by seeds and we also got
right EU shout out gold cut we got all
gold cut we got them all in the Discord
you can [ __ ] talk to these guys you
can almost suck their [ __ ] you can
almost some of you
can yeah that's about it
guys yeah um yeah go check it out that's
it I guess I don't know shout out to our
moderators thanks for helping and uh go
hit like subscribe all that [ __ ] and uh
with that I guess we'll see you next
week maybe I don't know we'll
see what do you got planned you got
doing back to regular interview I know
people might be a little tired of
[ __ ] around with me so yeah I don't
know I need to um there's a few people I
need to reach out to I've just been
cleaning up the house after a hurricane
hit so yeah yeah I mean sometimes
personal life you gotta do your [ __ ] bro
you know gota dear [ __ ] gotta handle
business with stupid asses so yeah I
gotta go talk to Mom about this [ __ ]
headphone [ __ ] making me look dumb I'm
trying to impress you guys on the
internets or whatever I know Mom didn't
help m mom you know she blaming on the
smoke or whatever I'm a stoner kid [ __ ]
like that I don't know
whatever anyways I appreciate y'all if I
don't see you again Matt if I don't see
you again people in the chat I guess
I'll see you when I see you I don't know
everything but I sure do know a lot I'm
Chucky the [ __ ] pollins thanks a lot so
he's in the Discord too so you can
always go [ __ ] with him that way and
with that peace want to sit at the table
with the syndicate
check out our patreon and our link tree
or description below our merch site is
officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is topnotch I've
been saving old designs for years for
this purpose so please check it out
Syndicate gear.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource old catalogs
and knowledge we hope you join our Union
of breeders and Growers come check it
out want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have have an underground Syndicate
Discord where we get together and solve
old strain history together daily it's
an amazing community of learning away
from IG and it's an amazing resource for
old cataloges and knowledge we hope you
join our Union of readers and Growers
come check it out