foreign
[Music]
welcome to breeders Syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene Through The Eyes of the folks who
lived in I'm Matthew owner of Riot seeds
I'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not so John breeder and grower
from Mendocino
welcome to the underground
[ __ ] Dude Perfect skirt from up north or
catapulted
all right how's everyone doing welcome
to breed of Syndicate uh I'm Matthew
this is my buddy not so I think we're
going to talk about some cups and we're
not talking about the kind that protect
your genitals we are talking about the
kinds that come with awards for for
prestigious uh for prestigious
accomplishments in cannabis
um first off uh one of my homies gray
School uh hit me up and asked me if I
could let everyone know that a um that a
fellow Outlaw grower has gone down
they're trying to raise some money for
Emerald Delta over on um what is it
called GoFundMe so if you can we're
going to have a link kind of floating up
in the description as we're going like
on the bottom go check it out type it in
the description all that yada yada yada
go help a friend out
um it was it was all weed charges and
it's like a hundred and sixty thousand
dollars bail in Tennessee so
[ __ ] the police anyway so let's continue
um yeah so cups cups and events recently
a a big event has happened called the um
gangier event or Cowboy cup I want to
say um Cowboy cup yeah yeah you've seen
it out and about
um on the
on the old Instagrams and the the other
social medias it's been popping up a
bunch people have been wanting to talk
about it so I wanted to put up a quick
um explanation kind of from ganjir I
think that is the best one to do I
believe it's on this window let's see uh
yeah can you see it
yep all right so this is a quick um
explanation from ganjir of what happened
and all I won't read the whole thing but
I'll scroll through it
um it said last weekend 12 certified
ganjiers were chosen to judge at the
2022 Cowboy Cup in Stillwater Oklahoma
the judges were selected by both gone to
your team and organizers of the cowboy
cup based on experience filled of
expertise and ensure diverse viewpoints
were represented so basically they chose
a bunch of days
um they go into detail about how judges
were chosen whatever and people were
allowed to submit samples and they were
they had to have coas with their samples
certificate of authenticities basically
saying that there's no mold no residual
chemicals from growth whatever no no
junk in your [ __ ] right so they had to
submit paperwork with each sample well
at the cup I guess they had microscopes
like they show right here sitting there
to analyze each sample and here are the
results I I guess despite the COA they
wanted to review each sample there under
the microscope which I think is actually
good I think that's a great Safeguard
because you never know what kind of
authenticity these these Labs really
bring to the table so I also see
trichome development and stuff too
exactly you know I mean you get a real
good you get a much better view of the
bud obviously and people that that
understand buds can get an actual good
look at it what's going on there so the
samples it says uh unfortunately results
were not great
of the 12 samples in the sun-grown
category 10 were found to consistently
show both Visual and aromatic
indications of contamination so that
means 10 smelled like mold or
whatever
presence of something some kind of scent
of the eight samples in the light assist
category seven are found to consistently
show both Visual and aromatic
indications of contamination
not good of the 20 samples in the Indo
category two were found to consistently
show both Visual and aromatic
indications of contamination this means
that contamination was clearly visible
in 19 of the 40 samples submitted to us
for assessment and here's some pictures
so you guys can get an idea ladies and
gents I'm sorry I always say guys ladies
and gents can get an idea for um some of
the contamination in there it said
because the levels of contamination both
were both clear and evident to the
certified gun years the samples were
disqualified from the competition each
disqualified sample was photo documented
for proof of the contamination so yeah
not good not looking good for the
Oklahoma entrance
okay so I gotta remove this thing there
we go there we go so not looking good
for the the Oklahoma entrance
um there were a lot of people really
hyper super pissed off that thought that
uh there was some rigging going on that
maybe these people were trying to sell
them I guess during a speech or some
kind of post that one of the people from
ganjir made it offered them some
training in being able to spot
contamination and mold and maybe how to
grow different and this upset a lot of
people because they're like we're
Growers we know our stuff we had coas
you had a little scope with the you know
you know stuff like that so that's kind
of how it was taken and uh it's it's
really interesting to watch how it
um turns out in the community
yeah I mean I I will say I do think it's
a little just to start I think it's a
little silly that
um in California in the west coast at
least I would say that when people are
going for awards and things like that
they you know uh they make sure that
what they're submitting is is hopefully
not going to do that right not just
grabbing random handfuls uh if you can
find 19 out of 40 that's basically 50
percent yeah if you can find Visible
enough mold that all the judges agree it
needs to go then
you know uh there wasn't a very good
quality control for a lot of the
entrants put it that way
yeah so that's where we know we're at
with the situation now but we kind of
wanted to talk about how we got to this
situation the the the
points of harvest cups and how they kind
of originated and on to the Amsterdam
cannabis cups and on into you know other
sorts of
quasi Harvest cups that maybe started
more traditional and legit that became
more corporate and on to where we're at
with a lot of these you know extract
throwdowns but to start I mean not so
who knows better about the early
cannabis Cups than my boy Nazo so let's
jump into this
I yeah I mean I I think there's probably
two kinds you could say you could say of
Cups there was like you mentioned there
was a lot of informal cups which are
essentially friends Gathering to share
weed right yeah and then there's like
cups that are advertised and and more
famous and uh like the um you know like
the High Times cannabis cups
um and the you know the emerald cup and
a lot of the different you know hashish
competitions or different things that
have happened where it's a little bit
more public and as a result of that
there's usually money and rep involved
so it brings a different it brings a
different flavor to it I think always
um and you know uh these days uh as as
evidenced by some Cowboy Cup in Oklahoma
cups are just events that anyone can
hold and as a result there's hundreds of
Cups Across America now probably uh when
it comes down to it but in back in the
day as far as like ones that got
advertised there was pretty much one
yeah there was the High Times Cannabis
Cup that was in Amsterdam you know yeah
and Matt Cub had a major impact
um probably it's you know the most
impactful one uh because that was a real
nice issue at High Times yeah uh and the
Cannabis Cup winners would have like
there'd be pages of really high quality
gloss you know for you know nice
pictures write-ups the whole bit and I
think it kind of drove seed sales and
desirability especially in the in the
90s yeah it was a big deal to win cups
don't you agree yeah I mean seed cells
were kind of dependent on that on these
cups that were going on and most of the
people that were entering those first
cannabis cups were dealing in seed sales
I mean most people's first images that
they ever saw of any kind of AK-47 or
big bud or white widow or you know a lot
you can name a lot of different strains
where like probably the first time you
ever saw it was pictures and High Times
in the Cannabis Cup well I mean the the
Cannabis Cup so prestigious in a lot of
people's minds like at least in the
general publics that when a lot of us
get into growing when we first go to buy
our first pack of seeds the one thing we
think about has it won a High Times
Cannabis Cup because most of us know
even with basic smoking knowledge when
you jump into this that there is a
magazine called High Times and that they
have an event called the Cannabis Cup
and that there are winners of these
things you know so I think that's you a
lot of people's first entrance is is who
has won the Cannabis cups when they get
into growing
and it it was kind of one of those
things too where Amsterdam at the time
was uh one of the few places in the
world where you could gather openly uh
with a weed festival yeah um so it
it brought together a bunch of heads
from all over the place yeah I did you
know uh and there was some there was
some weird stuff about it too there was
people that thought that
people that went there were watched they
were worried about a CL of a bunch of
gathering of Growers and Seed makers and
Hustlers and stuff because you know it
was heavily under prohibition at the
time and there was big agencies in
Europe and America like wanting to know
what was going on
um so there's even a bunch of drama
about the cup has always had some weird
politics yeah um but from a cannabis
perspective and certainly from like a
younger Smoker's perspective I had
safety it's safe to say that a lot of
people would get that that issue of High
Times and drool over the multi-page
photo shoot yeah of the winners and the
entries and you know and all that type
of stuff and so
um you know uh some of the and in fact
too some of the late 80s stuff you know
it's so old now that it's reference
points for some of those early strains
and photos of those early strains
um in in the I don't think we've
mentioned it yet the first cup was held
in 1988 correct
I think it might have been 87. I think
so too because the first High Times 87
one was skunk one but it listed here is
88 but I want to say on the front cover
of high times it was the red issue and I
want to say it was 87 but I might be
wrong am I wrong
yeah
and I think we learned something
recently here about the Second Cup
winner which is the early Pearl skunk
one or lights five Haze right we did I
mean that one that one's gone through a
a metamorphosis so when that got
released it won the 89 Cannabis Cup
overall right and that's what Neville
sold it at and that's what he entered it
at but then a couple years later he
changed the name to Silver Pearl by
Hayes yeah right but it was the same mix
he listed the mix he just changed the
name so you could still read exactly
what it was yeah and then when Sensei
bought out his company they just changed
it to Silver Haze yes
um and they took away most of the
information of what was in the hybrid
itself it was just a name and a vague
description but they mentioned that it
won the 89 cup yeah
and Neville helpfully laid out what the
mix was so
um it's just it went from uh I mean I
can't even remember how it was written
is it like EP by Skunk one by nl5 by
Hayes yeah yeah yeah so that's not a
very great marketing name no it's not
the best it's not the best marketing
name at all no so never got Neville got
rid of that and called it you know and
called that strain silver Pearl let's
see I'm gonna remove this thing so we
can see it I don't know if you can see
the uh screen here it might be too tiny
for you to see huh it's it's too tiny
for me to see but you can walk me
through it okay third cup we got
Northern Lights five from the seed bank
classic
so um maybe I'll throw in a little
tidbit about that too
um there are several pictures
um from various people that Matt and I
have gathered of uh living flowering
plants well and well close to harvest
and dried flower of that exact famous
nl5 cut yeah and so without you know
because it won
um it got the full photo spread
and it got some pictures and it gave us
a reference point 35 years later or
whatever
um for what that exactly looked like but
there's more to the story like even more
because if that Neville's if that in all
five that won the cup wasn't the same
nl5 that was shipped over
in that little
terrarium whatever terrarium type
situation
then referencing the the
Seattle nl5 seed line to that specific
cut would be a little confusing
yeah I mean there's it's one of those
things where Matt and I you think you
have something like that figured out and
Nuance comes in
um so I I mean they um
I'm not even exactly sure what to say
that one but this that different people
have different perspectives and remember
things
you know and yeah even today like the
history history is uh
gets it gets altered perhaps is the best
way to put it it can be fluid it can be
fluid it can be fluid well you know you
think you understand something and then
something comes along that that kind of
flips that on its head and so Matt and I
recently got some Credence that like
maybe you know um we had heard a long
time ago that one of the NLS might have
been NL Steve Murphy's Afghan mixed with
uh a Neville Afghan yeah
and um and Seattle Greg in a post a long
time ago even sort of confirmed it
but then all the other evidence came out
against it and it kind of dropped and we
never heard it again well recently we
heard that that was probably true yeah
that it's a pretty it's a decent
reliable source that wouldn't it's
definitely a close end and reliable
source so
um you know it's it's kind of a lot of a
lot of this old oral history you have to
lean into what you believe
um but what Matt was referencing is that
we believe that there was two Famous nl5
Cuts there was one uh that was a little
bit more sativa that was passed around
the the Pacific Northwest and Seattle
Greg's crew and there was one that
Neville found out of nl5 labeled seed
yeah that Greg sent him that he thought
was a total Afghan throwback and
exhibited no sativa influence that he
could discern whatsoever yeah and
supposedly this one mother cut became
the winner of all that uh and went on to
become famous and got bred to all kinds
of things
supposedly I think I think the story is
that he crossed that to that in all five
cut
to either Afghani one or that Mazar you
know and then that something was
selected from that and that became the
nl5 cut that won the cup
indeed yeah so that's that's something
to clarify like if we ever speak
misspeak on anything and we get you know
any future info we'll always uh update
it as best we can without throwing
anyone under the bus or doing anything
crazy but we like to to make sure that
we uh get everything as accurate as
possible no matter what even if it is uh
us being wrong at one point it's
important one next
so we are at let's see here
we are at uh skunk from free City so I
assume it's like a skunk one maybe I
don't know who free city is
then we have um hey skunk one from
homegrown fantasies or homegrown fantasy
which became homegrown fantasy fancies
later yeah and then it says uh High
Times Cannabis Cup winner Master Kush I
don't know why it says that beside it
Hindu kushek across the skunk one
which I wonder if that was uh I wonder
if that was pot of gold
hmm
I do I wonder
did it did it say
did what did it say again
it says Hey skunk one from homegrown
fantasy then in parentheses it says Hi
Times Canvas Cup winner Master Kush
equals Hindu Kush X skunk one but then
below it it says Haze uh the 1993 is
haze Northern Lights five from Tennessee
bank and then it says the same thing
next to that High Times Cannabis Cup
winner Master Kush equals Hindu Kush
cross the skunk one so I don't know why
they're putting all right that's
confusing let's move on so yeah once
again once you get to 30 or 94 you get
to Jack Herer that's 95 they're wrong
right no widow's 95. no so I uh I went
to that cup when I was when I was my huh
which cup was it the 94 cup for Jack
Herer
yes
because because what they did is
um that cup uh that was that was one of
the first times I went out to uh get
seeds I'd gone that summer previously
but I went back and fall
um and they uh
they wanted to dedicate that whole the
whole theme of the Cannabis Cup was
around Jack Herer and his
um and his contributions to cannabis
yeah right they had speeches by various
people and all kinds of stuff special
limited edition posters too I still have
a few yeah one of them one of them
I promised one away already so they
really they really tried to ramp up
marketing then right and so they wanted
to release something that was named
after him for that cup and Neville had
been working on this uh
nl5 Haze by Skunk Haze project but he
didn't really feel like it was ready
yeah but the dronkers convinced him to
release it
um and they released it at the cup
um and it was called Jack Herer after
the theme of the cup yeah
um and then and then Neville kept
working that line and three or four
years later he re-released it uh and
proved as he thought as super silver
haze yeah
so
yeah I was at that that cup
um one thing I'll say about the the uh
the these cups is from a personal level
right I went to like three of them
and it was definitely my least favorite
time of being in Amsterdam
um because late it was usually in late
November
um and Amsterdam's cold that time of
year
right so it could be sleeting or icy
rain or it's freezing and then you're in
these coffee shops and like and they're
super crowded and most of the best weed
is being hoarded for all of the
dignitaries and like famous people and
various folks coming in to smoke weed
for the Cannabis Cup yeah uh so for a
normal person it was like crowded cold
um and it was harder to find good wheat
yeah but it was still cool to see and
they did just like at they did we were
just describing they did usually draw
big name seed drops
um at the Cup itself
yeah
um because it got a lot of free press
yeah and everybody was there you know I
did find recently in an old article it
was the the year bubblegum won the
Cannabis Cup and it was in an old
article in High Times They were
interviewing Tony from Sager Matha and
he was the one who entered it in for the
gray area and it was actually
bubbleberry that he entered in his
bubble gum so yeah I saw that and that I
was like what I didn't even know that so
apparently sometimes what is entered in
and named isn't necessarily what it is
we need to oh yeah that should be
clarified too I mean people
you know there's uh Neville would say
that you know the same cut that he had
of you know got went of nl5 skunk Hayes
got like four or five different names
yeah and we've seen that out west a
bunch too fast forward a bunch of years
but what happened I think is by the by
the early to mid 90s the Cannabis Cup
became a big vehicle for selling seats
yeah and so Matt was about to talk about
what is it 95 like the year after it's
wooden White Widow one yeah so it looks
like by 1995 greenhouse seeds started
smashing the butthole out of the
Cannabis Cup we have 95 white uh White
Widow 96.
White Russian yep 97 was Peacemaker yep
we got 98
SSH super Hayes 99. we got super silver
haze again three times yeah and then 2
000 all of a sudden all of a sudden
something weird happens and we have
blueberry winning a cup as it should as
it should always win every cup and don't
you forget it but that that's that was a
departure from the normal right so what
should be mentioned is that at the time
um White Widow White Rhino Peacemaker
which is a great white shark
um and Super Silver Haze all came out of
the same shop
yeah um it was all out of greenhouse uh
the white family was stuff getting
released by Shanti Baba and the haze was
stuff getting released by Neville
yeah
um so Greenhouse I think they swept I
think they placed top for
five six years in a row yeah it got
pretty ridiculous
you know
um and for different things too yeah
yeah there were lots of accusations
during that time of purchased cups and
whatnot and of course there were heavy
arguments that it was only done on Merit
during those years I mean um and to be
real they had some of the most
accomplished breeders in history working
for them at the time so they didn't
necessarily have to buy cups to win most
of the people around them were using
f2s or you know different filial
Generations or hybrids thereof the work
established by the people who are
winning the cups so by that point I
don't know that it was necessarily
something we can go aha it was already
corrupt it was well I mean with the
white family the sort of the proof is in
the pudding in the sense that
it started winning the cups in the mid
90s
and it was one of the most common
breeding tools for the next decade yeah
the amount of people that bred with
white widow or white white rhino or
great white shark or any of those white
family things I mean I think that
um you know I've mentioned before that
like when I first went to like some of
Ron's Harvest parties and stuff
um things by White Widow were one of the
most common things you would find yeah
um it was just it just became a huge
family
so in that regard I don't you know in
super silver haze did the same thing so
I do think there was politics but I
think there was a crew there that had
significantly better weed yeah I would
agree and they just sort and honestly
Neville you know I mean Shanti came in
with the white family late but Neville
pretty much dominated the 90s yeah to a
large degree yeah yeah absolutely I mean
yeah everything except uh
88 with skunk one and uh 91 up until the
White Widow in 95 was Neville everything
else is Neville so it was like Neville
had this had this big run and then
Neville and Shanti joined forces and
then the stuff they released together
under Greenhouse had a big run
um and I also think too that like I mean
because it did for me
um you know you'd go to you'd go to
Holland and you'd try to buy those seats
yeah
so by after the the year that blueberry
won the cup we have a new entrant for
the the the king of the crown which is
Derry from Barney's farm with Sweet
Tooth
um you remember the Sweet Tooth oh yeah
yeah that's some breeder Steve work yeah
the Sweet Tooth it was a blueberry sweet
pink grapefruit if I remember correctly
no no no yeah yeah yeah yeah
and you know there was this there was a
Fino suite two three
um there was a lot of seed there was a
lot of people I would say in that in
that era
probably the three or four most common
breeders as far as like new school was
like there was the white family from
Shanti there was the blue family from DJ
um you know there was uh
um there was stuff from spice of life
which is we were just talking about
there was a lot of work being put out
right then by breeder Steve you know his
his Louis Legends ultimate Indica his
Blockhead his sweet tooth
um and probably uh probably even the
first the the first edition of uh of uh
Brothers Grimm was right around that era
too I want to give props to the real
breeder of Legends ultimate indica and
that's my boy red red if you want to if
you want to check out red we have a
interview with him and Chimera ways back
a few of them it was I mean there's
always been a there's always been a
difference sometimes the person that
releases the seed line is the actual
breeder yeah yeah of course many times
they're the aggregator yeah and they're
the person that was willing to take
seeds from someone else and go public
with them in some fashion yeah you know
and a lot of breeders are a mix of the
two
they made some things themselves and
they got some things from other people
and you know and they went that way that
route but I would say that uh yeah I
mean it was one it became one of the
biggest drivers of uh of sales of seeds
and popularity it was like kind of an
event thing even if you didn't buy High
Times every month if you were a stoner
you probably bought the High Times
Cannabis Cup issue yeah
I would say in that era and there during
this time when blueberry started winning
because for two years it was blueberry
stuff that won
um there was some alleged alleged maybe
we should say alleged
people getting caught and banned from
participating in the cup for a few years
after Shanti and Neville disappeared uh
maybe our young our little buddy this
guy so yeah I mean they uh
that's that's kind of an interesting
story in the sense that greenhouse seeds
is uh was a partnership between uh
Neville Shanti and and Arjun right and
it was several very cool coffee shops to
visit in Amsterdam
um you know and they sold some of the
best flower in the in the spot and they
had they were the exclusive spot to get
uh Neville and Shanti work after Neville
left Scentsy yeah so for five or six
years there they kind of rolled the
roost and I think eventually Shanti and
Neville chafed under
um sort of being like the back end but
still had to be in the shadows a bit
while Arjun was the face
um and they decided to break off and do
their own thing uh as Shanti first and
then never a year later and after
Neville's experiences at Scentsy uh when
he partnered at Greenhouse he did not
let any seeds or breeding stock or
anything like that be controlled by uh
Greenhouse they kept that in-house
themselves
um so when they so they provided
Greenhouse with a bunch of flour and a
bunch of seeds to sell
well when they left that left Greenhouse
a real issue because it was the biggest
seed bank at the you know Seed Company
at the time it had been winning awards
for five or six years in a row it had
all these unique lines it was crushing
the competition and all of a sudden it
didn't have any breeding stock
um or any uh or any in-house breeders
yeah
and I believe that's when uh Franco got
hired
yeah I have no idea when Franco came in
that was I believe he came in after
Neville and Shanti left yeah he wouldn't
have been there when they were there and
he and he and then and then he worked
for greenhouse and they ended up using a
bunch of greenhouse seed that they had
to do Fino hunts and they started making
a bunch of Origins Haze one arjun's
haste Super Lemon Haze all these
different things yeah um but we believe
that they actually got banned from
competition for a year
for trying to tilt the scales in their
favor I think it was a few years fan
actually it might have been a few it
might it was at least one yeah at least
one at least one but it went to show
that what he really wanted obviously was
he really wanted to win some cups after
his Stars left yeah
it was a big Financial thing you know
so from 2001
to freaking 2 000 I'm trying to watch my
language so freaking 2000
12. it is a head-to-head show and this
is a long time between Barney's Daria
Barney's and Greenhouse and we are
basically having Cannabis Cup winners
with Morning Glory whatever the hell
that is a Hawaiian snow which was
whatever they were selling that month
this Hawaiian snow we have amnesia Haze
we're all familiar with that we have
Willie Nelson not made by Derry from
Barney's Farm our John's Ultra Haze
number one God knows we have G13 Haze I
believe from um who made that was level
two Neville originally maybe yeah yeah
but I think he gave it I think he gave
some of the Soma and so many so uh
someone did yes yeah but I think that
goes to show right there that
um there was probably a 15-year 18-year
period where the Cannabis cups and High
Times in Holland were the epicenter yeah
and then the epicenter shifts yeah and
you're talking right around that time
you're talking early 2000s right yep
2001 to 2012. well now we start getting
some of the early Emerald cups in
California
um now we start getting some more
activity the forums and things had
changed things a whole bunch so people
were communicating in different ways you
could you could buy and trade seeds on
the internet
um and Amsterdam started not becoming
the primary destination that people flew
to to get seed yeah you could get it
from Canada you could get it from local
different folks you could get it from
um you know dming people on overgrow or
cannabis world or icmag right yeah
I mean when you were first coming out
like who who was big on the Forum
selling seat
oh God who's big on the Forum selling
seed vikai
it was the end of the vikai era
that everything was like space queen
Widow something yeah JoJo was big
um Dutch Flowers had just started or
started ended
um
who else is Big during that time
Brothers Grim had already ended oh spice
Brothers
um who else who's that other dude um
it was another guy that did all like
brothers Grim Repros I can't remember
off the top of my head but yeah I did a
bunch of Apollo 11 stuff like that was
real big and TGA had just started uh
making their name
right
so and those are all for the most part
non-uh non they're not Holland based
situations exactly about that time Joey
weed thank you um I I had just I think
about that time I had been hipped to the
whole Market by about 2007 2008 I had
already been hip to the whole fact that
the market had been moved that
everything that the Dutch were selling
was probably made in Spain and not
exactly what they would have been
selling say even
10 years prior you know although so it's
fair it's also fair to mention that in
1999 or so maybe it was 2000 and they
changed the laws in the Netherlands
where before you were allowed to legally
grow cannabis to make seed
um and then they changed it and they
closed that loophole uh and around that
time a lot of the traditional seed seed
companies in Holland got raided yeah and
genetics were lost and and no everyone's
been very tight-lipped about that era
but we know since he got visited we know
serious seeds got visited we know Tony
from sag Martha got busted so bad he
shut down for 15 years yep um it kind of
rolled through so some Nuance of all
that stuff moving to Spain uh or and and
or Switzerland is all of a sudden
Holland became unfriendly yeah and sadly
people lost some stock some mother stock
and some father stock and you know and
things got mixed up and there was great
financial pressure to not admit what
you'd lost yeah
right
I mean it's kind of like we kind of
trust Scentsy in the 90s and
increasingly not as the 2000s went down
right
is as as Neville had less less to do
with greenhouse and Scentsy I think
I think a lot changed and it became very
obvious and it was mostly because I mean
there's only so many people that really
take everything so serious when it comes
to genetics and being that anal about
getting everything right the way it's
supposed to be there's there's only a
few that have ever existed in my opinion
so then you could probably say that
sometime in the in the early 2000s
um the uh High Times Cannabis Cup after
sort of like a 15-year run of dominance
really started losing Pizzazz and like
the capturing the imagination of stars
yeah it changed
um and you know we you know 215 and in
Colorado and there was different things
that were going on in America at the
time where things were starting to
loosen and open up more and more
um so the epicenter of Interest shifted
yeah
I want to say the first Emerald cup was
probably in the early 2003 or four let's
see
if I had to if I had to guess I would
say within a year or two of that and it
started in area 101 in Mendo
um which is a little bit little ways
north of Laytonville
um
and uh that's a property Tim Blake owns
and uh he threw events there for a long
time
uh I can't remember exactly when it when
it grew but but that's kind of like what
shift it is is cups sort of went through
a lull of not being all that important
yeah and then I think they probably had
a resurgence
when the West Coast Medical cops started
growing in popularity yeah the emerald
cup
um when the emerald cup especially got
bigger High Times started throwing
instead of having one cup a year they
started having how many man oh my god
well at first they were doing like
um like a High Times cup California and
then they would do High Times California
and I remember the first year Denver had
it and then it became like High Times
you'd have California one once or twice
a year it'd be California once or twice
a year would be Denver and then you'd
also start adding in Michigan and then
it became like three times each you know
each day each year and then it just
became a [ __ ] show of you know however
many a year I couldn't even keep count
anymore well that so that thing
dramatically changed it from like going
from sort of like a once a year event
yeah right that was fairly short to
turning it into sort of like a circuit
yeah right it was a circuit and so that
being that it was a circuit it morphed
from instead of it just being sort of
like a collection of people Gathering
and a competition yeah it it grew this
little economy all around it as well so
a lot of these cups it would be a gray
area in these states where you could go
and you could see a bunch of Growers
flower and you could buy directly from
small breeders right
um and so it became a way for industry
people to see each other yeah and uh
that was for sure that that really was
what it became to be it for a while I
think it was pretty special and I think
a lot of people thought it was pretty
special like not just not just on the
the business level like a lot of us
would make most of our money for the
year at Emerald cup
um but on a level where you get to see a
lot of the people that you grew up
looking up to in this business and and a
lot of times you'd get to have dinner
with them and you'd end up finding a
pier as opposed to someone you just look
up to it was it was a wild time it was
it was definitely different
so then it became multi-layered in the
sense that you could kind of turn some
of those events into what you wanted
them to be if you were super into the
competition you could stay in those
areas and focus on that yeah
um you know if you wanted to stay in the
area where you were going to meet a
bunch of breeders and Growers and
Industry types and various people that
would gather you could just kind of use
it to rub shoulders and network and chat
and see people in person yeah it's where
a lot of of clandestine people decided
to start showing their faces
yeah that's true too you know so it's
where you could go and decide I'm gonna
punch Matt Riot yeah yeah
that is a popular choice too yeah I'm
gonna go to Emerald cup and I'm gonna
punch Matt right in the face one thing I
don't want to forget it is for some of
the old-timers the nugs and jugs stuff
like that if you want to talk about some
of that real quick did we did we cover
it no we haven't we haven't mentioned it
at all we kind of honestly we just
started talking about like the lack of
of cultural impact that the can the
Cannabis cups from High Times had hit by
the early 2000s yeah and then we just
started riffing on their Replacements
but we really didn't go into depth
beyond that okay let's hit let's hit
nugs and jugs because I think I think
that's one of those special small events
that not a lot of people know about that
existed and why don't you chat on it for
a minute I wasn't around for that
yeah you go ahead
I mean some of them some of them we've
almost done like uh halfway whole
episodes on WE you know like Ron's yeah
you know those would be those would be
considered like uh like Harvest parties
or whatever but
um there was a lot you know separate
from like the emerald cups and the stuff
that was was was so blatant there's
invite-only cups yeah you know there was
invite-only Gatherings that had no cup
it was just the way for you know dozens
of of characters from our world to
safely meet up and swap stories and
seeds and plants and clones and weed you
know uh it was where a lot of like
little people's private interests
started blending
um and it was an ERA too before
it was before anyone was worried about
personal rep because that was so
fleeting and it was still dangerous so
yeah it was the kind of thing where I'd
go to a Harvest Festival and this dude
would give me you know a hundred seeds
of blue widow by by sweet two three and
this person would give me 50th people
were just excited to sh that you wanted
to take seeds of their work
you know so there was a lot of trading
that went on amongst amateurs and
enthusiasts and stuff like that but they
were all the stuff we mentioned before
there was a new wave of breeders that
had followings
yeah you know people were all excited
about breeder Steve and uh and you know
Brothers Grimm and
um you know DJ Short with all the
blueberry stuff right there was
exploding and you know all the white
stuff was popular because it added Frost
and density to almost anything you added
it to uh and so you know and there was
people going over to Switzerland and
seeing breeder Steve or seeing Shanti so
nothing like a little in-person chat to
make a fan base right yeah uh because
that's what some of the cups became too
right it was you could go and meet your
breeder and talk to them in person yeah
and there would be lines I mean you
remember this is kind of late in the
emerald cup but uh our buddy uh uh Bodhi
uh was famous for not being there yeah
yeah being there and not being there
yeah and the first year that he had an
actual booth I mean it was there was
like a 75-yard line for a day and a half
yeah
do you remember what he was doing that
day like the first time he showed up he
was yeah he was he was like getting in
costumes and getting in his own line and
like standing next to people and like
talking to them about his own stuff and
they didn't even know they were talking
to him and then like walked up and sell
them seeds real fast and they'd freak
out yeah he would and he yeah
I don't know if it was that year the
next year but he brought he got this a
hold of this enormous stack of original
1985 Neville seed bank catalogs yeah
that came from Clyde and it came from
Clyde yeah yeah I just remember he
walked around he had this big pack you
know this big side bag and he just all
the all every good friend got a couple
of copies of Neville's first catalog
that he put Santa Claus did it was
amazing yeah Santa Claus did and
probably some like weird tobacco seeds
and some some crazy Indian sativas that
he had gathered or whatever perfumes
there was perfumes yeah so that's just
the kind of neat thing that you can do
because it was like it's it's almost
weird in the sense that um all day long
uh you know customers and fans get to
hang out and get to go meet the people
and ask questions and buy seeds direct
from that person and know you're not
getting scammed yeah and then after all
that and between all that at night like
a bunch of the friends that are doing
all that kind of stuff get to actually
see one another in person yeah and I
mean that's kind of what our party's
formed out of was like
we would all be at the emerald cup we'd
all be like headed there anyways and we
would try to like make time for each
other during the day when we're doing
these transactions but we would get so
bogged down especially in the later
years that we didn't have time to even
talk to each other and we just we'd just
be like all right next year you'll catch
it you know whatever but so at the end
we were just like [ __ ] it we're just
gonna have to set aside a full night for
partying after where we can all hang out
away from everyone and just chill and I
you know like it it just naturally
evolves sometimes that way and it's
really fun you know it was kind of like
one of those old Harvest Harvest parties
of old
yeah you know where a bunch of people
bring a lot of nice weed and they set it
on the table and it's a bunch of
chatting and eating and smoking and
hanging out and
um you know there's there's cool Parts
about that obviously like with the
emerald cup and uh the high times and a
lot of the stuff that started happening
on the west coast it became again like
it was in the beginning with the High
Times festivals in Amsterdam it became
again like a Prestige money making
important thing yes yeah and people
would put a lot of effort into winning
because they wanted to advertise that
they had won you know and all the
shadiness came in like there was there
was uh they'll remain nameless but there
was some clubs that would just hold back
the nicest weed and hash they bought all
year yeah and then enter it under their
own label
yeah of course I mean that's that's a
move like how are you gonna prove it
wasn't your own bike but then you walk
into their thing and they've got all
these Medals of all the [ __ ] that
they've won look at all the good weed
that's been in our store look at this
yeah we've got all these different
Metals you know and uh and you know
hashmakers winning a bunch of metals
flower makers it's like it's it's free
Hardware it like makes you maybe it
makes it easier to sell in dispensaries
maybe it gets people asking about your
seeds maybe at this and that
um and so as a result of that it went
from you know Harvest festivals that
like they're totally non-economic way or
just a way of for a bunch of weed nerds
to conduct business make friends and
exchange yeah but then there's also this
Commerce aspect where it's like winning
is a big deal
yeah you know and so that's where the
that's where some [ __ ] comes in and
that's where room and you know we people
aren't the most like you know there's
plenty of non-ethics that goes into
something that's like unregulated
um and so there's lots of rumors about
how real or how not certain Cups have
been over time sure yeah I mean that's
gonna happen
you know people that win want to tout
their [ __ ] people that don't win want to
be like it was [ __ ] rigged this
person's friends or family are related
or this is happening or
they paid for it or there was money
exchanged or you don't know how it works
and you know there's uh there's probably
some fire there with the smoke
um there's no point in talking about
individual aspects but there were so
many of them and there was so much money
at stake it seems silly to think that
there wasn't some
you know it wasn't just purely
altruistic double-blind studies
dispassionately deciding uh which weed
is best absolutely yeah
definitely not double blinded any of
these events even when you try and I
told you about this earlier I won't say
which event it was but there was an
event me and another person
um spent making it was originally going
to be called the Breeders Cup and we
were just gonna invite breeders and the
idea was breeders had to enter in their
own weed that they grew but it was still
there's still an honor principle
involved with that right like they just
had to present it you know
um that that idea was expanded on and
taken for another cup and I went to that
event and it seemed cool and everything
you know everybody was chilling and
there was one thing nobody accounted for
with all these rules that we thought
we had accounted for everything someone
brought a green
jar that was Green Glass and clear
and anytime that jar was going around to
the different tables they always knew
where it was and it was supposed to be
double blind so nobody knew whose weed
was which right like supposedly or
nobody had a green jar exactly and when
it came by your when your own weed came
by and you knew it was your own weed you
had the honor System saying hey this is
mine I'm not going to vote on it however
suppliers of green jars voted on green
jar you know it it was a lot of [ __ ]
like that so even when there's things
you can't account for and I don't think
that they brought the green jar there
just to like purposely do that it just
is something that that organically
happened and it was like wait wait a
minute we have an advantage here we know
which one's ours and green jar won the
cup
I mean there was one there was a lot of
money to be made in that era I remember
like the the whole like DNA Crockett
partnership
um there were certain years of emerald
Cup on Friday and Saturday where they
would have like a four-way Booth yeah
they would just have a line spidering
off it in every direction yeah and
everybody was after Tangy and double
banana Tangy and this and that and
everything else and you know but I mean
it was like you know there were certain
if you were a hot
Seed Company leading into that show
yeah uh it could be a huge windfall I
mean for example like with what you're
saying right now during those years the
DNA and Crockett entered that stuff I
was laying out tons of Calio and banana
OG stuff in fact banana OG was the basis
for most of my breeding program during
that time and it didn't matter because I
I didn't have the prestige I didn't have
any of that like Crockett nobody knew
who the hell Crockett was before they
popped up nobody but the second DNA
picked them up
to the top because it was in all the
High Times magazines and all of a sudden
they were saying well we have this
banana oh it's in high times and it just
flew and you're not even kidding like
there were lines out it had always been
available ever since Oregon kid had put
it out someone was releasing banana OG
something ever since that point but it
was as if it had never existed before
the second entered High Times and the
hype had struck well I also think to tie
into like the marketing and the push
aspect of things I do think they were
smart in the sense that they in the 215
era they grew green they grew some
greenhouses of their work yeah and then
they got professional photographers to
come in and just take absolutely
gorgeous shots of their wheat yeah you
know and and some of their weed was very
photogenic you know
um and you couldn't tell if it was going
to get you high obviously or anything
like that but like Instagram yeah they
they but they drove sales with a lot of
AD copy and I mean Instagram you know uh
weed people weren't ready to be marked
marketed to yeah a lot of the popularity
in weed used to happen organically in in
small groups and spreading from there
yeah we talk about this ad nauseam every
yeah but it's like that's another
example of it right is that is that you
know I mean when I'll give another
example uh you know when uh when
Skittles was hard to get
right and so the vast majority of people
that was going to get after it could
only get hybrids you know you take a
somebody that had it like uh Dying Breed
seeds at the time or something and they
would they would have a huge line for
that first two days of emerald cup uh
all selling 300 to 500 packs mostly 500
of red seeds yep out the door just like
bam crazy because people were after it
so
um like Matt mentioned uh you know if if
you marketed your stuff the right way a
few of those events could take care of
you for the whole year yeah definitely
it was big and it was so it became so
much more than a like the the winning of
the cups was important
for sort of bragging rights and a
different way to Market but the other
part of it was just sort of this gray
area seed swap every kind of act all you
had to do was buy a booth and have a few
permits and you could do uh all kinds of
crazy sales
now you have to since 2018 you have to
be licensed it has to be through dispos
it's far more regulated and controlled
but in the era that Matt is remember
talking about fondly it literally was
sort of like a weed swap meet
open air Cowboy Market it was fun
sharing you know here's a joint here's a
dab talk about this oh I've got six
different eight different jars of my
different strains you want to smell the
line I'm selling I just grab them all by
their [ __ ] jacket and drag them
across the floor nobody gives a [ __ ]
yeah wow wow we used to uh I mean Matt
and I actually used to joke that we
could have like a charity boxing matches
at Emerald at Emerald cup where everyone
could settle all their beefs or not or
make up you know yeah oh you just
disappeared can you hear me still I can
hear you your picture went kaput
yeah I don't know why it went cupboards
so the right camera selected blah blah
blah let me see what's going on that's
all right go ahead and keep going but
yeah anyway
um so Emerald cup and those and and some
of those High Times especially in
Southern California for Crews down there
it became a place to regularly see other
people
it became a place where Growers and Seed
makers and various industry people could
meet up
um now it's like I'm split no you're
right good
um anyway they in my opinion
um you know a lot of people went and it
was sort of totally irrelevant that
there was a competition going on
uh you know they they went to just uh
they went to get seeds so they went to
meet certain people or they went to CNB
scene
um or just you know be able to walk
around and and see what who was
developing there he's back there we go
booths all kinds of stuff and so there
was a very cool
I would say like raw capitalistic
freedom to it yeah it was um it was
something special and that era is not
here anymore but also you know what what
else is interesting is we could bring
something up that I find kind of cool is
that the first all the first cups uh
when we first started getting like real
testing imperfect as it may be I
remember there was only four or five
strains that tested in the high 20s okay
right like literally it was like there
was a couple examples of chem 91 there
was a Strawberry Cough
there was a Scentsy star Scentsy star in
a headband and that was basically it
yeah right for the first five or six
years that there was testing with cups
yeah and then
we started to see test creep
where all these numbers and all these
terpenes and all these THC percentages
started climbing and we used to joke
that you know there was one or two
things in the 30 Club
yeah and then fast forward five years
and there's dozens of things in the 30
Club yeah
and you know and people started breeding
by numbers
because they wanted to show high numbers
in the dispensary and they wanted to
show high numbers in the competition
yeah I watched someone claim 50 the
other day on the reg so it's still
happening
I mean I would even say I I don't know
about people listening or whatever but
for my strangely for me I would say that
the not all of it but the vast majority
of my favorite weed tends to come in
between 18 and 25 percent yeah
I don't know why there's some exceptions
but it a lot of it falls in that range
um yeah and well I find a lot of the 30
Club to have boring and not very long
lasting highs yeah
You know despite I mean I mean maybe
they're potent in the sense or maybe
they wash well you know and they yield
well but I don't find that like you know
I don't think that all these 30
percenters plus uh are revolutionizing
cannabis and making these older lower
weaker things irrelevant it just reminds
me of the the old article from 1982 and
I want to say it was are The Connoisseur
who I think is someone I'm not going to
say who because he's never publicly said
who he is but um he was referring to in
1982 to ban the Indica he felt that the
Indica was going to ruin cannabis and
that it was going to dumb down good weed
and indica
afghanis pakistanis tend to be what shot
that that that percentage Spike up so
I mean maybe they were just Nostradamus
you know well I I think it's interesting
we we've chatted about that before too
but yeah
um most of the sativas they were smoking
were bred for smoking flour yeah and
indicas were bred for harvesting resin
and you know and the and and the two
things are very different you know they
didn't care about burnability with with
you know Afghani or Pakistani they
didn't care about like any they cared
about the hatch yeah the flower was just
a carrier and so I think a lot of I
think a lot of that stuff got worked
into weed
um due to you know police pressure yeah
flowering times indoors and it does seem
there was a lot of 70s and early 80s
heads that did not like the effects that
the indicas were bringing to the game
yeah they appreciated the earlier
flowering times and the chunkiness and
the frostiness but as far as the point
of smoking weed how they enjoyed smoking
it in joints yeah a lot of them felt
like it was kind of inferior
I I think a lot of those dudes like
nowadays smoking a thing like cookies
would just be that you know if you took
that to them in that time and brought it
to them they'd be like what the told you
[ __ ] you know I really do think
they would think that because now we
have a heavily inbred Kush style plant
that is you know very very narrow in the
type of high in my opinion that it gives
yeah I I mean everybody responds a bit
differently but uh you know people know
that I I don't I I don't reach for
cookie jars too often as far as like my
go-to's as far as what affects me pretty
well
um but I also say that you know I grew
up uh
and I'm not that young anymore I grew up
in an era where like the pure sativa era
was long gone yeah we were well into the
mixed hybrids era
um and uh there's a lot of tempting
things about Afghan yeah you know uh you
know the it's it's you're trying to keep
you know a lot of times a lot of those
early breeders like Neville and stuff
they were trying to add the structure
and the frost and the density from the
Afghan but keep the flavor
and the the uh I the effect from the
sativa and in fact that's why a bunch of
their Afghan breeding material was Bland
and low Terps and boring yeah
right yeah that's what it sounds like
you wanted yeah they picked
intentionally low terpene uh plants to
breed with sometimes yeah when they
wanted the terpenes and the and the
flavors to shine from the other side of
the hybrid through yeah
right so it was like a strategy
yeah that's what it sounded like uh I
don't want to expand on it yet I'll let
someone else expand on it
when we uh do that interview at some
later date
but yeah I mean it it uh one thing
that's very cool is that
uh we've done whole shows on specific
breeders
um mostly because in the era that they
came out there were so few of them a lot
of them dominated the game yeah uh and
even in the era we just talked about
with the cups there was really not that
many people in competition with one
another no not really when it came to
who is breeding the actual stuff that
was supposedly winning these cups yeah
you know it's like that era of the NBA
or whatever where it's like there was
like you know 12 teams yeah or something
you know where like there wasn't that
much competition amongst each other but
the competition was more concentrated
and then the American cuffs really made
it a democracy
yeah I don't think most people you know
uh Matt CSI
um you know uh Shaw uh you know you
could swamp boys you go through a whole
list of people that like
um a lot of people got introduced to
their stuff by walking past their
[ __ ] booth yeah
excuse my French but what just literally
just but just just you know there's a
banner yeah you're pushing through the
crowd and then oh there's Matt Riot yeah
you know
all that blueberry thing looks pretty
yeah they usually didn't see me I was
kind I'm kind of small so I'm usually
tucked in behind I just look behind me
there's 20 people and I'd be down in
there somewhere there's Matt waving up
from underneath underneath the uh yeah
yeah
three apples High giving them a wave
Matt's actually standing that that seat
is just it's a fake back yeah it's a
fake taxi I'm standing
uh but yeah I mean it it uh it was
you know a lot of times I wouldn't even
want to bug my friends who had booths
because people would wait all year to go
talk to Caleb yeah
you know they had a whole list of things
that they wanted from him and they
wanted to ask him questions and like
Whittle it down yeah same with you same
with you know there was a lot of you
could buy a booth
and oh you sell seeds you sell hash you
sell tincture you sell extract you sell
you know lozenges or edibles or any like
[ __ ] like that you could go meet a bunch
of customers and and make some loot yeah
I mean my favorite my favorite Emerald
cup story and I've told this to a bunch
of people and you'll probably get a kick
out of it you probably heard it a
million times but I was at Emerald cup
and
um this guy had emailed me beforehand
and I didn't really know him too well
but we had talked back and forth through
the email and asked me to put aside some
Clockwork Orange seeds for them and a
few other things but mostly that and
um he came up to my booth and he he
handed me this notepad and said it had
written on it hi I'm you know whoever it
was and I you know uh this is what I
came to get you know and I realized oh
he's deaf and mute or something like
okay and I you know wrote down what he
got you know you did the exchange he's
like do I get a discount and I'm like oh
yeah yeah of course like is he yeah so
here's a discount and so he walks away
and he comes back or no no before he
walks away he goes thank you
and walks off and I'm like this [ __ ]
guy what the hell just happened and then
he comes back and he asked me so do you
want me to put the the discount in the
fire fund or do you want it back so I
was like I put it in the fire fund that
ended up being Denali that's how I met
Denali really yeah yeah that so I never
forgot from that from that experience
out of meeting and those days like you
would meet thousands of people and it
was really hard to have a memory but
that was like one of those ones that
stood out because someone did something
[ __ ] crazy
yeah I mean it was uh it's it was a big
thing it was cool in that I like that
kind of like
disorganized chaos capitalism yeah you
know I think sadly
um legalization has uh stripped a lot of
that like organic uh there's a lot of
people that can't have a booth there
anymore I won't even attend it anymore
and not I don't say that other people
shouldn't I just I don't have a purpose
for going anymore now it I
I'm not involved in the same Community
those people are involved in they're
going to that with their licenses and
that kind of [ __ ] so so yeah so
obviously they're right there it's split
the weed Community yeah a lot of people
a lot of the people that you would want
to go and see
um you know people and you know people
would use IG and other things and they
would find out oh Matt or Caleb or this
person they're going to this event
they're going to be at Emerald cup
they're going to be at this High Times
I'm going to plan and go see them yeah
you know and people would come with
specific plans especially Emerald cup
because it was in December and back then
people usually had Harvest money burning
in their pocket and it was in an era
where a lot of people grew seed outdoor
because they wanted individual
good-sized plants
um you know that drove a lot of sales
too yeah that was a major aspect of it
there was a lot of 25 to 50 plant
Victory Gardens that they wanted to grow
from seed because it was generally
accepted you could get a bigger and more
vigorous plant from seed than clone so
if you were doing a limited number of
plants
um growing from seed you could probably
get more off that 25 than you could if
it was a clone plant yeah
if you pick the right strains and you
went in the right direction that was the
other cool thing about Emerald cup was
that it was a lot of
it was a good time to get a lot of
different samples of different things I
had released that past year from
different Growers that year who had
grown it and they'd bring me samples so
I'd go home with shitloads of samples of
my different strains grown in all these
different environments so there was just
so much unique to that time and I don't
know with legalization if there's ever
going to be a time where everybody can
enjoy that unless they're you know
multi-millionaires can can afford
licenses and all the other stuff I just
don't happen again you know there's the
old uh there's an old Grateful Dead
saying like don't be sad it's gone be
glad you were there
um and because
you know and when we were talking about
all these first cups in the 90s and
stuff like having that kind of open swap
meet where thousands of of potheads and
Growers and Seed makers and hash makers
and all that could mix and mingle and
talk yeah about their craft was
Unthinkable back then yeah
you know it was really Unthinkable back
then I mean I mentioned it before there
are definitely people that believe that
there was a lot of of DEA and other
agencies scoping at a lot of those first
cups I believe it and I was just
thinking now I don't know if you could
do it again even if you like found a way
to run a black market one with all the
freaking snitches in our scene like
they're just so abundant our scene
doesn't police itself for that anymore
it's just a too different of a time to
pull it off I really don't work I think
you could talk probably about like
certain areas of music or this or that
or whatever where there's certain things
that develop organically and they're
only there while that persists and then
when you lose it it's it shifts and it's
not the same as it was yeah
um and I think you know I think in
addition to you know cops became really
away for Because by the time that a lot
of these big cops were happening again
um people were willing to show their
faces and show up
people were willing to associate
themselves with I grew this and I have
this and I'm bringing pounds of weed
yeah and I'm going to keep it in my
booth and I'm not going to be arrested
yeah I remember even being sketched one
of the first times when they when Tim
first moved it because I used to go to
it up in uh in Mendo when it was thrown
up there and it was much smaller and I
remember I got there on a Saturday the
the first year it was in Santa Rosa yeah
and I was walking up to the front door
and there was this dude that was like
all waddling past me and he was all
[ __ ] happy as he was happy as can be
and he had like a box full of plants
that you know and it's like they're just
sticking out the top and he's like
walking to his car and I had this moment
of like uh you know of just having been
so secret for so long I was like man
things are really changing yeah
yeah you know and then you walk in right
and all of a sudden you're like
especially from someone who who grew up
in an era where like plant counts were
very important right and you know 100
could be a five-year fan you know uh
mandatory minimum federal sentence and
this and that then you walk into these
things and there was an ERA where there
was clone sellers that had like 8 000
cuttings for sale yeah
just racks racks of them racks of rooted
cuttings and you were like whoa
there you know what I remember one year
I was at a booth with a nursery and I
was selling seeds but everybody who
thought that the Clones behind me were
my stuff and right I remember that
caused so much chaos because everybody's
like yeah can I get a clone of that and
that it's yours right it's on this list
oh my God that comment you pinned you
know in Chicago when I lived in Chicago
I used to make friends that had a
totally clean lifestyle drive me to the
grow store yeah because of their license
plate
you know yeah I knew it dude who would
wear [ __ ] wigs and all kinds of
costumes on the way to the grocery store
and it wasn't a few cars yeah it wasn't
like boxes of clones was anything weird
or we hadn't been doing that among our
friends for a while it was just like you
were walking down the sidewalk in Santa
Rosa it's a big Fairground for people
that don't know it's a massive
Fairgrounds you're just like out there
like right in the open in the most open
sidewalk and everything it's like you
know tons and there's cop and like
you're just walking all happily down the
street with a bunch of rooted plants and
I was like oh
weird yeah you know weird yeah we don't
expect that okay and then you go in
there and you're like man people have
tons of dabs tons of tons of jars tons
of clones all kinds of stuff that if it
was like in your car and you got pulled
over would might be a mess yeah even if
you were fully like medical and
legitimate and went to clubs and all
that type of man it would still be a
mess but it was like an accepted gray
area like you were on base
yeah right depending on where you live
like I see dudes come to to my city and
like they'll be smoking a joint on the
street like it's nothing because they
think it's California and you're cool
and this is just they're still hot
places in California where if you do
that you're gonna get nailed so fast and
they don't give a [ __ ] if you have a
license or any of that they're gonna let
you go to court and figure it out so
yeah you know that that I uh it was it
is cool in the sense that there was like
an equilibrium at that time so
anytime you could feel free and open and
safe
in our community is a blessing yeah
that's for sure because it wasn't like
that for a long time and so I think
um I would say that the emerald Cup
itself probably turned into part
um part business
part economic part award uh and then a
big family gathering yeah
where all these people would come in
from all over the place from Colorado
from Washington from Humboldt from Mendo
from the Bay from LA and mingle yeah
you know
um and all that and you know cannabis
has not really been able to have
conventions
no well I mean not not at that point no
no so it sort of doubled it it sort of
like did all these different duties
you know
um and then it changed too because most
of the time the [ __ ] that was winning it
wasn't even that easy to go out and get
those and figure out like it wasn't the
same like it was from Greenhouse no
you know it was like oh this person won
with sugary from some spot in
Laytonville yeah I don't know how to get
that weed yeah a lot of the times it was
like that early on
um it I think over time it did turn into
more of uh only things winning that you
could buy seeds of because that is where
the money came you know was directed it
definitely got more like that at the end
of the cups yeah I mean everything you
know everything that's wild and free and
unregulated eventually loses some of the
wildness and and and they start acting
rationally in terms of money and and it
morphs into different things
um and then it you know it becomes what
the regulations and the rules allow yeah
now it's sort of like a cooler image
it's like a it's like an industry meet
yeah much more so than like a gathering
like a bunch of important people don't
even go anymore to me I think it's more
like MJ bizcon and I don't see a lot of
difference like I mean maybe they still
do Awards I think they have a separate
Awards event they moved it to La too
which is even funnier because
one of the things that was cool about
Emerald cup was that it started in Mendo
so it was done by people from the
triangle and old Growers from the
triangle and it was a big family
gathering and then even when it moved to
Santa Rosa it was still NorCal Sonoma
County is is very much still you know
the the very southern tip of that bubble
you know uh but once it's in LA and it's
in a theater and it's Awards I mean I
get it they're they're moving with the
industry Trends it's not going to be
what it was so is this Emerald cup that
everybody's talking about going to going
to be in LA or Santa Rosa it's now
is it going right now last weekend right
now yeah right now in L.A in Santa Rosa
okay that's why I didn't they call it
they call it I believe it's like they
call it the emerald ball now
I got some [ __ ] Emerald balls for
them you know and then I do believe they
have like a separate ceremony in La yeah
but it got a little convoluted with
covid for a few years there and not
being able to have those kind of events
and then they did a separate event in La
last year so I don't know exactly how
they're going to shake it all out yeah
but for a minute it seemed like they
were going to abandon NorCal for La
which was going to be kind of shitty
um but it does appear that they're still
throwing a party up there how weird is
it and I'll leave names out that the
owner of emerald cup was giving awards
to his daughter soon to be husband
and smashing all the cups with it was
did was that ever heavily debated or
talked about
I mean there's not uh as we talked about
in the beginning we were trying to avoid
specific instances because you know you
don't want to battle over a certain
ground but certainly
um there's whenever there's money and
Prestige right and all that stuff on the
lot reputation on the line uh economics
on the line
um that's why people debate whether how
legitimate any cup could be and then
there's people that get a little bit of
inside information and decide that seems
kind of sketchy
um in lots of awards uh family members
and close friends can't participate yeah
um but that's not true of cannabis
Awards apparently not it is definitely
enough yeah you know and um you know and
so you know doesn't it does you know
there's nepotistic things that occur
certainly and there's friendships and
there's beefs and there's in crowds and
out crowds and weed and
um you know I don't even know how blind
some of the blind stuff is yeah and then
if it is blind you have a group of
people and it's just their expression of
prejudices yeah and even even with all
that you're you're it's still the honor
System saying this is this strain I'm
presenting you I mean I'm I'm pretty
sure without I'm not going to get into
specifics but I'm pretty sure there was
at times some some weed that that was
winning quite a bit that was not very
pretty uh that was entered into the sun
grown categories and stuff like that
that was grown underneath uh multiple
nice uh indoor lighting like
supplemental indoor lighting yeah like
you have a little section that you're
growing your stuff you're going to enter
and it's in the greenhouse and it's got
the Sun hitting it but it's also got
Ceramics and some LEDs and some of this
and some of that and it gets extra
special sauce and yeah it's Sun grown
and then it comes out looking like crazy
and all of a sudden it's winning and you
know
um because people we come from a culture
that bends or ignores rules yeah I mean
there people will do anything to win
yeah especially when maybe if you win
you know
um that that next year uh you find it
way easier to move a lot of your
products for higher pricing and
dispensaries then and then that next
year because you won and all your stuff
was in dispensaries and a bunch of
people smoked it you have a crazy line
out your booth for your hybrids yep
so there was multiple there was multiple
arcs like that where people won and then
the economic interest was great for them
for two or three years after that there
was reverberations
so of course there's going to be that
kind of stuff always always you know
that's just I just don't think people
know you know that's a thing like
there's a
there's always the the announcements
there's always you know like stuff
that's surface level and then there's
the stuff that like people behind the
scenes know and then there's stuff that
people in certain groups that you know
or family friends of certain people are
like
how did that fly I mean [ __ ] I guess you
know it just does and it's it's not just
one specific cup it's a lot of them it's
all of them and like I said even with
the one that I helped organize and I
helped plan the rules for it there were
things that we couldn't even possibly
conceive of a grain jar like
we really thought we had it all nailed
out but there's always ways yeah we've
had friends we've had friends that have
that have judged various things and
they've seen things that they didn't
think were the greatest you know uh
behind the scenes
um and you know there's uh there's a lot
of pressure now I think
I think a lot of those cups they were
making so much money renting out
expensive small amounts of Booth space
to all of you guys yeah
um that just just throwing them was
highly profitable for them they were
making millions up just the booth space
it's ridiculous yeah um so you know
there was there was that there was a
desire to throw more and more and more
of them right
um and now with all the rules and
regulations and all that other types of
stuff it's taken a lot of the soul out
of it
and it's also just the competition of
people that can afford licenses yeah and
there's one more thing I want to talk
about before we I mean we're getting
okay
um
is judging and you know I talked about
it briefly in the gangier part you know
when they were talking about how they
select their judges or whatnot I noticed
that a lot of times at even some of
these prestigious events
judging isn't necessarily based on the
most
skilled people in the room at assessing
cannabis in fact most often that is not
the case when it comes to judging
um there A lot of times it's people
paying they pay for their judges pass or
their they pay for their judges kit
where they get all kinds of extracts or
Buds and
it's very hard for me to understand
someone that is new to cannabis being
able to have a qualified nose
um any of it really I mean how what are
you basing your whole or you know it's
another aspect too where it's like it
might be just a collection of Industry
people and people associated with the
people throwing the event yeah
you know and in some cases you're like
oh here's a random assortment of
different kinds of Stoners it's fair
the family buy your way in though blows
my mind blows my mind and that's for a
lot of these big extracts caps too like
just below buy your way into judge so
I'm gonna put something in and let some
random ass kid that may have smoked
twice in his life judge it doesn't make
any sense that's the thing it's like
it's totally unregulated and there's no
penalties and there's no outside body
governing any of it yeah so it's all the
honor System and like you said
um I mean that's part of the reason why
we do these shows is like because
there's a bunch of stuff we talk about
all the time that isn't well known yeah
you know a lot of people part of the
reason why the the cups thing works so
well is because for the a lot of smokers
they're just like oh my God that must be
some of the best [ __ ] out there yeah and
they don't have the Nuance to it you
know yeah they don't know the context
yeah exactly they don't have the context
they don't they don't know the
characters involved personally or
whatever you know
um and it's not to say that like it's
all corrupt or whatever all the time
it's just people have their belief
systems and they're influenced by what
they like and what they don't like
um and uh you know and and then you know
there's there's
it's like in food like anything that
doesn't have a legal definition like
natural yeah it doesn't actually have a
real meaning it's an advertising meaning
yeah I went over that one yeah so you
know so uh so cannabis judging right now
is absolutely subjective
yeah very much so and like I said to the
point of where
judge calling it judging may be a little
stretch and then a nice way of putting
it
the other part of it is let's say that
you're totally Advanced and that you are
uh uh Titan in your field and all kinds
of people respect you you know and you
know let's just you know and you're
you're in the hash game or whatever and
everybody loves the hash you make and
you're really good at it and you have a
fine nose for it right and you're
definitely one of the people that could
be judging sure and then you're smoking
20 dabs in five in in two hours yeah
yeah like the effect of each individual
dab and like what it does to you and how
it makes you feel or even if you're
smoking 20 joints in the course of a few
hours of different weed and you're
layering all those effects and highs on
top of each other it's not like you're
waking up in the morning smoking a joint
of this
going about your business and really
getting a sense for what that one thing
does yeah
you know so unless there are some places
that give you samples ahead of time and
have you take a bunch of notes
um but there are there are there's also
like uh
um just back to back to back to back to
back to back yeah
right and then how well can you judge
typically when I smoke 10 or 15 kinds of
weed that I don't smoke on a daily basis
I get ripped yeah
yeah yeah it's just what happened you
know I smoke a bunch of my friends weed
you know and it's weed that I don't I
don't smoke very often and it's all
rapid fire and I'm just join after joint
after joint
yeah you know I might not be the best
judge that day yeah
you know
um I don't know if you don't like the
way that I matched my uh my my clothing
to this lovely chair behind me I think
it's pretty good you did a good job
matching it I went through you know
there was a huge debate in my prep team
uh on uh
you know the designers that you have
sponsoring you I know it's a big wide
choice in your wardrobe it's all the it
but it really does is it accents all my
face makeup you know and that gives me
that natural tone that I'm after yeah
it's good it's working well for you son
so
so yeah I mean
so we're at one minute or I'm sorry one
hour 23 minutes we'll probably cut this
one a little bit short but I wanted to
um let everybody know we're going to be
doing the show at a different time now I
mentioned briefly on Instagram you're
going to start doing the shows on
Saturdays after this show there's the
last one on Fridays we're going to start
doing it Saturdays at 1pm Pacific
Standard or whatever time Pacific 1pm
Pacific Pacific time yeah yeah so that's
where the the show is going to be moving
to uh we were we were kind of looking at
where everyone like YouTube gives you
those like statistics and that seems to
be where everybody is watching at a good
time and we've noticed that people say
like they prefer to watch it on
Saturdays in their grow room and I know
this is late for the east coast and
especially for some of our um across the
country people and not so is back and
forth across the country all the time
now and he's he's he's getting old he's
getting a little old in his age we worry
about him we worry about him staying up
too late so yeah is there anything else
you wanted to get in on the this topic I
mean I uh I think you could just simply
say that uh you know cups are a little
bit of humanity you know there's
Community
um there's meeting with people of of
similar interests there's bringing
different groups together that might not
be that might not have been friends or
met before there was a lot of positives
to the different eras of the cups yeah
um and then obviously but you get rep
and you get money and you get
um economics involved and then you get
all the shadiness and the backhanded
deals and like the how can I lock in
money for me
um and those kind of things go hand in
hand so when you hear us talking about
all of the ways that we fall short on a
perfectly ideal cup it doesn't mean that
uh there's not value
to going and seeing folks and and doing
all that type of thing
um it just changes uh you know people's
reasons for going change yeah you know
and over the years they've the the whole
existence and reason for them existing
have changed yeah and I mean I think
some because they've happened for long
enough now some of the excitement of
just being able to go and meet a bunch
of people and put faces to names yeah
you know that might just be an internet
handle there might just be a someone you
knew from IG or whatever but then you
get to spend a few hours with them and
and break bread or whatever
um because you met at the cup and get
baked and exchanged some cool [ __ ] yeah
um that was a neat aspect for a while
it's become more common now so it's not
as exciting
um but in the beginning
um it was it felt pretty special for a
good long time it did and you got to
meet some of the most amazing people
that you could meet in the industry at
one point
so for all those reasons I have mostly
positive memories of it yeah I will say
something funny though and this isn't
going to knock anybody but I remember
going to the cup
and I thought to myself especially when
it was in Santa Rosa I'm like we are the
worst dressed group of people there is
this dude and he looks like he went to
go transplant you know in his car hearts
in his ripped shirt that day and then
sweated and then rolled down the dirt
Hill and then drove to the cup yeah but
in his hand he's got like a fifteen
thousand dollar dab rate yeah right
right and a really nice fanny pack you
know and so you think oh that person
looks homeless except for their carrying
around this like foot tall piece of
glass that's like worth a small car yeah
worth more than my life
right you know and so there was just
there was just people that like you know
what you what you put your money there
was like well dressed snazzy people
there with nice watches and this and
that they were straight Hill hippies
with zero ink like I don't even have
clean clothes yeah but I have all this
cool weed [ __ ] you know and I don't care
and so it brought together very
disparate groups of weed people
yeah watch out for that dude walking
around pretending to be deaf and dumb
too watch out for him he's a
[ __ ] yeah
yeah he's a tricky old man dude perfect
script from up north or catapulted
all right so
um anything else dude no I mean just
that we're we're gonna move to the
afternoon on Saturday like Matt said we
hope it's a better time for everybody
um and uh you know it might be easier to
give us that than your Friday night uh
especially for people on the East Coast
so for people's lives in general yeah I
don't know what that is but uh and you
know everyone's at the emerald Cup this
weekend probably so enjoy yourselves uh
and uh have a good week everyone yep
cheers
foreign
[Music]
Square burp scripture
there's some GNC
dude I'm sorry dude I'm tripping but