welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
[Music]
revolution
hello everyone welcome to the breed of
Syndicate I am thousandfold and tonight
I'll be your host because unfortunately
uh Matt isn't feeling very well um so we
got the youth here we have bringing back
farmer Dan uh from the last episode
which uh was quite the hit if you
haven't checked out the episode of farad
Dan I highly recommend checking it out
we've got MADD booze back and we've got
local back back as well and tonight
we're going to be talking about
selection so we're returning to some of
the breeding Theory uh that we started
on last season um and yeah also want to
recommend checking those out so I think
we did four or five
episodes uh on breeding and I've made a
little playlist on the channel so you
guys can go check that out I'll put in
the description as
well um but yeah so we thought we would
this is actually Boo's idea to do one
focused uh more focus on the selection
part of reading um I think for me what's
interesting is that you can't really
talk about selection without talking
about everything else right so it's
we'll probably go over some of the same
concept but from the point of view of
selection which I think will make it a
little bit different um and yeah
hopefully even though it's somewhat
theoretical we'll be able to lean on the
experience knowledge of some of these
guys uh and maybe get some like
anecdotes or examples as we go
on
um but yeah I think without further Ado
uh we can jump straight
into what are you selecting for um and
so I guess here with we're thinking
about like breeding
goals um we're thinking about like trait
selection um and perhaps another way of
thinking about this is like this is
maybe when you are thinking about the
genetic material you might have at hand
and where you might be taking it um I
wonder if farmer Dan could start us off
because I'm kind of curious I mean you
know we're kind of fresh from his
episode and I kind of want to know like
maybe from his work experience you know
what is that very initial point of
trying to decide like where a project
should
go um I think with a lot of people work
that it's honestly more like just an
exploration originally where they're
just like I like these two things I
think it would be fire if they go
together and it's kind of just more of a
mashup you know what I mean but like
that can still be real breeding if
you're like actually do Identify some
traits that you really like out of there
and um start selecting for that you know
and so um especially when there's like
not a lot of new avenues to go down and
so um I usually start with something
that I like app parent and so like a
popular one right now is rosin and so I
like to like really deep dive like why
like you really get in and see like
what's up with this plant's resin you
know and like microscope it you have to
wash it you have to see how it's
breaking off you know and just like
really hone in on that one
thing you know and that's kind of like
how I start is that like I just like
find something that I'm really
interested in and then I want to learn
everything about it before I even start
trying to work it you know
mhh I mean I think that's quite an
interesting distinction as well like
whether you have enough information to
even know what you are wanting or
looking for um because it might seem to
some people like ah like why are you
just growing these out without knowing
what you want but it's like how do you
know what you want without growing them
out yeah well and if you think about it
a lot of people buy seeds because they
don't have access to the Clone that they
want to grow and so if you can't get
Skittles you buy a skittles hybrid but
you still haven't experienced Skittles
yet and so you kind of have to grow
these and like that's your only
experience from it and maybe you do find
something you like you know and so like
you know what I mean not everyone's like
blessed to have this like wide staple of
plants to work with and like work with
them long enough to have like gained
experience with it and you know some
people have to start from just the first
seed packs they buy and so I feel like
that's kind of like more common than um
guys like us that have like you know
access to big libraries and stuff if we
want it or need it
MH um I don't know local and Bo like
yeah what do you guys think in terms of
like determining goals and you know
determining what you're looking for all
that what are some of your
thoughts yes so selection's sort of
Paramount to the whole process so the
the idea I had for this one was not so
much selection as you know what I mean
selecting a particular plant but the
whole process throughout like when you
even select a packet of seeds to begin
with like Dan said you know going with a
cultiv you're familiar with or perhaps
looking to delve into a line you're not
familiar with and and find something
else out like it really starts right at
the start so like right now for instance
um I'm not staying in the spot I'm at
for quite a long time I'm going to be
here for a couple months so for
selecting for my outdoor this year I I
went with shorter flowering things than
I usually would you know I didn't really
plan a breeding project or anything like
that just wanted to stick with
a couple of things that I'm interested
in taking a look at that won't fill up a
lot of time but when I'm selecting uh
it's pretty much always based on one
primary trait and and that's the effect
so um I think it's interesting having
Dan and having local on because uh it's
uh it's preference you know it's
personal preference when it comes to
effect as well and um there's a lot of
other selection criteria that comes into
it that can be like secondary criteria I
like to call them you know anything from
um the bouquet so you know the nose
flavor you know longevity of the high
stuff like that how it breeds Etc if
you're going like deeper into it all but
I think the primary thing people select
for uh should should always be high and
uh everything else lines up with that
you know so when you're you're making
like a large selection from a large pool
and youve found like a number of
cultivars that are have the effect that
you're looking for then you can start to
look into those secondary
characteristics and those LS you know
and see how many line up on the same
plant and go from there
but uh I I think it's interesting to
hear how other selects too because like
Dan in particular you know coming at it
working in um cultivation facilities you
know working in such large pools where
you're potentially calling and stuff
like that I'd love to hear sort of more
about that
too yeah yeah we we're going to get into
some of like the differences when you
get to SC like you know different scales
and stuff um and before we get dive into
some of those like yeah I want to hear
from local as well just like initial
thoughts when I say like you know
determining breeding goals trait
selection you know what do you
think um so yeah like um me for example
like I I sometimes I do pop things with
intentions but a lot of times it's kind
of right recently it's been just to kind
of learn stuff um but like once you kind
of have an idea you know like you kind
of have a direction on where you want to
take it based off of what you
saw
um like for example
um I have like a a sweet pee um it's
really really like narcotic and I I love
it a lot but I don't want narcotic lead
all the time um so like since I know
that um I think like you know
um an approach to kind of mitigate that
would be Crossing it to narrow leaf type
plant um something of that nature um
but yeah I don't I don't really pop
things with um like intentions to cross
just yet but I do like having Keepers
obviously from a
pack yeah yeah and I think you you
brought up a good point as well which is
you know sometimes you're just trying to
Counterpoint um certain things with with
other things um or like set up like you
know interesting like jux positions
between like two quite differently
expressing plants
um yeah okay no really interesting to
hear you all about like uh that thing
about intention and information because
you
can't really I think it's quite common
sense all you can't really have intent
without information really it just
doesn't it doesn't really make sense
yeah yeah I think all of us kind of
touched on the fact that it's just like
there is like an exploration period
perod for most people when they're like
growing something you
know yeah and you know we can we can now
turn to like some of the stuff that
booze is interested in like you know
some of the initial conditions I guess
of the genetic material you're working
with as well as like your
own uh scale constraints I guess you
could say like you know infrastructure
and resource constraints so yeah here's
where we we talk about like the
difference in
like maybe doing a an exploration or
hunt on on like a commercial scale like
Dan as opposed to some of the smaller
scales um yeah boo did you want to say
anything again about that stuff like
yeah just touching back quickly on so
just touching back on the goals and
stuff quickly too um even what Dan and I
were talking about before the show it's
kind of relevant to exposure as well
like local and I were talking about some
of the sativas and stuff that we've got
at the moment of smoking with and Dan's
like not as into theas but he came to
like look into some Mexican stuff so
your goal should be relevant to that as
well you know what I mean like if you've
been exposed to something you like it
you want to breed that because you know
it's the thing that you're into that's
um something that I think gets a little
bit overlooked and muddy these days
where a lot of people are just breeding
for maybe these secondary traits that
are less important uh like Instagram
sort of specific traits so yeah that's
another thing that um yeah I think it'd
be cool to get
into um so in terms of so sorry you
wanted to talk about
like uh primary and secondary traits is
that what you were suggesting or yeah
I'm just saying that like in this day
and age so like back in the day when
yeah s yeah back in the day when there
was like less pressure to like breed for
Instagram and stuff like that and you
just breeding for yourself that it was
you know what I mean there was less need
to talk about this kind of stuff because
everyone was just breeding for primary
traits just the things that they like
which was the effect you know what I
mean in this day and age there's less
people that are are working in that line
and more towards these secondary traits
like the way things look or color and
stuff like that and so um yeah it's
interesting and then like when you get
into larger populations and stuff like
that when you're finding a lot of
cultivars that have got this uh effect
that you're looking for um yeah I just
want to hear how it's like how people
would go about that like you know how
you going to select a specific plant
when they're so similar you know what I
mean like are you going to have to look
to a lab and stuff like that and use
numbers so yeah I'm just interested to
hear how um some of the other fellas
sort of see these secondary traits and
how they'd select like if they've got a
line for instance like local with his um
electric boo across to Appalachia
Appalachia that he's popped he's got a
number of ones that he's like really
into so how does he go to whittling that
down to um you know just one or two
plants
um so so I grew uh a handful of those um
were
female um and they were um some that
looked like uh appy
um and kind of uh smelled like it um
more or less like some of those
um kind of um like I don't want like tar
fruit um I haven't like grown the appy
pure but I've seen some of like bod's
hybrids and there's like a common note
that is totally
appy um and a lot of those had that
smell and then there were some that had
um like dog [ __ ] smells um I've only
smoked the dog [ __ ] I haven't um grown
it myself
um
but what I I liked about a lot of these
not a lot of um like yeah maybe four out
of the the number that I grew uh they
had like really nice like sativa Spears
and I'm I'm kind of a sucker for that if
I'm being honest like that that's kind
of why I'm like looking at the sativas
like the high is great but man that like
that structure I mean you can make
something productive out of it
um but yeah I kind of um kept four of
those um that had
that structure um and now I'm kind of
just
uh doing a lot of the tests um smoking
right now um and some of them have like
a a leathery kind of savory thing going
on and then there's this one that has
like a mango gummy bear smell and it's
like kind of pretty transparent to taste
um and the effects are great and I'm
just like
uh it I'm kind of like don't know where
to go like do I just like go if they all
have the same effect do I just go for
Taste um and I'm kind of thinking so
like I think that's kind of the next
step and calling the the next or the
handful that I have at the
moment yeah there's like a the way I
think about it too is like when you're
working at home you have this like great
opportunity to like throw all those
secondary traits out the window and just
look at high because you're you're
really ideally just looking for
something that you like to work with and
that like you like the effects of and
then like when you start scaling up to
like going into a commercial scene well
then something's got to be like a five
out of five in every category or it's
not really like marketable in the way
that it kind of like has to be to like
sell well nowadays and there's that
whole secondary
drive like that they have to make a
profit off what they're making and what
they're selecting through and so like
secondary becomes like they all become
primary really because it has to smell
good it has to taste good and translate
it has to be like pretty and it has to
get you high and so it just like it
honestly limits the number of plants
that you can even find that meet the
criteria by like a few factors of 10 you
know I think I think we're at like a
tenth of a percent of everything that we
pop even has a chance to go commercial
and so it's a the numbers go way up and
then you start seeing tons of multiples
you start seeing maybe you don't find
what you're looking for at all in that
first generation and then you have to
kind of make the call of like oh well do
we try and like F2 it or BX it or like
keep moving it forward to see if it's
there or do you drop it you know and
because there's there's a financial cost
to all of it you I mean no matter what
scale but it's really significant at a
commercial scale and so um you can even
kind of get into the point where like
the process itself is its own selection
pressure because it has to Vibe within
your like speed and pacing of what
you're doing it has to Vibe with like
your soil and cultivation environment
and so like that's one of the things
that I've been noticing a lot is that
the process itself ends up becoming a
selection pressure that weeds out a lot
of really good plants that never even
get a chance to be
seen yeah no I makes sense absolutely um
that at higher numbers you you just
you're you're just increasingly
splitting hairs right yeah and at that
point you either need more information
or otherwise you have to rely on like
either like arbitrariness or like or
like your gut right yeah and you can do
things like comp pair testing numbers
but like does it really like represent
what people prefer in reality like from
what I've seen usually not and so um
then you start getting into this world
of like well how do you like quantify a
subjective experience in a way that we
can like run numbers on it and that's
really like it's a pretty interesting
challenge in itself of like um running
those types of surveys and then like
trying to run stats on it and like get
anything useful from it besides like oh
well these people liked it and these
people didn't you know it's really hard
to get answers out of people about that
kind of stuff too and so um when you're
breeding for yourself I feel like it's
really easy because you have that
freedom but yeah when you're breeding
for the masses it's like well what's
like the largest number of people gonna
enjoy and that's kind of like a weird
interesting perspective to have to take
on you
know I'll say this as well like this
conversation's quite a difficult one
because it will feel quite circular
MH uh right because you in in kind of
like we've already kind of articulated
how you kind have to move forward you
know weird like you have to move forward
to like move back to move like forward
again sometimes to get like you know
different kinds of
information
um but I think we kind of also jumped
straight into like literally the
evaluation decision-making part but
there are some other things I wanted us
to talk to first as well like so I had
this whole section that I thought we
could talk about which I call like
initial conditions so this is stuff like
what numbers are you working with what
generation you know what filial
Generations are you working with uh how
stable already you know how narrow uh is
the is the pool that you're working with
and if you've already determined you
know what your your target you know
primary secondary traits are you know
how much do you know about the
likelihood of those traits being
passed um so this kind of I guess this
kind of information partly arises from
an exploration already but partly it's
also about like the numbers you're
working with and like yeah like I said
like the filial generation and like what
you know of like the boundedness I guess
of the of the genetic pool already um do
any of you have like Reflections on like
what some of those things how some of
those things would
affect the project overall or like how
you start
out yes say like if you yeah got a
little case study sort of thing man so
to speak so going back to that I guess
trait base selection we've got a cutting
a friend of mine found Eli local bird
seed shout out dude uh it's sine cross
to Kentucky blueg Gras from pip so it's
still Violet so he found it in I think
out of two packets or one packet it was
one of the runy aenos super low yielding
compared to the rest but the smoke is
just yeah it's unlike the others in the
pack super dank always Lays me out cuts
through it's got an amazing nose on it
too but it was an outlier so to speak
from that pack so right now we're going
through the stages of how to work on
that so he's done some hybrids uh he's
done a couple of interesting ones he
crossed it to uh Southern Charm from
goat and monkey which is like a Irene TK
so already there he's going back to a
grandparent of sorts you know what I
mean it's the in the from the saene on
the mother side of the steel bolot so
that's one way where he's tried to uh
just enhance that effect to go back to
an initial parent you know what I mean
so like a back Cross of sorts and so
working that forward we're trying to
think well how are we going to be able
to put that into a seed form how can we
get that particular phena to pop out
when it itself already was an outlier so
talking about like selfing it so we want
to S1 it and then listening to what
people like chir and Caleb have said
about locking in traits by selfing you
have to take it to an S2 but then an S2
as a seed line can be something that's
uh generally hard to germinate or this
that and the other or you can just
present itself a lot of problems like
even popping s1's like I had this idea
about when you get s1's you're going to
pop them and it's going to be like an
exact replica of the parent so when I
see all these s1's off it I'm like oh
okay that's just you know what I mean if
I want to try that clone I'll buy that
S1 but then in growing a few packets out
and seeing like all these weird like
runty like inbred Expressions that come
out of it I'm like oh okay so maybe like
a feminized hybrid is the way to go to
find like a better expression of that
initial parent you know and so now it's
just like like you said a little
circular but it's like what path do we
take you know there there seems to be
like multiple ways to skin this cat so
if I'm trying to like lock in this one
trait and select just for that when it
itself was an outlier like you know
there's a few paths to go down so I've
listed like you know Crossing it to
itself a couple of times or potentially
hybridizing it and searching for that so
that's something that I'm interesting in
if you guys have gotten any experience
of having like a particular trait that
was you know not super prevalent in the
line like um say like that Cherry AK or
something something like that and how
you would go about potentially breeding
towards
that yeah like I think an easy one is
like the Z TPS because it seems to be
just like this oneoff in the genan pool
because like when you S1 it you don't
find things that are like exactly like Z
they'll be close they'll be nice they'll
be similar but they're not dead ringers
and so um you this is like the part in
the process where I feel like you have
to get like a little your hands dirty
too like you do your pedigree analysis
to the best of your ability and kind of
like look at what the parents are if you
know anything about those parents like
what do you see about like in the
progyny of like what you're working like
a hybrid of them you know um to just
like identify like what you think might
be coming from where but then like you
really have to like to see how
something's like past or to see how
stable or inbred or narrow it is you
know you have to uh like roll up your
sleeves and start you know growing out
plants and so like on the z um it seems
to me that that Aroma profile that's
like really pungent is a fairly
recessive trait and so when you outcross
it to something that it's not closely
related to you don't see it pop up very
often at all you see kind of like its
dwarfism its like resin traits of being
like Sandy and kind of oiless um but you
don't see those those tur profiles show
up very often
um and what I've kind of noticed is like
I had to like
re-evaluate the process that I was doing
well like maybe using that parent itself
doesn't pass that trait the way that I
want it to well what if I take two of
its children that
like they may not even have the profile
but they have a nice one and if you
cross them together you get this double
up of that recessive you know and so
that took like a lot of and that worked
for me you know and I found a few nice
plants that were kind of exact what I
wanted and um but it was almost random
at a certain point because like yeah I
had an idea of the project but I had to
like grow all the plants out and I found
two out of you know like a couple dozen
that were exactly what I wanted you know
and so um you really have to just like
start making the crosses and growing the
plants out to see like how something's
inherited um local any Reflections on
that not that I could add at the
particular
now yeah yeah
um anything to say about how do I put it
uh feels like we have covered okay Dan
maybe what's your take on like in terms
of starting points
like does it change your approach to
know that you're working with an S1
versus like an
outcross yeah cuz you can kind of like
feel that there's no outside influence
of another variety you know like I I
look at s1's as like a peak into what
the the parentage might be especially on
these like clone only types and so um
that's like one of like on the same like
example like a zerp thing that's like my
next Avenue of uh exploration is like
well do the s1's pass it better than the
the original clone did you know and so
I've I've yet to see like a real world
example of that yet but in other s1's
I've grown uh
you know like you can definitely see
what gets locked in easily and then the
things that are like more Elusive and so
then you can start
um kind of like playing with that in
your mind and kind of unraveling the
mystery in the puzzle um on like filial
Generation Um I had a thought on that as
well um because I've had projects where
like I had a really nice mom and a a
reversal that you know passed the traits
that I wanted but but a lot of the
traits were kind of lost in that F1
hybrid and they were all kind of bland
and kind of boring and it actually took
getting to that F2 Generation to kind of
like segregate traits a little bit and
get the Expressions that were more
interesting and a wider variety of them
where that that F1 hybrid was kind of a
the honestly one of the closer things to
an F1 I've seen where like all the
plants were like identical and like you
know just like a slight Nuance
difference in Aroma between um
uh between each other you know and then
in the F2 Generation you got this wide
segregation of all kinds of stuff and
that was so much more fun to play with
and look through than that F1 because
it's like I'm not trying to make like a
true F1 hybrid where they're all
identical like I'm not growing fields of
weed I want really interesting and novel
combinations of things and so filial
generation can play sometimes it's worth
going forward because you know you're
actually going to get new
combinations
yeah and I think that does articulate
one of the big tensions uh within every
project where it's are you looking for
outliers or are you looking for
stabilization or
homogenization right is that is that
like a feir
paraphrase yeah like I don't really want
like homogeny you know like that's like
that's a really common goal of plant
breeding because of the application but
like when you're growing indoors and
it's a clone
that you want identical to be packaged
so the consumer can have the same
experience every time that they go and
buy that which is like a standard across
all commercial products really you know
like you don't want a different
experience every time you go open a can
of Coke you know but weed's kind of more
on that like
wine uh you know like more like sensory
pleasing type of product that like
everyone kind of has a different
preference and a different like it's
just like beer you know um some people
want their cheap beer they Mexican beer
their craft Brews you know um and so
there's got to be something for everyone
and that's why I don't really breed for
anything but diversity now because it's
like I want to find new combinations of
things I don't want a seedline that's
like all Keepers because it's so much
easier to fix the secondary traits than
the high you know and so that's what you
I always find in a really stable line is
like kind of boring
weed is I'm interested in Boo's
Reflections on this uh because I think
that's an interesting take which is that
like um can you say it again secondary
traits are easier to fix yeah like it's
easier to fix the structure the look The
you know what I mean like it it's it's
not that hard to make most of the plants
look the same but to get all of them to
be like a great high or a higher
prevalence of them because it's like
breeding's a stats game really like
you're looking to like increase the
probability that something's found in
you know like if it's 1 to 20 in the
original you doing your selections maybe
brings that up to one and four or one
and two and that's a success you know
what I mean that's like um it's far as
like a stabilization project goes um but
like fixing High seems to be like really
elusive that is fascinating who thoughts
it's why the whole thing's such a yeah
man it's like why the whole thing's such
a head [ __ ] for me because you get
something like all right you get an
elite and you times it to an elite and
you're likely to you know what I mean
you're starting the good stock on both
sides the
you know you can kind of expect what
you're going to get but then you get
something you know you hear about like
the breeding of Hayes and stuff like
that and how they had to work through
you know so many generations and so many
different lines and like made so many
wrong steps so it's just tricky to get
my head around and I guess like you said
there's no like one way to go about it
there's so many different ways but I'm
um you know like you just don't want to
forget something in a line like even
what local said about before and all
right um I want I saw a few Expressions
come through that were like spear like
and you know they really had the high
that I want so if I select for that way
like you know through link traits and
that like what am I leaving behind so I
think realistically I'm like I'm looking
for a model that can be applied to to a
lot of different selections like whether
I'm working with some sativas and some
hazes and stuff like that whether I'm
like looking through some some indicas
or some you know what I mean some some
more broadleaf stuff um how can I know
that I'm going to be like how what's
like a Target model for breeding you
know what I mean like what's a Target
model for for not leaving these traits
behind I had a I had a kind of uh
tangential question maybe off this which
is we've talked about effect being you
know a primary trait that you know we we
can somewhat agree on partly because
it's elusive but partly also because
it's desirable right what about
something like smell
flavor because that there those two are
often sometimes even
like uh pitched as though they were
intention right like sometimes you know
you can find something that has great
smell and flavor but it doesn't have the
potency right so often you hear about
that
tension yeah I guess that's like with
the Skittles and stuff like that what
dam was talking about it's not like
purported to be exceptionally potent but
it's still you know what I mean Super
famous line everyone's into it and even
like what Caleb's doing with the
reversals and stuff like that um
reversing one of his selections like
making S2s looking for that particular
smell so I guess yeah even with the
bubble gum and that everyone says it's
not the most potent line but you know
it's got an amazing no so I guess these
are considerations you know people are
doing these kind of things so like on a
larger scale Dan like when you were um
doing some of these breeding for for
other facilities and stuff like that was
that one of their major concerns like I
know you said in your interview that you
were you had selections that you might
want to have kept but they never would
have seen the light of day because they
weren't what met the the quoter or the
you know what I mean status quo there or
whatever how how did that go was it like
they were going for the stinkier sort of
ones or the ones that you know bit
better Aesthetics so no sometimes
there's stuff that's like really tasty
and like really or has a really nice eye
but it's like horribly
ugly you know it's just like not gonna
be salable or marketable because like
you could never take a nice picture of
it and like a lot of times those will go
into like either like future breeding
projects but like most the time they end
up in the bin you know because it's like
it was almost good which is not good
enough um and so uh it's it's kind of
unfortunate in that right but there is a
lot of people that breed like almost
exclusively for flavor because like
potency itself is also subjective you
know some people only like to get so
high I hear that from a lot of older
folks like when I've been in
dispensaries and stuff and there's some
senior citizen with their veteran hat on
and they're like oh the last stuff you
gave us was like way too way too strong
like we need need something lighter and
so um there's like a whole portion of
the demograph or a whole demographic of
the um consumer pool that like kind of
wants light weed because you know when
they maybe first tried it or whatever it
was probably only 10% THC or less and so
uh um I actually do like tasty weed it's
not like it usually is lower potency in
my opinion as far as like Fruity and
Candy stuff um but it's desirable in its
own right like I like to have them
around and like do blends with more
potent weed like a nice OG or a chem or
a hybrid of that you know um and then
put some really tasty wheed on top and
get some of that flavor and so I think
it all has its place you
know I want to ask you as well Dan like
and this is probably what I would
consider like a naive question uh but
you mentioned before that you thought
fixing effects was harder than fixing
some of the other like maybe more
structural uh trait
would you say the same of smell and
flavor that it that that can be hard to
fix as well or yeah it can be pretty
elusive some stuff breeds really
dominant for it you know and you can see
that and it makes life really easy
because it's just like every time you
have like a population you're working
with like for me right it has to be the
five out of five things um every time
one of those is fixed it just makes my
pool of selection slightly easier to
pick through because then you can go
based off of potency and other four you
know like it makes it Easy by
eliminating one of them because they're
like oh they're all really pretty or
they all taste really good and so um
that doesn't have to be a pressure at
that point you know and you can start
looking more and diving into the other
things without that convoluting
it
yeah I feel like there was part of that
I didn't answer but we're all Stoners
sorry no no no I think I think that was
you know I think we got we we got the
point and there's also of course like no
definitive way we can say that
like uh that's always going to be true
right like it's just we're just talking
about like what from what you know
someone like Dan has seen uh in his
experience
um yeah I mean anything else in terms of
like some of these I'm calling them
initial considerations but it seems
silly to call them that now because like
we discussed like you already have had
to done quite a bit of work to even know
about some of these questions or answers
I guess um anyone have any other
Reflections because if not we can move
on to quite an interesting thing which I
think people don't get to talk about
that much um in this
process anything from you
local or anyone
else yeah well I've got something but I
think it leads into the the second bit
so I don't want to I don't want to
[ __ ] all right we we can just so we
can move on and then you know again like
this talk honestly like while I've set
out these kind of
like progression of points like honestly
we're just going to keep looking back so
whatever so the next thing I wanted to
characteristics and stuff like that like
I've been [ __ ] on them a bit but
relevant to note taking well they're
super important because you can't smoke
it till the end you know what I mean so
you don't know really how the effect is
going to be so having all those
secondary characteristics to lead into
your note taking and breeding notes and
stuff like that super
important well that was that is this
section right so this section is about
like I think again especially from Dan
it must be it would be very different
from like anyone
doing uh breeding with seed making at
home but it's about organization and
like how you you organize your
information uh your data collection all
of that um but maybe this time we start
with like booze or local like on a
smaller scale like how do you get ready
to embark on this kind of project like
what do you prepare in terms of like
your notes or documentation you know
that kind of thing do you take notes
local like do you have like a little
notebook that you're writing down all
your observations on or do you just take
pictures or what's your call um I do a
lot of pictures but I also like you know
I have like a note on my iPhone um that
I kind of keep like track of the smells
more or less
um
cuz like I don't know you you can't
really smoke it like you said so
this information
is it's relevant but it it's not
relevant until like you you've done the
final analysis of all the data I
guess yeah because I like to look back
on it after like I I generally keep two
separate sets of notes like the ones I'm
holding now like handwritten and that's
like while pretty much like from week
two or three of flow I start doing that
so I don't really care about in Edge you
know what I mean things will just do the
what they'll do and generally I'll group
them like before I flow them out I'll
just group [ __ ] from highest to from
like tallest to shortest you know and
that might not be realistic of what
they're going to perform like just like
growing a bunch of stuff from seed I'll
do it that way and then I'll start
taking notes yeah week two or three flow
pretty much once they start putting
putting out a smell so I'll be like
writing down you know Aroma On the stem
um if I'm seeing any resin or stuff like
that even the way like the FL floral
structure is so um if it's like tall or
short or uh how similar they are to one
another and then depending on how many
things I'm running I'll start grouping
them as well like if I'm running um I
don't know 14 different fenos from a
line and I see that okay three of them
are presenting this like you know sort
of more rounded top more of like a moth
Bly sort of nose whereas these other
ones are more like you know Spears
taller bit more gassy I'll like group
them together and then when I'm actually
trying everything out after drying it
and assessing again I'll um go and those
categories and assess that way and so
like when I'm whittling down um you know
14 fenos down to to four you know I'll
have my four different categories and
you know select the best one from each
of those categories and then go from
there so that's that's how I like to do
mine I um I think it's really helpful
like I used to just do it all in my head
and I still do like for the greenhouse
where I'm just growing like one packet
of seeds but where I'm working indoors
and I've got like you know multiple
packs of things on the go and I'm trying
to like keep on top of everything I find
it super handy then when I'm calling
I'll generally just go through you know
and just assess and um group
characteristics and then yeah cut back
from
there yeah I'd have to say like my like
home process is like really similar to
that as well like I just keep a lab
notebook like I did in college and [ __ ]
and um I set off a section leave a few
pages and just take notes on you know
structure and height and you know
estimated flower time when I cut it down
um if it was responding well to like
just the base feed that I was giving
everything if it needed something extra
or like needed more water on average
just like really base cultivation notes
so that when I come back and find if I
find something I like and I come back
and regrow it that I'm not like starting
from square one again with like you know
uh what I think they're probably going
to prefer and like um but um it gets a
lot more hectic at a commercial scale
because
um I was just talking about it with on
the server with someone in the DMS and I
was just like it's it's chaos at times
man I have like 40 spreadsheets and um
they've got everything from like like
I'm a little tedious with my notes right
especially at work because like I'm
taking notes all the way through flower
just like brief ones and like they're
really just like what stands out the
most when I'm like going through a big
room of like seedlings and you know
they're already flowering like it's like
I'll take a few small notes but it's
really at the end um where we start
getting a little more intensive and so
like I'll look at like it's height it's
General stature like it has big strong
stems or it's thin and lanky I'll look
at uh like its Leaf ToBD ratio if it has
like lots and lots of big fan leaves
coming out of the buds or if it's more
like an OG and they kind of just are
little skirt at the bottom kind of thing
you know um I'll look at a lot of resin
traits like whether it's sticky Sandy
I'll look at uh you know General Aroma
profiles triome density as far as like
is it like you know coated or not and so
like I have a lot of like um qualitative
scales that I use for that where it'll
be you know like high resin density
versus medium or low kind of thing and
like you know little sub ones in between
um but um yeah the the real note taking
happens after it's dry you know that's
where I start getting like a lot more
meticulous about like Aroma notes and
effect notes and um what I
like there's a part of me that wishes I
had that much more time and money
because I would totally build something
for you yeah it'd be fun I've been
wanting to do a community one honestly
where it's like you know like send out a
pack of seeds and I'm like all right you
can grow it your way but it's like these
are the traits and like the things that
we're looking at and these are the
scales and it would take some big effort
you know what I mean but I think it'd be
really cool like crowdsource Big Data
pools like that where you're like have a
thousand seeds popped of something you
know I was thinking mostly just about
managing the data so I could know I can
easily Envision like a tool with like a
proper database um with you know proper
querying and Reporting and everything um
yeah that's what I was talking using
spreadsheets yeah yeah yeah there's like
a few um there's like a a company called
like breed Bas there's a bunch of them
honestly that are like kind of plug
andplay Solutions um but um there's no
like can of specific ones as far as I
know so there actually might be a market
for that you know because it is kind of
its own different process and like the
needs May differ vastly from like a
normal crop that's in the ground for
quite a while or you know only gets
turned over once a
year
yeah yeah but it it's clear like how
critical documentation and like proper
archival is for this process especially
on like a certain scale because like
booze was saying there's just no way you
can hold that stuff in your head past a
certain point even as a homeg grower
like I had some plants that I forgot to
take notes on because it was like during
that whole surgery thing and um I was
looking at them dry and I'm like I can't
remember anything about this there's
five of
them it is easy to forget yeah it is
yeah and so even it's also not long
before like your current run just blurs
into like previous ones as well for
sure yeah um anyone else got any other
points on like organization or like
documentation yeah danam when you're
doing like those massive pops like 600
seeds or whatever are you guys calling
in veg or like early bloom like based on
some of these traits if like you're not
seeing enough resin density or whatever
or no nothing like that but we will call
stuff that's like uh like um not
thriving in the environment like if it
misses like you know cuz we have to like
clone everything keep a backup copy and
then send it off to flower um and so um
if something like say doesn't clone
easily it'll probably get taken out if
something um isn't thriving in the
environment it probably gets taken out
if it Herms it definitely gets taken out
like Zero Tolerance on that sort of
stuff and so um you end up like removing
probably about 40 to 50% of the plants
based on on some of these traits on
certain runs because they're just more
prevalent in those lines for whatever
reason I'd love to have the numbers to
be able to do that you know what I mean
because I keep [ __ ] like my buddy will
pop like s1's or whatever and he's like
oh anyone that comes up looking mutant
or trifol or whatever I'll just [ __ ] him
off but I'm sitting there thinking like
man my friend found you know this one of
the best plant I've ever smoked and you
know it was this runty little thing so
I'm like you know if I'm throwing away
all these little ones I'll you know what
what am my behind potentially so I'll
keep him and I'll just baby him like if
I keep him in the veg a little bit
longer and you know FL him out longer
than the others I'll hang on to them
because yeah so I always wonder like in
large facilities you know you'd be
stupid when you've got like investors
and stuff as well you know you can't
spend time [ __ ] around with like you
know seedlings that just won't veg Etc
so yeah it's interesting to hear there
is a cost to it though you know because
it's like a lot of people say those
runts are the best smoke a lot of the
time you know and so that's one of the
things I wonder when people talk about
like that the highs are disappearing on
on Modern weed now is just like if it's
really the process selection pressor
that's like removing Those runs before
they even have a chance to be evaluated
as flower kind of thing you
know there's something funny to me about
this because it's
like
the I I feel like CSI is one of those
people who's famous for saying that he
likes growing out those runs right or
seeing what referencing yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah cuz once you've lost them
you can't even go back and know whether
you made the right decision or not I
guess unless you like keep them all the
way until the end still and just just to
like prove to yourself that you made the
right call but that's so much working
and of itself um yeah and again at that
scale it almost necessitates being
really ruthless because you have to be
but I mean like Skittles I think is a
dwarfy little mutant that probably would
get cold in any facility ogkb is
probably a little dwarf mutant that
nobody would select for I think OG even
to a certain degree falls into that
category because it's real finicky it'd
probably get cold nowadays just because
nobody wants to grow it because it's
like you know it doesn't fit the model
that's going around these days that's an
interesting point right because am I
right in thinking
that by any idealization of like
structure and yield and everything a lot
of hype strains wouldn't necessarily
like be ideal fits right so fashion and
the market are also clearly playing
playing a huge role um in I mean it's an
obvious thing to say but I think that
actually kind of links back to what we
were talking about earlier with the um
like fixing secondary traits is like one
of the reasons that's so easy is because
in the modern gene pool it's all coming
from such a narrowed down point that
it's already fixed for me like I don't
have to select for Purple OG structured
low Leaf to Bud ratio plants because
it's like honestly what's fixed in the
genan pool more than anything else you
know it's almost like a new Baseline
yeah exactly it's the new skunk
one and so um it's a it's just it's good
it's a good structure it P it passes it
because it's so fixed but you know um
that's why kind of what I was inferring
earlier on by like oh it's easy to fix
secondary traits it's not easy if it's
like you know a rarity in a jean pool
but like in AR jeene pool that most
people work in it's uh it's it's all
fixed for you and so that's what I meant
by
that local you're a academic type
academic young man AR sh do you like at
University and the things that you've
learned about selection so you know
going all the way back to like um what's
his
name what the do with the [ __ ] P's
name
again yeah man
the yeah um yeah going back to that do
you find any of that applicable to to
the breeding that you do like are you
you know leaning on academic [ __ ] for
that or what
um in a way not really
um
like I don't know there there's just so
many genes at play that it doesn't
really apply but like I think there
still is like
um you can kind of achieve an F1 you
know if you properly select the
parents
um but I I haven't gotten that far to
like have two true true breeding parents
you
know
um but I don't know I'm kind of just
looking for good weed man and like yeah
breeding can fix traits to do that but
like at the end of it
like you know good weed is good weed
right um so I was interested to ask you
because everyone will obviously see own
by this chat I know [ __ ] all about
breeding and genetics and all that kind
of stuff so I was interested to see
someone that actually has like learned
this kind of stuff if you find that any
of the academic literature is relevant
to to breeding cannabis just at home but
but I find the whole thing I
actually oh sorry oh yeah no go brother
go for
it um we actually like basically had a
whole episode on like the science and
what we felt the limits were in
application it's probably worth like
rehashing a little bit of it local just
did touch on it slightly like Mendel's
model uh of heritability does depend on
like certain conditions ideal conditions
being in place right like you actually
knowing which uh Al's map to which like
traits uh which
um like whether it's like a a proper F1
leading to sorry proper like IBL parents
leading to a proper F1 which leads to a
proper F2 Generation which often we
don't really get I feel like in in
cannabis and then we mentioned a whole
bunch of other things as well like there
are these other strange things where
what is it like one trait can be
controlled by multiple
genes um or or one gene being linked to
multiple traits is that possible as well
I feel like both of those are possible
yeah well like people the the scale is
kind of what people fail to like realize
is that like I was doing some um reading
on some Gene correlation studies with
reversals and it's like 12,000 different
genes that are activated during the
reversal process that aren't active
during flowering and each one of those
um has like on average 12 different
alals or versions of that Gene and So
like um they're it's it's like
incomprehensibly complex you know local
did you have to do like taxon
um and like I plant ID when you were in
college um so that those kind of classes
were actually like kind of done being
offered because a lot of the boty
professors were like kind of on their
way out yeah they're always retiring and
like right and taxonomy it's
like I don't want to say it's a dying
field but like it's not really relevant
anymore sadly except for grasses grasses
are the only thing I would have loved to
do something like that but it mine was
kind of more like um ecological models
and [ __ ] like that yeah because I was I
was actually just having a conversation
the other day about how like I didn't
learn anything about breeding Beyond
mendal like I learned I took a bunch of
genetics and evolution courses and like
ecology courses and stuff but the the
only thing that I feel like really helps
me in like my breeding is like really
was the the tax the taxonomy and the um
plant ID and like developmental Anatomy
because you get um you get like really
used to identifying really really minute
traits that are like sometimes not
visible to the naked eye and like um
that's like what's determining where you
go next on the dichotomus key of like
what you're looking at you know right
and so I feel like that's like really a
really good like training course for um
trade identification because you're just
honed in onto all these micro
features that that's interesting that
you bring that up cuz uh one of my
professors she did a lot of like um what
was it um like pedigree type analysis
where she'd grow a lot of like um you
know um crosses that she would make from
you know different populations or cross
within populations and kind of see what
genes were coming from what specific
population um and it it like when you do
stuff like that you kind of do learn to
pick up like those really minute traits
that might not like be an end all be all
answer but like you're like okay I know
this characteristic I know that this
will breed can breed for this you know
type of deal
deal um but if anything it was more like
um learning models yeah what it is it
it's nice to know um but it's not a sent
yeah it's not like a whole piece like
it's not a tool in the toolbx per se but
just like a
mindset right
yeah and mendle got lucky people always
forget about that like he was looking at
like the perfect plant breeding model
possible of like like real simple
dominant recessive jeans and like a
plant that's like an obligate in Crosser
unless you like open up the flowers I
don't know if there was luck I think he
it was intentional right like he chose I
I don't know
man but yeah yeah that's true it could
have been intentional I I haven't I
haven't read it referenced that way
but well I think that's always what's
interesting about any application of
Science and we talked about this on your
episode too where like the construction
of the model and then testing the model
is like one thing but checking the
models fit to reality is not the same
thing um yeah yeah
exactly
yeah yeah I mean that's that's
definitely the kind of question I would
love to ask someone like Chimera if you
know if and when we get him on because
it's even aention for me in producing an
episode with him where I'm like I'm sure
he could tell us a lot but it's like how
much of it is just out of theoretical
interest for most of us versus like
stuff with like practical implications
for us uh
um you know us people at home so to
speak yeah yeah there's a lot of really
cool theoretical and like like
technically achievable stuff that yeah
that just doesn't have any real
application to like further anything but
it is really cool like I've designed a
bunch of experiments like that they're
just like absolutely worthless probably
wouldn't work but they're like a really
cool theoretical
concept yeah I mean like this is a
little detour here my peps but like from
your experience
breeding and selecting on those
commercial scales like have there been
lessons you've been able to take
home yeah the genan pool's way more
narrow than most people think that's
like what always like is just like
smashing me in the face is because like
you get a new marketed name and you grow
it out and you look at it and you're
like oh it's just this slightly reworked
or reflavored you know and so it's
actually hard to get diversity outside
of the Sea World you know isn't that
because of like the particular playing
field that you're in it is yeah yeah I
mean but it's kind of like I don't know
it's been hammered on this show a
million times just like that the genan
pool's kind of you know like in trouble
as far as like the way that it was
legalized made it to where you know like
the nurseries want to Mom up something
that's going to sell and so they pick 12
or 15 things that they think will sell
and what sells right now is like candy
gas Purple OG structure and so like
there's economic forces like selecting
the genan pool right now which is really
stupid yep yep yep I think yeah you're
right it's very shorted this narrative
well yeah yeah it's nothing that hasn't
been said on here I feel like a parrot
so you no no no no no not at all I mean
like that is those are the conditions
that we are facing and so it's hard to
ignore them when yeah like you said like
smacking you in the face every day but
then like whenever I've been to a new
state that's been legalized cuz like we
always tried to be their first is uh um
you get a lot of cool cuts that kind of
just CRP up from all these people that
are just like hey I've got this and
there so you know like Regional diet of
weed um but there's no provenance to any
of it you know what I mean and so it's
like oh did I really have that or was it
just this weird oneoff thing you know
like I saw some stuff like that in
Oklahoma like this dude like showed me
some weed and it was all lime green he's
like I call it Mountain Dew and it kind
of had this like I don't know it had a
soda sweet smell to it you know um but
never heard of it never seen it again
and so like there is pockets of
diversity it's just like we need good
caretakers kind of
thing
amen um well we this is funny like so
the next section I I had in mind is kind
of looping back again honestly it's it's
I called it evaluation and decision-
making and I suppose like this is this
is kind of after you've gotten all your
information right all your data sets are
there you've flowered and I I presume
like harvested and tested
everything and you're at the point now
where you're having to make those
choices of like what to keep and whatnot
to keep I mean we've sort of been
talking about this the whole time right
this is this is selection already so I
don't know is there anything else you
want to like talk about again while
we're here um anything that's come up
for people since we started talking
about
this I mean like it's all that that this
is the part where like you're going to
really enjoy having your notes you know
what I mean because when I'm smoking
something I like to look I like to read
my cultivation notes while I'm smoking
something and writing down the smoke
notes you know um and so uh I'm actually
more curious about like the criteria
other than like yeah that's fire um that
Matt and local are both um like how are
you thinking about it because like I'll
always have like a few decisions where
like obviously there's the one that was
like the strongest and there's usually
the one that was the tastiest but is
there anything that ever like sticks out
to you guys that you guys are like oh I
don't I don't know why but I have to
keep this for this reason I mean like
for me for
example things that like to like grow
themselves essentially is a it's a
really nice
um trait for me uh I don't know why but
I'm kind of just
like at this point a little convinced
that things that you grow better are
ultimately can express better so it's
like when I'm selecting something that
grows a lot better for me I feel like
I'm ultimately going to get the more
true to expression and it's not like my
weed doesn't ever get me high you know
what I mean like I don't know I get you
know it all works
um
and you know like for example like the E
appy stuff I thought a lot of the highs
were all there but it's just like it
comes down to like what is going to grow
the best for me what do I want to keep
around the
most but it it becomes hard because
like you know you have that whole fomo
thing uh yeah for sure um it's like you
know when when you get rid of something
you're almost like kind of second
guessing yourself cuz you're not sure
what was lost like you don't know what
you can't get
back it's like how long do you keep it
you know yeah exactly at this stage and
then yeah how many how many cards do I
want to keep as I said before like if
you've got a line and you've got like
four sort of relatively different
expressions and you're a fan of all of
them like you just hang on to everything
or you like recombining those fenos in
an attempt to you know what I mean
create something that's even better in
combinations it's interesting like where
do you go from there and I like I tend
to hang on to stuff probably longer than
I should like I have like two or three
things and I'm just still whittling it
down and cutting hairs and at that stage
I'll start asking friends and I'll be
like all right which one do you like out
of that and you know what I mean like if
I if I really can't can't get to a
logical conclusion myself about it and
um yeah so of also it's like where do
you go from there it's the next step
like is this the epitome of this line is
this like where I want to with this
plant do I want to try and maybe get
another packet of seeds and see if I can
find something better than that and yeah
it's the fomo thing too and I guess it's
a little bit of imposter syndrome even
like looping back to the start with
exposure like you and me thousand um and
even local to an extent not being in
California but like you and me you know
what I mean we haven't been exposed to a
lot of these things so I have I've been
to Amsterdam I've tried you know a
couple of decent hazes and stuff over
there and other cuts um but for the most
part like you know I haven't smoked the
real Sour or I haven't smoked like noog
any of these baselines really so you
know I'm keeping it I'm like the you
know obviously I'm keeping it for myself
but you know I like to think of like I
know myself as a bit of a seed saver too
like I've got a large collection and I
want to you know keep it around not just
for myself but for others as well so
when I'm thinking about like you know
selecting something or hanging on to
something I'm like [ __ ] is this even
worth it like you know I might like it
but you know is it worth like just
getting rid of this so I can focus my on
popping more packs of seeds to find
something even better like I guess not
having that um exposure to that stuff
like you know you sort of set your own
baselines and then yeah it's interesting
oh definitely man like I it's funny when
when Dan was talking about in a way I
guess how jaded he was with the Jean
Pool I had to also had I had a moment of
being like you know I'm so far from that
right cuz I I just haven't seen haven't
seen any of that
um and so so even like right now I'm
running uh Blazer Panda's born in the
purple which is a T1000 from CSI humble
uh and uh Underdog URL also from CSI but
Panda selection and it's my first
encounter with like an URL OG
combination and an URL like full stop
it's nice and I know that it is nice but
I also can kind of see through it I can
see in it I guess
like where people have taken that since
you know we want to consider o OG
probably being like a a component of
some of what's Happening back like way
upstream and it is fascinating to kind
of get these like snapshots uh of where
things have been and gone or like where
things have come from because prior to
this I was also doing like you know TKS
s1's 91 S1 KMD hybrids just to kind of
like yeah start working my way through
some of those names um and it is a very
different experience I have to say for
sure um uh and like you said as well you
know in a way it is a bit of a gift too
because we're not as
constrained right by either like the
market or taste or like
fashion
um but yeah definitely interesting yeah
no myars over there I
imagine no oh [ __ ] plenty of Myas dude
just full of yeah
damn that an easy one to bring over
right like yeah I guess so yeah that
part that's the easy part you're
probably closer to where the myars are
getting made than I
am oh man good point yeah probably flies
fewer miles here yeah yeah
um yeah man it's uh I think the T1000 is
probably
like it's probably one of the places I
would tell people to go if they were
looking for like better or like
healthier or just like reinvigorated
versions that would still hit that
modern appeal you know what I mean
because it is the base of like
everything that we look at in some
convoluted way um yeah and so just but
just imagine if that's all you ever
saw at the same time you
know um when I try it I'm like I can see
how nice this is but I'm like I can also
see myself getting quite tired of this
as well you know yeah yeah and like it
it's fixed you know it's truly fixed and
so um I don't know I'm just kind of
tired of smelling those creamy Anis
Aromas they're good I still like them
there's always a place in my heart for
some Sunset sh um but um past that I
kind of think that's where it peaked
honestly slightly tangential but um
brings up interesting point that spindle
made yesterday in the Discord about like
potentially making a new clone only you
know so it's weird like 90% of the [ __ ]
well I won't go that far but aside from
cookies and stuff like that but you know
what I mean 90% of the [ __ ] that was
kept around seems to be like from the
'90s early 2000s with like all the hazes
and diesels and kushers and Chim and
like that kind of stuff like the [ __ ]
that was kept around in Clone form train
R stuff like that um how would you even
go about making a new clone only in this
day and age with so you know what I mean
like a million marketing channels and
stuff like that to have to Wade
through I think it was like uh I can't
remember who I was talking to maybe it
was local but um I was just like looking
at like the modern jeane pool in that
bottleneck and I drw a [ __ ] little
diagram I'm like OG pers and then you
know like just like the base you know
like thin mint sherbet gelato everything
we have now and I think the way to make
something new is like more like what
some of the homies on the server are
doing and so I like I really like when I
see things like um last episode we
talked about pack and the um Santa Cruz
wreck like like that's a really cool
it's two clone onlies right but I think
where like the real magic is bound to
happen is that like that's an uncommon
cross that I haven't really seen made
before this and then you also get high
and Lonesome and he grabs it and he
takes that and Crosses it to the appy
and like neither of those are really
like they have maybe some elements in
some Modern things but it's so outside
the fold of the bottleneck that we see
now because it's like an upside down
triangle is how I view the modern gene
pool and we kind of just like fold in
some things from down below every now
and then but it still comes down to a
point where it was like one or two cuts
um and so um being completely outside
that gene pool and like going back to
pedigree analysis you know what I mean
like like you can look up enough of this
stuff to make sure and just be like oh
like this seems like an uncommon idea
and I'm outside the primary gene pool
that's like what people need to start
doing and start adding some new trees to
the forest instead of a new Branch to
the family tree kind of thing I'll say
that some of those Santa Cruz recks man
look pretty [ __ ] zah like yeah on par
with like modern blue dreams resin
coated man when you grow it right and so
like I can totally believe it and she
gets dark or at least the Santa Cruz
wreck some of them got pretty [ __ ]
dark dude I've noticed that the Blue
Dream throws purple with LED like uh
pack and I have talked about that a
little bit you get a lot more of that
anthos cyan in production for some
reason with LED over Sun grown or you
know HPS
huh I I wanted to okay I kind of want to
signpost one thing I think we're kind of
like leaving behind selection I think
that's probably good I think we just
open it up and just like we can all just
talk about like what we're into in terms
of like projects that hypothetical or
real projects and and stuff like that
and I wanted to prod local a little bit
because you know he he now has like and
I don't know how much I don't want to
pressure him to like talk about if he
doesn't want to but I feel like now he's
kind of got a really interesting library
and a really interesting kind of like
pool of genetics to work with and I'm
curious to know like you know what he's
going to do um loo do you want to speak
to anything about like what you you're
thinking of maybe playing with in the
future you can be vague if you want um
or as detailed as you want to be um so
yeah um right now like I don't have
particularly anything in the works but
I've been
um working on reversing the sweet pee um
cuz I'm I'm super set on it um I think
it it has really great smoke quality and
I I think that I can use that to my can
you tell us about the lineage again just
for the people who don't know what that
is oh yeah so that sweet pee um so it uh
comes from
uh two um p91 s1s um two different ones
that bitter um Bitter Sweet SD made um
he made that like two and a half maybe
three years ago um and I've grown about
14 um and then there were two that I
really liked um and now I have the one
that I have but it I've I've had it like
for going on three years now I want to
say um what kind of plant is it what you
know what does it smell like what how
does it
hait so um that that's that's the hard
part it's
uh it's kind of like a soapy in a way
bright um at least my my specific sweet
peac cut because uh not not all the p91
stuff would smell like this um at least
based off of the the sweet PE that I saw
um but there's kind of like a a nice
soapy um bright note some slight n uh
nutty kind of notes to it like a Savory
kind of nuttiness and then there were
some that had like a a leathery note to
them but with that like kind of
bright I don't want to say like um
eucalyptus but more like camper or
something like
that yeah totally but it's it's it's
really hard to describe the smell cuz
it's not
like it I can't really put words to it
other than like in my cuts instance like
that bright and soapy smell that's okay
what about so you've obviously thought
about what could complement it obviously
or like or pose like a Counterpoint to
it what what are your ideas or possible
ideas um so uh so I guess we could take
this to kind of like the primary and
secondary thing like I I know for a fact
that it it's pretty damn strong um and
now what I'm looking to do is uh kind of
either reduce the potency or like kind
of um use it to like carry taste better
if that makes sense so like something
like the Death Star I would I would love
to pull that off but um it's not looking
too successful um but it would have been
nice to kind of see what the sweet pee
would have done with the Death Star in
terms of kind of being able to carry
that n like that rank taste
um because I don't know we like that
like it it does taste good but sometimes
I don't think it carries the best if
that makes sense I don't know like it
it's it's hard to to put to words but
kind of that super skunk stuff doesn't
always taste the
best yeah cuz I was going to actually
ask you for just everyone like rounding
out the historical context like the p91
itself like you know what what is the
vibe of the
p91 um that's the thing is we don't know
like it it throws I don't want to say it
throws a lot but it throws enough to say
that it's a poly hybrid of some
sort um at least in my opinion because
like you know the the C the sweet PE is
like two S1 so relative like you would
in Theory it would be like um relatively
stable
right um it was like in regards to the
potencies and smells but like there was
varying structures and you know that to
me kind of points that there might be a
little more behind it
than you know some some may would think
I don't
know okay no that's really cool thanks
for telling us about p91 I mean
uh I also wanted to ask you about some
of the nld stuff that you have also
because I think then booze could also
speak to some of that um and also want
to hear from boo about what his plans
are with some of those but Lo what yeah
do you want to tell us about some of
your nld stuff that you've got and what
you might want to do or you might be
trying so um like I've mentioned earlier
I'm kind of a sucker for those Haze
Spears so like the Band-Aid Haze number
seven the E appy number 16 that I have
the EA number 14 also does something
similar to that um but the one thing the
one I guess the one complaint not it's
not even a complaint cuz it's kind of
like a shitty complaint is like the way
that the buds form on the sweet pee like
I wish the buds were a little more
elongated um but it would be nice to
like you know take that structure from a
haze and kind of implement it into sweet
pee and you know kind of kind of see
what comes out of something like that um
or like cross something like a a haze or
a narrow leaf type plant
to like
um let's see like a snow S1 or something
like that or
um yeah something of that nature kind of
play with the idea of like doing that
you know narrow broad to see if you get
you know kind of heterosis if you will
because ultimately um like if you're
asking
like me for like my breeding goals I'm
going to want to create like a good
amount of diversity so that I like the
room is is Paramount like I I
have like the the possibilities are
endless that's kind of what I I would
like to do for myself like in terms of
hunting like it doesn't get boring Etc
it might be harder to find things
but that's like the beauty of it is
being able to go through plants right
absolutely booze did you want to speak
to us nld stuff yeah yeah just before
loc what are you cross on the sweet P2
like you reversing it onto a bunch of
your cuttings or you just like testing
to see if it flipped or what's the point
um so yeah I have uh so I have the Death
Star in the tent I have the bandid ha
number seven and I have the Santa Cruz
wreck number six which was one of my
favorite ones
um some seeds are forming but not a lot
like it's nothing too crazy but at least
we know that the pollen does something
right how many did you reverse uh just
one at this point and I have a bunch in
veg um you know ready to go it's just uh
there are other things that I need to
kind of prepare for in the future that
you know may a reversal right now might
not be like the best idea I don't know
yeah I'm shot for time a little bit as
well but [ __ ] I've already like
flipped six and they're all throwing
nuts so I'm like all right we're all in
but um I got a cool Plant it's a thread
cutter so it's uh the mom is I think
similar to something you've grown the
mom oh no it's similar to The Glass
Onion that you just did thousand but
it's um star fors the mom so it's uh
what is it it's it's
rubber yeah Kem DF and then gel onto
that so I found one out of 18 that was
uh my favorite in terms of effect and
smell so it was runy compared to the
others it's kind of weird it throws
these big chunks on like little stick
frames so not really like a cam or
something that I'd expect to see but
yeah out of all of them it kind of grew
almost like a vine to start off with
compared to some of the other like more
robust indicas but throws like really
good resin fantastic High and um yeah it
seems to like other [ __ ] in the T have
been a little bit affected by mites this
round like I've had a drama just like
with inspections and that having to um
bring stuff outside and then bring it
back in so I've like got a couple of
pest concerns and they don't seem to
really be getting any damage so I've um
I've reversed some of them because I've
got a couple of sativa Cuts in the
Arsenal from my mate uh as well as a
I've got a starm MOX cutting that's from
another buddy that's like starg cross to
Mal Harkin and the thing with that is
the the mock which is the uh being
reversed on to the stong in this
instance uh it appears to be super
dominant cuz even though it's been
reversed onto a bunch of indicas you're
still getting like 14 to 15 week fenos
popping up it's just uh I'm interested
to see how that will cross to this Inda
plant because the mock the star MOX it's
throwing like pretty decent Siz buds as
well but nothing like chunking out like
the the thread cutter so Crossing this
uh something that's on like a bit of a
lankier frame um that's supporting large
flowers like the thread cutter onto
something that's on like a you you a
much more sturdy frame and throwing like
a more spear-like but I'm interested to
see how those two will go together but
um breeding sativas together is
something that I'm super interested in
going forward uh I haven't really done a
lot of it to be honest like I've just
been in the popping seed stage but made
of M local bird seed he's done a really
interesting run uh recently he's used
like a TV mail from bod and crossed it
onto three cuting that he has so the
ISAC Hayes which is from Yos Sami that's
that um a G13 cross to a C5 F2 of sorts
and then what else he's got he's got a
Band-Aid hay3 and then Harlem dreams
which is like a blue dream cross to a pi
S1 so by Crossing them onto the the TV
it's interesting because you don't
really see a lot of people doing these
sativa hybrids like a bit more now you
know obviously it's like a seeds and bod
and stuff like that but when you think
like in the 80s a lot of the magic that
um came over to Amsterdam was like you
know from the haze and the skunk and
stuff like that which featured you know
some pretty crazy equatorial land races
so it's just interesting to you know now
that a lot of diversity has been sort of
lost to an extent and a lot of people
are playing around just in a a smaller
gene pool it'd be cool to see like
what's been left behind so to speak you
know see what like a Colombian cross to
uh Angola red does or even some of the
the older stuff from Neville and
Crossing That Into You know some of this
more um rural land race stuff and just
see what pops out of it that's what I'm
super interested in and like granted I
don't think it's an easy path like it's
I think it's pretty easy to you know get
a couple of packets of seeds these days
and make something that's pretty
phenomenal like breeding is has kind of
been simplified by the am sheer amount
of people that are making seeds and
working with good things like in the 80s
when there was only a couple of people
doing it you know it was kind of a
crapshoot um so to speak you know
because you have just numbers alone you
know what I mean like you're working
with such less numbers but now that
there's you know so many people in
America working with clones and
collectives like I don't think it's that
hard to to find good plants uh in you
know these cultivated varieties so going
back to like land races and earlier you
know Regional cultiv eyeses I think
that's where it's it's going to we're
going to be able to find these um really
unique highs and on that line as well
like with my jerus one that I've got you
know I think that's a pretty unique old
school line as well you know [ __ ]
Herms like something would and it's got
a fantastic nose and if it is like some
Hindu Kush like from the 80s or 90s you
know either from Neville or from um
someone else that had imported it or you
know perhaps locally like from
Washington or whatever um you know I
think that could be cool to inject into
some of these sativas as well you know
kind of like doing a F1 hybrid of sorts
kind of like Neville did with the nl5 so
yeah that's something that I want really
want to do going forward too you know
once I've busted into some of these you
know packets from White Buffalo and
Wally duck and some of these other cats
um yeah find some cool fenos and put
something like the the Jagger onto that
or an urk or a um purple indor or
something like
that I think one one high level
reflection that I have here listening to
all of you is like there' have been kind
of suggestions from for like different
tactics for or strategies perhaps for
achieving novelty or like
achieving uh something that is you know
not subject to the same uh I don't know
uh constraints as like some of the more
hyped stuff right whether that's like
going a little bit further Upstream to
some of the like uh older Elites like
the blue dream and train wreck going
even further Upstream to you know yeah
like bro is saying land Racers Regional
cultivar um or just kind of being
adjacent right like going sideways
perhaps a bit more as well um and yeah
that's you know that I I find like
thinking about it on that level quite
interesting too where you have this like
huge possibility space and you can like
or graph maybe and you like go up or
down or you go you know
sideways um I find that stuff really
interesting yeah I think it's uh I think
that there's not a lot new I think you
every now and then I see something novel
come out but it'll be like something
really small and not it's because I'm
searching so hard to find something
interesting to look at you know um but I
really like I agree with Matt I think a
lot of people are going to have to start
taking some of these um the honestly
just the oldest Cuts you can find that
are still good and don't have that
aren't you know like you know row shaded
glasses type Cuts like um and we're
going to have to you know start Crossing
those out with other things that um
aren't common either and that's like the
only way we're going to find um anything
new and exciting that new Elite cut you
know like I have no idea what it'll be
but like I definitely know when
something things like when I look at
something and I'm like oh that's kind of
played out you know and so uh um I'm
really we were talking about this before
we started recording was like I'm really
interested in old Mexican Cuts I know
it's kind of a pipe dream or Mexican
seeds is uh um that's kind of seems to
be where a lot of the magic from like
the seed bank days and you know uh with
a lot of varieties like that Mexican
seemed to be kind of a perfect Middle
Ground between really really long
flowering and something that's like
manageable in the Northern Hemisphere
and then also has like those nuanced
flavors and highs and expressions um I
mean I'm sure that comes with a ton of
Herms that's kind of what I've seen from
Land race stuff when you try and work
with it it's lots lots of Herms that
goes back to Matt just being like it's
not an easy path but I think it is the
path that we're going to have to take to
find exciting things that aren't kind of
um just redundant and you know kind of
tropes at this point
any other thoughts on like possible
directions that could be taken from any
of
you I do think that someone recently
told me that there seems to be like a
few types of cuts um like the white
being one of them where like when you
cross it with
something the the profiles in the plant
seem to be more than the sum of its
parts and there doesn't seem to be a lot
of examples of these um but we like like
you know
what's funny about the white is it's
kind of just like a really resin coated
odorless aromal OG type you know what I
mean but like it seems to like make
really interesting Aromas in its progeny
and I don't really know what that's from
but I think it's something that people
need to be looking out for
more I mean is it a
naive uh assumption for me to be like oh
it's obviously a recessive trait of some
kind um I I would assume yeah yeah or
even just just something that like
there's types of genes that need to be
outcrossed to like Express and you know
just because something's fixed in a gene
pool well like the homogeneous
combination may be like not great but
then you know when it's crossed out with
something then it can express in the
desirable way and so I think people need
to get away from the idea that like a
dominant trait or a fixed trait in a
population is always a good thing you
know oh I have a I have a bit of a uh I
don't know what you'd call this kind of
question maybe I don't know if it's
silly but I another another way for me
to ask something like this is also like
are there particular smell or flavor
profiles that we
haven't either come across here or
haven't been like Po popularized yet uh
or that are more rare than others that
you guys are interested
in I think the plant's honestly capable
of doing all of them from what I've seen
you know I've been surprised by stuff
you know um but like I can't really
think of something that I don't think
would be like possible you know because
like what it seems to me like is that
like um just like cannabinoids a lot of
like Turpin and aromatic compounds have
like multiple versions of them and
that's almost like the evolution of the
prevalence of like a compound in a gene
pool you know what I mean where it's
like you can have different um
prevalence of different
um uh like isomers and types of like uh
um like lyine or that's probably a bad
example I'm not a chemist I'm not like
super deep into scense science you know
um but it
um yeah like I think that we can get all
of it it's just like when you have a
narrow gene pool you get one thing you
know and so if we can get that worldwide
gene pool opened up again I've heard
people describe all kinds of wild
combinations from you know trips up into
Nepal and stuff like that and Northern
India and so I've never experienced that
myself you know but like um spicy hashy
fruity combos seem to be big and you
know um I think it's just going to be
more novel combinations of smells and
Aromas more than like anything you
haven't seen in weed
before because we've got everything from
garbage to to artificial grape candy you
know
I was who was I I think locco was on
this conversation maybe you were there
as well Dan I was I was asking I was
asking them
um about uh fruit smells and how often
they translate and which ones tend to
and which ones don't so I know grape is
probably quite a good one right in that
it does tend to transfer from smell to
flavor no I've seen it go both ways yeah
I've seen it go both ways on the on the
fruity stuff and it's almost seems to be
like a prevalence of it like it like
it's its own trait as whether the flavor
translates or not because it's going to
determine like the chemical form that
that Aroma compound is in and like
whether it's like surviving combustion
or not and it's like form that tastes
good or if it's converted into a form
that tastes good you know and so that's
like a huge thing is there's a lot of
stuff that's fruity that doesn't taste
fruity and I don't think that's very
desirable yeah yeah if it smells like a
peach I want it to taste like a peach or
something else equally as good you know
what I mean it's kind of cool when
flavors like um I don't know maybe you
smell strawberry but you taste blueberry
or something like that some weird combo
like that that could be really novel and
really
cool yeah yeah because I was going to
say like blueberry is a good example I
don't obviously we know because because
we are associated with Matt obviously we
know quite a bit about it but I feel
like for the purposes of The Wider
Market it's not that well recognized
perhaps yeah it's kind of one of those
common questions though that you get
asked by people that are I mean maybe
just at a certain tier in the industry
but they're like oh it smells like that
did it translate like it's definitely
something that comes up in my
conversations with work quite
often local you know you were telling us
about that like was it white gummy bear
or uh you know smelling EA like does how
how does that translate to flavor um
um I would say it translates pretty well
actually um I don't know if it's cuz
like it I don't know it has like a
really kind of wet oily
resin and maybe that kind of allows it
to like carry really well but it it
tastes just like it smells and then
obviously like as you get towards the
end it just turns into weed but it The
Taste is definitely noticeable um
and I mean I I don't it doesn't get me
any less High than the other one other
ones um but I don't know it's I
guess yeah it it's a hard one
cuz I mean some of them don't taste as
Amplified as that one like the number
fours has the same smell but it doesn't
taste as like um volatile if that makes
sense or like it's not as like flavorful
as a number one but the smells are the
same I had a followup question for both
of you who are uh so Matt Matt boo is
like um may may be unavailable for the
rest of this chat we'll see how he goes
but for now um for you two Dan and local
uh I I had a question because when Matt
Riot was doing his uh smoke reviews he's
doing flower reviews for a bit for us
and like what was interesting was
obviously watching him uh smoke it in a
bong and then smoke it in a vape right
oh sorry smoking you know Vape
it I don't think local Vapes right local
I mean do you Dan and like how do you
how do you conceptualize that
distinction I mean it's just like a
difference in in heat really you know
cuz like I remember when like the puff
Co first came around they actually like
didn't get hot enough to combust your
oil fully so you always had this just
like pool of your last dab in there and
the new ones are great the new ones like
can do it um but like I've noticed like
a lot of the vaporizers um they have
this like popcor Flavor that comes with
them and um I've never tried like the
what what does he have like the V rip or
whatever I don't even know what that
thing is looks like he's free Bas and
crack to me um but
um I I don't know man um I have like a
Pax three I think a little handheld dry
flower vape and I really like it but
it's definitely not for flavor it's for
like ease of use and like so I don't
feel like I'm like like I don't know
inhaling liters of smoke into my lungs
every day and then I'll get cancer and
die you
know um but um yeah they all all the
Vapes that I've ever tried all kind of
like in a way change the flavor and make
it slightly worse because that popcorn
flavor is still there but um um I
wouldn't be skeptical to say that like
some people enjoy it more I think that's
more true for like the E dab rigs and
stuff like that is that you get like
really really excellent flavor because
you can dial in that um temperature of
your Banger just perfectly to the tenth
of a digit you
know
yeah um yeah locco any thoughts on that
that whole topic of like different
consumption modes so I smoke primarily
out of glass now I mean that's literally
all I smoke actually
um
and so I used to smoke joints
only and what I've noticed is um it took
me a while to like acclimate myself to
the taste of like flow through glass but
like it does taste better um but I don't
have a vape personally and I had the
same like feelings about Vapes as Dan
until I tried that rip that mat has mhm
cuz like all the other ones did make the
weed taste like popcorn like the first
hit was great and then every like
everything else after that was asked but
that rip it like you actually get like a
lot of the nuances like the the Death
Star tasted really [ __ ] nice through
that um I had a um afgi cross to appy
that I tried through that that was also
really nice
um um what else yeah like I don't know I
if I had like the setup for it I would
totally get it I don't know what goes
into it I've used it once and that's it
but I don't know glass it's easy like I
just feel like it's the most average
measure of like what the consu like what
people are going to smoke it as or how
they're going to smoke it you know what
I
mean yeah and I think like it goes into
like how you smoke too because like I
know older people that just pack
enormous bowls and they like want to
pass it and like everyone's just smoking
this charred ass bowl and I'm just like
it's disgusting you know what I mean
like I've I don't really like smoke in
groups very often you know what I mean
like a lot of people I know smoke but
they don't want to like sit around and
Blaze um and so like when I'm packing my
bowls like I pack snaps and I'm like I
barely burn it you know like I don't
want the plant material to really burn
up that much like I want to burn all the
resin heads and then like unpack like a
partially charred pull and pack myself
another fresh one you know and so um
yeah if you you're not going to get that
flavor if you're packing these massive
bowls and and taking multiple hits off
of it because it's getting cooked each
time you know and so um how you smoke
yeah even with like just in the category
of like like combusting weed um there's
so many like different little nuances
that can like make or break your
experience and how much you enjoy it you
know I
mean yeah I I'll also comment the one
thing that I did like about joints a lot
is that you know you have do have some
development to the smoke like it's not
the same thing from start to finish like
it has stages yeah which a bong is like
I I think it was thousand that was
saying it it's kind of just like a
oneand done type of deal like it has no
like like it just Peaks and then goes
absolutely straight down from there
exactly yeah yeah don't smoke the
downhill but like uh see I don't really
like joints and blunts that much anymore
like I did when I was a more social
smoker um but I I always say like the
best hit on a joint is the dry
hit yeah because you get great flavor
for that just that little tube of paper
and some ground up weed in it like you
can like really really taste you know
it's a different experience than like
just the the smell sensory of it in a
jar like because you're actually tasting
that and it's reacting on your tongue
and so um I feel like that's actually
one of the best ways to like experience
what something tastes like I just don't
usually like it once I start smoking
because those stages to me they like
mostly go downhill like I'm open to be
proven Wrong by like a specific sample
you know I guess though one one benefit
is that it does give you like some
additional data points I mean it may be
like really trivial in the end but maybe
baby
yeah there's the wi Dash thing there's
like okay maybe this type of flower
seems to progress better you know it
doesn't go downhill as quite as much as
other ones that kind of thing um I guess
I'm just bringing it back to like you
know this this is also another way of
thinking about all the different ways
you can try to evaluate your flower we
obviously didn't talk about like how how
well it extracts and all that stuff
obviously that's like another another
kind of like metric you could use yeah
yeah that goes back to like the
thing like rosin is just such a pain in
the ass trait to breed for because it's
not only growing the plants and
identifying the resin traits there's
also all the post Harvest evaluation
side of it it's not just like oh is this
dank you're like no then I have to go
through a whole separate process of
turning it into the best hash I can you
know and I'm not a expert hash maker at
all and so like it sucks when I have to
do it you know what I mean um yeah I'm
hoping I can pick up some skills from
some of the people on here and just get
get some practice you know but um it is
like its own whole beast and so um it's
uh it's interesting I I haven't made
heads or tails of it yet but you know
what I mean like it's not as simple as
taking one 5% washer and Crossing it to
another because you don't even know if
they like wash for the same reason and
so evaluation can take like so many um
different like you know it can have so
many faces to it um but going back to
the Joint flavor and stuff like that's
one thing I love about like Jack types
and train wreck and stuff is those
flavors do last through a joint and like
J1 too j1's really nice for that
um it's really enjoyable when you do get
those those experiences yeah man
terpinolene bro that [ __ ] like lasts
forever yeah it's
great especially cuz you can get like
sweet bubblegum terpinolene like that's
one of my favorite things right now is
that it's like you can have a lot of
different Nuance on terpinolene or like
mango terpinolene you know and so um I
think that's another not well explored
Avenue because people think tealing is
just tealing and it's like no I I've I
disagree at this point now oh totally
dude it's it's like the I don't know it
it's the everything turp right for real
yeah yeah more than
Mercy oh I love it man [ __ ] it's it's
divisive like I I've had arguments
friends about it and stuff like that
because I I agree it can be present in
boring situations like I've had a couple
of bags of stuff that was just like you
know not decent smoke at all like if it
pops up where you don't want it you know
what I mean exactly I a bunch of OG
hybrids and it utilized um one of the
parents on mons side had like the cat
piss in it which is I think it's just a
San Diego cat piss so it's like a super
silver haze cut of sorts and so like all
three throughout veg I'm getting this
nice like lime fely sort of Aroma and
then as it all capped off pretty much
all of them cured out to like a toine
sort of smell in that instance I didn't
like it but man most time I love it like
some of the favorite smokes I've had
like the Dutch Haze in Amsterdam from
coffee shops like the better Haze I had
over there was like the teal smell I
didn't see too much of the A5 kind of
stuff but um yeah even over here man
like yeah some of the the more preferred
plants I've found have had to pinoline
in it for sure but but I'm um it's
interesting with flavor like getting
back to like vaping and smoking sorry I
missed that part I [ __ ] I got like a
nerve thing at the moment I'm all yeah
[ __ ] up
we like some weed man like seems to be
the stuff that's more hashy I prefer
smoking so like I predominantly Vape but
if you get something that's got like
that hashy or like the kushes tend to do
it like that jager cut even has it a
little bit it seems to like cling to the
palette and you know what I mean it's uh
I don't know compared to other stuff you
taste it where it's just like you know a
smoke or a cool smoke flavor or even
like the more astringent [ __ ] like some
stuff I've had that super citrusy I
don't like smoking it just at that
temperature I don't know does something
to the mouth feel but in a vaporizer
it's all fine like because I I really
like vaping like I've had a vape for I
don't know five or six years like have
the crafty from stores and Bickle that
one's DEC for portable and then I've got
like one of those ball Vapes now which
are like the tabletop ones with the um
the little hammer and like the rubies
and [ __ ] that heat up it's next level
like it's similar to that vrp thing that
that Matt has I guess and for in terms
of like getting TPS and stuff out of it
and um and effect as well yeah that [ __ ]
rips does the
job um maybe this is encouraging me to
go back to using my vape a bit more cuz
like I I go in and out of it uh but I
think especially when I've just got some
like freshly harvested flour it's
probably a really good time to pull it
out it's good with cess as well like in
both ways I think like you said before
smoking it and vaping it like you know
when you really get down to the
nitty-gritty of like sorting between
like a couple of fenos you know see how
it works both ways like we did a little
um Cana competition no not even [ __ ]
competition man that's a wank but just a
bunch of us like 10 of us in the other
Discord that you're in we did like a
little you know trade and share sort of
thing and with each sample of that I'd
try one you know smoking in the bong or
whatever and one in the Vape but um man
I have to admit it'll be unpopular
opinion but every once in a while I will
put a little bit of tobacco into a joint
as well I
it
Blas no not in the bong man [ __ ] that
I'm not that animal but like having like
a bit of red wine or something it's been
a nice meal you know it's a cool night I
I'll put a little bit of tobacco in but
it's got to be good weed like if if it
tastes like [ __ ] and it's going to like
you know just be completely covered by
it um not into it but but yeah I was a
fan of that America Spirit tobacco cuz I
lived in [ __ ] Europe man for like a
year and a bit you know everyone over
there smokes that way I smoked American
Spirit when I was traveling there yeah
it was cheap yeah I was gonna say
actually like hash and tobacco man that
is a really interesting combination
like sometimes you could really taste
like the hash like I mean I don't
make like any sort of like special I
just use a [ __ ] trim trim screen and
use that but like even that mix with
tobacco dude is super [ __ ] nice
tasting and I don't I don't smoke
tobacco either so no me neither no I
don't smoke cigarettes or anything but
yeah no hash and tobacco is the next
level like in Amsterdam the pre-rolled
ones that they sell at the coffee shops
for [ __ ] house because it'll be like you
know like the tiniest little bli hash
and like two cigarettes but yeah rolling
yourself with some decent has like
decent hash making a snake in the middle
and stuff oh yeah beautiful because it
completely covers the flavor and it's I
don't know it's and it's unbridled you
know you're not having to mix it with um
you know a different cannabis variety
you know because it's not like you've
got like the stift off that same [ __ ]
plant unless you're growing it yourself
at home maybe I'm just a degenerate but
I love taking bong rips of those 50s the
Moes they're so good wait what do you
what do you mean it's like half weed
half tobacco I don't really do it much
anymore I've I've heard Moes I've heard
Mo I've heard
um God I've heard a few other ones too
not so always called them 50s like I
don't [ __ ] know man I've heard a
bunch of different names but it's all
the same [ __ ] and it's I heard I watched
a documentary and I think it was Oregon
or some [ __ ] and it was like a a
concerned parents
thing all these kids were like mixing
their balls like 50/50 in the woods and
like passing out and [ __ ] man it was
crazy yeah if you're not ready you're
going to nod back like it's going to rip
your head off yeah yeah or throw up more
like the [ __ ] rule than the exception
like it's probably going out a bit now
but for the most part
most I remember doing that with like
gravity bongs and stuff like doing like
three ler pulls and stuff man like I
think it was like bod who said like in
um like in his travels like into like
the Himalayan areas like I don't know if
that was Nepal or what but like he said
that like they um they say that like you
the weed makes you high but the tobacco
keeps your feet on the ground something
like
that um I always liked that that little
saying oh yeah I remember it Mellows
that it Mellows the the harshness or
like you know what I mean sometimes
you're just like floating away floating
away High yeah lost like intro you know
introverted and mute I don't know about
man like if you're not used to it
[ __ ] hell like I I want to move like
I did an exchange in Europe for like 12
months at school and then mve back and
then my mates come and visited me and I
hadn't smoked tobacco in like six months
and I remember that first split that was
[ __ ] higher than I've been in a long
time like it hits differently when you
haven't had it for a while but but why I
like to not do it now it's just if I'm
drinking for the most part you know what
I mean like
same yeah the inhibitions go down and
you're like [ __ ] it who's got a
cigarette I've always found it to be
mild psych mildly psychedelic for me
because I don't like since I don't smoke
tobacco at all dude that nicotine [ __ ]
me up oh dude that Rush is yeah it's not
small yeah I like to dip so it's not
that bad for me so oh dude it's ex it's
excellent dude it's I almost compare it
more to an opiate to for me though and
like my personal experience cuz like it
feels like a very short-lived like
opiate lethargy you know just like gone
on the
couch no I get that I understand that
yeah um I will say that like it actually
does bring me some joy that we got so
far off track because typically I'm I'm
really anal about these shows but I've
actually been waiting for a good
opportunity to like just let let let
people go off and just we just talk
about whatever um but I think that like
we're coming to the end of the two hours
and I don't know um booze you did have a
few other questions about more like um
some of the mechanics maybe or tactics
when you're breeding selecting I don't
know if you want to go into those or if
we should just like rap it here like
call it here um oh it's just more like
the whole thing man said it's fairly
[ __ ] multifaceted and very open to
discussion as well like selection in
general it's like what I preface the
whole thing with like you know from
selecting the pack of seeds to the way
you grow it to the light and everything
you know like it's pretty [ __ ] open
but just like yeah in the I guess tail
end of it all once you've made before
you go into that sorry boo one last
thing I'll say is that one thing I have
definitely learned now this is like the
fifth breeding episode I've done it's
really hard to say you're going to talk
about this like one part of breeding
without talking about all the other
parts um and I think I'm like starting
to understand that like for some of
these episodes you know the like outline
is probably only like you know useful to
like a degree after which it's like you
know like you say there's so many
dimensions so many parameters and like
variables that like you just end up
having to loop around but yeah sorry
that was just me like hiding up you're a
good brother keep the ship steady I like
it admin
fold oh man dude I don't PA enough um
yeah did I mean did you want to ask any
of those questions because some of them
are interesting and I would be kind of
curious to know what these guys think so
maybe this is the way to round it out
yeah for sure man yeah so like once
you've made your selections you know
what I mean you've you've gone through a
couple packets of seeds or whatever and
you've come out with a few numbers like
are you going to run those from clone a
couple of times like what's your
consideration after that you know what I
mean like how many times basically do
you want to see that thing perform are
you going to try and dial it in like how
quick are you to throw things away do
you guys generally keep like multiple
things from a run and run it again a few
times just to narrow it down and make
sure you haven't like [ __ ] up
underwatered whatever along the way
what's yeah I I I like the way that this
guy has has taught me um here one second
good night
buddy sorry my son's going to
bed but um reading should almost always
be about like um omissions more than
selections when you're at like a really
large scale because like it's about like
honing things down slowly so you don't
miss so like there's usually a few
plants that you can throw away because
you're like oh that is that is some
garbage it doesn't smell good doesn't
taste good the effect was kind of me you
know it's weed but um and so I kind of
like that that model of like not so much
making selections as much as like
figuring out what to get rid of and that
way it's not such a hard decision
because you're not wondering of what
could be you're actually looking at what
you can see and like what's right in
front of you instead of like well is it
possible that this could be in there
kind of thing um but like I think you
also said like how do you like do the
numbers I like to like narrow it slowly
and so like say I run you know a 10 pack
of seeds I found three that I liked I'll
probably go and fill my 4x4 tent with a
few clones of each of those you know
what I mean because it's actually kind
of nice to see um if there's any slight
variation or like I don't know I feel
like it gives you a b idea of what
you're looking at from an individual
when you've got like four side by side
it just like for me that helps me just
like delineate and like you were
mentioning earlier of like grouping
plants in categories you know like that
that also is kind of where I'm doing
this where I'm like okay like I'll try
and pick the best out of each category
so I'm not like comparing you know very
subtle Nuance more that just like I've
got a few different plants you know what
I mean and I'm like I like this one for
this reason this one for that and then
like at the end that's the hard part
where it's like
oh I'm comparing apples to oranges kind
of but they're all from the same line
and I can't hold all of them forever I
don't have enough veg space and I'm like
you I hold on to stuff way longer than I
should and so I'm trying to get better
about that but I think by like breeding
by Omission can be like a useful tool in
that
[ __ ] yeah man what about you local you
got a cold heart you just throw things
away or what do you think he's probably
got like 90 Solo cups in his place
man
um yeah I don't know man it's it's tough
because right now I'm kind of in that um
quote unquote
collection yeah stage like I mean like
Growing Seeds s and find and keeping
stuffff from
that um but like I don't know like I
wish I had kept something for example
from the sure best one but you know um
I'm gonna have to pop another pack
unfortunately because like there are
just like so there's just a lot of [ __ ]
that sometimes I can't clone or not like
physically can't clone but it's just
like do I realistically need everything
from this run you know what I mean like
I don't know because some some grows are
just like
uh pop it see what it is and move on you
know yeah just a little data point good
reference point exactly um but I don't
know it it's hard to pick Keepers man it
really is especially when you're you get
a little critical about
it and this is where like I mean it's
obvious but they really is a limit to
the kind of like formal kind of like
data driven side of this right there's a
part where that just has to end like we
said earlier and you're just then
relying on your like instinct yeah gut
some kind of like act of God like rooll
of the dice you know random arbitary
decision yeah there usually is like a
hard deadline in like the scaled stuff
where it's like no no no decision has to
be made by this time and sometimes it's
really hard and like you say it's a gut
decision it's Instinct it's like what
you know and so like that's when I start
leaning on like which one's the most
potent cuz if I've screen them out
chances are if they make it to those
final steps that they're all pretty damn
good and so that's when I start really
honing in on effect where I'm just like
I really love this and do other people
also like the effect and like you know
it's good to be able to Outsource some
of that to uh the masses or just even
the people you're friends with or work
with whatever um and start crowdsourcing
those uh those types of notes but I
honestly think it's the breeder's job at
the end of the day to make that call and
to to stick by what they know and what
they think and that that gut instinct
because um that's kind of like what
you're developing right it's just like
you don't always have a reason but
you're just like H I like this plant and
for me that's kind of served me pretty
well I was also gonna say
that I typically find that there's like
an instant bias between the plant that
you have your eye on like when it's
growing and when it like comes out in
flower like I often find that that
correlates heavily for some reason I
don't know if that's just me and my
biases but I don't know it's like a
keeper it it's like it's Paramount you
know as boo said in the
beginning yeah I always kind of of
gravitate to the the production ones
that are pretty easy to grow because
they look so good they usually smell
good but I I usually find them a little
La luster in the Smoke Department
compared to some of their runty pain in
the ass
sisters um but I've been growing some
weird [ __ ] until more more recently I'm
excited to be a little more on the map
and out of my own little projects for a
while because it's nice to go through
that exploration phase every few years
and just find some more cool cuts from
projects your buddy have done and stuff
like
that thousand are you hanging on to any
clones like I know you're not growing
like massive numbers or anything but how
do you gravitate like when you're
popping seeds are you thinking all right
I'm going to you know hang like am I
looking for something to keep is that
your idea or you sort of just having a
look until maybe a later date when it's
more conducive to to keep and
[ __ ] I'm so I'm like I have been
provisioning for it and I am rerunning
some Glass Onion stuff right now um as
well as this like born in one of the
born in the purples um that I liked um
yeah for me it's hard like it's hard to
know how long I can keep anything um I
have some very very yeah you you all
three know that I have some like very
severe like spatial constraints but I'm
still testing the limits of it uh I can
at the moment like in my Nursery quote
unquote I've got like maybe like six
plants in there six
individuals um so I can keep a small
number um but I don't think I've done
this long enough to kind of really
have seen any pions yet if that makes
sense yeah at this point I think all I'm
interested in is just seeing how
different the Clones do like for now you
know and just kind of getting like a
general appreciation for it like I
remember asking
faran uh just in a voice chat once like
about how he saw those differences and I
think one of the interesting things he
mentioned to me was
and correct me if I'm wrong Dan like uh
for a lot of clones it takes like six
months for them to sort of stabilize for
the horomones to stabilize or whatever
and at that point you know they tend to
be more stable but if you've just taken
them um they may
still behave and grow and express quite
a lot like the seed plot am I correct a
good yeah for sure and I think on some
of the longer flowering stuff I've
noticed it more um but it's kind of like
I don't know if I'm just like reading
into something I've heard the guy say
that was like an Old Dutch saying or
whatever you know what I mean that um uh
that you know you want to like a plant
that's from the equatorial region has no
like light change pressure no
environmental pressure from cold that's
going to kill it off and so there's like
this super elongated time clock for the
plant where before it's like ready to
flower whereas like something from the
northern latitudes it has to Flower by a
certain date to Flower by a certain date
to then like die and so I feel like it's
kind of like in that kind of Realm
that's like how I conceptualize it you
know what I mean is like what was this
like Jean Pool like originally doing to
any extent it's hard to say on like a
modern one you know but um I've
definitely noticed it on some longer
flowering stuff even like blue dream
types and um you can kind of see it in
certain seeds like when you grow outside
is that like I've popped seeds and like
September and they didn't flip for like
a month even though they're seedlings
outside when there's only like 12 and a
half hours of light you know and so like
they have these built-in clocks in them
to some degree that I don't think yeah
that I don't think that we like fully
understand and so I like to kind of just
let my siblings chill for a while like
I've been blown away by how fast some
people have gotten full-size flowering
plants from a seed pack on the server
and I'm just like no I'm still in my 4
in over here man just letting her go and
so um maybe it's because I'm not in a
rush um but
um I don't know yeah I kind of like to
let things sit for a
while yeah I think for me like Boo's
sort of already kind of indicated
towards this but I think earlier on I
just was hungry to see more variety
right just for the first few years
that's all I wanted yeah and I'm sure
you still and that it's not like that
desire is gone but I think that there is
it's now being increasingly counted
appointed with that tension of like well
surely you want to see some like some of
the same stuff too you know again and
again too so it's like trying to balance
that is yeah interesting as well yeah
like I always love fuel every time
someone gives me even if it's like a
super purple zah like when it's fuel I
love it you know and I'm like I'll smoke
that yeah give me a jar yeah yeah
absolutely certain things that never go
out of style and fuel is one of those
things and I think I'm just getting to
that point of of starting to understand
what it is that I like and and maybe not
even quite why yet but yeah yeah so yeah
now I've been on a journey the same way
I've just been growing what or growing
Staples and smoking Staples forever so
it's a good Baseline but it's like what
do you actually want to smoke and so I
always default to chem and ogs because
like that's what gets me there but like
I'm sure there's plenty of other stuff
I'm pretty excited about some of the
high and Lonesome stuff I've gotten and
um some of the blueberry stuff I've yet
to run and the blue dream crosses and
stuff so that's right you got some
Bonnet f2s did you not as well yeah yeah
he gave me an extra pack too so now I've
got like um 30 to go through something
like that I think there are 10 packs
each I got the box here that he sent me
but um yeah he sent me all kinds of
goodies I was really stoked that I got
some uh some GLE Mountain Dew because um
I've heard some of the guys on here talk
about that and I was like man I feel
like I missed out on that one cuz the
dog [ __ ] is one of those curious cuts to
me that I have not really experienced at
all but for them some of the pictures
I've seen I'm like oh that's right up my
alley man that electric bugaloo is uh
it's got my number any final thoughts
I'm good brother [ __ ] mostly just
yeah you know end of the day [ __ ] with
any of us said just select what you like
yeah
exactly yeah yeah I think this ended up
being quite a cool conversation like I
think um we ended
up I think you know more or less just
rink towards all the like not all but a
lot of the kind of critical decision and
decision points you may
encounter in selections what some of the
initial considerations are um and really
we did just talk about breeding as a
whole um but I think where I liked us
going that I wasn't prepared I didn't
expect rather was like I think it was
cool to get each of your Reflections on
like what you thought a good direction
or strategy would be um as well just
hearing about some of your your more
personal tastes and yeah especially when
it gets down to that like we said that
impass in selection where you're like
information is not going to help me
anymore um I think that's all really
interesting that like probably doesn't
get talked about enough um in like
breeding conversations so yeah really
cool um if nothing else I'm going to
start shouting out um maybe before there
any shout outs from you
guys no I just did my whole set the
other day so I'm good for right
now
[ __ ] shout out to you man appreciate
getting us through this one moderating
it around and and Matt hope he's getting
better
soon yeah for
real yeah absolutely shout out to Matt
yeah sorry he's not feeling well and
yeah hope he feels good
brother yeah um yeah thank you so much
you guys it was really fun and like we
haven't had you know this this
combination of people on before but like
this is a great team um
and we will be seeing all of them again
really soon uh farmer Dan and local
probably sooner uh because we're going
to do that Z episode you could even tell
in this one like they were both sort of
already starting to talk about it um but
yeah we're gonna we're gonna have a Z
episode a dedicated one which will be
fun oh I'm
St yeah you yeah you nerds it's going to
be it's going to be a good one I'm
excited for that that might even be like
the next one we record potentially I'll
be in touch yeah for sure man I'm
ready yeah so
otherwise you yeah go I was just gonna
say thanks for having us
dude oh man my pleasure all three of you
I love talking to like anytime um okay
so shout out to uh not shout out um get
you season r.com I believe H lson just
had a new drop I believe Park might be
having a drop drop soon um in the next
few months perhaps uh Riot SE Court
Europe if you're in Europe uh G by seeds
uh run by our very own Matt booze over
here uh for
Australia um do check out our disc
Discord and patreon if you're interested
in joining us uh as we've implied and
gested to many many times over the
course of these episodes lots of cool
conversations and interactions going on
over there all the time and last but not
least we have the Codex
um go check that out um I'll be bugging
Matt to add stuff to it as we go on and
we'll probably have to do another
episode soon just to kind of give you
all an update on where that's
going um but otherwise yeah thank you
all so much um I assume you're listening
to this on your Friday evening for most
of you and yeah hope you have a good
weekend thank you everyone yeah thank
you bro peace
man want to sit at the table with the
syndicate
check out our patreon and our link tree
or description below our merch site is
officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is topnotch I've
been saving old designs for years for
this purpose so please check it out
Syndicate gear.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it
out