[Music]
welcome to breeders syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
lived it i'm matthew owner of riot seeds
i'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
how's your friday night so far
that's all right
was uh there a wide variety of color
schemes to pick from from your uh
earmuffs no no there's not no it was
just uh periwinkle and yellow was your
only option this is it this is what we
get that was it this is what we get i
mean when i guess it's extra extra small
they have limited colors i know we need
to get you one so that when you do your
audio it won't bleed in and it'll be
easier to yeah
you know when they say one size fits
most yes they throw in that disclaimer
for my head yeah yeah i bet i bet they
do they do you can watch like a ball cap
just like creep up
let me see if i can get some lighting
going on in this piece oh that's a
little better maybe
yeah there you go there we go
i can see your your shiny glow from
being pregnant indeed yep it's all the
estrogen i'm taking
yeah that yeah that helps yeah it does
it helps the transition
all right so tonight
we were going to get started talking
about
provenance in its place in cannabis in
the history why it's important now
um
it and even more so now than ever
so if you want to get started i i don't
know if you remember where we kind of
talked about starting off but kick it
off
yeah so i mean there's kind of like
probably what we'll end up doing is is
talking some like historical examples of
it
um from the beginning to like now
because there's a lot of it that's
relevant right now actually yeah um and
then just kind of like what we need as
far as ethics and stuff like that
yeah so the two paycheck you know like
uh both the hair and the beard are
completely unchanged from last week i
did zero uh time in the chair before i
started so
everyone can see me get progressively
shaggier
more aged as time goes on
yeah that's for sure
you know so
there you go that there we go um you
know so uh
you know there's an aspect now where
like
i guess it's it's sort of like why do
you care
yeah
and people i get that a lot people care
people care for different reasons
right
um you know the smallest minority uh of
us which i'd say matt and myself and csi
and some others are in
is the one that care because it's the
truth
and because we're like weed history
nerds and we want to actually know the
story
of how it came to be yeah
right
um but there's a lot of people that only
care
uh relative to how it helps them
yes right and in some cases you know um
you know when you interview some of the
original people that have like the stuff
you're so desperately after
they have that view too yeah they they
know it but they kind of only care about
it
in a way that it helps them
or how can it help me now
yeah right and so a lot of times what
happens is like you know you start to
talk to some of these people and like
memories are kind of hazy
and then as they get an idea about what
could happen with it well then they get
more specific
yeah you know and
um most of it is oral and most and some
of it is a lot of it is argued over
so it becomes really hard because it's
there's not a lot of proof
yeah
right so
uh
we've chatted about this on previous
casts but
you know when we were talking about like
the ron parties and stuff like that 20
years ago where i met caleb and fletch
and a bunch of different people
yeah i was hunting for old things then
yeah and it was hard uh in the last five
or six years
all of a sudden there's been a huge push
towards like well what was those 80s and
90s genetics like yeah and all of a
sudden they're everywhere
right
they're absolutely everywhere
right so you have this situation where
you know it doesn't take much all it
takes is one scammer to have you know 74
colombian or whatever yeah and it's not
actually that and it gets passed through
some good hands and it's almost like
bitcoin washing or something it gets
like
it gets its reputation gets verified
through others yes and so there's a lot
of aspects of that of how that works
you know so
um it's kind of a conversation that like
could go
uh
any number of different ways yeah uh but
maybe i'll start in the beginning
which is
i remember reading
uh stuff that uh sam skunk man wrote
about how pissed off him and rob clark
were in the early 80s that like five
percent of growers gave a [ __ ] about
genetics yeah five percent would be
massive now
massive and so there's an aspect where
it's like same as it ever was yeah right
like that's what we're about to chat
about and they were bitching about it in
1982 yeah
um because and i don't even think that's
wrong necessarily uh there's a lot of
people like i live in mendocino county
obviously so it's kind of weedland and
it's been going through some seismic
shocks lately
right as far as all that goes and you
really start to see the people
that um
are in it for it
and we're in it for spending cash or
we're in it for ease or whatever you
know like a lot of people were into weed
because weed i mean matt's seen this
with the seed game yeah from when he
started to now
right i mean how many big influx and
then a big outflux and right now i mean
people dropping like flies out of the
scene you know people that we thought
would probably be around you know no
matter what i was kind of shocked you
know it happened though
well i mean some of it is some of it is
breeding is a pain in the ass too you
know and so it's like it's like maybe a
band maybe it has a a one to five year
life for most of them yeah you know it's
really hard to make a 20 or 30 year
career
out of breeding yeah and not being able
to go anywhere not being able to take
vacations all that comes if you take
reading very seriously and collecting
very seriously provenance all that that
you can say goodbye to all that uh well
on top of that too it's like for if you
if you compare it to music
having a being a one hit wonder means
you're more successful than most
musicians yeah because you still had the
right kid and then
because you had the one hit and then if
you have like a period of dominance for
like five years or something
that's pretty incredible yeah and the
number of bands that stay relevant over
15 or 20 years even is a tiny fraction
of everyone famous yeah yep so imagine
you have some huge hits
for breeding and then five or ten years
later what are you doing and then five
years later what are you doing
can you keep making hits can you keep
yourself relevant
it goes into it i i you know what i've
seen very few um seed makers be able to
keep themselves relevant unless they had
like a big marketing budget you know and
high times ads other than that it's it's
always an up and down battle for most
people
um
and so you know there's a there's an
aspect too where
um
i don't even know how to put it like
that but
that's what happens when i read comments
you know i can get totally thrown off
track
but
um
you know there's there's a thing now
like if we if we go from from what sam
said to now
now all of a sudden it's important to
have old cuts because people are trying
to differentiate themselves on the legal
market
there's a ton of new smokers who are
interested in these legendary things
yeah right
um and therefore there's money to be
made and rep to be had
by having them yeah and yeah you know
one of the things matt will tell you
this too one of the main ways to be a
breeder is let's say you end up being a
guy that's associated to a super famous
cut even if you weren't the breeder but
you were just somebody that got it early
most of those people have seed companies
yeah and they do they have a famous name
so they do breeding around what got them
there yeah
in the hopes that like
people that are interested in that would
want to get it from some og tied into
the
chem or the sour or the cookie what you
know whatever whatever it might be it's
ghettos or yeah whatever it might be
yeah whatever whatever whatev whatever
matt's background he has decided he is
going to uh out
outpace me weekly
uh i have no figurine competition i
can't even come close you know he does
have figurines but they all have big
dicks so he can't put them up and
they're all sent to me from matt yeah
you know i don't know if you've ever
been on the riot christmas list but
that's really all it is is like phallus
art it's the largest collection and i
have doubles don't get on it you know
that's you want to you want to avoid
getting on it yeah og and i'm not even
i'm not even dissing people but it's
like
by any means but yeah og like you know
norcal i see mag around around uh og kb
you know or cornbread ricky you know
around tk or
and anyone anyone then when you get
famous by it like a lot of people do
breeding sort of based around their
famous cuts
yeah right yeah
i mean
so then there's an aspect where it's
like one of the best ways to become a
breeder where people buy your seeds is
like claiming that you're associated
with [ __ ] yes yeah the big claim
the big claim and a lot of these claims
like it doesn't even matter if they get
refuted later on as long as they help
you with your rise on the way up and
build your fan base
yeah
whether it's ancient skunks or this or
that's or whatever else it's like just
to get yourself known and on the map
yeah
you know
and you know so we'd weed was never
ready for modern marketing techniques so
you know we have this running joke in
our crew called the pre-pre
yes right yeah which is
all these strains that people have that
exist before the strain existed
yeah and you see this like we'll talk
we'll make jokes like oh we mentioned a
strain that probably hasn't been brought
up in 10 to 20 years publicly and
they'll be like [ __ ] [ __ ] in two weeks
we're gonna see it and then sure enough
two weeks later someone's like yeah i
got that cut and it's right here you
know
yeah the pre-pre it encompasses a lot
the pre-pre and like you know there's
we're not i'm not going to be big on
like like names or anything like that on
this particular episode it's more going
to be like actions and themes because
that's easier
yeah but
there's parts where it's like okay like
somebody's got oh i've got this thing
i've got 93 scentsy star yeah
but it got released in 95.
yeah you know or i've got 95 black
domina but dominant didn't get released
until the cup in 96 which is in november
so there's all these things where it's
like there's these cuts and they're like
they're like the earliest they could
possibly be and then a year or two
earlier
sometimes decades earlier yeah there's a
there's a 79 blueberry floating around
yeah yep
you know um when you know dj says that
he got his afghan to start the project i
think in 79. yeah
and then blueberry isn't blueberry like
an f4 f5 f4 yeah f4 yeah right so then
he did he did multiple generations and
testing and all that different stuff but
there's someone that has it that's his
from like before he you know the the
year that he started
the one i see the most is super skunk
that has like the most years around it
because nobody cares to look up when it
popped up yeah someone just said there's
a there's an 89 super skunk yeah exactly
it got released in the 90 catalog yeah
you know um sour was found a lot of
people think sour was found in 95. it
wasn't it was found in 96.
uh the diesel 1 and 2 was found in 95.
but a lot of people sour it goes right
back to summer in
it's 95.
free the pre-cut before that pre-cut
there's because most people really when
it boils down to it it's like
it's almost like testing like has what
what's happened with thc testing where
it's like the
the lab knows that both the dispensary
and the grower want a high test because
that way everybody makes more money yeah
so the market knows that these earlier
dates
do well
and thus these earlier dates appear and
so we i've had this running joke that
like with the magic of a sharpie and a
label
ancient gems are unearthed all the time
yeah yeah
and i want them to be true and every
once in a while a few of them are true
yeah but
it's like it gets it gets earlier and
earlier and earlier and then you try to
refute it and it's like whack-a-mole
yeah you know and then and you know and
it's like so provenance
provenance with seeds is really hard
because they're just beans and they all
look fairly similar so it's like how the
how would you know if it's an 85
you know the best way to identify old
beans is they don't crack yeah they
don't crack very easily they don't or
they none of them pop
yeah or they're not viable and you're
like oh wow maybe these were really old
because they didn't none of them worked
yeah it's really frustrating because
they're only fresh for about five to
eight years yeah and that's stored
properly uh one summer in a bad closet
or in a hot garage
can dramatically lower their lifespan or
even kill all of them yeah definitely
you know and so now we're in this
situation where
i i i did i didn't shave this week for
street cred you can see all the gray uh
because all these 90 strains are coming
back around now
and most people didn't experience them
back then
yeah so therefore people can sell them
to you
and you have no personal experience
so would you like my 89 super skunk
would you like my 93 cent c star my 95
black domina my
you know my pre sam skunk that's another
favorite of mine yeah yeah
this is the this is the this is the sam
started in 75 this comes from before
then when it was still ranked or the pre
pre hayes brothers hayes the yeah
whatever whatever it might be going back
even way before i was like born
yeah and they still have stuff and
people that have been like secret and
doing and doing repros and stuff like
that and
every once in a while that stuff does
exist yeah it does happen it does happen
from time to time that someone comes out
with a legitimate i i have not been
online and i've been holding this this
exists it does happen so it's like we
don't want to rain on uh every parade
that pops up because we could be pushing
away good people well yeah you don't
want to be like there's this uh there's
there's this there's this funny like
from the welfare
feral era of uh of uh saturday night
live where like there's these two gay
kids that work in this clothing store
and no one's good enough to shop there
so everyone that comes in they just
insult them relentlessly until they
leave
yeah you know and so
you know you get tired because some of
it is obviously impossible right and
then they'll be like you call them out
on the pre-pre
yes and they'll be like oh well my buddy
got it directly from the breeder yeah
it might be pre-released but my buddy
got it yeah right or they just go along
and they just change on following posts
they just update the year to the
earliest year possible yeah and go along
with that new thing
yeah and those other posts get deleted
and they just adapt and move forward
and and when we were
talking about starting doing this
podcast together
one of the main things that me and natso
were talking about and we've talked
about this before but
um
are we doing a disservice to the
community by putting more info out there
that is accurate to the to the letter
when it comes to to know knowledge you
know because it's actually helping
people craft their stories more craftily
but luckily usually the people that do
that are so lazy they don't really they
leave holes all over so i think we're
good it leads to conundrums i mean
somebody was saying about
you know various you know the nl5 thing
i think i'm actually gonna do
uh a post on ig soon and like a little
like mini podcast talk on it that we
have planned just because most people
there are some real pictures of nl5 that
neville had but most people haven't seen
them
no you know and haven't put it together
and there are posts that neville made
where he talks specifically about it
uh and certain aspects of it and stuff
like that um and most people haven't
seen that either
yeah right and so
you know there's a part where it's like
i'm such like an old weed nerd that like
every old story god i want it to be true
yeah yeah he does he really does you
want it to be true but the other part of
it that's really weird and maybe we'll
bring this up and it's kind of rambling
but
there's a lot of people on ig
uh this is going to be shocking that
like aren't the way they act on ig in
real life
yeah i know that's [ __ ] weird there's
a ton of people right and so there's a
whole group of people that find people
on ig
like me or others and be like i want
these cuts that i see this guy posting
about
yes what does he want
and then try to convince you that they
have it so that you can they can get
what you have
by trading you something you're after
yeah that's one thing when you're doing
trades please please be very you use
some critical thinking and and
if if you're looking for stuff that's
old or rare don't send someone a list of
your want list
because if they come back and send you
everything on your want list there's
probably red flags to be thrown if it's
old or rare and some people are really
good and generally speaking what happens
is if you get bamboozled out of cuts
or you get traded you trade you know old
rare [ __ ] you have that's awesome for
club cuts that they renamed most people
stay quiet about it because they don't
want to be embarrassed that they got
took advantage of
or they don't want to lose the monetary
value of what they just bought and want
to pass on the [ __ ] butt and
sometimes they end up breeding with it
for a few times before they realize what
it is and then they have a bunch of
seeds they made with it and so like
there's a lot in weed of like
you know a small percentage of people
know a bunch of stuff that's not public
yeah and it gets kept quiet
for for reasons like that yeah
you know um and you know and so and then
some what those scammers do
is then they use
i'm gonna make a post with a big picture
but yeah um that is nl5 that is that is
neville's mother that he used to make
nl5 haze
nl5 skunk one all that that's the only
nl5 cut he used in breeding
uh at scentsy in the last few years
um and so
you know but there's people that let's
say they once they once here i'm really
not going to name names but let's just
say
that you know they've managed to trade
with some well-regarded people yeah then
it makes it easier for them to trade
with others because some of that guys oh
he likes them and trades with them that
guy must be cool
it also gives gives
provenance seeming provenance to the cut
because now it's gone through someone
reputable and when it's not through
someone reputable's hands it adds that
stank
they they have they get two or three
people to buy into it and now all of a
sudden they got two or three well-known
people that they can trace real that now
they have really good cuts
mixed in with their club renames yeah
right because they can oh i got it from
this person and that person and you know
it's like and they got it from this
person and those people are all well
known
yeah and so that happens a lot like
there was a thing and we don't call it
that much anymore but like there used to
be a thing long before you could sell
clones and and not be ostracized
because 15 years ago that's certainly
what would have happened
um there was a thing that we used to
call trade baiting
right and trade baiting was basically
trading people to get a cut that you
thought would unlock a bunch of other
cuts for you yeah
like the chem d or you know various
different things people would would get
it promise to not give it out
and then use that to get 15 or 20
different things yeah
right and that's a lot of how like fakes
got spread because some people got cuts
only with the intention of using that to
unlock other things they wanted
yeah and that's how a lot of stuff
spreads people want stuff
yeah that's it's that want that need
that fomo yeah it's like adam smith like
the invisible hand people have a want
there's going to be an invisible hand
that brings the goods or services to
them yeah and there's people out there
that if they don't have that they'll
just say they have it
yeah because they want what's in your
pocket
yeah
you know um and so that's where you know
so now we have a bunch of
so when when old strains were unpopular
it was really really hard to find
anybody that would say oh i've got old
[ __ ]
because there wasn't any money in it
yeah now there's a bunch of money in it
they're everywhere
yeah
right
and so
you know and and
yeah seemingly you know and then stuff
gets awash and you've got oh i've got 89
this and and i've got this and i've got
that and i've got
you know and
and it gets laundered through a few
respectable people
and then some of those respectable
people breed with it a couple of times
and it's in their work
yeah and that's what makes provenance so
hard yeah
is everything comes out of the shadows
there's nothing really it's written down
it's nothing that's easily proved it's
all person-to-person honesty chain
so
maybe i'll use an example of something
that i consider to be like really good
provenance okay right so
you know greg pops what the dog which
became called the chem 91
okay he gives it to my buddy staten
island
okay statin gives him the skunk and
comes west
from that statin gives it to skunk va
myself and another friend
and we've all had it since yeah so it's
like a short chain
everybody agrees on both sides that it
happened
and then you don't lose it
yeah that's what we would call really
excellent providence yeah
you know like the people involved are
believable the time frame is believable
yeah
you know
um and and all that
uh and then we have stuff that's got
really bad prominence
yeah you know like uh something that
that matt and i have been trying to
figure out recently
is
does the actual cut of kush that matt
matt bubba and joe d and and uh josh did
that did does that still exist
yeah
you know um
the prominence on that one is hard
because they lost it
multiple times and it got renamed in la
and there's like half a dozen different
cuts that all claim to be it right yeah
if you have original ghosts they claim
that to be it
if you have original 92 og they they
consider that to be legit yeah right the
first sfv is supposed to be it
can you think of others
i i was just thinking of
something that makes the the chem 91
story a bit more complex because when
you have a situation where someone you
know has has a good reliable transaction
and we have reliable provenance getting
it to him
and then the next thing he passes out
like for example chem d
in a short period of time two people get
two different cuts
and no one can quite remember who got
which cut first but in such a short
period of time you can't really tell
which one would be considered the
original or not you know and at that
point it becomes
is an unreliable narrator always
unreliable or
can we just get it wrong once somebody
said sfv is it there's more than one sfv
cut that floats around yeah
after a seed line was released called
sfv there was no more
trying to dig up just sfv without
running into a thousand of them so
that's what i mean in the sense that
there's some things that are fairly well
agreed upon yeah but then there's a lot
where the provenance gets lost or murky
yeah and it's kind of and it's kind of
like and then in that case it's it you
know it suffers from renames the ghost
of right now isn't the ghost that was
getting traded 20 years ago yeah
it's not
yeah
you know um
and uh you know there's you know like
the eight you know there's people that
have the old ajs
yes sour diesel and there's people that
have the another aj's
sour diesel
i i keep trying to figure out if stony
puff and stuff in here is the stoney
puff and stuff from um overgrow and and
cannabis world and stuff well i guess
that's a good person for provenance for
the show i guess he could clear it
you know he could probably clear it up
yeah but yeah and so then it becomes two
it becomes like uh provenance that that
becomes like based on your trust or your
knowledge so it gets to be pretty small
circles that know what's very what's
verified yeah and i have people all the
time like in legal california there's an
aspect where
um
you know it's almost like all these
strains are like punk rock bands that
never signed with a label
yeah so nobody owns them
so there's this like multi-billion
dollar industry that's getting developed
and all these sharks are looking around
like nobody owns any of this [ __ ]
yeah nobody controls the rights to these
cuts why not
well that's the beauty of a black market
industry a clandestine industry it's it
leaves a lot of room for snakes to come
in because the only reprisal is is
physical there's not like legal
reprisals for anything right but then
that doesn't mean that there's not
people that are going to like trademark
the name
oh yeah yeah for sure you know and try
to control it and say this cut is it
because they want to make money off it
and you know there's a risk that it's
like imagine somebody else tries to like
imagine somebody tries to to to you know
trademark the chem 91
and then anybody else growing it or
using it has to give them kickbacks
yep
you know um so there's all this weird
stuff where there's like there's all
this compartmentalized tribal knowledge
about cuts
and it's not widely known a lot of it
and people use that murkiness
to hustle a lot of fake history yeah
and even sometimes some of the most
people that would be in the know some of
the old-timers
they're part of that same issue
yeah because they'll tell you there's
plenty of old-timers
that have come out of the shadows
and ended up scamming people
because they have
prominent their name itself who they
were where they came from
yeah you know there was a famous
incident with uh
um you know the g13 cut
yes yeah yeah that was a little weird
you know um and uh the person that was
offering it and selling it for a lot of
money had impeccable provenance
yeah
but it was a scam
if i remember it was double d's cut of
g13 that was that dr green thumb said he
had then double ds said don't use my
[ __ ] name you didn't get it from me
if i remember correctly that's how it
went
neville at the time when we were talking
said that that's not the cut but then
neville also he told me hit up dr green
thumb and get some of them seeds for
free so who knows who knows where that
story really landed you know yeah but
that that's exactly kind of the thing
where it is
you get claims there's sales happening
you get arguments by various people
involved who all don't agree
people are tempted to buy it right
because everybody knows that controversy
uh sell seeds
yeah
right so there there's there's also
people that i won't name
uh that i think are kind of sociopathic
in the seed game
um but they said something i think was
really revealing one time even though
people were giving them a lot of [ __ ]
about a lot of fake releases
he said everything i released sells out
yes and you could see that that was what
mattered to him
yeah
right and so a lot of these people
foresee you know for seeds it's like
that's really what matters to them
they want them to sell for the pack
price
yeah you know the truth is genetics from
me the truth is uh a cut of my maui
uh by superdog
uh and it was it was uh seeds i gave to
mandelbrot and he found
he found it and some apparently some
rasta he was smoking with said this weed
is the truth
because he got super buzzed
uh and that's the moniker that got added
onto it
um but yeah he's saying
stoney puff and stuff again mark emery
almost every seed maker post neville
either added mystery confusion
uh or some lies
in order to sell seats if i remember
correctly stony's the pnw hash planet
okay
really that's yeah that's why i have his
name on my head right now because of
that yeah
so i mean and there's you know and and
basically now we're in this point
um where you know the history might
become valuable because almost every 80s
and 90s famous line
is starting to have its day in the sun
again getting offered as seeds and
people claiming to have the real deal
holyfield yeah
there's one thing i'd like to cover
um
and that is how how
how groups and clone groups were formed
because we did kind of touch on you know
going to the parties back in the day but
i've noticed that that that's one of the
questions i get from some of the
youngsters in our our breeder syndicate
discord chat is like how do i even get
to these groups with these cuts like how
does that even work it's a foreign
concept to them and it's just like you
just make friends with people and you
talk you shoot the [ __ ] a lot of times
you're not even talking about weed when
you shoot the [ __ ] with someone you're
just talking about what you have in
common and over time people decide okay
this person is full of [ __ ] or they're
not and we share because we're friends
and that's that's kind of how it goes
and it's a slow process sometimes you
don't ever share anything you know in a
group sometimes you share everything you
have and
you know that's how it goes but that's
how the groups used to work it's it's a
lot different than than just going and
buying the cuts today
i would say
that like if peop the grail
of to me of uh of that kind of situation
when you actually like go jedi master or
whatever and you get beyond most trading
and people just want to give you things
yeah is that you just have to be honest
about what you're after and what your
intentions are
the whole time yeah
and then if you're honest and people
like you and you're not pulling anything
on them because you're honest
like you you know you get you get into
more and more different groups because
there's only so many collectors yeah
it's a small community that's always
been the case
everyone wants what's hot and what sells
for a high dollar
but actual collectors that are holding
on to things for like how they breed or
how they love the weed or whatever else
that's pretty rare
and when when people pass me these lists
that people send them like cloneless and
say hey do you think this person would
have this or that the first thing i
think is who is this person connected to
who does this person know that i know
that's in these groups because you know
usually if they're showing off like a
really rare clone it's like okay who's
he connected to who would he have had
access to to get this cut is that very
likely how rare is the cut who do we
know that's currently holding it this is
all involved in provenance and looking
through it and trying to figure it out
and um yeah a lot of times it doesn't
add up anymore
and you have a you can have a situation
where
you know a lot of us know each other and
so what matt was just talking about it
might involve a few phone calls
and
you know and like cross-referencing and
checking yeah
you know
uh
and all that and so you know and because
there's a thing too where like up here
you know um
and there was like there's you know
we'll get to it in a bit there was like
a a nugget that created this show
essentially or the idea for this show
um but it is it's really hard to get
people that's what makes that's what
makes me laugh so much is that it's so
hard to get anyone to hold on to old
things
that whenever you just see a tsunami of
old things you're like well [ __ ]
yeah you know yeah no you know i wish
there was no and the thing is is that so
everybody asked me about my like my
collection and all this different stuff
so
you know my collection is basically like
i'd like to say that it had some like
master plan or i knew eventually one day
you know i mean i like to breed and
stuff so like holding on to plants i
think are cool uh i do that sometimes
but mostly uh it's um you know it's it's
stuff i personally like to smoke
yeah
and i didn't care
if
um if it was valuable
to others it was valuable to me
right uh and for the most part most
people just want what's easy to sell
right now
yeah and they'll dump
whatever they were selling before that
isn't as easy as the new thing
yeah very quickly
very quickly you know and um and so you
know did i think one day holding on to
all this stuff like i don't have
you know a bunch of my old cuts because
i had some master plan
yeah i had old cuts because i liked
growing them in the greenhouse or
whatever and having some head stash
along with whatever else i was doing
and i liked making hybrids with them
because they're my and then maybe i get
better wheat
yeah
you know but that's not most people
honestly
they hold on to cuts because the value
that they put on the cut is monetary
yeah
whether by breeding with it selling
clones of it or selling flour of it
you know and i i saw someone just uh
made a comment that you know like well
provenance is [ __ ] it's in the flower
make a produce flower and that's cool
except for the fact that a lot of the
times that the cuts people are hunting
they've never had any experience with
the flower before in the first place so
how are they ever going to
then smoke the flower and be like yep
this is the one you have to have
experience with with it in the first
place to be able to do that so while i
agree with that if you don't have the
experience with it in the first place it
doesn't really do
anything better than um
trying to establish that oral history
you know luckily luckily we're not so
far forward that a lot of these people
are totally gone a lot of people are
still around that we can you know trace
hand to hand to hand to hand back
and then there's a there's an aspect
where it's like how old is your memory
yeah just because you had a cut for x or
i had a cut for x amount of years
and then you go 10 or 15 or 18 years
without seeing it
are you just because you had it are you
certain to be able to 100
identify it again
this is the problem we have with trinity
and it's and it's the reason that
nobody's like me csi no one's willing to
say yes this is the [ __ ] one you know
as much as i would like to as much as it
would probably sell seeds better if i
were it's just like it just
the memory isn't there anymore half the
half my crew thinks it is half my crew
thinks it isn't
yeah
you know um and uh you know someone just
said trades used to happen off samples
you know how hard it is for me to get uh
um
to get samples from people of strains
that they have a flower that they grew
yeah because a lot of people get clones
just to flip them for other clones yeah
or to build their stable or to this or
that or whatever you know so
it's there's an aspect where um you know
it it
i don't know
uh
memory gets tough
yeah it does
you know it really does so and
psychosomatic stuff it is always a
factor too and bias and wanting to have
it there again like finding that old
you know forgotten clone
that's got to be it you're already
wanting it to be it so it can be it you
know so that's all somebody just said
one thing i i will agree with is that
the trinity cut that we have and is
floating around
is um is really good wheat
yeah so regardless of the truth of it or
not it's enjoyable it's very enjoyable
smoke
it's also similar it's also similar a
little bit to the train wreck trinity
that that i grew from jill it has a lot
of similar traits to that and i think
that was an older cut using the old
trinity but i'm not 100 on that yeah and
i mean there's there's a thing too now
where it's like you
um you know there's certain cuts that
i've had for long enough like you know
if i was to lose the chem dog or
something like i would be able to
recognize if it was real again yeah
because i've been growing it since the
late 90s and i've grown it a lot
and it's super unique looking and
smelling i just i just have such a
relationship like the smell of it
you know and like the look of it and the
way it makes me feel
you know it's like that's not something
that i had like a short-term
relationship with that's like something
you were like made like you were married
to your wife for 20 years like you could
you can you can hear a voice yeah and
you know it's you know it's just that
kind of some things are like that but
you know it's it's hard because
most people in weed and there's nothing
wrong with this are younger
and
they want access to their history and
all these famous old cuts
and they're willing to give up money or
see you know or other clones or this or
that or whatever else and so there's a
there's a group of people that are
ethical about that and there's a group
of people that aren't yeah
and there's somebody that's asking me oh
we need s-ones that la kush bro oh and
so i don't know if like this is kind of
like we're almost an hour in so maybe
we'll chat about it but
matt
matt spoke about like we joke about how
um you know we'll talk about something
not that we're super important but like
you start talking about something and
you you get you get people also talking
about it right
and then all of a sudden you see it pop
up
yeah
so
matt matt and myself we were discussing
it this week and it's i think in the
last
eight months ten months
there's been three different breeders
that have put out seeds that have by the
nazo's la cush label
yeah not so's headband
yeah right where in the previous 15
years that label didn't exist not once
not one time anywhere ever
yeah right no
no
you know uh
whatsoever and then all of a sudden i
start talking about it and not only does
the name it's it pop up but my name gets
associated with it the only time your
name got associated with it originally
was when in our group because there were
two different headbands we like the one
that we had and the one that you had and
we had to identify it so we would have
like referred to it as that you know but
it was never a popular name before we
would talk about it
and that's a lot of how some of these
internet names like none of us ever use
the term i use the term chem 91 often
now because it's a good communication
tool yeah but none of us ever called it
that yeah that's an internet term
just like the skunk vacuum
yeah that's an internet term
you know um it was never said you know
and so you know i get that people might
want to like attach names to cuts
because it helps differentiate yeah
that's just being proportioned
sure and you know for me i was anti it
happened anyway
some people
some people attach their name to cuts
intentionally
yeah when they know they had nothing to
do with it
you know like
i don't know lupa headband something
like that yeah yeah so he got the cut
from someone else
and he decided i'm gonna say it's the
best weed in the world
and it's my week yeah
you know and uh
um
you know and then there's so there's
this aspect where it's like it puts me
specifically in this weird conundrum
right
where
um there's a small group of people out
there that think that i'm chatting with
all you guys every week that matt and i
in order to do some like long running
scam
yeah
because most people can't most people
don't actually like
um
what's the best way to put it most
people don't think how you think
yeah most people think that what would i
do in his shoes
yeah
right and since most breeding is about
money and it's not about love or
cannabis or anything like that like they
feel like there has to be something for
it right yeah so i chat about stuff matt
and i chat about stuff we generate some
interest which is very kind of y'all to
have interest in so there's interest in
these seeds and these cuts and this this
and this that but i don't sell that
stuff
so
there's a small group that thinks oh
this is what's coming
yeah but since i'm not doing it there's
another group that's just adding my name
to [ __ ]
and you can buy my clones
that my name on it
or my hybrids with mine with my strains
that from people i've never met
or you know and and i can't i can verify
he's not coming he wasn't even breathing
hard before he said that
uh
you know so um so then what do you do so
it's like so
if i offer it then like it i wasn't
about the history i was just trying to
pump you all up into some [ __ ] to
sell it to you yeah but then if i don't
offer it other people are going to offer
it to feed the desire
and so we've gone nobody's used the word
not so's headband in 15 years and then
we have three different people using it
to breed with in the last eight months
and clones of it for sale
right and these people have never
reached out to me or talked to me or
this or that or give me given me flour
or like done any kind of like basic
investigation to make sure that like
they think they have the same thing
no no
not whatsoever that's a lot of work
that's a lot of work you know so it's
just like all of a sudden somebody sends
me something and goes hey dude do you
give your buddy uh did you give your
buddies uh the cut so we can make beans
and i have no idea and then if you get
mad about it they just like it because
then it's just more controversy and
people some people will think oh you
must have it yeah he's mad because he
must have it must be true
and you know there's not even a thing
where i'm like oh you can't call
something headband unless i approve
yeah but how if you've never met me or
smoked my flower how the [ __ ] do you
know it's it it's gotta be the same one
that i have
yeah it doesn't make any sense it
doesn't make any sense at all yeah you
know and so there was a there was a cut
this week that got some controversy that
matt brought to that like
it turns out it started its life as j
plant speaker sauer that was bought from
a club
and then jay got mad and it got renamed
the real sour
maybe now it's me and now it's not so
his headband that may be the story but
that wasn't the first story who knows
it just is one of those
and then you know and then there's
arguments and anger back and forth and i
don't even want to say names because
it's not that's that that point's not
important you know
but it's just one of those things where
it's like i have people all the time on
this show dm me can we get cuts can we
get seeds can we this can we that
right and so i've never really done that
to the public i've done it mostly in
private to friends
but then if i don't do it public
there's going to be scammers that see
there's an opportunity and just do it
and some people are going to get scammed
called the catch-22
you know so what do you do
you know and then there's a funny thing
too right where it's like i see this
with headband and sour all the time and
i'll keep talking about it because it's
it's relevant uh obviously diesels and
headbands and sours are sort of kind of
having their time in the sun again
they had a brief five or six year period
of not popularity as purples and various
things swept the land again
but now they're coming back
and
everyone wants to have the oldest
realest best
cut of either
yeah so they can sell flour or seeds at
high prices to people that want to
experience the real deal or clones or
clumps or sell clones for 300 500 800
000 bucks whatever it might be
right so
i don't know that i have
i don't know that i i've had i got this
hour 22 years ago i got the headband a
year after that so 21 so oh what 2000
2001 right in there right
yeah i don't know their provenance
before they came to me
they came to me with a label
do i know for sure that my cut is the
original diesel 2 cut that i don't
i just know that i've had it since this
year and never lost it
yeah do i know that sour is the right
sour
and the real sour and the one that manny
found in the bag of weed i don't know
that either
but i've had it since 2000 and i haven't
lost it and most people
that are selling these ancient cuts now
got these diesel cuts within the last
few years
yeah and so their history of it doesn't
even go back very far
so what you're saying is your cut must
be the
albany sour
well that's the funny part is that five
years ago
because there's a story too that
matt and pip and a bunch of friends kept
asking me well which cut is it
right and i got it a long time ago and
it came helpfully labeled sour d and so
i thought i had sour d and so i never
traded anyone ever for sourdy
why would i i had to cut and i never
lost it and i liked it
so
then matt and pip and other friends
start telling me well there's rez cut
and there's shroomie and there's amish
and there's ecsd and there's choco and
there's new york city
and so i start collecting all these
things
and growing all of them and it ends up
none of them are my headband and none of
them right my sour
and now when i collected all those there
wasn't anything called the the catskills
cut
that the albany cut there's like there's
a bunch of amherst
no you know no j plant speaker of which
i know he doesn't really like his name
being attached to it there there's about
half a dozen new sour names that have
just come up in the last three or four
years
right and everyone ties back to the mid
90s
guaranteed
and most of these people if you ask them
how long they've personally held the cut
it's a it's it's a you could count the
number of years on one hand
yeah
you know and so i don't know that my
shit's the real deal i know that i like
it a bunch and i know that i've had it a
long time
but it doesn't seem like the chain goes
all the way back to when it started
where you can guaranteed where like
people have it
so everyone just claims they have it
yeah
and none of these people want to send it
to the original sour people for
confirmation
no
they just
don't have a clue who they could send it
to that's in the sauerkraut most people
still think that
whoever goes on the podcast and claims
that they have
yells the loudest that they're the sour
guy is who it is and rez got his sour
cut supposedly in 07
you know 06 something like that
and then he released the line called
sour diesel
yeah ibl which made it even more and
then you know people would get bag seeds
and call their bag seed sour diesel yeah
right and so there's a bunch of people
right now selling cuts for hundreds of
dollars that they're very very very sure
that it's the oldest and the best on the
realest deal
and selling you expensive flour to try
real sour diesel
yeah
and because there's a bunch of desire
for it there's not a bunch of uh ethics
around it
and you can whine and [ __ ] and moan and
ask questions and then they just get
pissed off
and their buddy and their buddy and
their buddy and they find out the names
of who it came from originally and then
that's you just had it
so there's there's another aspect that i
had written down here and this is one
like this is this is the conversation
that i have with a lot of people that
sell seeds behind the scenes and and
one of the ones that's repeating that we
we always come back to is how do you
compete in a market of dishonesty where
the loudest the cheapest or the most
expensive it what is what usually um
sells it's not necessarily who can prove
that they've sourced it correctly it has
nothing to do with what sells in all
honesty
very very few people care about that so
in a market where the name is what's
selling along with the trademark and
brand
how do you compete
if you try to do it the right way when
it takes months
it takes years to source something
correctly at some times and then looking
through the line then testing the line
how do you compete in a market like that
yeah that's tough
yeah none of us have ever figured it out
i mean
in the mats in the seed market more and
the flower market
it's the same thing where
you try to grow the i try to grow the
you try to grow the best weed you can
yeah and not everybody does that most
people don't do that most people try to
grow
you know just barely good enough to pass
yeah that's that's kind of the market
it's always been the market but if you
grow really good dank
um then you're gonna battle with brokers
that always tell you that they can get
cheaper dank yeah and since their
goal is margin
right
they would rather buy something worse
that they get a bigger range on
in terms of profitability that week than
something better with a narrower range
where they give a fixed price yeah and
so they'll always they'll be like if
they if they look at you and say this is
the best weed i've seen in six months
they're not gonna offer you more for it
yeah
you know but they're gonna everyone
tries to kick the tires and make your
weed worth less
so they can get bigger margin from
whatever they're doing
yeah and so that's this it's the same
thing with like with with flour even
it's like you can grow real flour but
like
you know and there's a bunch of people
up in my neck of the woods that got used
to got pissed off and just got used to
growing bee weed
because that was what sold and that's
what moved and it like why put in the
all the extra effort
yeah and now the market's so tanked you
know um you know they haven't grown fire
in a really long time
they've grown decent commercial
yeah and they used to be able to survive
off decent commercial and now they can't
you know because it's been a long time
and so same thing with seeds it's like
you know they you're going to flood the
market and then you have a situation
where if you're ethical and you want to
test stuff before sale
someone's always going to beat you to it
always and that's why when people are
saying you know like well just grow the
fire and fire will prove it's that's not
how it works i mean greenhouse let's
look at the the top of the industry
greenhouse
dna
you know like uh dynafem
this is the top of the industry even in
the us you got compound you know burner
this is the top of the industry so do
you really think fire is going to make
it through all this when that's the
custom the market's customer driven
and customer driven means that rappers
probably are driving the market so at
what point does fire win
and i laugh when people from florida
and virginia and georgia i don't it's
not it's not like i'm laughing at them
but it's like when people from these
various states are like oh man you
california and you just grow the booth
yeah and i'm like no no no
you're the brokers that that brought it
to you they bought the booth
yeah they probably had a different
choice but they made more money off the
booth and they still thought you'd buy
it
yeah so that's what they're bringing you
yeah if you insisted upon real fire and
refused to buy the booth they'd have to
change their game
right but they were buying the boo for
cheap and flipping it to you for a
little less expensive and their margin
was better yeah
so you know boof exists for a reason
in that regard yeah it does you know and
and there's an aspect too where it was
like this week you know once again i'm
not i won't mention names or anything
but like you know matt got upset because
my name got used and you know the
person's response was basically like oh
he's just butt hurt that we beat him to
making seats
i could have you know i could have been
begging not so for that cut when we met
and i've never asked for it once
you know you know and it's because they
know that there's like there's a market
out there for it there's people that are
excited to try it and since i'm not
feeling that market they're like [ __ ] it
i'll beat them to it i will
yeah
and i'll do it better than he can
yeah and it's marketing they're just
trying to sell something what are you
gonna do six months later complain
that the cross didn't come out the way
you thought
yeah and most people don't pop their
seeds right away so even six months most
people are working at two and a half
three years before they get to the seeds
that they purchased and the seed game
much like the flower game as matt will
say is
uh in rough choppy waters right now
sales are down and uh expenses are high
and and volume is low
um and so people are searching for
whatever little edges they can
yeah
you know
uh and so it's a real issue where it's
like people ask me so
if i was to do something where i was to
like offer up cuts or offer up seeds
uh and try to fill a demand that a bunch
of people have
i would be selling out
yeah
but if i don't
other people are going to and are going
to and are doing it currently
and it's not even real
yep
uh and part of the reason why matt and i
started this podcast was just to give
certain weed heads an opportunity to
hear real
yeah when there was just a sea of
self-serving disinformation
and infomercials and some really bad not
that there's not some quality talks out
there so don't everybody feel bad but
like just
you know an attempt to like get get some
at least some stand against the [ __ ]
yeah
i mean
you know people already didn't like me
it wasn't going to hurt my reputation to
do this [ __ ]
and uh
yeah
it was nice to be able to do it with
someone that had a good reputation
already you know what i mean and that's
honest so and it's interesting in the
sense that the more i talk
like it's nice that there i get people
that you know matt and i do get quite a
bit of nice messages about this thing
um but there also is resentment and
anger and hatred
yeah because we'll do a history episode
and you know all of a sudden i'll say
something or matt will say something
that contradicts some narrative that
somebody else has and we don't even
mention them by name
but they're pissed off
because it it undermines what they're
trying to do
yeah there's a lot of things i would
love to talk about and even even with my
loose lips like as far as uh
you know talking about what i feel like
talking about there's a lot of things
that i don't talk about
somebody just asked so who does right
now if you wanna if you wanna get any
headband crosses from me um uh you can't
but uh i did share the cut with uh uh
with csi
and there's some really [ __ ] good
ones and he released some tk and some
chem d and people send me stuff all the
time it looks like those are both really
nice hybrids especially the d um he'll
probably be releasing some more stuff in
the future
uh i'm still on the fence about myself
um but uh but you know he has it
directly from me
and i gave it to him so he could make
seeds so people could have a chance to
grow some hybrids of it because he's got
a big reach
yeah you know
and all that different type of stuff
um and uh
you know there's a there's a thing too
where
matt and i think that probably within
the next five years the seed market will
probably shrink a lot
and thus the breeders will probably
shrink a lot
yeah i i say in the next six six months
we're going to see a drastic decline
back to where it was you know maybe a
few years ago you already see a lot of
people starting like opening up the
vault
yeah and offering a bunch of stuff from
their collection that they're like what
the [ __ ] am i gonna do with this what am
i gonna do with this maybe somebody else
wants it maybe i can generate some money
yeah the amount of boats rvs various
things up here for sale
uh you know the the downturn in cannabis
right now has caused a fire sale amongst
all sectors
yeah it has you know uh fire sale of of
all sectors and uh
um you know and so
you know there's
part of the reason why uh
there is a a decent amount of my work in
modern things
is because i was really stupid back when
prices were high 20 years ago and i was
growing seeds for me and friends
on the side
when everybody else was just bumping out
flour and getting high prices
so there wasn't that many people
breeding 20 years ago and you were in a
perfect spot for distribution in that
area where people growing mass amounts
of weed yeah i mean as far as
distribution as far as getting friends
to try it sure as far as making sales no
no not sales but no
it was a it was a passion project money
losing venture yeah and so as soon as
the easy money goes out of it i
anticipate most of the breeders that
mostly just mash together stuff via
reversals we'll go do something else
yeah
um
and uh you know
so
you know it'll probably shrink which you
know there'll be a bunch of volume uh
shrinkage and then the people that are
passionate about it will stay in it
yeah
and then you'll have less options but
you'll probably have better people to
buy from overall
i hope so i hope so i mean when there
was a uh not a big like burst in the
scene before cookies and stuff when
seats were still kind of small there's
probably 50 of us worldwide you know
2006 to 2008.
now there are
thousands and thousands so i i hope it
gets smaller
just because it was nicer people weren't
as cutthroat but i mean
you know it's cool it's cool seeing a
lot of different people's point of view
though like being able to see all the
different
um crosses and stuff from all the
different points of view is always cool
yeah i mean that that is neat and i'm
not trying to dissuade anyone i mean i
always say on the show when and i say in
private too when people ask me
like how should i focus on being a good
breeder
and i always say like you know try to
breed things you like
yeah try to like i like i like these
things from this plant and these things
from this plant i wonder if i cross them
could i get the traits i like of both in
a single plant yeah could i make wheat i
like myself
you know
uh people time please put the cookie
lineage out there or not the the cookie
thing is like i don't know when we'll
get to the cookie thing uh that might be
that might be a while it's hard one of
the reasons why
uh matt and i started like in the 80s
with neville and the city and the and
corel and the city club and all that is
that
um there was less people to get mad and
argue
yeah
yep
yep you start in the 80s and you go to
the 90s and there's only there's there's
less humans that are gonna get mad at
you
i only get sam skunk man mad at me right
now for for what we've done i mean he's
is like trying to be a a billion dollar
empire
they're definitely positioning
themselves to sell out to like you know
some huge corporation when it goes
federal um they have stores all over the
place they're big into branding
um and all that and so trying to
you know that's like really poking the
dragon
um because they don't give a [ __ ] about
the truth
like the truth is irrelevant to them
they're building they're trying to build
an enormous brand
with stores all over the nation
and clothing and all this different [ __ ]
yeah i mean there was footage of bernard
going into city council meetings and
talking about the illegal growers in
that city by name so i pissing people
off who do [ __ ] like that is not my bag
not no they got they've got and you know
they're backed by a lot of money and
stuff like that and so you know i know
that there's i know that and it's not
that's not the only reason
i'm not going to do it yet part of the
reason is is that uh there's a lot of
lying and there's a lot of stories to
unravel and
um you know i do try to when i talk to
people to be pretty upfront about what
we think we know for pretty sure
and what we are unsure of
yes
and so when everyone has a different
story and everyone's kind of a shady
shady liar and everyone has issues
uh you know i know a lot that people
don't know
um but i don't think we you know we're
not quite there yet yeah we don't have
the full picture yet i don't think we're
quite there yet so
uh as a result of that we're probably
you know and since like matt and i
started way back
we've just barely gotten to talking
about the last 10 or 15 years yeah
you know
uh and i still want to go back i still
want to go back and cover the 90s forum
era because that one episode we kind of
just went on a tangent and that would be
fun to do
so i mean one of the one of the things
one of the things talking about you know
we can tie this into provenance or
whatever you know and like strain
history is
like as you know cookies is a good
example so you know skittles is too and
all these different things where it's
like
you have a loose association of friends
with no contracts and no organization
and then a strain that comes out of
their little circle gets hella famous
yeah
and then there's a grab of who does what
so there's four or five or six people
tightly involved in the cookie story
early
yeah as far as like when it got famous
forget about like how it got made or the
various steps but as far as like after
it started getting providence yeah right
and there's no contract so who gets what
piece of a pie
you know same thing with with skittles
skittles used to be you know tony mendo
and fields and
and uh and third gen
shiloh
um and then you know there was battles
over direction and this and that and
everything else and it split into into
two camps
yep and then you know shiloh and brandon
didn't get along and so they split
uh and so fame and money has been the
end of a lot of close of weed
friendships
yeah because who owns it
who should profit off it who gets what
who did what
you know um and look at burner you know
burner's the face of cookie i can tell
you straight he had nothing to do with
it
yeah
oh
he promoted
he's a great clothing guy though yeah he
promoted it and he's good at promoting
and he look has the part and and all
that and so the guy that had the least
to do with it got to be the most famous
face of it
yeah
you know people are kind of learning
like some people say nobody owns the
plant
yeah
people say someone just said nobody owns
the plant
uh there's a lot of people that are
going to be trying to own plants yes
you watch
owning plants trademarking names uh
trademarking strains genetic markers all
that different types of [ __ ] that's all
coming
yeah and you know for me that's very
complicated because i'm one of those
people's like [ __ ] dad i don't want to
[ __ ] deal with that [ __ ] like but
i'm going to be the one who loses out in
the end for not giving a [ __ ] not
wanting to do it you know what i mean so
it is it's another catch-22 that like if
i don't at least learn about it and how
to protect myself then i'm going to get
railed i had an interview this week
lawyers i had an interview this week
about my my collection
yeah you know and a big time nursery
that i won't name yeah and i you know i
wanted to see
what they thought
yeah what was their line of thinking
what was their offer you know what was
their you know not like like is it good
enough to sell out or anything like that
but yeah just like you know thoughts on
like how people are arranging
because a lot of these things you know a
lot of these nurseries a lot of these
rich people it's like one of the things
they don't have is they don't have the
stories they don't have the cuts and
they don't have the know-how
yeah none of it and they all thought
they could buy their way into
a clandestine scene
the marketing you know the lawyers the
certifications the licensing
the
real estate they got all that
yeah
so there's a big thing where it's like
it's almost like they're going around to
desperate growers and be like you know
um do you want to license your [ __ ]
you know
but then it's like who like for instance
like who licenses the chem 91
duh t-bud
but yeah you know but i'm serious
you know yeah
like greg
staten island
skunk va me i see
someone else someone we've never heard
of
yeah
you know like how would you even how
would like how would you even go for it
well i hate to break it to you but my
grandfather is actually uh the king of
dog bud he was elected so i think it
might be
yeah i mean you know you uh you know
secret societies all that yeah me and
all my secret societies that's one of
them indeed awesome
but you know but that but that's that
kind of stuff is coming so it's one
thing if like you want to talk to a
breeder and like
you know freaking uh fletcher wants to
license rainbow belts
yeah because it's like he made it yeah
but what about every old cut that just
came out of the ether
and got traded around
there's people that are going to be
attempting to lock those in
that's coming
yeah i always wondered why um rob
clark's name was associated with og kush
on philos over at thai that was weird
and those guys you can look around i
mean though like philos exists in a
different form now
you know and i saw and there's different
and you and you look and there's there
you know i love rob clark and his
contributions to cannabis but he's
awesome
he's on some suspect boards
yeah yeah you know of some of some
companies and stuff like that you know
um
and uh yeah all these people who has the
claim to the stake and then when and
then like
and then how much of that stake and then
whatever and it's like a lot of these
people are just trying to collect
genetics and dangle money in front of
you
yeah and not even money for buying it
like money in the future like like spot
us to them
and then we sell a bunch of them we'll
give you money
yeah but really we need to give us the
collection first
and that's going on all over the place
and they're looking for
uh they're looking for they're looking
for desperate people
yeah for sure and and unfortunately for
them and unfortunately for the scene
they don't give a [ __ ] if it's real or
not they just want someone to tell them
it's real
and if it's a big enough company
that proliferates
more than any real cut ever would and
that's how things change for good that's
human
when it first happened
um in the 90s uh strains got trademarked
right
so i bought i bought super skunk direct
from neville
um in the in the in the late 90s right
um but it was called ultra skunk
yeah because
uh
scentsy owns super skunk
yep they own the name
you know um you know a white widow is
owned by greenhouse
even though their breeder who you know
shanti left
or whatever it's it's like they own it
it's almost like someone saying they own
breeder syndicate
yeah people get the name they get the
name or whatever and so that so what's
cool about history
uh in any case not just weed history but
uh humans aren't really that much
different
yeah so by studying the past you'll
start to see a lot of people a lot a lot
of similarities in in the end today
and what happened in amsterdam in the
90s is happening again
yes
you know you might even say arjun is is
is you know greenhouse was the
dutch cookie
yeah very much so you know
the
rich backed by backed by a bunch of
capital
right really connected backers
yeah all that type of stuff you know um
and there's big money behind all that
and
just like just like a greenhouse did
when they went to south africa and
africa they got all their strains there
and it took out a lot of those heirloom
mines they're gone i was just talking to
someone from south africa yesterday
they're gone we see burner going to
thailand and we're going to see again in
the next several years those heirloom
lines are going to be gone and replaced
by what is being pushed over there
what's being what's selling best over
there i mean a lot of a lot of morocco
is dutch strengths
yeah a lot of jamaica has been replaced
by fast-growing uh dutch dutch genetics
in jamaica same with mexico that kind of
stuff starts getting it starts getting
pushed around and things like that you
know and so you know cookies doesn't
even grow eat
yeah they're a clothing company and a
dispensary yeah you know they just they
just uh make arrangements with people to
grow weed for them
and then they have their own branded
bags
yeah they control the they control the
mylars
they do they control the mylars and the
point of sale and you're buying cookie
from cookie's store
and burner was at the grand opening
but they don't grow wheat because that's
too complicated they're they're uh
they're a brand
i remember back in the day he said we
aren't into genetics that's for nerds
i never forgotten that when they started
selling seeds i was like oh that's cute
you know yeah i mean but it's like
that's the you know
you can knock it but obviously
you know he's in this for you know
reputation and money
yeah he wants i probably should be too
but you know but it's like that's that i
mean that's like you know
there you know there's there's nothing
wrong with money and there's nothing
wrong with making a living sure i'm just
saying that like some people like don't
really give a [ __ ] at all about what
they're involved in they just want hits
yeah yeah right they just want to make
money
they just want to survive
you know and uh
and you know so they're opening all
these stores in these different places
and all that and you know they have
dozens you know they they make contracts
with dozens of people they don't
yeah
a lot of brands don't grow wheat most
big famous brands not that i'm not
picking on cookie most big famous cali
brands are not vertically integrated and
rarely grow their own work
yeah or they have one small grow that
doesn't fill their brand and they give
clones to other growers to fill the
brand and make the mark up on the
difference yeah
so you know the brands are starting to
become more important than the weed and
then
and then when you're in a situation
where
uh
you know um
i just started reading the comments
again and got totally distracted yeah
sure when you're in a situation where
you uh
you know you buy weed and mylars and you
can't even see or smell it most of the
time yeah because it's just got a bunch
of opaque art on it
it's sort of like a mystery bag
yeah
you know um they license cuts and then
they you know and then are they even the
real cuts
it doesn't matter in the end you know it
doesn't even matter
yeah and they you know they have
different breed they don't even have
like in-house breeders
yeah they have breeders they work with
like they worked with uh jbz for a while
who also buys seeds from other people
yeah and you know they work with
compound and they work they they farm
out all that stuff
yeah so they're always on the lookout
for different people that you know and
it's like well you know you want to
stand next to burner and smoke weed at
openings and get more rep
and get your weed in the store you know
but i want to make sure it's clear a lot
of that is farming out to people who
farm out those weren't actual people
making seeds that you mentioned they
they were hired to make seeds and farmed
it out
yeah there's there's layers of farming
yeah there's lots of layers there's
layer and
you know there's layers there's layers
to all that like i contract with you to
do this you say you're going to do it
you hire your friend to do this and it's
like it's very
you know
so there's an aspect where
you know um right now like history is
mostly useful for marketing
right
that's kind of how i see it
yeah it seems to
be nope he's cutting out he must be
in a bad spot
oh i thought we had him
so while he's cutting out i'll go over
this real quick
after the show on our discord patreon
and uh it'll probably be you know an
hour to after we're going to pick some
people from a random drawing to
receive the can of bible collection huh
and that lucky person is also going to
receive
a medium bottle of the riot reversal
spray so
after the show we'll be doing that
getting the
giveaway going for everyone on the
discord patreon as a thank you for
everyone who is
participating in that and tomorrow we've
got some good fights to watch too as
well so i'm looking forward to that
and i'm looking forward to not so
popping back in eventually here
hopefully
probably got a phone call that tends to
kick us off yo me with that wig check
y'all me
all right what else do i have if you
want to join the breeder syndicate
patreon go to um
um uh google type in greater syndicate
patreon and that's how you'll find us
and he's back
thanks for stopping in stoney
that's cool man it's real cool i want to
talk to you afterwards i'm back all
right there he is i live in the country
so we've had very few technical
difficulties relatively speaking yeah um
you know it wasn't bad that wasn't too
bad i blame it on matt's headdress yeah
my headdress did it it was the yellow
his yellow headdress or something
happened yeah um
you know so i'm back i apologize i don't
even know where i necessarily got cut
off but
you know i was trying to make the point
that
um his strain history and provenance and
like whose hands it went through there's
a core group of us that are really
interested in it
and there's uh a bunch of people that
are only interested in the marketing
aspect yes
and while there might be a great amount
of interest in the public about it
right um that doesn't mean that like
that leads to a bunch of people honestly
trying to go forth and figure it out
yeah no that and rarely does that
because it takes time it takes money and
time
friendships
trust respect
that would be funny if we were talking
about the cfam and i got cut off because
like uh
it triggered some algorithm that they
pay for yeah you know and they were just
like nope nope cut the signal yeah cut
the signal this is not the publicity
that we're into come back with nothing
with a hole in his head
but you know i'll mention something
about about about cookie just from like
a personal standpoint like in the uh
you know i'll never have a good a good
collection of
uh
of cookie cuts
because
uh
there's too many things to try to hold
on to already
and i don't personally like most of them
very much yeah
so it's like you can't hold everything
you know because that's that's crazy
so you really have to pick and choose
what you personally enjoy
yeah and it's going to be interesting
now because
cookies is just old enough where
people start talking about like
do you have the real forum
is that the real 09 animal
yeah yeah
right is that who's got the thin mint
yeah
who's got the and the and the
the hands on that is pretty terrible you
got that amherst kind of cookies
oh my gosh the amherst thing bugs the
hell out of me because
i mean that was like with the diesels
and stuff like that that was literally
just something like uh mandel just
decided to add on to the story yeah why
not you know when i gave them cuts
yeah and then all of a sudden there's
amherst sour diesel or whatever you know
yeah so
uh animal animal is one of the better
ones but mostly because it leans way
more closer to og yeah i like the more
gassy
you know the gas the gas stuff tends to
have
you know the problem is might be my
biggest issue with with with uh cookie
but you know not to just diss the hell
out of them or anything is that i think
cookie came out in this in this era
where they got [ __ ] hard where
um ig happened so visually appealing
weed was super important yeah and
testing was starting to be super
important
and there was probably good highs in
that weed
that got sacrificed for better looking
better testing lead yeah
and then they lost the high and they
can't get it back
yeah
kind of that's kind of how i see most of
cookie
yeah i mean they they were playing and
they weren't breeders and that's what
happens when you inbreed
yeah yeah it really is what happens i
mean that's what happened to blueberry
it needed some uh need some new juice it
needs to be outcrossed to something
completely different yeah
you know um and uh you know and so but
that's kind of like like cookies and
skittles and you know all that kind of
stuff that's sort of like the start of
what maybe i would consider like
modern marketing
and hyping in cannabis yeah
that's where that's where it started
yeah
i would have to agree because before
that it's like so silly
like
in the previous era before that where
like sauer diesel was king
nobody cared what cut of sour diesel you
had it just had to be gas and good weed
and sell yeah so all this all this [ __ ]
about like which exact one it was
was semi-irrelevant when brokers were
pounding on the door demanding a bunch
of it [ __ ] it didn't matter if it was so
much new york city diesel it smelled
like [ __ ] grapefruits and perfume
yeah they would you know like it just
went and so like this massive thing of
tracing down sour lineage is almost kind
of new
yeah
it's newer i would say yeah and it's
only been in the past like decade that
we've been able to kind of put it push
everyone all together that was involved
with it same with og same with all this
other stuff some of the really quiet
people were some of the most important
and only really started posting or
talking or communicating with people to
spread their part of it yeah and that's
another issue with provenance that we
should mention
is that often the first and the loudest
and the most consistent with their story
gets their story out yes and they might
not
and that might not actually be accurate
yeah but if they don't have anybody
challenging them from the group
yeah it can stand uncontested for some
time
yeah
like take for instance um you know
there's multiple cuts that i think are
really good cuts that are headband yeah
but matt and i consider to be og cuts
yeah
but they're all claimed every single one
is claimed to be original new york city
headband came from new york
from new york the original head band the
legendary one yeah right
you don't know what you're talking about
and then just when the last year or so
manny and swell and some others started
talking about what that cut looked like
and it turns out it was very fox
taily diesely looking skunky cut yeah
and all of a sudden people holding real
new york city headband guaranteed
that looks like an og kush
yeah
they had 10 years of nobody was
contradicting them with their headband
story yeah maybe it was how can you say
yeah
and now they're like well [ __ ]
you know you're a dick for bringing this
up you're a dick for bringing it up all
over again even though the
all this is still out there to be ready
what do you mean the guy that had it
named it says this isn't it
yeah
right
um and uh you know and
yeah and like you know funky headband in
upstate new york people are talking
about it and there's two different
headband cuts in california both which i
think are really nice um that are very
og cush like yeah
very og kush like don't smell or look or
anything like like like the guys from
back in new york describe the original
headband that they grew as yeah
but you know that took that only
happened within the last couple of years
yeah
you know i'm down to get that to get
those quotes and [ __ ] yeah to get those
quotes and to get them to confirm
exactly what it was like and to get them
public maybe a small group of friends
knew
yeah but it wasn't something that was
widely disseminated and so when there's
legends and there's very little
information on them it allows a lot of
people to just step in and say well this
is well this is what's true
you know um
and uh
you know so there's an aspect right
there where
um provenance is only cared about
by a few people
most of it used it for marketing or
sales
uh and um
you know and then you know once it
becomes popular
it's like as soon as it's as soon as all
this stuff is unpopular again all the
old stuff will go away
because nobody will care
they won't take the magic power of a
sharpie and a label
yeah
a lot won't remember
they won't remember
you know
um
and uh you know there's yeah so there's
p and you know one of the one of the
cool things too was even like on even on
like our discords and stuff like that
where uh matt and a bunch of friends of
mine gather
uh when we started throwing those
parties around emerald cup
it was for a lot of us because a lot of
us were from different parts of the
country it was some of the first time
that we got to get together and actually
smoke personal flour of each other's
yeah and put highs and flavors and and
visibility to like what was just talking
in pictures before yeah
you know
um
and you also like this is for real like
i mean
if you're gonna go hang out at one of
these events always remember to bring
something cool and that that doesn't
suck because
your ass gonna get judged by what you
bring no matter what no matter what
strain it is how it's grown you're gonna
get judged that's how it goes so come
correct
that's just a little advice for
people yeah and i mean it it uh
um
and you know that's the other part of it
is it's like it's hard to grow good weed
yeah too you know i
you know i saw this thing where i grew
uh
um you know our buddy pip gave me his
version of the east coast sour diesel
when i was doing my head to head to head
to head
diesel comparisons yeah and i grew it in
the sun and he came out to one of our
parties and he was like oh my god dude i
think i've only grown it that nice twice
yeah
i don't think i did anything incredibly
special i just think that
the soil it was in in the sun
and the the the weather that year was
nice and it just came out nice all of
the diesels came out really really um
flavorful from that depth that yeah that
year yeah yeah that was that was a good
year and so i had a lot of good weed
those couple of those those few years
before covet ruined it or whatever but
um
you know but a lot of times it's like
you hear about a bunch of this weed
and you and but you it's not like
everybody gets to smoke it
yeah
it's not like you know csi is sending me
and matt like dozens of samples all the
time of all the things in his library to
peruse
oh he's not he didn't send you oh no no
no no probably not
yeah weekly
weekly week daily yeah the daily your
daily just go check the po box and it's
there you know daily for daily supply
perfectly cured and so yeah there's
people there's there's people that uh uh
that were that are that are asking oh
you should release it you should you
should this and so there's a part where
it's like
so maybe we'll maybe we'll throw out a
little bit of like soapbox or
pontificating here for a second right
uh
the reason why i hold strains
is basically one reason i like them
yeah that's how that's how a strain gets
held by me for a long time and it's also
this thing where
you know it's like it's part of our
heritage and history
right
and so if enough people hold on to
enough strains that they like
then there's a reasonably good chance
that a bunch of diversity survives yeah
and there's only so many people that are
willing to do it
like if you're holding it hoping that
one day it ends up being super valuable
you'll probably be bitter
yeah we we actually saw a case of this
where a friend at the time
finally got a hold of an old cut and he
thought because he got a hold of this
old cut that it was going to make him
rich and or famous and it didn't turn
out that way yes and he was going to be
able to make seeds and there was going
to be various things that happened with
it and it was going to like unlock
he was going to be leveling up
leveling up that's a good way of putting
it yeah and it didn't work you know
and
if you really loved it and it was just
about it then that wouldn't have
mattered
yeah none of it
because you know if i was trying to like
if i was trying to gain a bunch of reps
from my seeds and a bunch of money from
my seeds then like all my breeding is a
total failure and i'd be so pissed
yeah because everybody would be like oh
people stole it from me and did this
with it did that with it or whatever but
if your goal is to preserve it and you
want people to smoke better weed
right
like the guy getting all pissed thinking
that like i'd be all pissed off because
i was beating him to the punch
like i i want people to smoke better
weed
yeah i think diesels and you know and
those kind of plants are better weed
than a lot of what's been bred with in
the last few years
so you know i'm happy that there's weed
out i want good pot
yeah i want good pot to to to use to
make better pot to then
make better pot than other people used
to make better pot
exactly and eventually everyone's going
to forget who the [ __ ] you are yeah i
mean most of all nobody after a hundred
years dude or even after 30. i mean
everything
neville might be really famous
but most of the stuff that he bred is
bred into other things and his
contribution and name to it is lost even
though it's probably the backbone of a
ton of stuff we work with he's famous
for like a few of us nerds and that's
about it anymore and that's unfortunate
because he should have that that special
place right see so there's all kinds of
people that i'm chatting about this
they're like please let's do it please
let's do it release do this kind of
thing and i could do this you could do
this thing where you could be cool and
you could maybe offer that
right but then you're a capitalistic
sellout piece of [ __ ] yeah like the only
people that are allowed to be
capitalistic sell out pieces of [ __ ] are
people that actually are that way yeah
then they're just immune from it they
don't care yeah they just don't respond
they just they just they're just like
whatever and they're just like oh yeah
like i just proved you're exactly like
me
yeah
right but most people who are listening
to this
probably are here because they like good
wheat
yeah
you know like that's that's the weird
thing and it's like i don't have like
you know as matt's well aware like
there's good friends of ours in the in
our circle that have my strengths
just because they're good friends
yeah just now you know
everybody else yeah just not you
you know but um i can't i can't then
people would say i'm using you can't
happen
yeah well i mean there's there's there's
aspects to it too and stuff and it's not
even so much like uh
um
you know life and covid and and it's
it's been
odd in the end really that's what
exactly what would happen that's exactly
what happened so it just can't it just
you know one of those things and that's
where i look at it like people don't
believe that i actually gave that cut to
our homie to make hybrids with just so
more people could try it yeah no and i
don't get anything for it no
where like a lot of times people don't
understand that like for a lot of people
that hold cuts
they demand any other breeder working
with it pay them royalties or give them
seed or make some kind of arrangement to
do it there's a lot of like secret horse
trading that goes on
first people so people want to get in
positions where like they're the
controller of the cut yeah
right and i just gave it to him because
he's my good homie and i know he'll back
it up for me and he won't pour it out um
and i was like make as many hybrids as
you want and a bunch of people are
growing good weed and enjoying it so
that's nice
you know
but that
does that is that beneficial to me no
no
you know like not at least in a
financial sense no
you know um but
but people can't conceive that you would
have something valuable and just share
it
yeah i mean you you sure you're all your
vibrators you're really cool about it so
they can change that
it's the it's the you know once once
they're no longer good enough for me and
i have to upgrade
you know
hey gotta share you guys gotta share
and and so there's there's an aspect
where it's like i know i'm not the only
reason why i threw that out there is
because
like
isn't isn't for people to be like oh he
should have done this or this person
should have done that it's more that
like
you know not everything has to be about
money
yeah
right not all the time now we do
everybody needs money
right and it's like so there's nothing
wrong with selling i don't think there's
anything inherently wrong with selling
clones or selling seeds or selling good
flour or like anything like that because
it's like
you're trading on value
the problem becomes is that just because
of humans
a bunch of people are gonna scam you
yeah
that's really what's gonna happen and so
then it's like i don't know like
um
you know i think i would like there to
be better weed more often
yeah i think the current craze for the
last four or five years has led us kind
of far away from better wheat
it would be nice if better weed came
back around
it would
and it's still around it's just you got
to get in the right circles well the
problem is
that's exactly what i'm talking about
where it's like it's always in certain
circles
yeah it's just the public how do you get
the public to have it how do you get
more people to access it how do you get
young people that listens every week and
loves our [ __ ] show or something and
they would die to try it and there's
nowhere for them to go yeah it's a
conundrum it is a conundrum you know
because there's nice people
you know that are younger and into it
and and hyped up and would love to try
these different things that were talked
about and
and and all that different types of
stuff and it's like there's not an easy
verifiable way to figure out what to do
that's right
you know though but like i kind of look
at the the discord chat is a good way to
meet the people like the the next
generation of people that are really
passionate about this like they shine
through real obviously because they're
the ones who won't stop asking questions
about genetics what's in this what did
you use of this what did you see in this
i [ __ ] love it like most people think
you would probably get annoyed after a
while but nerding out like that that
that is one oh yeah people sharing all
those i mean the reason the reason why i
know that like people are finding a
bunch of cool stuff in the la la by d
is because people send me stuff and
smoke reports and pictures all the time
yeah and they're pumped
yeah i just i spent last month smoking
the uh was it the la crosse to the
triangle my buddy uh spaced invader and
um king cultivars and that [ __ ] was fire
fire i loved it
yeah so that's good yeah
you know but it's like it's it's there's
a way where
uh how do you how do you figure that out
because
you know i don't know it it like this
whole show was kind of based on that
it's rambled a bit but it's like
provenance ethics
how clone trading started where it is
right now
uh because i don't know
i don't even remember i don't even think
five years ago people were offering up a
bunch of clones on
on ig very often yeah they were but but
it's just there's so many more and
there's so many more trying to say they
have xyz rare cut because it just wasn't
people weren't as interested in xyz rare
cut from the 70s or 80s
it's just there is that demand now for
whatever reason so now yeah now there's
tons of new people that are jumping in
and they want access to all these
various old things
and there's clone dealers that have you
know that are offering up i mean wasn't
there like some [ __ ] where this guy
raised like there was like 180 000 or
something from like
rs 11. oh yeah yeah something like that
yeah and they sold like you know they
sold more like a thousand dollars a cut
or something
yeah you know
um
so you know and and back in the og kush
days it's like remember resin's joke of
250 thousand dollars for the louis the
13th og yeah yeah because there was this
one guy that had it it was like a
marketing thing you know i mean yeah um
uh i had a dude that told me that they
paid 55 000
for the for a hayes cut from florida
because they were selling they were
selling a business
in their regard you were going to be
able to grow that and hustle it to a
market
in fairness that cut does have amazing
extracts that you're talking about it's
pretty [ __ ] good
yeah you know but i just mean the sense
where they're like oh you're going to be
able to grow this and sell it to new
york and you're going to make x amount
of money and da da da so if you want
this business and we have it
you have to buy it and so there's it's
like this weird thing of like are you a
hoarder are you a sharer are you with
this are you that how do you how do you
navigate that yeah because now that
we've been talking about a bunch of
stuff and we talk about pot that we love
a bunch of people ask us about pot that
we love
yup
you know this one dude said rs 11 made a
million and it was dirty with viruses
of course it was
that sucks
you know and now people are popping up
with all kinds of crazy numbers that i
you know of of people selling access to
various clones
yeah we hear about that because people
message us they're like hey should we
trust this person and like i don't even
like answering that [ __ ] because it just
makes more people mad when i answer that
[ __ ] so
yeah well yeah it's it that i mean it's
it's hard to because then it's like if
you if you tell the truth and you're not
very trustworthy of that person's
provenance then they think you're
pulling money out of their wallet
yeah
so they're pissed off at you
you know um yeah people used to sell
people used to sell the skittles
you know people used to sell the og this
out like it's it's it's ongoing it's
been ongoing for a long time
yeah it's just social media made it
easier
i think
okay so
we've gone pretty heavily through the
provenance part and i do you want to
talk any about any um of the new
potential ideas that we have coming up
we're probably going to do the the not
so story time finally
yeah we can chat about we can chat about
all that so
as people are uh may or may not be aware
uh we have our uh we have our our
discord back
and and our and you know various things
um and uh and we've been putting a bunch
of content uh old content and some new
content up on youtube
right for people to chat about
and so we thought rather than having
like these long-winded rambling
conversations every week that go in a
million different directions at times
we might be able to do like some more
focused stuff yeah because a lot of
times in the comments people ask to get
hella focused on certain things yeah but
it's hard to go off on those tangents
yeah so what we're thinking about doing
is uh
uh matt's gonna do some of it but i'm
gonna do uh a couple of things one of
them is uh
uh not so story time as matt likes to
call it
where people get to listen to me ramble
about various canna stories or various
historical bits or or funny things
yeah right one of them might just be
a a five or ten minute uh discourse on a
whole bunch of different strains
yep nl1 nl5 this that whatever it might
just be like the collected knowledge of
this is what we know
you know because a lot of times people
ask us about stuff too we've covered it
on previous shows but it might have been
a year ago you know halfway through one
of them yeah it could be three years ago
it was me doing it solo and i think it's
something me and natto covered it
happens all the time now yeah so you
know those things should go you know and
it would basically be like a
conversation starter and a place that
people could go listen to something for
5 or 10 or 15 minutes um and sort of get
like this is the best we know and here's
some educated guesses
so like strain history
story time and then maybe a third thing
that i've been thinking about which is
like uh gross styles
uh
and
you know and trade-offs
yeah what are you trying to do how are
you trying to do it
um a lot of people that are that that
are trying to give grow knowledge or
trying to sell a certain method
or hydroponic nutrients or whatever it
may be whatever it might be nutrients
amendments
biology
you know a way of life
and they want to convince you that if
you just follow this path like you know
christianity or [ __ ] whatever
buddhism you know this will give you all
the answers yes and life is rarely like
that uh with growing there's a lot of
trade-offs
sure is
you know and so not every growing style
is is suitable for every growing
um you know every growing goal
yeah um hold on real quick people are
asking if we have to change anything
with patreon no there is no new one
there is you don't have to do anything
different the discord it kicks you
automatically into it most people that
are already a part of it already there
if not you just go back to patreon and
click connect to discord hit disconnect
and then hit connect and it'll kick you
into the room and that's it it's got to
be a part of the patreon and we now have
three different
levels
for patreon and the third one's a pretty
cool one so go check that out too yeah
and it's basically just like matt and i
like taking full control
yeah over the process
you know
um weed partnerships are hard yeah they
are they can be very complicated
complicated with two people so yeah and
all that and so um so you know there's
now people are saying oh follow lucas
formula to the holy land that's that's
some of this some of the stuff is like
how
uh but yeah it'll be it'll be chats
about all kinds of stuff lighting
nutrient
greenhouses styles trade-offs and and
some are going to be solo with natto so
you don't have to hear me say yeah every
five minutes and summer could be solo
with me to where you might just fast
forward the whole [ __ ] thing but i
might even we might even have a
situation where people been asking about
like uh fuck-ups
yeah
um you know so there might be there
might be some aspect of like you know
where did you really flail
yeah i've got plenty of stories i got
yeah i got plenty of stories of that too
and that between that and just and
friends and seeing every everyone around
me growing for 25 years
uh you've seen lots of failure lots of
updates
yep you know
so
um so yeah i mean we're gonna we're
gonna be trying to be doing some like
shorter and some more medium term
content
uh you know all that type of stuff it's
basically just like trying to share
culture yeah trying to share info
and and if you're a part of the patreon
discord um like we have the five dollar
fifteen dollar and then the fifteen
fifty dollar one now on the 15 and 50
we're doing like small private group
sessions uh we're going to be trying to
do that once a month where me and not so
sit down with maybe five people in a
group and just shoot the [ __ ] and get
more personal than we ever can get in
these larger groups so check that out
too
yeah
it'll be fun you can ask not so about
all these dirty dirty dirty sex nights
like i do every night
you know matt is uh it's hard for matt
to think about much else
it's that face
it just goes right back to it you know
it's mostly just trying to throw me off
whatever i'm talking about and have me
stutter and uh and stumble
uh while he laughs he's uncrackable he's
uncrackable i don't know if i'm
uncrackable or anything like that
but you know generally speaking
um
ethics and cannabis is weird provenance
is weird because we come from
uh you know a shady
gray area illegals quasi-legal
you know thing where it's basically just
about your word
and you know uh people were either there
they weren't there
and and so you know there's a lot
we see a lot of scams yeah and one of
the ways that matt has become so popular
uh on instagram and other platforms
is by trying to expose said scams
yeah that's more my my autism twinging
though it just [ __ ] drives me nuts
you know and so everybody that everybody
that he tries to expose ends up hating
him
and then that trail gets longer and
longer
they got an
army an army of haters and then some of
their fans end up becoming haters
um and so
you know uh
we just want to give out real
information and you know two when it
comes to the story time or when it comes
to strain history or whatever it might
be
people think that we might be threatened
by better information that comes out or
more information that adds levels of
detail or might change perspective
not at all
the whole point of all this stuff is to
start conversations and to start people
chattering and to start thinking and if
people come out of the woodwork with
verifiable information that makes the
history deeper and richer
like rather than being insulted that's
cool yeah that's awesome i don't know
that's that's to be you know so some
people come out and it's like oh they're
like oh you can prove i'm a liar
no you're trying to tell stories from an
inherently shadowy world
yeah where not everyone agrees and
people argue about everything yeah and
you're trying to give some form of
reliable history
that's as close to what you can get as
what you can get but there could have
been somebody there that adds an angle
to it that you didn't see
yeah and so that's kind of what history
is right it's like science you build on
what you know
and when something comes along to change
part of what you know you add that into
the fabric and keep going
yeah so rather than being discrediting
it's like it's it's a it's a chance to
sort of like crowdsource
information
that's at least how i see it
no i i definitely see it that way as
well i mean
uh if if info comes out we end up being
wrong about something i'd much rather
correct myself and be right than to
continue to be wrong
and i'm i'm much happier knowing more
info that's that's one of those things
about being a nerd more info is great
even if it's counter
you know to what you think
yeah i mean like i you know i understand
what everybody likes history until it
bumps up against their prejudices yeah
exactly you know science too you know
it's like if they prove something and it
goes against your religion or your
belief set or you're this you're that or
whatever and you're like no
you know
oh also before we get done um the all
the websites are working writeseats.nl
riot seedco.com and writeteach.com no
matter which one it is it all takes you
to the site after this on the the
patreon discord discord patreon we're
going to give this set of the canon
bibles away to one lucky person
and
a medium-sized bottle of reversal spray
so after that if you're part of the
patreon we'll probably be an hour after
the show before i even start going
through the names and adding them into
the randomizer thing so if you want to
join you have about an hour to join
after this to be a part of the giveaway
yeah i think that's really it that is
pretty much it
yeah i mean as always i really
appreciate the couple hours everybody
gives uh on friday night
yep you know sorry for the brief uh
technical difficulties but um you can
always reach out to us you can always
chat with us more on discord you can
always you can always message me on ig i
try to be responsive i get buried
sometimes but i try to be responsive to
everybody
you can join the you can join the the
discord and and get some cool stuff and
chat with us and you can also give us
ideas of what you want want to hear more
about yeah we're taking a lot of input
from the from the patreon discord people
on different uh episode ideas on the
single episode ideas um like i said it's
it's up on youtube it's up on every
platform be sure to look for the 2.0
because if you're only following breed
or syndicate and not breeders think of
2.0 you're not going to get any of the
new
episodes so make sure you're following
2.0 be sure to like share subscribe
review all that stuff it helps us so
please yeah and then share and subscribe
there might be stuff where it's like you
know we think it's we think we've talked
it to death but a bunch of people want
us to chat about it because they they
want it to be in more detail
and then we'll be like okay we will yes
so it is responsive in that regard yeah
we try to take everyone's input into
this
but anyway
people keep asking how do you get to
this discord you go to patreon you go
google breeder syndicate patreon you
join the patreon and once you've joined
the patreon it'll give you a thing that
says connect to discord you click that
and it'll take you write it so that's
all it takes
that's it fantastic all right everybody
enjoy your friday night
thank you so much yep see a bunch of you
tonight peace
want more breeder syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsheets.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
you