X would be bubble gum ah
bubble gum I am I I did I had a lot of
experience with a lot of other bubble
gums in the seed line but this this
specific clone I didn't get until a few
years ago and I I find it phenomenal
it's an amazing breeder uh it's mold
resistant this specific cut that CSI and
pip and all those guys use came via 1995
from the cup I believe it was bought the
same year that it won the cup so uh
that's that's what goes around it's a
serious it's a selection from serious
seeds bubble gum the bummer for me it's
a great breeder yeah it's very frosty
yeah it's fairly potent I wouldn't say
it's up yeah I wouldn't say it's up
there with the best of the best but it's
got It's got a good little punch uh the
disappointing thing about it to me is
that it smells very strongly of bubble
gum Terps yes
um but the flavor does not translate for
me not even a little bit no I don't you
don't get any it doesn't it's