ready go
so
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
what's up cool cats and kittens
how you doing
we're gonna have a fun time today
so a little bit we will be joined by
natso oh here he is
buddy
i put out your favorite guitar
oh i see that yeah all for you
indeed i mean this background is nicer
than the yellow two-tone yeah it is it
is it is nice for two-tone yeah
yeah so i'm waiting for some people to
pop in and then we can get started um
we're going to talk about a few
different lines we're going to talk some
northern lights i believe i think we're
going to talk some uh widow which we've
never done
no not yet we haven't covered that we
probably should devote a full episode to
just the white family at some point but
um
yeah it definitely changed changed
everything post 95 yeah
is that a 95 thing
yeah it's a 95 thing yeah and it kind of
it kind of dominated
that and its hybrids for probably a good
well i mean at least at least the next
five or ten
you know it ended up winning it and its
children and its cousins and stuff won a
bunch of cups and it ended up getting
crossed to everything
everything known to man and fginned and
copied and renamed
oh yeah i mean i remember when um
there used to be this uh there used to
be this like harvest festival
uh that got thrown at the end of every
every season up by me and it was kind of
like word of mouth
is that the uh the ncga one yeah indeed
ten percent run ten percent round indeed
but i mean it was like a place where
like you know csi and and
flat like a lot of people
from like the forums
and you know that were movers and
shakers in both america and europe kind
of came out you know
and what's funny about that is like when
i first went to those things
i was like hoping
because i you know whatever it was 20
some years ago now so i was in my 20s
obviously i was hoping to meet like
old-timers like me
that had what that had things that i
wanted
right i was like oh i'm gonna get to go
this thing and i'm gonna meet all these
people
and it was like
everything that was popular on cannabis
world
bcga stuff
i mean you know and not that it was bad
but i just mean
blue widow
you know apollo 13 apollo 11 genius
um you know but but the but the two most
common things that were crossed then was
well the three where it's probably
the blue family
the white family and some stuff like
sweet tooth that was coming out of steve
yeah and we were taking family yeah
people were taking males of that stuff
and crossing it to everything
yeah literally everything so just about
everything there not everything there
but a lot of things there where some
combination of those three families bred
into everything else yeah
so there was white everything
so let's start with uh the white tails
do you want to start with shanti or
ingamar or somewhere in between
uh we can uh
we can start with
i guess we'll start with i guess we'll
start with shanti okay right
so what's an absolute fact
is like in 1995
uh neville and scentsy and that whole
crew they still kind of uh dominated the
scene right yeah and shanti
at the uh at the greenhouse label uh he
released white widow
right which had a combination of it was
different
than all the stuff that other p it
wasn't just a renamed rehashed thing
which is so common right now and but
back then in europe too right yeah it
wasn't a rehash it was something new and
it was a super frosty potent
um high thc afghani that crossed well
with things
and it sort of turned cannabis on its
head
yeah i think it had a killer name
you know and that was like back in the
day when you'd get those like high times
with the super nice spreads for the
cannabis cups and like white everything
which just started being labeled
throughout all those winters it looked
gorgeous
um all that type of stuff so
so that's indisputable as shanti came
out with a seedline yeah about
everything else about it is is i guess
you could say is disputable uh there's
versions
that exist right uh there's one version
which shanti will tell you that he bred
it and it came from his stuff
yep and it and it's a you know and
you know that's that's where it came
from it came from his travels and his
stuff and he brought it there
there's another
there's another story that is kind of
proposed by like i guess arjun would be
it and ingmar and and pretty much all of
amsterdam is uh on the ingomar side as
as best i asked you know all the jokes
ingomar is this is this dutch gentleman
and supposedly in like 89 or 90 he was
smoking hash and out of the hash fell a
few seeds yeah which is pretty uncommon
but some it must have gotten just
pressed
in there or whatever yeah and so he
found this thing
that was
supposedly like uh maybe the cut of
white widow
and they started selling it at grow
stores
right and they started selling it to
friends and they started passing it
around
and um you know arjun claims that he
bought it from dude years before shanti
got involved
and all that yeah so where it came from
and who developed it and all that
there's kind of two camps and it depends
on who you talk to
all those dudes have beef with one
another
so it can be
kind of hard to uh get like
past the beef
but yeah definitely where it became what
made it famous
was it being released shanti releasing
another greenhouse label in 95. yeah and
and in fairness you're always good at
passing the beef dude
yeah you know i mean what's interesting
about that actually is that so when i
was a kid and i was going over to
amsterdam a bunch there was a bunch of
dudes then that were in their 40s now
they're in their 60s and 70s i guess
right yeah and they a lot of there was
camps just like we have now in
california there's people that had beefs
with each other they're people that felt
wronged on deals that went bad or
partnerships that went to skew or that
[ __ ] has my cut
or whatever the case may be
amsterdam in the 90s is actually like a
pretty good indicator
of cannabis and now
yeah it is yeah because humans are the
same yep like we don't change all that
much so all the same type of
interactions and all the same like well
you get credit you got credit for this
but it was really mine
you know that [ __ ] happens all the time
today right if i remember correctly too
peacemaker was another one that was
debated i think uh peacemaker was also
ingomar's peacemaker was also a great
white shark so they
made it over that i was at that cannabis
cup
uh when peacemaker won
and i think it's that's that's one of
the coolest names yeah it's a god it's a
really good it's it's shitty that they
got rid of it and turned it into a great
white shark yeah which is a cool name on
its own but it's like not quite
peacemaker which is now shark shock
right yeah so peacemaker
peacemaker became great white shark
and then greenhouse trademarked great
white sharks so you can't only
greenhouse can call strains that yeah
and then when uh shanti left he called
it
uh
you know shark shock
yeah so it's had you know like a lot of
cannabis strains it's had three or four
different names depending on what area
you're in
uh i went through hundreds of those
seeds
and uh
it's um that was a killer line i loved
it a lot actually yeah some of the most
potent weed i've ever smoked came out of
that line
but the weird part was is that i
i could get really skunky
like really terpy skunky ones that were
mild to moderate potency
and i could get super potent ones that
tasted like cool smoke
but i could never get
this the skunky super potent one in the
same plant
it sounds like that's a common um
kind of thing with yeah i don't i mean i
look like
i i kept one that i would i would
classify as turplus
yeah i think i've had an afghan kush
like that that was very turples i mean
it wasn't that bad it didn't have off
terps yeah no
but it was like the absence of flavor
yeah but it was so potent honestly like
it gave me tracers in my vision that i
kept it even because even though it
didn't taste like anything
like nothing
you know and so i i probably ran through
two three four hundred something like
that seats of
great white shark from greenhouse trying
to find because if i would have found
if you could have found a super potent
one with as skunky as some of them were
yeah
i mean that would have you know yeah a
lot of people's daily smoke yeah for
sure
but the white did that i mean that's
kind of like uh
i just called it the white but
you know so they're really getting
confused folks white widow
but yeah what the white widow was one of
those things where it's like kind of
like the nl line with neville it's it's
it's like it didn't have a lot of terps
but it was super potent and super pretty
and it added it made the bud look nicer
and it made it look frostier and it made
it look denser
all those things that growers like
and so people started blending it with
everything
you know
uh like blue widow was super famous
about 20 years ago during those parties
right because you got the if you could
get the terps from the blue and some of
the color and you could get the potency
from the other like it was a pretty good
marriage
yeah if you could get the frostiness and
resin production of the widow on the
blue
but yeah widow was one of those things
just like you know cookies or skittles
or something like that where like
everybody got it
and crossed it to everything they had to
see what would come up yep
that's kind of like it was one of those
type of strains yeah it was where all of
a sudden for me it was one of the first
like mega hyped name strings for my
generation
like uh i you know when we were first
getting bags of [ __ ] really good weed
everybody would call it either white
riot rider white rhino or white widow
whether it was or not but it was one of
the first ones in my generation that
really broke through with the names
shanti still sells white white rhino i
think he calls it medicine man or
something yeah
yeah something along those lines and
then like uh simon had white russian
which i liked a lot that's right was
which was uh ak-47 by white widow yep
um so yeah it got it was a greenhouse it
was at syria seeds
it was white labeled like crazy all the
canadians all the canadians had it and
crossed it into everything yeah um
so there was a yeah but blue widow was
probably like that was like two totally
unrelated families that liked each other
yeah that was some pretty good [ __ ] it
was a pretty good [ __ ] ron had a really
good cut of that that he'd pass around
yeah it was good and then people tons of
people had seed
of that it was pretty free seed trading
era it was before st it was before the
feminized revolution
yeah you know so it was all still male
based
and
old days when it was easy to [ __ ]
make seeds
it was easy to yeah i mean i
you i don't think i don't even know
anyone that's ever had a failure with a
male
uh yeah i don't either um
i mean you'd have to
i mean you could have one or two males
in your room and hit it with a stick at
the right time and get 100 pollination
everywhere exactly the amount of effort
that people go through now to like make
sure they get enough pollen
out of reversals
and then even with that and all still
the failure rate and all that but that
back then it was like yeah you picked
your best couple males
but it was like what do you call it uh
you call it shock the shotgunning method
yeah because you don't really know what
the mail is going to do to you crack the
seeds yeah so you're just kind of you
know everything is placed until you run
it
everything's yeah you know and so
so yeah so the white widow is like the
story is either shanti bredit
uh which is like and shanti still sells
it
or
uh it was a clone that got found in
afghanistan in
hash
yeah and was sold as a clone
um so maybe they're both true
in a way
because someone had to take it and and
make a seed line from it
at some point i think both of them
claimed that there was brazilian in it
too
there was some kind of brazilian sativa
mixed in and if you look at like the
if you look at all those picks and all
the phenos you're getting from the 90s
it was pretty heavily influenced by the
afghan side of things sure yeah but the
black widow now that you can get from
shanti people find all kinds of sativa
expressions in those so
i don't really i mean you know it's prob
the the parents probably changed at some
point oh what a long time to keep cuts
i would imagine you know i mean none of
those none of those none of those
none of those euros ever admit that they
lost anything but uh
yeah
no they don't you know you ask scentsy
or whatever and they still have all the
same original parents you know
yeah so sure
but yeah i mean white white widow was
that was that was a game changer as far
as that goes
one of the biggest during its time one
of the biggest
well yeah i mean it kind of it kind of
replaced skunk one
as the the primary thing that people
crossed
you know because that's what would
happen in amsterdam it's like some new
amazing thing would come out and
everybody would buy seeds of it
and then mix it with their own [ __ ] and
try to get on the same sales type oh
yeah like they do now
like they do not mean it's like a
standard operating procedure and then
that's even why people should know that
too right is that like that's even why
some of the old-time breeders and stuff
they get all sketchy about telling you
actual lineage
because they know that whatever lineage
they say is just going to end up on some
competitor's pack
yeah
so you know shanti gets out there and
says oh it's this by this by this and
this is what we did to it and then that
exact
thing is is on his is two or three other
seed companies
yeah they're using you know so a lot of
times people like it it sucks like but
we went from like neville and some
people like that being very direct
to today where people hide the secret
sauce yeah
yeah it still doesn't make any sense um
i i you know when i see people hiding
their lineage it tells me usually if if
it's a seed maker or a breeder that's
hiding the lineage it just tells me that
they're they don't understand how
expression works or any of that because
you there's no reason to even try to
hide that kind of stuff you can't make
the same thing happen twice and people
get the same exact expressions twice you
know no i mean that's real weird things
i just think i i think it's an ego thing
yeah people people like the illusion
that people did a lot more work before
they release those seeds to you
yeah that that's that is true that's i
mean i'm not saying that's everybody but
that definitely percolates through the
seed [ __ ] world as far as i'm
concerned yeah it is
people people people
don't like accidents they want it to all
be intentional and you know private
genius that they reveal to the world
chat right now
these guys are killing me
the old j cash
you know and yay jan cash i mean i
suppose i i never saw any uh i never saw
any seeds come out of hash but that
doesn't mean it's not possible
yeah sure especially back then when they
were just whipping [ __ ] they weren't
really filtering it none of that kind of
[ __ ]
uh compressing the block yeah but i mean
it it happens back then
i mean 90 you know and and i you know i
will say that like that area of europe
was the primary
export area for that for hashish from
afghanistan yeah like there's an old
hash smoking culture in northern europe
over there and so they did have a bunch
of like that was america got much
shittier hash
than europe
yeah
late to the hash game you're europe well
not only that but there was like an
overland route
that was traditional and been there for
a long time there wasn't oceans in the
way that you could get there via land
you know and through a bunch of
countries that weren't as hardcore about
searching for [ __ ] is america yeah uh i
we got seagrade hash most of the time
i didn't even realize how good
traditional hash could be until i got to
amsterdam and started meeting certain
people
yeah you know
really eye opening
all right before i derail this
conversation um i'm gonna put up a pack
of the banana tie uh f1 up if anybody
wants them
i'm starting them at 200 and then we're
going to go back to talking so i'll just
pin it as we go
and uh as it gets higher i'll add more
[ __ ] in but i don't want to derail the
conversation too much
so yes banana tie 200 banana tie at 200.
yeah
there we go
so
so yeah i mean i don't know we um
you know i don't i i don't even think i
think white widow was probably
the widow family was probably the
primary thing until kind of like the
sour and diesel wave yeah i think it was
happening
you know and then and then kush came
kind of quickly behind that like kush
had been around for a minute but like in
order to become popular enough people
have to have it yeah and it was very
hard so you know i mean that's that's
that's the weird thing it's like there
was all this [ __ ] with like the chem you
know but it took so long because there
was only like four of us in california
that had it
yeah so like how many how you know how
many can like four garages and a couple
light depths and and whatever else even
do
i think people underrate how much um
the can of bible came into play during
this time during that era right at the
end of the the widow era into the kush
era um in popularizing a lot of these
strains that people had never heard of
smoked seen before stuff that that was
held super tight
i mean jason uh jason king was at those
was at those events
yeah you know
i was pretty good friends with him back
then
um and actually like in especially in
the second and third kind of bible
yeah you know a lot of the people that
he met and he photographed were either
friends or associates of ours yeah like
he came to lake he he was living in one
of eddie lep's houses
in lake county and we would take them
all over mendo and humboldt and stuff
like that
and you know he would take he would get
pictures of various people's farms and
get introduced because back then
especially like
you couldn't just be like a photographer
and be like i want to take pictures of
your weed yeah i know
no that was that was that was not the
era that that was acceptable so you kind
of needed
like a friend someone who like would
vouch for your existence yeah you know
and so we you know we uh but in that in
that cannabis in the i think it's like
the second one
uh my super dog is in there a bunch of
times the mendo perps is in there the
chem dog is in there the snow
we had about i don't know mothership we
had about seven or eight things nine
things or something like that that we're
all in there the pineapple mothership
was that one that you grew
yeah the the uh i'm in mendo somebody
just asked that the mothership is kind
of a crazy story dude i should tell it
just because people would trip out so
jason king had this girlfriend
at the time and she was from
uh the mountains of north carolina
right asheville all that and as most
people probably know asheville is kind
of like it's a little different than the
rest of northern north carolina it's a
little bit more hippie it's a little bit
more eclectic and all that
and so they had this uh
they had this uh strain out there they
called the mothership
right and so
he uh
um she was gonna get it shipped out here
because it was this old ascetiva that we
wanted to try right yeah so i agreed
they ship it out and uh
again i'm i'm thinking to myself it's
going to come and it's going to be you
know a couple clones and a little box
yeah and this is this has got to be
o2 or something like that so long before
smartphones or like checking your
package online like you know just
mailed it and when it showed up it
showed up right yeah so
i'm expecting this little box of clones
and i opened the door one day and
there's this box that's like two feet
tall
on my doorstep
i'm like [ __ ] so i take it inside i have
no idea what the hell it is and i open
it up and there's two plants a mother
ship in there
in dirt pots
staked
you know and they're like they're like
you know 22 24 inches tall each one of
them there's two full one gallon pots
with
two foot plants
bent over in there yeah and then they
tamp down a bunch of packing material
and stuff so the dirt didn't fall out
yeah so instead of mailing us cuts or
like unrooted snips or any of like the
modern tech or whatever they literally
mailed us two two foot tall plants in
one gallon pots
that's one way to do it yeah they both
lived yeah
and all those all those pictures in the
can of bible of mothership
um they all pretty much come from those
two moms
so what was in mothership do you know i
have no idea no clue no no clue i didn't
even like it that much to be perfectly
honest
uh it has some off like i know it still
exists which is cool yeah just because i
don't think it's related to much else
but yeah
it did this neat thing where it grew all
these golf balls all over it
and the thing was super floppy but it's
the only plan i've ever seen that it
would like flop over like 50 percent
and then just hold itself up and grow
sideways
so like you really didn't need to stake
it it would flop
but then its stem would like catch
itself and instead of snapping
you know or just hitting the dirt or
something like that it would hold itself
up and so if you grew it in a greenhouse
or indoor it would grow sideways through
your plants and it would weave itself
through other plants you had that's
[ __ ] weird
yeah it was it was really it was like
the it was a really unusual trait it's
it's stems didn't want to snap and they
would give and then bring themselves
back up
yeah that's interesting but that was
kind of in that era
where weed was weak
yeah like it hadn't real that was even
before like the purple craze where urkel
and grape ape and granddaddy and all
that [ __ ] kind of took over yeah that
was sort of like the last era
where
people like any any type of quality weed
that people grew sold easily
yeah right so people grew whatever they
wanted so was it a sativa type height to
it
traditionally
traditionally sativa type high you know
it had fox tailey buds
was it long flowering or not it wasn't
particularly long flowering like 11
weeks or something like that
and if you grew it outdoor you kind of
wanted to let it ride till you know
halloween
but in mendo and lake county and stuff
like that it was uh it wasn't that
wasn't that hard to achieve yeah there's
lots there was lots of weed most most
good weed in my opinion was done between
the 15th of october and early november
at least where i was where i'm from
so people are asking for the not so dog
story the name of not so dog we got to
do it one more time
the name of not so dog yeah oh man
um
maybe i'll give the edited version
so the edited version is uh my buddy who
gave it to me
um also gave it to he gave it to a
couple other people right not very many
people had there was like four of us he
gave it to uh
skunk va
you know uh he gave it to it got to um
you know i see collective it got there
was a couple up there but there wasn't
it was like four maybe five at the most
who had it and so we used to do this
thing where
not everybody had fresh wheat all the
time
so we'd keep each other in the loop
about who had what coming down when
yeah so this person could grab a couple
ounces this person can grab qp or
whatever so you'd have smoke so you have
fresh smoke you know yeah and so my
buddy from new york he goes up to tahoe
to grab
um we call the tahoe dog
right yeah
and it grew killer up there because it's
so cold
that the air that he would especially in
winter the air that he would bring into
his grow room would be like in the
single digits of the teens
and it would make that [ __ ] frost up
like really strong like it looked like
compared to mendo and sonoma where the
rest of us were like that mountain weed
was like
it was nice
it was really nice i had the same effect
in chicago in the wintertime like
there's something about bringing in
frigid air
that just makes like
makes it it's like a reactionary thing i
don't know yeah so anyway he goes up
there he goes up there to get this he
goes up there to get a like a pound of
dog yeah right and he's and he's
supposed to split it with me and so he
comes back and i was living we were
living in uh willows at the time which
is in northern mendo and he's like dude
come meet me and get this thing
so i come meet him and we're like it's
the middle of winter and we're off on
this side road and he hands me the bag
and he goes tell me what you think
there's something there's something a
little different this time and i opened
the bag and i stuck my hand in this bag
and i started smelling it
and i was like this is not so dog
and he's like what do you mean he's and
i'm like it's not so dog and he's like i
don't get what you mean and i'm like i'm
smelling it and it doesn't smell like
the dog yeah it smells like not it's not
so i don't get the
and it turns out that homie had
homie had uh
mislabeled a cut
and then kept that cut as a mom oh
that's the worst and then it was
actually like it was actually romulan
and that's why dude from new york was
tripping because it was so frosty and so
different yeah
he just thought he did this weird thing
and he crushed it and he brings it to me
and i'm like like in the dark i hadn't
even seen it yet i didn't even know what
it looked like i just stuck my face in
the bag and i was like it's not
and so
fast forward right and uh i'm trying to
uh
i'm trying to join uh
instagram
because everybody was bugging me that i
needed to climb out from under my rock
yeah and join instagram right and so i'm
trying to join and every [ __ ] name i
pick is already chosen
so after about 20 or 30 tries i get all
pissed off and i think well what if i
try this and i put in not so
and
that wasn't taken
there you go there you go so it was kind
of like it was just kind of like an
inside joke
about how when homie i mean he got it
back we gave him the dog back yeah
amongst us there was like it never got
lost
but there was individuals
that lost it briefly yeah and they had
to get it back from one of the other of
us over that time period you know but it
never
do you remember our natso our not so
experienced at the at the at one of the
houses the not so bubba the nuts
i do yeah i do the not so bubba
that is uh
yeah so
that that was funny too because i had
grown i don't know i had like a couple
of beds that i basically grew like all
this head stash yeah
and then i basically like you know i was
so busy with harvest and all that that i
put all that head stash we dried it and
bagged it and put it away you know and
then i dug it all out
i think it was me and a few of our
friends or whatever like the night or
two before that party yeah and we went
and we dug out like 40 or 50 kinds of
weed and jarred it up and brought it all
down yeah and this guy that we're no
longer friends with anymore i won't even
say his name not even worth it yeah he
uh he had given me he had given me the
the bubba kush back
but it was actually
cannerado's 5x2 yeah it was the 5x2 his
selection of it it was his selection of
the 5x2 and so i crack open this jar
and i'm like showing it like our buddy
pip was there and bittersweet and uh and
a bunch of us you know and it was like
people are like dude do you know what
the bubba is
and i was like yeah i know what the
bubba is what are you talking about
they're like what is this weed
[ __ ] i don't know and the weirdest part
of that thing was on top of all that
weed
there was a big fat nugget trinity yeah
yeah
but it wasn't there was only one nug of
that trend on top of it and then the
rest of it was all [ __ ] yeah it was all
that other that was like some light
terpenoline minzy
yeah it was not it was not a great
expression no that whatever that was was
not a great expression of cannabis in
general yeah no no that was some mids i
loved the fact that it was that dude's
selection though
yeah his personal selection
i mean you know when you when you only
when you only pop 10 or 15 seeds or
something like that it's really hard to
find a winner yeah yeah that and that
and like you know things do change from
seed to clone and
as time goes maybe it was cool as a as a
seedling but it really was not cool as a
gun or something something no no and
that was we were lucky though that was
really the only thing that was
mislabeled out of all that work yeah and
that magical trinity nugget right that
magical that magical and that that threw
us off even more because that thing was
so different you know yeah we're like
what the [ __ ] did how did this trinity
get in here
yeah but i mean we had i mean that that
year i think we had
i had two six foot by 26 foot beds that
i just grew like all the mother stock
and all the head stash yeah
those two years in a row i think i did
that yeah so when i brought all that
work down to uh down to that party so
there was literally like probably like
40 flavors or something i don't know
yeah it was wild every time you have
pictures of that both parts
yeah
it was wild and some of it i didn't
bring because it wasn't done
yeah that's right
yeah i think the 91 wasn't done at that
point
no i didn't bring the i brought the chem
d yeah yeah i remember you bringing the
chem d especially the second time when
resin got the the white hot sweats
that was that was actually pretty weird
because you always you always talk about
things you know and like just so people
know when they're listening you know we
have we have friends from all over and
stuff and we chat on discord and some
different things and so you talk about
all this weed but it's not like you get
to smoke all your buddies weed
because we're a pretty like dispersed
group
you know there's people there's friends
of ours from all over the country all
over california and so a lot of times
like we gather up and it would be some
of these people's first chance to smoke
like some of this stuff
yeah you know and that that chem d that
i did inside i grew it under ceramics
ceramic metal halides
and it it it put a few people on the
couch not being able to speak yeah you
know uh one of the one of the our friend
resident was one of the very first
people to grow o.g kush in l.a
uh he got so high off sharing a joint
that he almost decided to go to bed and
call it a night
yeah remember that he recovered
yeah all of a sudden he's like just
sitting there sweating for like 30
minutes just kind of and then he just
goes i'm back fellas i'm out of the blue
yeah they just all stick with our pants
so that was really uh that was that yeah
that's kind of cool too because a lot of
times like
you know you can smoke good weed and i
don't care what kind of weed it is
eventually you build some level of
tolerance to that specific stuff
but if you've never smoked it before you
haven't smoked it months and you smoke
something different you know like we're
going to talk about the
the the headband cut that i have in a
bit
like that that we will get you high
every day
all day long yeah but if you haven't
smoked it in two or three months or
longer and you smoke that weed the first
four or five ten times you smoke it it's
like different
yeah
and there's a lot of weed that's like
that
yeah i think you know that like if
you're not whatever it's cannabinoids an
entourage effect or whatever combination
it just like your body's not used to it
and so it hits you a little bit
different yeah it could even be you're
in a different house different
environment all kinds of things go into
that for me so somebody was saying i
missed that kind of butt it's not around
like that and you're kind of right but
it it is around but it's like people's
uh
what people pick has changed
yeah you're not going to find that in
mostly in cookies hybrids it's just
you know you're like
most people like 20 years ago the only
reason why things were elite was because
enough smokers liked them
yeah right that was pretty much it and
now it's a lot based on testing and
looks and height and other various
aspects
so there's a lot of uh there's a lot of
flash in the pans or mids or whatever
they get pushed
you know um where you know back in the
day it's like i don't not even everyone
had to say it was an elite yeah but
enough smokers who were respectable were
like this weed is fire yeah and then it
would kind of become generally
acceptable
that whatever that was
is fire
yeah you know
and uh the you know the name strain game
has been really bad for diversity
sure has
you know so i remember
one of those years um
i think it was uh denali brought now i'm
used to smoking blueberries and stuff
and i'm used to them being you know ant
anxiety for me and chill and he brought
out some old right berry og across to
g13 hash plant seeds i've made a long
time ago and he grew it and he handed me
a do with that i got the coke shits i
remember just like walking up in that
house that first house like up the
stairs like yeah that was [ __ ] up
there's some [ __ ] that'll get you that's
actually one of the things like even uh
when i was talking about those those uh
those ron parties 20 years ago
is if you show up an event and you smoke
10 or 15 or 20 kinds of weed you're not
used to smoking you're gonna get some
odd effects
yeah
you know one second um drowning with
dagon i don't know how to pronounce that
yes that is the one with juicy fruit
tying it and it's up for auction right
now at 2 20.
uh someone says
someone says you're growing if you're
growing the headband and candy
[Laughter]
advice and people are asking about
advice on the headband
i don't really i mean
those are two of like what i consider to
be like the most potent strains i
personally have
so
um
you know there's a lot i i would just
try to find plants you like
you know i mean as far as effect goes
that's me that's generally speaking the
advice i always give is it's like
what to try to find something you
personally like
you know when and when you're when
you're sprouting seeds everyone's brain
chemistry is vastly different so yeah
find something you like
yeah i mean there's there's things that
like i love personally and matt would
despise as a daily smoker oh yeah
you know and csi and i don't have the
same tastes at all when it comes to
he recognizes like we have the same
taste as far as like what we think of as
good weed
but what we are preferences and what we
like to smoke are very different yeah i
think um urkel even hits in the same way
that it hits me whereas we like to breed
with it a lot we like to grow it a lot
but [ __ ] we will not smoke it because
everything with it gives us [ __ ]
panic attacks every [ __ ] time people
are talking about flowering time so the
chem d is usually like a
i would say it's anywhere from like uh
eight and a half to
nine weaker ten weaker at the most
um and the la is more like a 10 or 11
most of the time
so most of your phenos are probably
going to come in that like 9 to 11 range
and if it's real squat and afghan
looking it probably leans d
if it's tall and lanky it probably leans
a little bit more of the headband yeah
you know
and we have some of the um
the the la cush coming up probably going
to be crossed to the nl5
um the second round
of the nl5 stuff you're doing some
hybrids with it as well as nuts let's
talk about your maui
so the maui the maui is a cool story
in the sense that it goes like way back
so we uh
in uh 1994
which seems eons ago now i guess yeah we
had just me and my crew had just kind of
turned adults and back then it's like
and especially in the midwest where i
was from that's where you went to go get
good weed
seeds was amsterdam right yeah and so we
all flew out to amsterdam
and uh
the short version of the story is we
bought a bunch of seeds
and we were in this coffee shop and
there was this old man who was probably
like in his 40s or whatever but to us
when we're late teens and he seemed
ancient i'm sure and we literally like
shared a cappuccino and shared a couple
joints and shot the [ __ ] for 20 or 30
minutes and he told us that he was from
america and he came out he was from maui
and he came out and he traded he was
trading seeds with uh some of the dudes
in europe and he did it every few years
right
and he gave us uh he gave us a handful
of seats
well it just so happens that we go back
and we bloom all this [ __ ] that we
bought and the best thing that we had
was this weed from maui
that the dude had given us at a coffee
shop for free
and so since we
didn't know anything about it because
we're dumb and we didn't ask any
questions because we were like 19
or whatever uh
only thing i know about it is it it the
dude grew it on maui
and it is
a really it's kind of a strange plant
and that it has super thin
very thin almost like thai type leaves
they're double serrated up both sides it
has like red pedials on the underside of
everything yeah and
but it's short it's only like eight
weeks eight and a half weeks and it
yields huge chunks
all over itself top to bottom
so it but then it had it throws leaves
all over itself but then the leaves are
so thin
unlike a lot of afghanis it doesn't
really choke itself out with over over
leafage yeah you can like see through it
if that makes sense
because all the leaves are like this
wide you know they're all really skinny
you know and so we um
that uh yeah so csi i gave him that cut
so that cut is we sprouted that seed in
the summer of 1994.
so it's going to be 28 years old this
year jesus christ something like that
and he also has another maui i think as
well the maui wowie if i remember
correctly yeah so yeah so he so that one
and that maui um
that maui ended up becoming relatively
famous because i
uh and probably like o2 or o3ish i gave
a bunch of seeds to mandelbrot
of which um
you know i gave him a bunch of super dog
by maui by superdog
and he found this cut called the truth
in there
and he ended up breeding a bunch with
that
so that maui kind of like percolated
around
and it was grown in mendo for years and
years um
because it it'll it'll give you a four
to six pound plant that's done october
15th yeah
and it's not great resin production it's
got great resin production it's it's
it's i wouldn't call it like an absolute
elite
you know like i think it's beautiful
though but it's got it's beautiful it's
it's got a decent high it's got crazy
structure crazy yield
um it's a really it's like one of the
better plants i've ever crossed things
to yeah
so
um
so yeah that he's gonna use he he likes
pairing things
or like looking at different varieties
and trying to see what he thinks is
gonna cross well together
so maybe something to do with uh you
know northern lights has you know
potentially some hawaiian in it
different ones or whatever like he's
going to cross that to the
that's going to get ended up getting
crossed to the maui
um but he released what was it he
released the tk by
maui by tk and maui
yeah
and and i get pictures all the time it
really seems like those those uh maui by
kem or
the la by chem d
people find tons of killer [ __ ] in it
yeah so hopefully you know um
one of the things that's good about csi
is that he's prolific
yeah
he's very prolific dude so by me sharing
some cuts with him
it gives people a chance to try a bunch
of stuff that they might hear about a
bunch um you know because he's probably
the most prolific breeder i know
um someone was asking the the flower
time and parents on the banana tie which
is up for auction right now um
uh
god damn it um it was the the juicy
fruit tie
uh cross two the platinum banana ogb x1
flowering times right around some some
people are getting them around nine to
11 weeks some pull it early um
it's it's it tends to
dominate towards the mother cut which is
what i would have liked it to have done
except that it does have added uh resin
production and some have that beautiful
banana with like juicy
fruit stripes gum for those my age fruit
stripes gums the best description of
what that that mother cut smells like
and right now it's at 220 um
yeah so if you guys want to grab it i
don't have a lot of them left so i'm
just
putting it up and i'll throw in a pack
of the silver pearl blue bonnet as well
which is actually perfect pearl blue
bonnet the silver pearl s1 from our
buddy pit
yeah so i'll toss that in too and that's
a nice cut too dude that cut is
phenomenal i fell in love with it the
first second i even saw it let alone
smoked it once i smoked it it has this
uh
it has its own type of bubble gumminess
which will lead me into something else
but it has its own type of bubble
gumminess that really was brought out
with the blue bonnet it has a lot of
good blueberry bubble gum phenos
and speaking of bubble gum uh me and csi
have a a a selection inside the nl5 we
call it the number seven
and it is
as he as he puts it and he's a big fan
of indiana bubblegum it's one of his
favorite breeders all of it
it is more pink bubblegum
louder pink bubblegum than the indiana
bubblegum cut so we're really excited to
bring that one out and we're also
crossing that specific uh
cut to bubble gum at some point
um
so a couple of things i'll talk about
silver pearl in a second but
one of the things that we should
probably mention that's neat is that one
of the things that's that
csi does that a lot of other people
doesn't
doesn't do at least is that
he'll you know
you can do multi-stage
breeding
right where what matt was just talking
about is it's like he popped a bunch of
stuff he found things that he liked
he made selections and then he's
crossing those selections to a wide
variety of other things yeah and so
there's a lot of breeding right now just
because the way the market is it's kind
of like
one-offs you know so it is neat uh in
that sea of one-offs that where you can
do some multi-stage
where you can pick things select things
cross those things to other things that
you like once you figure out what it is
you know yeah um
and all that and bubble gum is is a
terp
in afghani
yeah you know a neville talked about
some of the maple leaf stuff smelling
very strongly of bubble gums yeah the
original big bud cut had a bubble gum
like nose
yeah so it's one of those it's it's one
of those terps that occasionally pops up
in afghans yeah you know you'll get
you'll get a bubblegum nose and what's
interesting about that is that
while the indiana bubblegum absolutely
smells like chewing gum when it's
growing yeah and when it's drying it
doesn't really taste the same that it
smells no that's the the one problem
that that i found with it is that the
taste doesn't translate
um as well with the bubble it doesn't it
the smell
i mean when it's when you know those
terpenes in the air when it's blooming
it's straight up smells like bubble gum
yeah and then you smoke it and if you
got that like big league chew style
flavor on your on you know in your taste
buds yeah i would probably be one of the
highest regarded cuts out there i i you
know i've had this uh debate going on
with csi about
looking through the durbin poison
indiana bubble gum specifically because
i found out uh in the
in the 95 centistar line there was a
bunch of terpenoline and there was one
pheno that was hardcore pink bubblegum
with some terpenoline and whereas it
wasn't as pink bubblegummy loud as the
indiana bubblegum cut the flavor was all
pink bubblegum so i think in that um
durbin indiana bubblegum there there is
likely to be some some bubblegum tasting
stuff he was he was probably trying to
push you away from it just because you
have to you'd have to sift through so
much terpenoline yeah so find it there'd
be a lot of terpenoline that you'd have
to find those those runts
as it were somebody wanted to talk about
the silver pearl so i'll talk about that
before we lose track so our buddy pip
has a cut of silver pearl
uh lineage and origin unknown
but i will say it looks very very very
much like the fino that neville used to
post at
the seed bank and
um
you know and at scentsy
uh looks very very very similar to that
exact plant yeah um and it it looks like
90s weed
for lack of a better term don't you
think yeah very classic it's not super
dense kind of airy yeah yeah um
it uh you know
this might be something that like people
think is off-putting but like
you know there's a lot of smells and
weed that you wouldn't think are nice in
other instances but in weed you like
them right um but and uh it kind of
smells to me like really young baby poo
really oh it does yeah
it has it has like a baby like a like
not like when kids start eating food but
like when they're on like a pure milk
diet and they're a couple months old
you know
it has this like weird baby poo type
smell to it it doesn't have a bunk to it
it has a funk to it you know and and
what's interesting about that is like
you might think oh gross you know but
roadkill is really gross
yeah like there's no you know people are
like oh i want that there's there's
stink and weed that that like you
related to something else in life but
whatever that is it's gross
yeah that shoreline recently both indoor
and outdoor and there is some [ __ ]
gross to that [ __ ] like it's but it's
good it tastes great yeah so when we
there's like a different aspect to it
where like you can describe things that
might be gross but they're good but yeah
that he he created this it was called
perfect pearl wasn't it yeah that was
the best ones yeah and uh so yeah he had
he had this cut that i i believe it's
from the 90s it just looks tough
like 90s weed it's probably
and we're basically lucky in that regard
because most weed from the 90s most
lines we're lucky if one or even two
phenoes exist yeah
at most yeah
you know i mean that's that's basically
like how much has survived from just
like 30 years ago
which is a crazy thing to say yeah you
know so every
every uh
what are the three gassiest strains
you've ever come across
i mean gas
to me maybe we should talk about that
for a second to me gas is skunk
right like it doesn't have to be but i
feel like like that that straight skunk
smell and that sour diesel smell and
that fuel terp
and the gassiness i think those are all
like variations
of the same terps but you're gonna
confuse people that when you say skunk
do you mean skunk one or
like skunk one is the most confusing
name
yeah because uh you know it but yeah i
mean it
it um
like actual like skunk aroma yeah you
know which which is like the everybody
calls it like the lost terp and i think
it exists in all these different forms
yeah just not in that pure
roadkill form
yeah and i i think it's a lot more
accessible than people realize they just
don't listen
you know super skunk never left
like like headband like you look you
look at diesel style plants which
there's a lot of
yeah and they're just like like from a
breeders perspective they're classic
skunkoid type plants
yep the their bud structure the way they
grow the way they look kind of mexican
colombian with some density like they
they're i mean that to me is like the
diesel family is like modern skunk but
keep keep keep
uh i gotta keep insisting on on
specifying not skunk one because i know
that's all people are gonna hear and
think
yeah so we could clarify that too i mean
i i don't post on ig very much but i
kind of posted a couple times
last week because i got all mad about
something
uh because this this idiot blocked me
for voicing my opinion yeah but uh
basically like that you can you can
actually like look for a longer thing on
my on my uh my my post or whatever but
basically
when sam the skunk man got skunk won it
was super skunky
according to sam according to sam it
reeked it didn't matter how you grew it
who grew it where you grew it what you
fed it what environmental conditions you
had it in yeah and uh he it was all
skunky and he didn't like it
and so he spent from 75 according to him
to the mid-80s doing everything he could
to get that skunk smell out of skunk one
yeah because he didn't like the high
uh nearly and he didn't like the flavor
yeah so
then he took some
some still slightly skunky skunk one to
amsterdam
and kept breeding it to sweet citrus
floral everything yeah
so
for the last 30 years
every four or five years uh people come
up and they say i've got this old rare
special secret skunk one
and you're pretty much you're gonna find
what you want in that skunk one yeah
you're gonna right and instead of just
saying oh it's sam skunk one that uh you
know gypsy nirvana couldn't give away or
i got it from seeds men or i got it from
the flying dutchman yeah i got it from a
million places because everyone sells
skunk one still sells it never stop
selling it never stop selling it it's
the most common weed strain in weed to
this day yeah
just because a bunch of americans aren't
growing it doesn't mean it's the most
common thing out there yeah and they
crossed it to everything in the 90s
everything was some female by skunk one
yes it was the most common thing and
that skunk one
produces citrus
and floral
right yeah and sometimes cheesy
lots of grape and grape you know and
never anything skunky yes no burnt
rubber no burnt tires no rank no nothing
that sam spent 15 20 years of his life
doing his damnedest to make sure it
didn't smell like that ever yeah this
might he did a real and he did a really
good job
he was did the best job you know
and so now it's like i mean i don't want
real i'm not really trying to like call
it out or anything like that but
you know like for instance uh when um
when the swamp boys first came out yeah
you know uh they they they had a couple
of different plants that they bred to
everything and one of them was skunk one
yeah so rather than calling it oh we got
some skunk one they're like oh we got
the skunky thing we call it orange
blossom trail
and it's got notes of sweet citrus and
it's an old florida skunk well you know
skunk one throw citrus yeah so they got
some skunk one they found a good male
they you know they crossed it to things
um todd who i got into an argument with
is trying to sell ancient skunk one
beans
and and hope
and each and he's trying to sell hope
that you're gonna find
that lost skunk terp in there well he
saw that worked with with with uh
dominion so he's like i'm gonna do yeah
i mean
don't wait your audio
can you guys still hear natsu
yeah there you are there you are i'm
back so
so that's that's the same thing too
right where it's like we should maybe
we don't have to talk about the whole
thing yeah but
but we can talk about something pretty
basic is that you know uh duke came out
with this
ancient virginia skunk from the mountain
men of the hills and these guys bread
for ssse
these guys bred skunk for sssc they were
the american breeders for sssc
all this and that you know and that he
inherited these these beans from his
uncle
and this is what he started you know
dominion seeds and crossing everything
to right sure so later on
matt and i got the opportunity which i
think was super cool to talk to the head
guy from sssc sure and we got a i don't
know if a bunch of people put that
together but like we got to ask him
directly
did you ever work with any americans
did any um did you do any breeding in
america were there any people breeding
for you in america and sending you seeds
yeah you know where did you get skunk
one so-and-so did you have people from
america even mailing seeds all kinds and
he said never no
didn't exist
and all skunk one comes from sam yeah
and he said that specifically all his
skunk one came directly from sam all his
skunk one came directly from sam so
you know i don't know i don't know where
um i don't know where duke got his skunk
one
but
it's all the same skunk one there is no
secret
breeder for skunk one yeah it all cut
you people who br who who have skunk one
they bought kilos from sam
sam would would not sell to the public
he didn't want to have what happened to
neville
um and so but he would wholesale to
other retailers in holland because that
was legal yes because seed sales were
legal so he would wholesale his he gave
a ton of seed to
positronics
and to neville and sssc and later to the
flying dutchman and
i'm sure seeds men and so on and so on
and so on and so forth oh yeah yeah and
everyone tries to claim that they have
some ancient rare oh we've got the sam
skunk one from before it wasn't skunky
before sam even touched that [ __ ] oh
we've got that oh no and then and then
you know you got this you got whatever
his ass name is [ __ ] leo stone yeah
claiming that like oh they've got
they've got skunk bud from you know from
brickweed that got sent to france in 71.
four or five years before sam even
started working on skunk one yeah french
connection bro well you know i mean you
know what brickweed sent a
sent to
europe was it was probably colombian or
mexican yeah exactly no but nobody was
making hybrids and homegrown and
bricking it up and mailing it across the
ocean
so everyone tries to come out with these
ancient
you know
yeah i mean he did he said he ca it came
from his fam nba the guy that we yeah
and
you know
his uncle and all that you know and so
i'm not trying to i'm not trying to diss
anybody i'm just trying to i'm just
trying to like straight say
that all these different people say they
have rare unusual secret skunk one
it's all the same skunk one it's all
citrus
you know cheese
floral
grape
you know people breed with it because it
improves bud structure and it improves
calyx the leaf ratio yeah it makes
plants look decent it's decent
especially if you haven't ever
experienced skunk one i'm sure i'm sure
it's unique and decent and that's why
it's in so many lines today it was a
revelation because when sam brought it
to europe it was it bred true for any
number of
different traits and you could get four
or five pounds off it in a greenhouse
yep and they were dealing with all these
weird sativas and all these things that
didn't want to finish in their area and
it was northern europe and shitty
and he brought skunk one there and it
literally was a revolution
but people acting like
skunk one is there some secret skunk one
everyone using skunk one is using the
absolute most common
oldest breeding technique in the book
yep which is consumers like buds that
have nice blood structure and nice calyx
to leaf ratio skunk one does this
i'm gonna take a male skunk at one and
i'm gonna cross it to everything
yeah and then i gotta concoct some rare
special stories so people don't see it
as the same [ __ ] that everyone else has
been doing for forever yeah
and that's the seed business folks
that's how it runs
yeah i mean that's that's the seed
business and so you got to add floral
language to it and so right now todd
is trying to make it seem like
the same skunk one that's been available
from
sam to everyone
is some rare and unusual and secret
skunk that's been released from the 80s
it's all the same stuff yeah it's all
from the same dude and it's probably the
same [ __ ] that's in your cookies that's
in ensure that's in all of it it's been
from the same dude forever and if it's
not from the same dude it's because
somebody bought a bunch of that dude's
stuff and bread it themselves
and just to make more seed
but they didn't do anything specific to
it it's all it's all skunk one yeah you
know
and so one thing we do know about skunk
one right is that there's all kinds of
people we know that have ran large
amounts of skunk one
yeah hunting for skunk terps
and they just don't exist yeah
not happening
it
there's there is some stuff that there
was there were some things in the 80s
that people got that they crossed and
even in the 80s they never got skunk one
to be skunky yeah they had to cross it
to something else together it was
popping yeah that was it was also skunky
to get that skunk turk to pop
like neville took skunk one and threw it
on maple leaf and he got super skunk
you know there was a few different
things in the 90s but now it's like
people are just it's like the same
you know i don't it's like fashion or
whatever right it's like the same
regurgitated [ __ ] and it's like oh
there's a new generation that doesn't
know let's resell them the exact same
thing but let's butter it up
what's cool though is that now with so
many more people making seeds so many
more people able to grow
instead of it being like a cycle of
every ten five years now it's like every
two years every one year every six
months oh yeah and there was that and
there was that guy what was this i
didn't want to say his name was blue or
scott there's yeah
there's there's other people out there
that that sell uh you know there's
another guy that that had uncle fester
skunk everyone all these
all these rare skunks
right all this you know you're right
skunk one is that but i've got this one
hook
that gave me this ancient rare skunk one
but from before it went fruity yeah and
i'm gonna sell it to you now before it
went to amsterdam
you know yeah
and so it's it's
so the the sulfur someone's asking about
the sulfur talk
uh
uh todd mccormick made this post that
maybe people
uh weren't getting skunky smells anymore
because they weren't using sulfur
burners as much yeah because people
don't use sulfur burners anymore i i
kind of took it i kind of took it as
like a bunch of people were buying his
skunk and not finding any skunk
and getting upset about it because it's
not in skunk one
and so he's trying to ruminate on what
could be the difference
right yeah and it's not like any of the
skunk one stuff here's the other thing
people should know
is that uh sam skunk man has been on
every [ __ ] forum since forum started
for weed yes
cannabis world
overgrow
i see mag
you name it yeah he has been spouting
his version of events
for like 30 years yes he's been writing
it down
it's no secret you can have the dude
himself will sit there and lay out
exactly what he did and why and why you
won't find what you're looking for
you know yeah but people want to make it
people want to make it seem like that's
and that's what's kind of coming right
now is everyone was like
5 10 15 years ago i saw a buddy joke
that like
uh you couldn't give away gypsy nirvana
skunk one seeds 15 years ago yeah no he
couldn't i couldn't give him away
because people knew what they were and
they were like no i don't really want
that yeah
you know so
i mean that's but but that's what that's
what's happening is now
you know you can you can segue to it or
whatever and it's the same thing with
sour it's the same like all these old
things that have name recognition
but a lot of people on a personal
experience with them are gonna
repackaged
and unscrupulous people are gonna like
you know sell you hopes and dreams
you know
yeah that's how it goes
and and that's that's a big part of it
is is
they're relying on people not to have
had experience with it in the first
place and and they're relying on all
this knowing that it's very likely a lot
of people aren't gonna have that
experience with it so how the [ __ ] are
you going to tell them it's not that and
that's that's
never stopped existing in the sea world
no i don't think so i mean
they uh
you know and and just just so people
know it's like i see people saying we
should talk about that too running
todd's purist indica and nl5
um
you know we uh
i shouldn't say we uh matt did an
interview
uh with uh with the guy basically the
head guy that kind of
created nl
and his group of friends and his group
of friends and his little group of
growers or whatever kind of is the
reason why nl is so famous
and they sent uh neville and scentsy a
bunch of seed and the rest is kind of
history
and after
um
i believe it was after he did that
interview yeah with you
he found some seed and he sent some seed
to you right matt directly yeah and then
he also sent some seed to todd yes at
the same time at the same time and so
um
you know it's not todd's anything
todd got it sent to him from
you know got it sent to him from greg
you know and the stuff that that uh csi
and and matt and you know this the kind
of little collab thing that's been going
on
um that's all the same seed stock that
todd got
um but we we got it from the same we got
it from the same person yeah and i we
know the main thing was that like
there it seemed like there was going to
be a race to pop them to get them out
there and i didn't want to do that i
wanted to make sure that they could all
be popped at at one time because why i
just looked through
four or five in your closet and then do
a repro from that when you can do you
know 80 of them so we we decided to wait
until it was uh
it was time until we had the space to do
it luckily csi humble provided that and
and luckily we we've pulled it off and
really started and csi you know he's
really experienced he's got a really
good numbering system he's got a really
good note-taking system he's got a
really good way of identifying you know
different traits and different things
that might be of interest
and um
you know yeah the someone just talked
about could you talk about the gypsy
nirvana era
uh that whole that that whole movie and
just that whole era that's probably a
whole show in itself yeah that yeah yeah
that's a wild show yeah that's a that's
a wild show but even his era and
everything that was going on then i mean
we could talk for it that's a
there's a lot going on then yeah we
could bring chimera on for something
like that because he was you know
involved heavily into that stuff at that
time that'd be a good one somebody said
the only time i ever got a sandalwood
smell was there was this
ak-47 that was sent around the colorado
area and the 90s yeah and it smelled
extremely strong of sandalwood uh our
buddy crybaby could probably pop in and
and tell us what terpenes that is uh i'm
i'm old and i don't i don't have
whatever that is memorized but yeah i
don't have any terpene anything memorize
myself either but i have some of it
memorized i know that terpenoline smells
like jack and and
and witch hazel train and train wreck
and stuff like that you know so
um what people are saying nl so
nl is like nl is super famous because
neville and scentsy you know but
basically neville made it so he took
seattle greg seeds
and grew up a bunch of them and released
multiple lines and then a whole bunch of
hybrids yes right and so
he released nl1 and nl2 pure
and then he found one female that was
like a throwback plant of nl5
and that nl5 mother cut if you will
uh he used extensively he crossed it to
hayes he crossed it to skunk one he
crossed it to nl2
uh it was in the poly a lot of the
polyhybrids he sold it was in there yeah
so it kind of bubbled up and got
super famous
uh steve murphy was involved with nl in
the sense that his afghani seeds given
to
greg is the beginning of nlp and the uh
story behind that was um a lady that
steve murphy knew
went through the hippie hash trail
through the mountains of pakistan and
afghanistan and collected seeds and they
don't really know if it's an afghani or
a [ __ ] to be sure but she's the one who
brought them back for steve murphy and
he gave some of those seeds out and they
made their way into the nl the base for
nl the base for nl and so
yeah i mean
and then those guys all got busted in
the late 80s
and
uh greg basically said if he hadn't sent
them to europe it probably all would
have been lost yeah
and
you know uh neville neville was one of
the only only only breeders selling
seeds back then so the stuff that he was
selling became immensely popular
i think you know and then there was
other people was it dutch passion that
sold nl2 was oasis yes yes that was a
dead so there was other there was you
know there was there was other people
that that got neville's seeds or scentsy
seeds and white labeled them or made
their own crosses
um and then so
one thing that we should say is skunk
one and and nl and all that is in almost
everything
it's in a lot of today's work
it's just
generations past
yeah
you know so i mean that's kind of how i
see it it's like yeah nl skunk and hazer
and so much so much and so it's like you
might not you might people younger
people today might not have like much
access to them pure
yeah right
but they
i mean their grandchildren and
great-grandchildren and poly hybrids
from them are all over the place oh yeah
their fingerprints are everywhere
and uh that's partially america's fault
because we give [ __ ] nicknames to
everything
yeah it really is we do we give
nicknames to everything so you start
giving nicknames to thing in your crew
and then only the nickname becomes known
and then you don't know what seeds it
was
yeah you don't know what it came from
you know i mean so it's like you can we
could somebody asked about the dog [ __ ]
the dog [ __ ] was was called uh the dog
[ __ ] got named that an organ
in minnesota where it was popped it was
called electric bugaloo
such a bad name such a better name way
cooler name and it's also very very very
likely that it's an nl5 haze from the
early 90s
but you buy some nl5 haze from the early
90s and you pop a seed and you like it
and it gives you a great buzz and you
call it electric boogaloo
and then you send it out to oregon and
some idiot calls it dog [ __ ]
and then now it's a dog [ __ ]
someone k uh arizona regenerative keeps
asking about granite daddy perp so the
basic story of granddaddy purp is that
it's an urkel uh hybrid or rename
whether it came from ken or whoever else
um the the surviving cuts all are based
on purple and most people that have both
cuts chose to go with the original which
was urkel um yeah that's that's just a
rough run down on it that's it and
there's there's something i mean there's
a lot more i could add to that one but
one of the things that is interesting
about it
is that for as popular as urkel became
there's
i mean there's people out there that
want to claim the mantle
but there really still isn't a
verifiable believable
urkel origin story no there isn't and
it's one of the few cuts that got that
famous
that
like the the story or you know
information hasn't hasn't popped up
you know it really is still a mystery
and there's been people like csi and
myself and others who have literally
been hunting for what it is for 20 plus
years yeah
there's a lot of claimants but none of
them
hold any gas it hasn't seemed to hold it
hasn't seemed to hold any water yeah um
and so that that
when you know when uh
when when urkel came out and became
super famous
that was like the what i call the purple
craze
right and so that urkel granddaddy
purple grape ape purple dragon
um all that all that different type of
stuff my mendo perps all that stuff
became super famous
and some of those names i'm sure renames
some of them are bag seeds
yes that's how it goes
um you know some of them are just well
you know
if i call it grape ape i can claim it
as my crews
and i can take it down to you know and
back then it was like all that weed was
going through a lot of the dispensaries
in the bay area just limitless amounts
yeah and so uh trap mouth glass pointed
out there's skunk in s1 progeny of urkel
and yeah uh yeah even even if you have
the clone or some of the the hybrids or
swans in veg if you take cuts of it it
smells like skunk spray everywhere um it
doesn't pop up very regularly but it's
definitely in there
and you know i mean at the time that it
was found i mean it kind of it kind of
kind of started spreading a lot in the
early 2000s yeah that's right on the
tail end of all that
skunk and everything skunk one and
everything yeah but it wouldn't be
surprising at all that it would have
you know whether it's a poly hybrid or
whether it's a skunk one or a skunk one
hybrid that got mixed to something local
up here
but it's one of the few strains that got
that famous that like there really
hasn't been a verifiable
story i think the only thing accurate
that i've ever heard about it that
sounds accurate at least
is that it's packy skunk one or afghani
skunk one i could i could totally see it
you know yeah but um that that's that's
trailed along with it all throughout its
little life uh and what people say so
it's just interesting that we got that
much there's a lot of stuff we could we
could go into uh
into uh well thought out hypotheticals
yeah that's a deep one yeah
you know there's a difference between i
try to like i try when i talk to people
to like differentiate when i'm i think
i'm talking in like actual fact
yeah and when you're venturing into like
educated guesses or what the plants told
you or you're stringing together a story
from bits and pieces that you know
you know yeah
so
you know um
i mean definitely yeah i mean the guy
said there's definitely afghan like
it definitely doesn't have very much
stretch
yeah no uh urkel was always one of those
ones where
you get it to about the size you want it
to be and then you flip it
yeah
it's it's not gonna it's not gonna grow
all that much one of my favorite urkel
hybrids has always been the um
the urkel trey dog that high lonesome
did there was so much skunkiness in that
[ __ ] line he killed it
he uh uh csi has one
i mean
uh tk by urkel yeah yeah and that's what
that t-1000 came from or whatever you
know yeah and that stuff added a little
bit of potency and a you know a little
different a little different kick to it
i liked that one quite a bit you know
so
i mean
but yeah i mean it a lot what irritates
me is that
there's a lot of like
i don't even know how to put it but
the weed game seems like it reinvents
itself every five or ten years yeah
right and so as a result of that you
keep getting this is what makes matt so
mad is you keep getting people
coming out with the same tired scams
but ready for a new batch of people that
haven't heard them yet yeah and the same
[ __ ] stories and there's some people
i mean there was there was some [ __ ]
somebody posted new york city kid or
whatever oh that dude's had like nine
different monikers and he's still around
spewing spewing bull on various on
various aspects of things and so
i just want to say my favorite was when
he pretended to be an old lady who was
married to a man who just passed that
carried the asian fantasy that was my
favorite yeah my favorite nyc kid won
and so yeah you know rascal uh
there's an era there from like like that
was more matt's era than mine because i
was having kids and wrapped up and and
living in the hills then but rascal in
0809 10 11 like he put out a bunch of
fire yeah he cried rascal i you know
it's a shame he still doesn't too much
but he had a three or four or five year
period there where everything he was
releasing was good yeah and he was one
of the he was one of the first people
along with matt and a few others who was
actually successfully reversing things
yeah so he i don't know if he gets
enough credit no he predated me too so
but he was he wasn't he was an early
wave of revolutionizing how we breed
yeah and people found a lot of fire
in a lot of his lines from back then
manic you still got you still got some
rascal gear
hook it up
yeah i mean matt matt and i actually it
was probably six or seven months ago we
were looking through uh
um
we were looking through a seed list of a
friend of mine who was getting rid of
his seed freezer right yeah and it was
basically all from
say 07 to 2012.
yeah yeah roughly yeah it was roughly
all right in that range and it was
amazing
how little of any of those things you
could still buy today from anyone oh
yeah most of that's gone most of that
was and that's only 10 years 10 12 years
ago
and then you go back another five or ten
years and that stuff's gone and you go
back in the 90s and that shit's gone
yep
you know and so yeah rascal i give him a
bunch of credit
um because you know he bred a bunch of
fire yep and he was one of the first
people to kind of start the new
asian fantasy is some [ __ ] that jason
king put in his can of bible and he said
it was one of the best strains he'd ever
smoked and it was a crazy sativa
and i think that can of bible entry and
how highly he talked about it
created a massive demand for it
and then
it was it was unique looking and that
created and a forum and internet scam
opportunity sure did
same with hp 13 and everything else yeah
and so you know that kind of thing like
in back before ig and all that like the
forums
um you know that was that was where you
scammed people over the internet
yeah you know and uh
so there was a lot of asian fantasy
rumors asian fantasy is almost one of
those weird things where everybody that
talks about it nobody's really smoked it
the only person i know who's actually
smoked asian fantasy and knows the one
guy who's kept it and is going to die
with it
is bodhi and he knows
and apparently obviously jason king
smoked it and loved it enough to write
like super eloquent you know
write-ups about how amazing it was but
then that dude wouldn't share it either
no you know so
um yeah and and that's really what it is
it's like every five or ten years
everything that was available isn't
available yeah
you know people are talking about top
dog and the blue asian in fairness nyc
kid scammed a lot of people and he was
the guy who scammed with the blue asian
that's it happened to everyone during
that i mean i was friends with the dude
for like two or three years and he
pulled the long con so it could happen
to anyone especially yeah at times
everybody gets i mean one of the things
about cannabis is that since it's not
documented very well most of it
um you know you can walk out of the of
the shadows and start claiming a bunch
of [ __ ] yeah like you know my uncles
grew super sativa seed club skunk one
and bred for them in in the 80s in the
hills of virginia yeah or i found asian
fantasy and we did this or i you know
you just whatever story there's still
today people
um
walking out with stories
yeah because who's gonna and they don't
even care if 10 of us know it's [ __ ]
yeah no i mean leo stone's the perfect
example if if i'm going to use a name
just
couldn't give less of a [ __ ] that it
doesn't align with history and that a
lot of people are going to know he's a
liar he's going to know that most people
won't be able to encounter that that guy
said it straight up and he was totally
accurate in what he said he didn't give
a [ __ ] yeah because his his seed
releases sell out yeah that's
so yep he has a goal
he reaches that goal
the haters or whatever i don't even like
that term really but like all the all
the all the people that call them out
and all the [ __ ] and everything like
that
um you know
he doesn't care because it drives drama
and he sells out
i mean there was this thing the other
day where you know uh he came out with
you know like his stupid sour diesel
cross that's full of [ __ ] or whatever
uh that one and it was like limited to
three it says it all over it limited to
300 packs
and then this guy gets a gets a pack and
it's like you know stamped number 399
yeah
you know so
i mean it it just is uh we're right for
scammers yeah and we're right for
selling legends and selling hope
you know and you know todd mccormick or
whatever he does get
he does get his seeds from
real people
he just doesn't add any of the nuance
to it
that you think people would want
you know uh he just wants you to believe
it's
like like walking into the seed bank in
1986 and plopping down money same thing
when obviously it's not
one second um i'm gonna uh give this to
benny bag of beans in the next two
minutes if anybody else wants to get on
it it's uh uh the banana thai f ones
which is the the juicy fruit across the
platinum banana ogb x1 and the perfect
pearl cross to blue bonnet which is the
silver berries so if you want to get on
it get on it now i'm just gonna i'm
gonna push it off in the next two
minutes to betty and thanks for everyone
who's participated so far
somebody's saying todd is cool i don't
know todd personally i've never had a
crosstalk i do todd
he might have issues or whatever like
you know there's a lot of people that
know him or what i was just making a
comment in the sense that
like you call your luck you call your
seed company authentic genetics
you go to great pains to say it's all
from the original the original lines
from the original breeders
and you make a bunch of people think
it's like unchanged kept by the right
guys from the 80s and nothing ever
happened to it yeah and it's not the
case
yeah it's not the case
yeah yeah i mean
i my biggest problem when we first
butted heads was the whole prop 64 thing
which
leads to where we're at now yeah
if we're dying our whole community's
dying and and a lot of that can be
pointed back to prop 64 which todd was a
big proponent of because he had a lot of
rich friends and he wanted to push that
through
yeah i mean todd can todd can uh todd
can talk about what a uh
you know a weed warrior he's been and
while i do have sympathy for anybody
who's been jailed
or suffered uh because myself and others
have all gone through it for sure uh i
didn't live in beverly hills at the time
uh nor did i move back to beverly hills
when i was done
um so there's a there's a level of like
wealth there you didn't have woody
harrelson bailing you out no
no i didn't live in beverly hills you
know i didn't have any mansions yeah for
the cop there's a lot most people didn't
have uh mansions for the cause yeah
that's true you know they had trap
houses and and you grew in shitty
neighborhoods where they didn't they
didn't want to bother you yeah because
you weren't a problem and you grew you
grew on that you know you were on the
outskirts you grew on the edges
you know i mean most people mendo and
humboldt became famous because it had a
good climate but also because people
could disappear into the hills and get
away with it
you know
oh that's interesting um i didn't know
if anybody had asked him project steve
monster how many um males and females he
used in his nl5 reproduction line uh
yeah i've only heard from so i'll i'll
say this about that is that
if you want to get
an l
from
greg
then you can get it from
matt through csi
right and csi has whole pictures of his
rooms
breeding
updates
this that everything else it's all
pretty well documented right yep and
who knows how much or little todd has
done yeah
you know you can you can see how big
uh csi did it yeah
you know you could see that he was
blowing off whole rooms
yeah and he's made selections and he's
done all this different stuff and it's
you know we have a we have a mutual
buddy that's pictures
pictures or it doesn't count
yep you know which i don't think is too
true when you go back far enough because
it was risky then but for now jesus
yeah we're actually doing a run
of the clones of the seed moms even
though we've already pollinated all we
kept clones of every single male and
female to see how they flower as clones
so we know that you know if we're saying
this one's gonna be bubble gummy from
this specific one we'll know that it's
actually bubblegummy as a clone and can
pass onset traits so yeah there's a lot
more involved that people have no clue
about yet yeah i don't think anybody is
going to recreate nl5 haze
um i mean it would be nice we're doing
some interesting stuff but it would be
nice straight in all five haze because i
don't think any of us are rocking just
straight original haze because it would
take a big pop of old original haze in
the first place to find a pheno worth
breeding with and then you gotta hope
that it passes on any of the traits um
but we are doing some crosses with the
nl5 stuff that will be similar to to a
nl5 across the nl5a something like that
and then i wasn't even trying i wasn't
even trying to diss it because basically
what you're saying is is cross a an
extreme sativa to an indica yeah and
hopefully find something i just
personally think that
nl5 hayes is probably the single most
successful release seed line in history
yeah mr toad has an original it don't
even start me on mr toad
so i mean here here's the thing about
original haze is that original haze is
also not rare
it's also easily available it all comes
from the same dude just like skunk one
it comes from sam skunk man
right
and he has sold kilos of that you used
to be able to buy
pure haze f10
in the 90s from the flying dutchman
and they'd have big write-ups on it you
could get pure haze from seeds men
you could get pure haze from all over
the place yeah
um it's not rare
it's not hard to find
what is hard to find is it does seem
that the haze seeds that neville got and
positronics got and
uh
sssc got in the mid 80s
they found phenos that were much easier
to create quality with
than after sam had done multiple ops
open pollinations
so
there's uh you know you could like you
i'm not what matt is basically saying is
that the amount of work it would it
would take to find the type of haze
that's that neville found
yes is really hard yeah
because open pollination is a great
thing but it really opens it up which
means you have to hunt through
so much more
i do know that scabby and white buffalo
have some really good hazes they've been
showing off and uh crossing so i think
that maybe maybe that'll be a cool
project use one of their their hay
selections across with the nlp that
that's a definite possibility tom tom
hills hayes is from positronic stock and
we are uh bidding on the the banana tie
f1 and the silver berries right now
somebody said what is super skunk super
skunk was a very skunky
skunk one male
that neville crossed to maple leaf
indica a fino he called afghan tea
and it became probably the best selling
thing at
his company and then later at scentsy
and it was the line that popped all the
skunk terps that everybody dreams about
yeah
for lack of a better way to put it is
there is there a neville's haze
selection neville selection of neville's
haze in the u.s
uh some people have it i'm sure not the
one that i want yeah i will tell people
if they want to talk about neville's
haze for a second
is that there is a neville's haze fino
um that still floats around europe that
is by far the strongest sativa i have
ever encountered
um it neville's haze especially the
older neville's haze has
like some effects in it that i that are
super uncommon in cannabis yeah uh it's
incredibly potent um i hunted for mine
myself i think uh we have a buddy of
ours on her direwolf is on here he got
some some uh neville's haze in the late
90s
and he made bubble hash or something
like that that like lasted him 10 years
this stuff is wicked potent yeah it's
it's anxiety inducing it's
yeah this the fort collins cough is that
somebody in the room
yeah the cough is i used to grow the
cough
um
i used to grow the cough uh that's why i
say that i think nl5 haze is the
is probably the most successful line
ever released because there's probably
seven to ten phenoes of it that still
exist
right yeah
i mean there's the cough
there's dog [ __ ]
there's uh
c5 there's the pith there's cuban black
like i mean you can go yeah there's
endless really there's and then there's
and then there's a bunch of stuff of
that and so there's like there's
probably more phenos of that most things
you're lucky if one pheno of a line from
that old survived yeah
and nl5 hayes has like freaking
like i said you know it's probably got
double digit elite phenos that are like
30 years old
snow high
as much as um i butted heads with him
over the years he had a [ __ ] amazing
amazing double seize cut
that i i don't know if he still holds it
or not but if if uh people that are
looking for a good devil's haze
if he has some of those crosses out
there he had a purples neville's haze
male it was just that though both
selections are phenomenal phenomenal
yeah i mean it's it's it's got you know
it's one of those things where when you
cross two marijuana strains that are
very unlike one another
you can get some unique combinations
of potency terps
growth all that kind of stuff
i hadn't heard that trout mouth i'll
look into it i hope that's not the case
so
um yeah that would suck yeah
i mean you know
seed breeders and old schoolers and
stuff we're like a canned tanker we're
like a difficult bunch yes you know
every generation has a group that
doesn't get along you know you can go
back and people will be battling each
other on forums and you know people have
strong held beliefs you know
uh i mean tom hill is an amazing
contributor to cannabis but boy was that
dude tough to get along with yeah he's
complex
you definitely don't want to get on his
wrong side you know
because you'd take your head off you
know
um
so i don't know but yeah i mean it uh
i don't have any idea
uh
what i know top dog we uh we both know
top dog i don't know what he's
specifically using on anything
um aces
uh used to be a lot more reputable
they have some shadiness to them
um but it's indisputable
that uh there's some dudes in europe and
other that gave them real cuts yeah they
got that real cut of neville's haze i
was just talking about they have the
real a5 they got the re they got real
cuts yeah um there's definitely some
junk
uh in their stuff but i mean that's haze
so
that's how that's just a part of using
haze
karel does not have his haze still he
has
a 35 year old cut of his haze by skunk
one yeah the skunk one haze but he
doesn't he doesn't have any original
breeding hazes or anything like that
there it is possible
that the haze c exists
which is neville's old breeding male
uh it's possible shanti has it it's
possible it's in spain
it's impossible for us to so far get any
um verification
other than them saying it exists
so this this is a good point autoflower
ak let me get this straight neville
popped a handful of of haze seeds and
found multiple gems in a in a bag from
sam
uh but you
but you think sam's opening that line
made it harder to find keepers that is
one of those um enigmas of haze right
it is
yep and like i said before
opening
you can lose it too
yeah absolutely you can you can op
and op open pollination for for for
anybody that doesn't know open
pollination is basically taking
males and females of the same line and
breeding them together using no
selection and just trying to preserve as
much genetic diversity as you can yeah
so sam has been very clear over the
years for some stupid [ __ ] reason he
never did selective breeding with hayes
never he just decided to continually
open pollinate it
and so it seems like
uh and you know we actually learned some
pretty interesting stuff
um from corel
in that uh sam probably didn't have that
many haze seats
when he came over because he gave
according to corel he gave
he only gave 10 or 15 to
positronics
he only got tennis yeah neville only
like there was me you know so maybe he
only brought over some and he kept some
from himself
and
it does seem like that everyone
that got those original haze seeds from
sam before he had a chance to do
anything with them in europe
that's where all the haze comes from
pretty much for whether it's yeah yeah
positronics positronics is where tom
hill or old timers haze comes from
you know corel had some neville had some
sam still did open pollinate but then no
one has really found any elites
or anything from those open pollinations
that they bred into things to my
knowledge i'm not saying it's not in
there
but when you have a situation where most
of the line is going to go 16 to 24
weeks
and they're admitting that 80 of it is
junk and 10 of it is is nice and 10 is
special
finding that 10 that's special
is hard
yes it is finding a breeding male
that is going to pass those special
traits is even [ __ ] harder
you know um yeah they got lucky
for lack of a better term
yeah and and realistically neville with
whatever he was given
he obviously did a better selection um
based on either luck chance or what have
you and the in in the continuous open
pollination with sam basically open the
line up so much you will not run into
the same phenotype like that
uh very often which is why you're
probably seeing uh high amounts of
variation and not running into the
keepers
and there's there's another interesting
thing that we should maybe say too
when it comes to that is that there's
also a theory
that a lot of the euros uh didn't like
haze by skunk one
because they thought the skunk terps
dominated
the hazecross
and also skunk one is primarily sativa
so it was a sativa leaning plant crossed
with a pure sativa yeah some people
think that the reason why neville had
such such success with it is because he
was able to cross it to very different
indicas
g13
northern lights and a lot of his most
famous hash plant
and there's phenos of those that all
there's there's hash plant haze g13 haze
nl5 haze they all still exist yeah
so some of it could be
that he just had some nicer afghans that
blended better
that could be it too there's people that
believe that pretty strongly yeah you
know
that maybe the things he was crossing it
to was just nicer
you know and it's also possible you know
we don't have a lot of we don't have a
lot of uh
i mean do we have a bunch of
cross-referencing from sam's early era
matt
well
of just about what he was up to and what
he was doing i mean that was one of the
most the longest running and most
angry
part of the forums
yeah remember when he was know it all
for sure yeah he had a few names you
know had a few different names and
people would argue over whether or not
he was the neighbor to the hayes
brothers what he knew whether it was
true
the one guy and it makes sense because
back then only your good friends
would know you were growing uh rob clark
who i respect a lot backs them up yeah
but they've been best buddies for 40
years yeah
you know um there's people that think
that he stumbled upon skunk one it was
already kind of mixed
and he just kind of finished it there's
he claims he started it we have his
version of events
you know um and we don't have we don't
you know there might be other there
might be other aspects of it but it
could be
even that
you know hayes and skunk had similar
ancestors somewhere yeah
because hayes was pure colombian
yeah
you know and so maybe it didn't cross as
well as the pure afghans neville and
shanti did make super silver haze
together
um
i could tell that story because it's
pretty cool uh
when neville was in jail in 1990
somebody grew out some
nl some nl5 by skunk haze seeds
nl5 haze by skunk haze seeds and they
found this crazy fino that became super
popular in europe
and
when he got out of jail he started
breeding it
and uh
he wanted to find he was trying to blend
the three most famous european
you know seed bank lines together yeah
northern lights skunk haze
he was trying to find some combo right
and he wasn't that happy with it so he
bred it for four or five years or
whatever and then
ben and alan drunkers who owned scentsy
by that time he was working he was their
head breeder because they bailed him out
of jail
and bought his company yeah uh when he
was in a tight spot
which he had eternal resentment for
um
because basically it's like they kind of
were like we'll get you out of prison
and get you back into holland but you
have to give us all your [ __ ] yeah
and so he and then they hired him and he
went from being a business owner of the
largest seed company in holland to
the head breeder
and had to give them all his work yep uh
but
be that as it may
um the first cannabis cup i went to in
1995 was named after jack herrera
the whole thing was themed after the
emperor wears no clothes
jack was there they were doing all this
[ __ ] about hemp was going to save the
world and ben and alan drunkers being
money-oriented dutch people they wanted
to release a
jack herrera strain yeah
and so
they uh
say neville said it wasn't ready they
said i don't care
and they released jack herrera
which was his
nl5 haze by skunk haze hybrid
yeah
and then
uh after
um
after he left uh after he broke up with
scentsy and went on and did his own
thing he
started working with shanti who was
younger than him and probably a little
bit more vibrant and had a little bit
more like
verve to get going then than he did you
know yeah um he started they started
working under greenhouse and they
started breeding
uh a haze project which after two or
three years of work i think became super
silver haze
mango haze and neville's haze that's
correct yep and uh super silver haze was
neville's preference
uh mango haze was um
shanti's preference
um same uh same father different mother
uh type of thing uh so half sisters i
guess and then neville's neville's haze
was only supposed to be
a personal project
right yeah it was only supposed to be a
personal breeding project for his holy
grail
the grail that he never stopped chasing
and um and that uh yeah that holy grail
and then he they found such fire in it
at first that they ended up releasing it
yeah um and everybody that got those
first few years of releases there was
crazy sativa power in that weed yeah and
that was kind of the tail end of
neville's kind of like like intense
contributions to breeding yeah mango
haze super silver haze and neville's
haze were kind of like the last three
big things that he did
yeah he did some small releases and some
other different things under some
different groups and with some different
help like from uh
what's dude's name uh
yeah
kanga and he you know he definitely did
some stuff but the last thing that
really became like
like world famous
right like super silver that was [ __ ]
that was
famous
it won like three cannabis cups in a row
it was like you know
it was famous yeah super famous
so
yeah what about the out i mean yeah the
outback is is another one of those
um i mean lots of people have the mango
haze top dog has mango haze you can get
mango haze still straight from mr nice
yeah it's still available it's still
available top dog is bred with some
mango haze
um you know so i mean it's one of those
things where it's like you just wonder
do the parents are the parents still the
same yeah
and you don't get a lot of honesty
no no not with that dude
not with any dude
damn that's right that's true who the
[ __ ] is honest
you're right i mean which which
like tell me which which like guy has a
fire line that got famous that was like
oh yeah that [ __ ] was famous sucks i
lost the parents
me
um american dudes american dudes
american dudes that are stupid as [ __ ]
admit that [ __ ] yeah
so the la the la cut is definitely a
diesel someone's asking if it's a sour
cut it was sold as sour in my area for a
long time it's definitely
diesel type
i i wish i i was hoping with i don't
even want to say their name but i was
hoping with the scammy genetics company
that burned everyone yeah we would
finally um get to see relationships
and see mom dad cousins nephews aunts
uncles and all that and it would like
really clarify a bunch of stuff but
um
you know uh
what happened to my dutted skunk six
uh
that's a real shame so in 2017
um there was huge fires in my area it
was sort of the start of the last four
or five years of every every season has
massive fires and like the second or
third biggest fire in mendo history took
off
and i got evacuated
uh from my spot for about a week and i
lost all five skunk six months
god damn it
it was it was that was a rough week it
was very difficult so
fires uh you know there's been really
bad fires the last four or five years up
in sonoma humboldt mendo
uh trinity
and uh
mandelbrot did have the rear so that's a
that's another long story dude but
uh mando i gave i i uh
yes mandel brought i gave mandelbrot
sour diesel he had real sour
he did is skunk six also humboldt snow
or is that five
skunk six is definitely not humboldt
snow um
uh that's skunk five they called they
called humboldt snow skunk five in
florida i actually the girl who uh whose
boyfriend and her brought it out to
california actually lives not very far
from me
and it made it to eugene in glassblower
circles and it was called snow
yeah a lot of people called it eugene
snow because it was from those eugene
glassblowers
it got brought down to our buddy csi and
if you got it in humboldt it was
humboldt smell
so it went from skunk five to eugene
snow to oregon snow to humboldt snow and
depending on who you got it from one of
those names would be the name you you
attributed to it
so
is the res cut is my headband is in the
root beer that's correct you don't know
that that's not such a [ __ ]
shenanigans you don't know that that's
that i mean that's what he says so
he tentative he he says that's the cut
that was used so lindsey and i will i
will say that in some of the hybrids
that that csi released people have found
root beer terps
yes that is correct there have been some
root beer terps that have popped up in
the latk and the lad
um so it is possible
rez is a scumbag
he was an [ __ ] as our buddy heian
lonesome can attest he was an [ __ ] on
the forums before all the shenanigans
happened with the police
um i have no idea if you have the real
sour diesel
he's on the east coast
somehow yell does have a lot of super
skunk like traits that come out of it
i i can't i'm not even dissing it i'm
just saying that like
i didn't know him back then i mean i
knew of him
you know but like we lived on different
coasts yeah well it's not like we were
in the same hood or the same homies or
ever saw us grow room or i ever smoked
any of his [ __ ] weed
um snow cap is not snow bud
snow cap was a large yielding indica
um but is not related to snow
so yeah yeah there's a guy here saying
multiple la by definos had root beer and
s terps
snow cap was being grown on any leps
farm back in the day i used to live
about a mile from eddie left farm i used
to go out there all the time
um
and uh
yeah um i stopped when he decided to buy
seven acres across the 20
and higher low asians and he was going
to grow 32 000 plants
and i told him i'm like dude if you do
this
you know the dea is like oh three i
think or something i'm like they'll
never let you get away with it yeah
they'll never ever let you get you you
they will come after you they can't let
you get away with it yeah
and they didn't uh he put out 32 or 33
000 plants and it was actually
interesting the way he did it people
should know
that he got medical cards for every six
plants
and he had a [ __ ] grid
mat yeah he had a map of his whole
property
where you got a 10 by 10 and six plants
and it was all numbered and every single
one of those 32 000 plants had a [ __ ]
medical card attached to it with six
plants and a ten by ten that is fun and
he had a plan
to have these all up and down california
yeah and it was going to be eddie lap
farms
and you are going to be able to you can
grow your legal six plants but maybe you
live in a city and you can't yeah you
can grow them out at eddie's yeah yeah
and you could you could actually like at
eddie left farm you could go out there
and
um
you could go out there you could default
he would do a certain amount of work and
a certain amount of basic food and this
and that you know some shadiness to it
let's let's be real but
uh you know but you could and he did
give a lot of stuff to patients and he
got ego
um
he got kind of his ego into his head and
uh they busted him
and he got 10 years
his wife died in prison i believe of
cancer
um and then he got out and he was sick
and everybody was growing
the size that he had the balls to grow
yeah and not getting in trouble for it
um so he was yeah he used to live in
upper lake um i drive past his house
that he used to have awesome uh often
up there on the hill yeah you know uh
and he i i still have signed pictures of
because back then
a field of weed was like you had to be
up on spy rock or you had to be out
somewhere in the sticks yeah yeah for
someone to grow something like that you
know
the real trinity does have some pine
nose skunk 6 was a thing
skunk 6 was the old super skunk cut that
got put into sauer
uh
it it's a long story we don't know we'll
chat about it here right this minute but
skunk six and the super skunk cut that
got brought west that skunk va post
pictures of is the same plant and it
sounds like it was a super skunk hybrid
was the last
uh it's basically the the breeder it was
a skunk it was a skunk hybrid that he
crossed to a bunch of things he's kind
of a rainbow hippie and and not the most
uh you know a lot of these old-timers
they're short on specifics yeah yeah
they were doing a bunch of drugs and
partying and taking acid and tripping
around breeding things and not taking
notes
yeah and then some weed nerds 35 years
later like what were you doing
you know 1988 you know
specifics what number was that and
people are like oh man i don't know
yeah you know but um but what we do know
is that it was this it was it was a
skunk hybrid that he bred for a number
of years and the final thing he did was
he crossed it to neville's super skunk
from seed
and the the fino number six got sold on
dead tour a whole bunch
uh and got went out to colorado came out
to california with us
became very famous
and it was only called skunk six by a
very very small few groups it was we
never called it insect there was
multiple years of debate on whether or
not the skunk six and the super skunk
were the same cut
yeah it took tracking him down and
having him confirm it because all the
cali people just called it super skunk
yeah and then some of the colorado
people that were like his old dead tour
friends some of them called it the six
so it's just that nickname [ __ ] again
you know yep
why aren't the nl's after five around if
they were made
because
uh
greg well no he didn't neville didn't
make use of them yeah greg explained
this
only the one and two were mostly indica
they got progressively more sativa
because they were rated on height
and i think the six seven eight nine ten
eleven neville just found to be a pain
in the ass
if you look back over his early [ __ ] in
like 86 and 87 and 88 or so
you can see nl9 and l8 you can see
different ones bred into things
and then i think by 89 or 90 he had
basically decided
i'm going to use nl1 nl2 and nl5 yeah
and that's it so those are the only ones
that really got
really got blended
that's really all it was you know he got
him in 84 or 85 and he [ __ ] around
them for four or five years and then he
settled on one nl5 female and
i believe
all the nl1 and two he used was male
yeah
yeah for the most part he used those as
breeding kills
all right i'm gonna call this option
pretty soon again get in the bids people
have bid a little bit more i keep saying
i'm going to call it but uh get in your
bids within the next two minutes and uh
i'll call it this is for the uh banana
thai f1s and the silver berries
okay
what else we got
trinity was awesome i agree
we have it today
still has a big ass cola of trinity in
their freezer from back in the day to
compare to
oh wow
yeah and that's the hard part is all the
people that were involved with trinity
basically all lost it in the same two or
three years
yeah
and then by the time it floated back to
people 15 years later
there's half the crew thinks that it's
real and the other half thinks it's even
the people that think it's not real they
think it's a close hybrid
yeah like it's got trinity in it no one
says it doesn't have any trinity in it
it's just a matter of is it the cut i
remember
you know and how is my memory from 1999
to now
and god knows how much it's changed
environmentally since then and yeah it's
a really hard thing to line up like that
you know so um cactus is still around
our buddy uh uh
707 seed bank
um has cat piss in his work
i think that shoreline done outdoor
is
phenomenally more catfish than any other
cactus i've ever smelled including the
san diego that thing is so catfishy uh
the the outdoor grow of it that i have
here
so yeah and there's there's different
there's there's more than one cat piss
yeah and the captain's people do
disagree
on what is catfish there's some
pittsburgh cat piss and there's norcal
cat piss there's the socal cat piss that
he's that matt's familiar with
and there's debates around all that [ __ ]
too you know yeah
and a lot of them are like super silver
haze types where the terpenolane kind of
leans toward uh pissy
yeah
yeah we still have the snow i remember
the snow the snow came out of that same
trinity came out of that same eugene
glass blower small circles
yeah um our buddy csi has had the snow
since probably 98-ish
and he breeds it and all kinds of stuff
so it's there
i don't know the the lineage on um
shoreline at all i mean i'm i'm like the
last person to get it
it seems it seems it's mysterious so i
don't yeah
albert walker exists yep it's around
it exists
so
um and maybe i'll say this before we get
off anybody that has anything old and
rare don't get rid of it
yeah please don't uh right now
especially with the way pricing is and
what and what the pressures on the scene
right now there's a real risk for a lot
of cool genetic diversity to go by the
wayside
um because people might not have money
or might get into a bad spot
and not they might get worried about all
this is i can't even sell this for what
i need you know it's not even worth and
then they just decide to get rid of it
and then you know five ten years from
now there's a bunch of [ __ ] that we wish
still existed
yeah so if you've got something you love
try to hold on to it because you might
be one of the few people left that has
it you never know
yeah you might be one of those people
that has a contemporary line that's
missing
you know 10 years from now 15 years from
now if you love something hold on to it
tight
very much so so
yeah
dude you're at
370.
370. yep
things are climbing
yeah they're slowly climbing
i guess uh yeah well let's let's let's
end this option and then maybe i could
do one more and we'll
talk about the nl projects and and kind
of what we're seeing
um
and we are i think we're going to have
some uh
some natsos la cush crossed to nl5 at
some point yeah
yeah
i've been you know i uh the maui is he's
had it for probably over a year it's
just a matter of making its way into
rotations and being crossed to things
you know
yeah there's some really exciting ones
the corn might be in there which i think
would be an interesting cross uh the the
male nl5 that that we have is our keeper
so far is is uh
a spitting resemblance to the purple
indica which i think is fascinating
since it comes from the same area
yeah
it is fascinating
so that one's going to be also in the
rotation seeing how that purple indica
lines up with that male and i think
that'll be pretty [ __ ] cool
it will be i mean we you have hope
yeah you know
there that ellie that people have been
that la coach by kim d people have been
finding killer stuff in it yeah that's a
great combo it sounds like it seems like
that one really that one really is like
people send me pictures all the time
yeah so
yeah
uh we can we could we could maybe get uh
pip on here one of these days you know
yeah
he's a little shy but he's a good buddy
of ours so we could always ask him you
know you know right now is a tough time
because uh the
the industry itself has changed so
rapidly in the past two years that it's
a real it's a hard time to get people
excited about talking about cannabis
when it's so when the actual scene is so
depressing right now yeah so many of our
friends
you know um and shout out to down with
dirt he just recently passed um
there's gonna be a lot more of that
going on and it's sad but yeah shout out
to him if you knew him send his family
love
and that's that's actually something too
is like there's a not one of what i just
said about the clones but about seed
making too where like there's a lot of
diversity at risk
because people need to be able to make
enough money to survive
and as things get more centralized and
more corporate larger scale and a lot of
the small garage size grows and a lot of
the passion type people start getting
pinched financially it becomes a lot
more difficult to be like oh should i
dedicate this space to something that's
just for me
or should i just grow the whole thing
based on whatever my buddy says he can
get me for it right now
and so a lot of experimentation um
a lot of experimentation is at risk
because you've got to be surviving
pretty well to be experimenting yeah
and what matt was just saying is that
there's a lot of people staring at
survival doesn't mean it won't like
shift and change but right now there's a
lot of people that have gotten used to
living a certain way and making certain
making money off a certain way and the
weed game is dramatically changing
yeah
you know it's really dramatically
changing and so
uh the people that are taking it over
right now they don't really care about
diversity that much they just they just
care about margin and wanting to sell
you some [ __ ]
so you could definitely lose a lot of
[ __ ] in the next five or ten years
yeah
yeah there's there's leaf variegation in
the headband and the chem d so i'm not
surprising you see it in the progeny
will you answer dickey's question if if
l.a kush is a five-fingered plant
please um
you know that
that should vary right
it varies it varies i mean it it it it's
not specific it's not a three finger
but it could have it could have five
seven
you know
um
there is that's it's
i don't know that everything there's a
guy that's everything has og kush camera
cookies in it i don't think that's true
no i mean my cherry berry doesn't ak-47
bluebonnet we did a bunch of stuff in
this last blue round to try to keep that
from being the norm um and i
made a great attempt at it anyway
he's it's true that a lot of stuff does
but there still is if you think about it
there's a bunch of stuff that doesn't
what's up cody it's um uh uh banana tie
and the silver berries i'm trying to
think of what you put up after this one
i think we're gonna call it in a few
seconds i keep saying that but it keeps
going up so i need to add something else
in and we'll call it i'm throwing it
ellie kush has green leaves i mean i
have i have some pictures uh posted on
my page about about it various things
yeah it's
i mean the one thing i'll say about
diesels and la and all that is that you
are not identifying that [ __ ] by picture
uh old timers hayes does not predate sam
sam was the one who introduced uh hayes
to the seed world period i mean he he
may not be a haze brother per se but he
was the one who brought the seat line to
the old timers comes from pozzi right
yeah positronics yes i no i don't know
old-timers has a different claim on
theirs
okay
yeah
okay calling it calling it calling it
professor q 390
writing it down
and then i'm going to throw up the p91 s
ones
i'll just do a pack of that i don't know
if they'll sell for worth of [ __ ] well
let me write this down professor
uh uh-uh uh q
390 and this is the
cherry berry
this is silverberry
and then banana tie
and
i think i put in bubble berry v2 as well
so after it's here again
professor q thank you very much um so
yeah now i'm going to put up the um p91s
ones
start them at 200 and and if you get
them you get them those of you that know
p91 is an old san diego cut um i didn't
make very many of the s-ones i only had
the cut long enough to make s-ones and
passed it out to uh canarado
um
uh one of the third gen dudes and um
genotype a2 in michigan
um it's some type of old super skunk
silver pearl maybe cross of some sort we
have the one of the original packs of
the s1s right here so 200
i'll throw in some more [ __ ] with it
and we got that okay now we can continue
i lost my train of thought oh i'm sorry
i apologize
you have to apologize i'm sorry i just
spaced out first i realized we like been
talking for a couple hours yeah
it's good i've been trying to get i've
been waiting for
matt and a buddy to talk about the bull
rider cut
but uh yeah it um
see bull rider predated me in san diego
by the time i got down to san diego
there was no bull rider to be smoked
except for afghani bull rider and i i
did have experience with the afghani
bull rider it was one of the most dank
loud things that i ever smelled in my
life but trying to find the original
bull rider was just not happening um a
while ago a buddy grayskull um
sent me some seeds of the original bull
rider backseat
and i was originally gonna give it to
someone to tissue culture and thank the
[ __ ] stars i didn't do it
and um recently sent those back to
uh uh grayskull so he could have them
tissue culture so hopefully
yeah bull mountain that that was
actually it was called bulgani i think
is what they kept calling the afghani
bull rider up in mendo when they brought
it down
yeah that's that's my coverage on bull
riders probably some kind of nl5 haze if
betsy it really is it's sister and and
to be
um compared to it i would guess like
skunk one no five hey something like
that i mean uh betsy still exists
yeah and is held by friends but we don't
know anybody that we know i don't know
about half goo either
after he's still around yeah um um pack
has it oh yeah i [ __ ] love app gooey
i wanna i'm gonna actually do that [ __ ]
i do like that one
and i haven't seen that one in a long
ass time at this point did you like it
when you did i did like it
yeah
i think we're gonna like uh
train wreck cross to it soon too
boy
oh a hog's breath question what was
hogg's breath there was tennessee hogs
breath in san diego hugs meth yeah no
that was a uh adam gun lie there was no
such thing as a tennessee hog's breath
hog's breath was a san diego original uh
one of my first mentors was the person
who bred it and uh he passed away
but yeah it was
god knows what it was he said so many
different things and it could have been
just keeping people on their toes but it
was [ __ ] dang it was very like cheesy
toe funk [ __ ]
it's a little bit of sweet depending on
how you uh grew it you could get some
fruity expressions from it too but most
of it the way james grew it was [ __ ]
foot funk cheesy nasty it was great
it's good people are a bunch of people
are saying they still have it or it's
still kicking around hawaii and
still this and that so that's nice i
mean
you know one of the things that's cool
is like if you live in an area where
there's not so much pressure to change
a lot of old cool [ __ ] can just kind of
stay around because people can grow it
and find a home for it pretty easy
in california you get stuck where it's
like oh this you have to do this you
have to do this
oh that doesn't work anymore you have to
do this
yeah
you know and now it seems like it's
really bad where
prices are so low and things are so
rough like people don't even know where
to turn
and by the time they start growing
something they think is going to be the
next big thing it's already played out
yeah and there's a lot of there's a lot
of hype and there's a lot of flash in
the pan type stuff
where for a minute it gets a good ticket
and people are all excited about it and
then one too many greenhouses or indoors
gets it and then nobody wants it yeah
you know so
after we was just that that there's one
thing about after we always remembered
like any time after we was in a hybrid
that that terp would dominate real well
and it was to me the way uh the way i
always smelled it was like a a blueberry
cantaloupe type it was just so addictive
and it's it's always stuck with me over
the years and my favorite f gui cross
was done by bodhi and it was the afkoui
double purple doja which is like an
apollo 13 type and he's got these
[ __ ] massive yielding [ __ ] half
gooey terps ah he sent me some of the
last of those seats that i really need
to get some more made
yeah two dog was asking um
i think sourdee preceded any of the
other stuff
in the sense that
um when sourdy was getting passed around
that's what it was called
it was years before new york city diesel
or east coast sour diesel or
you know shroomy cut or you know
amish or
you know all that different types of
stuff and that's what makes it so
confusing is everybody just got a cut of
sour d
uk cheese is a fino of skunk one we
believe yep
okay here i'm gonna i'm gonna throw in
something extra with the p91 s1
i keep saying i'm gonna do it now i
think this is uh hold on
i think this is only six seeds
let me make sure
but this is the banana chunk and it has
the first name on it this is the old
original packaging of uh i think i
called it deep bananas at first which is
the chunky monkey
deep chump pl uh platinum banana ogb x1
oh [ __ ] i just found them [ __ ]
treasure trova seeds
i just found just a bunch in this one
how about that [ __ ] so there will be 10
seeds in this pack
hot damn i love when that happens so
that in the p91 s1 or up right now
this is a really rare
line that we put out there's a lot of
pictures of it out there and it was
[ __ ] phenomenal i've been trying to
keep enough back to remake it but yeah
i'll put this one out there maybe
someone else remake it
i didn't take any shrooms no
i didn't
no screens today no shrimp no no shrooms
today no i don't if i'm gonna do that
kind of thing i'm definitely not gonna
talk in public
you know yeah for a while there i got i
got
to where i was taking so many shrooms
that i could i could like keep my cool
better than i could being [ __ ] stoned
in a in a room on shrooms
there is a ruby red grapefruit pheno
that people love out of someone's nycd
the thing that people get upset about
with soma
is that he took supposedly some bag seed
of sour
brought it to europe and crossed it to
some kind of afghani
fruity thing that he had over there
and then he called it
diesel
yeah and sold it as the real deal sour
diesel at a time when it was hard to get
and uh that's why people get upset
because if you're it's nothing like real
sour or the diesel family yeah not even
close it has a lot of it does i mean
people like that i'm not dissing it i'm
just saying yeah
you know
and uh who has real sour diesel crosses
um i do
you know there's yes i does archives
does there's there's different things
about it you know like it
it um sour diesel is another one of
those where people are coming out of the
woodwork with real deal sour we could
probably do a whole show on on what we
know and don't know that would upset a
bunch of people uh the good part is that
most of the diesel cuts are pretty nice
most of the most of the phenos that
exist are pretty nice weed so if you get
stuck with one that isn't the really
nice it isn't the real deal
you know um
and then someone was saying something
before about what'd you see first urkel
or lavender i kind of saw them at the
same time
um right around 0-304
yeah
so i uh that was right around that same
time and that was about
four or five years after i had popped
mendo p
uh there was definitely nothing
like mendo p when it first came out
um as far as something that just
naturally turned purple that deep
there's plenty of afghans that turn
purple with cold
and you know as as october came along
and outdoor and stuff if you left let
them out and let the second run go late
and it got cold at night they could turn
deep purple but
um it was four or five years before that
next wave came
so and i don't know when it started
that's what i was saying before a couple
a long time ago is uh
we don't really know what year urkel
popped or where it popped or who did it
exactly
there's various people that claim it but
um
one thing we know is that it wasn't
called purple oracle when it first
showed up
and i don't want to say the name because
it's not my story to tell and i don't
want to give people
you know ammo to [ __ ] fake it but
yeah it was not called purple oracle
when it first showed up yeah just like
just just like i was saying before like
you don't want to give out uh
you don't want to give out sometimes
real info because people will use it
and um like you know like i don't watch
this [ __ ] but matt watches a bunch of
like murder mysteries and you know uh
people doing bad stuff to each other
yeah and a lot of times the cops and
stories will put out one or two things
that's a lie about the story
right did you know that matt
they do that and they do that because
so they can weed out all the
all the like hot tips that they get that
use that bit
yeah because human nature you put out a
story and some people will start calling
and start oh i saw
and so they put out some fake
information just to make sure that they
can weed out because if we if he said
what it was
then there'd be a bunch of stories about
oh my uncle
from white thorne
grew this and we called it that so it
must be
you know
by my seeds
know i have kryptonite and it throws a
lot of mendo perps phenos there's a lot
of people that have mendo perps and
their stuff that don't want to say
there's mendo perps in their stuff
yeah
you know it's really obvious when when
it's in your stuff yeah there's uh
there's there's a lot there's a lot of
there's a lot of modern stuff that has
mendo p in it that people never want to
admit that it's in it
yeah so
you know but that's pretty common
yeah jim ortega on a podcast i don't
[ __ ] know that guy is a sketch
yeah about being in public he did some
prison time
uh he came from a different era of
cannabis
i don't think he has any interest in
being public
although i would personally love
to pick that dude's brain for a while
yeah um you know
so
um but yeah jim ortega is uh you know he
gave some really important strains to
neville
yeah he did yeah and he's kind of a
total mystery and cush 4 is going to be
one of the ones that you will see in the
nl5 cross
crosshairs
and maybe maybe in the hawaiian lights
too if we're lucky
did i take cuts i i used to take cuts of
and most a lot of breeders do this uh
csi certainly does is
you take cuts of everything you're about
to bloom from seed stocks so if you find
it and you love it you still have it
so that's why the mendo perps survived
they have 50 year old seeds will they
pop
what do you think unlikely
unlikely i will say that
that the couple seeds of mendo perps
that i had um although it wasn't called
that i named it that but the couple
seeds i got were 21 years old at the
time that i got them and they popped um
20 year old seeds can pop 50 year old
seeds seems like it's going way back
i mean that would be like 1970
yeah right that's way back
cheese northern lights yes there will be
cheese northern lights absolutely i
think this is a great one great idea
from philadelphia he said i'd like to
hear anonymous people on the podcast
like they say what their role is without
saying exactly who they are giving up
identifying details that would be
awesome
and we are planning to pop the purist
very very soon we are going to follow
through on um the the newest northern
lights acquisitions unfortunately we did
not get as many of those seeds as we did
of the
nl5 and the hawaiian lights we are going
to try to do something with them
worthwhile if if anything
is worth work doing with if that makes
sense
uh there's a question i'm pretty sure
that that there's some mendo p in the
cookie i'm not gonna go into that whole
thing either right now because that's a
whole story and it would probably cause
a bunch of guff but
i guess it it was good for two hours
yeah [ __ ]
that's all good i do believe that there
is mendo p in
in cookies
uh the story is definitely for another
time
there's a lot it's kind of complex but
uh
you know
um i i mean there's
really what it boils down to too is
there's
20 20 some years ago there wasn't nearly
as many people breeding as there is now
because there wasn't money involved
uh as much there wasn't really american
seed companies doing stuff and so most
people breeding were doing it just kind
of for the love of it or
should try to like give good weed to
their friends yeah and so as a result of
that an inordinate amount of
um the stuff that people were working on
made its way into a lot of the stuff
that's famous now
just because there was only such a big
pool
to to pull from you know
it's kind of is kind of the way it
happened
i guess we've been doing this a while
i'm i'm going to call the option give
back call the auction and we're good and
we can do it we can do it again yeah we
will do it and next time i promise you
not so we'll be more naked and um
hd hd
hd dick
yeah i'm you know i'm just it's just
chin up so you know i can do it
nobody knows no
thanks so much thank you thank everybody
for listening
everybody have a real good night
and uh yeah
indeed
good seeing you brother
good seeing you too
thanks to everyone who showed up and um
yeah all love from all of us
[Music]
do
you