[Music]
i
am
ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
all right so uh i wanted to welcome not
so dog everybody um this is a very good
friend of ours uh probably one of the
oldest members of the canned illuminati
and uh a good friend um he has an
amazing history in cannabis and i really
think it's about time that be shared
with the public
so
for starters let's talk about what got
you into growing
um what got me into growing was pretty
simple really uh
i it was two factors mostly i grew up in
chicago
and so when i got into
smoking weed there was really two kinds
of cannabis you had access to there was
brown mexican which was about twenty
dollars an eighth and there was green
mexican which was about thirty dollars
an eighth and anything else beyond that
was incredibly hard to find and
expensive
and so
um
eventually um i realized that in order
for me to be able to
uh have a consistent supply i had to
start growing it even on a small scale
and when you first started growing what
were the strains that were around other
than the green mexican and that were
there any strains around that were
floating that were popular to be grown
at that time
so my my story is a little different
than most in the sense that like
i knew one person that grew weed uh
in terms of what we called kind bud back
then
so there was no um
there was no like community there was no
access there was no internet
um
there you know obviously like you're
growing in a police state where
uh the laws are extremely strict
and heavily enforced and so i think
about
maybe three people even knew what i was
doing
um and so
i got this strain from carbondale
illinois from an old deadhead friend of
mine that was called the crystal chunk
uh which i know nothing about other than
the name
and um that was really what got me
started in growing was just that one
little strain i mean we would the only
places that we knew how to get good weed
on occasion you would find it here and
there but it was basically either going
to dead shows or
that was really the only consistent
place that we knew chicago was super dry
and the
the demand far outstripped the supply so
um i didn't really
you know i i didn't know anybody i
didn't know how to grow my one friend
that knew how to grow he didn't even
tell me that he grew until he was about
to move to colorado
and he gave me clones
right before he left
and then i bought three books i bought
um
rob rob clark's marijuana botany
and i bought
ed rosenthal and mel frank's
growing guide and i bought jorge
cervantes's guide to indoor
and i read those religiously because
that was literally my only source of
figuring out what i was doing
yeah uh marijuana botany's been a a key
book for a lot of older breeders and
people very serious about this that's
pretty awesome that that was one of the
first books you picked up and were able
to read religiously i mean that could
have gone a lot different had you been
growing later and read like three pounds
of light you know
yeah i mean i you know i'd like to say
that i had some discerning like you know
taste and i just literally bought all
three of the books that were available
in like the independent bookstore
that were growing cannabis and those
were the three that existed
um and so i kind of just lucked out
there wasn't very many books there
wasn't very much information back then
about how to grow weed i mean it was
late 1993 early 1994 so
i mean you're talking pre-internet uh
pre-pre anything really there was really
high times and uh these very few books
and high times was uh predominantly a
cocaine magazine going back and looking
at stuff
yeah i mean you know now being an
experienced grower like i would shudder
to read a bunch of those articles and uh
have anybody like take those is like
gospel but
um you know i was young and ignorant and
had no idea
oh of course and and you know what even
even though i wasn't around back in the
80s and early 90s going back and
revisiting some of those old magazines
have been some of the biggest treasure
troves to finding old uh lost maybe not
lost but forgotten information that that
isn't currently in the uh
isn't isn't circling the interwebs
yeah i mean even even later on with like
overgrown cannabis world and stuff like
that any cannabis
source in my opinion does have a whole
bunch of tidbits
out there that are interesting but you
really have to have a pretty good base
of knowledge to sort through what's crap
and what's not
um and so really that's kind of actually
what started my
quest for knowledge
is that
um and who knows if i would have had a
buddy that would have been like here
here's how you set up six lights this is
everything you buy this is how you run
it here's some strains this is what you
do
that wasn't available to me so the only
way that i could figure out what i was
doing was by learning and searching and
trying to find every bit of information
i could to try to figure out how to
how to make it work
okay so we're going to jump over mendo
perps for this second and
the reason i want to do this is because
i want to go over why you chose the name
not so dog but in order to do that i
think we have to do you want to visit
the uh
the name first or the chem dog story
first or mendo perps really i mean it's
your choice
i mean that actually yeah that that
launches
five years into the future from that
point i mean i grew in chicago from 94
to 98 and then i shifted out to
mendocino county california
um and that's where all those stories
that you just talked about start to pick
up
um so
i mean i don't know uh which one you
want to start with either one is fine i
mean the mendo perps is probably the
easier one to start with because it led
to the other
yeah but let's do that
so i was uh i was living
in i had some friends of mine from dead
tour and that's the reason that i ended
up
in mendocino county was i had a landing
spot in california
and so one of them was a glassblower
which at the time was
um you know really just starting to
spread uh
you know there was a core of like bob
snodgrass and a bunch of other people in
oregon um and you know various hippies
and people connected to the dead started
to take up blowing glass pipes
as you know sort of the new way to smoke
and and you know it was kind of the end
thing to have and so
um one of my friends uh learned how to
do it and was um
you know but back then the tech was
pretty poor
you know uh people were fuming gold and
silver and stuff and heated glass and
they'd stick a fan in their window and
he bought this
literally yeah it wasn't actually it's
sad in the sense that some of the
earliest guys
um you know they have lung damage and
stuff like that from breathing in heavy
metals and not having proper
ventilation and you know air removal
systems and stuff like that to stay
healthy while they're working
um just like any other new thing
like uh like
when we first started blowing bho using
a [ __ ] uh a water bottle
coffee filter and an open [ __ ]
blasting little pan you know in a garage
clothes yeah or you know if you if you
were to blow bho back then and you use
pvc pipes and then you realize that if
you stuck your finger on the inside of
the pvc it would end up being all rough
inside and pockmarked
you know and then nobody had any idea
about how purging or anything like that
or
i mean
every every era i mean even like in the
in the dab era that started people used
to like smoke off like cherry red
bangers that were seven eight hundred
degrees oh yeah um that obviously like
once you learn that's carcinogenic and
not good but i mean that's kind of like
when you trail blaze on anything
you know um you know everybody learns
off the back of others that came before
them and used knowledge spreads and
stuff so
you know in the 90s obviously before the
internet really exploded
uh you know knowledge was hard to come
by um it really was and so
you know like
basically like the the ways that i got
knowledge i knew people on dead tour
that grew weed and i would pick their
brains i would go to amsterdam and i
would and that's a whole nother movie
that we could talk about but i would try
to pick their brains as much as possible
and how to grow and then
mendocino county
uh being the southern part of the
emerald triangle had a lot of old-time
growers and a lot one of the few places
in america that really had cannabis
deep cannabis history at that point so
um by moving here i learned a lot
and uh
so anyway my buddy buys this piece of
property and he wants to set up like he
has some money and he wants to actually
set up a
a healthy
way to blow glass and so
we got this old guy who was in his 50s
at the time uh 60s right in that era
and he was a retired hvac installer so
he knew all about
how to set up the you know the
ventilation and how to get like you know
a constant 14 miles an hour of air
away from the
from the you know uh from the torch and
all this stuff
and he had cancer
and at the time uh
the um the lady i was with
um it was part of the reason why i moved
out here actually is because she we were
battling she had cervical cancer and she
was going through all this chemotherapy
and all this stuff in chicago
and uh cannabis really helped her
reduce her vomiting and all that and
it's that's a whole long story but but
basically they passed 215 in november of
2000 of 1996
and it came into effect in 1997 and then
we moved out permanently in very early
and so i felt bad for this guy he was
battling cancer
same thing as my um
my girl was at the time he was kind of
older he was broke
and so i gave him like a quarter pound
of weed and some hash to help with his
chemotherapy treatments and stuff
because it really
had made a massive impact on like
controlling the nausea for the
treatments um
for my girl at the time so
he didn't have any money he was kind of
embarrassed to take it but i insisted i
mean obviously weed was worth a lot more
than you know this was before the green
rush or before
it was still essentially illegal even
though these laws had just passed you
know
yeah and all that and so he
you know um but i just gave it to him
you know and i was like look man i don't
care like if it helps you it helps you
you know don't worry about it i don't
need any money you don't have to feel
guilty just take it and so he kept us he
kept helping us set up this system and
then one of the visits
um he brought me this little like empty
pill bottle
and in that pill bottle it had um a
couple seeds and he was like you know i
used to grow quite a bit in the 70s and
80s before the helicopters came in hard
and he's like i don't have any money or
anything like that i don't grow anymore
but maybe
you could find something in these seeds
that you'd like i dug them out of my
closet so i didn't think very much of it
and i
thanked him or whatever and
i grew them up um and uh
you know
both of them popped
right and
um
i got one male and one female
uh so i grew them up to about three feet
tall
and i was getting ready to take cuttings
off of them and i back then it was like
you know there was a lot of bedroom
grows back then right sure um and so i
was i was taking uh in this
three-bedroom house i had i was going to
convert
one of these bedrooms into a slightly
larger veg and mom area so i had a buddy
help me build it out
and um
we built this room out got it all
situated and we moved all the plants in
there and the next morning i go in there
and he had missed a stud on one of the
one of the wood hooks and this
old-school heavy
metal light had fallen
from the hook and swung down and it had
chopped off the male of the base
i can only imagine the horror as you
walk in and see that
i mean at the time you know yeah it was
like the the light was hanging
vertically and just shining against the
wall all super bright and at the time i
was super i was stoked because at least
it killed the boy you know uh not the
girl
um
you know and so i mean i didn't even you
know and then anyway so i take cuttings
off this thing and i flower it
and
i've it you know it if you've seen
pictures of it obviously the the mendo
purple is a is a royal purple it's got a
crazy smell that's pretty unique to
cannabis
and so i had this weed of it you know a
few months later and i flipped out
because i'd never ever seen anything
like it and we need to to insert
something here
where we kind of explain to modern
growers even as recent as eight seven or
eight years ago purples were still very
not common to come across it was still a
a trait people were trying to braid for
there wasn't a lot of true breeding
purples so to find something that was so
black
so beautiful so purple and bread true
for those traits was something really
unique
i mean this is this is even before
i mean in 1990 this is years before at
this point any of the granddaddy purple
purple urkel
um you know any any of those ones that
kind of came in like the early to mid
2000s wave
this is still four five six years before
any of that even really began even
remotely to spread out
um so you know i mean literally like
purple weed back then was like hearing
stories of purple haze or something that
you'd never seen or there was something
there was some indicas you know um in
mendo that if it got cold in the late
season they would turn purple
but that was cold induced not natural
you know and this thing turned you know
uh royal purple in a climate
mid 70s grow room so it was pretty much
a shocker
to be perfectly honest yeah it would
have been it was it was really a shocker
and i was in my early 20s at the time
too so
um
so i bring this weed to uh to this to
this gentleman and
you know he
he totally thought he gave me different
weed
uh he was like oh my god i haven't seen
that he's like i only grew that one year
and i grew it in 1977 in kovalev up in
the hills
uh now people that aren't from mendo
might not know but kovalev is basically
a little indian reservation in the
middle of nowhere really tucked away
it's a beautiful valley
but it's super remote in the late 70s it
was probably even more remote
um
and so at the time that was 1998 so then
i realized that the seeds that i had
popped were 21 year old seeds and i was
22 at the time
so it was it was it was kind of a trip
and in that regard um and
you know like a lot of old-timers i mean
he
you know that's what he remembered about
it he only remembered the year because
he only grew that strain one year so
basically
he must have found a couple seeds and
some buds
threw him in a in a you know a pill
bottle and stuffed it in his closet and
forgot about it for a few decades
you know
so it was literally like a time capsule
uh to the late to the late 70s you know
um
and
actually to the early influx of the
first afghanis hitting the u.s
yeah right in that right in that same
era you know um
and so you know he he passed away uh
from his illness which is a shame um and
so i never really
i was never really able to get much more
information other than the year and the
location that he grew it and um
all that you know so
obviously like after i
after i uh
realized what it was i was super bummed
that i didn't have the mail um because
at that time i would have crossed it to
itself and everything and had a whole
line
you know um
and all that type of stuff but um be
that as it may i uh
you know i um
i passed out the female to various good
friends and things like that
and uh you know she survived and so
what's interesting about her
is that
i think she's unique uh in terms of her
terpene profile
um
there's nothing else i've ever smelled
that smells like her
and so it's just interesting in the
sense of you know you go through
different eras just like now
you know everyone's searching for skunk
which used to be a super common terpene
in the 80s and 90s and now is like a
unicorn
whatever the mendo perp smells like
however you'd like to describe it it's
not something that survived in other
modern cannabis strains
um so maybe it wasn't unique at the time
but it's certainly unique now
and uh and it does have uh according to
humboldt csi it's he said that you know
like was it ten percent
show skunky terps
yeah there is i mean i i got i you know
he he's done more positive work with it
than anyone probably and i've gotten to
go up and look at
um rooms full of uh s ones that he's
done and
it certainly is a genetic that has a
wide variety of
of stuff in there and we joke that like
you could give a few hundred s1 seeds
out
and uh various people could make their
own unique lines completely based off
what selections they picked um
you know there's
there's black ones where the buds are
all black and the leaves are black
there's burgundy ones there's ones where
the it's very dark purple there's a wide
variety there's everything there's every
shade of purple from lavender to
dark dark black to almost a burgundy or
a maroon there's ones that have pine
sole aromas there's ones that have a bit
of cush or a bit of skunk
um tall ones short ones
um decent amount of hermaphroditism in
there at various points
so you know sometimes when you s1 stuff
it kind of is what it is it's it's a
fairly narrow gene pool but she's got
a pretty wide gene pool and so that
combined with the fact that she's fairly
low thc
leads me to believe that she's probably
like an unworked
um initial land race from somewhere um
because most cannabis back then was
between
7 and 15 thc at best you know
sure and uh with the hermaphroditism
that that's and a lot of people don't
know this or understand this but in land
races and even specifically afghanis
when you run land race afghanis you're
gonna run into a lot of intersex trades
and and that's the way land races work
they're unworked um not all
but a good deal and and those early
afghanis tended to have that tendency
you know yeah i mean that's an
interesting thing too in the sense that
like i mean hermaphrodism is obviously
like a survival trait um
that you know allows seeds to be perf
you know to be created in a different
fashion sure um and so for us
you know since we had this big push
towards seedless it became one of those
things where like it's always
universally bad in people's opinions
yeah
but there's a lot of phenomenal strains
out there that end up being people's
favorites that have hermaphrodism sort
of locked into them for better or worse
train
wreck classic example
sour diesel
exactly old super skunk for sure
yeah and so and i actually think that
sometimes you know that's a that could
be a discussion for a different point we
touched on it in the live that we did
but that you know i actually think that
some terps and certain aspects of things
might even be linked traits to
hermaphrodism and that by breeding away
from some of that everybody assumes that
it's guaranteed it's an individual trait
that can be bred out with no harm to
anything else
and sometimes that could be true but
also i think that could be untrue and
sometimes there's linked traits that you
might really like that are tied into
that hermaphroditism at times
yeah i didn't learn about linked traits
until i was doing a lot of reading
hands-on it wasn't something that i
learned about early on you don't read
about it a lot in cannabis breeding
talks especially on forums and whatnot
but link traits are super important for
people to learn about it's a it's it
basically it's it's uh considered a
siamese twin type trait like you don't
get one without the other and it passes
on as such
yeah i mean and so you know in a lot of
regards it's like hermaphrodism became a
bad word because obviously like with the
way that the finances work in cannabis
like getting a lightly seated room or a
heavily seated room could be problematic
you know but i mean there's also this
thing where several of the most famous
cannabis families
of the last 20 years are essentially
based on multiple instances of
hermaphrodism creating a series of
things that led to some very famous
stuff
absolutely um in that list we have og
kush sour diesel chem dog what else do
we got
cookie
cookies exactly
i mean a lot of these things were you
know they were just
you know i mean people would get people
would end up with some seeds that came
out of their little personal or their
little small scale indoor room you know
that they would hustle to themselves and
friends and they would save some bag
seed and then that bag seed later on
could end up being some of the more
famous strains in cannabis you know uh
sour diesel was born off accidental
herming multiple multiple aspects
multiple rooms at different times of
accidental harms that's right cookie was
the same way
there's other ones we could talk about i
mean
gg4 was multiple accidental herms so
it's really humbling as far as trying to
breed where you know people put all this
you know you can put all this intention
and everything else into it and fail and
then some accidental stuff and a six
lighter ends up changing the face of
cannabis
absolutely
it should be humbling and i think it's
something people need to constantly be
reminded of and it's often overlooked
people try to add their own stories to
history to make it seem more intentional
but in the long run yeah it's a lot of
happy accidents
and i mean you know we we again we
mentioned this in the live but like one
of the reasons
that the actual you know what people
call the mss or i call the super skunk
or maybe some people call the skunk six
one of the reasons i think why
it became um you know so hard to find or
possibly lost was that
you know she was she hermed live pollen
at times early and late and she could
see the whole room for you um you know
at the drop of a hat at the drop of
stress or whatever and so people get
scared of that and they try to breed
away from it or they eliminate a cut you
know all it would take is
one time one room seating heavily and
you can't sell it for as much and you
ditch the cut you know and you don't
realize 15 years later that you'd be
like searching heavily for that exact
thing
um a lot of times people would eliminate
really good strains because they had a
tendency to rot or they had a tendency
to herm or they had a tendency to do
this
and there was other strains that they
could get as much money for or sell just
as easily that didn't have those risky
bits and so they would get just get rid
of it and not realize later on how
important it might be and now you know
20 30 years later we're sifting through
a thousand fake mss cuts
[Music]
as fads happen you know i basically feel
like the named clone thing and fads
is was really detrimental to cannabis in
the long term in the sense that like in
the 90s that was probably the golden era
as far as diversity because anything
anything that was good quality cannabis
would sell easily which meant that all
these all these different things that
people had
all these various like family oriented
strains that were up in humboldt mendo
that were grown every year they were all
viable
and every time a train wreck
or a purple craze or a sour or a kush or
a cookie or skittles or anything like
that happened
literally
dozens to hundreds of high quality
cannabis strains would get shifted to
the side
because they weren't as easy to sell as
what was currently easy and most people
only want to hold on to
whatever is currently easy to move at
the time
so like i mean to give a perfect example
in maybe 0.40506
when the purple craze was raging
everyone and i mean just about everyone
up here had
purple urkel grape ape granddaddy purple
um all you know mendo perps all these
various things because there was an
endless
you know demand
for with brokers for as much purple as
you could produce they would take and
they would go quick and so that led to
a whole bunch of stuff being shifted to
the side that was really good but you
fast forward 15 years and how many
people held onto those cultivars people
absolutely are hunting for original
urkel original gdp original this
because as soon as it went to sauer and
kush and other things
98 of the people that had it ditched it
yeah and weirdos like me and caleb kept
working purples because they're pretty
or you laugh at times when people are
like where's that 2010 era sour diesel
oh yeah
which is pretty late to the sour diesel
game but for some people it's like that
was when they actually had access to a
real cut and then they lose the cut and
they think they can get it back from
someone else and then they can't find
that cut again
and and and realistically a lot of the
times specifically with sour diesel 2
they'd be searching for a cut with the
name sour diesel and they would have
already been they would have absolutely
been growing a different cut not related
to sour diesel so they just won't find
it again
yeah i mean sour diesel you know we've
talked about it a bunch it happens to be
one of the more confusing and extremely
difficult uh families to sort out what
cut came when
from who where i mean even though we
know multiple people that were
originally involved and we've gotten the
chance to interview them and pick their
brains about stuff
there's still a decent amount of holes
and unknowns
and you know the cuts don't there's
certain things where like you know the
the the chain of of of you know of who
had it when is really well established
and with sour it's a lot more difficult
sure is i mean yeah that is pretty crazy
that we've been able to talk to the
people who first had their hands on the
original seed that was popped and we
still can't quite untangle the whole
story
and it's not because they're lying it's
it's not necessarily all of them you
know some of them are really good dudes
but it's just a matter of of different
perspectives and memories
and with that specific one i don't think
that there there was a you know
obviously there was a seated room and it
seems like even in the very beginning
there was at least two possibly three
sour cuttings
like you know popped by different
members of that crew
exactly
[Music]
just wanted to give a quick shout out to
my buddy crybaby
um he's the one recording this and
helping us with uh getting this done so
a huge shout out to him he has some
amazing f2s and open pollinations
available you can find him at
crybabyorganix on instagram so give him
a shout
[Music]
yeah so anyway getting getting back to
what we were talking about a little bit
ago
um the mendo perps um
i um you know when we were talking on
our live and i was talking about the
history of super skunk and in regards to
that specific cut and stuff
um
you know the
the my buddy you know which i call you
know from staten island or whatever he
lived in sonoma county
and um i gave him a joint a purple of
mendo perps one day um not long after
i'd found it and he fell in love with it
and he
um he ended up giving me
um
what people now call the chem 91 and the
super skunk
for that cut sort of just an informal
trade or whatever and so that's kind of
like the mendo perps led me
to the chems is basically is the easiest
way to describe it
and now that we're touching on that
let's uh let's go ahead and do do the
the entrance to the chems how it all
went down um i know we talked about on
the live feed but there's gonna be a lot
of people who only listen to the podcast
and aren't familiar with the live feed
interviews so go ahead and cover it all
i'll give the i'll give the
a relatively short version of the story
because um our buddy uh skunk va has had
a uh you know has has told the story at
great lengths and stuff but
the cliff notes version
is that
um
skunk va being from virginia
had some you know hippies and friends of
his and mentors that were from that area
and uh him and our our east coast buddy
used to go and see
all the jerry shows the jerry garcia
band shows at the war field basically
every time he played
and so
um he uh our our staten island buddy had
this strain called the francine and the
francine was a
old indica really flavorful prone to rot
and
some of these friends
of skunk vas from virginia
flew out and were absolutely in love
with this francine
and so they told uh our buddy that if
you bring us the francine we'll give you
some skunk cuts that we really adore
uh and he at that same time had already
made arrangements with chemdog
um
you know chem dog had the chem dog and
he didn't want to pass it out to anyone
because he didn't want to get cut off
from his sources or his you know
he didn't want anybody to have it on the
east coast basically sure
but because dude had moved to sonoma and
lived on the other side of the country
in california he agreed to give it to
him as long as he didn't share it with
anybody back east so
um
homie drove the francine
from california all the way out to
virginia
and traded the francine for the super
skunk
uh
in 1993
and then he
drove up to massachusetts and met kemdog
and he got that's where he got the what
we call the dog other people call it the
chem 91 or the kem dog
he got that
um there was also the chem sis back then
but he didn't like that one very much so
he didn't end up taking it
um and he had some extras of the super
skunk and so he gifted one to chem dog
before he drove back home
and then he drove back home and brought
the super skunk and the chem dog out
west
um
and that's and how it ended up in
california
that's how skunk va and myself
and ic collective all got a hold of it
was through our buddy and so that's the
short version of how
so yeah it was basically
jerry shows
uh hippies liking weed
uh some informal trading and it just
kind of ended up where it ended up on
the west coast
and what year you said it was 1993 when
it ended up on the west coast
it was 1993 when it ended up on the west
coast yep and uh our buddy held on to it
for a few years
when jerry died in 1995 i believe
um skunk va like a lot of people stopped
traveling and got a home
uh wasn't on dead tour anymore and
that's when he started growing the super
skunk and he has obviously
posted some old polaroids on his page
which are amazing because it's you know
visual evidence of that exact cut
um
you know and um and then and then he got
yeah he got the super skunk and the chem
dog in the mid 90s from our buddy um and
then a few years after that i met um i
met those guys and i traded the mendo
perps um for those two cuts and that was
the start of me having them
okay and let's talk about how you got
your name
so that's a little bit more complicated
um
so basically um
our staten island friend he was an early
adopter of the
don't pass things out
which is unusual because he he freely
traded with me but for the most part he
really didn't want things getting out
and he really didn't want the chem dog
getting out and so if you got it from
them you pretty much had to swear that
you weren't going to pass it to anyone
um
and so for a while
quite a while actually this is like long
before the internet or forums made it
famous on any level
um there was really only
to my knowledge i think there was only
about four people that really had it in
california then there was him
uh
skunk skunk va um
a guy whose handle is icy collective on
instagram and
then myself
and so there was really only like four
grow rooms that really had it in it
and uh
it was some of our favorite herb and
um staten island and skunk va lived in
uh
in sonoma county i lived one county
north in mendo and ic lived in tahoe at
the time
and so depending on who had the freshest
herb we would trade amongst each other
all the time to make sure that we always
had fresh you know fresh chem dog
and so
um
staten island drove up to tahoe
the tahoe dog uh not to confuse people
with tahoe og but like when the chem dog
was grown in tahoe
there really is something about mountain
grown herb
and the cold cold temperatures that you
can get up there
um
i noticed this in chicago growing in
winter if you can bring in 5 or 10 or 15
degree air into your grow room it really
makes the plant frost up
um like maybe it's a defensive mechanism
i don't know but if you can bring in
bone-dry bitter cold air into your room
um it definitely causes a reaction in
the plant and so
i see grew some of the most visually uh
appealing
uh 91 that you could find and so we
would always get fresh batches from him
whenever it came down and we would trade
amongst each other so staten island went
up
and he got a couple pounds off of him
and drove it back home
and uh
he met me and we were outside of this
little town called willits in uh in
mendo
and it was in the dark and he want i was
gonna get some of it
and so he's like man he's like i can't
believe it this stuff just it looks so
different i've never seen it look like
this it smells a little different i
don't know what happened
and so he hands me this turkey bag and i
open it up in the dark and i stick my
nose in there
and i'm like it's not so dog
he's like what do you mean and i'm like
it's not so dog and he's like what is
that i'm like i don't think it's the dog
i don't think
i i don't i don't i'm not getting the
nose that i would expect he's like it's
gotta be it's the only thing he has and
i'm like i stuck my head in it again and
i'm like
no i don't think so and we got a
flashlight out and we start started
looking at it and
it ended up it wasn't and
it ended up it was a
um he had uh mislead there had been some
mislabeled cuttings and he'd kept a mom
and he'd filled a room full of cuttings
of what he thought was the chem dog and
it ended up being this other cut
um and so
yeah and then
when i was uh when i was trying to uh
join when friends of mine were
convincing me that i needed to join
instagram and some other stuff and climb
out from under my rock um
i kept entering names into the thing and
every single thing i could think of was
taken
uh which was got hella annoying
so
i just
popped that name in as a joke and lo and
behold
it wasn't taken
you know and so uh it didn't it was kind
of like a like an inside joke between us
um because
of yeah it was i'm not even sure what
that strain was to be perfectly honest
because he only grew at one time before
he got the dog back and got a properly
labeled mom again but yeah that's kind
of how the not so dog came to be
i absolutely love that story
uh what can you tell us about superdog
um so that's a little
that's that's kind of involved but uh
basically what it boils down to
is that um like i said staten island had
the super skunk and the chem dog and
those were kind of our two favorite
strains uh or some of them at least
and um
you know uh him and i were doing a bunch
of breeding together um
hobbyist stuff i mean back then like
there was no intention of ever
uh you know selling anything like that
whatever that was way long before some
of these like most of these american
seed companies got started we were just
trying to
um
breed i'm kind of like the traditional
way to breed right like we were trying
to take traits from two different things
and combine them into one
and so
um the super skunk had amazing terps and
it was lime green and it was frosty
and it reeked and it grew tall
and the chem dog was kind of dark it was
kind of ugly but it had incredible
potency
and so we were trying to see if there
was a way that uh
we could combine those traits in the
same plant
and so he had actually started the
project before i met him
um it was like one of those things where
you'd laugh at it now where everybody
comes out with 20 strains a year but
this was literally like a
four to six year project
um that we would do here and there
um and so he had actually done uh the
initial stages of it um on his own
and he had taken a hawaiian
and crossed it to the super skunk
and then that was
i think it was it was brought to f3
maybe selecting two
the skunkiest traits we could find
and then that was and then a male of
that was hit to the dog
uh chem 91 and um that got labeled
superdog
and then we hunted through
a bunch of those seeds
and
found some keepers
there's actu there's a picture in the
second can of bible
of some buds of it as well as a bunch of
plants
passed it out to a bunch of friends
um and then
you know we started doing this thing we
did some
line breeding with it we did some open
pollination and we eventually
did this huge open pollination um where
we took like the seven best
uh super super dog males that we found
and we hybridized them to everything we
had which would have been
a whole host of stuff my maui cut fact
the chem 91 the super skunk the warlock
the black domina the mendo perps i mean
basically every nice cut we had access
to we blew off a huge room of it
um and uh and yeah it really was
kind of the best of both worlds um in
the sense that
the
super skunk for all of its legendary
status or whatever it really only had
moderate potency
and the terps were volatile in the sense
that it smelled like a dead skunk the
last two or three weeks of bloom and
maybe the first three or four weeks of
post-harvest
and then if you held onto it long enough
it honestly went a bit generic
yeah you know whatever those terpenes
kind of went to a little bit more
generic green bud once those terps faded
and the chem dog they were actually
perfect to grow together because
the chem dog took a while to cure and
didn't really reach its quality until
about a month after you cut it down
where the super skunk was at its best
the first month you cut it down yeah
yeah so if you grew the two together you
could smoke a [ __ ] ton of uh of super
skunk super fresh and it would be
amazing and then by the time the super
skunk was starting to lose a little bit
of its luster the
the dog would be just exactly perfect
and once the dog hit that perfect point
it would stay good for months and it's
um and so they were really nice to grow
together
uh and so we were trying to get
the terpene
uh and aromas and all that and some of
the stretch i mean if you see those
pictures that
uh
skunk va's posted it was stretchy
where
where the chem dog was a little bit more
afghan a little bit slower growing not
not extreme afghan it had some stretch
too but not as much
and so we were trying to we were trying
to figure out a way can we get the
potency of the chem dog
you know mixed in with the vigor and the
nose and the taste of the skunk
and uh it was a hobbyist project
and in a sense we did it for us and our
friends and so
um yeah we just basically [ __ ] around
with breeding here and there in
different rooms and different places
over time
working on it refining it passing out
various cultivars we found to friends
and stuff like that and that's kind of
how it all got started
so my first interaction with superdog
was seeing it inside the can of bible
number two
and at that point you know
at that point kim four was circulating
kmd was barely circulating um cam 91 was
almost not circulating at that time but
a few people had it but jesus was in
circulation and uh i remember when bodhi
gave that to me i thought wow this is
supposed to be mass super skunk and chem
d i and i loved that cut but i always
thought what would it be like with chem
91 so when i saw the super dog inside
that can of bible that became one of my
white whales my white whales and it
still is it still is one of my white
whales because i still haven't found it
um
yeah but that's that was my first
experience with the super dog
seeing it
looking for it i eventually
uh i think it was a diesel crossed to
the chem dog dnl
and i named that superdog 2010. now this
is long before we were friends but it
was just so funny um when we did meet
each other and became friends to find
out
i was friends with the guy who created
one of my white whales
yeah i mean you know the farther you go
back in cannabis it really is kind of a
small community
you know in that regard and um
you know i used to joke that you're only
like three hippies removed from anyone
uh
you know and it really yeah i mean back
you know like it really
it really was like um you know uh
it kind of now it's spread out there's
all kinds of people doing it all over
the place but um back then it was
riskier it was smaller there was only so
many people involved
um and you know and on top of that like
even breeding
i mean all the breeding that we did
essentially
was a labor of love like there was no
profit margin in it there was no
american seed companies there was no
real way to market your seeds
um anything like that i mean if you were
if you were trying to
you know start a seed company you went
to amsterdam
absolutely and tried to do it over there
so really it was like
um all that breeding was done with
intent to grow
better weed
for our friends and you know and to have
it there wasn't any
fame involved there wasn't any money
involved and in fact it was a money
loser because obviously back then
prices for herb were extremely high
compared you know uh and so
blowing off even small rooms of seed um
that you weren't even gonna make any
money off of you were just going to hunt
through yourself
it was basically a labor of love you
know there wasn't
any
there wasn't any intent behind it except
for to try to you know grow better weed
and be like this strain and this strain
maybe we can combine them and we can get
these traits to pop out in one strain
combined you know
i think a lot of that is missing and
this is just my opinion but i think a
lot of that is missing in today's market
um obviously times have changed you
don't have to
i mean
you never had to but the idea yeah was
americans went over to amsterdam
and they started their seed companies
over there um
a lot of that has changed to seed prices
have gone up it's become a market in
itself to sell seeds to where people are
getting rich you look at dna you look at
uh you know a greenhouse any of those
companies that are mostly seeds
and to this day you still don't sell
seeds um so it's very admirable to me
admirable to me
but i still think you need to sell seeds
i mean i don't i don't know like in a
sense like
it wasn't so much that um that you know
i just it just wasn't even it just
wasn't even feasible back then really it
didn't seem like it was possible or yeah
american seed prices were what 20 bucks
a pack if you knew someone something
like that it was it was a way different
world
to be perfectly honest uh while i never
thought that way
my buddy that we did the that i did the
project with
he
he saw what could be coming and he had
this idea that um
you know if we made rooms full of seed
that you could actually produce way more
seed in that room than you could ever
produce bud and that you could actually
do really well with seed and his
intention uh at some point was to
flip it around and start selling some
seed but it was really like it was
really too early people weren't into it
people didn't want it we tried to move
it to friends and things like that at
the time
and uh you know at that era people just
wanted dependable clones
that would sell for high dollar and they
didn't most people didn't want to do
hunting um they didn't wanna
you know they didn't want to put in the
time they just wanted to get a plant
that was going to
work for them and move it on and so we
did a bunch of this stuff and it was
kind of like
i don't want to say it was ahead of its
time but you could just say that the
market perhaps wasn't quite as receptive
or ready and that there wasn't a
distribution channel um
like the internet and stuff like that
that made it easy to do that
i was just doing it because i wanted to
create
better weed to smoke for myself and
friends
but my buddy from staten island he
actually kind of
he did see what was coming although we
were years away from actually making it
work where
he realized that like one day
um you know seeds could be extremely
popular in america
and that there'd be a demand for them
and that you know off a six or an eight
or a ten ten lighter you could actually
make way way more seeds than you could
ever make as far as um
producing flower for sale or anything
like that
um and uh but honestly
um the world really wasn't ready at that
particular moment you know they uh
it was really the height of like certain
clones fetch top dollar and so the vast
majority of your friends just wanted to
run those clones because it was
consistent it was easy
most people didn't want to hunt back
then
um
you know and that type of thing and so
he
he was a little ahead of his time in
that regard in terms of like what he saw
coming i never saw that as much
um but you know um you know i just
wanted to create different things that
friends and i enjoyed to smoke
uh and so what that led to was that
um you know i i've never sold beans or
anything like that but i've given a
whole bunch of beans
and strains i found from those beans
away to close friends
and various people and anybody that i
thought had a good heart
uh as far as uh you know where they were
at with herb and that
um in retrospect because i did that i
went through some struggles uh and that
you go through in cannabis at times um
and
the only reason why some of this stuff
exists today
is because i passed it out
because i personally ended up losing
most of it uh through a series of
unfortunate events
actually oh god
yeah acts of god police fires various
different things can occur where you end
up uh you end up not having what you you
know i mean it's happened it happened to
all the guys in amsterdam um it hap it
happens it happens all the time you know
uh yeah
you know people get in trouble people
get visited things happen fires happen
ex-girlfriends get angry at you and
trash your stuff uh all kinds of there's
all there's all kinds of different
stories about their out there about how
famous things end up getting lost you
know and part of the problem is is that
if you hoard things too tightly then it
really narrows
like who has it and um
you know and then uh
you know it can be lost permanently yeah
that's that's always the big catch 22 in
pickle um
how much do you really trust someone to
give them someone something that's
special how well do you know them yeah
you know but i mean the thing is is that
you know back then
you know we're talking late 90s early
2000s it really was a different era
in terms of all that like nobody was
it was all still pretty underground
nobody was trying to make a name for
themselves nobody was trying to become
famous off it
like i said if you were going to do that
you would end up moving to amsterdam or
something along those lines and trying
to do it on the on the legal or
semi-legal kick
nobody was really advertising it was all
word of mouth and extended friend groups
you know
yeah um so you know there's uh
i had a we i had another friend uh
out here at the time and in
the early 2000s
he had started to show some interest in
breeding
um and working some stuff and he was he
was from up in northern humboldt
and um
i hadn't really done that much before
and i was i had done a bunch of it
and so um you know we had other inch we
had other shared interests that we had
together and
so we were hanging out and he wanted to
get started and so i ended up giving him
uh
a few thousand seeds
of various things that we had made
mostly super dog crosses
and some clones to add to what he
already had
um so he could get started and start
playing around with stuff
and that guy ended up becoming
relatively famous um especially
um after he sadly passed and his name's
mandelbrot
um but if you
anything
um
anything that he you know i'm not i'll
just like pre you know preface this by
saying that like by no means what i'm
about to say am i claiming a bunch of
uh mandelbrots like mantle or anything
like that but
if you look at
um anything that he did if it has chem
dog super skunk
maui
sour
uh a few other things um that all came
out of seeds that i gifted him
yes
you know is basically i gave him a few
thousand seeds to get started so he
could hunt and play for things and then
out of the uh
out of the
the maui super dog
um he found that cut called the truth
um
you know uh he
you know so i mean he changed some names
and stuff so if you see something that
says amherst super skunk that's the same
super skunk cut
um he spelled chem dog instead of dog he
spelled the d-a-w-g
um you know he took a little artistic
license here and there on on some of it
um but anything that you see
that in his stuff that has that as a
basis um
that was all stuff that i gifted him you
know um and then he took those things
and bred with them and crossed them to
things that he had
um and made his whole uh emerald
triangle
um emerald mountain i think was the
first one that he had
uh he was doing a bunch of stuff up in
arcata
um
and uh after he died
um his brother who's a super nice guy
um has tried to continue it with emerald
mountain legacy
that's right
yeah and you know sadly when he died um
it seems like um i don't know who they
are but a bunch of people seem to have
raided his mom room and seeds and stuff
like that and so
there was kind of a free-for-all on who
got his stuff
[ __ ] typical
yeah it kind of got it kind of got you
know it kind of got a little dicey there
or whatever but you know he left um
you know he left four kids behind who
were pretty young
uh and um one of our mutual friends
obviously uh mean gene uh did a very
successful auction uh to help out the
kids
and his brother came out to try to
continue on what he'd been doing and
help support the family and stuff like
that and so
you know
um
you know uh but yeah so as far as
as far as some of the superdogs stuff um
it ended up being
you know it ended up being the basis for
a significant percentage
of what mandelbrot ended up breeding
with and using
um because i supplied
not everything he had some of his own
cuts and stuff like that certainly but i
supplied a number of cuts
and
a bunch of seed to get him started on
his breeding projects and so a lot of
what he did
got based off that work that uh
myself and my buddy from you know
from staten island did together
you know
and that's kind of like how things were
a lot back then i mean anytime i'm
talking about any kind of breeding
project whether i mentioned them or not
i almost almost never back then were you
doing something alone in your basement
by yourself
you always had a buddy who was helping
you or a partner or you brought the
strains and you ended up doing it at a
friend's spare bedroom or
you know i mean there wasn't
back then nobody cared about rep
nobody was trying to have ownership we
were all just trying to like breed on a
certain level
um and so
you know um
you know most most cannabis stuff occurs
in groups
you know and that was that was certainly
true with most of our stuff sometimes it
might as well just be a helper sometimes
it was a full partner
sometimes it was someone that like let
us use
a room or a spot on their hill for a
project we wanted type of thing
um
and so that's how most of that stuff
went down
um unfortunately
you know um you know i uh
you know mandelbrot got a little bit of
a an ego
um about various things and didn't
really want to like
once he got a bunch of credit and a
bunch of fame he didn't really want to
um
you know he didn't really want to return
certain things that i'd given him after
i'd lost them in various ways and that
went on for a few years and we
eventually patched it up
and he was gonna make right on
everything and give me back certain
things that i had lost that he still
held
but sadly he you know uh he had a sudden
and unexpected death
and so that never really came to
fruition
um so
uh
through a series of unfortunate events
myself and
my buddy and some others we all lost the
superdog plants and lines
um
but they're not totally lost because
tons of people have ran his work
and so they exist
in that form all over the place
yeah i still have this mystery cut here
called the truth that may or may not be
from him
yeah i mean that you know um so i mean
that's that's really like i mean to me
it's
it's like that's i mean we've talked
about it before but i have like a few
things in terms of what i think makes
you a good breeder or not you know let's
go
well i mean i think for for one thing i
think the most important part is that
you know
can your can your breeding can your
breeding produce elites
and what i mean by elite i mean right
now you know with mark modern marketing
and stuff like that coming into cannabis
uh everybody has elites everybody has
rare amazing fantastic killer genetics
right but in the in the old days what
became an elite was like enough growers
enough heads
smoked it and thought it was worthy
enough to be
something that was
highly desirable
and that's how
all the old elites became elites
was that not everybody had to agree that
it was the bomb but enough people agreed
that it was the bomb and it was
desirable and that it had
whether it was its terpenes or its its
potency or its effect or its growth or
you know some combination thereof
um
you know that's how that's how
all the name strains that we like to
collect got named and got popular right
so
you know and so there's some people
out there you know and so like
you know i don't even care if your lines
produce a bunch of garbage to be honest
as long as it's possible to produce
elites out of your line you know because
i mean let's face it like we're
essentially trying to do
we're essentially looking for lebron
james
yes right
or a supermodel or you know something
along those lines you're looking for a
rare combination of traits right richard
simmons exactly yeah you know and and
it's like so obviously like in the in
the line itself
you're only going to find those
superstars every once in a while
otherwise they wouldn't be elite you
know when people like say a keeper in
every pack you know i mean that to me
just means that like
you could have a high floor but a low
ceiling
correct where you find something that's
reasonably decent in most packs
but you don't find very much that's
that's so i would prefer to have a low
floor and a high ceiling
where i think that's what tom hill went
for too like with the haze and whatnot
well yeah i mean the hazes especially so
the haze
you know i mean obviously you know um
we've talked about this a bunch in
private but like
there's a reason why there's so many
hazes that are 30 plus years old that
are still carefully held onto
sure um
but even those guys that had access to
tons of seed they had to go through a
ton
to find what they wanted
yeah the metric ass ton
yeah i mean and so
you know it's there's a bunch of i don't
want to say the word garbage but there's
a bunch of stuff that you wouldn't pick
for yourself
because it's too much jungle weed uh in
some of that stuff and so
you know i mean there's certain seed
companies out there
that have sold literally millions of
dollars in seed
and i and they don't have nobody is
trading cuts
of theirs at all
yeah over
you know
decades of over decades and it's not
like every once in a while people don't
find nice things in there that they hold
on to but like
you know so it's like if if someone has
gone through tons of your work and
nothing has popped up
right
that ends up being that way in my in my
opinion that's kind of a failure yeah
which is okay because it's like
breathing is mostly failure yeah it
should be if for someone with a
discerning eye and uh with enough
experience it should be mostly failures
yeah and sometimes you know sometimes
you just don't get what you want most of
the time you know um so that's kind of
the first thing is like
you know like i don't so for me it's
like i don't really mind if
you get junk or bunk i mean i used to go
and i mean we could talk about this at
different at different points but i mean
i would make you know multiple trips a
year to amsterdam and buy a bunch of
seed
right yeah
and
you know there's things i bought from
neville or scentsy or whatever that i
never found jack [ __ ] that was worth
anything
yep but then there's other people
that in that exact same line found
highly desirable keepers that have been
kept alive for a long last time
very true
you know and one of the mistakes that i
made back then was i would go over there
and i would buy like two packs of like
15 different things
yeah when when older me would have been
like i'm gonna go buy two or three
things and i'm gonna buy 50 or 80 seeds
of each thing yeah
and really try to deep dive but you go
over there you get all excited you know
you're like i'm gonna get this i'm gonna
get this i'm gonna get this i didn't
really understand as well as i do now
like
you know it's much better to try to go
through 30 40 50 60 females than it
would be to get eight
sure because what are your chances of
finding a supermodel or lebron james and
eight females you know any any
geneticist or breeder would laugh at you
if you had that small of a selection
pool
yeah i think most breeders outside of
the cannabis community looking in like
readers that are uh in agriculture tend
to think what we do and how generally
speaking as far as like uh
seed companies and whatnot they think
it's silly that we would even consider
f1s f1s nowadays
yeah but i mean at the same point when
you're growing corn like you know 50 000
corn starch aren't going to get you
lifetime in federal prison that's very
very true
so yeah i mean obviously there's like
the luther burbank thing of pic pick the
best and ditch the rest yeah but when
you have severe legal penalties in many
states that are based specifically on
numbers
you know
um you know genetics is a numbers game
it sure is right
and so you know and and all that and so
um i actually think we've been able to
do an amazing amount of positive work um
in the 90s and early 2000s based on
garages and things of that nature
so you know the second thing i would
think is beyond the ability to throw
elites is
um do other breeders want to take your
work and work with it
that's super super important to me as a
legacy type thing that that should be
what we all strive for
because really eventually everybody's
going to be forgotten sure um you know
one of the the first podcast you did i
wonder if you did a poll
how many people even knew who seattle
greg was
you know
not very many really but he is one of
the most important founding people in
cannabis in in that regard you know
absolutely um you know so everybody gets
forgotten dude you know so it's really
like
you know the thing that won't get
forgotten even if they have no idea who
you are is that if you improve the
cannabis gene pool
if you create plants and you create you
know elites and stuff like that that
other people end up using and breeding
with
then you know you made a lasting
contribution
that's a legacy because people might
have no idea who he is but they're
growing nl poly hybrids they might not
even realize that there's nl in there
but they are
you know and so
he made a lasting contribution to the
gene pool
that exists for decades after he quit
you know
and so i you know that
you know being able to find elites in
your stuff is one
two is other people
thinking highly enough of your work to
want to use it in their own work and
continue on with that stuff you know yep
and three is kind of a silly one because
it's all ego but three is if people want
to steal your work and rename it and
claim it as their own
uh then they really like it yeah
exactly because now they want it to be a
part of their legacy they they would
they would like to steal your legacy and
you know and then make it their own and
get the credit and get the fame and get
the whatever from your stuff so
obviously if they're trying to do that
then whether or not they give you the
credit or not they secretly think quite
highly of your work
absolutely and
you know and so i mean i obviously like
you know you were in you were in music
for you know
for a while and stuff and it's kind of
like breeding is kind of like the music
industry like there's lots of talent
that never gets recognized sure there's
lots of talent that never makes any
money
you know
um so if your goal is like is social
recognition and money um most of the
time you're going to be disappointed
in that regard and there's lots of
people that did a ton of good work you
know and lasting impacts
that you know we're at the you know i
mean look at you know look at look at
all the the 80s hip-hop none of those
guys made any money but fast forward 15
years and the next generation of hip-hop
some of those guys are worth hundreds of
millions of dollars now
you know so it really is like what era
you came up in
you know
uh you know neville
probably died pretty broke
yeah um
and uh right definitely did
you know he never really he never really
uh
um
he never really benefited
uh in that regard in my opinion um you
know most of his money went to legal
fees yeah you know he never he didn't
end up like arjun from the greenhouse
where he was worth millions of dollars
and had stable this and investments or
anything like that like he was enough of
a pioneer that he actually spent chunks
of time in jail
and had the dea trying to put him into
prison for the rest of his life and he
got [ __ ] over by business partners and
i mean some of that obviously like i
mean he had his own personal demons and
struggles and stuff but sure um but he
also was one of the most important
people in cannabis but he didn't you
know he got he got notoriety and fame
based on it you know yeah um but because
america has this this rename game
where we give nicknames to weed based on
cultural stuff
it kind of like a lot of a lot of stuff
that's neville's
uh people don't even know
because because it gets a name like
electric boogaloo or it gets a name like
you know
dumpster or it gets a name like if or it
gets a name like you know
absolutely
you know and some of those things you
know it gets lost to time what they
originally were
you know and sometimes those strain
names change again
based on what crew they go to you know
and so that happens a few times and so
you really have to have a good you know
get some luck and some history and some
digging to find out like what what
things are you know
and so all that kind of stuff gets lost
to time so for me
it really is like
breeding is like what you ca what you
what you add to the gene pool
because then eventually other people are
going to be smoking good weed that you
had some small hand in creating or
making better or adding that it gets out
there you know
i mean yeah
because i uh you know in that same
instance that um you know i lost some of
the the i lost my my super dog lines i
lost the mother cutting of the mendo p
the mendo perps for a number of years
yep um but because i shared it i got it
back
you know
and um you know i did some breeding with
it and some of those things are in some
pretty famous things right now and um
but i mean our mutual friend csi i don't
think anybody has done more
like he's the one that made sure that
the mendo p and its genetics are
permanently in the gene pool
yes
he's bred with it so much
and he's added it to so many different
things and so many people have bought
his seedlines
that
he's really the person that made it a
permanent addition
you know and he makes a perfect example
of of the difference between uh you know
someone that's been doing it for a long
time does it write every time not not to
say he doesn't have failures but he he
does
what a real breeder should yet he's not
one of these
mega famous you know multi-billionaire
millionaire [ __ ] aryans
no i mean all right you know that's the
thing about ariane is that like he ended
up
in a perfect space and time you know he
really did
there really there really is something
to that where it's like he got shanti
and neville
to form greenhouse with him you know
yeah um and then they brought their
genetics and their famous cuts and all
that and then you know he won they won a
bunch of cups
back when like the high times coming out
of what what was winning cups was like a
really big deal sure you know and so the
amount of americans and the amount of
people that would go to amsterdam and go
to greenhouse and buy weed and smoke
weed from greenhouse and then buy seeds
made him extremely wealthy
you know um but he was i mean he he was
the business side of it and that and
that's you know that's like a whole
other interesting topic of like
the and it's happening now in america
where it's like um in the 90s it's
really like uh you can really learn a
lot from watching what happened
in
um in amsterdam then where the breeders
and the people with the passion for the
plant and all that ended up melding with
the money
you know
and
you know uh it wasn't always the
happiest marriage you know uh
i mean obviously like you know going um
you know
uh neville had his seed bank
right yeah if he doesn't get if he
doesn't get caught up in operation green
merchant
and spend a year in jail
he probably never partners with
ben and alan drunkers from scentsy seeds
without a doubt and he would have never
sold his stock to shanti he never would
have he never well he never would have
given his stock to the to scentsy yeah
exactly he went he went from owning the
biggest most successful seed bank in
holland
to being the head breeder
of somebody else's seed bank yep
and then sensei ended up trademarking a
bunch of the names or even changing a
bunch of the names so they could
trademark them
and so he ended up having to sell out to
business people right yep and then
lost control of a bunch of his own
genetics
and then when shanti and him went to
work with arjun because he learned from
that right they never let arjun have any
of the moms or the dads or the seeds or
the herb or the cuts
they would they would grow
and they would provide the flour and
they would provide the seeds to
greenhouse
but they were very well aware that if
they allowed
you know
the if they allowed him to get a hold of
it that he could just cut them out
yeah and they probably knew his
personality too
well because that's that's essentially
what it what happened to you know
scentsy seeds ended up owning most of
neville's work yep
from the seed bank
you know and you know and so he didn't
want that to happen again
and so you know there's always been this
push between the people doing the real
work and then those people don't tend to
come from money and then the people you
have to bond with that actually come
from money and that like that tension
there
sure
and
you know there's people in cannabis that
are in it for the plant and you know
they want to make a living obviously and
be comfortable
um and you know and they have this
desire and then there's people that are
into monetizing it
and their primary interest
is monetization of what they have
and we deal with that all the time
in america right now i mean there's a
huge
there's a huge push to that right sure
yeah and the one thing that holds true
that i'm learning
is that most of the guys that are in it
for the monetization one of their first
moves is to get someone else to make
their seats for them
yeah or or just you know they have a
story of how they came across
the elite stuff that made them famous
but it's not as good of a marketing
story as they would prefer
yeah exactly
so they come up with these lies and this
marketing story where they just kind of
make it up along the fly
and then you have various forum posts or
various videos of them different eras
where it's hard to keep track of what
they said when
and there's a small percentage of us
that are you know nerd out on that kind
of stuff and abel are able to piece
together
like what was really going on but i mean
you know there was a lot of years there
where a bunch of people buying cookie
thought that burner was hand watering
their cookie
yeah they sure did i mean they really
did like yeah you know and that's a
testament to
burner's marketing capability
and his ability to like you know
push fame and push things and you know i
mean they really
like cookie was cookie was primed
to be because it's so visually pretty
you know yeah it really was perfectly
suited
for
the instagram and the in the in that era
it really was and then and they were
timing for it and they did a really good
job of
marketing it and hyping it and
pushing it and you know they they stole
names from girl scout cookies and
you know thin mint and they use
but you know i mean that's the thing
that's why that's why the girl scout
cookies push back is because
marketing and brand name recognition
people spend enormous sums
right
like developing that kind of stuff
especially the girl scouts
yeah you know and so
i mean they you know they that's why
they went from girl scout cookies just
to cookies
right because they would have been sued
into oblivion
about it right you know yeah and you
know but he they took
you know
cannabis really wasn't ready for modern
marketing techniques
you know and so we were super
susceptible to these kind of modern
marketing techniques where
i mean you know
obviously you and i you know you get
into a bunch of trouble
um because you poke holes in people's
[ __ ] all the time publicly right
yeah
and you know you have your method of
doing it i i you know i i would choose a
slightly different method but
but you have your method of doing it but
for them
you're attacking their money
that's exactly what it like they don't
give a flying [ __ ] about the truth
right they care about their image and
how much money they're making and so
they view it as a direct assault on
their pocketbook and their rep
which is super important to them yeah so
you're coming at it from a
from a history point of view
right
and you know they're coming at it from
uh like why are you messing with my game
it's just marketing bro
right you know and they're just trying
to make it in the world and they're just
trying to sell their stuff and
you know and it's like you know and
and they felt like the happy accident or
you know how many people like claim
you know uh how many people over the
years have claimed the origin of a
strain just because they were the first
one to like get out there and lay claim
to it oh sure all the time all the time
right and then you find out that they
were just gifted it early on and the
other people that gifted it to him
wanted to remain anonymous
and they realized they didn't have to
and so then a ton of people end up
associating that with them
and they end up demanding percentages if
other seed breeders use their work
or they sell the cut for high dollar or
they do all these various different
things
and really
like they just got they were just in the
first handful of people that got it
and yeah decided to market it in that
sense
that's how uh
katsu's name got
attached to bubba permanently someone
gave him that cut
but he distributed it his name's a part
of it now he started a company
yeah you know and i mean i you know i'm
not i'm not trying to like
you know necessarily like call out
individual people but obviously that's
super common yeah you know and there's
nothing negative on him it's just that's
how people's names quickly get attached
to something
yeah i mean you know uh my buddy our
buddy he never he never attempted to do
this but literally because skunkier was
the first person to get on the forums
and start talking about the chem dog
extensively
there's a bunch of people that call it
the skunk va cut
actually in canada they just released a
line um the canadian health whatever
called skunk va and it's supposed to
have chem dog in it oh my gosh
he never he never played that game of
trying to like lay claim and honest you
know i mean we've obviously with his
with his interviews and stuff like that
um he's been extremely upfront and
honest about how it all went down but
just because that was his handle on the
forums
and he was the one dropping information
about it it got a label associated with
him
yeah i mean that's
when we all amongst our crew we all call
it the dog
yes right that leads to internet
confusion like nobody's business so it's
got to be the skunk va cut or it's got
to be the chem 91 or it's got to be the
chem dog 91 you know it has to have a
label that makes sense
for people
and it better not have a and w in the
middle of dog
yeah you know and then you know and so
but you know i mean that's a thing where
it's like he wasn't even he wasn't even
remotely trying to
but it still got associated with his
name
sure you know
like just because people needed a way to
talk about it
right which cut oh the one that skunked
the skunk va has yeah you know
and then other people took that you know
took different cuts that they had and
tried to actually like lay claim
you know and then they never thought
that information would come out later
that would like put them in a bad light
but then eventually it does and then
they're like oops
you know
but they're not going to like refund
anybody's money or any other thing that
they did when like they insisted that
you had to give them x amount of
percentage
for
the the right to breed with their cut or
to sell their cut or they just monetized
coming to you from the dark scary slimy
place
let's talk about l.a kush because it is
so important to you it's it's it's i
would say your your family cut right
it's one of them yeah i mean that that
that that's a good segue because
the name is horrible
it really is you know it's not a good
name it's it's
just in the sense that
because of when i got it
right
um which was the very early 2000s yeah
you know um
you know kush hadn't wasn't famous yet
at all
right yeah like there was there was i
don't think the tk had even made it to
california yet no um and
the cut that um you know josh d and
those guys brought
was only with a couple of people and so
there was only a few rooms in southern
california that even had it you know
um shout out resin love
yeah
uh and a couple others and uh
you know and so
like you know when you talk about
kush now when i first got on that when i
first got on instagram or different
things
like everyone would laugh and be like oh
bro that's not kush you want me to show
you what cushy like there was no and
then the other name for it is headband
right yes but headband is is almost as
confusing of another name sure is you
know and the history behind the various
headbands and what got named headband is
right up there with sauer
uh as being uh not poorly understood you
know not well understood not not very
well sourced in terms of like
i mean to take a step back for a minute
uh just to use it as an example we're
really blessed in the sense that
you know chem dog pops a seed
it becomes what we call the dog he gives
it to my buddy from staten island dude
drives it out he gives it to
gunk va and i see and myself right and
so there's a chain there's a chain of
hands where you know when it was popped
by who who gave it to who it never got
lost that's it
right
and
lots of stuff like this isn't very clear
like we have no idea who first named
headband headband yeah no too many
people take claim for that we don't know
who the first headband cut was
sure don't we don't exactly know what
the first headband cut that was named
headband was even made up of
we don't even know if it had anything to
do with diesel or kim the first headband
you know and so now i mean i will say
that you know so we can segue into the
la cush so
um
this is kind of a funny story is that
um when i gave all those clones and all
those
um
all you know i gave a series of clones
and a few thousand seeds to mandelbrot
and he was just getting into growing and
he had a few things he had the train
wreck and he had a few different things
and he had this sour diesel
that was different than the sour diesel
that i had
right yeah and so we traded we were
supposed to trade sour diesels
okay
and so he's like well these he only had
like literally i think he had three or
four cuts that he was holding on to at
that point
and um
he
um so he's like i'm gonna give you a
couple of these headbands and a couple
of these sour diesel cuts
right yeah um and so he brings me four
cuts
and he's like i forgot to label them
but two of them are sour diesel and two
of them are the headband
right yeah
and so
i get these cuts and i label them all
carefully and i mom them up and i take
clones off each one of them and i flower
all of them you know
and i can't tell them apart for anything
dude
not at all it all looks the same to me
i'm bringing friends by my grow room
nobody can tell them apart you know
yeah and
and they all just look the same to me
i'm like but only two of them are
supposed to be sour and two of them are
supposed to be headband
right and then my friends are like this
looks like sour to me now granted this
is a very early 2000s right yeah so sour
wasn't even like very well known then
either yeah you know
it was just starting to make its way on
the west coast i mean sour was popped in
right yeah
and you know so this is this is only you
know
five years after that or something right
so not very long and uh it had just
started to creep around it wouldn't even
really become famous for another five or
six years really yeah
at least on the west coast on the west
coast sir on the west coast sure so
so i'm growing this thing i'm bringing
everybody by and everyone like they're
like dude it kind of looks
like similar to your sour it must be it
must be his different sour you know
because it kind of looks like yours yeah
right it's not exactly yours but that's
got to be it you know
and so i grow it a couple times and i'm
i'm calling it sour right
yeah
and then uh at that point in time
um mandelbrot had
he had an open case against him you know
um so that was part of the reason for
his code name and he never drove himself
anywhere he always had a driver so that
um if they got pulled over
he never had to give his license or you
know his id or anything like that you
know
yeah i mean yeah it was it was it was
true like the first i think the first 10
years i knew him i never saw him like
behind the wheel of a car he always had
to have a driver did he wear costumes to
the grocery store
no he didn't he didn't do anything like
that but it was like he
he definitely
you know everything had to be in
somebody else's name sure you know um
because his name would you know he had
some trouble in montana
yeah and so you know he didn't want to
deal with that and so he just kind of
you know back then being a hippie and
going in certain circles you could kind
of go offline
and live a lifestyle and never have to
pop up on the on the screen you know
yeah yeah and certainly in the 90s and
early 2000s before everything got
computerized and everything else it was
way easier to do that
um so eventually like for
six months or something after i got him
i had this room full of what i thought
was sour and he was rolling down from
humble
and i was like dude
you didn't give me two different strains
you gave me this one strain you never
gave me what you're supposed to give me
right
yeah i'm like because i can't tell these
things apart for anything
like i kept all four original of your of
your cuts you gave me they're all moms i
have them all labeled different i grow
them all it's all the same [ __ ] yeah
so he comes down and he walks in my room
and
he's like this isn't sorry this is the
headband
i'm like what he's like yeah this is the
headband this is what we call the la
cush there's the headband
and i'm like it's not he's like i didn't
give you my sour
you know
and
he ended up liking the sour that i gave
him better than the sour that he had so
he was like i don't even want to give it
to you because honestly he's like i'm
using yours not mine you know
because yours is nicer so he's like you
definitely got the better of the two
cuts that i gave you
you know um and uh you know and so yeah
and so then i was like
[ __ ] it's the it's it's headband
right
yeah he's like i'm like witch headband
he's like well it gets called the la
kush but it's really a headband
right
and
already you know with the name changes
yeah but you know actually like you he's
written he wrote some articles um and
stuff like that where if you go and you
look and he talks about like him
breeding and he talks about breeding
with the maui super dog and breeding
with other various cuts that i gave him
and every time he writes about the la
cush in parentheses he'll put headband
or original headband yeah you know
because that's what he got it at but
then in la they called it the la cush
which obviously within a few years
became you know nonsensical because
the kush that became famous was
significantly different you know
but then it wasn't right
so
and that's actually and you know he did
some breeding work with that headband
cut and that's that's what became the
707 headband
is
the mother of uh the mother of the seven
oh said headband is that's is that is
that cut
and you know he actually passed it out
freely
uh to various people at times but it was
releases but it was really finicky
um and it didn't it wasn't as as
consistent a producer as the sour diesel
that i gave him was
and so most people dramatically
preferred the sour
yeah even though i liked the high better
of the actual headband cut
right
yeah and so this is
this is years
years before
i mean i don't think the lumpa headband
cut popped up on the scene until like oh
eight
or only yeah much later yeah
i mean uh csi knows it for sure because
he's got all the uh like you know like
he does and as inspector style he's got
all the forum posts archived and stuff
like that of when it actually came about
but yeah even the other even the other
cut that got renamed headband that's a
kush
that one didn't even start to spread out
until 0607 correct you know so this one
preceded these things by you know five
to nine years
in a way
so i think it might be the original
headband cut
uh i don't know
you know
yeah because we we never even found out
the human that named it headband or who
cracked it or
but i will say that um you know we were
talking much earlier about
you know for instance
csi you you touched on like why
you know
why he's kind of the gold standard and
one of the things that he does is he
grows out a ton of his own work right
yep so when you grow out a ton of your
own work you obviously get to see what
traits the various plants you have pass
on to their progeny
which if you don't grow your own work
you don't get to see what's a consistent
breeder you don't get to see what what
what it throws how it behaves you know
you're just taking two famous names
mashing them together and offering them
to the public right yep and so
you know
um one of the things that the superdog
project did to me
was it gave me a really really good idea
of what
uh the super skunk and what the chem dog
do
right yeah especially crossed obviously
but like what they throw and all the
various ranges of what they throw
and that like you know and so
um you know i'm pretty convinced
that uh that headband cut has
91 and super skunk in there
it's interesting
um you know how
you know is it you know and and we've
talked about it you know like i mean one
of the one of the people involved in the
in the sour diesel story at the very
beginning was vondo right yeah who we've
gone to interview
and
you know he popped
you know he he popped some of those
seeds after he moved to southern
california
yep
i'm not saying that like the headband is
that but i'm just saying that you know
um
somewhere
it you know if you grow it and you grow
the sour it is in the diesel family yeah
i remember smoking it
i would bet almost any amount of money
that how how exactly it's in the diesel
family
like what exactly it contains but it's
like i've grown enough of that stuff out
right
and sour and 91 and you know super skunk
and 91 hybrids and stuff that
it's in there somehow
yeah
but i in the
you know 19 years or 18 years or
whatever that i've had it um information
has been super hard to come by
you know
um i like you know like we said even
with the sour thing and even getting a
bunch of people that were there in the
moment
um
finding out which cut is exactly which
is problematic
very automatic yeah and so
you know it ended up being it's like one
of those things where it ended up being
like one of my favorite cuts for effect
but it was pretty finicky grower and it
could really freak out on you
and so it led to a lot of people getting
rid of it until
somehow me and maybe one or two other
people ended up being the only people
with it
is really kind of what happened and it's
like and you know strangely enough
um before i even knew mean gene
uh me and jean got this sour cut
from a mutual friend right
yeah and it was it was my it was the
headband cut
and it makes sense if it was being
passed to sour by mandelbrot well the
other thing is too is that and and this
is this is an admission
um but there was an era
where like a lot of people would come up
to humboldt mendo and they would act
like a big dog like they were a big
broker sure
and they were in control and they had
the money and they were the man
right
but in reality the actual man that gave
them the money was like go up to mendo
and buy these buy one of these three
strains
yeah
so there would be times where it was
like i would have amazing chem d or
amazing this or amazing that and they'd
smoke it and they'd be like this is
absolute fire
and then they'd admit to me that they
didn't have permission to buy that
right like it would happen all the time
like
i need to buy these things these are the
things i'm looking for i don't have
permission
you know like they wouldn't want to
admit that but when it came down to it
because finally i'd be like dude if you
think this is some of the nicest weed
you've seen in like eight months why
won't you snap it
yeah and they'd be like well the guy
that i'm getting it for he told me i can
only get these two things
right
so my whole crew
started selling that headband cut as
sour diesel
yeah and it became
the sour diesel so there was this thing
where it was like all these people
wouldn't have permission to buy headband
right yeah and nobody knew what the la
cush was
right yeah but they could buy sour
diesel all day
and so
we called it sour diesel
to people because that's what moved and
they would absolutely love it and then
the person that they gave it to they
would be like you i want you to get as
much of that sour diesel as you possibly
can
like that's the one i want find that one
right
and it was it was this whole thing right
where it was like all of my crew knew it
was headband
but the brokers only had permission to
buy two or three things
right and it passed this sour
yeah even though it was more like fuel
and diesel than it was the traditional
actual like what i consider to be the
sour nose yeah um you know me and jean
um he gets it uh as sour
and that formed the basis of what he
still has today called the root beer
right
yeah
and then he lost a cut
and he kept getting back different sours
and none of them were the none of them
were the cut that he used to make the
root beer
right yeah and then years later
i'm sitting next to him and you know
we're we're hanging out together and i
pass him a jar and i was like tell me
what you think of this
and he opens it up and he's like holy
[ __ ] that's the sour
that's the sour that's the sour i use to
make the root beer
you know yeah um and so for us it was
like we never like
renamed it intentional like you know
what i mean like at first yeah
at first it was renamed because like it
didn't come with a label
and everybody assumed it would look so
close to diesel that it had to be diesel
yeah
it wasn't whatever headband it was
supposed to be it had to be diesel so we
called it diesel for a bit and then
mandelbach cleared it up that it was
actual headband
and then brokers still wanted it
as sour
you know
so it ended up getting called you know i
mean
the labels never changed you know
yeah like in our own personal gardens or
anything like that those always stayed
the same but
you know um
you know we always called it but you
know for a bunch of my friends it's like
they got you know that's it it ended up
being like
the sour diesel cut that they ran
for years
you know during that whole
hype phase or whatever you know
um
and uh you know so
and yeah and it's like it ended up
getting dropped by most people
um and lost and renamed and different
things and so then it ended up where
only a couple people have it um
and
it's still like in terms of potency um
it's it's way way way up there
in terms of effect and it's
still one of my all-time favorites
um but it's probably like
the biggest issue i faced
it's like when i would try to describe
it like i said
is that if i called it headband
everybody had familiarity with some
other headband yeah
and they believed that whatever headband
they had the familiarity with was the
real headband the real only and the
original
yeah and then if i called it la kush
then i get a bunch of people laughing at
me that i was an ignoramus and that i
didn't know what real kush was and
they'd show me what real kush was you
know yeah which of course i knew what it
was but though so then those were like
the only two names you know
and yeah and all that you know and so it
became really difficult to like talk
about it and then there's this funny
thing with elites
and it happened to us with the dog too
um where
you know various brokers and different
people it's like how good can it be if i
don't have access to it
yeah
i know what the best stuff out there is
and if i have what's my most i know what
the best desirable stuff is and so if i
don't have access to it my buddies don't
have access to it and it's not one of
these hype things how good can it really
be
yeah
right
and so you battle that kind of stuff
like people would people would trip now
but like i mean there was a point in
time where like
you know uh
people didn't want to buy the chem dog
it wasn't frosty enough
yeah that's true
it didn't look good enough i mean if
they were willing to sit down and smoke
a joint
100 it would go
but if they're just but you know lots
and lots of people are just basing it
off
name
look
knows price
yeah
and you know the longer things have gone
on the less and less people smoke and
the more it becomes just about like i'm
just middle-manning this to the next
person
you know
so i just need a price point and a label
yeah
which is why
you know and that's what started like
other people like
you know breeding with all this
different stuff and that's where you
know blackberry kush or this or that or
you know people changing names to like
add a name that like
you know would sell
yeah right
i just need a name that'll sell
i got this cut it doesn't sell i need to
add a name to it
someone needs to take it from me
you know and uh
yeah and so the you know i don't i mean
you know and then you know if you want
to talk about headband
um
is my cut the day wrecker i don't know i
don't think so
you know is my cut the original headband
i'm i definitely know that it existed
years before some of these other ones
you know
um
i mean you know like the the other
headband
um and the lumpa those are basically
like in my opinion those are just
straight kush
yeah those are ogs yeah those are just
straight ogs like i don't know if
they're s ones or bag seed or whatever
else but
i mean they
they're very lg kush dominant whatever
it is very og kush dominant and they
don't breed for anything else where you
know um
you know and so
you know is headband sour og
is it
just super skunk 91
you know a a colombian super skunk
leaning fino you know
there's theories that i have but not a
bunch of proof
yeah you know
when it really comes down to it um and
what's interesting is that you know i've
posted pictures where i showed you where
um we had some i had some friends of
ours that went to
the hills of columbia
and brought back some seed
and we grew it out and the colombian
looks the closest thing
to the la headband that i've ever seen
yeah i remember seeing this picture yeah
side by sides where it's just obviously
it's not the exact same
but like the color the structure the
look
yeah
and obviously like you know there's
colombian and skunk right yeah
absolutely so what if it's just a 91
super skunk
that leaned colombian yeah it's but very
very possible but kept some of that you
know that that you know that 91 power
yeah and not that that means anything
because obviously it's just a trait but
it does variegate you know especially if
it gets hungry you know i mean i can
almost
you know and so
i mean there's a lot of stuff like that
where it's like sometimes you get a lot
of information and you can really nail
down
like provenance and lineage and where it
comes from
and you know and other other strains
just because of the nature of the beast
and how it's all black market or came
from prohibition era you get as much
info as you can and then you hit a point
where it's just like a wall
i did a uh live feed and it's i think
it's up on youtube if people want to
look but i actually tried to show
what happens when you research the day
wreck or original diesel cut like the
best way i would just a a framework for
how i would go about starting to
research a strain that i have no history
on and funnily enough like we talked
about dude the diesels are just
convoluted the pot things pop up out of
nowhere
you know as all of a sudden this
clone is injected into the scene with no
with no history
i mean i have i have some i mean you
know we we've discussed it and i have
some i have some tidbits that aren't
very well known that i think are part of
the sour story
it's not the complete sour story but
it's certainly parts that don't get
talked about too much you know
um
and uh
you know and then it's and then there's
also this thing too that happens where
it's like you have people that are young
and they're in their early 20s and
they're making decisions and they end up
doing stuff that becomes famous years
later
and then
you know
there's rep and
and this and that attached to all that
kind of stuff and how do you
you know how do you delicately search
for the truth without stepping on their
toes about like you know certain aspects
of their story or history where you're
not even like
trying to like out out and call them
like oh you're a liar you're this you're
that but
i mean let's be honest like if you're
doing stuff when you're 19 20 21 24 or
whatever and then 10 years later it
becomes famous
like you don't know what you were doing
at the time was gonna matter
without a doubt yeah how do you even you
know maybe maybe your memory isn't even
that good you know maybe you know maybe
you don't i mean what they've discovered
right is that one of the most unreliable
things in court systems is eyewitnesses
absolutely yeah
and they've proven it over and over
again where it's like eyewitnesses you
would think that but people's memories
are different
you know and they can convince
themselves that they remember things
that aren't exactly the case
yeah memories and perspectives
everything yeah or you know you might
have an incident where like one of your
best friends and you experience
something and they barely remember it
but it sticks in your mind like really
strong
yeah
yeah and you know you can't believe that
they don't remember certain details
because you remember them really clearly
and they have a vague memory
you know
and so
deals with that with me all the time
where she looks at me like i'm an alien
because i don't remember something
yeah and that kind of stuff really does
play into it you know i mean
you know i mean obviously this is like a
wide-ranging topic about things but i
mean i i think and i think i have some
reasonably good proof that i think the
basis of sour diesel is
91 by super skunk
i would agree
you know and um you know it's that you
know there's certain things that i
believe that are just like evidence
based on like observation of knowing the
strains and seeing them both bred
together
yeah but then you know we have other
tidbits too where it's like
i mean i don't know if this is this this
should be the time that we talk about
this or not but
um
you know uh
after
after chem dog got
um the super skunk
in 93 um
he started growing it
right
uh and it turned and it hermed all over
his stuff
yeah right and that's the interesting
thing you know i mentioned this on the
live but i'll bring it up again
just for the people that missed it where
the super skunk was unusual in that you
know if you have an eight week strain or
a nine week strain and you get tiger
striped seeds out of it when it's
finished
it got pollinated in like week two or
three yes
right because it takes a good anybody
that breeds knows it takes a good four
or five weeks
from pollination
you know or even longer at times yeah
yeah
yeah for really for i mean i just mean
after the initial pollination right
that's what i mean yeah so so you know
it it takes a good long time so when
you're finding viable seeds off of a
strain you cut at 62 days or something
it was probably pollinated in week three
yep real early on and so the super skunk
would throw herms early and late right
it was a real pain in the ass in that
regard and it was super live pollen
and
it really really was i mean it
if you stressed it at all or anything
like that it would just throw live
bananas yeah
and um
you know and i mentioned this too is i
think that
with linked traits i think the most
ranked super skunks
came
with terms
i think that some of that terp was
linked to that hermaphrodism trait and
that as people tried to breed away from
it they bred away and more towards the
sweet skunk or the
onion garlic skunk and not like the rank
rank skunk right yeah
so anyway so
um chem dog calls up my buddy
in 1994
and he's super excited because he's
grown up
some of these seeds that accidentally
got made
by by him growing the 91 and the super
skunk in the same room
and he is in love with them
so he calls up my buddy from staten
island and uh who's obviously in sonoma
at this point and he's super excited in
1994 because
the super skunk accidentally pollinated
the chem dog
um and he's growing out some of these
things and he thinks the hybrids are
incredible
they're bigger
they're more vigorous they reek
all this stuff right
yeah and that was actually one of the
one of the
like you know inspirations
um not you know was
um for even beginning the super dog
was we want obviously we we wanted to
combine the traits into a single thing
but you know we already knew people that
had accidentally done it and this is
obviously
way long before
you know reversals or anything like that
you know sure um so that that wasn't
even in the cards you know um
but uh he was he was
ecstatic
he was preferring
to
grow these to even the chem dog
right yeah they were they were bigger
they were stinkier they were more rank
they were you know they just
you know and think about it too right
like so 1994 whatever i mean you're
talking chem dog is in his early 20s
yeah
right super young still
you know um
and uh
you know and so he
um
so he was telling my buddy
that
he was basically
running rooms of these things
right
um and that was what he was doing
and because they yielded better
and
you know and all that right and he was
selling it as chem dog
because that was that was his name that
was his gig and so like
yeah it was like you weren't buying a
strain you were buying chem dogs weed
correct
right that's kind of how they looked at
it you know
well
so
i've grown the 91 for a couple decades
now and
you know uh
you know skunk va's grown it for a
quarter century now you know and various
things and it really doesn't hurt
yeah it doesn't make seed
right correct correct so the part that
people don't know
is that so you take this conversation
where he's expressing to my buddy how
much he loves growing the hybrids and
he's growing rooms full of these hybrids
and he's having great success
and when we interviewed vondo and those
guys right
yeah they said in 1994 when they were
getting all that work from chemdawg
they found what 15 or 18 seeds
you know
something like that something or
something along those lines as they were
as they were getting the work from him
right yeah
so
a bunch of people
were um
you know they've always you know
everybody thought okay you know like the
story is
that you know it came out of
chem 91 seed yeah you know that was the
basis of it right sure but without that
conversation to my buddy
you wouldn't know that he was actually
growing hybrids then uh correct you know
and so
and then you know like when you when you
take what i consider to be any of the
children of the super skunk
they all have herm tendencies
yes they do it all passes that herm
trait onto it
you know and
and so
you know in like i don't even think i've
found 15 or 18 seeds in chem dog in the
20 years i've grown it
i bet yeah
you know or like it just doesn't you
know so for them to find that many in
the space of like half a year
right
and then you combine that with
then you combine that with um the fact
that chem dog expressed how happy he was
with the hybrids that he'd accidentally
made right
he thought they were significantly
better than the original correct
yeah
all right i mean that's what you said
yeah yeah and i mean i can i can totally
see that in the sense that
you know like
the best super dogs that we did years
later had the growth and the vigor and
the stretch and the rank of the skunk
but it had the potency
and the depth of power of the of the 91.
yeah right
so i mean we we had a slightly different
path to that and that ours wasn't an
accidental herm pollination right
um
but i could totally see that happening
right
and he's selling all that as chem dog
because he's chem dog because that's his
brand that's his brand right and
and so you know and so then these so
then vondo and these guys they collect
whatever it was you know x amount some
amount of seeds in the teens
and they grow those up you know and
and and you know they get diesel they
get diesel one and two right yep
out of that diesel one herms
right
and we're not sure what else was in the
room or exactly what happened but out of
that herm came the first sour plants
correct and
i believe he said that there were seeds
in a baggie labeled our diesel
yeah
right and so yeah if you look
at those polaroids that in this last six
or eight months that skunk va has been
posting right yep you can see the sour
in the structure of that super skunk
oh without a doubt
i mean you can it's just like as clear
as a bell you can see it you know
um
so
do i know the whole sour diesel story
you know um by you know every step of
the way no
but i think that those two bits of
evidence that aren't super well known
like i think the fact that it started
out as beans out of a 91 super skunk
hybrid
are
pretty solid
without a doubt now there's two things
right so the beans that they were
finding
they could have been
um s-ones of this 91 super skunk right
or they could have even been the super
skunk
pollinating that hybrid itself again
it sure could have
because he had you know he was still
growing the super skunk every rip you
know yeah so you know you don't know
it's hard to say but
you know the original sour cuts i can
see the dog and i can see the super
skunk in both
like
i mean you know i grew the super skunk
for 10 years before i lost it we still
have the chem dog icons in the you know
in the in the original sour cuts
i can see it oh without a doubt i would
agree
it's in there you know and then that's
another thing right where it's like that
super skunk's you know ability to herm
on itself
essentially created like
an enormous line
yeah
a major part of the industry
create the sour diesel for a good 10
years was like the most famous the most
desirable cut in america yep
the east coast had an endless endless
desire for it
it sure did you know it had the nose it
had the potency it had the name it had
power it had all those types of things
you know
and uh so you know i mean there's all
this these rumors about dnl and rks and
this and this and everything else and we
got to hear vondo's version and all that
and just like anything else there was a
few other plants in the room at the time
too you know yeah um
you know so it's not like
it's not 100 figured out and it's
unlikely just the way that it worked out
with a bunch of young kids growing some
rooms and partying at the same time than
it ever would be
um
but i think that you know that part of
it isn't is is really not known at all
you know yeah it isn't and so a lot of
people just assume
that oh it had it you know the basis of
it is this you know yeah and people
don't realize that like you know chem
dog called things chem dog because that
was his brand
yeah you know i mean he called the d
later on chem dog
yeah i remember that yeah because you're
buying weed from cam dog
and and and
for the time that actually that made
sense a lot of people would have done
that
yeah i don't i don't think it was
anything shady no you know it's like
people didn't have this like intensive
like lineage and this and that and
everything else he was chem dog
he grew chem dog you bought chem dog
from chem dog
you know
i mean you know whether that was the 91
or that whether that was a 91 super
skunk hybrid or whether that was the
chem d
you know or whatever else you're buying
chem dog correct
and all those things he was growing were
probably fire because the parent
genetics were incredible so it's not
like anybody was unhappy
yeah i'm sure
i mean those guys vondo on those guys
they saved all those beans and cracked
those beans because those things were
fire
and they knew they were special and they
like they were special because they were
getting fire so like when they realized
there was seeds in there they kept
hunting for more seed
to save
right just like traditional 90s you know
you find beans and a good bag of weed
and you put it in your little box
yep in your sock drawer or whatever you
know and
you know and so
um
they but then you know the most likely
thing to me
is that the diesel one or whatever
hermed on itself
yeah i would agree
you know and then it's a it's a mix of
you know and then you're gonna get all
whatever is whatever the 91 actually is
combined with super skunk which is a
skunk one by maple leaf indica
you're gonna get a whole range at that
point yeah
of things
you know going through those jesuless
ones i was able to see so much of super
skunk all of its different expressions
and i think it may have been one of the
most valuable tools uh and learning
experiences in my breeding career was to
go specifically through those gsls ones
yeah you know and and it's like it
you know people have tried to piece
together the story and it becomes
all it takes is a little bit of
misinformation or a little bit of
misunderstood information and then you
try to like extrapolate a bunch of facts
based on that you know
yeah um you know but
you look at you know you look at some of
the stories where it's like oh well this
stuff was chem 91 by northern lights one
yeah right but then it doesn't look
anything like that
no
but then you look at the sour diesel and
you look at those old pics that skunk va
is posted of the super skunk and you're
like oh man that looks like
they look very close
yeah and
and that segues into
the the massachusetts super
skunk specifically what we've what we've
been learning lately in regards to
possibly there'd be there being two
different cuts
well i mean so
you know one of the things that happened
is that
i mean this is just this is just
conjecture on in on my on my view
obviously because i'm from the east
coast and i wasn't tied into those crews
super deeply i mean i will say that like
most of the stuff that i believe i i had
talked to
my buddy from staten island extensively
about the entire history of all of it i
mean we used to used to sit around and
um
you know uh
the that original ss cut i mean if you
opened up the 90
uh seed bank catalog from neville you
could take side branches of that ss and
you could hold it right up to that and
it would be like an exact match
yeah i mean it was just exact right like
and he would show trimmers all the time
like look that's super skunk
that's super skunk
you know and you know we've recently
learned you know from uh you know skunk
va's mentor or whatever that um it was
basically you know the the most likely
thing is that it was a
a super skunk f2
yep right
is is is the is the most likely you know
story that we know that seems to be the
most based in in in fact or whatever and
yeah
and he labeled it six and that led to a
bunch of confusion because some people
called it six and some people called it
super skunk and those two groups didn't
really overlap you know yeah and all
that kind of thing and so there's still
some some not entirely perfectly known
but that seems like it's most likely so
you're starting with
you know something that you know
obviously he kept it because it was the
skunkiest of
of skunks you know
and can you talk can you talk about some
of its growth traits how did it grow
uh i mean you can see you know it grew a
bit like sour diesel but not as dense um
it had that feathery
look um long and lanky long lanky spears
you know gotcha um
it looked dense but it was really light
if that makes sense you know like
especially if you got it too dry you
could just crisp it with your fingers
you know
um it would it would look full
but there was a lot of like air to bud
ratio in there you know silver pearls
that way i think
yeah and so you know it um you know it
uh for most people it looked kind of
like a less dense sour diesel yeah you
know you could have a huge butt of it
and it wouldn't you'd put it on the on
the scale and it wouldn't weigh that
impressive yeah
because it was it was the opposite of
like rock hard
exactly even though even though it might
look firm
it wasn't dense
yeah
you know it was lime green i mean really
if people want to like i said
um you can look at that 90s super skunk
in the seed bank catalog that famous
picture
and he would hold up side nuggets prop
after crop after crop to that picture
and it would be like a dead ringer if
you would yeah and it just looked
exact and he would laugh about it you
know
because they're super skunk there is
there's your proof boom you know looks
exactly like it does in the catalog
reeks like a dead zone yeah
you know
and like i said it wasn't you know it
wasn't the
you know like by today's standards its
potency wasn't on par with the best
stuff we have today
yeah it just it was moderate potency and
i think we've we've both found that like
when you find the terpius things
they tend to be not the most potent yeah
um you know maybe that's because some of
those terpenes haven't converted into
you know thc or whatever else or
entourage effect or whatever you want to
call it but
um sometimes really flavor flavorful
things are either light or moderate and
potency
yeah which is what led us to like the
superdog project was trying to combine
the potency of the dog with the flavor
of the super skunk you know yeah um and
so getting back to what you were talking
about
people call it the massachusetts super
skunk even though it's from virginia
and the only reason why it's called
massachusetts super skunk is because my
buddy dropped it off with chemdog on his
way back out to the west coast after
getting the dog
and it's hard to say
you know i mean unfortunately uh you
know this is pretty famous by now chem
dog got wrapped up in that whole res the
rat issue
yep and he got busted in 1996 i believe
2006 or 96.
i thought it was
i'm not sure
i thought it was earlier
uh it might it might have been earlier i
just remember the the the high times the
first one he did i want to say was 2006
my point my point to all that is that i
think he he definitely got i think if
you look back on the old forums he
definitely got himself into a bit of
trouble in 96. yeah and i think most of
the super skunks that got passed out
after that
um
like doesn't look like those pictures
that's that skunk va posts
no not at all
not at all it looks much shorter it
looks much more afghani it looks much
denser right yeah it's short squat
shortened squat instead of being
long and
and running you know
light spears you know
um and so you know
it's amazing that he has those pictures
from 1995 because those are absolute
evidence that's guaranteed the cut yeah
being able to find those solved or being
able to see those pictures
it answered a lot of questions that we
had had
yeah you know and so it's well then it's
like i mean he grew it for quite some
time and i grew it for quite some time
and so did other friends of ours and
stuff but it's like there's no way you
can convince people based on your memory
you know so having actual evidence
like that from that era
you know i think it's quite possible
that you know there was a mix-up on the
east coast and what got really passed
around at length about as mss wasn't
correct and and what was used in geezel
was whatever the second cut that was
going around as mss was
you know now it's also entirely possible
that it you know it could be
you know that could be
an s1 found in the actual buds of super
skunk
you know it definitely could um because
it hurt you know and so you know maybe
he had
you know some seed in it like i said in
your 90s box of good seed maybe he had
some seed that he found in the chem dog
from super skunk seeds and that's where
some of those hybrids and other things
came from and then maybe he had some
beads he found in super skunk and that's
where that came from you know and that's
why your diesel experiments
look so close to so many different kinds
of super skunk expression
yeah there's definitely super skunk in
it but because it wasn't
it wasn't the same one and then you know
various various mss have popped up in
recent years as
the skunk terp
um have been
you know has been sort of like the
unicorn or the holy grail and everyone
wants to have it and claim that they've
got it
um you know but
until somebody like me or
you know
skunk va or others like
everybody claims seeds of it but nobody
brings jars
to events
where or passes it out where you can be
like oh this is it
exactly
um people want to breed with it people
want to get it be like oh this is legit
but then
it doesn't look like the one of old it
doesn't smell like the one of old you
know we we both know that skunk va has
gotten a number of of cuts or samples of
things that people are pretty sure is it
from the east coast
and he doesn't think they're even close
yeah you know
so you know as far as we know it's dead
yeah
currently that is the status of mss or
if it's not dead it's
with people that you know someone could
still have it somewhere but it's not
tied into
um you know the community where it
hasn't actually popped up
exactly you know and you know that can
happen sometimes things can be lost and
one or two people ends up having it and
they don't even realize that it's
because they're not tied into the forums
or the instagram or the larger community
and they don't even realize they're
sitting on something rare and amazing
yeah
so it could be that
you know it's a little more suspicious
now because so many people want to find
it and then want to sell beans of it and
have it and have that terp again you
know yeah but so far it's been a lot of
a lot of dead ends
yeah it's been a lot of
mss names but the chirps just don't
match up
no they don't match up and the look
doesn't match up and it's not
it's just uh you know they just
it just doesn't match up so you know i
mean who knows i mean i know for a fact
that some of her children exist
yes
and
her children have been bred into all
kinds of things you know yeah and all
that and so you know it it it's like we
were talking about with breeding way
earlier
the progeny exists and are being used in
all kinds of ways um but whether or not
the mother cut exists is a whole other
factor
yeah absolutely and you know until until
skunk va put up those posts with the
with the polaroids
the only thing i had to go off of as far
as math super skunk and i think most
people um was that very first chem dog
article in high times where he shows one
picture of something labeled mass skunk
and
whatever is coming out of jesus is the
spitting image of that plant and
and unfortunately
of course
because i'm so so integral integrally
tied into the diesel cut um
i wanted it to be the original but
unfortunately that's not how [ __ ] works
sometimes and you just gotta go with the
facts
yeah i mean
obviously it doesn't mean that it's not
an excellent cut in its own right for
sure
and all that and it's like you know i
mean
you know on on the varying expression i
mean obviously like if
if the original super skunk cut that
we've been describing is an f2 of super
skunk in itself
um then who knows what was exactly in
those genes i mean we know that
super skunk originally was a
was a an
80s skunk cross to a maple leaf indica
that was known as afghan tea you know
and so
you could get some
more indica variations you could get
some more skunk variations you could get
some colombian or some mexican or some
you know
and all that and it seems like the
diesel leans a little bit more towards
the afghan side of things oh for sure
um and then it seems like those pictures
that chemdog had in the high times
leaned more towards the afghan side it
sure did
you know
and you know i mean
chem dog and stuff like that you know
like
you know i don't want anybody listening
to any of this to like
you know jump down his throat and
anything like that because
in all honesty like
between the 91 and the chem d and all
that like
several of my all-time favorite cuts
came out of his little rooms
yeah absolutely and he was 17 or 18
years old when he popped the 91 and he
was in his early 20s making a bunch of
these other decisions when these other
things were happening
and he just had his little thing going
on and had no idea that everyone was
going to be pouring over
like
every action and every utterance and
every everything later on to try to find
out like the exact history you know
and you know what it's like you know
what it's like to be a
a young partier in your 20s you know
[ __ ] yeah i do and just then just doing
things and you don't you don't you don't
realize that they're gonna for most
people
what they're doing right then isn't
gonna have any future importance that
anyone's gonna care about
yeah exactly and for him it's like that
era of his life has gotten put under a
microscope
you know and various things that he said
in 2006 or 2010 or 2015 all get you know
whatever the case may be
it's like people expect him to have some
kind of encyclopedic knowledge of
everything that happened
you know yeah i realized
i can't even remember my early 20s
yeah you know and i mean in all honesty
too it's like when you think about like
you know uh joe b and peabudz sold wheat
on dead tour
right yes
they sold him some weed
yep they weren't growing weed they were
buying and selling weed as middlemen yes
you know 15 years later they realized
that something came out of this bag of
weed that they sold
yep
like for real you know and so you know
they played a critical role in making it
all happen
right
yeah without a doubt and like they might
even be some of the few people that
actually smoked the herb that the 91
came out of
the dog right yeah the dog bud or you
know or whatever it ended up being you
know but like they got that from someone
else and you know it's like you let's
say you bought a couple pounds and sold
them in a weekend and then moved on to
some other pounds and you did that
constantly
like how much info would they even
really have
yeah
you know and it's not like they knew the
17 year old kid that they sold weed to
that took it home and grew some they
weren't like
tight personal friends where they were
part of the story after that until way
later
yeah that was much much later when they
came back and realized all that
it was basically like oh six
yeah
before they realized
so now you're asking to them to remember
like some weed that they had for a few
days 15 years before
everybody and everybody wants to know
like immense details about it when like
it seems like according to pipa like him
and joe b were on dead tour doing that
from the mid to late 80s on constantly
yeah
and you're asking them to remember like
one weekend one stop
yeah that would be [ __ ] impossible
for me when that's all they were doing
and they didn't realize that any of that
was gonna have any special importance
until forever
yeah
you know
um but then you know later on like
everybody expects me you know these kind
of people to be experts
on everything chem
because they were there in the very
beginning
yeah and and like you said some of them
didn't have any um interaction with chem
dog that didn't smoke it again for many
many many years after that bag was sold
yeah really until the reunion era when
they found each other on the forums
again
exactly which was i think 0-6-ish yep
something along those lines i think
that's you know that might be the year
that that joe b and peabod actually
first saw
91 in person yeah i think it wasn't
and got to smoke some of it you know
yeah um
you know i think they they saw it and i
mean they when they all got when they
all when they all found each other again
you know chem dog gave i think chem dog
gave joe b four seeds that he said were
part of the original thing he found yeah
and that's where the one and four came
the one through the four came from
the nl5 hazecross
well yeah whatever whatever the you know
whatever it is the one two three four
that's where those came from right
and then they went over with the one two
three four
and they traded that to
um our friend i see collective for the d
yeah that s skunk that skunk va had
flown out to the east coast and gotten
and brought back um you know because
chem dog had lost the dog
and wanted it back
and they you know and so you know he
flew out east and gave it to him and
brought back the d that's how i got the
d
um was no six when they first brought it
back
and
you know they were flipping out over the
91.
did you get stinky d
because they hadn't they hadn't they
hadn't seen the 91
yeah exactly
until then
you know because it was really only in
our little crew that that saved it
everyone else had lo every you know had
to get been lost back east a long time
before and it was really only four or
five of us that kept it safe between
that mid 90s and
and uh mid-2000s era
yeah um and so you know
i mean it and then there you know and i
mean the the whole d thing probably
could be for another
another another episode or time or
something like that because it's going
to be your full episode that that that
has that has a that has a long long
thing to it and various aspects of it
how long have we been talking dude what
do you think
[Music]
hour and a half i think uh crybaby
will you type it out
two hours and 30 minutes
that's perfect dude
oh my gosh
[Music]
thank you so much dude it really oh yeah
i'm taking the time to do it
you can cut the recording cry baby i
think we're good yeah we're good
[Music]
scary
me
you