ready go
[Music]
so
welcome to breeder syndicate
good evening everyone welcome to reader
syndicate i'm here with uh our other
host natso i don't even like calling you
a co-host because you're you're really
just the other host yeah the other host
indeed
all right
so today we're gonna cover um
uh cannabis breeding as it was back
in the dutch era mostly in pre-dutch era
and a little bit after and why it
matters today and why how we apply that
to what we're working with today we're
going to try to take you through like
some early days of breeding kind of up
to what we've already done so far which
is like the the 80s holland era and that
style
and then we'll move forward onto
different stuff later and so we we
thought about like
um i don't exactly know how much time
we'll spend on each specific topic but
we thought about like it might be
interesting to
um
we thought it might be interesting to
talk about how we got here as far as
breeding techniques yeah i see in the
comments
we have people know where we're going we
have to know where we came from i think
yeah exactly
so
um you know the the easiest way you know
we won't we could spend an enormous
amount of time on how cannabis moved
around places
um but
you know the basic premise is that for
most of the like what we consider to be
like the land race regions right when
people were starting to get imports into
america they were coming from mexico
yeah uh colombia
panama jamaica
thailand cambodia laos um
you know those type of places
and they were importing seeded weed
right and so how did those farmers how
did those farmers get to the point where
they were growing tons of cannabis and
exporting it to our region right
well basically it's at some point in the
past we don't need to spend a super
amount of time on this but
you know somewhere humans figured out
the thc had cool effects yeah it gets
[ __ ] up
you know by by a lot of by a lot of
people you know um you know humans
started interacting with plants and the
nature around them they started figuring
out which ones were good to eat which
ones were good for health which ones did
this which ones did that and so on a
certain level there was a point where
um people figured out that you know
marijuana that you know the wild
marijuana strains had some effects
whether it was like hand-rubbed shiraz
uh making hashish by rubbing buds and
then getting it on their hands and then
rubbing it off and smoking it or
consuming it or various aspects like
that people started to sort out that
this was a useful plan
right yeah and so like just every other
kind of useful plant from corn to
watermelons to anything else people
started messing with it to get more of
what they wanted
yeah right and so we what we think is is
we think as as you go from wild
populations
right that um
that uh started that humans started
interacting with to planted populations
of cannabis by humans
what we assume is the traditional method
is that people would go out into these
fields
and they would pick uh females that they
liked the smell they liked the structure
they liked whatever it was about it
maybe they liked it at increased thc
compared to its neighbors sure and they
would keep those plants
and then therefore next year they would
plant a bunch of seeds from their
favorite females yeah right and so then
over time year after year generation
after generation humans started slowly
improving their local gene pool
and breeding it towards things they
wanted
yeah maybe it was terps back then
although they obviously wouldn't have
called it that aromas effects
weight you know finished who knows
different farmers i'm sure had vastly
different things but you know farmers
back then seed collecting was part of
the the way they grew everything
so you picked your favorite plants they
were seeded and you grew that next year
and then over time
uh humans started having a massive
impact on what kind of
you know what kind of plants were being
grown
because they'd done this selection over
time over time over time and that pretty
much i think happened
um virtually everywhere
anywhere cannabis was endemic sure yeah
i mean it's it's kind of not well known
but just really quickly
they think that cannabis sort of started
in the highland areas around china
tibetan plateau
um you know that kind of region it went
down into india it went down into
pakistan and afghanistan
and about 2 700 years ago
we have verifiable evidence that the
scythians who were like central steppy
people were using it in their culture
that it was being used in the very
northern parts of afghanistan and in
certain parts of the caucus mountains
uh and then also we've they found thc
burned in temples about 60 miles south
of jerusalem about 2 700 years ago
so
right so there's so there's a situation
where obviously like we have we don't
know how long ago it started but
china
and uh tibet and the caucus mountains
and where israel is right now are
obviously pretty far far apart from each
other
especially from the way that people got
around at the time which was you know
camels horses donkeys etc right so so
smoking and consuming either hash or
cannabis
um is at least 3 000 years old
documented in multiple spots yeah
probably goes back
significantly farther than that we just
haven't found
absolute evidence that it occurred
sure um and so you know then you have
then you have a scenario in which um so
that's kind of how it start starts up in
tibet and china area it comes down into
pakistan india afghanistan it starts
going into iran and the middle east
then it goes down into uh into africa
right yeah um in russia it turns into
what becomes known as ruder alice
uh
and um
so
so then so then there's uh you know the
the weird part is the americas
right is how it got to america uh it
seems like
um although this isn't 100 verified but
it seems like that most of the stuff
that ended up in america
came along with the conquistadors and
then later the slave trade
uh it seems like a bunch of hemp hemp
was obviously used for most rope most
sales
i was sailors brought it with them um
everywhere
because it was like if you got
shipwrecked or something you might need
to grow a crop of hemp to turn it into
sales or rope again so you could get off
your island or wherever you were
um so
you know uh hemp was hemp was critical
to that era's
trade and so it was kind of broad
everywhere so it seems like
uh to brazil
to the caribbean to mexico when they
when they start talking about that kind
of thing
genetically
most cannabis from those regions ties
back to some kind of african
yeah
right
another weird thing and uh there's
there's not a lot of evidence to back
this up but the strange thing is is when
they did genetic work on panamanian and
colombian
that has to
tie back to uh
um to southeast asia
yeah okay which is weird and so i only
have like one little tidbit on that and
it has nothing to do with cannabis
necessarily but obviously
at some point um
if that if it's true and the genetics of
panama and colombia tie back to more
southeast asia region then somehow it
had to get from there to
from southeast asia to the western half
of south america right
and so there's essentially two options
either
it happened once the spanish and others
started trading with the east
after the conquests
or there's another interesting thing
where there's pacific islanders
and some others that they've done
genetic testing on in southeast asia and
some of these islands where they have
discovered pre-columbian um indian
people's dna
uh in these pacific islanders from about
1100 or 1200 a.d
oh wow so we know for a fact because
they interbred they had babies with them
they implanted some of their dna from
pre-columbian peoples into pacific
islanders and so we know for a fact
that hundreds of years three four
hundred years perhaps before uh columbus
sailed and discovered and rediscovered
uh the caribbean and americas
um there was some kind of trade or at
least inter relationships between the
pacific islanders and the panamanian and
colombian peoples
um
if people are [ __ ] they're probably
smoking yeah and and since we know that
that hamilton
was absolutely was absolutely required
for sailing uh it makes sense that it
theoretically could have been required
for sailing um back then and they they
traded some of these pre-columbian
indigenous peoples that were sailing out
to the pacific islands um they traded
them some seeds
and the seeds would be necessary on both
ports if they're going both places and
so that's not proof we have guaranteed
proof that they were interbreeding in
1100 a.d because of the way dna and
genetics works so we know that there was
trade ongoing
um we don't know exactly when
but uh it does seem like colombian and
panamanian tie in somehow to the
southeast asia portion of the gene pool
not the african where mexican jamaican
the island weed
the stuff that's on the eastern side of
south america that all seems to come
from
african origins
which makes sense because there wasn't
just a mammoth amount of trade both
slave and otherwise coming over from all
portions of africa over to the new world
yeah right
um and so we know some of it was
introduced then
it's entirely possible that that some of
it was introduced earlier i mean you
know some of this some of this stuff is
not poorly poorly you know documents
poorly documented for lack of a better
term uh you know the conquistadors
burned most of the writings
of the mayans and the aztecs and the
other peoples because they thought they
were devil works so
most of their knowledge was sort of lost
so who knows maybe they even had it
written down
uh and we just don't know
so
you fast forward again and you have
these various people in these various
regions
that are improving their own genetic
stock
the people in thailand the people in wow
the people in mexico the people in
colombia they're growing their stock
they are working with what them and
other local farmers in their area have
access to right
and they're breeding it every year and
that's where
all of these
varietals kind of came from um obviously
it was all seeded weed
um you know there was uh you know and
there was two distinct cultures going on
too right maybe we should mention this
so
in the north indian pakistan and
afghanistan regions it was primarily a
hashish culture
so
they viewed the plant as essentially i
don't want to say they beat it as
garbage but they viewed it as as a way
to get a hold of the trichomes
yeah whether they did hand rub like i
was talking about or whether they did
dry sift or whatever method they used to
extract it
uh they thought that the proper use of
cannabis was to turn it into hash
yeah um you know and so but then you go
to lao or cambodia or thailand or mexico
or colombia these kind of places
they smoked flour
so you had some groups breeding for
specific
basically hash plants
right and then you had some groups
breeding for smokable flower yeah
right
and those were the kind of those were
the kind of
selections that people were making back
then right
and then you know uh
obviously like america is founded on
capitalistic principles right and so if
there's a demand somewhere and there's a
supply somewhere else adam smith says
that the invisible hand should come
along and get the supply from where it
is to where the demand is right so you
have all these regions that we've talked
about have been probably improving their
crops year to year they're saving their
best seed like they do with their food
crops they're slowly improving their
genetic lines but there's really not a
lot of interaction between them and
other groups they're kind of growing
what's available in their area
except except for the one thing we we
had talked about i believe it's
referenced in rob clark's hashish book
except in afghanistan where they were
importing they had learned the trade of
uh of of hand rubbing and hash
collecting via the root from india so
most of the stuff during that time they
were importing indian uh uh more sativa
type narrow leaf varieties to
afghanistan because that's what the
indians were using to make their hash
and they weren't using their afghanis in
their fields yet they they weren't using
those to
get the trichomes collect and make the
hash they were actually using indian
sativas during that time and it wasn't
until more modern uh
the past 1950 when they started using
collecting their own varieties so maybe
a better way to more accurate way to
state it would just say that like we
can't discount that there was some
regional trading going on sure right
between say you know india pakistan
afghanistan they're all connected to one
another you can kind of go back and
forth
there could be panamanian and colombian
going back and forth there could be some
caribbean exchanges
but in general there wasn't caribbean
trading with thailand
yeah with afghanistan there wasn't like
different regions of the world
the regions themselves mixed a bit you
know it's obviously not written down so
it's really hard to determine with any
kind of factual basis how it exactly
occurred
um but you have all these
over all hundreds of years by the time
that like
america gets involved you have all these
uh weed cultures
that have developed around the world
some of them are hash cultures some of
them are smokable flower cultures so
obviously they made different decisions
on their strains based on
uh you know whether they wanted to smoke
flower or whether they wanted to to
create a hash plant sure um and
you know prohibition was was fully going
on in america
and
um you know invisible hand comes in and
there's a bunch of people in america
that want to smoke pot
musicians jazz artists
hippies
uh counterculture beatnecks
various various types of people get
introduced to it
most likely mota
uh probably most people's first
experiences with it were probably
mexican
coming into the country
there was a lot of you know back and
flow over the border uh with mexican
like you know farmworking and stuff like
that they probably brought it with them
there's definitely records of of famous
jazz people smoking in the 20s and 30s
looking at jazz cabbage yeah you know i
mean obviously it was it was a big
enough issue
that uh they decided to do some crazy
prohibition in the late 1930s
um
up till that point and uh so
so then you have a situation where you
start hitting like what matters to most
people i think
uh with with this way that we've kind of
brought ourselves to here is that
various entrepreneurs
decided to start sourcing
weed
from various countries that grew weed
and figure out a way to get it into
america and sell it for a high dollar to
american people
and the difference in profit between
buying it from a thai farmer
to selling it to a guy that lives in
venice beach
was extremely high
so there was a lot of economic incentive
for these people to start figuring out
ways to smuggle it into the country and
and feed the demand
right yes
and so
uh sadly uh one thing that was so we
start getting imports right we start
getting
we start getting imports and we start
getting things from
uh panama people start smuggling from
panama and colombia people certainly
start smuggling from jamaica and other
caribbean
islands
mexico
hawaii
um you know asia there's some pretty
famous smugglers that were working in
thailand and cambodia and lao
in the 60s and they start you know all
the famous stuff you've heard about uh
colombian gold panama red
thai sticks
every every um
i'm sure matt can think of some others
there's a bunch of them
uh
jamaican lambs bread
you know holly from from
mexican um you know mexican stuff was
generally named by region you had
mitchell khan you had oaxacan you had
this you had aaron yeah you had various
things and that's kind of like those
were the first names
that you would get
um you know the very first names of weed
was like where it's from
and maybe some nickname like maybe
maybe they dried colombian gold
into a brownish gold color
and then there was panamanian red and it
had red hair or there was this and you
know they wrapped they wrapped in
thailand they wrapped the loose buds
around sticks to make it like a more
these go from like a super leafy
hermaphroditic loose flowers and they'd
pack them tight to make it into
something and you get thai stick and so
all the original names they're not
really strained names they're like this
is where it's from
and this is its nickname that we gave to
it from where it's from possibly a color
or smell or some other attribute yeah
yeah you know or a rhyme
yeah right maui wowie yeah exactly they
guaranteed picked it because it rhymed
yep that was that's the reason right
and so
you know um
and so that's when so that's when like
the the breeding that everybody is
familiar with kind of starts
yeah right you've got all this seated
weed
coming into
america from all these regions i named
southeast asia the caribbean uh mexico
america you know south america that type
of thing and as you know i mean for the
younger cats out there
you know i used to sit there with my
head down and a tray at an angle and you
would break your weed up here
right and then that allowed all the
seeds to roll down the tray and collect
at the bottom lip of the tray as you
broke up all your herb
right and then you'd have a bunch of
fluffed up herb for a bowl or a bong or
rolling a joint or something along those
lines right
um and so everybody got free seeds
right free seeds we weren't really too
much
we weren't really too much of a hash
culture and that's part of the reason
why and then also hash is his trichomes
separated from the flower and the such
so
everything that was coming into america
at first was various kinds of sativas
yes
because the sativas were the butts
you know yeah and if you were getting
imported afghan of afghani
indica hash you were getting blocks of
hash yeah
you weren't getting afghan blood like
that important yeah it didn't come with
free seats yeah yeah there was no
receipts no there was sometimes the
random seed in the brick hatch
the random bud i mean there's a famous
actually uh there's some serious debate
in europe over uh over there's two camps
basically on the on the white widow camp
there's uh you know uh just so and the
only reason why i bring that up is
because there's a guy over there ingemar
uh and one of the one of the stories
about how white widow happened is like
the founding part of white widow is he
was breaking up a block of imported hash
and some seeds fell out
yeah and he got an original afghan from
some region out of that block of seeds
yeah so it was rare um
you know there was some hash being
imported into america
but like i said you know it uh it didn't
come with free seats
yeah where um there was no seedless in
any of these other regions so all the
sativas that we were importing came with
receipt
yes and that free seed is the start of
every famous breeder you've ever heard
of journey
yes for the most for the most yeah it
really is yeah it is so people start
smoking weed
right people start liking the weed
and then some people have get the idea
i have these seeds
i wonder what would happen if i started
growing my own weed
right and then there's places some of
them are pretty famous the emerald
triangle
trinity county humboldt county mendocino
county where i live
um the central coast san francisco uh
santa cruz area of bakersfield yeah of
california yes legendarily
you know basically anywhere where it was
mountainous
remote
people weren't gonna find it
and the climate was cool i'm not saying
people weren't doing it in other parts
of the country because of course they
were
um but
uh you know wherever people could start
to get away with it with their with
their imports they start growing it yeah
and mecca's were built and mecca's will
build and then the only reason why i
brought up those regions is because
enough people in those regions all
decided to start doing
then it started the beginnings of
american
growing culture
sure right if you're growing in upstate
new york or oklahoma or florida or some
[ __ ] um
you're probably trying to keep it pretty
small
yeah you know there was definitely some
stuff with hippies in santa cruz and
mendocino county and central coast and
different areas that um they were a
little bit more open with each other
uh and so there was a little bit more
trading going on and a little bit more
of a culture started to develop where in
some of the other more harsh police
state regions of the united states
that were a lot more populated it was a
lot more secretive and you know circles
were even smaller right sure so
you know people start growing seed
probably with varying success
and
they start discovering stuff
right they start discovering that when
you grow thai and you go colombian
boy is it hard to finish in america yeah
very you know the stuff wants to go till
december january our weather doesn't go
that long
um
people start having issues
with getting you know because if you
could grow weed from the seed then you
could get free weed
yeah and you wouldn't have to be buying
it what does this pre-weed look like
when it hasn't been compressed and
bailed and shipped
from you know international locations
what would it be like if you got it
fresh
so yeah the initial success for people
was
um you know people people could get the
mexicans to finish
because the mexicans typically were
farther away from the equator and they
were a little shorter right and they had
significant struggles getting the
colombian and the panama and the
ties and the different stuff like that
to finish right yeah
so this this this is where people start
to get the idea of like i got some thai
stick or i got some colombian gold and i
got some oaxacan right
and what happens if i grow them up when
i cross them
yeah that's that's basically the start
of american breeding that's the that's
the the honest to god that's the start
of how everybody in america started
breeding things right
and i'm not going to say america is
unique but it is rare in the sense that
america is the plate or one of the
places
where for the first time in hundreds of
years
people started crossing these wildly
different gene pools
from these different regions together
yes
right um i think i think the way you put
it the other night and i wrote it down
because it was it was worded very well
whoever and wherever the weed was
becoming imported the most that's where
the weed was blended together the first
time
right
and that's that's well put that and so
you know um and so there's
so
so yeah so basically um
you know there's uh you know there's
some pretty famous stuff that started
happening then
uh people started getting these
different these different things they
started breeding them together
um they started experimenting with stuff
um in the san francisco bay area and in
santa cruz and stuff like what became
known as hayes started which according
to sam and others was essentially
colombian by colombian
um
you know and uh but you needed a
greenhouse
you needed you they figured with some of
these some of these land races you
needed to grow it in a mild climate
which the central coast and uh the bay
area definitely had
and you needed you needed some way to
protect it from the weather and give it
maybe some heat or some whatever and and
and finish it right
so they start crossing things yeah one
of the famous people that started
crossing things is a guy named rob clark
right yes
uh rob has some very famous stuff that
he did he started crossing colombians
and mexicans
uh because mexicans finished quite
faster and so he was trying to get the
qualities of the two and get something
that would finish in california yeah
right
and so
they start breeding obviously sam skunk
man is breeding obviously there's other
various people that are popping and
doing all kinds of stuff a lot of the
the oldest and most legendary names that
we know yes
are from this era
sure they're from this like pioneer
take some thai take some cambodian cross
them together cross it with some
colombian cross it with some mexican
cross it with some this cross some
jamaican buy this
you know trade some seeds with your
friend
um and
you know uh so that's kind of like the
start of
like uh cannabis growing in america
yes on any kind of scale and
so even when i started in the early 90s
um i still have them some over there
there's i got like three books that i
bought
uh knowledge was extremely limited there
was no internet there was no forums
there was no foreign
no and so and so even for me in the 90s
think about how difficult it must have
been um for the people in the 70s that
had even less knowledge oh i'm sure
right because one of the things i'll
hold it up right now one of the things
that taught me breeding
was this
the bible
this is the bible uh rob clark
took his experience with growing a bunch
of weed and breeding a bunch of weed and
he figured out
how marijuana grows how it breeds how it
triggers
all the different traits the different
traits and he wrote this
i mean matt's right he wrote sort of a
bible
yeah right he wrote a basic bible so
when i started out i was able to buy
this bible
when i got interested in weed and i was
able to read this book over and over and
over again
and it taught me a ton about how to grow
cannabis
yeah
i'm sure matt had the same experience
most readers
most breeders that get curious about
breeding um you've read rob clark's book
yeah if you're a seed maker and you
actually are passionate and want to
learn and and make things better you
almost everyone eventually runs into rob
clark's work and eventually i think with
the breeder syndicate thing one of the
plans is to do for patreon a course
based on uh cannabis evolution and
ethnobotany uh rob clark gave us his
permission to use that for a course so i
thought that would be pretty cool to do
yeah and so he i mean i don't need to go
through all of it but he started talking
about the differences in latitude
and you know finish times and the
differences in the various kinds of
cannabis and regions and what to expect
from them
how to make seed how to make seed mature
like really like and so you know he
deserves an enormous amount of credit
sure uh because i'm sure there was an
enormous amount of [ __ ] ups
yeah in order to learn breeding when
breeding is 90 fuck-ups there was uh
there was a there was a you know they
had to learn all that and they had to
they had to put that down into some kind
of information base and i'm sure his
journey to learn was significantly
harder
uh than the people that came after him
i'm sure because there was no
books for him to buy
exactly right i mean i don't think there
was any cannabis books in the 60s and
you know there was
not breeding i mean in the 70s it sort
of exploded a little bit
um steve murphy uh who we've talked
about
murphy stevens it was his pen name but
you know the gentleman that gave the
afghani seeds to uh seattle uh greg
which he used to create what we know as
northern lights uh he wrote some i think
like by 74
73 74 ish he had some books out uh mel
frank and ed rosenthal
started contributing some stuff uh there
was uh uh since mella tips
um there was high times
uh
there was various other magazines
there's all kinds yeah there was all
kinds of things so people started
70s is where all of a sudden there
starts to be like um
information coming out that people can
access and they don't have to like learn
from scratch
or what their neighbor knows or what
their buddy that got them into it knows
yeah right
and uh and so and so you know rob uh rob
did things like rob crossed colombian
and mexican
right robin and sam skunk man are
friends
you know skunk one is
afghan by colombian mexican
yeah you know they start blending things
um longer things with shorter things
they start playing they start looking to
see can i get the traits of this mexican
with the traits of this colombian
can i get this tie to stop herming and
not take seven months
yeah i uh can i this
structure to the tie the blood structure
all that type of stuff and so
you know and then um so people so people
start
um
uh crossing these things right
and so maybe this is a good time
so that that's what's really happening
in the i don't know exactly when it
started happening in the 60s um but it
definitely was happening in the 60s to
some degree it accelerated greatly in
the 70s
one second i'm just going to chime in um
greg actually said i studied luther
burbank and then bought all of rob's
books burbank worked with cannabis in
california yeah so there you go even
even somebody like greg who's i consider
to be a very early pioneer oh yeah doing
a lot of stuff uh rob's work helped him
you know um
and so that's kind of and that's that's
also a theme that i'd like to say uh you
know right now is that and this remains
true no matter what episode we're gonna
chat about is that every single breeder
out there
stands on the shoulders of the people
that came before them
whether it's whether it's the seeds and
the genetics they have access to whether
it's the forums or books or knowledge
from older cats there was a wave of
pioneers that really figured it out and
then every generation after that every
group after that they got to take
their work in genetics and improve it or
mess it up you know it was the case
maybe depending on your opinion right
yeah but they also got a bunch of
knowledge by the time a lot of you guys
on this that are listening got into it
there was probably forums you could go
there with breeding forums i mean you go
on the breeding forum of overgrow and
there's sam skunk man and camara and
people that have a lot of knowledge you
start reading that um and you know the
internet books started putting the
knowledge out there in a way for people
to really access which really sped up
the time it took you know um
you know on a i mean on a previous
interview
uh that you know greg's on this when
when uh matt interviewed greg i mean
greg spoke about you know they got some
afghan beans uh that were extremely
limited from uh steve murphy and they
crossed them to themselves and then they
basically crossed them with every sativa
they knew of yeah hawaiians colombians
thais you know lots of mexicans lots of
mexicans lots of this lots of that they
were just everybody was just playing
around with and that's the other part
that people need to know right is that
nobody knew what an afghan by mexican
would look like
yeah it hadn't happened not yet they
knew what colombian by mexican would
look like because that hadn't happened
either so a lot of these pioneers
they're taking you know rob's like i
wonder if i took colombian and mexican
and crossed it what does that look like
yeah you know and then maybe later on
when skunk one is born sam is like hey i
got access to some afghans
let's cross this afghan into your skunk
into your you know your colombian
mexican maybe that'll shorten it up even
earlier and it'll be done in october
and this and i think this is a good
segue into talking about how breeding
for uh just to see what happens um
turned into breeding for traits as they
learn these traits as they as they saw
you know this one's purple this one
smells like watermelon this one smells
like cereal they started learning well
if we combine these traits you know
let's let's see if we can get this trait
to pop out if we cross this and this and
they started
going and actually having a purpose for
breeding uh with cannabis and finding
out that there were these traits that
they could follow long flowering short
flowering colors smell taste high all of
it and it went from seeing what can
happen to a real
purpose a real purpose yes and so i
think probably the two traits
in the beginning that people were after
was
i like the way this weed tastes and
smokes
it won't finish where i live
yeah how do i get it to finish
where i live because a lot of this stuff
like panamanian uh colombian the
southeast asian stuff is all very near
the equator it takes a long time uh
america is not particularly near the
equator um you know so they had to
figure out how do i blend stuff to get
the stuff i like and be able to grow it
in my region
yeah
right and obviously there's a big
financial incentive in that too
right because you don't have to import
it it doesn't have to come through
customs and that's kind of where green
bud was born
yes right uh you know the way that most
of these traditional cultures they
didn't have air-conditioned dry rooms or
anything like that a lot of them dried
hanging in the woods a lot of them dried
in the sun
a lot of them dried it and then
key load it
right and then it begins to ferment
and it gets wrapped up in plastic for
weeks or months and then shipped for
some period of time you know if you were
lucky maybe you got some green mexican
that was only lightly compressed that
they figured out some way to get it
across the border without smooshing it
into a block that you could cut with a
knife uh yeah you can actually like
break it up into actual buds instead of
it just being like a flat mass
um
you know and so that's where you know
greg steve murphy was breeding in the
70s uh greg and his whole pacific
northwest crew
the you know most people in california
were breeding either outdoor or in
greenhouses yes
uh the indoor wave was still and maybe
this is a good segue
um for a second i printed out this thing
and uh you can't really see it so i'm
just going to read it because it's
really really dark
this is a this is a seed catalog
um
you know uh from 1981 it's tied into sam
and his crew
we assume um but it lists uh strains in
order of of when they matured october
november and december and it lists like
what so it gives you a snapshot of what
people were actually working with right
yeah and uh so i'll read it to you in
october
you had afghani one afghani two afghani
two purple skunk one skunk two
yep that's all they list five things
before that finish before halloween yeah
the faster finishing right then you have
november right
nepali malawi nepali afghani malawi
nepali
early haze by afghani
yeah and those are done hopefully by
thanksgiving
yep and then here comes the mother lode
of everything
and i'll say on this list it says all
the above can be grown outside in most
years in the sf bay area and that's the
october and the november stuff right and
then below it it says
all below
require a greenhouse to finish in the
san francisco bay area
yeah and now you've got south indian one
two three original haze 1-4 burning bush
nepali haze haze nepali nepali hay south
indian early haze south indian hey south
indian tai hayes south indian south
african haze burning bush by nepali
burning bush by south hayes
uh by south indian haze and then you
even have one category matures in
january
extra late new year's haze
yeah i bet
maybe when people are listening to that
right
yeah and uh you're uh you're realizing
that oh my god everything that they're
mentioning other than afghani and skunk
i've never had
yeah i don't have i don't i don't i
don't malawi and nepali and
haze thai nepali and this and that and
everything else
um
there's a bunch of um
there's a bunch of stuff like that so
that gives you like a snapshot of like
these are what the breeders back then
were crossing to each other
yeah
right which is super different
okay
and so you know um
maybe we can mention this even though it
kind of like it fits in but it kind of
doesn't but the reason why we're talking
about all this stuff is that basically
like every 10 years in my opinion
cannabis reinvents itself
yes and absolutely and what was common
becomes uncommon or rare
yeah and then you go 20 years from that
point and what becomes uncommon or rare
becomes like impossible
yeah
you know uh
matt and i were recently looking at
somebody's freezer collection that they
had been gifted
it was a big collection it was super
impressive it was really exciting to
look through and most of it was from 08
to 2012.
yeah and i was selecting heavily during
that time and that so that was matt's
kind of era when he was really
collecting a ton and stuff and
and it's amazing that it's it's only 10
to 13 14 years later and 98 of that
stuff that's on the list you couldn't
buy today if you wanted to
yeah and you'd be lucky to find a
reproduction if you were lucky you'd be
lucky to find a reproduction you know
and there's some famous people on there
like you know a bunch of stuff that
people found fire og rascal work
he had tons of awesome [ __ ] back then
too and nowadays like i i even still
look out for like white oracle and white
master and a few things when i see them
in lists but they're they're not common
and he was selling tons of those packs
back then
you know he was killing it still
probably is so all this stuff that we're
talking about right is that you know um
what's common in this in the 60s and 70s
becomes uncommon common in the 80s
almost unheard of in the 90s
a unicorn by by today and that just
keeps happening right every every 10 or
15 years
uh what you used to be able to get easy
access to
becomes super hard to find right sure
but then every generation those 10 or 15
years they're building
on certain things like i mentioned that
list there's a series of afghanis that
made it over to neville and sssc there's
this there's hazes there's skunks
there's different things that happened
in that
in that era that survived sure right but
most of the stuff on that list you've
never smoked
yeah i've never smoked yeah you know
i've never smoked burning bush by nepali
myself
bush is i don't i've never seen it i've
heard it was maybe a vegetable i've
heard i've heard it was a pre-pre to
haze you know it was an early
you know but but you know these names
south indian stuff like that um you know
they they just didn't they just that but
that's what they were growing
so
all these guys what that shows you is
that all these guys um
all these guys were basically breeding
sativas
yeah
right that's the majority of that list
was some sativas there's a couple
afghanis even skunk one was 75 sativa
yeah it was a blend of mexican colombian
and a little bit of afghan
so it was still even heavily influenced
right
um
and so
sam skunk man became very famous in that
era that's where you know he he says he
started breeding his skunk one in 1975.
um you know he bred it for eight or ten
years before he brought it to uh
california brought it from california to
amsterdam
uh mel frank was working with an afghan
that got named afghani one that he got
from another bay area breeder uh who had
gotten some afghani seeds
um he got some durban poison that he was
working in the 70s they were breeding
some other stuff like that rob clark was
obviously busy
um in uh you know seattle greg's neck of
the woods they had somehow come across
some afghan and they were also blending
in
um
so you know all the various sativas that
people had then
in hawaii you know people call stuff
hawaiian but there obviously is no
hawaiian yeah uh 98 of the species uh on
hawaii are not native
um because it's an island in the middle
of nowhere uh that created by a volcano
yeah but people started bringing
colombian it's very tropical people
started bringing thai and colombian and
afghans and mexicans there and blending
them
and growing them on the islands and then
they became known as hawaiian
yep
you know even though there are there's
no hawaiian genetics there's a blending
of sativas
maybe with a touch afghan
quick plug for our uh everybody if
you're if you're enjoying it uh we have
our patreon shop up or we have our
merchandise shop up and we have our
patreon uh throughout the week we
discuss a lot of this stuff in discord
what we're going to be talking about we
go on a lot of topics answer questions
there and we have a pretty [ __ ]
awesome community for me there so go to
our patreon radio spreeder syndicate if
you want to participate and again merch
we got hats hoodies shirts you name it
we got it now
[Music]
there we go
this has been you know it kind of like
uh took a while but yeah it kind of
walked people through
sort of like and now we're starting to
enter this point where
um we'll talk we'll talk a little bit
more about how the shift happened
and then we'll and then we'll answer
some questions
right because we got some good questions
this week so we might as well chat at
that so fast forward a bit people are
doing all this stuff in the 70s
and um you know in the uh in the late
70s
uh things were really blowing up people
were doing all kinds of stuff together
um and very in these various regions i
was talking about it was really
advancing
uh then carter loses the election
reagan gets uh reagan gets involved
and the war on drugs gets ramped up
and the world goes to [ __ ] for from the
from where it had been the penalties are
yeah
they start putting more money into it
and uh they start flying
they start taking helicopters and they
start flying in hawaii they start flying
in mendocino county they start flying in
the central valley and some of this
stuff right
and so
what that does is that all of a sudden
all these guys are growing all this weed
and they're growing in the mountain
regions and they're growing it in
valleys and stuff like that
and they're not too concerned because
nobody's looking for them and then also
there's a helicopter flying overhead
sure and they got a big field that
nobody's ever bothered with before and
they get in trouble
right
so pressure starts happening right
so
you know they start hunting it
uh people start getting in trouble
and then
this is when so we mentioned before
steve murphy's book um and stuff like
that but
people were on the what's called the
hippie hashish trail
where people were traveling to nepal
people were traveling to india people
were traveling to the hindu kush
mountains they were meeting up with
tribal you know people and stuff like
that and so there was some small amount
of afghan seeds and indicas that started
making its way into america yeah mostly
only to breeder circles certainly not to
consumers the way every bag of every
sack of weed you bought had a bunch of
seeds in it for free
but they started trickling in smuggling
style
to trinity humboldt mendocino to the bay
area to various other places
um you know in in steve murphy's book
you see some broadleaf afghans in 74. uh
obviously
uh you know uh you know seattle greg uh
was working with some of this stuff
um and so the the big advantage in the
beginning to people was that you start
crossing these afghans into some of
these sativas and now maybe you're
getting stuff that's finishing you know
the more heavy afghan you select you're
finishing in september or october
sure and one second i just want to make
sure everybody's really paying close
attention to this part because i found
one of the biggest uh myths in cannabis
is that afghanis existed in our culture
you know in just as long as sativas and
as long as we've been smoking or
narrow leafs you know people didn't know
that afghanis came as a late entry so
when you see a lot of these people
making claims about 60s afghanis and 50s
afghanis it's very easy to discount with
history
so
while
seed of sativas like we said before
we're getting imported by the literal
ton
with every bag of weed you bought you
got uh seeds of seeds
and the the indica stuff was being
brought back by smugglers and what i
would imagine would be relatively small
amounts
uh you know in his interview uh you know
greg told you that he got a whopping
four afghan seeds
yeah whopping a whopping four you know
um and the biggest problem that you know
you grow in afghanistan and you and you
grow in the hindu kush mountains it's
obviously colder there and it's
extremely dry so people start growing in
america
and they rot
yeah the sativas were grown in tropical
much more humid regions they had a lot
of genetic resistance to rot and so a
lot of the things that people were
trying to figure out is
they can grow these afghans and they're
like oh my god it's an amazing beautiful
frosty crazy looking weed yeah and it's
not done and you get some weather and
all of a sudden it rots them and it has
a totally different high than a lot of
people are used to yeah people go from
an up energetic kind of zippy high
somewhat psychedelic lack of this that
indicas come with much more couch lock
much more heaviness much more limitation
so a lot of the early smokers
didn't like indica
yeah it clashed so hard with what they
were used to as buds
yeah and the effect they weren't super
into it but from a growers perspective
since i read all that stuff
you know going from november december
harvest to september october harvest
when you have police pressure becomes
extremely important
yeah
right
and so
you know i maybe we should talk very
briefly um because it's a pretty simple
subject but when i moved to mendo in the
late 90s people still mostly grew from
seed outside
and the traditional way that you grew
from seed was that you would grow some
seed you would pick your males you would
take your males to like a kind of a
darker part of your hill somewhere and
you would stash them
away from your females you would grow
your females in some patches right
and then you'd collect pollen and you'd
go take this pollen from all your males
and you'd brush it on some of the lower
branches of your favorite females from
that year
yeah and i believe that's how the vast
majority of breeding occurred even when
you look at like rob clark's book he
talks about like putting like a a paper
bag paper bag the paper bag with a with
a tie over specific branches and putting
one on the bag you know even talks about
like gluing a strip of clear plastic so
that it gets some sun on it while it's
doing this
yeah
all that type of stuff and so most most
70s breeding in america was
pollinating the bottoms of stuff you
were intending on selling
yeah
and then keeping it
yeah right
and then you know with the police
pressure and stuff like that that's
really where modern modern breeding
starts
yeah okay so
um
70s breeding not exclusively but
essentially was the vast majority was
seasonally
they would pollinate their best females
with males they had kept somewhere else
yeah right
with the advent of indoor lights and the
advent of hydroponics stores and people
like
uh and growing in the pacific northwest
like we've talked about multiple times
people started to do some of this
breeding inside
yeah they started doing it away from the
helicopters
away from away from the lights away from
the ability to get caught and it also it
also enabled um people to do more than
one breeding a year
yeah yeah
i mean back a lot today
back in the day you got like you got one
shot
right yeah that that's that's what you
got you all of a sudden you go indoor
and now as you know you can get four or
five shots if you want
yeah you know right
and so that's when that's when you know
prohibition
really forced people to start going
inside
and going inside
is obviously how 99 of modern breeding
occurs
yeah i would say
you know there's not i mean there are
some people that still breed outdoor
and i would say most people breed
outdoor in modern times because it's
much more cheap to make seeds that way i
think the ones that take it very
seriously and are doing actual
selections do it indoors but generally
speaking must do it outdoor you know
maybe i should rephrase it most of the
seeds that you guys have access to that
you can buy currently were probably made
indoor
no you know you don't think so no not at
all
it's all done outdoor and greenhouse
yeah 99 of it 99 of it
yeah
yeah even today
even today most of the seeds that people
buy are going to be coming from
places
see big seed banks from the uk maybe
stuff like that
so i the way i was looking at it is most
of the most of the small and and
most of the hype breeders that people
are actually buying a bunch of packs of
these days
they're you know um they're mostly doing
they were mostly doing it in indoor
scenes
um some of them were doing it in
greenhouses
um certainly he's correct in the sense
that like if i'm only talking about what
most people have access to obviously
when it comes to like all the mexican
and all the traditional stuff and some
of the stuff that's going on in europe
at a larger scale uh where legality is
different like switzerland or spain
they're still probably using greenhouses
that's like 95 percent of the market
though
for america i think yeah
oh yeah no no american american boutique
breeding is still small market um
and even then a lot of these guys are
doing it outdoors making the seats
outdoors and crazy crazy places that you
can never imagine you can never imagine
so small small greenhouses
tucked away
make the most amount of seeds and and
that's i think for during the uh
early to late
up to 2008 2009 a lot of the boutique
breeders were all doing it indoors
indoors yes
that was a poorly phrased way to say
sure that from the 80s 90s and the first
10 years the 2000s for about a 30 year
period
prohibition had a lot of breeding
happening indoors exactly a lot of your
famous strains that you know of uh
whether they were from sssc or from
neville
or from smaller breeders in america
all the northern lights work all that
type of stuff the prohibition was heavy
the legality was still not spread out
very much and so for three decades
um the vast majority of of breeding that
we're aware of
uh did did happen inside yeah and now
it's opened up again uh you know in
various ways in the last you know 10 or
15 years and it's beginning to shift
yeah it took legalities changing in the
u.s though really i think that's what
changed it when people were able to grow
outdoor and not get popped for it they
realized that the amount of seed you can
make outdoor versus indoors is
monumental but pollen pollen control is
totally a different subject control is
hard um not and now and pollen viability
is hard too i mean i know people that
have tried to throw off huge greenhouse
runs
and their greenhouse is too moist and
pollen doesn't like heat light or water
and i've seen a bunch of people have a
bunch of failure uh because they weren't
able to control their humidity
uh in their greenhouse and they think
i'm gonna make 15 million seeds
and they make 80 000
yeah which is still a lot but it's a far
cry from 15 million because they lost
control of their humidity
so
um
you know part of the
so this is kind of taking us up to like
people are getting busted
everything bad things are happening and
a lot of these american breeders okay
and this is what segways into what we've
done the last few shows a bunch of these
american breeders start fleeing
where it's hot and uncomfortable which
is reagan america
to where it's more comfortable which is
europe holland
right rob yeah and ends up in hop going
into holland sam
uh jim what all these guys are bringing
that's why neville and all these groups
got access to it uh was not because that
all these guys wanted to share it was
because they were seeking a new place to
continue doing what they were doing
yeah it got real pop it got real
problematic in the early in the early to
mid 80s late 80s
um i mean you know uh to bring up
seattle greg again he you know he
mentioned on
when you interviewed him that by the
late 80s a rolling series of busts had
pretty much taken out his whole crew
yeah all the work that they had done had
been lost
yeah to them you know luckily he shared
it with people in holland
um
you know sam skunkman and rob and mel
and ed and
these different names that shared things
with groups they did so because it was
getting uncomfortably hot to do it where
they lived
right
and they were trying to they were trying
to figure out where to do it and so that
kind of segues us into
what we what we talked about which is
kind of where we were at of
this is how breeding got
and then with sssc and with neville and
with other groups and that whole era
not only because holland has you know um
not the greatest weather uh but also for
clandestine reasons and simplicity and
everything like that
most of the breeding in the 80s and 90s
at least by the mid 80s uh through the
90s uh was indoor
yes
you know the famous strains uh you know
sour diesel was made inside a lot of the
famous pops that happened uh that came
about 90s weed was coming from indoor
right that was where people could get
away with it
um people were able to grow in the 60s
and 70s for a while freely and then the
cops found out what they were doing and
they started looking for it and it
became much more difficult to get away
with it
and uh
and so then people responded to that
police pressure
by hiding it
yep
and then we went from sort of like
yearly breeding outside and in
greenhouses to
much more cracks at the same thing you
could breed you could set up different
rooms it's probably very unlikely that
somebody like neville or somebody like
the super sativa seed club group would
have been able to offer as many strains
as they did
oh yeah without individual rooms yeah
the amount you know matt and i were
joking about the amount of pollen
contamination
that could have been possible back then
yeah you know but certainly if you were
trying to do it outside in greenhouse
you're limited to one
you know one set of pollen
yeah otherwise it's just going to be
you're just going to have pollen grains
flying around and who now knows what is
happening playing who's your daddy with
seeds like a lot of these guys do now
yeah right you know so indoor gardening
also allowed people to
uh
you know
it allowed people to do multiple
different lines you could offer skunk
one and durbin and nl5 haze and nl5
skunk one and you could have
you know i don't exactly know the size
of these people's rooms but
it's probably not that much different
than it was today some bedrooms
yeah closets some garages
you know some converted spaces
yeah
and that's kind of like
that kind of like brings us from like
where we were
importing you know uh indigenous
people's weed
uh to like how people first bred in the
70s to how it changed and police
pressure kind of led us to like where
we're at today
yep um you know that's kind of that's
that's kind of the arc and that kind of
leads us right into what we talked about
at length the last two episodes of how
neville was doing all his work
yeah
they were uh
you know they moved it inside
you know
so i don't know maybe we can pause since
we're how long in now an hour and 10
minutes hour and 20 yeah
yeah
maybe we can pause and we can start i
don't know can you see questions because
you're yeah i can see questions this
time yeah so maybe we should uh maybe we
should start an order on the votes
aspect yep
all right
there you go uh what are each of your
guys daily driver strains right now and
what do you like about the strains to
use them every day
go ahead uh what's your what's your
normal daily driver like uh not
necessarily today but your normal one
that you you would grab if you had it
every time so i like you know i think
it's pretty obvious to people i like
uh sour diesels and chems and headbands
um you know i like strains that have a
potent and unique high
and i also like strains that i can smoke
every day and they get me high yeah
there's a lot of strains out there that
get you pretty high the first number of
days you smoke them and then you kind of
plateau on them
and they don't take you to where you
need to be
yeah on a daily basis so i like strains
that have lasting power and the ability
to like get me high the way i like every
day
and there is no i mean the chem 91 makes
me feel like i'm a stone teenager about
to watch a comedy eating popcorn and
make them it's a warm fuzzy comforting
buzz
you know uh nl5 hazes can make me feel
up energetic maybe a little paranoid
um you know different types of things to
be honest there are certain things that
are quite famous
that i find have a boring high
you know so um
chems headbands sour diesels
uh you know sativas that type of thing
uh you know it depends on my mood
obviously i don't want to smoke uh you
know a high-end sativa like dog [ __ ]
like at 11 30 at night right before bed
because i might like set my mind off
until 1am
but
uh yeah
chems headbands diesels that's what i
like what do you like matt
um i'm pretty uh obvious with mine like
i'm a blueberry thing and i like the
different ties they seemed
afghanis were most afghanis
it's generally speaking broadly if
afghanistan to relax people and and you
know ease them in that [ __ ] me up that
[ __ ] makes me stay in my head it's like
living in your [ __ ] head and hating
life so i tend to like the ties they're
really light i like lighter highs so if
i have to punch someone i can still i
don't like to be disabled you know so
that's typically what i like
and one point that we should make is
that uh
you know we have some really good
friends where some of my favorite
strains they dislike they don't dislike
them they breed with them but they don't
think they're high very much
and so there is
you know everybody thinks what happens
to me is normal
but with weed it's not normal people can
have different effects i know people you
know there might be people that have a
little add
that they smoke a racy sativa and they
feel calm and relaxed and mellow
where they smoke an afghan and it makes
them want to jump out of their skin and
climb up a wall
yeah where an afghan for me makes me
want to like lean back and eat some
popcorn and mellow out and laugh
yeah an afghan makes me want it like
would make me like think about chopping
down my grow you know like paranoia yeah
so so it's kind of it is very individual
it's it doesn't affect people the same
the next question is what in your
opinion
was the most prominent strain to come
out of holland
in the 90s other than kim nl hayes and
skunk
boy
well
i mean was a big one for me one of my
one that i was really interested in was
purple star and that was a uh a dutch
purple afghani of some sort
um you know this is kind of cheating
because i kind of think it's like modern
skunk
but certainly in the 90s uh you know
sour diesel in america
um became you know it's it's a it's
possibly a blend of chem and skunks so
maybe that's not the same but it is it
is different it's not either one of
those things that's its own thing and it
became one of the most popular strains
in america during that time frame
um you know it's hard because when you
say nl haze and skunk
there's a lot of things that have at
least one of those components in them
yeah you know very hard not to name one
yeah it's very hard not to name
something that doesn't happen
uh you know but but if you're gonna name
some of that stuff you could probably
throw in uh the white family that came
out of holland you know i mean in the
mid 90s
the white widow the great white shark
the white russian uh that whole line it
doesn't have any nl haze or skunk that
we're aware of
yeah
you know it was completely it was
different genetics uh it was extremely
popular it was all over high times it
was winning cups yeah it was getting
blended into all kinds of stuff
when i first started growing white widow
and white rhino were the ones you know
like that's what people were talking
about yeah um you know another thing is
uh this this kind of i think this angers
dj but um
you know dj gave uh dj gave tony from
sag martha a bunch of blueberry lines
and sag martha started selling blueberry
and probably for most people that was
their first ability to actually purchase
those lines yeah um he didn't you know
if he was giving it to friends or people
in his small network it certainly wasn't
as
prevalent as giving it to sag martha
yeah and later later on in the 90s after
he had soured on sag martha i believe
dutch passion
uh
took over some of his blueberry work and
stuff like that and so
whether or not he is appreciative of
that or not certainly sag martha and
dutch passion and their breadth of sales
put blueberry and those lines on the map
they did it gave people access to them
it gave people the ability to buy them
you know it made them it made him
essentially forum famous when cannabis
world and overgrow were happening
because all of a sudden you could get
these like these cool sounding strains
with these pretty colors
all that kind of stuff was going on so
um
those were those were pretty famous
you'd have to say they certainly caught
americans attention
um and they're also not nl chem haze or
skunk
yep but for the most part most famous
things have a little chem
haze skunk or net l in them you know
he's the building these are the building
block strains so it's hard to get away
from them
all matt
okay
what was hogg's breath creating or was
hog's breath created using sssegenex yes
uh the only thing i know for sure pretty
sure is uh the jimbo used uh williams
wonder now whether it was williams
wonder crosstalk random nl williams
wonder cross 2 and afghani williams
wonder it hard to say hard to say
his story
did change based on who we told but that
was intentional he did not want people
recreating it
that that cut was kept very tight until
uh several years after his passing and
it is now
out there um his sister has the
hodgepoth company and her husband
they're doing an awesome job with it uh
awesome awesome clothes i'm stoking all
my hogs gear and jim was a major
influence on me for those that don't
know
so yeah pogba breast one of my favorite
all-time strains i believe crd
underscore sd is going to be doing some
stuff with the hogs breath family to
bring it back again
all right
can you guys talk about the 88 g13 hash
plant the indian worked with not bread
please bodhi uses it as a male and i
believe haze man or someone else even
though they weren't supposed to be
released pure yeah um the the g13 hash
plant was selected in uh from supposedly
bought 1988 by a scentsy which was not
the case um
and
and that was by swampy who was an old
overgrown member indian was his friend
uh indian gets his name attached a lot
of stuff but what ends up happening is
he asks other breeders to send him
precedes he distributes them without the
breeder's name and it gets his name got
stuck with it again like the ada g13
hash plant um but it is it is the g13
hash blend aka mr nice
that seed bank or was it dizzy bank
distributed 88 was it 88 so there's
there's a couple things with this that
i'll throw in uh one
is that
there is no 88 g13 hash plant in the sea
bank it comes out in 89 yeah um so you
know once a year uh anyway but
and um from my understanding uh it had
been sort of bred to f4 before bodhi got
it
and bodhi
cracked him and
did some he didn't realize it had been
bred to f4 and bottlenecked a bit so he
got it and he bred it and he bred it a
few times and he realized that all the
breeding work that he had done with it
was kind of bunk
and his best work
with it which is what he crossed
everything to and everybody has access
to was actually the initial seed pop
he did better with the initial batch of
seeds that he got because they'd already
been heavily selected for
then him trying to work within the
narrow pool post that he thought he was
going f you know f1 to f3 maybe yeah he
was really going like f5 to f8
yeah and that's a big difference right
that doesn't mean so i think most of
what you're getting when you get stuff
from bodhi is the initial batch of seeds
that he had got that had already been
narrowed down
and
i don't know when they came from they
didn't come from 1988
they were sold in 89 and in 90. they
were not sold by scentsy um and i don't
think until uh they needed mr nice i
believe until they named it mr nice and
matt and i discovered that that didn't
pop up in a scentsy catalog until almost
1999. yeah that's a long time so it was
available for two years from neville's
seed bank in 89 and 90. i believe that's
probably where they come from
uh it was probably a pack or two that
the guy bred with
you know honestly and so that's not that
big of a selection pool
uh and that's the it's obviously you
know i mean podi's had some great
success breeding with some of that
uh it's also probably one of those ones
where there's not a bunch of places to
go with it
yeah it kind of is what it is
the breed's very dominant um it's pretty
purple
smaller butted uh some are some are
large yielding but i i believe the one
that the male the buddha uses imparts
purple traits the deadly gmail i think
he calls it and also uh for those that
don't know swampy who originally put out
those g13 hash plant seeds he also did a
cross called free leonard and that was
the g13 hash plant butterscotch wine i
believe the butterscotch wine was a
female
yeah
and that was phenomenal
phenomenal um
who was it was it oren that worked with
it i think uh
yeah oren worked with it for a little
bit and has done some cool [ __ ] with it
um it made his caramel line and a lot of
people have since used the caramel linen
and you know yeah
that's about all i can go
the next question we'll go over very
quickly because i think matt and i will
both kind of want to punt on it but
we'll see
did barney's farm ever have their own
in-house breeders have they always been
a bulk seed reseller uh i don't think
mata and i have a super high opinion of
barney's um i think they've always kind
of been
a serious seller i think they came in
very late to the game when the dutch
scene had already been significantly
reduced from its golden and even silver
era they kind of came in at the at the
tail end of all that
uh i don't know anybody that has
actually bred for them doesn't mean that
they didn't have a little bit of their
own house stuff doesn't mean you
couldn't have found good stuff
uh certainly most of the dutch seed
banks in the last 10 years have have
certainly fallen off from what they were
previous to that in terms of what people
find from them so
uh next question
longitudinally on seeds and pollen
uh one is quite easy
if you put seeds in the fridge
and or the freezer um you can extend
their life
excel you know by quite a bit and that's
pretty standard just about every breeder
i know that wants longevity on his seeds
um
they uh
you know they put them in the freezer or
the fridge
right
yeah
i'm just trying to read the questions no
the pollen the pollen um matt can speak
to this i'm sure
pollen is a lot more delicate than seeds
it has a lot more limited shelf life and
in rob's first book they talk about you
know baking some flour in the in the
oven you know and then mixing that flour
either 10 or 100 to one and then
freezing that
um
you know uh pollen is a lot if you're
heat light water all kills it um it's a
lot less viable than a hard seed to keep
alive
so uh
you know
that's all i'll say about that any any
way you want to store pollen that's not
fresh
there's various ways to go about it if
they're all iffy
people have some greater success than
others
next couple questions uh ignore it
ignore a few of these because they're
just nothing yeah i can't i'm not gonna
you know t tk og urkel sour diesel those
are all their own longer things anyway
uh do you think mendo perf is possibly
related to the purple skunk it was only
available in the original 85 catalog and
it being inbred for eight years and the
sativa effects of the purple hindu fish
type plant with those purple flowers
sounds similar
you know
um like a lot of 90s stuff that you get
the lineage and the back story that you
would prefer to come along with it
is not there
the only information that i have that i
think is factual about the mendo perps
is that the guy that i got it from
grew it in the late 70s in kovalev which
is a remote valley in mendocino county
i don't know anything other about it
besides that i don't know there's a
famous poha purple isn't there i mean
there you know there was it's sort of
you know and part of the reason why part
of the i should say this too is that um
a lot of land race stuff that we were
talking about a lot of it tested between
7 and 15 thc and it was really the
blending of these various land races and
afghans and these hybridizations that
really started bumping us up into the
higher teens lower 20s mid 20s type of
thing
and so the mendo perps while it has
amazing qualities
um it has very low thc it's probably
somewhere between
eight and twelve percent if you're not
bumping it up
um which actually kind of lends it lends
to its truth that it could be an
original
land race brought over um but i don't
have a regional origin
uh the only thing i've ever smelled in
my entire life that smelled like the
mendo perps was the
nepalese temple balls that i got from
hash smugglers in amsterdam
i thought that it might be nepalese
because of that but i have absolutely
zero evidence pointing one way or the
other other than the fact that it's
purple
alright
i don't think it's purple skunk simply
because matt and i have grown tons of
skunks various kinds of guns
it doesn't really have any other skunk
characteristics i think sparkle is
purple skunk i really genuinely do i
know uh csi probably i think he is uh
more akin to something x18 or ptk
something like that
i think it's purple skunk one purple but
i do not think mendo purposes purple
skunk
um okay so here's some funny ones what's
my favorite color in weed
uh you know uh
don't say green well i mean you know
it's uh it's you know i i do okay here's
the thing i do think that purple is
extremely physically attractive to look
at i do think that the cookies
and that the stuff from dj short and his
son jd can be extremely beautiful the
lavenders the pinks the blues
i think the mendo perps is beautiful
do i think that those kinds of weed uh
are as potent and as strong as the green
weed
no
no no so if you like very light to
moderate potency it could be your thing
but literally every potent strain that i
hold and care for
um is some shade of green
yeah i i want to see purples i need that
aesthetic oh my gosh
i would love people i would love people
to breed an extremely high potent
potency purple
i haven't seen it i've seen a few the
the purple unicorn was the chem d
blackberry widow from jojo rizzo it was
the first time i got kmd potency in a
just stark purple plant yeah i'm sure it
could exist i'm just saying as far as
most purple things that you're aware of
it's not relevant they tend to be they
tend to be lighter
yeah this is a good one the the golden
age of canada
gonna you know i'll talk about this one
for a minute because
this one's kind of dear to my heart and
maybe it's just because i was young
but i think the 90s was the golden age
of cannabis
um
you know i still think that we could go
into another golden age i don't think
it's like it's it's unachievable but the
reason i think it was the golden age is
because it was like the first poly
hybrid era
right things were less inbred um you
know there was a lot more f1s and
various poly hybrids coming out that
were quite potent
and the you know the chems the sour
diesels the nl5 hazes like most of our
fame like very extremely famous that the
cushes
they all originate from that era
and people are still using a lot of 90s
cuts
um in their breed work
they're some of the most common cuts to
use they're sort of the backbone of our
modern industry is 90s cuts
uh and the other thing i think that
makes 90s cuts different is that 90s was
the last era before the the name game
and matt can speak to this extensively
but one of the downsides to the name
game
is that every time a famous name or a
famous craze happens with cannabis
so many cool unique things that were
easy to sell
before get pushed to the wayside because
as soon as something becomes not easy to
sell
the amount of people that are willing to
hold on to it becomes tiny
so
you know um i'll give you guys a perfect
example you know i live in mendocino
county when the when the purple craze
hit and
and everybody wanted to grow grape ape
urkel lavender
uh you know so on and so forth there was
all these hill people that had been
growing all these killer strains for a
long time and easily selling them
and then they couldn't sell them and
their neighbor was like hey
you grow this urkel i'll sell as many of
them as you can get every gram
every gram you go give me your urkel and
so all these strains start to get
dropped and so a lot a lot of the reason
why we still breed with 90s work is
because that's when the that's before
the bottlenecking happened
and now if you look at what people are
selling now all these boutique breeders
every famous thing gets crossed to every
famous thing yeah so sour got crossed to
everything kush got crossed to
everything cookies got crossed to
everything skittles
you name it then they start getting
crossed to each other from both sides
again
by this by this you know cherry pie by
cushmance by wedding cake by
and it's all the same blend of the same
30 cuts
unintentional inbreeding
unintentional inbreeding because and
that's and i don't mean to call out
breeders
because that's what the public wants
yeah yeah too
um soma definitely
soma definitely had some worthwhile
offerings
um his lavender stuff was worthwhile
declining
he got some g13 by hayes a from neville
that he used as a male in some of his
sativa lines and a lot of that came out
to produce a lot of the cbd lines later
on that g13 hayes
so uh you know when i used to go to
amsterdam uh you could buy his his bud
from the dam crane which was one of the
nicer coffee shops in amsterdam
he grew good weed um some of his weed
was quite popular it was a little
different um
that's because he keeped it first
you know i try to be nice to people but
he was and he was a little notorious for
potentially running his tumblr for two
or three minutes before he put it in the
bag to sell the thing so he could
collect keith
that's for real
uh who is a legitimate source for nl1
nlc's
the problem when i mentioned earlier on
the podcast which is like every five or
ten years weed reinvents itself
you can go look at almost all of these
catalogs from the 90s and it is almost
impossible to find the vast majority of
these lines in seed form
unhybridized pure
skunk you know i mean it just is it's it
sucks to say it but
um every 10 years stuff becomes rare
that's the 90s now that's you know 25
years ago plus
most of the stuff that was available in
the 90s is no longer available today
you can't get it um it exists in various
hybrids i have i have a tendency to
think that bubba kush is has heavy nl1
influence
um
you know so i think some of this stuff
exists in different names
um but that's the sad part if you don't
buy it and store it uh you might want it
later on and you can't get it
yep
history of the 1979 christmas tree i'm
gonna skip that one maybe i don't know
it maybe if csi comes on at some point
um
uh
aspiring breeders um
[Music]
i'll uh skip that one too not because
not because it's a bad question but it's
kind of complicated yeah
i haven't heard of any bud called ufo in
florida
nope um
i don't know anything about freeze
drying cannabis i know there's companies
out there
you know
there's there's companies that are
that are claiming that freeze drying is
amazing uh i have specific methods of
drying and it certainly doesn't involve
freeze drying
uh here's a good one when and who
started making feminized seeds dutch
passion off uh gives themselves credit
for it but it was actually a man named
mohan ram and i can't remember something
set a ctt they were first doing the the
scientific spare experiments on plant
reversal using cobalt
colloidal sgs and several other methods
um
okay so here's something that's
interesting
um
i uh we'll skip a couple of these not
because they're not nice questions but i
don't know anything about the new york
recreational
rules or anything like that i don't know
anything about the new uh uh attorney
general for our state yet
um
you know
uh
central american cannabis what's the
importance of it i mean it's very
important um mexican is is central
america
uh and mexican has been bred into all
kinds of stuff
that we use the other central american
countries not so much
um it does exist
but it certainly didn't have the impact
in terms of breeders working with it
there's certainly honduran and el
salvadorian and
you know that kind of thing
panama's also is also technically
central
um
is also technically central america so
uh the two famous ones from central
america that have a lot of influence and
have been bred into a bunch are mexican
and panamanian yeah um
let's see
cubing
cubing is sort of bxing
in a way it's kind of giving [ __ ]
concept but
yeah cubing is is
great if you have a true f1
and you want to isolate a single
one or two traits that that that's
effective and then you cube then you
then you cross forward that's that's
generally how it works um however i
always give this example every time
people tend to think of c99 when they
hear cubing because it was back crossed
three or four times um i can't remember
what the claim was from seoul but it was
all [ __ ] anyways but
in a sense in a sense you don't want to
take a line that has
[ __ ] a thousand phenos and try to
cube it you're not gonna get anywhere in
four steps back
to isolate all the traits like that and
a lot of people confuse that cubing
isolate a few traits crossing forward
isolate multiple traits
that's that's really the the best way i
can describe it
um that kind of ends most of the
questions i think for this week there's
a few we didn't get to urkel is potent
no
i don't think urkel is super potent
but other people might think so i
definitely think it's one of them
i think it's one of the more potent
purples but i would not put it up
against the more i would not even
remotely it wouldn't be in my top 10 or
even 20
uh most potent strains that i've tried
it's one of the top 10 that will
instantly give me paranoia any time
i mean you know
it's just the way it goes with my brain
yeah there's a guy there's a there's a
gentleman asking about do you think
landry seeds are still good at the
source
um you know i don't know anything about
those guys but i certainly
support people going around in
afghanistan and pakistan
is he talking about a specific company
or is he talking about i think there's a
company called land race seeds that yeah
that brings stuff over from afghanistan
and pakistan
um
it's not that easy for white people to
go there and collect things right now
and when we went to war with them for a
couple decades and so it's a little
sketchy with the taliban and stuff and
so the fact that you have people that
are going to collect and send seeds i
don't know what will come of it but it's
definitely an access point um and we'll
go from there
uh
you know and uh
the difference in early colombian haze
i think the difference in early
colombian haze and why it was better was
it was just raw crosses and less inbred
i think there was a lot of mistakes made
in the 70s on accident as people learned
they didn't use large enough population
sizes i think it's been documented
that a lot of the best phenos that the
haze guys liked started disappearing in
the mid to late 70s because they made
some some poor choices with selections
and they weren't sure what they were
doing
um you know the south indian stuff has
kind of been debunked now sam is saying
that it was always colo by colo
yeah which is colombian by colombian
he's saying that the this four-way blend
is a bunch of bunk
uh and it's not true
um so
uh i can't i can't speak to that
um
so i don't know you know i mean here we
are as that's basically the
end of the questions there's
you know there's a guy that said that
mexico is north america
uh i'm aware that uh that uh that they
don't consider central america a
continent but since the question was
asked about what came from central
america that was beneficial
you know if people are talking about
central america it's pretty much panama
to mexico
i realize it's all either north or south
america as the way that uh geography
would work i was just trying to answer
the question
the durbin stuff we're going to ignore
simply we have some stuff coming up that
i think will shed a lot more light on
the durbin thing next week and so i
don't want to chat on that
two weeks
two weeks something like something
relatively close there'll be some really
good
new information
i think we can talk about it now since
it's most of it's in the can um is that
you want to talk about it real quick
just plug it yeah
we could plug it really quick so um
you know we uh we we were blessed and we
have been able to interview
um
the
the founder of super sativa seed club uh
and um as part of our like 80s breeding
program neville's obviously passed so we
weren't able to interview him but you
know neville and super sativa seed club
were the two largest ones
and we have a quite long interview
coming that we're going to be giving
some context to where we asked him a
bunch of questions about some very
famous trains what it was like back then
um a lot of cool stuff a lot of stuff
that surprised even matt and myself uh
new information he was super engaging
and cool
uh i'm really excited about it we gotta
edit it a little bit in various ways
just for uh you know but um
there's a lot of myth busted there's a
lot of there's a lot of stuff that's
going to come out that's super neat
there's a lot of stuff that's going to
come out that
you know
that might make people sad or flip some
stories that have been kind of accepted
on their head
um
you know i think uh
the durbin thing is interesting you know
um you know and so we'll we'll sort of
save that that for that but uh the
durban story is a little wider than we
once thought
let's put it that way so yeah we do have
that interview coming it should be great
he was super cool to chat with us uh
he'll really flesh out what life was
like back then and what breeding was
like and he was one of the two biggest
seed banks in the world in the 80s
so we're really excited to be able to
bring that stuff to you guys in the near
future
um
you know and uh
you know so
i don't know that kind of like that kind
of takes us to uh
um
that kind of takes us to sort of the end
of like our arc here we answered a bunch
of questions
i don't know
yeah uh again
you want to want to be a part of this
you want to be a part of some of the
research we're doing if you want to see
a lot of the like i i a lot of people
know i collect a lot of old stuff you
know like old cannabis memorabilia um i
post a lot of the shots from those books
in there like as i come across them cool
[ __ ] that adds to the history of
cannabis
we have
a depository we're working on with a lot
of old catalogs a lot of old magazines a
lot of old books that are inaccessible
to most people
um we also have the merch up again uh
you can click buy syndicate merch um
right under
one of our heads
and uh it should take you there and you
can buy a hat shirt anything that helps
support us this [ __ ] costs money to do
and we're actually like i just bought a
new mic that i couldn't use this time
and a few other things so it does cost
money the more you support the more we
can do and the more we're appreciative
and we can do more giveaways and cool
[ __ ] so yeah let's just throw some one
basic plug is that uh you know if you
guys can't figure out how to join you
can always send a
a
dm to matt or myself on ig or readers
or breeder syndicate will share the link
uh that'll take you right to where you
need to be uh you know we have our own
like we have our own chat in there where
you can ask us questions all the time
and we we chop it up with people on a
much more regular basis
uh our point to all this is to get
information out there and talk about the
stuff that interests us
so
um yeah if you can't find it for some
reason give matt or myself a shout and
we'll send you a link and point you in
the right direction
and i hope everybody enjoyed uh
listening to a longer
um a longer thing and just hit us up and
we'll see you guys there
um as someone said not so accept my
follower or have three years bad luck
uh dm me on on ig i have i have like
over a thousand uh i have over a
thousand people waiting it's not
intentional um but if you hit me up
personally and i can chat with you for a
second i'll accept you and we'll go from
there
there's a link at the bottom that uh
breeders said to get just put up there's
the thing to pledge at if you can't uh
if you want to send us a link i'll send
you a link too and we're going to be
doing this all the time so
we're going to have some shorts coming
up we're going to have some cool
interviews with some old schoolers we're
going to have more lives that are just
like this so there's going to be some
variety and content coming
um some more interviews uh
you know
like i said some short topics some more
long-winded [ __ ] like this that's an
hour and 50 minutes long
and so we're just gonna we're gonna
start adding adding to it over time and
trying to make it cooler and hopefully
everybody enjoyed listening while
they're what they're up to
i like the uh the idea of keeping us all
on an even playing field when it comes
to information some guys like to secret
squirrel that [ __ ] others don't um
we want everyone on an even playing
field to be able to make the best weed
possible because every if everybody's
making good we can all build off each
other's [ __ ] so thank you guys for
showing up thank you very much for
showing up we really appreciate it we
all hope you have a great weekend uh
enjoy everyone
[Music]
you