[Music]
welcome to breeders syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
lived it i'm matthew owner of riot seeds
i'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
yeah i mean i can say in a general sense
i just went on a
mission looking for pockets of old
things
yeah and you found some pockets of old
things i did yeah i did yeah so
you know and that's it's kind of
interesting too because it's like one of
the one of the things about
about weed that i find really
interesting and we'll talk about this as
part of like the clone thing tonight
is that how
like brokers and the demand from the
public dramatically changes what people
grow yeah right so
in california or oregon or washington or
these places that are like really sort
of like in tune or can't sort of came
about with medical or legal earlier
there was a lot more rapid change in um
and what people grew
because of what people demanded
yeah and so in some cases now
um you know you have to go and look for
some of these i don't want to call them
backward states because that's rude but
like yeah states that were slower to
adopt
uh you know some of this stuff which
meant that people could grow things that
were a lot older and they still worked
really well for the crew that they were
giving them to
yeah because there was a lot of
competition with the new new as it were
there wasn't there wasn't pressure to
change yeah um and really you know that
it kind of ties into what we're talking
about tonight because pressure to change
and a desire to make your life easy and
give the broker what they want um is
what kind of makes uh old cuts disappear
yeah you know that is it and that's what
we're seeing today and we've talked
about the last few episodes i mean if
you would have told me 10 years ago
that uh sour real sour diesel could be
kind of hard to acquire depending
yeah
no one would believe it yeah i'm
actually shocked that lately today uh
people keep telling me that the forum
cut of cookies is becoming hard to
source which blows my mind yeah i mean
it's one of those things where you know
i've mentioned this before but
um every five or ten years weed
reinvents itself yeah i mean matt and i
matt and i looked at i have a friend up
here who got a freezer of somebody who i
know everyone talks about freezer beans
or whatever yeah but uh my friend got a
freezer of
old beans from people that was someone
that was retiring and kind of getting
out of the game right and instead of
being like from the ancient 80s or sssc
or [ __ ] that people claim it was almost
all from 2008 to 2012. yeah it was way
too cool era i reached in i reached out
to matt because i was busy having kids
and doing a bunch of sit then and that
was sort of like really your prime time
yeah
right when you were like really really
in tune with what was going on yeah and
it was it was surprising to matt and i
looking over it
just how ancient a lot of those things
were and how 99 of it was unavailable
yeah even especially the rascal stuff
like at the time was really hot selling
really well a lot of the femme stuff he
was
our main competition at the time as it
were for femme stuff and looking at it
i'm not a lot of that stuff's hard to
grab now and it's great stuff yeah a lot
of it and that's only from
you know 14 12 14 years ago yeah which
doesn't seem that long to me
it's not actually because
i you know it uh traumas are very
current
you know it always feels good yeah so
that's what that's what's interesting is
like you get back to 10 12 years ago and
and it's almost impossible to find
um a lot of seed stock from then and
then you go back 10 more years and it's
harder and you go back to the 90s and oh
my god and you go back to the 80s and
it's almost legends
yeah
you know which isn't really all that
long but the way prohibition works and
the way the market works so you know
there's people there might be people in
various states that are slow to adapt um
that have been rocking the same thing
for 20 25 years yeah because it's worked
for them
right and the little customer base that
they have that they you know that they
give their access to is super stoked on
it yeah um and you so you almost need
those pockets
um you know because like you know when
we talked about the purple episode every
big grower i knew ran some kind of gdp
urkel mendo p
um you know great yeah something hybrid
yeah
and then fast forward 10 years and like
six people held on to it
yep that's how it goes out of hundreds
just in my little area yeah
you know
and yeah there's someone that's talking
right now about oh i'm sick it has to be
purple
you know the purple craze was like i
would say it was like 030405
maybe a little bit of 06.
and then it went away for 15 years yeah
it went away for for quite a while 15 18
years or something like that and then
now all of a sudden it's back
and people are just as annoyed now as
they were back then yeah
you know
um although back then i would say
one of the biggest things about the
purple craze that i don't like
uh was it was really the first time
where
a lot of diversity got lost
because
people just wanted what the brokers
wanted to buy yeah
and so they were growing all these
different things and you know
um and then all of a sudden people are
like well i want purple
yeah
yeah a lot of beautiful beautiful green
lovely strains went by the wayside for
the the oracle days yeah and we're gonna
we're gonna talk about like old clones a
lot today and that was really one of the
eras that be that kind of ushered in
like the everybody wants to grow the
most popular thing at the time yeah
because pre-purple craze of like you
know early 2000s the amount of diversity
that worked for the small and the medium
market was pretty incredible yeah if it
was good weed it probably sold
unlike today unlike today where you do
see a lot of really good weed go by the
wayside for
stuff that maybe we would all agree
isn't
as what we would consider kind as some
of the others oh somebody just said oh
six is when i first went to reggae on
the river and the custy kids had got
purple
got purple shirts on i went to i went to
reggae on the river from i don't know
probably like 95 to 0304 i think 03 was
like their their 20-year anniversary
maybe or something like that
and uh
after going for 10 years i'd seen most
of the acts i wanted to see and it had
gotten kind of
a little hectic
yeah i kind of felt like it was more
like have a bunch of city kids show up
on the river and hope nobody dies
kind of
can you imagine reggae on the river in
bakersfield how that would go with that
there's no river there's a river here
but we didn't have we have the kern
river here which is big but we didn't
have that we what we had was called
reggae fest
and it was just i started playing those
shows in about 06 because we had the
reggae band going on at the time but it
was very different than like the steel
drum
type reggae that a lot of people had it
was just phenomenal to see what
bakersfield offers in terms of reggae
fans it was it's pretty cool i mean i
never got to go to reggae on the river
myself that's a that's a tangent but i
will talk about it just a couple of
times because when i was coming out here
in the mid 90s as a midwestern kid
reggae on the river has like two
extremely clear memories where i really
realized that like the emerald triangle
in california was a different place than
where i was from yeah um there was there
was dready kids walking around reggae in
95 96 back then it was still a two-day
it was still a two-day weekend festival
and it was a lot more locals that hadn't
had like as many like city kids and
stuff coming up from the bay yet
but people were walking around with with
five gallon buckets with spears in them
and you could buy a spear like a a spear
of wheat a top oh oh i thought you made
spirits to threat i'm like wow it's not
like that kind of spear but i mean like
for me as like someone who comes from
like a world where it all had to be
hidden
oh yeah walking up and down the lot
with a bunch of stems sticking out of a
top and pulling out an 18-inch top to
sell
that's [ __ ] awesome that was pretty
incredible and like where where reggae
used to be it's like um where the river
is you can like look up and like the 101
the highway 101 is way up there right
yeah and i remember i was like sitting
in a seat on the riverbed and i was
pulling bongs
and i looked up and there was a highway
patrol looking right at me
and so coming from the midwest like if
you make eye contact with a cop and
you're doing drugs like you're it's not
a good scene yeah no and he waved to me
and then just went back to what he was
doing
and i was like literally ready to like
throw the bong in the river and run into
the crowd yeah because that was like my
training like what i you know like you
it was time to run yeah
and he just he just gave me a wave and
and went back to what he was doing and i
was like oh my god you know
there you are you're back
yeah oh my god
so yeah i mean those are but those were
like two seminal moments at reggae on
the river that for most people might not
be that big of a deal
but it just showed like what yeah like
how different how like there was a
bubble that we lived in
you know yeah it was a bubble
that was a bubble so
i i went through and and tonight we're
gonna be might be joined by someone i'm
not sure we talked about it but as
stoners will do we just decided that uh
we'll see if he shows up you know
because you know
plans or plans and that's that's rough
even for me so we'll see if this person
shows up but um
i went through the can of bible 3
because i remember that there is a great
list in here of the the late 90s early
2000s clones
and i thought it would be fun to go
through this list together
and and there's some that i added in
there's some that i took out of their
list because they really weren't that
relevant in terms of anything they just
happened to be things that he was aware
of that he threw in the middle but um
we got it all together brynn even made
it pretty with a fish and
uh yeah whenever you want to start going
through it we can start going through it
uh
jason someone just asked jason is not
the guest no i i no one's talked to him
but um you know who knows you know i
used to be pretty good friends with him
a long time ago he would definitely be a
character to have on one day
um yeah for sure in that regard you know
yeah it would be very interesting
super opinionated i don't know maybe
he's mellowed in the last bit but uh you
know
highly opinionated he definitely oh and
that's mellow uh you know he was super
opinionated in person uh some people it
drove him absolutely nuts i can relate
that i really liked him and i liked like
his vibe and what he was trying to do
yeah yeah for sure but it's hard because
like when you're when you're so certain
about something and you don't leave room
for other people's opinions
yeah you can secretly offend a lot of
people sure which matt knows nothing
about
i wouldn't i wouldn't i'm very people
he's not he's not he's not into that
um
but uh
but yeah you know they
so just as a general sense um before we
before we you know dive into the list a
little bit um i will say that you know
like i was mentioning earlier
um
when there wasn't much weed
uh most weeds sold
yeah because it was better than mexican
that was sort of like the standard like
if it was better than green or brown
mexican it's sold
and then as
the thing matured and and like and and
and fads and waves started happening
certain popular cuts started getting you
know more in demand than others yeah but
there was this period i would say from
the mid 90s to the mid 2000s
that may have been
the greatest diversity era we've seen
and that's where most of these cuts that
matt and i are going to talk about come
from because
they came at a time when there was a lot
of seed banks starting to operate
uh in amsterdam and there was a lot of
genetics starting to get traded around
friends
and
um almost all good weed had a place
yeah
and it hadn't really it hadn't really
been like oh you you don't have sour i
don't want to buy it you don't have
purple i don't want to buy it you don't
have gelato i don't want to buy it that
hadn't happened so that meant a lot of
people
could
grow what they liked pick what they
liked and form a little vibe on it yeah
and i would honestly say that's probably
all that stuff that we're about to chat
about is probably the backbone of today
you know i would also uh put this in the
era
before og kush was readily available in
seed for everyone
that's when i noticed a big change in
whole collectives being just og kush we
want og og you're [ __ ] nothing you
know um
right before that was readily available
for everyone
i i remember i remember uh walking into
a club in in the in uh l.a
yeah seeing literally no exaggeration
like 25 different types of kush
yeah yeah and like reminders based on it
and you're like well like that's all
you're that's that's the whole thing
yeah you know
like there's nothing else
um but you know the reason why there's
financial reasons that happened uh
there's there was you know there's
various economic indicators that push
all those things
yeah you know like when i first started
coming out to uh to mendo
it was very very common to buy mixed
phenos pounds
yeah it was all the same strain right
but they were they they would blend the
different plants together
it didn't have to be like i have a 50
pack of just this one cut
that hasn't started yet but then
eventually it became it had to be this
one thing
yep
and every time that's happened even
though the purples i love the urkel and
the mendo p and stuff like that are
pretty close to my heart and i love sour
diesel
and
most of the sour diesels that people
argue about right now whether they're
real or not or most of them are good
smoke yeah og kush's are excellent smoke
i'm not as big a fan of cookies but
you know um like you know they're all
good
yeah they just they just came at a cost
of everything else
a big cost a big cost of everything else
so i don't know i don't have the list in
front of me you have in front of you i
don't know how you want to keep it in
some kind of entertaining format all
right i will just start naming and then
um let me know if you you have any
members somebody said the aoda
i don't i'm not familiar with it what's
that aota is aota
and it was all of the above
okay
uh we used to rock the aota in the early
2000s i don't know who mentioned it
um but the iota was really tasty lead
so whoever mentioned that uh super cool
that you popped that up yeah that's
something i didn't even know about i
don't think i don't think i've seen the
aota since probably
oh i don't know i don't know when the
last time i saw the oh the the toyota
but we had it in our crew i don't even
remember where it came from
to be honest
um but it was uh it was it was it was
good weed it was it was fruity
and uh it was it was really tasty
okay so i keep remembering little ones
to add in as i'm going through this but
i'll start at the top afgooey which
predictably was going to be one of them
do you have experience with the apko
uh
you know a lot of people liked the af
gui
i sort of thought it was blandish
you probably smoked that nasty ass
outdoor version i mean i don't know you
can talk about it then because i don't
have the greatest memories of the afgoo
so i it it was spelled so many different
ways people would spell like afkahui
f gui some people think that gooey is f
gooey uh which goes from gooey breeder i
don't know i don't have enough
experience with gooey breeders gooey um
the fbi i was familiar with was a more i
wouldn't say short but yes it was it was
more squatter than most uh
uh plants you people are used to dealing
with it has this beautiful almost
watermelon blueberry type terp that was
very hard to describe and it was true
breeding for it um almost everything i
crossed it to or that it was crossed in
took on the af gooey smell and i could
see how people could get very
overwhelmed by it because it's very
distinctive
you could also describe as like
cantaloupe berry it was it was unique
and i i tended to love it it would pass
on beautiful resin traits uh had good
potency not the best yield but
i think overall
uh it's one of my faves off this list oh
there you go i was going to dis it
slightly because i know i just saw a
bunch of
lo of midi midzie before we called
things mids uh
midzie outdoor
yeah and i i would think it could be
very midi outdoor it was not that it was
not i never saw the greatest examples
but then there you go you know yeah
um how about i have no experience with
real albert walker but i did get the
[ __ ] fake albert walker have you grown
albert walker i don't know that i grew
the real albert albert walker but i do
think that was a pretty flavorful and
potent cut
yeah
i know fletch has a lot of familiarity
with it fletch would be an excellent
person to chat about the history of it
that's one that like
not
my none of my old crew
uh or really had any access to it you
know yeah i think there was one friend
of mine that might have been growing it
for a bit but it wasn't it wasn't too
much
okay um now this is one that a lot of
people are familiar with from um
oh what the [ __ ] dutch flowers their
work with it the blue dot
oh
i know there was two the blue dot uh i
am familiar with that that stuff there
was this guy
oh my god does he go by crunch bubble
uh
there was a guy on the forums you could
probably search for him or whatever and
uh the blue dot was one of the big
strains that used to get pushed through
grown in oakland a lot and it was pushed
through one of the early uh dispensaries
that we called the third floor that's
what it was third floor third floor
which was a pretty famous dispensary
back then in the east bay
um a lot of people got their purple cuts
from the third floor they were very tied
into my area to humboldt and and mundo
and stuff like that they got a hold of
like the the granddaddy and the urkel
and stuff like that and yeah crunch
bubble from icmag he used to blow up
tons of blue dot back in the day
um it was a nice cut i never ran it
personally but there it was like it was
one of those like bay area specials yeah
it really got rocked a lot um and i
think it was part of blow fish
that guy used to send it you know you
know you have like 40 lighters or
whatever and yeah early warehouses with
like do you remember like all the old
like
skinny rectangle sunlight hoods oh yeah
you know with like the with the single
ended 600 watt hortolux hell yeah you
know and like the trays and all that
like that was like cutting edge at the
time yeah um but you know he had some
you know pretty good-sized scenes or
whatever that and and there was like a
huge demand for blue dot yeah so
i don't have a bunch of personal
experience growing it but i mean i would
get bags of it on occasion going to the
bay
um and it was definitely like it was a
bay area classics yeah for a period of
years
yeah uh someone just said i do think
that green crack is a pheno of skunk one
um
you know at least it's it's heavily in
there
yeah
and put it that way
yeah i could see that definitely i mean
the mango that loud mango turp i usually
associate with skunk one touch stuff as
it is
um
blue
[ __ ] dream
blue dream
so blue dream is one of those things
that has a bad reputation
um
mostly because
uh
anything that could get eight to ten
pounds at you know five let's say five
to ten pounds be a little bit more
generous anything that could get five to
ten pounds
outdoor reliably
um got blown up in my neck of the woods
and so if you to me if you grow blue
dream in like a little pot and you get
like a four to eight or ten ounce plant
or something it's really flavory and
really pretty wheat
yeah but most people's opinion of blue
dream is this giant outdoor
sort of b grade maybe poorly dried
um you know rock hard buds the terps
aren't really there
um but you know it kind of got famous
because
um
you know people used to call it blue
dream billionaire right where back when
weed was worth a lot you could put out a
99 blue dreams and get 700 pounds
yeah
[Music]
that's sweet [ __ ] yeah so there's it's
there's this run with blue dream green
crack even my maui a little bit
where
um it's really big yielding
and then most people smoke the big
yielding stuff
and don't smoke like the little more
carefully grown nicer versions
yeah so their memory of it is uh
is just the big blown out crazy nugs
that are b grade
so another thing that i remember with
blue dream during that era was that a
lot of people when it first popped off
were growing one cut there was one blue
dream cut that was going around it was
pretty pretty well um
passed out like people a lot of people
had this cut was being blown out of
collectives and it was pretty damn i
mean good for the time it was very
resonance had good potency good yield um
didn't mold up too easy none of the
stuff that you know would normally keep
stuff down but after that big huge first
push seed lines were released named blue
dream by emerald triangle seeds i think
hso put out a blue dream and those
quickly quickly were picked up and run
and those cuts were passed as blue dream
and the original cut was quickly drowned
out by um
other blueberry haze type combos
i do think that that thing that matt
just described is actually a common
thing
that can happen to certain strains where
a strain gets named something
uh then it gets named and put into a
seed line
and then there's all these phenos
floating around that aren't the original
cut that made it famous yes
um you know so there was a bunch of
different blue dreams it was supposedly
blueberry by some kind of haze
um it was a super so the original cut
was super silver haze crusty dj short
blueberry yeah and and so
you know they uh but you know like i
said if you grew
if you grew like a little six or seven
ounce plant of that thing in your light
depth or your greenhouse or your indoor
it was really nice weed
yeah it was i like it i i still like it
our buddy pat works with it currently he
did the blue dream train wreck hybrid
for all of us older heads that's like
phenomenal and cool
yeah i mean
yeah good
uh i was just gonna say that you know uh
the first time i really showed my face
on any of these things was when our
buddy uh csi asked me to do an event
that he was throwing up in humboldt and
i went and i was on a panel with
him and um uh you know me and jean and
kevin jodry and just different folks you
know yeah um and he talked about like
you know train wreck
for northern humboldt was one of like
the first
named cuts
you know the rap
yeah the wreck
so there's a lot of legends with the
wreck because it was uh
it was you know it was
i don't know if i don't know if santa
cruz original haze that's a whole
different movie uh
super silver hayes is a much much uh uh
changed child of haze
i see i think what select genetics 2 is
referring to is again there were several
different seed lines uh unknown
undisclosed haze so most people would
agree that that blue hen from um what
are they called can
kentucky see i can't remember off the
top of my head but blue hen was the
super silver haze 98 blueberry probably
where it was selected from um but it was
also widely grown other
than that under the name blue pen as
well but the very first santa cruz cut
blue dream which still exists is a super
silver haze cross that's the one we're
referring to specifically and it's tasty
not everybody likes the high um
and if you grow it too big it definitely
is shitty but i think that's true of a
lot of weed there's a sweet spot of
yield and quality
yeah you know bluegrass seed there you
go thank you cameron bluegrass yeah
there's a there's definitely a sweet
spot it's not all the same sweet spot
with strains but there's definitely a
point of diminishing returns as you get
bigger and bigger plants where it just
doesn't give you as nice of weed yeah
you know so next would be bubble gum
bubble gum i am i i did i had a lot of
experience with a lot of other bubble
gums in the seed line but this specific
clone i didn't get until a few years ago
and i find it phenomenal it's an amazing
breeder uh it's mold resistant this
specific cut that csi and pip and all
those guys use came via 1995 from the
cup i believe it was bought the same
year that it won the cup so uh that's
that's what goes around it's a serious
it's a selection from series seeds
bubble gum the bummer for me
it's a great breeder yeah it's very
frosty yeah that's fairly potent i
wouldn't say it's uh
i wouldn't say it's up there with the
best of the best but it's got it's got a
good little punch
uh the disappointing thing about it to
me is that it smells
very strongly of bubble gum terps yes um
but the flavor does not translate for me
not even a little bit yeah i don't you
don't get any it doesn't it smells like
you're smelling big league chew yeah but
it doesn't smell like you're chewing it
doesn't feel like you're chewing big
league chew when you smoke it yeah but
it's a great breeder it's super
consistent it's one of the most mold
resistant things out there
um it's a cool plant yeah yeah arrowhead
hemp farms yes indiana is serious seeds
it is a serious seed selection though a
lot of people put the indiana bubblegum
as the mother of serious seeds that they
use but that's not the case it was
actually a selection from their uh
seedline and if we want to go even back
further there's you know adam dunn has
this whole thing about where it came
from
um you know neville felt like they just
stole it
from
working with him yeah and renamed it
that it was it was some big buzz it was
some combination of stuff that he was
already working on yeah um you know um
so there's there's dispute over where
where where it came from yeah and that
happens a lot where people try to
obscure origins
yeah definitely that's a common thing
you know so
all right i see full writer in the
comments everybody wants to hear bull
rider and do it i i hate to break it to
you guys bull rider was before my time
it was before my time by the time i got
to san diego bull rider was r.i.p
[ __ ] nothing the only thing you could
find was afghani bull rider which there
is no proof evidence anyway the afghani
bull riders related to the original bull
writer it's very different um well betsy
is said to be a sister original writer
what's up we still have uh old betsy
still exists
and is still held and run by multiple
friends and
crew
um and it's supposed to be a sister of
the original bull liar i don't know that
matter i know anyone that has original
bull rider that we believe
not that we're sure of but old betsy
exists and who knows it could exist
outside of our
our experience
it definitely could exist but i haven't
seen it a lot of people made uh
a lot of claims about it recently but
none holed up and most are
based on the afghanistan maybe i should
say something just real quick one time
when i was in chicago
uh before i moved to california i saw
some bubble gum
that they had bought from out there and
brought back and it had
hot pink hairs and was lime green
um and was super gorgeous
i never really saw it again i only saw
it a few times who knows who was growing
it back then but i did see
a very cool version of it a long time
ago uh when sirius first released it
yeah
so um yeah that we went through bull
rider bubble gum
banana oh gee do you have any i know
you've grown banana og do you have any
uh memorable experiences with it i do
actually think that
you know a lot of these things
especially in dessert and uh and fruit
names now annoy the [ __ ] out of me
because they have no relation what
they're marketing
they have no relation to whatever they
name them after but i do think banana og
does have a little bit of banana terp to
it yes
you know i i will say that i will say
it's it does have i get a banana sense
when i smoked it
uh it's an odd og i don't really know
what to make of it
um the oregon kid or somebody like that
made it famous it's not really my
background on that one so banana og came
from a pack of ogiers kush his original
release of what he wanted to be the ogco
seedline um
no chiquita banana is not the original
game way later and as a rename um so he
got it as
uh
the og kush
the the clone that he had and he got he
selected a male from
some
i think it was an indoor
um 60 40 from segrematha which meant 60
sativa 40 indica i remember that line
yeah yeah he popped those and i've asked
um tony from sacramento what it was and
he said it was just something he bought
in bulk from someone he didn't know it
was just labeled 60 40 so he knew
exactly what it was so anyways whatever
was in the 60 40 kicked whatever would
be true for these banana terps so he
released ogier's cush expecting it to be
a good version of og kush and that's
where people found this beautiful clone
that was very banana like and later on
you know as people pop more seeds more
people found different clones they would
call banana og there's one that
circulates right now that most people
have is the same one and it's very good
there's a few more that are more laffy
taffy like artificial banana type and
that's what you smell um i've smelled
one banana hybrid from um
pico our buddy and it smelled like
[ __ ] banana bread like just dead on
like that banana cinnamon it's one of
the most amazing banana smelling things
that i've ever smelled so i'll throw in
something that's uh
kind of related um
you know
before uh there used to be in the in the
40s 50s and 60s
um the banana the banana that everyone
ate was a different banana fino that you
eat then you eat now yeah and it was
destroyed by root fungus
right it had a much different flavor
than the current banana that everybody
has grown up with but what's interesting
is kind of how banana candy tastes a
little different than you would expect
it to taste
like it's banana but it like it's kind
of you think of it as like candy candy
banana yeah
that flavor was was developed off the
first bananas that were commercially
sold in america
yeah
and they didn't change it
you know
yep right there
there you go the cavendish
the so most banana candy is based on the
flavor of the cavendish banana not the
modern banana that everybody is used to
eating
and you know i actually owe a great deal
of my career to the banana og and some
of oregon kids stuff and uh tony from
sacramento stuff it still lives on today
and a lot of strains that i work with
and the others work with so banana og is
the [ __ ] i think i like it though i will
say in a lot of outcrosses depending on
what you cross it to there are phenos
that are just straight cardboard and
they're hard to dodge um
but that clone stands the test of time i
think for sure it's a it's a good one it
kind of got buried a little bit and it
got lost amongst other things but it's
it's a it's a cool unique terp and it
had a nice buzz yeah
so you know
here's a fun one that that
probably is is actually several
different different clones or seed lines
hold on one second
these guys are correct actually the
cavendish replaced the
i was off the top of my head they're
talking about which banana cultivars
existed and i got it reversed uh okay so
the cavendish was the first and the uh
the cavendish is now and it replaced
this thing i don't know how to pronounce
it but it was like gross macau or
something like that
so
yeah someone keeps asking about the
chiquita that was the chiquita banana
was uh popped from the platinum banana
og kush which was a hybrid of bubba kush
something in banana og
and it came i mean that was so much
later because it was from my work and it
was later
like
seven years after i made the platinum
banana og and my work was so much later
after oregon kid did so no it's it
they're very different but um the
chiquita banana is based on it but has a
lot more in it
okay what's next
cat piss again
many many different clones i think i saw
several in san diego
called cat piss that were very different
from each other some i didn't smell any
cat piss in some people did
what's your experience uh well i'll say
a couple things uh one is that you know
i think that it's one of those aspects
of smell that people relate stuff to
so i think it's like i think it's like a
i think it's like how some people
perceive certain kinds of terpenoline
yeah right
um and since terpenoline is kind of a
common aroma that pops up i think
there's more than one cat piss
uh and i do believe we're going to have
uh sha bud on the on the program next
week
in the next couple of weeks and so we
could probably save the deep dive into
cat kiss for him
because that is one of his specialties
and he knows an enormous amount about
the history and he's tried all the
different ones there was the san diego
cat piss
there was a pittsburgh cat piss
um there was different types yeah um you
know but uh you know so there were there
was a few different names
yeah one second i'm bringing in someone
if he wants to
see how he's doing
all right what is cheetah piss who
[ __ ] knows
this is so other than having the name
piss in it
um you know that's marketing that's like
a cookie team coming up with marketing
names cookie
never really has any names that tie to
what this strain is actually like yeah
um they definitely have a team of
marketing people
deciding what to call things
and what kind of art goes with it and
what the packaging is going to look like
and what the mylars are going to be
um so they're a very new school type of
approach to naming strains
so
it's all good gene you can text
if you so you have time uh
what's next
um someone asked if any ssh smells like
catfish yes i mean yeah that's a great
example of turpin i have that pissy
smells i have argued if you go and read
like a bunch of neville's uh old posts
on hazes he'll talk about when you
inbreed hayes all you get is a bunch of
cat piss yes
and when we in breed haze
all we get is a bunch of terpenoline
and as any breeder will tell you once
terpene becomes the dominant smell in
your strain
boy is it hard to get other smells to
pop up
yeah
you know it is very very very dominant
yeah now there's different terpenolines
they're not all the same some are sweet
some are astringent you know some are
this or that or whatever there's
definitely a range interpenaline there
but um but yeah i when whenever neville
talks about cat piss i think of of
turpentine yeah and i do too i mean i
know there's afghanis that are acrid and
ammonia type and that's what i used to
think of when people would say pissy i
would think of the acrid ammonia urea
type smells but i think a lot of people
think of terpenolamine and i just my
nose does not pick up that piss scent
from tropinally and then when you you
know the other part of it is like once
you when you grow or you smoke c5 or
something like that and it's just a
terpenoline monster yeah and he refers
to it as very cat pissy
yeah then obviously that's what his mind
goes to
yeah
you know
so
okay um next the cheese
the cheese so
the cheese has a pretty cool story yeah
it might be the oldest skunk one fino
that's spread around
yeah it's supposed to be from the late
80s
it's supposed to be popped by sort of
like a bunch of
would you call them punk anarchist
squatters
supposed to be i don't know much about
the crew i thought they were supposed to
be ravers or some electronics same thing
yeah same thing yeah you know i mean
when anarchists you know like punks
uh underground weirdos listening to
unpopular music yeah you know yeah type
of thing but skunk but it was a phenom
of skunk one and most skunk one
uh is
citrus or floral
uh sometimes grape
uh
never skunk
and the rarest would be probably the
kind of a funky cheese yeah
aroma yeah and so there's a sister of it
supposedly called psychosis yeah which
is not nearly as circulated uh you know
the english are all big on it because
it's one of the few things that actually
originated from their island
yeah the blues livers psychosis and
there's another one too that they always
used to talk about and and i really i'd
love to grow them one day but i have
never been um
where i could get it from uh
from a source with provenance i've only
gotten it from like seed lines or you
know and it's one of those cuts that
different people give different names to
like the bright side cut or the this
yeah that cut you know that kind of
thing
but it's basically
it's basically a classic skunk one yes
yeah you know um the other thing i
will say about is i learned a lot from
that cut
a huge amount from that [ __ ] cut i
learned that it was one of those cuts
that like early on growing it it was
really foot funky cheese for me so as i
got it later and it was fruity and sweet
i was like no wait this is a this is a
[ __ ] fake cut [ __ ] this thing this is
not what i remember and it was one of
those cuts that really taught me um
yeah yeah people are talking suicide cut
there's like any like a lot of old
famous strains
um you know i'll use a different example
i mean in my lifetime i've watched the
chem dog get called chem dog we
shortened it to dog
our buddy came online and it became the
skunk va cut it got called the chem 91
um you know different cuts that are the
same
the same cut can get different nicknames
and different different things over time
with different crews yeah
you know
exodus suicide bright side
you know all these different things um
they're all you know
there's like there was like a small
little family that came out of this late
80s english scene
you know
so um and you know it's it's it's skunk
one it breeds really well for calyx you
know you know better it improves
leafiness makes less leafiness makes
long running colas it's mildly potent i
would say i'd say most cheap most skunks
are in like the
mid teens
in terms of in terms of thc
you know gets big
a little metallic maybe i don't know
yeah
um someone mentioned one that we
actually i should have put on the list
but i didn't and that's blackberry
do you did you ever have any experience
with blackberry up there not blackberry
kush but just blackberry uh
we had more with blackberry kush
although i always thought it was just
blackberry and people added kush to it
because at the time all these brokers
wanted cush so it's like here's your
purple kush
yeah um the original blackberry was a
lot different from the the blackberry
kush the blackberry kush was a white
rhino bubba hybrid from oregon kid um
the original blackberry was from um a
dude named soma blaze if i remember
correctly scott soma blaze and he ended
up passing away naboo ended up
kind of carrying on the torch of it and
you know there were a lot of beautiful
pictures i think in one of these can of
bibles if i can pull it up super fast
has a beautiful picture of it there's a
real famous picture of it inside of a
jar of um like blackberry preserves
uh that was really famous of it um
at the time there wasn't a lot of
colored weed
so it stood out very much so
and and it was it was used a lot in a
lot of the hybrids that were famous from
that point on um
because it bred true for whatever its
purple traits were um for a long time it
you know people thought it was different
from the mendo perps but i think later
on people realized that there was a good
chance it was a a bad seed for mendo
perps and i think that's kind of where
we're at with oh man if nebu had a
voodoo doll right now you'd be i know
the jungler
but it does seem like the timeline
uh is is correct yes you know the one
thing i'll say about the blackberry
whether it was blackberry or blackberry
kush
um both of them were pretty weak
potency-wise yeah hella mitsy fam
i don't know i wouldn't say midzie but
not potent
no i yeah it was very hard to get high
from that stuff you know
if that was the only thing in your jar
you better have a light potency a light
tolerance i should say if you want to
get anywhere on it for me yeah yeah
for me too and and yeah blackberry kush
especially i had a very hard it was
beautiful too because it was super
resinous and it was one of those things
that i always put in my head
as like that was some beautiful looking
weed and when you pick it up you see all
that resin it was the it was the it was
the [ __ ] that taught me pretty [ __ ]
frosty weed doesn't necessarily mean
you're gonna get [ __ ] up for me uh
blackberry kush was the kind of thing
that brokers would come up here and
freak out on and buy a [ __ ] ton of
yeah once
yeah once yeah and then they wouldn't
they wouldn't move it they were like no
i got way too many complaints it was too
like people want to get high
and some people are comparing it to
purple punch but um
purple punch has i think personally
great terps and i would say blackberry
kush really was not on the great terp
range no and we didn't even call there
was no terps then that was even that was
even before most uh the the revolution
of hashish that happened again with all
the nails and all that so it never got
the it never really got the
i don't know it was it was bumped in
mendo for a time but yeah yeah whatever
okay here's your your your favorite
cam dog
i think we started covering some of it
so go ahead the camera dog you know yeah
i mean you know it was uh it's one of
those things where it's been talked
about tons by various people myself uh
our buddy skunk va and all that
um i would say that the best thing you
could say about chemdawg is that it is
it's got rare potency
uh very rare potency and the potency
tends to be dominant and translate into
lots of hybrids that you make with it
so it makes up for be and strangely it
doesn't look very resinous uh it's not
very pretty it sort of looks to me like
ancient um
it's you know it's like some kind of
ancient ugly afghan yeah i think it's
hideous and in like i see the skunky a
crazy composer those two can make that
[ __ ] look so pretty i i don't know how
they do it but most grows like even
micros of it i see it is just
cannibalizing its own leaves oh it does
i mean that that actually sour does the
same thing as that and that's kind of
why i think but they um there's an
aspect to that where a lot of i'll say
this and this might piss some people off
or whatever but uh
there's a lot of people that are taking
we would always take the the dog to like
say 10 weeks
yeah right and that's when we kind of
somewhere between 65 and 72 or 73 days
depending on how long you could let it
rock you know yeah and uh
you know it would test somewhere between
you know 18 and 22 or 23 then but it
knocked your head off yeah and then when
all this testing [ __ ] came into
effect they realized that that was too
low
yeah and so some people started cutting
it at like 53 54 days and you can see
white hairs all over it but it'll test
at 29
yeah and then so the grower gets to grow
it quicker and turn it quicker
and then the dispensary is happy because
it gets to put this high thc label on it
and a lot of people end up on the legal
market these days buying premature chem
dog in my opinion yeah
yeah i don't care
i care what it does to my head yeah
yeah so
it would be nice if it had flavor too
that helps sometimes this is what i'll
say sometimes and this is just my
personal opinion sometimes
chem dog has amazing flavor
yeah really deep flavor that i love and
i can smell it in the weed and it and
that smell translates
and like i grow chem dog all the time
and maybe one or two rips a year
it gives me that flavor
yeah
and i have tried a million different
ways to figure out whether it's heat
whether it's newt whether it's this
whether it's that i've grown salt i've
grown it organic i've grown it every
which way you can imagine
yeah it's just finicky sometimes it
gives me the flav sometimes
the potency is almost always there
yeah it's it it the potency and the high
is pretty is pretty standard
yeah the closest i've seen of that chirp
extreme was from and i always talk about
this but like it i
like i didn't get the love for chem 91
or the dog as you guys called it until i
smoked a chem 91 hybrid that he had made
that was very chem 91 dominant in the
terp but it was just turned to a 10. i
imagine it's probably how chem 91 was
when you guys first started growing it
and
i understood the love for it after that
because that that turk profile is
[ __ ] nice and it's very unique i've
never smelled anything close to it it uh
it's in there it's just hard to coax out
and it does do this thing where
you can grow it perfectly organic or
chem what you know whatever you want to
do and a lot of the times it'll get this
leaf rust and it'll start cannibalizing
its leaves and it'll start dying i'll
start looking like [ __ ]
yeah um the bud itself usually stays
perfectly fine yeah
you know but uh but yeah it's rough i
see i see a lot of those endless white
pistols on it too just like no matter
what people do it just will keep
throwing white
or stigma so i'll throw i'll throw out
something interesting when you used to
grow it under like hortolox or your
standard whatever yeah it would take 80
it would take 70 like i said 68 72 days
something like that right yeah i grew a
bunch of my favorite head stash under
pure ceramic metal halides like a blend
of the 31 and the 42
and the dog [ __ ] got done two weeks
earlier yeah and i pulled the chem the
chem 91 at 87 days and it still had
white hairs all over it yeah so it did
this weird thing where the spectrum made
this sativa finish two weeks faster than
i'm used to
yeah and then made the dog go two and a
half weeks longer than i've ever seen it
and it still wasn't done that's super
weird who the [ __ ] knows why that is you
know yeah but yeah i mean i've been i've
been growing it since 1998 it's one of
my favorite strains so i usually have
one or two at least going for head yeah
so i've grown it a lot
okay next up your second favorite maybe
ken deep
kim d yeah
uh chem d chem d is cool you know uh
chem d has a different high than chem 91
it's prettier it's frostier much
prettier it smells people's
call it you know i don't like the way
you call it roadkill or dead bodies or
some kind of like decrepit funk i i
always refer to it as like bad breath to
me but what's weird about it is that i
can crack a jar six feet away from
someone and they'll be like who's got
the skunk
yeah but i've also smelled baby [ __ ]
come out of it like pure putrid baby
[ __ ] but so it has a lot of expressions
yeah but then you get close to it and
you can't smell that skunk yes you just
smell the putrid yes you know
um and i think i think it's a i think
it's a i think it's a hybrid honestly uh
this might get me in trouble but i think
it's a hybrid of chem 91 and uh super
skunk yes um and i think the super skunk
gives it its frost and its color it even
herms kind of like the super skunk did
yeah um and like i said uh the chem 91
throws that crazy potency
yeah um so it's a short squat afghan i
would also say that uh there's three or
four fakes that float around yes um and
those fakes tended to get
trade baited a lot more than the
original cut so matt was talking about
how certain cuts got buried by the wave
of what came after
yes lots and lots of people have fake
chem d
everybody wanted d but not everybody had
access to d but there was always a bunch
of people willing to to to pass around
fake versions of it for a little bit of
tinga you know so well and there's this
thing too where it's like when i say
trade baiting what matt and i mean when
we talk about trade baiting is some
people would go after cuts just to get
certain things to be able to trade them
for other things yes so like there was
people like myself or skunk va or others
that held on onto the the chem d and had
them and there's different people that
had it and they held it kind of tight
and then there were some people that got
it just so they could use that cut to
unlock a bunch of other cuts they wanted
to get access to yes so they spread out
and it just so happened that they got
some fakes
and even like some pretty reputable
people that like are supposed to know a
bunch got faced yeah so it was it was
out there there was a bun there's a
bunch of people and it can be really
hard to tell in the bag
what you know they look very similar
side-by-side grows usually show you and
to me the real d like it has a potency
and a flavor the other ones don't
yeah
so there you go on that one
i have no idea someone just said i have
no idea if the gmo was made with the
real camp i mean gmo was made in spain i
think so i'm very doubtful that it was
used it's a great gmo is a great cut on
its own so yeah just kind of irrelevant
in the sense that it works good it
yields good it smokes good it
wash is good so you know it's a good cut
yeah um and i i always like when i
categorize it in my head i always refer
to like the candy i remember it as the
more cushy looking one by its nature how
it stacks and everything and the chem 2
i always remember as the most cushy of
the bunch it was more like little tiny
nugs looking at all if i'm being real i
think there's there's chem 91 in both
sour diesel and in chem d
yeah and chem d is sort of like a squat
afghan version
and sours are sort of like a tall lanky
colombian
uh skunk type version yeah
that's my that's my view okay chem dog
number four
chem dog number four is cool
uh it's probably the most widely
circulated
chem
yeah uh i would say i didn't see a lot
of fake cuts ever
there's not really fake cuts it yields
like a champ
um
and uh
it it reminds me a lot of nl5 haze
yes
um our buddy pip who we joke loves to
take everything 12 weeks no matter how
long it's supposed to take
um i had him take a really nice nug of
chem 4 and put it on top of a picture of
neville's 1989 nl5 haze
i have it on my phone i can't you know
and but it's like it really is a dead
ringer yeah um and i if i smoke enough
chem d
or a chem 4 i get like a raciness in my
chest
yeah it has long running buds it's much
taller
uh the only thing i'll say about it is
that uh it takes probably 12 weeks
and a lot of people cut it at 10. yeah i
think a lot of people were cutting it at
eight to nine like in california so
there's a there's a lot of chemd that
doesn't make the cut um because most
people don't want to take it that full
12 weeks
i like that quote the blue dream of gas
yes yeah but if you if you take if you
take the chem 4 84 days or something
like that and you grow it nice it's it's
really nice yeah and i would say no chem
4 is probably one of the furthest from
the original um it looks like nothing it
looks nothing like uh the the chem 91
actually chem 1 is probably the furthest
from the original but kim ford
definitely is very far from it indeed
yeah um
uh let's see
we don't have to do the kim sister s1
specifically let's do um we can do the
kim sis real quick okay go ahead uh the
kim sis is dead
yes um it exists in a couple of s ones
one of them is called the bundy cut yep
uh one of them got traded as chem d all
over the place
uh mislabeled
my buddy that i always call staten
island
confirmed that greg had both the sis and
the dog
in the early 90s yeah and he chose not
to bring the sis west because he didn't
like the high and it was ugly as [ __ ]
yeah
so there you go yeah that's that's good
history on it you know
um
uh cherry slider do you have an
experience with cherry slider no
it came from a dude named skitty um it
was it was from the early boards um
i wasn't a big fan of it very leafy
somebody just asked what does the chem
sis skunk va uses i think he uses the
bundy cut
which is a chem sis s1
uh i talked to greg about the chem sis
because it since it never came west uh
with my buddy i never really had a bunch
of
access to it or anything and he told me
as far as he knew the original was dead
and there was only some bag seeds that
existed so
be that as it may
all right um you ever [ __ ] with
chocolate trip
no
no okay that was a dutch flowers cut
um the one i grew is the one a lot of
people grew and i thought it was like a
c99 probably but no one's ever said that
like i've never talked to anybody about
it so maybe i'm just [ __ ] stupid one
thing i'll say about dutch flowers
is that i've always i've always i've
said a bunch on this show that i thought
that weed wasn't ready for modern day
marketing techniques yeah because we're
a bunch of like half autistic weirdos
that hide out with plants but
um you know
dutch flowers in the forum days
they wrote beautiful
ad copy oh the best i mean you would
read their metal haze or their chocolate
trip or they're this or that and you'd
read it and they would get people so
hyped for their drop
just paragraph upon paragraph of
gorgeous writing about what the weed was
like
yup and people would get so [ __ ]
excited about every single dutch flowers
drop
yep uh and you know
yeah they they did well with let's get a
professional ad guy in here and evoke
some language
yeah they used language very well
they sure did i collected their stuff
heavily and even after i found out like
by growing a bunch of it that it was
really it was either just stuff renamed
or just not very
interesting you know um people are
asking questions real quick that that
are going way too fast
so i'm apologize if your question
doesn't get picked up because we're
trying to chat and whatnot
um
but i will say someone just mentioned
pot of gold pot of gold was a uh
um
pot of gold and uh was it was one of my
favorite probably my favorite thing that
came from
the flying dutchman
and it was a hindu kush by skunk one
yeah it was a very very flavorful strain
i liked it a whole bunch they also had
this other thing called the real mccoy
which was a hawaiian by scott and they
might be on the list but there's a it
was a hawaiian by skunk one that was
also super good
um i liked both of those a bunch and
then the final good question i thought
was gravity from neville
um
we think although we're not sure
it seems like gravity is unreleased
versions of black domino
uh so black domina was a scentsy release
it was um hash plant by nl1
by uh garlic
yeah but he had a few different versions
that he made before he released it and i
think gravity is one of the two
unreleased versions
uh yes metal haze is one of the dutch
flowers ones as well uh that was
basically a skunk haze and it was
definitely one of the ones that they got
people drooling
over releasing it i grew a bunch of that
one as well but we are going in
[ __ ] alphabetical all right
i'm [ __ ] it up so whatever
you got damn pendejos so um
uh let's see
um cotton candy
cotton candy did you ever grow a cotton
candy cup i did grow a cotton candy i
wish i knew more about it
um and i actually recently grew a cotton
candy s1 through my my my buddy who
lives near me that i've traded back and
forth with for forever i don't know
anything about the lineage of the
backstory of it
um but i did like it
it was federation seeds cotton candy was
the one that i was familiar with and
like most stuff from federation there's
um a lot of
accusations of name renaming whatnot so
i'm not sure what it really is but i've
always been a big fan of it you know i
liked cotton candy i think that it'll
make a comeback one day just because
it's of its name
and it's a structure it had a good
modern look to it
yeah somebody just threw in uh uh
scentsy star genetics um luke from
paradise seeds is scentsy star
sensitizer is an amazing line
he refuses to talk any lineage or
history that i'm aware of about
specifics
of scentsy star uh matt myself our buddy
pip others have been hunting forever
for real information uh don't know
yeah yeah i i've tried recently with
luke and
and i highly respect luke like he's one
of the most respected um actual breeders
over in amsterdam by other seed makers
and breeders he's a very serious breeder
but it came from a different era where a
lot of people stole his his genetics but
he would give out testers people would
release it before he even released it so
uh yeah i would say a lot of the um
people like uh
simon from serious seeds luke uh others
they didn't see any benefit in giving
out lineage that their competitors would
just steal and claim to have the same
thing
so neville was extremely open about what
he used and where he got it and every
other dutch person after that was
tight-lipped as [ __ ]
yeah i would say that's probably
accurate right yeah that's super
accurate yeah they got they got very
tight-lipped they saw no benefit to
revealing what it was made of it was all
their secret sauce they didn't want
anybody stealing the genetics and they
didn't even want anybody writing similar
genetics on their own packaging
yeah so they just kept quiet about it so
i don't we don't know what scentsy star
is we don't know what aka is we don't
know what cali mist is please don't
is something that we have a really good
friend of ours on the discord
um that is probably more suited to talk
cough history than us
but cough is very likely an nl5 haze
fino
it came out of connecticut
in the early 90s and it made its way to
colorado most people refer to it as the
fort collins cough but it did start on
the east coast
um it's uh it's an nl fight to me it's
an it's an nl5 haze yeah it grows like
it it smokes like it it's got the buzz
like it um it's a it's one of those you
know it's one of the surviving nl5 haze
phenos in america
um there was cough one and cough two
which were hybrids of that which have
their own sort of story behind them
um he might be good maybe we'll have him
on one day to promote he breeds and does
cool [ __ ] and he's
a good friend of ours and he knows a lot
of the story
but that's the baby
he just did a um an interview with dude
grow shows
a working man where he gives the whole
history that he knows of the cough that
people want to watch it was just
recently uploaded and he's a trustworthy
character and he's had it for 20 plus
years and yeah you know he knows most of
the people involved that brought it to
colorado
so you know um it's a great cut it's one
of the survive it's i would say i've
i've said this before too but nl5 hayes
probably has the most surviving
cuts around of any 90s cross
yeah
i would say so that between europe and
here
um and that's one of them
yep
so it's a great cut yield's huge
takes a while takes 12 13 weeks
you know but there you go
um
dabney bloom did damn blue ever run up
in your area
it was it was big in san diego and it
was big in socal
but yeah that's something i know like my
my knowledge might even be negative
yeah it's it's it was an awesome cut
very frosty it had a blueberry muffin
type terp very it was more potent than
most of the blueberries that were around
so yeah um that's about all there is on
it i haven't seen it in a long time
somebody's asking about big sur holy
weed holy jesus oh yeah i guess we
didn't we didn't cover big sur hollywood
we could do a big sir holy weed that's
that's that's
i got a couple of things uh big sur holy
weed has a lot of uh there's a lot of
legends behind it it was supposedly
grown by monks in central california
um i will say that my my buddy who gave
me both the super skunk and the chem
it was his favorite weed that he could
get on dead door
and supposedly there was big sir holy
skunk and big sir holy haze oh
interesting and both were sold on dead
tour and he swears
that
big sir holy had such a unique smell
that you could have somebody walk by and
that was like the fanny pack era you
know
you could have somebody walk by and not
only could you tell that they had good
weed you could tell that they had the
big sir holy yeah
um and then there's a gut there's some
guys obviously that
brought some seeds and some stuff that
have some legend uh to it that brought
it to maybe adam dunn or somebody like
that and they had this supposedly they
mixed it into sage
um but that's
you know it's working
didn't make sage but so he wouldn't have
been told i can never pronounce this but
it's supposedly descended maybe from
purple
oh the z hots nejo purple yeah yeah and
and they also refer to it as zac attack
as purple because zakatekis is a z and
easier to pronounce but yeah it was the
zhua tanejo purple that's so the
phonics truck never stopped by my house
so i just let matt take that one because
i was gonna mangle it bad
if i tried to say it but there's a bunch
of rumors about it it's a legendary
strain one of my oldest friends uh it
was his favorite weed on dead tour and
it was sold on dead tour two different
types
yeah
yeah yeah i i don't know what's been
proven about it but it hasn't been
proven about it um i know that that's
supposedly one of the key ingredients in
scentsy star um
that was from a direct quote from adam
dunn but
thank you for what it is um
yeah you know there's the dance people
are asking a bunch of questions and
stuff like that and we're trying to go
through this stuff so you know there's
there's good questions we're not going
to get to them all which i apologize
i mean we're trying to do this in
alphabetical order or some kind of order
so if you guys are asking for [ __ ] down
in the asses it'll be a while because
like this
[Laughter]
yeah i'm determined to keep this in some
kind of [ __ ] order okay day record
diesel
uh you know i um that one has a lot of
legend to it
uh and i think because it has a lot of
legend and not a lot of like
like information
there's a lot of claims made about it
yeah
like some people refer to the day
wrecker as the first real headband
yeah although the original crew that had
the first headband never called it that
at all
yeah you know um you know it's uh you
know diesel is one of the most famous
american families
yeah and there's a lot of nicknames that
get attached to it i've never ran
anything that i thought was day record
diesel that had any kind of
um
any kind of verifiable story
yeah i i've done a deep dive and it's
actually on the breeders syndicate
youtube i believe it's up there and you
can watch it up there i recently made it
available um
i did a deep dive on trying to uh
research provenance based on internet
research on the day record diesel and i
got not very far it doesn't go back very
far but the clone's been around a long
time so it's really hard to find things
other than like some some tour manager
from grateful dead kind of gave it out
to some people and that's likely where
the where it begins the story but um it
it does appear to be some kind of chem
91 hybrid to me like chem 91 early og
type hybrid
um super nice it's really potent it's
ripping potent and breeds for that
potency i love the cut but i just don't
know if it's the original diesel like it
claims probably not
what's the next one
uh we got dog [ __ ] electric boogaloo oh
i know so okay so
uh the dog [ __ ] electric boogaloo was it
it came out of minneapolis area
minnesota in the very early 90s
it's supposed to be a nl5 haze
i wouldn't say that's a hundred percent
guaranteed it's conjecture a little bit
but boy does it really
i think it is uh it made its way to uh
oregon and got renamed dog [ __ ]
which is a shame um because it was uh
i think electric boogaloo is one of the
coolest
weed names
yeah it is um
i grow it i like it a bunch
it's uh um
you know it's a 12 or 13 week
uh sativa
very up high
uh and it kind of looks like to me like
classic 90s
northern lights uh it kind of smells
like classic 90s sweet to me yeah it's
it's it's one of the pretty if if it is
pure nl5 haze it's one of the prettier
ones as far as like visually attractive
um i've had it for a while i love it
yeah it's a great cut
great buzz highly recommend it highly
recommend the hybrids that come from it
if you can get it or get hybrids of it
uh i enjoy it quite a bit
so this is one that's totally i have no
experience with at all but you might
dumpster
uh dumpster
is
uh
supposedly the story of dumpster is that
a guy got busted
right and the cops in the 90s were
throwing
all of his equipment and his weed out
in a dumpster
and while they were upstairs [ __ ]
with it some people walked by and saw
weed plants
uh sticking out of the dumpster and
grabbed one and ran off with it
and
they named it dumpster yeah
likely story so i mean it might be real
who knows that's the story behind it
whether or not that story is true or
whether it's a tail or whatever
um that doesn't give you a lot of
information about its lineage yeah
obviously but you know
um g13 we did just a few weeks ago with
archive we just uploaded it we went into
more detail on it so we can skip over
that one for now um
the golden [ __ ] goat
i'll let you talk about the golden goat
yeah um it was made by
uh jeff mr dink from colorado if i'm
correct there was a sister cut i believe
there uh i can't remember its name the
funky [ __ ] or something
like that um i think it was a
iss romulan
island sweet skunk an island sweet skunk
was a rename of something else from
somewhere else island sweet skunk is
supposedly an nl5 haze vino
really yep 100
um i know multiple canadians that have
told me that
and uh supposedly it got renamed by mark
emery
yeah who wanted skunk seeds
to sell in his catalog um but it is
supposedly an nl5
haze fino
um you know and it was crossed to
something from uh
the one that got sold from marc emery
was crossed to something um that breeder
steve had
i can't remember i could get the story
it's not popping up in my head right on
the top of my head but that's that's
what it is yeah and they're right
actually uh mr dink was from kansas that
is correct i don't know why i said
caller it got real popular in colorado i
think maybe he moved there i might be
wrong on that but it got super popular
at colorado for a long time
and yeah island sweet scone hybrid of
steve's uh sweet skunk and that's why he
flipped out about it um sweet skunk
widow there we go sweet skunk widow iss
um
yeah i mean that's what steve says it is
and the federation supposedly changed
the name in his story
um
but yeah it was i thought golden goat
was very frosty it was a nice like
narrow leaf dominant plant i liked it a
lot um but yeah it was it was one of
those ones that got overblown in
colorado so a lot of people just kind of
[ __ ] talked it after a time but i
thought it was pretty good i thought it
was decent um
the granddaddy purple
so
granddaddy purple came about um in the
purple craze era
i would say that the probably the first
two
purple cuts that got famous right then
uh was my mendo perps and the urkel
um and then right around that same time
lavender came up there's a debate
uh between whether or not lavender was
massively different than urkel or was
just a different little fino
my buddy that i was just talking about
uh that lives over in lake county i
remember 20 22 years ago something like
that
um he had brought down the lavender
from uh
uh myers flat area of humboldt and i had
the urkel
and we like looked at it and it was like
the same it was like almost as close to
the same weed as you could imagine
yeah um yeah granddaddy purple was
supposedly that uh urkel by by big bud
um people of people have tried to push
it on that the this gentleman that
disappeared sadly a long time ago from
salmon creek that maybe it was across to
the salmon creek big bud
people that worked for him and stuff
like that said that they don't believe
that because they never saw
it
you know and why wouldn't they have it
if it came is it that chris guy yeah
chris yeah chris jackie he disappeared
in 03 or so
um he was murdered uh but they've never
found him so um it's an open case still
and um
you know so there's there's different
versions of of grant of of the origin
story i will say that the origin of
granddaddy purple the origin of urkel
uh are all very mysterious yeah there's
lots of people that have tossed their
hat into the ring
um and said various things about it oh
yeah for sure but i don't know that you
know it's one
for how popular it became
um you know it's one of the ones that
you really can't tie back to anyone um i
know some gdp stories i don't know if i
tend to believe them um but um
i'll tell it you know and people go
ahead make their decision on it so
there's this one there's this woman i'm
friends with her family
um it was pretty rare to have a pretty
woman growing up in
laytonville and and mendo area we're
kind of like furry weird hippie men to
do it you know so
someone in their 20s and 30s growing um
supposedly there was this old vietnam
vet that brought back some some seeds
from vietnam
and uh grew a bunch of hate and grew a
bunch of sativas and started mixing them
with local afghans and sort of had his
own which was really common at the time
his own
his own hill wheat
right
and then
um he was retiring uh because he'd done
really well and he gave he gave her a
few hundred seeds of his hilt hill weed
right
and um
she said that she found what what got
called the gdp in the first 50 seats
yeah right uh later on she partnered i
helped her build it actually she
partnered on a 66 lighter with uh ken
estes
yeah right i can say his full name
because he's he's well known yeah um and
she gave the cut to him
she's a super anarchist had no interest
in being public or anything like that
ken took it down to the bay and added
his name to it of course he's one of the
first people i know of that added his
name to a cut
yep you know later on other people
started doing that taking cuts that
weren't theirs and throwing their name
on it as part of claiming it yeah um and
he's given some mangled versions of that
story i just told
yeah because he didn't actually have any
part to do with the origin story he got
it from my friend
yeah and um the interview that i post
all the time of ken telling his origin
stories at first he says it was a
a skunk from a vietnam vet that quickly
turns into a native american gifted it
to him in front of a um some headlights
because he was such a wonderful white
man
um so yeah
so he turned it into a seed line that he
helpfully called ken's gdp
yep um and all that and so
um but my version of it and i knew them
at the time
was that she gave it to him
yeah and that you know and this is back
in the early 2000s or whatever when
everyone wanted to stay invisible
especially if you were running 60 70
lights and off a generator in the woods
sure and he decided to go down and flow
it into the bay and flow it into third
floor and flow it into various
dispensaries and made a name for himself
yeah
so you can choose what you want to
believe
yeah about all that
okay here's here's another one that ties
straight into it and that's great
kyle cushman's is it it was he the
inventor was it brett bogue from um
apothecary was he the inventor of the
grape vape who who is who is the creator
of great bait
this might also get me in trouble
um
but uh
so i'll say this okay and i'll just let
people decide yeah um
you know as as everyone is well aware
uh you know when things become famous
quickly one or two famous cuts start
getting renamed or hybrids or bag seeds
start getting named because there's this
there's this you know um big push to
have your own [ __ ]
yeah it happened with kush it happened
with cookie it happened with
the purple crates right
so at first there was just mendo perps
and urkel then all of a sudden there was
mendo perps urkel grape apes gdp
platinum purple purple dragon
on and on and on and on right yeah
so
uh some people think that grape ape came
out of willets some people think that
grape ape um was just a rename okay
um but there's a gentleman
uh you can find him on the internet he
his name's dallas um and he partnered
with with uh shiloh and he claims that
he flew it down from canada
uh in cigar cases
and brought the grape ape to mendo
so he claims that
um kyle cushman had nothing to do with
it other than kyle cushman moved to
mendo
and i don't remember 0.506 or something
like that
and became friends with dude and got it
from him
very very very good but kyle had
absolutely nothing to do with it
whatsoever if you want to give anybody
credit it's either
renamed
gdp or urkel
a bag seat of such or homie actually did
that
yeah
you know with a lot of these outlaw
stories and stuff it's kind of who you
choose to believe
i remember there was also the story that
it was urkel shiva scott as well and
just that's just what went around with
it i mean me and modi both referred to
it as purple's pretty sister it showed
up
after the purple craze was what i mean
i'll explain the purple craze for a
minute when i mean the purple craze i
mean that there was brokers coming up
from the bay to mendo and saying we will
buy every gram
of this purple weeb that you can get
your hands on yeah you have 50 of them
you have 80 of them you have 150 of them
you have 250 of them i'll cash you out
and so what happens to growers when they
start hearing brokers want to cash you
out on however much you have
yeah and so your neighbor is like dude
i'm having some trouble moving my weed
it's not going as fast as i want and the
neighbor's like well i'll give you this
cut and you just give it all to me
yeah and i'll move everything you got of
it
yeah
right so
you know and then after a craze happens
like that um all these different names
pop up right
so you know it went from one or two
purple strains to eight or ten of them
within a year or two
yeah and it probably would have lasted
longer but sort of the cush
the kush craze and the sour diesel thing
happened
and sort of pushed the purples to the
side
yeah
you know
so that's right
green crack also known as green cush
with the sea
um
i you know i i don't have a verifiable
story
behind it you know i know people claim
various things you might know more about
it than i do that you might want to
speak on it
to me it's some kind of skunk one
yeah it grows like a skunk i don't know
that it's pure skunk or anything like
that but boy
it grows and a lot of i think a lot of
like uh dna's lemon skunk and all that
[ __ ] is just a prettier name
for green crack
oh interesting yeah um
um it was called green kush when it
entered our circle and i got it through
the hogs family circle
um so it was originally whenever it was
on the tags it was always cush kush and
no cecil did not make green crack or
have anything to do with it how cecil's
name entered it and me and cecil went
over this specifically because i was one
of the first people to bring green crack
into seed form to the community and
stuff so i wanted to hunt down the
history on it and i had heard the same
thing with cecil his crew had a seed
line called kush c-u-s-h
and
that's as far as the connection went it
was that they both had renamed cushes
and and they were both spelled c but
that's as far as the connection went um
yeah i think it's probably a skunk one
type because it's super mango um with a
little bit of cold it would turn mega
mega purple it also bred true for that
purple trait and it would show up
genetically as opposed to just with cold
and its hybrids um i think i i want to
see it come back but it's one of those
clones that was everywhere and now is
nowhere all at once
um i'll say the same thing
i'll say the same thing about i said
about blue dream you grow a four to six
or seven ounce plant of green crack
it's really nice weed yeah you grow a
five or eight pound plant in the outdoor
and beat the [ __ ] out of it and don't
drive the right way
yeah but you grow a little moderate size
plan of it it's got really nice lemony
terps it's got a unique kind of aroma to
it it gets it has a nice uplifting buzz
it's very pretty it burns well
um and someone mentioned it i do think
dna's lemon skunk is just a renamed
green crack
that they prettied up to breed with
probably i mean they were known for
doing that i mean when they started
their company no offense to them or
anything they just went around mendo and
humboldt in various places and gathered
up as many good clone onlys as they
could
yeah well they started their company as
soma's little little
little buddies and he gave them a c99
that they renamed to uh some sort of
haze cantaloupe i believe they called it
that yeah so that's they started their
company off of uh c99 and renamed it and
when you start your company that way
it it
there's no reason to start doing it the
right way
that's why i look at it
the seed business has never been
particularly honorable no
yeah um we got hogg's breath
that's you know yeah that was that was
our san diego crew it was made by jimbo
james hogg rest in peace um
he said several different things that it
possibly could have been made um his big
one was a williams wonder hybrid um i
think personally it was probably a skunk
one some type of afghani williams one
would fit wrong lights would fit of some
sort
um it could be foot funky cheese
it had a lot of the similar thialic
smells of like a chem d or a
a cheese
and i've seen sweet hogs
it's it's it has very specific type
growth traits on top um
kind of foxtelli a little bit on top
um yeah uh it wasn't allowed out of our
circle for a long time and once it was
it was out in everyone's hands so yeah i
think a lot of people are working with
it now and the real real ones out there
and um even though james is gone his
family still runs the clothing company
and grows and still pushes it so
yeah it's still out there and cool to be
had there you go
yeah um here's yours headband
well here we go uh headband
headband used to be very mysterious
yeah and because it was very mysterious
in origin it was supposedly came out of
new york
and there wasn't a lot of information
about it which allowed a lot of
different people to be like this cut is
the real new york city headband yeah um
and so as a result you know i have an i
have uh i have an la cut i call that you
know i got his headband
um you know there's a a headband that
lumpa attached his name to
never yeah
um there's uh there's a headband that i
call the 56 day
um you know there's another one that i
use a lot yeah people are wondering yeah
there's a there's a number of headbands
um almost all of them are good smoke
right um
but then recently it's come out and some
of the old sour crew
um has come out uh and said that uh
um
that you know the the they had these
cuts diesel 1 and diesel 2 which were
bag seed
of some chem they were getting
and um they grew them out and there was
a buddy of theirs in new york that
thought that the diesel 2
um made there made it feel like there
was a band around his head after he
smoked it
and yeah they nicknamed it the headband
and it so happens that
um
that diesel 2
there's it so happens that that cut
uh
um
that cut is the
the seeds coming out of that cut is
where the first
um is where the first sour diesel came
from
yeah okay
so then uh 707 headband the headband
that i have that i call the la
um 707 is a child of that made by
mandelbrot yeah he crossed that to
something that i'm not sure of
um and then you know you get things like
people were you know there's people that
um and who knows if that's
there's there's there's people that um
that think that have tried to say that
the one that matt uses what i call the
is the original new york city headband
and people advertised it at that duke
had it they were bit they're him and his
crew were big on saying it was the first
headband
um loompa was big on saying that his
headband was the only real headband and
everything else was a pale imitation um
and then the sour people come out and
start talking about it and it turns out
that
you know um
the headband they're speaking of that
was the first one was not cush-like at
all
yeah
so it's one of those ones that um
there was a lot of stories based on it
because there was a bunch of mystery
uh and there's also a thing about that
56 day i call it the 56th day just
because that's
it's like the least offensive nickname
of it but um that came out of the cush
crew in southern california and it came
up to the bay
and they renamed it
yeah intentionally
lumpa's story is a bit shady
um
he got to say the least and he got it
and he got it and he decided to add his
name to it
yes and ever since he's been extremely
touchy
about uh that headband has to be the
best headband and everybody else is just
a [ __ ] for trying to have as good of a
headband as luma headband yeah um so
it's really a muddled history you know
every time we talk about it it stirs up
so much [ __ ] you guys have no [ __ ]
clue so there's the 707 headband which
is a mandelbrot seed creation that he
used off the the mother cut that i still
have the l.a
yeah there's a couple what i consider to
be og kush type phenos which is the 56
and the lumpa
um the old school guys uh that first had
the diesel 2 and the headband they think
it's dead
yeah and they're suspect that it could
exist on the west coast
so like a lot of things there's mystery
yeah let's put it that way
there was one major claim that um duke
had bought it from chemdawg but i
specifically asked him dog about it and
he said he's never grown headband so
that that's a problem
i mean i'm pretty sure i'm pretty sure
that when
uh you know when uh duke and and homie
tried to work for your buddy matt matty
leet yeah that he got it in that little
era when he was in colorado yeah and had
no previous experience with it yeah that
cut that that he uses
is a super super nice very potent cut
sure yeah it's just it's just a cush cut
it's not diesel
yeah it's not the original head
definitely definitely and they and um
you know and uh
yeah and lumpa's headband is is a is a
cut that he got under suspicious
circumstances
and uh renamed it
yep after himself
yep and uh matteo yeah uh hemphill
worked with the elite crew dave yeah so
that will do exactly what i'm talking
about uh uh icy collective probably
skunk va
they all have that that that that cut
kind of got pushed around the bay a bit
i think i got it no six maybe
um
and uh so
um but yeah i mean i it
it it's not original headband um and
yeah duke got it when he worked with
matt elite and uh and bob hemphill in
colorado
yeah i'm i'm not saying nothing i i get
blamed for every time duke's names
mentioned i'd say [ __ ] um you got
jack's cleaner
i don't know [ __ ] about jack's cleaner
bro my main experience with it is uh via
ncga's work with jax cleaner i know
subcool you know he used it for um jack
the ripper it was very cleaner lemon
cleaner type
you know scent profile very strong
um
uh
narrow leaf super resinous super [ __ ]
resinous um
and it bred true for that resin type and
you see that all through tj's work
so yeah
um killer queen
uh i don't know very much about killer
queen
um i know that it was a big building
block in subcool's world
was that yeah uh no yeah i think maybe
space queen
i can't remember if killer queen was in
space queen i think it was
um but it's not it's it's one of those
you might have some stories about it i
don't have any personal um you know it's
out of that grin it's grim brothers grim
right yes no no no no it's um it's um
vic high
it's based on it's based on grim work
it's based on grim work
uh c99 romulan no no that's space screen
hold on hold on bringing it back uh
airborne g13
c99
romulan i believe
i'll say vic high was um
vic high was one of the most well-known
uh early early forum early internet weed
personalities
yeah he was a super nice cat
super smart super intelligent
intelligent smart uh really made a name
for himself on the early forums and the
overgrow and
and cannabis world and and that whole
era
um
i never worked with it but um
it was uh it you know he he was very
popular he was a real smart cat he
helped a lot of people he was nice
um and so it got popular off that i
believe
yeah
um
lone star who did the blue bonnet that i
worked with also had a killer cut of
killer queen they would go around big
yielder very c99 type dominant but had
to uh more fruity terps from all the
other [ __ ] in it um
there was a killer queen that was later
done with the supposedly the pacific g13
by motor rebel that was very different
from the original killer queen but the
original killer queen was a bce original
and it's still used to this day um yeah
it's it's a good one
sweet
lemon g
lemon g uh lemon g is um
you know some people call some people
call lemon g some people call it lemon
g13
uh we have a really good buddy pip who
cropped that one for years
yeah it's kind of it's on that citrus
level where uh
you know i i view most citrus as sort of
two one note for me
yeah you know um but it was a big
yielding kind of ugly long running
cola's plant
um and it's kind of one of those weeds
that people love for two or three days
and then get burned out on yeah yeah i'm
not i'm not a huge fan of it i can smell
lemon g and everything lemon g is in
like lemon tree i'm convinced is a lemon
g hybrid like it's so it's super obvious
to me um it's not the prettiest bud not
at all no it's kind of i would consider
it a post cookie era i would consider it
ugly it would yeah it's very ugly um
so it burns heavily cropped yeah a lot
of extract people love it you know but
um yeah m39
i can never [ __ ] remember
the
the code names
that sssc used gunk one and all five
um i think it's just skunk one nl5 but
it might be a skunk one no five haze i
can't remember but yeah
if that's the case you know i will say
that you know when we talked to corel he
was extremely honest and upfront about a
lot of their various different subjects
yeah he did get a little cagey when i
asked him about uh that and the basic
five and if he got any seed stock from
neville
um and sort of just called it by
different names at the time
uh he laughed and smiled and didn't say
a whole lot
yeah you know uh so we didn't really get
any specifics from it
um but there's no indication that he got
um that he got you know any private uh
nl stock from anyone
yep
so
you know what are you gonna say about
that
here's an interesting one the
massachusetts super skunk
boy
so this one has been described in other
podcasts and stuff quite a bit
yeah um it's got an enormous amount of
confusion about it it's a attained
legendary status
uh especially because some of the people
that are involved in it are very famous
yeah um it was in high times
uh and
especially since that rank uh roadkill
skunk
uh seems to be the scam of the minute uh
where for the last five or six years
people keep claiming that skunk their
skunk terps are gonna blow you out of
the water and it's right around the
corner
um
i had it
because the guy that went and got it
from virginia uh
crew uh brought it west yeah um and gave
it to you know um you know when uh when
jerry garcia died and skunk va started
growing uh he got the cut from my from
our buddy uh and started growing it he
posted some pictures of it on his page
um i believe it's in sour diesel
you know it's not really from
massachusetts it got dropped off there
uh by my buddy when he got the chem dog
from dude
um and what's interesting about it is
that the cut
when uh when skunk va went east and got
the chem d and brought it back when we
gave when greg got the dog back
um
by that point
according to according to uh to our
buddy he had already lost it
and the the uh massachusetts super skunk
that they posted in the
um in the uh
high times was a lot shorter was a lot
squatter was a lot and that's the one i
believe is the mom of jesus because
diesel is a spitting image of that one
and i was going to bring that up in the
sense that it's more than likely bag
seed but it's one of those ones where
nobody really wants to claim the truth
on it
yeah a lot of people keep popping up
swearing that they have it
um
a lot of ms it's one of those ones where
it's like there's a massive demand for
it
but
i've never seen anyone that i grew it
from probably not 90 i don't know late
90s to 08-ish or something
uh yeah and uh i've never seen a jar of
it
yet
you know everyone that claims that they
have rank skunk and it's gonna pop in
their seeds i've never seen a jar
i've never you know and you would think
that it's so popular and people so want
those skunk terps that all these various
breeders and stuff that claim that
they're gonna you're gonna find a bunch
of skunk in their work
um
you know it's uh it's one of those
legendary cuts now
yeah most people got rid of it because
it smelled like crazy
and uh
you know and and all that and like the
the massachusetts super skunk i will say
uh this isn't super well known but it is
not pure super skunk either
it was bred through various skunky
things that ssc sssc had and neville had
and then when neville released the super
skunk they crossed that
um
that line that they already had to the
super skunk
and phenos of that are what became
famous
yes that's the latest um
the information that we got if one of
our members of our crew got directly
from the guy who pot or bread
bread the mass super and there's an
aspect where you know there's like like
we were just talking about with the
headbands
mystery history allows various people to
make wild claims thinking that it won't
ever get popped up um it came out to
california with my friend when the same
time he brought the chem dog out and it
survived amongst our crew and he grew it
for some time
um it went to colorado through that that
breeder's other friends and it got
called skunk six out there
uh after the the the number of the fin
the number of the fino you know that
they were growing
and it's got a lot of legend to it you
know it's probably in it's pr in my
opinion it's probably in chem d it's
probably it's def i think it's in sour
um and a lot of people want it and it
seems to not exist
uh you know maybe it exists in various
forms we'll see maybe it pops up one day
but
more people have been excited about
selling the name
than making sure they have it
in my opinion
people have been excited about selling
the name
so
i will say one other thing
um that uh
you know uh neville always said that his
two best-selling things were super skunk
and uh and nl5 hates yes so there's
probably a lot of super skunk out there
blended into various things i think that
i personally think that super skunk is
a lot of what people refer to as skunky
dank um that went around in their area
was probably if you know super skunk i'm
damn near convinced of this after seeing
stuff like the old p91 um my heirloom
afghani line just an old afghani line
that happened to be from florida is very
super skunk like um the clock worked cut
um
all kinds of [ __ ] around me was super
skunk
i navigated to people ask how the hell
could it have disappeared and it's
really simple
um most skunk you know people think
about this crazy terp and i will say
that it had the turpin spades
right it was incredibly stinky
it was only moderate potency it was only
moderate density you could have this big
ass bud and you'd put it on the scale
and you'd be like oh that's going to be
six or seven grams and it'd be like two
and a half
you know and it was pre-carbon filters
um so it got a lot of people in trouble
i mean i remember driving up to my house
a bunch in summer and like parking in my
driveway and i could just smell it
and you know it was you know like i said
earlier in the show other things get
more popular
and people drop [ __ ] and then they think
oh i can always get it back someone else
is holding it someone else is holding it
and now it's like
you know
people can't find it you know so
but uh it exists in a lot of children i
definitely think it's in sour diesel i
can smell it in sour i can even see it
in sourdough yeah there you go i would
agree a hundred percent
uh this one's for my buddy sub rob
um the matanuska valley thunder [ __ ]
i have a cool story about that yeah
let's hear it so it sounds to me like
the matt nuscavalli [ __ ] ends up
being kind of like crippy or diesel or
something like that in terms of it was
like a name for fireweed yes right
and uh
when i was on dead tour there was a
buddy of ours that was from alaska
uh and was on tour
and he would go home to alaska in
between tours
yeah and i gave him one time i gave him
like twelve hundred dollars for a
quarter pound
yeah and then he didn't give me any weed
for months and i thought he jacked me
and then he called me up and he said hey
i'm gonna send you something
and he sent me this weed and
it showed up in the mail and it was wet
yeah and i took it out and i dried it
and it was only like three and a half
ounces so i lost like a half ounce of
weight and it was three and a half four
months late
uh but he said it was thunder [ __ ]
and it was olive dark green with these
weird hairs and it was so good
my buddies and i kept it in the freezer
and we smoked it uh only for special
occasions over the next six or eight
months
yeah great high great buzz
much better weed than anything we had at
the time as far as kind bud granted this
is when i was 17 18 19 so take that into
account
uh and everyone that's claimed matanuska
[ __ ] since then none of it has
looked like it
yeah none of it looked like the weed
that i got back then one time
so yeah there you go i think that's like
everyone's story that i've met there's a
lot of people from alaska
that
i think are very convinced that you know
the map music [ __ ] that they had
was the original and the only and they
can tell you all about it you know who
grew it who made it et cetera et cetera
but there's a lot of stories like that
and i think that it i think they're
probably all telling their own truth i
know what i mean i will say too that uh
the the package that i got mailed was
mailed from denali alaska post office
yeah which was pretty funny
yeah that is funny yeah
now yeah yeah so
uh but i thought i got ripped off for
months because i gave him 1200 bucks
and i didn't see any weed for months
and he kept his he kept the funny thing
about that this is a little bit of a
side tangent but he kept his he was a
native to alaska and he kept his
um license and all that from alaska
because
alas native alaskans got um oil money
yeah every year
so even though he was on dead tour and
he was like in the lower 48 most of the
year
he would keep all of his [ __ ] at his
parents house and just go back there in
between and he would get like between a
two and a five thousand dollar check
every year yeah isn't that [ __ ] wild
one of my friends uh in high school got
shipped out to alaska
we were a bunch of punk rock kids and he
got in trouble he got in a lot of
trouble one day doing some punk rock
things and got shipped out to alaska for
a few years and he came back and he was
the first person to like talk to me
about some strain that was like he's
like bro
hugest thc numbers ever it's called the
magnus valley thunder [ __ ] you know and
he had this big tale of of uh
you know this very special potent weed
that was out there in alaska you know
and i was always trying to figure out
more about this thing and as i as i kept
digging deeper and deeper i i learned
that there were several people with
several claims to several
thunder [ __ ] out there the more you dig
into it the wider the story becomes
yeah let's put it that way lots of
bikers involved in most of them
let's put it that way so it's hard to
say if it was a one thing or it was just
a regional name like maui wowie like
crippy even my buddies everyone thinks
about diesel as sour diesel now
but you know in the mid 90s or whatever
the only reason why i got called sour
diesel was because the guy wrote our
diesel
yeah because diesel was slang for fire
weed in new york city in that time
yeah my friends that lived there said
that you got all kinds of diesels
because that was that was the name and i
think thunder [ __ ] is a bit like that
but there you go
yeah yeah have you have you ever heard
of sour diesel being called the [ __ ]
diesel
have you ever heard that no
okay and i've talked i've talked
i've talked to almost everyone at length
in the sour diesel original family
you know
um and i i never heard [ __ ] diesel but
you know there you go yeah yeah i don't
know why that's in my memory bank but
yeah that's one of the names of my
memory bank maybe that's a secret they
kept amongst the boys yeah just a few of
the boys
the boys you know yeah just a few just a
few of the bros okay so we're almost two
hours in
and we are only like
a portion of the way through this list
um so it'll probably be a few episodes
well keep it going historical
yeah um i think that'll be fun um i i
need to announce a few things we have
breeder syndicate 2.0 up um so the audio
podcast is back it's rolling
a lot of new things are
rolling with that
so it's available on any podcast
software make sure you look for the new
logo it's white and pink right now we're
developing some other new logos that are
pretty cool we have a lot of new cool
things going on with it
um we have the breeder syndicate patreon
where we all hang out you can come hang
out with us there
we have a discord and we're there all
the time taking questions
uh for seeds there's riotseeds.com
um we have my seeds and my
reversal spread
available uh not so anything you want to
plug
i'm not really big on plugging publicly
uh i mean i will say like as always that
like i uh i'm super stoked that
everybody likes to listen we're
definitely trying to bring like culture
and history
that's mostly what we're into i think a
lot of like podcasts end up being sort
of like infomercials about people which
isn't necessarily bad but like there's a
lot more diversity in cannabis world
cannabis culture
you know historical um that isn't like
just about making people look good you
know yeah so we are i always appreciate
people coming out you know um
and uh you know you always can reach you
can always reach me through dm on ig you
can always reach me on uh i answer a lot
of questions i try to get to everyone
sometimes i get i get swamped you know i
have a life too and stuff like that but
um you know we are we are thinking about
um you know it's one of the reasons why
we talk about some of these old things
is that we think they're going to make a
comeback perhaps
i am thinking about uh you know doing
some like uh doing some you know i've
never been really a public breeder and
i'm matt has been trying to convince me
to open myself up to lots of criticism
and hate and people throwing things at
me i write his i write his phone number
in every bathroom stall like yeah
you know so people so but then there's a
lot of things that like you know i've
always bred for stuff that i love and so
i don't know um i've been thinking about
maybe
you know doing some uh doing or
releasing some stuff that might be very
different than what is currently out
there
um and i don't know if people would be
into it or not but it's it's always been
sort of a you know a passion thing for
me or whatever so
uh you know we'll uh
um
how far did we get on the [ __ ] list
dude
we got pretty far in but there's a lot
that like people are talking about that
i've been writing down that i want to go
back and touch onto there was i will say
there was a there was a [ __ ] ton of
really good questions this week a lot of
them i missed because it's it's you
might it's like rubbing your head and
patting your stomach at the same time
it's really hard to like talk
intelligently in a flowing form and then
think about like four or five cool
questions all at the same time that you
see scroll by
so matt's been taking notes we'll try to
get we'll try to expand it and this show
is you know as much as it's about us
talking about random weed [ __ ] that we
do all week anyway
it's for you guys too
so hit us up all the time with questions
or you know or ideas or thoughts on like
what you might want to hear
you know
um yeah and i mean i'm not i'm not like
that that's the whole thing people i've
you know uh caleb matt other people
they've been trying for years to not
only get me to talk but to get me to
like publicly release stuff
and it's like it's kind of a [ __ ] being
a public breeder
so yeah i've been kind of hesitant to
like open myself up to like a bunch of
criticism and [ __ ]
um yeah but i might i don't know you
know deserves it there's a lot of
feeling
there's a lot of uh there's a lot of
cool things i think that get passed over
with fads
so you know
uh we are almost at two hours so i don't
know i mean maybe we could we're
thinking about having shaw on next week
that's right we could continue this um
we could you know two hours is kind of
long
uh but maybe we'll figure out a format
to do the rest of them fairly soon yeah
yeah i like that idea and if you're a
part of the patreon and um the discord
and you want to give us some other ideas
for other clones you'd like to hear
about from that era just throw it up in
there we'll see it
yeah i mean discord is definitely a much
easier way for us to converse back and
forth especially individual
you know yeah so um you know you don't
have to but it just it's it's easier you
can always reach out to ig but sometimes
i get buried yeah
so there you go
all right well thank you everyone and uh
yeah yeah we try to keep it in two hours
so we'll keep this going i'm glad
everybody liked chatting about old stuff
as always we super appreciate your
friday night
um and everyone have a killer weekend
yeah cheers
want more breeder syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out
need seeds check out riotsteads.com
where you can get our seeds and our
reversal spray for making your own
feminized
[Music]
you