ready go
so
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
[Music]
hey there's that handsome man there we
are what are you up to
oh i just got done with dinner with the
kids did you spritz your hair i did not
no you did not spray not no spritz
no spritz
all right shave
what would we consider the topic tonight
uh i thought we i thought we could chat
a little bit about like just like the
like the changing seed dynamic
and how it's how it's been one way for
it was you know how every five or ten
years or something it's kind of
dramatically different yeah especially
since
in today's world uh there's a ton of
stuff now that's coming out
that's uh you know old and authentic and
this and that and unchanged and you know
a lot of people might not know
that you know even stuff 10 years ago is
hard to get yeah yeah you know so i
thought we could kind of chat about uh
you know what how how how it changed how
it started
and we can take questions on this one
pretty easy we there's like a lot of
years to cover so it's not like you're
gonna be like chronological even or like
go into tons of depth on everything but
we can kind of give like a general
overview you know yeah um
and there's already questions about the
the nl repro and hawaiian lights and
this and that and yeah you know a lot of
people when you hear skunk one or you
hear nl or you hear this or that or even
sour diesel for some people it might be
like a legendary thing of old yeah that
you're hearing about but you might have
come up in an era where like it wasn't
popular or common
you know yeah and so you know there
might be a but there's a lot of
information out there about certain
things
um but you know it kind of gets needs to
get taught again and again and again and
again
yeah and it seems to be need to be
refreshed more often now than ever
before
yeah you know and then
people coming in
the information is out there and there's
you know there's i mean there's always
been dishonesty in the seed game but
there's there's dishonesty and there's
sleight of hand and there's letting
people assume
yeah that's a big one assumptions are a
big one where it's not you're not
actually
you know
lying necessarily you're lying by
admission you're just kind of throwing
it out there and being like oh well you
know
yeah you assumed that not me yeah
so where we want to start
maybe we could just do like a super
quick
overview
uh of what things were like in the uh in
the like in the beginning
okay go ahead you start with this one
this is your era it's my era so i mean
we've already done some like long
podcasts on this so i won't touch on it
too much but the parts that that are
important for people to know is that in
the beginning
there was only a few companies
it was all regular seeds uh reversals
and all that were years and years and
years away
and because there was not very much
competition
there wasn't very much pressure to
change things right yeah so companies
would come out with a lineup and that
lineup would often stay the same within
it within a mission or an addition or
two
over a number of years
um the seed bank from neville changed
every couple of years as he figured out
what he had going on
but the first like the first five years
of scentsy were basically the same stuff
unchanged and then every year or two
they'd add a new thing in
you know when simon from serious seeds
came out i mean he was pretty famous for
kind of having he had like the same six
things yeah six just like they did six
things you know um
and so that was pretty common back then
where it was like
most of the companies that you could buy
from were out of holland because that's
where it was legal
yeah and they all had printed catalogs
and there wasn't really internet or
internet was very young
and so the biggest difference from today
is that they all used males
and so if you look back at that early
work they typically found
males that worked for them
you know um and repeatedly used them
across multiple lines yeah
and you know and
finding for them it might sound crazy
today but like the older breeders would
tell you that like the males were the
most valuable cuts in their stable
because the females the females you
could obviously grow the flower and you
could decide whether or not you liked it
a bunch yeah the males figuring out
whether or not they pass the traits that
you wanted was time consuming
it was either that it was either a roll
of the dice and you got very lucky or
extremely time consuming yeah you had
you had to like look you had to make
seeds and grow the seeds and be like oh
that's not the male i want i'm going to
go to a different one
so typically breeders when they figured
out an actual male that was golden for
them
they hung onto it like crazy
yeah
right and i i get that one
i get that one you know and and so part
of the part of the thing
you know we were talking in the
beginning about like olden strains
popping back up with the skunk one and
this and the
and the nl and this and that and
everything else is that
some of the reasons why these strains
were so famous is because unlike today
where there's like a ton of breeders
releasing new names all the time and
they're there and gone
um
these things had lasting power
yeah they hung around
you said that then you
and back then if you bought a seed pack
usually the the following if you chose
to buy another one the next year it
would be a similar seed pack the same
kind of stuff
yeah and like even when changed even
with the canadians and stuff and other
companies started biting that initial
stuff
they still use those initial names
yeah
so they got
you know they got like you know that's
part of the reason why some of those
names have such
for lack of a better term name
recognition
even with casual smokers they might not
have never most smokers have probably
never smoked pure northern lights
anything
but everybody's heard
most it
really haven't honestly probably even
haven't smoked skunk one
yeah pure
you know even though it's in lots of
things but they've heard the name
yeah you know and so uh you know they uh
um
so that was kind of that was kind of how
it was for like a really long time was
that there was
there was different there was different
groups
and i would say for the first 15 years
it was almost all holland
amsterdam based
yeah
like 85 to 2000 or something yeah it was
pretty good
it was pretty amsterdam based and then
like in the late 90s early 2000s it
started shifting over to canada too
yeah and there was um you know there was
you know there was a bunch of different
groups from canada federation and uh
uh legends legends and and bbc memory
emory yeah i mean there was even there
was even uh the you know
one of the cool things about canada was
that before like when i first started
you either had to fly to amsterdam or
you had to get
mail from holland
yeah which was kind of sketch
you know and then there was canadian
seed companies that started opening up
in canada and then you could get it from
canada which was like a lot more
male back and forth between our two
countries right so it was a lot more
like lost in the shuffle
yeah and so he said mark emery uh the
one that was kind of famous for a minute
was heaven's heaven stairway
yeah um and they were all tied into like
the first forums
yeah
right right
your brother ron are you uh jim's
brother
ronnie god i was doing a really good job
i know i know your sister and i knew jim
really well underneath and they're my
mentors so that's pretty cool i've never
talked to his brother
um i'm going to go back to not paying
attention to the comments but yeah i
know i will pay attention soon it's just
hard it's just hard to chit chat and
read at the same time i lose my train of
thought
but yeah like
so
one of the one of the amazing things
about about the canadian seed companies
is that
there were individual like companies
like like scentsy or something that were
like in canada that were like making
seeds but there was also like sort of
the first seed brokers
yeah right
where you know uh in amsterdam days you
kind of went to each individual seed
company
and got seeds from them
yeah but mark emery or heaven's seven
stairway you know these these groups
like you could get
all of that
supposedly plus all this stuff from
canada
right and what's important about that
too is that the canadian people it
really kind of like widened what was
available
yeah you know there was different people
like uh you know reefer man was another
one you know there's various people that
started throwing out all kinds of
different stuff
you know um
you know uh dj short shifted his his
work after not being very happy i don't
think with partnering with with uh dutch
guys
yeah he wasn't too i think he was at sag
martha first
and then he went to dutch passion yeah
um and then he pretty much started
mostly selling his stuff through
canadian companies yeah right
um and that was this is still all
males era
but what happened
in the late 90s with with overgrow and
with cannabis world is now all of a
sudden
um like you talk about ig there was the
potential for people to get
sort of internet famous
yeah absolutely and there was some
people that were on that were on there
early on
that because they i'm not this isn't
dissing them so don't take it that way
but just because there was only so much
competition and there was only so many
people
like willing to do what they were doing
publicly
um they got kind of famous
yeah
right
yeah you know um the whole first edition
of you know uh
you know people started posting on
overgrow
threads with blueberry i mean
blueberries pretty close to matt's heart
you know and people would freak out
because it looked
so different than anything else
it was wildly different yeah
and that's another part of it where it's
like that's the start of where things
started getting internet famous and
everybody started talking about them and
like
one percent of people that were talking
about them had ever seen it in a bag or
smoked it or smelled it or touched it
yeah just online vision just online
vision and online talking and so you
could get a couple of people that
sounded intelligent talking about
something yeah and it was gospel
yep
you know i mean i used to used to go on
there and people would have grow grow
check you know grow forums and and you
know i'm growing this
and some of that stuff another thing was
like the original brothers grimm was
right in that same era
right yes
cinderella 99
blueberries stuffed with catchy names
that was new wasn't from amsterdam
wasn't from the same group was different
genetics
um and it kind of got super famous
yeah
don't you think
yeah yeah
and i went and it kind of
you know as far as like tonight's
discussion or whatever what's kind of
important about it is that
in the beginning it was literally like
sssc and neville
selling seats
yeah and then there was like 12 dutch
dudes selling seeds
yeah and then there was like 20 dutch
and then there was a bunch of canadians
making seed and then there was like some
aggregators of seed in canada selling
seed
yeah and then the internet comes along
and all of a sudden somebody from from
oregon like dj short or you know
brothers graham or these different
people could just pop up
yeah and there was wait there was what
was it was breed bay the for what was
the first
was it was it like probably like direct
messages in the very beginning which was
the easiest way for people to
communicate and actually get seeds oh
yeah yeah
yeah
that's more it goes down in the dm it
goes down in the dm so
you know the forums the forums was
really the first place where sort of
like the worldwide weed community could
start to chat
yeah
and it's where a lot of legends were
born
you know it's also where the people that
are legends started writing down
versions of events that we could compare
to what they say and wrote later
yeah so the forums is where a lot of the
real story of skunk one first got told
right yeah the real and we talked about
we talked about it with chem dog on the
last episode it's where people started
writing down thoughts about chem dog and
the original story
um
and you know people could find they
could be active on threads and they
could find other people and you could
start learning about sort of like the
larger weed history
yeah and a lot of times we'd see people
growing the clone and be like [ __ ] i
want that one so you'd go talk to them
and you'd make connections and you know
that's that's how it all worked that's
how the circles started the the clone
circles of people you know kind of
banding together as crews because they
realize like i've got to keep honest
people around me to trade with because
i'm getting [ __ ] all the time
and there was people like you know
there's people that are instagram famous
right now
in weed world there was definitely
people that were you know forum famous
and their opinion their opinions about
seed and their opinions about all that
um you know and that's where like a lot
of times for some people the first time
people saw old-timers start arguing
with youngsters over what the [ __ ] even
was going on
and you realized some of the
personalities behind some of this stuff
um you know like uh tom hill
yeah you know yeah vic high
and chimera and all of them yeah chimera
uh who you know um matt interviewed him
and read uh a while ago
uh
you know he he's actually really
personable to watch talk
but he was like the most intimidating
breeder to read about
yeah because his level of like technical
knowledge and education on how genetics
works is pretty deep yeah it was really
hard to argue with him very hard because
he could he could run circles around
people science-wise yeah i mean he just
he just he's you know he just
breeding and genetics and how all that
stuff works he had a you could call it
like a classical education in it or
whatever yeah
um you know and he got hella famous but
it's like nobody i never tried any of
his weed
i never tried any of his strains
no yeah i did
but i'm just saying like you know
something like i said some of the stuff
like with blueberry and stuff like how
many people actually tried the blue
velvet
yeah not many and it was so expensive
back then it was one of the more
expensive strains for its time you know
so a lot of people weren't buying it
and so the so people would like live
vicariously through like the people that
did buy it and they'd start a grow
journal on some forum and then
like that would drive seed sales for
certain ones like crazy
yeah because here's this crazy purple
blue like long before cookies or
whatever you know uh the blue family
really did look unique
yeah and so i think we're gonna do a a
whole set segment for people watching
we're gonna do a whole segment on the
history of purples because i think
nowadays um
looking around you see all the purples
and you think well this must have been
how it always has been but it just
wasn't like purples were rare as [ __ ] up
until
2008 you weren't seeing a lot of true
breeding purples that you could you
could breed with and reliably pass on
purple traits or only a few
and really in 2008 with matt's talking
about
those purples that started popping were
kind of all descendants from
half a dozen purple cuts that got famous
most of them were descendants of mendo
perps because blackberry is probably a
mendo purp spino and blackberry
the majority were blackberry or purple
oracle yeah so erical and mendo p kind
of created a million hybrids
yeah but you know i i mean
just we're gonna we'll probably yeah we
will do a whole show on that i guess but
yeah we definitely will there's an
aspect to it where like in general
people should still know that like from
you know so now
everyone all those people still had
males
hold on hold on uh roan dog no he will
never be on this show because he's been
taught too many lies about his [ __ ]
herbal but i'll i'll fill you in later
roan dog
go ahead couldn't let that one slide by
yeah so no i mean like i'm still not i'm
you know and so
so basically like just keeping it with
the seed game or whatever everyone still
use males
but now it did all of a sudden it was
really it was almost like democracy in
wheat
right yeah there used to be like an
aristocracy of seed companies
that like they
they didn't have very much competition
you know and they didn't have very much
new things coming in to like sort of
turn the thing so stuff like nl that
gets famous and all was sold for 20
years
yeah
right like yeah you know i mean skunk
one these you know uh hazes these
various different things super silver
haze there was like new things would hit
like we talked about the white family
and the blue family a little bit last
episode too those things had five or six
years of a run where they didn't have
very much else hypey battling them for
eyes and drool and you know oh my god
what is that
yeah right it was slower
right it was much slower but what the
forums did
is
they introduced the ability for
small-scale growers in america
to start selling seed
yeah
for the most part
you really had to like you know um i
mean even for someone like dj short to
sell his blue line he basically had to
send it to
dutch companies and hope
yeah right when i first started i had to
send it to to
at that time it was mostly british
companies that were doing it and
you had to send it [ __ ]
uh front it all of it you just had to
hope that someone wasn't gonna [ __ ] you
yeah you know and so you and so
basically then the internet allowed some
of these seed people to sell direct
yeah and and to create their own seat
you know
uh in a way
where that sort of i'm trying to think
of like who else was
um you know breeder steve got really
famous
in that same era because there was a
thing where you know once they started
changing the laws in holland in 99 where
they didn't allow seed production
switzerland opened up big
and so there was these there was these
you know there was these forum posts and
stuff about swiss groves
and people like breeder steve and shanti
baba and some of the other people that
had made the switch over there all of a
sudden like now it's like oh whatever i
see another huge 20 acre grow
yep 500 lights
just scrolling through ig oh look the
jungle boys are building another [ __ ]
warehouse
but yeah
seeing like seven greenhouses lined up
in a row that were commercially scaled
full of weed in switzerland
all of a sudden you were like whoa
yeah it's not in a bedroom anymore
right
yeah
and they were actually able to breed
over there and so yeah it was kind of
like
can you think of anybody else besides
like brothers grimm
the dj short breeder steve
you know what i was just thinking as you
were talking was that um what i really
remember was that nobody from europe was
selling direct there were very few
unless you were someone that was a
well-known breeder
you weren't able to buy seeds like from
scentsy you weren't able to buy from
nirvana direct you weren't able to buy
from shanti direct they would not ship
to the us whatsoever
everybody had to go through these these
other venues of the of the one spot
whether it was sea bay heaven stairway
um
onto seed bay you know uh uh seed
boutique places like that before you
could even get your hands on them so
nobody was buying direct from the
breeders back then none of them no one
was doing direct seed sales
everybody got sketched by what happened
to neville yeah and so that's what i
mean like i went out in the 90s when i
was going like you basically most of
them you had to go and get seed
yeah you had to go there and get it
yeah but they weren't they're gonna be
shipping it to you but having stairway
and mark emery in places like that they
would ship
yeah you know and and they and all of a
sudden you could like you'd get cannabis
culture uh which was mark emery's
magazine or height you know and that
that thing was pretty famous i think
most donors bought it because it had
some cool pictures and a few cool
articles but then it would have pages
of his seed company and what the
offerings were
yeah and you would just read those
paragraphs over and over and over again
yeah there's some good copywriting in
some of them yeah you're like oh
federation or you know or
casey brains or this or that and these
new names and with new names came new
claims
yeah and new genetics
and you know the the dutch started
losing their their place of like
centrality
yeah you know um but that also started
to speed things up a bit
you know um most famous strains had kind
of an arc of i would call it like five
to eight years where they were dominated
yeah
you know um and i think that was true
with like
like i said like with skunk and nl and
it was true with white widow and
blueberry and it was true with
you know um i mean you remember all the
hype about like like cindy 99 cinderella
oh yeah and like well yeah i mean a fast
fast flowering uh haze supposedly haze
type high that you could grow outdoors
and finish in time it's yeah it's kind
of like
dj used to claim about flow
oh yeah the seven weaker all the
qualities you want in a long running
equatorial sativa found in a seven week
you know yeah seven week plan and so
cindy 99 was kind of the same thing but
it was more like eight or nine weeks
yeah
much closer
much closer and so
um and also we should probably note that
um
whatever whatever
what's the best way to put it
dms and the internet
really started people
all of a sudden being able to trade
clones with people they didn't know
personally in real life
yeah
and i think that was kind of a
revolution
yeah that's that's when a lot of these
cali clones over cali clown only started
to make their way around the nation
you know because you really had to be
connected
um you really had to be connected in
order to to get things
yeah you know um and you and generally
speaking like you had to go meet someone
to get them
you know where
all of a sudden i mean it sounds quaint
now but like people could like go make
internet friends
and do some private dming
and all of a sudden they got some cuts
mailed yeah
that that to me has has
been lost from from what's going on
today for the most part not always but
for the most part a lot of people um pop
in and expect to
just be given you know just be given
they don't understand
you pay your dues you work you work your
way into certain circles you gain trust
and this is a several year
kind of thing you know yeah i mean
that's the
i would say that that probably is true
like um
in any like small subculture
yeah right like uh um
the the ability for you know for the the
people that are already in it to kind of
lay down the law the rules and like the
the you know what conduct is appropriate
yeah you know um
you know i could use like uh me i'm a
little young for that but
um some of my older dead head friends
told me the worst thing that ever
happened to the dead was when they had a
top 10 hit
in 1987 because so many people
mindset
well so many people started coming to
the show that like
95 of the people going there
knew sort of the framework of the rules
yeah and then you get two three four
five hundred thousand people that start
showing up at all these different spots
in different places and they don't know
the rules so much
and the same thing has happened with
weed like there used to be a thing where
i mean
20 years ago there wasn't anybody
offering like hey i've got all these
rare cuts this one's 300 this one's 500
this one's 800.
like no one would ever trade with you
if you may if you made a price list for
clones back then
you would probably be blacklisted
every collector would be like oh no
now people just look at it like oh it's
a perfectly acceptable business model
yeah
like i can just gather up all these
clones and i'm not even making a value
judgment
i'm not saying that back then like that
would have been crazy like you had to
build trust with someone and they would
usually extract some type of concession
that you would treat it in a way that
they felt was respectful in order to get
it
yeah and if they saw that they probably
wouldn't trust you yeah if you posted on
overgrow or cannabis world or something
like or i see mag later if you posted
some hey here's the 20 cuts that i'm
selling and here's the price ranges
yeah you'd be [ __ ] you'd be super
[ __ ] you'd be [ __ ] dude and like you
people would be jumping down your throat
people would be
flipping out
because it was it was considered like a
lot of those things were kind of
considered like family heirlooms back
then yeah
you know but what's cool about that is
that that revolutionized breeding too
because
like one of the things that like you
know neville got so lucky when he did
was he got all these american breeders
to just give him their work
and he got across it
right so that was very lucky in that
sense because it's like
he got to cross skunk and nl and he got
to cross hayes and then allen he got to
cross
you know all this [ __ ] so yes dms and
trading that went on in the forums
that started really like
changing up what what growers and
breeders could have access to
yeah and what they could use and people
mailing each other seeds that was even
more that was way more common
than
i think clone trading oh yeah for sure
way way more common like clone trading
was still pretty rare and sketchy but
people would be like oh i took this i
took this uh sweet tooth
and i crossed it to these eight things
that i have and now i have seeds i'm
gonna send them to all my friends
yeah clone mailing is also a huge pain
in the ass and it always it has been you
know it happened
it was just super rare in my opinion
then yeah it did happen
but i think trading seeds was more we
were still like in this in the you pop
seeds era
yeah yeah definitely don't you think
yeah oh yeah yeah i mean i just think i
think in general
sending clones was so much labor so much
more laborious there were so many there
were so few people that had legit [ __ ]
and it was easier to track who had what
back then than it is now
so there were there were all kinds of
factors that went into why seeds were
much easier to ship and why they were
more traded than clones and there's more
emphasis on seeds back then anyways than
clones market wise too i think before
the mid 2000s
um there was a lot less emphasis on like
i have this specific strain and it sells
for this much
yeah you could grow a lot of good things
and it would still easily sell
yeah right so people were much more they
were much more content with like oh send
me 30 seeds and i'll find a winner and
then i'm going to grow up my little
group and i'll have no problem moving it
yeah
that was a big issue too
you know is is that as the last the last
15 years it's gotten more and more and
more specific on do you have this cut
yeah
where i think that arrow that we're
talking about it was more people were
way more into like finding seats
yeah i think in that era you are more
likely to get
a real cut because the the whole fake
cut thing hadn't really taken off yet
well no there was there was no nobody
sold any so there was no money in it so
there was no reason to deceive and like
there was fake cuts getting traded
but like anything else it takes a long
time for that stuff to snowball
oh yeah because you have someone has to
grow it out figure it out that it's fake
in the first place go through enough
hands to be caught
sure and in some cases it's like so you
got a fake or two or whatever like
getting traded back and forth here and
there to one or two people and then fast
forward 10 years and the game changes a
little bit and there's 30 people
trading that cut
yeah so just get into way more hands
i was always honestly like that's more
matt's era than mine in the sense that i
was way more of a lurker
because i didn't trust technology
he's a like
to i didn't trust technology to dm
people and to give out my address
and to have yeah
i was stupid i was i was in the era
where people still weren't selling
direct and i'm like how the [ __ ] are
people selling direct i'm just gonna
sell direct and it was probably
a very very risky idea and i didn't
realize it at the time how indeed risky
it was i figured more people would do it
than me
i did super risky [ __ ] i just i just
like i just didn't understand like i
thought like with the push of a button
the fbi could just find my vpn and
everything they're all male phobic
i don't like it but i mean i would do
things like i would go to amsterdam you
know and i would like put
seeds sew them in the hem of my jeans
yeah like twice a year
and like and i would make these like
tiny little notes with like like prison
notes like the smallest lettering like
and nl5 skunk one this tiny little note
and i'd slip that in the hem and then
i'd push the 30 seeds in there and sew
it back up
you know so that's like actual like
smuggling in a way you know i was just
thinking how bad it would suck like if
you got home and you forgot to tell your
mom not to wash your jeans
oh yeah washes your jeans with your
seeds
when i was buying i i moved out uh soon
you know uh early on yeah there wasn't
uh there wasn't any like come home with
illegal seeds to my mom
um but yeah that was
and your significant other we used to
get really annoyed about
like the last day you were in amsterdam
you would like take
you would get a new hotel room and you
would take everything in your bag out
one by one and you would look for like
weed leafs
or something yeah or a small chunk of
hash you would make sure you laundered
all your [ __ ]
right like yeah uh
you know i have a buddy you know um i've
talked about him before but
um you know he had a he had a wallet
right and the wallet had a velcro seal
and like the tiniest flake of weed was
sticking to the velcro
and when he went through customs they
look through his [ __ ]
they find it yeah and all of a sudden
they're like what is this and there's
like the tiniest tiniest flake of
you know it was like a sweet leaf that
was stuck to the bud yeah and then it
stuck to the velcro
well that was like we had a two-hour
delay because then they ripped apart
everything in his life and they like
looked at the souls of his shoes and
they like imaged the bottom of his
suitcase i mean it was like they were
they were on him like white on rice i
bet
from one little flake
you know and then back then we were
sketched enough because you were flying
home sometimes we would do this thing
where
we would go to holland but we would fly
home from like germany or belgium or
france oh yeah yeah so at least there
was like a direct flight not necessarily
straight from amsterdam
yeah because you're going to be looked
at way more heavy coming out of
amsterdam sure yeah just because it's
like yeah it's like you're flying home
from like
yeah you know it's like it's like in the
80s you're flying home from bogota yeah
and you're doing exactly big sunglasses
you know like you might get looked at
for a minute you know because it's
bogota you know
so it it uh
you know it basically like it took a lot
of effort
then and the and i think the forums
really sort of like democratized and
made the effort easier because you could
like hunt [ __ ] from your living room
yeah
you know and unlike today i mean i've
like we i've made some comments before
about like ig being irritating me
because
you know people curate their page so
hard that a lot of good information gets
lost yeah because people will just block
you or delete your comment or even just
take down the whole post
if the you know it goes off it goes off
kilter for them yeah right yeah
you know even my my catalog posts have
been flagged and taken down just
pictures of cat pages from catalog so
people have access to see what was in
the catalog even those get reported and
taken down you know so in the early days
the only way that you could get
something taken down on the forum is if
the moderator you knew the moderator and
they were willing to do something shady
and get rid of it yeah back in the day
the worst thing that used to happen on
the forums was if people got too mean to
each other they would just lock comments
yeah lock the thread they would just
lock the thread but the thread the
information itself would stay up there
so i think there was like a generation
of people
that grew up
um
you know and i mean i i talked i've
talked a few times about like those
harvest festivals that i went to
a whole bunch of people you know from uh
from ron and stuff
all those people met from the internet
yeah i mean there was like groups of
friends from different regions
you know um but
you know i mean that's the first place i
met csi yeah and by run you mean ncga
for everybody watching yeah ncga north
cal grows guards association he's the
they used to throw in sonoma county they
used to rent out a house for three days
and basically have a harvest festival
that was catered where everybody would
bring down seeds and weed and hash and
their stuff and shoot the [ __ ] eat and
talk about life
yeah you know um and that's where a lot
a whole bunch of us even though like csi
and i only lived a couple hours apart
that's where we met
yeah
and it was the internet and then there
was people like uh like chip who started
um uh the cocoa that you know the uh you
know he started a co soil company yeah
the mendo royal
royal gold from
royal gold he has a podcast now and i
think he's in colorado or something like
that that's what i heard but anyway like
i you know i met chip there and he you
know he was just back from
uh switzerland
yeah and he had a bunch of you know
pictures of all these greenhouses full
of weed
and so it was like those kind of things
brought together a bunch of breeders
yeah right
and that is what really started like the
poly hybrid era where people started
being able to trade their stuff back and
forth
yeah and start crossing things to
different things and oh i've got this
little bit because most of the time back
then you got two or three cuts that your
friends grew
yeah
and that's all you had access to yeah
and then maybe
you know it's like yeah like if matt was
if matt was growing in san diego or some
[ __ ]
then he could get things in san diego
yeah but he wasn't going to get things
that were famous in new york or florida
or that wasn't that easy
yeah not during that era not during that
era at all it wasn't that easy
and so you know matt made the point now
where people like want access to all
this stuff really fast
yeah and they don't realize how many
years
of just being around and being trusted
it took
before
someone would start to let you in
i take i compare it a lot to like if
people are familiar with tattoo shops
how
when you want to be a tattoo artist the
first place you start is with the broom
you start with the broom
and you sweep the tattoo parlor and you
can do this for
six months to [ __ ] 10 years
it's uh it's all based on when you gain
the trust for someone to take an
interest in you and be like i'm going to
show you a trade because i think you're
worth worth showing this to and i'm
going to invest time in you and you're
going to return that by helping me you
know apprentice you know it was a much
more of like an apprentice situation in
in a lot of these things when it came to
trust i and i think too that was how
seeds work yeah i mean if you go back
um
you know uh why did you know after
neville left uh scentsy for instance why
did he partner with shanti
yeah uh shanti was probably younger and
more vigorous
you know he kind of took him under his
wing there was a lot of that that
happened there was a lot of people that
trained people coming up
yeah you know and you learned from
someone above you
um and uh you know i mean simon and uh
what's this [ __ ] uh
adam i guess yeah and tony from you know
so adam from th seeds simon from serious
seeds and uh
um
yeah they all worked under neville
yeah
and then they learned enough and they
learned what the [ __ ] they were doing
and they learned how to breed and they
worked for him for a few years and then
they started their own company called
cerebral
and and me i like i was talking about
earlier with ronnie dog i learned from
jimbo who he was referred to as his
brother but was like his uncle or cousin
or something i learned under him you
know like and he was not it was not an
easy person to learn under but uh
i learned a lot you know and later on
learned a little bit under neville and
and you get lucky sometimes i still
learn a ton even even this far in my
career i'm learning a ton under csi you
just it's it's how it goes i mean 20
years 20 years ago when i was in my
early 20s or whatever
you know you could go on the the breeder
forums
uh the of overgrow for instance yeah and
all of a sudden sam skunk man's on there
yeah and tom hill's on there
and chimera is on there
and like guys that are like real good at
what they're up to yeah and know a lot
and are opinionated and you know or and
they're fighting amongst each other over
who's what
yeah battling over this or that but in
those battles you get to see like well
here's why i believe this
yeah
you know and you could read that stuff
and you could get a lot more educated
yeah
you know
um
and so you know yeah you learn from you
learn from observation you learn from
someone teaching you you learn from
reading and various sources i mean
someone asked me
uh earlier today like you know what's
the what's the go-to how if i want to
start breeding where would i want to
learn
i told you i'll go to marijuana botany
yeah yeah that's that's what i always
tell everyone when it comes in here
marijuana first place if you want a
primer
rob clark did a real good job of laying
out all the basics so you might i don't
think anything's come close even remote
like there's greg green's breeders bible
all that and respect to him but i don't
think anything's come close uh to robert
clark's um marijuana botany even though
it's outdated
it still has so much info that is never
going to be outdated in it
it's it's like it really is a true bible
if you want the basics
and you want the terminology and you
want how the [ __ ] works and you know
yeah obviously it was written a long
time ago so things have advanced in
certain ways but like
um it's still a really good core
core thing to learn
sure um and that's and that's you know
that you know so the other part of it is
like people should probably realize that
um
when people
uh which did you call it with with red
and camaro the shotgunning method matt
yeah yeah the shotgun scatter method the
mailman you take some males you're like
these males look good to me
i'm gonna throw them on these plants and
see what happens sometimes you use one
sometimes you use five
yeah and then you'd have to grow up a
bunch of seed and be like which ones
have the traits in them that i want to
do for the next round yeah
you know um and so we it was kind of
more i think 20 years ago it was a lot
more traditional breeding
yeah you were forced
to take multi-stage breeding yeah
for the most part yeah
you know
um yeah and and you know and so
uh you know someone mentioned subcool or
gypsy nirvana i mean yeah the general
point is that
more and more people started being able
to offer seeds to the public
yeah whether they were making their own
seeds whether they were middle manning
seeds from other people
you know there started to be a wider
variety of places where you could
actually get them yeah
i mean it started off with two
right sorry bryn's doing a dance for me
you went from you you used to have to go
to amsterdam and and that's part of the
reason why like ssse
and neville met all those important
people
yeah because they were the only people
doing what they did
so all these interested parties whether
it's seattle greg or sam skunkman or rob
clark or
um
jim ortega they all met the same dudes
yeah because there's two of them
right and then there was 10 and then
there was 20.
and so
some cool was a lot of people's first
breeder disappointment
yeah um you know
there's a there's a there's a phrase uh
that's used a lot not not in cannabis
but just in general which is don't get
to know your heroes
yeah you know it applies to music it
applies to art it applies to a lot of
things sometimes your heroes the more
you get to know them the more you're
impressed by them
yeah sometimes it's
you're like oh my god how did why do
people think this way about this person
yeah
you know um and uh
you know and and and so you know because
see seeds have always been shady
always you know they're beans they all
look just like some you know i mean they
don't have that much variation in them
yeah they look like seeds some of them
were tire strikes some of them are pale
some are big some are small
but it's like you know you buy these
things and you don't know what you get
for months
yeah and then it was all prohibition so
what are you gonna like there's no like
you're not gonna leave a bad yelp review
yeah jumping online on amazon and being
like this [ __ ] bag [ __ ] i i suppose
you know like you didn't you were just
like you told your friends and that was
bunk
but like there wasn't you know like the
forums were the first place that people
started to talk back and forth amongst
like what'd you find
yeah
right
what'd you find you know and so it's
always been it's always been a little
bit rough because
uh you know i talked about it on a show
earlier too where people like shanti and
others all those people in the second
generation
they decided to start hiding the lineage
of what they used
because they didn't want all their
competitors to just copy them
yeah
i have been trying to figure out what
the exact parents are of ak-47
since
ak-47 popped up in the mid-90s
you know and
i did invite
uh simon on to talk about
that
um and and luke from paradise simon said
he would but luke from paradise is
another one where you just don't know
what the genetics are in any of his
lines but he's made some really awesome
lines scentsy star
yeah who knows
who [ __ ] knows i mean there's
theories about it being a big sur holy
weed cross all kinds of different [ __ ]
there's all kinds of theories and they
don't know because neville and and
carell from sssc didn't have any
competition they were just like this is
this and this
yeah this is how i got it this is where
i got it this is what i did with it yeah
this came from a guy in new york in a
bad seat here yeah this came from this i
bought these two cuts in oregon
and that's how i got the g13 and this
hash plant you know
yeah and then the second wave
they all obscured most of what they were
using and why
yeah and maybe they did it for
competitive reasons
but for like historians or people really
wanting to know the lineage
uh i don't know how many hours matt and
i and a group of our friends have spent
trying to figure out what's we've
scoured everywhere
looking for lineage on some of this
stuff oh yeah and you get hints here and
there but it's never anything you can go
off of even if you can track down the
original quote-unquote breeder or person
who relates release the seeds
nine times out of ten you're still not
going to know at the very end just
because so the nature of how they remain
back then people say cherry ak
um
you know ak was a very it had a great
name for the time
simon only sold six things
um and you know probably four of them
were pretty fire
yeah uh
and uh it you know and it's um
you know there was a sandalwood ak in
um
in colorado uh matt's done a bunch of
work with the cherry ak
i had a lemon ak for quite a while too
that we did work with there's the rc
cola ak
back in the day yeah it doesn't i mean
even like uh who doesn't like nebu or
something like that get all upset and
say no one else could have a cherry ak
but him
yes which is preposterous because if he
found it in seeds of ak-47
it obviously can pop
well i mean he says
technically he says he owns
he owns cherry liqueur ak-47 but he owns
also all of cherry ak-47 that no one
else has a right to use the name is what
he says yeah
obviously it's just a flavor profile
that pops up in that cross yeah so it's
like pretty hard to like
be like i'm i'm trademarking this this
terp
it wasn't even his strain but no you
know like i'm the first one that came up
um
and uh you know and so
you know he had but what's in cali mist
what's in the only one i think he
actually said that you knew something
was he had white russian yeah white
russian that's right
you knew half of it because it was white
widow by ak-47 yeah you know
um but aka and kali and some a lot of
these different things like people start
obscuring what's actually in stuff
yeah
you know or
they started taking famous
names you remember when who was who was
the who was the group uh
um that claimed to have nl9 in canada
oh i don't know on that one i remember
nl6 from kenny from trichome
technologies that wasn't related to nl6
yeah so there's so and you know
that's the thing now is that
you know we talked about todd a little
bit or whatever but there's people that
are popping up with these 80s and 90s
seed lines
yeah
and the names are so famous
neville did say
uh collie missed his nl5 haze
uh but then neville was bitter and very
i liked neville i liked neville i mean
he's a neville stan is what we call them
yeah but
neville was famous for being bitter and
saying everybody in holland everything
was from me
yeah they all ripped me off
and that happened when he came back
about nobody had nobody had anything
nobody had anything original and yeah to
his to his credit i will say
um
you know adam and simon and uh and tony
left his company and started their own
seed companies yeah and all of a sudden
had a bunch of lines really fast yeah
so it's a little sus
yeah
yeah that was probably right that his
stuff is in
a lot of what's around it doesn't mean
it doesn't mean that it doesn't mean
that like
all the stuff
that they used was from him
yeah
but they probably took some stuff
yeah probably even
probably even some breeding males you
know what was always interesting to me
about the whole um
hidden lineage type thing was that if
these guys were super
super well schooled breeders they would
have known that even if the people had
had the recipe let's say they just had
the generic recipe of white widow crust
the blueberry from blue widow and
they're like ha we figured it out they
could never remake it the same unless
they had the exact same clowns sure
it just didn't make any sense to me that
they would ever hide the lineage but
that yet it did happen
pot of gold is fire someone's kind well
i looked at the comments yeah um pot of
gold and uh
and the real mccoy were my two favorite
lines from the flying dutchman
yeah one of them was hawaiian by skunk
one and the other one was a hindu kush
by skunk one yeah i have a bunch of the
real mccoy i think that's the hawaiian
one it's the hawaiian one yeah they were
really good um
you know and so
yeah they uh um
they were like the reason why
the reason people someone just asked how
come
a bunch of the other nl numbers aren't
famous
um it's because after three or four
years of breeding with them
neville decided to use the one the two
and the female cut he found of the five
basically and that's it yeah so the
three four six seven eight nine 10 11
um they just weren't sold
yeah
you know they weren't sold
um and greg only seattle greg he really
he only sent them to what he told what
did he tell us he said he sent them to
neville and the drunkers
yeah
so there was basically only neville and
then scentsy
yeah and sensei just ran with what
neville had already discovered at the
seed bank yeah
so you know um
you know and so that's kind of where
they went is that and it makes sense
because if you think about it from
neville's perspective i mean he always
used to joke that he could be like
i'm gonna release the most fire line
ever and someone's like oh i found two
bananas and it didn't yield as much this
line sucks
yeah
sucks ass
right and so even back then the people
felt pressure from consumers
yeah
yeah and so
you know people like to breed with stuff
that makes happy customers
yeah
you know nl's 6 7 8 9 10 11 or whatever
that were all like like messes of afghan
and and sativa
they probably were a big mess and a pain
in the ass
very likely he said that he was using a
lot of indians
mexicans colombians mixed up in that in
that bid so there's going to be some
wild [ __ ] that just wasn't good that
they crossed it i mean even today most
people don't want to grow something
that's longer than nine or ten weeks
yeah exactly you get some nl10 or
whatever and you grow it and it takes 13
weeks and you [ __ ] can it
you know
most people would still do that today
yeah i would think so
just because it's like it it
you know and so
um
that i don't know like it
and so then maybe we should we should
talk about something for a minute where
it's like the real
so for let's say from like 85 to 2005
okay um
it was it was all
traditional breeding as the lord
intended it was all males and females
yeah you know
you just you let a few males go in a
room full of ladies
um and all the traditional types of
breeding were applied for the most part
because that's all anybody knew
yeah
and then uh around um
you know uh
i don't know matt knows better than me
but probably somewhere around
say oh six to 2010
yeah
uh
a revolution happened
in that um and i'll shut up here in a
minute and let matt talk but certain
people started on the forums
uh and doing research and stuff like
that figuring out that you could you
could induce a female plant to produce
pollen
yeah and you could make feminized seed
yeah and that information was rare and
tightly held and how to do it was
basically unknown
and
at first
matt knows better than i do
but it was kind of like who was it it
was you and
well i mean if you if you start back
with the feminized stuff you had dutch
passion really starting it um hai
was doing some work on it sam the skunk
man had covered a little bit of it
fett from spice brothers had talked
about it a bit and he was over in i
think new zealand
but as far as the american stuff it
really didn't kick on into the american
stuff till like og rascal
hybe me csi
and there are a few others but um soma
yeah someone mentioned soma his
his
rotalization method was notorious which
was basically the torture method the
herm torture method
right the small pop the extreme drought
that gets the hell out of it they get it
to think it's dying multiple times to
the point where it freaks out and panics
and throws some manners that you can use
yeah and and
during during that period probably i
mean i want to say all the way up to
like
2013 2014 femme seeds were just looked
down upon or at least the general
consensus was all femmes herm often see
term they all produce poor [ __ ]
progeny it's all it's all riddled with
[ __ ] mutants and you know and and even
though that wasn't the case and people
weren't finding that it didn't matter it
was such a common a common theme
that you were cheating
cheating
was a huge there was a huge issue with
with feminized seed where most customers
felt like you were cheating
yeah
you were [ __ ] up lines
you were selling out for profit
you were getting rid of males and
getting rid of traditional breeding so
you could
um you could skip steps and profit
yeah and people were looked down on
yeah for feminized breeding and i should
make the point the reason why i said it
you know that era was because
all the first people that matt mentioned
they were not sharing
how they did it
no
you couldn't find out from dutch passion
how they were making feminize seed
no no they didn't want that you couldn't
find out from that you couldn't find out
from any of these people yeah right so
did it exist yes
was it hidden knowledge 100
one of the first people i did actually
see say how to do it was phet
um
and he released someone else's info that
was around but put it out there pretty
wide and it was the first recipe um on
how to make sts mixture that i saw but
caleb remembers better than me on who
was the original person that wrote it
but my first introduction to it was when
fett published it
right and so you know
yeah that stuff was
um
someone said collodial silver was hidden
knowledge
you know people want to say that like
all the knowledge that people have right
now
um
even with breeders like matt or like csi
or people that have been doing feminized
seeds for the last 10 to 12 14 years
yeah it's still an art form with a lot
of failure
yes and there was a lot of failure in
the beginning it wasn't just like oh i'm
going to spray collodial silver or i'm
going to spray some sts
and now i'm done
yeah you know when i was doing a bunch
of breeding
you don't really fail with males
no no yeah i've never had a male tail
you know like you don't i never had i
never like was like oh i failed that
whole seed run and now i'm growing like
18 different strains
one or two of each right yeah yeah you'd
have one or two or three males and they
would produce an enormous amount of
pollen for your whole room
yeah
um when people first started
experimenting and
let's be clear
we're not done experimenting
no matt
and csi and i and matt and csi and other
various friends we talk all the time
about improving methods
limiting failure
everyone fails
yeah trying to trying to find the
consist what what brings consistency in
reversals is
it's very hard i mean me
i talked about this with csi three or
four times a week just our different
findings and and comparing our notes and
all that [ __ ] and it's just we no one's
found a consistent way to
guarantee that every plant every
expression of every plant meaning not
just pheno but it's
like expressions and
of the same clone two feet apart why one
reverses and drops pollen and the other
reverses and doesn't there we have no
answers to this yet i mean and it's
always experimenting they've done you
know they've done things where it's like
matt or him have have reversed something
and it's worked like a charm and they've
gotten unbelievable results and it's
dumped pollen yeah and then they go back
and they use those same plants to
reverse them again and they do the same
thing to the plant and it fails
yeah
or
or drops 10 of the amount of pollen it
should
yeah
um and so
you know i see i see our buddy pip yeah
he failed i mean and failure is really
frustrating for a breeder
yeah you know you might only get
if if you're non-stop breeding you might
only get three or four cracks at
breeding a year
and if you want to buy the sds spray
it's on riot seat code.com we got our
reversal sprint someone asked about it
so i'm gonna say
reversal spray up at right seatco.com or
you can buy it but just just read the
read the directions because i'm very
very transparent sometimes you're gonna
have to try three or four times not to
get it to reverse but to drop pollen
there's a big difference reversing
doesn't mean success
showing balls doesn't mean success you
only have success when it drops pollen
and makes seeds and makes seeds and
and you know even just on the forums and
all the learning of like how much of
what of each to use
should i use collodial silver should i
use sts should i use this other thing
should i use that have i tried this
yeah do i need less concentration do i
need more concentration when do i
combine them do i apply it once strong
do i apply it 15 times a week
and if you do all that and get success
and try to repeat it the next time the
exact same way with all the same inputs
it may not perform the same way it's
it's so uh
it's frustrating it is so in a way
um
you know uh
the the forum's slowly
slowly pushing
feminized seed was like a sea change in
how people bred
yeah because before everyone had to have
males
and everyone had to keep those males and
everybody traded seed
and then and then people were like oh i
can take this elite
and i can reverse it and cross it to
these other elites
yeah and so now most breeders honestly
don't even have males
a lot don't no yeah most most it's
completely shifted in the last 10 to 14
years from like a few people getting
[ __ ] on for daring to reverse plants and
cheating to being
the way everyone does it
yep
and i made i made a backwards switch
where i did almost all exclusively
feminized breeding for a long time
and
went back to doing mostly male breeding
despite selling the spray just because
uh
it is costly it is super costly to make
femme seeds because of uh the failure
i mean we've talked about it we've
talked about it before and our like
uh our buddy pip commented but
um we've had a bunch of really good
friends
that have tried to reverse sour
and uh um and failed
yeah
you know or
you know i remember you know you know
pip reversed it once and got like 30
seeds yeah
so you do this you do this whole thing
and all of a sudden you're like oh i
have a little handful for myself
but i can't actually sell them to the
public
i don't even have enough to give to my
friends
yeah i think csi the first two or three
times he tried to reverse tk failed yeah
it was real bad and he kept trying
different methods to even get the thing
to reverse
yeah and he finally got it to reverse
and it gave him about 10 or 15 of the
seeds he would normally get from
something that reversed well yeah
um so you know it it's completely
shifted how people breed
it's completely shifted what they're
after it's completely shifted like what
um
you know what uh
uh
what customers expect
because when i was talking about in the
beginning a lot of these seed lines they
would be available for like five or ten
years
yeah
most seeds today are one-offs
right
and maybe that same breeder will go back
and redo the line again
but most seeds exist
from however many seeds that dude got or
that lady got
until they're gone yeah and someone's
asking about red pollen on femme plants
it's totally fine it's totally fine a
lot of a lot of today's clone on the
lines that are being hit are
femmes they're just made with bad seed
herns so i mean it's it's so common that
it's in moot point
yes and yeah you could have things that
you don't realize are a femme plant
but yeah
you know and
you know um there i we i do have some
thoughts on why things don't reverse
well
that could be a show in itself
yeah um but people people should think
about
um you know because one of the things
that breeders get hated on the most
which i'm actually supportive of is
herms
yeah
um because you got to think about for
for forever of cannabis history
perms were a survival tool
yeah that allowed female plants to
pollinate themselves and continue the
species if for some reason the males got
killed or the pollen failed or they
weren't around yeah and so lots of
strains hurt
yeah and then in the beginning all the
weed was seeded
so why would you care if it hurt
yeah it was relevant you're selling
seeded weed all the thai all the
colombian all the mexican all this that
it was all it was all seat it was all
seated yeah so it's only really herm
started only really becoming an issue
for people
in probably the 90s
late 80s early 90s when people were
growing indoor and they had a very small
amount of weed they were trying to grow
for them or their friends or whatever
and they didn't want to get a seated
room
right
yep um
but
those herms had been bred in as a
survival mechanism for cannabis for
millennia probably
and we've and there's only been about 30
years of pressure to get rid of them
yeah
right
and then now the cookies is the
abundance
it's back in full form well what happens
to is somebody mentioned s-ones you know
and stuff and and you know s-ones
i'll be the maybe i'm not the first to
tell you but s-ones kind of suck
right yeah um you know i mean obviously
i have friends that sell s1 so i'm not
dissing it but even they will tell you
that like
the primary goal of an s1 is to find to
look in that exact strain without an
outcross
and see what's in its genetics
or for preservation period yeah or for
preservation you know and and you're
more likely to try to find an
elite or two or something you like
um than you are to get any kind of
consistency yes you know um if you want
consistency and you want phenols to pop
at some rate and outcross is better
yeah all right
but in a lot of cases
there might only be one cutting left of
an entire line for you to work through
yeah there might not be a male you know
there people don't keep males either
so how do you get a male a trinity
yeah how do you how do you get a male of
dog [ __ ] how do you get a male a corn
how do you get a male of
of you know you name it yeah
you know i know in a lot of cases you
can't
you used to be able to get males by
you'd buy the seed line and it was a
regular seed line yeah
now that it's almost all femme you can't
even get a male if you wanted to
yeah it would take some uh a lot of work
people say why are some s1s uniform and
some aren't
because
if you have a bunch of uniform
s1s it means that there's not very much
genetic variation in that cut whatsoever
if you get a bunch of crazy stuff all
over the place it means that you have a
pretty wide genetic lineage in there and
it's going to express in all kinds of
different ways so to dumb it down it
just means
if you have a bunch of variation you
have a line that probably wasn't worked
if you have a a uniform line it was
probably whatever that clone was came
from a line that was either worked or
already uniform to begin with by nature
yeah
you know so
um
you know and and so males have become
super rare
you know and
and all that and everyone is and so
breeding has gone from almost a
guaranteed success
to very dicey yeah
i would say yeah and and in
natural agriculture or like agriculture
normal agriculture
most most breeding work is done with
selfing and feminizing it's it's not a
lot of male work um cannabis is just
catching up to that
just catching up to it
and you know it um
and that's the other part of it is like
real real i don't say real breeding
because i don't want to insult anyone
but
agricultural breeding they are breeding
with very specific goals in mind
yeah
you know
um mostly bleeding is goals mostly
that's what it is well i mean in
cannabis breeding i don't know if it's
goals no seed making seed making in
cannabis is not goals but actual
breeding
so so for instance if you're breeding
something like i'll just throw it out
there like corn you might be going for
ear size and disease resistance and pest
resistance and when it finishes and you
have certain traits you're looking for
yeah and if you're gonna self or you're
gonna like breed on that level you're
finding plants that match all those
characteristics and you're trying to
lock them in
yeah
you know um
for the way we breed now
most people are just most people aren't
growing rooms a seed anymore
you're just pheno hunting
for a lot of people yeah you know so
there's not a lot of breeders that are
like i need to be able to breed this
super consistent urkel by snow
because people are going to plant acres
of it and these are the qualities
they're looking for when they plant it
yeah
you're like crossing things and then
hoping
you know hoping something pops up and so
you know our buddy bitter just said
breeding should be goal-oriented it
should
yeah i mean
and the more goals you add to what you
want the harder you made your job
yeah it's real hard the more you start
adding to it
finding what you want in one plant the
more things you put on that plant that
you have to have is tough
yeah
you know um
and so a lot of times now
maybe we should talk about this for a
second because this is totally your era
where it's like when breeding
breeding became
i'm going to reverse this plant
that's an elite that most people can't
get
yeah and i'm going to cross it to these
10 or 15 things that you also probably
can't get
yeah and i'm going to sell seeds and you
probably can't get either parent but
here's a hybrid
yeah and you've already gotten excited
about both parents
so maybe there's something cool in the
hybrid i haven't tested it
but there's a lot of breeders out there
now
that don't test their own work
yes correct they take this they're going
to be like you know and i'm not calling
anybody out specifically but it's like
i'm going to take gelato this and i'm
going to reverse it onto the
12 most popular cuts i know of
that are getting decent a decent ticket
and then i'm going to add packaging and
i'm going to make a special name for
each one and i'm going to hope somebody
finds something bomb and it helps my
sales yeah
you do you don't yeah you do lose you do
you lose hybrid vigor with s1 there
isn't a hybrid vigor there is no hybrid
you're breathing with your
you can lose vigor yes with s1's however
depending on it it's it's
it depends on how you compare it because
there's lines that are old clones that
are slow and if you if you make s ones
of it it'll make it look like you've
given the line new vigor but it's just
because you were growing an old slow
clone so
it depends on how people look at it but
hybrid vigor it it like like not so
saying it it implies hybrid hybridizing
and if it's an s1 it's selfie not
hyperbolic the way i look at maybe this
is a bad definition too because we could
talk about how misused uh names are in
in you know people get breeding terms
from other areas and try to apply them
to cannabis yeah and it doesn't it's not
exactly a straight because we don't have
the same kind of breeding techniques
but generally speaking uh hybrid vigor
is when you take two p1 parents and
cross them and in the hybrid
all of the dominant genes pop
it's not just two p1 parents though it's
two specifically
different genotypes it has it's not they
can't be similar in order to get it it
has to be totally different to get the
hybrid figure so you know a famous one
would be you know i don't know nl5 haze
or something yeah yeah
would be one a very a very indica with a
very sativa
very different lineages pops right yes
um and so and that's another thing too
is people don't like this and this is
this is what's like
if you look on some of the lineage stuff
of like i'm going to cross cushmints by
apples and banana by this and that like
there's so much incestuous stuff that's
gone on because people have overused the
same clones over and over and over and
over again yeah
most of the most successful crosses are
by crossing vastly different things from
one another
reading today is a lot more of i wonder
if i can find my own slight variation on
this already popular theme
yeah
wouldn't you agree yeah i'm not saying
everyone i'm not going to everyone
there's no exceptions but the majority
is looking for this is already popular
maybe i can get maybe the name and maybe
the look and maybe the pictures will
catch on yeah
and if i get one famous thing you know
i'm not going to call them out but like
um look at what
finding mac one did for for cap yeah
you know somebody finds a what they
consider to be a killer pheno in your
stuff
and all of a sudden the next
however many seed drops you have sell
out
yeah and there's hype around it
yeah but most people don't find their
own stuff because they're not
um
they're not growing their own stuff
yeah honestly like our buddy caleb is
one of the few people where you can just
see years and years and years of him
popping his own seeds that he made yeah
i'm gonna answer this question real
quick
um because it's one i see a lot and and
it's there's no steadfast answer to it
um it was from nigel no friends how much
phenotypic genotypic variation do you
experience from s-ones i've read a lot
of contradicting information and the
answer is it really depends on how
worked
one parent was if it's if it's a self
how how worked that clone was and how
not worked
the the pollen donor is um if if it's a
worked line let's say it's a
a
a deep chunk let's go deep jump if it's
a deep chunk and you s one deep chunk
you're not going to have very much
variation at all because it's a work
line there's already very few phenotypes
in the line that you selected the clone
from let's say you choose like cushman's
you you s1a phenotype of cushman's well
there's all kinds of [ __ ] in that i
mean it's going to be variant
to any degree you know so that's that's
why there's no specific answer to how
much variation is in an s1 it just
really depends on the parents and
another way to put it and uh
uh caleb talked about this before where
it's like
let's say you were to s1 deep chunk
yeah and you were to give out a bunch of
those seeds and let people make their
own selections
because there's not much variation in
that line
the people's own selections they're
probably going to look a lot like deep
chunk yeah but he's he's talked about
like how the mendo p that i that i found
has very very wide variation in in the
s-ones which leads us to believe that it
might be an actual land race right
um so you could he's like you know you
could give 50 or 100 seeds to 20 people
and tell them pick what they want
yeah and then if you had them two years
later all gather and bring the weed that
they had created
it would look vastly different because
people would be making their own choices
and that's actually some of the stuff
even early on like people like mel frank
that sent durbin to holland
or different things breeders will tell
you well it was this way when i had it
yeah but then i gave it to these guys
and they made different choices than i
would have yeah and now it's not even
remotely like what i preferred
yeah because they made different choices
than i did
sure i liked it anise and they made it
all red hair and sweet
yeah or bite or this or that or whatever
so
um
you know it uh
so s1 s s1 is just a tool
like these are all just these are all
just tools there's no there's no like
better way than another necessarily
um they're all just like based on what
you're looking for
you know um are you looking for
you know it's never really happened
before but like are you looking for like
i want to plant 10 acres and i want it
to be uniform
something like as uniform as deep chunk
would be very valuable for that
yeah absolutely you know something like
you know but there's other there's other
lines that are all over the place that
wouldn't be very good for that
but that line that's all over the place
it might be amazing to find
a unique
expression that you can then clone and
name and all of a sudden it becomes an
elite
and and to add to that
a lot of people don't understand that
when you select a clone uh from a from a
wide varied line let's say it's
you pop a thousand seats and it's the
only clone like it if you select that
clone to breathe
it may not be breeding true to the type
that it is because it was an outlier it
may only show up one in 500 times in the
f2 round so it doesn't necessarily mean
because you picked that clone it's
always going to be like that clone if
that clone is an outlier you are not
going to run into that clone very often
it'll be more often than you did in the
f1 but however
it'll still not be very often
again it could be an odd combination of
recessive traits yep and just because it
popped in that particular female doesn't
mean it'll pop in it's progeny
yeah
either
with me sorry that's all right
and you know people there was a guy up
there saying get rid of all the anise
you know um
you know everybody has strong opinions
about various flavors i don't think we
should get rid of any flavor
um because everyone has different
preferences
yeah
yeah you know
um there was yeah don't say that here
because then gene's gonna think that i'm
[ __ ] [ __ ] talking him and [ __ ] all
that [ __ ] no there was a time
there was a time when uh when
um
you know like terpenoline in uh
in uh watching my [ __ ] uh
you know and jack
or train wreck
was loved
it was certainly loved yeah it was
absolutely loved and then it bred so
true for itself that people got burnt
out on the true penalty yeah
people
[ __ ] a man people
like calio and all this citrus stuff
came out
and it was hella popular for a minute
and then it's like moderate potency and
kind of one note and it sort of faded
from
it sort of faded from the world a little
bit yeah
and then you know the dab revolution
happened well you know with and nails
started coming out and all these
accoutrements to be able to like smoke
hash in a different way yeah and [ __ ]
dna comes out with tangy yeah and the
most blown out terp that nobody wanted
was new again
and people were like oh this citrus is
just phenomenal oh my god
stoked on this citrus where did this
come from where 10 years before people
would be like ooh citrus no no no
yeah i don't want a [ __ ] citrus i
call that [ __ ] headache weed man i
always
i was not a fan of uh calio or uh any
kind of tangy or any of that [ __ ] but
what's interesting about that kind of
stuff is when tangy came out you know um
because it came out in the first few
years of sort of like the modern like
hash dab revolution yeah
it's not very potent
no but it didn't matter as flower you'd
get bored of it pretty quickly yeah but
you turn it into bho or you turn it like
there wasn't rosin really then you turn
it into some kind of extract and now it
goes from like 13 percent thc to 80.
yeah
and it gets everything at that point you
know and there was an there was another
aspect too where it's like a lot of
times with extractions not all those
terps come through strong
yeah but those citrus terps popped
strong
so all of a sudden they had it's like
bell bottoms coming back or something
yeah like you know you you couldn't give
them away
and then all of a sudden the next
generation is like this citrus is
incredible can we get more lemon can we
get more orange can we get more
tangerine yeah
and it's kind of faded
right yeah
i mean we had a our our buddy uh
our buddy pip rocked that lemon g cut
yeah a lot
you know and so people things go in and
out of things go in and out of in and
out of flavor you know
i was talking about that with panda the
other day i was smoking some georgia pie
and i had no no [ __ ] clue what it was
like what was in it but
lemon g
has this certain specific [ __ ] flavor
that runs through all of its progeny and
it's this thing get like for me i could
not scrape that flavor off my tongue
hard or fast enough but i smoked that
georgia pie and you can immediately
sense it in there but it's not listed in
the genetics so i hope those people who
have it out there give it give it a give
it a little flavor puff and if you have
some lemon g to compare it to uh uh tell
me if i'm right
so it you know and someone someone was
talking about just just now like they
were talking about how uh
um
you know
uh train wreck train wreck was kind of
unique because it was like it was one of
the first named clones in humboldt
yeah it yielded really big
people was all of a sudden going indoors
and stuff and getting big heels out of
it
and you know jack herrera becoming so
popular
burned people out on the terp for
probably 10 years
yeah
and train wreck being just [ __ ]
everywhere for a while
yeah train wrecking they just it just
gets burned out you know and so you know
flavors and terp profiles come and go
yeah you know uh i i don't really like
like for me like like that kind of
citrus isn't that popular because i
think it's too one dimensional for me
but i do like the sweet
citrus there's some of it where it's it
it it tastes like i opened my mouth and
sprayed orange cleaner on directly on my
tongue yeah yeah it's like astringent
yeah that's how i feel about lemon g is
it's just like having a lemon grow a
dick and piss in your mouth
yeah you know and so like if you like
sushi or whatever like uh citrus could
be like a really good like like pickled
ginger
it could be like a really good palate
cleanser before you smoke something else
but most people can't rock citrus all
day long
no
no you know they got me anyways they get
burned out on it but some people love it
so it tends to like you know i mean
that's that's kind of the thing where
um i can't remember who commented on it
but we were talking a bunch about skunk
one in a previous episode
and there was an era where like they
gypsy nirvana and those different guys
they all gave away skunk one as freebies
yeah oh yeah because they had because
they had a [ __ ] ton of it nobody wanted
to buy it
nobody wanted skunk one nobody nobody
you couldn't sell it for [ __ ] so he's
like god i got thousands of these things
maybe i'll at least just give them out
as free or remember when they were
everyone was giving out skunk haze
yeah yeah or isaac on case yeah
the thunk
the thunk yeah thunk yeah the thunk
and then
you know now all of a sudden people are
like oh what old rare skunk one can you
find
give me some of that old rare skunk one
and there's people from 15 years ago
they're giving me you mean the [ __ ] that
they were giving out for free and nobody
wanted yeah and i'm not even dissing it
no it's just how it was it's just it's
just people things go in and out of
fashion yeah
you know
um and uh
you know i mean
uh
the blue flavor
does it taste like blueberries
yes whoa
i've never smoked weed that tasted like
blueberries i want to get something
yeah
right a good blueberry should taste like
blueberries yeah
you know and and so
you know um
super skunk is not still around
uh
i mean from scentsy
i just mean like like there aren't
what we know of for sure as pure
super skunk cuts
we believe diesel is a is is there's a
lot of stuff this derives from it yeah i
think jesus is probably one of the
closest but yeah we don't know if it's a
hybrid of super skunk technically like
we can't say
we we can look at it and be like man it
really has a lot of super skunk traits
yeah extremely skunkoid in the way that
it grows and the way that it is and the
way that that but
maybe that's maybe that's something that
we should talk about because matt and i
talked about it when we were kind of
like mapping out what we wanted to chat
is that
every five or ten years
uh what you can get from seed reinvents
itself and so there's all these distinct
arrows
yeah
and i i mentioned it before on on
another thing but we were matt and i
were looking through a friend's
um freezer that he was getting rid of
and it had an enormous amount of seeds
from like 08 to
2012.
yeah and i would say 99 of them if you
wanted to buy a pack of it today you
couldn't get it yeah
yeah
there was tons of there you could never
get there there was stuff from mr knight
there was there was a few things here
and there that you could get from the
same company but for the most part it
was all like but that stuff at the time
was hella popular yeah
right yeah
it was everywhere back then but it was
everywhere it was everywhere it was
hella popular and then you know he
talked about og rascal og rascal for
three or four years
you know he had a bunch of good cuts and
he was one of the first guys doing
feminized seed and he made a bunch of
fire yeah he even had a super skunk cut
that was uh the 56 days super skunk i
want to say something like that
but you you you couldn't you can't find
that [ __ ] now nope
no it doesn't exist so so what happens
is seeds people talk sensi scentsy still
exists
but
you you can't get anything like you
would get from 90 censi no nothing you
can't get you can't get 90s serious
seats
yeah i mean some of these people might
get mad at me for saying it but it's
just like it's just not the way [ __ ]
works
it does it just doesn't work it's
different the parents are different
maybe they had to reconstitute the line
from seed you know
maybe they outsourced it to spain
who knows yeah
um
for sure most most seeding most seeds
are they're there until they're not
there and then after
you know 10 years or something like that
the only thing that exists might be a
cut or two yeah
right well we're about
almost at 100 minutes so we'll start
turning this down yeah we're going in
far
so yeah is there anything else you
wanted to get in
you know i mean that this is a big topic
you know i just lost a huge topic i just
thought that it would be good for people
to chat about there's a lot of
misconceptions about what breeders are
up to
and what they're doing and what their
methods are and and and you know
um all that and like breeding has
evolved a lot
and yeah breeding also evolves based on
competition and based on what the
customers want yeah
right
it's the customers drive it fully now
it's
because because the prices are so low on
wheat currently i don't think that there
is a a
an option for breeders to try to drive a
market as much based on
um
their own hype their own you know like
building a brand building the line it's
not like it was
no and i think there was a when i was
doing most of my breeding
there was there wasn't really american
breeders there wasn't really an outlet
yeah for those kind of seeds
that i you know we were we we wanted to
be but this was it was too early
yeah and there was kind of i would say
there's probably a 10-year explosion of
american breeders and all kinds of
people being able to jump in and be like
i'm gonna make crosses with this yeah
and that's kind of i think we're coming
to the tail end of that now yeah we
definitely are people are having to
figure out whole different ways of
reinventing their companies themselves
how seeds are sold
how they're marketed yeah
yeah and and and just you know and on
top of that it's like
it was profitable for a while
yeah and and the profit is is you know
uh
profit is defined you know most of these
seed companies were all supported by a
bunch of small and medium-sized growers
with extra money in their pocket yeah
so as it becomes more centralized and it
becomes more legalized
then there's less money going around
there's less desire to hunt through
things yeah
less ability yeah yeah and even and even
then too it's like
people today if you want to start
breeding today you're going to get a
hodgepodge of plants that are a mix of
everything that's been popular in the
last 15 years
big worm
was the high water mark was we're
holding his dick picture got weak that
was the highest that was the highest
point we ever got
that's for damn sure
i i mean you know a lot of these a lot
of these people got famous for a minute
yeah in certain circles you know
um
yeah you know lucky dog lucky dog is our
is our buddy uh you know he
he uses a lot of real cuts
yeah and one of the best ways to be a
good breeder as neville would say is to
have good good plants to work with
yeah
you can be he knows good weed he's been
around good weed forever that's a major
advantage
yeah knowing good weed knowing good weed
and
and honestly um
maybe uh i always i always get weirded
out when i talk about this but maybe we
could finish a little bit on this is
that
what's happened a lot with ig
as we're on ig
is uh
yeah um it's it's become very visual
yeah uh breeding and people's desire for
stuff has become extremely visual and
extremely testing based and extremely
named based
where 20 years ago 15 years ago it was
mostly effect based
yeah right things became popular because
they had a great flavor a great effect
right uh because most people couldn't
see it
right
and so people bred for effect
and there's a there's a corollary here
where in uh i don't know most people i
don't know if people know this or not
but
pit bulls and like staffordshire
terriers are basically the same breed
right yes staffordshire terriers are
bred for looks
and back in the day when when actual dog
fighting was still allowed pit bulls
were bred for what was called game
yeah right and game was basically a
uh i don't approve of dog reading by the
way but it's a good example game was
basically
um
a complete disregard for its own health
and a willingness to just get crazy and
fight to the death yeah
but you couldn't like but much like with
cannabis and smoking it you can't see
gain
yeah game isn't shoulder structure and
chin and jaw and color
none of that you have to find it in
there so
you can't tell if weed's going to knock
your head off by looking at it no you
sure can you know there's a lot of ugly
weed
that hits me way way harder than some of
the prettiest weed i've ever seen
that tests it like eight percent and it
will knock your head off harder than the
pretty no it's like a lot of good sours
or whatever they test in the low 20s
yeah exactly you get some purple punch
that tested 30 and i can't even tell i'm
smoking weed yeah and so there's a lot
of uh as people have bred for looks and
bed for testing
yeah they've lost that invisible effect
yeah
people call it the entourage effect they
think oh it's some combination of thc
and terps and this and that and theolos
or whatever we don't really know
what it's all there yet
yeah you know and but we know that
but people used to breed for effect
and people used to hold on to things
that had unique effects
and cookies and these and these type of
things started ushering in a wave and ig
is super to blame
for
you know for looks yeah
it looks gorgeous
you know oh this amazing tropicana
cookies it looks incredible what a great
job and then it doesn't get me high and
then you smoke it you're like [ __ ]
tangy mother [ __ ] yeah i mean like you
know who wants a girlfriend that's like
a true ten but she's mean to you you
know
i mean
like you know it's like that's that's no
fun either you know it's like what oh
yeah she looks amazing you're so lucky
and like oh no not when the door closes
she's totally rude and she sucks every
dude's dick yeah she cheats on me and
she treats and she's hella mean yeah
she's gorgeous
yeah you know and so there's a lot of
bland weed right now
there's a lot of very attractive very
bland weed
yeah a lot of blackberry kush out there
a lot of bland weed
yeah and so
you know uh
you know smoking for effect effect is
invisible you can't you don't know it
till you try it
there's nothing there's no testing you
know maybe we could get chimera on here
and he totally disagree with me and make
me look foolish but i still think that
the best test is the smoke test
yeah robots can't smoke weed and i'll go
to i'll go to bat for that i don't care
yeah because because of the end result
what matters is how it affects me
yeah or you
yeah but one of us and you know yeah
it's like it's it's whole it's our whole
desire for it is for it to i want it to
work good and taste good
yeah those are the top two things for me
effect and flavor now if i can get great
yield and i can get great looks i can
get all this other stuff great
yeah
you know but it's not i'd rather have it
taste taste and work phenomenal
yeah because in a joint you know
it looks like a white pee a white or a
tan piece of paper right yeah exactly
exactly in a bong rip and a you know i
mean what is it you know
you extract it you don't even know what
it looks like yeah now it's goo
yeah all all extractions look the same
to me i've never understood i mean
there's different types or whatever yeah
i mean in general it's all a [ __ ]
extract you're looking at goo or you're
looking for it's all different types of
goo so it's like you know at that at
that point uh what did what did chimera
call it uh you're a resin farmer
yeah that's right you're farming resin
yeah the flower content and stuff like
that
um
you know
it doesn't really matter so i'm big on
effect
yeah uh but effect doesn't come through
ig
until no it doesn't it's not yet
it's a lot harder to build rep off
effect because you actually have to
smoke it
yeah well it's not something test
results can tell you by looking at the
test results unfortunately no not yet at
least we can't you know but tomorrow
burner and and chris compound could come
out with the new new
yeah and it could be all glistening and
perfect lighting and professional camera
work and all that [ __ ] and everyone
would ooh and ah and this and that
nobody even knows if it's any good
yeah maybe its effect is boring
yeah yeah i remember a specific example
that i won't say but yeah yeah you know
so
i just wanted to throw that out there at
the end if we're going to talk about all
that is that you know breed for what's
important
yeah the most important thing is effect
right yeah because that's what you're
that's how it affects you yeah
and it doesn't affect everyone the same
so
you know try to smoke it with a decent
variety of friends
yeah
and see what they think too
that's how you find winners that's how
you find real keepers in my opinion
and that's and and to be honest
that's the reason why
you know stop some like a lot of these
things from 20 years ago are going to
have their day in the sun again
i hope so
because because look at all the people
right now coming out with i have real
sour
yeah that's true that's a good point
good point you know look at how many
people still breed with kush
yeah look at how many you know it's like
look at how many people on these go like
some friend you know are breeding with
nl5 hazes and stuff like yeah she has
lasting power
yeah
you know
where will purple punch be in 10 years
i hope everywhere i love that
well anyway yeah all right
i guess we're i you know you're going to
plug anything
um yeah go check out the website
riotsieco.com um we got our breeders
packs up we've got the spray up
um
uh you go check out
speakeasy.speakeasebank.com
and breeder syndicate has a bunch of new
episodes we've been dropping up um some
of its old content but newer episodes
and some of them had kind of fallen in
the
in the unhearable range meaning like
they just kind of disappeared now
they're back up so go check them out go
listen to them go support please like
and review or even if you don't like it
leave a review and say [ __ ] i suck do
whatever just go interact with it
hopefully hopefully you like it oh radio
yeah that outlet behind me it's a it's a
i don't know why there's some
interesting design choices in this house
i got alex gray canvas behind me
there you go it's it's an improvement
from the from the wall that i had before
but yeah we're going to throw these up
on podcasts too we're going to try to do
them every friday
and just talk about random stuff so you
can always hit up me or matt with
subject matter or ideas that you might
want to get talked about at length
um and oh yeah
join the the patreon bridge syndicate
patreon like a lot of you asking for not
to do a preview his his approval list is
[ __ ] miles long so the best way to
talk to natso is on the breeder
syndicate patreon go join and you can
talk to us
and you know we're trying to do this
thing where we talk about stuff that
mostly isn't about us
yeah and we're not trying to like
self-promote or anything we're just
trying to get a wide variety of weed
information out there and hopefully
people like it
so people use it
learn it learn from themselves how to be
critical thinkers we had a we had a
too long of a break but we're back at it
we're going to try to be pumping this
stuff out absolutely yep
so everybody have a real good night
thanks friday
lots of love everyone
[Music]