ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
thank you
what's up everyone
Wasabi hey what's up dude how goes it
all right
all right so everyone coming in
um the the Northern Lights five stock is
up on the site for the patreon members
so if you're a patreon member for
breeder Syndicate you can go buy them
right now boom they're up some of you
grabbed them already
and uh yeah so it's on right cco.com if
you are part of the patreon you can buy
the nl5 and the backstage area but now
we can talk about more important [ __ ]
like history like like uh uh what what
are we going to talk about not so
I mean tonight might be a a range of
things you know I uh we can talk a
little bit about
um NLS uh yeah a little bit and and uh
you know how things survive from now to
then you know we could talk about
um you know we can we're we were
thinking that we we actually opened it
up to some suggestions and there were
some things about some strains That Got
Away there was actually some pretty good
uh questions that came in so
um we're gonna try to tackle some of
those
you know uh you know throughout
throughout the thing and then you know
um one thing that maybe I should start
with is that uh you know we chatted
about some cam history some chem 101 and
stuff like that and you know whenever
you whenever you tackle like uh sort of
a big and famous weed history segment
right you're gonna get a lot of debate
right yeah uh which is good I like
master debaters you know and you want
different people to be able to
contribute and you want people to come
up and say things but then you're always
going to get people that are that are
going to pick apart one section that
they feel is incorrect or what often
happens and uh CSI and I were actually
talking about this last night is that
you know on some level when you want to
figure out the history it's like which
semi-untrustworthy person do you lean
more towards yeah right and there's
there's an aspect of that where it's
like it's very difficult to have a
situation where you feel like one person
is totally Angelic and honest in every
facet and this is how it is and there's
not debate so yeah debate is good
you know
um this guy just said he met Don the
Indian recently he's been dead for a
while so but you don't have to do that
there's an aspect to it where it was
like you anytime there's anybody famous
or even semi-famous uh especially if if
it's it's it's hard to like determine
who they are you're always going to get
there's not just fake cuts there's fake
people oh yeah right the second DJ Short
you know yeah there's there's you know
in any kind of famous lineage there'll
be like an accepted Story and there's
one or two guys in the corner screaming
that it's [ __ ] and it all came from
me or whoever you know and so what you
try to do is you try to like you try to
like corroborate information from
different people and you try to see you
know and uh you know there's there was
an aspect to it too because
one of the aspects about chemfam for
instance is that uh you know a lot of
the most outspoken people when it comes
to kem's story
um didn't have all that that much to do
with it yeah you know and then so you
get some people out of the woodwork and
stuff like that and you get and you know
and you try to tell a story and of
course there's there's parts and people
are going to remember things differently
and that's not really the that's not
really the the that's not really an
issue right because it's all about like
that's what like science right science
is right until it's wrong yeah and then
it adjusts itself to the new reality so
like when you're doing history it's not
so much that you're wrong or you're
lying if you get a part mistaken it's
that you might need more Nuance so you
might have there might be some stuff
that you don't say because you think
it's too out there
yeah
it's not corroborated enough you know
and
um and you know and how do you do that
and so like part of the part of the
thing we're trying to do with with most
of this stuff is that we actually don't
have a personal tie to any kind of like
big profit motive behind it yeah you
know I don't have some like secret chem
line that's all about to be released or
anything like that like there's an
aspect of history for history's sake
um you know history is mostly in
cannabis right now especially it's
mostly oral
yeah it's not written down yeah it's
held by different people they often
disagree they were often Young when the
history was being made and uh they often
didn't know it was history
yeah like there's a bunch of people out
there that were doing what all the
famous kids were doing back then uh that
don't remember what they did either but
it doesn't matter because nobody cares
to ask them yeah yeah that's been a big
part of it
you know
um you know and so and so you know
there's I just want everyone to know
that like it's it's not like when we
talk about stuff there's not it's it
definitely doesn't have to be
necessarily definitive it's always open
for debate we're always open for new
information and stuff like that and
sometimes a lot of times What CSI and
Matt and I and others do is we try to
match the story to what the plant tells
us yeah
you know there's a story where it's like
plants don't lie yeah
kind of thing
right so you know
um so I just wanted to get that out
there first because you know there's uh
Instagram and and uh that's part of the
reason why like these lives are cool is
because Instagram is actually like a
really bad place to debate anything yes
it is the comments are super short at
least on the forums you could get out
some paragraphs or something yeah you
know and you could actually have a
little bit more long-form debate and
Instagram is like a paragraph or less of
basically like you know [ __ ] you you're
a dick yeah doesn't match my money
motive yeah that doesn't that doesn't
match that you must have someone else
and then most people think that you
would act like how they would act too so
it's kind of yeah um you know it it and
you know the other part of it that's
funny too is it's like you
um you have an aspect too where it's
like and Matt and I talk about this all
the time where the claims of what people
have doesn't matter what family you're
talking about they get earlier and
earlier
until they're they actually predate the
story yeah and that's common too and
almost every famous Weed family yeah it
like it gets earlier and earlier and
people get access sooner and sooner
until the generally the person that's
generally accepted to start it there's
someone else that has it four or five
years before that person yeah yeah
you know and and so that kind of stuff
skunk one
that kind of stuff is is tough you know
so I just we're not going to talk about
that all the time I just thought I just
wanted to throw it out there in the
sense that like we definitely are open
for a debate this is actually kind of
like these chats are kind of like
conversation starters
yeah you know and we're trying to get
information out there so that history
gets debated
um you know and whatnot you know so
um yeah we call it pre-pre that pray
pray that pre-pre and and the and kind
of the way cannabis is is because you
don't get taught by your parents mostly
or this or that you come into cannabis
when you come into it there can be stuff
that's like extremely common knowledge
10 years ago that becomes rare info
today yeah
you know so I mean I I just we don't
need to spend a ton of time on it but
um but there is there's a bunch of that
and you can see it all the time there's
blueberry before DJ had blueberry yeah
there's blueberry there's blueberry from
Alaska that has nothing to do with that
there's you know there's people that
have Kush way early yeah you know uh in
different states there's people that
can't it's so it's all and it's like you
don't want to call people Liars or
mistaken and in some cases they might be
lying but in some cases they might just
be telling a story that they were told
yeah all right in some cases they have
Hawaiian OG and 70s yeah cannabis
folklore is a good way to put it there's
a lot of folklore there's a lot of
Legends there might be kernels of truth
of the Legends and that's not even
saying that everything that I say is
absolutely true like there could be
aspects of it where you're mistaken you
know and we tried Matt and I to to like
delineate like when we went from what we
think of as like actual fact
to like now we're kind of like making
educated guesses yeah speculation versus
speculations yeah you know
and um and so on and so forth so
I just wanted to get that out there that
this is definitely a sort of a venue to
start debate yeah and to try to get some
facts to debate about so you can you can
reach out to either one of us
here on Discord or wherever uh if you
want to keep it going or it Sparks your
memory or anything like that just wanted
to put that out there
uh but someone asked about the Maui dog
I can talk about that super quick just
because Maui dog is supposedly a bag
seed that came out of a bag of dog Bud
that was bought in Sonoma County uh
right around the turn of the century 99
2000 ish and they took it to Maui and
they creatively named the S1 or whatever
it was that came out of that seed Maui
dog
right it's also confusing because I made
super dog crosses with this other cut
called the Maui and those things got
used and mandelbrot's work and other
work and that's also called
um you know Maui super dog and other
stuff like that so but that's all it is
it's just a bag seed from supposed chem
91 bought around 99 2000 and then they
popped the seed on Maui and then they
crossed someone crossed that to some
skunk on Maui and that became the skunk
dog
I think it was Molokai Frost was what
Grace Paul said something on something
along those lines you know some kind of
Hawaiian skunk yeah you know so
um anyway you know that's kind of that's
kind of it and like there's other topics
that we're gonna cover in the future
that are probably going to create even
more debate than that
yeah I would think so and there's and
anytime you get into a debate about
something where people have the real cut
or they're selling seeds of this or they
have their reputation staked on anything
they only want to talk about stuff that
makes them look better yeah it's the
rare person that wants to discuss actual
history most people in cannabis history
are interested in like burnishing their
own Legend yes and so we're trying to do
a little something different where you
know we're not completely just polishing
ourselves the entire episode yeah and
for for future reference I I don't have
any tied a chem because I once said that
earlier that I was trying to burnish my
reputation with Kim I don't have any
ties to cam none you we're going to talk
about a bunch of stuff that we don't I
mean my my personal tie to chem has
nothing to do with the creation of any
of the Famous Cuts yeah it just so
happens I became uh best friends with
the guy that brought them West yeah
that's really and you know so I ended up
one of the few places by sheer chance
uh long before it was famous you know so
um that's kind of that kind of yeah I
mean there are two Maui dogs like I said
one of them is from my work that's Maui
super dog and one of them is uh uh
potentially a dog bag seed crossed to
some skunk in hope in Hawaii yeah I
think matchmaker is also right there's
the dog in Maui dog and one is Maui dog
with one g I think and then there's the
dog with two T's that's also yeah it
gets even more confusing
you know it's very confusing it's very
confusing I believe Maui dog was popped
they said they popped it when they got
back home so it probably dates from 99
or 2000 or something yeah and the one
thing I will actually say that leads me
to believe that the actual straight Maui
dog could be an S1 of uh
um actual chem dog is that
um you know I got to see a number of
rooms run by our buddy CSI they were all
uh chemdog 91 s ones and boy does that
Maui dog look like an S1
yeah it does I mean is that proof
without genetic testing no it's not but
a dead boy does it it really you could
see a bunch of things in that room that
looked very very close to that cut
and yes there's also skunk dog someone
just posted it out yeah skunk dog is a
child of that cut yeah and then the only
and the other part of it that may that
may be true is that three out of the
four people that I knew of at the time
that had uh chem dog in California we're
growing it in the Sonoma area
I spilled all over myself I was I was in
southern Mendo uh skunk VA was in was in
Sonoma then
um uh our buddy from Staten Island was
in Sonoma then so it's it's I mean it's
possible you could someone could have
bought a bag
you know
um
so yeah so what's the first one we want
to cover do you want to cover the uh the
mom techniques or do you want to cover
long-lost strains
we could cover we could cover mom
techniques first that's probably a
little bit more concise of a topic yeah
um so Mom techniques are uh you know
there's uh they've gotten a little bit
more complex in recent years
right which we'll get to in a minute but
basically uh the way I always did it was
that
you know if you want to start a new mom
um I would you know let's say You're
Gonna Fill let's say You're Gonna Fill
your room with with a run and your mom
is getting kind of old and tired right
so you you veg up your room and what I
would do is that I would pick the
healthiest nicest dankest looking
vegetative plant in the entire room to
be my new mom yeah the one that hurts
your heart to not put in the bloom room
because you wish that all of them in the
bloom looked like that one in the
beginning
um because you always want to start with
the healthiest stock you can I believe
that in ag it's called the cultivarca
and and moms and plants can get beat up
and it can take months there's a season
or two to get them back to health
so it's always key to keep
um to keep moms like to keep the best
stock possible yeah I think uh the other
thing that not everyone gets to do but
I've gotten to do for the last couple
decades is
um and Shanti does this too which is
kind of cool is that the Sun goes a long
way to healing plants so if it's
possible for you in your area without
being getting in trouble or something to
put your plant outside with some
artificial light in the night time in
Spring and early summer and you give
that plant two or three months of
growing outside or in a greenhouse and
then you take cuts off it and bring it
back in
that cut will be a lot healthier yeah
um I think some of that is mitigated now
because when when that Tech existed
there was kind of like two kinds of
indoor lights metal halides and high
pressure sodiums and both of them were
uh pretty limited compared to the Sun
yeah now we've got ceramic metal halides
and plasmas and a lot more things that
you can get like a wider Spectrum
you know so I think that makes that
makes a big deal and then they've talked
about it before but
um one of the ways like especially with
all this dudding and stuff like that
that's been going on and viroids people
talk about outgrowing the viroid where
they try to take cuts off the growing
tips yeah because it maybe hasn't moved
all its way up to the plant
and that was kind of accepted Tech but
now there's this wrinkle to it where
they actually say that there could be
more genetic drift at the tips
and the lowers might have less mutations
who says that I could show you some
stuff after the show yeah but it's
really coming out and so now there's
like a little bit of a conflict of like
you know less genetic mutations Perhaps
Perhaps lower down on the plant but then
more risk of disease if any exists in
the plant
um but long-term maintenance is hard uh
keeping these these plants alive and
keeping them happy and healthy for a
long time yeah uh is tough and the
larger of a collection you get the
harder it is to keep them all happy
yeah that's that's for [ __ ] sure
because a lot of times I want some needs
yeah Matt can speak to this too somebody
like you know if you have a big
collection and you're breeding all the
time you might have 80 of your
collection I don't want to stay in
stasis but like you're kind of giving it
low light and you're not trying to let
it get out of control or grow all crazy
yeah and then the 20 of stuff you're
gonna take cuts off of and use in
various breeding projects you're
boosting under better light yeah because
if you boost everything under a better
light it's expensive and then everything
grows way too fast
and then you're hacking and slashing and
training and doing a bunch of work just
to keep them you know they outgrow their
pots they outgrow their happiness level
um you know so Mom rotation is a big
thing yeah
I'm still a big fan of the the
10 by 20 tray full of Pearl Light in the
bottom [ __ ] three foot tall clone
miles right yeah just yeah yeah I I've
been guilty of that one several times
but it's just because it like like he's
talking about it's it's a real easy way
to keep things growing as slow as
possible uh when you're doing it like
that because sometimes yeah keeping moms
doesn't necessarily mean you're gonna
run
um all that clone Stock A lot of times
you're just throwing [ __ ] out because
you've backed up 10 or 20 uh yeah and
you might only say Mom you might only
need three or four plants but you take
25 Cuts yeah so you can and then you
know I was talking to CSI last night and
you know I mean the amount of backing up
that he has to do versus like the
collection that he has as far as moms
versus the Fino hunting that he's doing
versus all that it's like it can be kind
of exponential yeah it's almost like 80
like think about it's like 80 of my uh
actual stock that I would keep would
just be backups of moms and even
counting the flower stock it still seems
like all I kept was constant backups and
moms I see our I see our Buddy Radio
Ridge uh on here and a lot of the stuff
that I'm talking about is trying to
maintain moms like in a house inside in
a garage in limited space
um obviously if you have if you have a
nursery or you have a greenhouse or
multiple greenhouses and you can use
natural and artificial light it gets a
little easier
um but a lot of Fino hunting on that's
done in cannabis traditionally is a lot
of space
yeah that's a good question thoughts on
reveging a plant becoming a mom so I I
instead of doing the outdoor thing that
not so I was talking about I like to do
the Revenge stuff and I and I tended to
do it anyways because you know if I lost
you know clone stock of a mom that I
just floured out what have you or if
something was was
riding a lot slower than it than it
should be it wasn't as resinous a lot of
times I give it a revenge and it would
just give it that little bit of a boost
so I I I I but I run my my veg at 24
hours light all the time so it's really
easy for me to re-vege you know
somebody's talking about genetic drift
off the main street that's part of the
issue is that cannabis is just starting
to get studied in certain ways
um so there's a lot of new information
coming out and some of our traditional
techniques are going to come up against
studies and Science and uh you know
we're gonna have to see how it all plays
out
um you know I I always try to take a
when it's when it comes time to
re-veging for me I don't really re-vege
I re-vege until I can take fully in
vegetative healthy cuts
yeah and then I start over
yeah that's a good plan too but Reve
Edge is great it just it just takes a
while uh sometimes one of the techniques
that breeders also use is sometimes like
when you're Fino hunting you um you
might take a bunch of cuts like two
weeks into into bloom and you end up
going in there and cleaning up a lot of
the lowers which you have to strip out
anyway and you use those as cuts and
then they freak out for four to six
weeks yeah but that's actually helpful
because it slows down the process and
they don't get too big yeah because if
you can't take a ton of perfectly
healthy Cuts right before you flip you
might have to take cuttings multiple
times before you're even done with the
cycle
yeah if you're trying to keep them small
and contained
you know
yeah so
um and there's writ I mean the the Euros
are really big into Revenge uh they
would do things like they wouldn't keep
any back stock of anything and then when
they found flowers they liked they would
take that that plant out of the room and
re-vege it
yeah that's a gamble
it is easy to re-vege for me because of
the 24 hours thing I never really really
lost a lot of plants and re-veging but I
also was a big um fan of keeping as much
bud on the plant for re-veging because
Bud would grow out of ever I mean uh the
Revenge nodes would grow out of every
single spot on that bud so the more bud
you keep the better the chance you have
and a lot of people don't like that
trade-off of like not being able to you
know cut cut butt off and smoke it do
all that but when it comes to a revech
sometimes it's uh one outweighs the
other
and my Matt might disagree with me on
this but if I had an inkling that I I
might want to re-vege ever I would
typically leave all the lowers on
yes so then I could chop the plant way
back yeah and take all the well-formed
buds off and leave all the larfy funky
stuff is the new tops and they're not as
far into Bud as the rest of it so it's
not as long of a process to get them to
snap back and go back into flower yeah
I mean for so so what people understand
what we may mean by Revenge just so we
get uh clear too I'm sure most people
understand it but when you when you flip
uh you take a a vegetative plant and you
flip it into bloom
um that white cycle releases a whole
whole bunch of hormones
right and those hormones are there to
like make the plant produce flour and do
all the various things it's going to do
in bloom well if you stop that process
and you throw it back into Veg it's got
to work all those hormones out of itself
right and that's where you get you'll
get a lot of like single blades three
leaves a lot of very funny looking
growth for a while and you kind of know
you're out of it when your plant starts
throwing very normal Leaf structure
uh without any pistols or any kind of
weirdness like that and it can take a
few months
yeah usually it does it can take a few
months
um you know and the more larf you leave
on the bottom the easier it is yeah I'm
not saying it's impossible but it is
harder to get things to re-vege out of
main buds
yeah I mean I I usually get a pretty
good Healthy Growth out of all devices
from my perspective maybe I should
rephrase it is uh you get less rot yes
yes that's for sure because you might
end up having to go out there and cut
out mold because now you've got this
like overripe flower that's trying to
figure out what it wants to do maybe
it's dense and you're trying to get
vegetative growth to come out of it and
then the bud is rotting around the
vegetative growth and you're cutting
stuff out and so you know I mean it
there's a lot of ways around it
um and you know just not not only that
like not all strains act the same either
that's for sure
so
um yeah you know the the killing of the
fun the funny thing we always joke about
is like the the cuts that don't make it
in the backup those are always the
favorites yeah that's uh that's genuine
generally how it works that's how the
the one that you're like oh my God this
one is amazing and you've got like 75
Cuts saved and you lost three and it's
one of the three yeah it can be very
frustrating yeah
so
yeah
you know but that's Mom maintenance is
basically like you can only leave a
plant in a pot for so long
um there's a there's an arc of Health
that happens kind of yeah
um and you can get plants on the upswing
and on the downswing
um sometimes when you're re-veging I
should throw this out there sometimes up
potting the plant
and giving the root mask especially if
it's like you pulled it out late
um giving the plant a bunch of fresh
soil to grow new Roots into yeah versus
like stuck in the same pot that it's
been kind of root bound a little bit
tends to help do you ever do any root
trimming root ball trimming
um
I don't usually Bonsai my [ __ ] no uh
sometimes every time I've done it I've
just [ __ ] trashed plants like I've
tried it like you know I mean Bonsai is
one thing but [ __ ] trimming up the
root ball I always [ __ ] that up always I
cannot trim roots and keep [ __ ] alive I
do I mean I do think that like when
you're transplanting I do like to take
my hands and rough up the edges Because
unless you're growing in like certain
kinds of air prune pots the a lot of the
pots tend to the roots tend to chase
each other's tail right and so you and
so you want to break that up so they so
they shoot out new shoots essentially
I'm talking about taking them and like
if they're in a [ __ ] five gallon pot
trimming the [ __ ] root ball down to
like a [ __ ] three gallon have you
ever done that I have not done that I've
seen people take like bread knives and
like shave you know
I just generally rough it up on the
outside and on the bottom as much as I
can and then pop it in yeah yeah
um but that doesn't mean it might not
work you know
um you know so there's a I mean if
that's kind of bonsai techniques right
yeah
but I never could get the root mass [ __ ]
down ever
yeah you know bread knife
that type of thing but I mean it you
know generally speaking I would say
everyone has different opinions on this
and it depends on what you're using your
mother for
um but you should replace a mom every
six or nine months yeah
as a general rule you know and always
always always keep the healthiest plant
yeah boosting the end like obviously if
you're not flowering at the point at the
point where you decide that you want to
re-vege a plant you're no longer feeding
it for flour you're feeding it to be
brought back to a vegetative state so at
that point feeding it more in Cal Mag
all that [ __ ] helps yeah a more balanced
meal than as opposed to like a Flour
Mill that's low nitrogen you definitely
want nitrogen it's gonna it's gonna
freak out
and uh look weird for quite some time
yeah so you have to have some patience
you know yeah
you definitely have to have some
patience with the Revenge but it's a
it's a useful technique it's a space
saving technique just like anything else
that has its own risks
you know yeah um you could be you could
be bringing pests from your flower room
that don't exist back into your mom
yeah
yeah that could happen too yeah
um
but yeah I mean mom maintenance is
You Know It uh it takes a while for moms
to uh to build up the right kind of cuts
you know and you kind of start with like
a small plant that can give you one or
two cuts and it kind of takes a few
months of training a plant to get like
this plant's gonna give me like a room's
worth
yeah or I've built my plant up to X so
it really does depend on what your goal
for the plant is I mean I have a bunch
of plants and a lot of them I only need
a few cuts off of every now and again
so it doesn't do me any good having them
in a giant 10 gallon pot and as tall as
me yeah I know not at all you know but
people let it get that way and then
sometimes it's really tempting for a
grower you see a mom getting super
healthy and you don't want to beat that
the tar out of it yeah you want to let
it boost
you know so so while we're talking about
Mom health and and you know taking Cuts
backing up Cuts what's one of the ones
that you've uh lost in that kind of
situation where
um you were trying you thought you had
you know clones of it backed up maybe
and had one mom flowered it out and
realized you were [ __ ]
um I've lost all kinds of plants yeah it
would be hard to pick just one
um I'll start maybe like General and
then we can go into specifics yeah most
people even most of my friends
have always just wanted to bloom
whatever was popular at the moment yeah
so it's easy to get Pete like when when
it was the diesel craze or the purple
craze or whatever it was easy to get
friends to back up Urkel or Mendo P or
sour or something oh yeah and then the
market changes and they're not growing
it for the market anymore and you're
trying to get them to hold on to
something for you so it doesn't get lost
and they don't want to give up the space
yeah there's a lot of people that try to
have the smallest veg they can get away
with
yeah you know and it makes sense I mean
veg doesn't make them the money no it
doesn't make them the money you know and
so I'm not even I'm not even dissing
them on it I'm just saying that like
that's kind of how it is and so you end
up trying to like share things with
people
um that you hope that they love it
enough that you can get it back from
them yeah and how a lot of these fakes
and how a lot of these issues start is
you have a real cup
you move on to do some rooms of
something else
and then you go to get it back and it's
not it
yeah or they killed it or they were
worse at it than you were you know yeah
and so a lot of things got lost that way
um people break up have X's you know
that mess things up you get depressed
you move you have accidents you have a
fire you get busted
um you know there's a whole host of ways
where you lose things yeah and I think
every old older grower uh every
collector every breeder has probably a
list of [ __ ] that they wish they still
had yeah I would think so I mean I have
a bunch of stuff that you know I was
[ __ ] around with when I was in my
early and mid-20s that I wish that with
my current experience I had right now
yeah
don't you yeah there's a there's a bunch
I mean especially during the Mooney one
where I handed over my whole collection
yeah someone lost all of it in one shot
you know luckily luckily most of that I
was able to get back from other people
that I backed it up with but there was
still a lot in there that were my own
personal selections of my stuff that
never see again and I'm sure that's
probably one of the more common
occurring things for breeders is to lose
their own personal selections quite
often I would imagine and and the market
changes and the the what people want to
grow changes yeah and you end up chasing
something and uh you know and then you
can't
I mean look at right now like you know I
talked about it on a previous show but
it's like sour was the most popular
strain in America for over 10 years yeah
and there's massive debate on who's got
the real yeah yeah
and it turns out that most of the people
that have it didn't keep it when it was
unpopular yeah
and they tried to get it back when its
popularity came back
um you know I had a bunch of friends
that had the Trinity and we all lost it
and I spent 15 years looking for it and
we kept getting it back and it kept
being fake yeah or a hybrid yeah
and there's stories like that over and
over and over again
you know what's one of your white whales
in terms of something that I lost or in
terms of something that I want something
that you've lost that you wish you still
had I had uh probably next to the Maui
the best thing I ever found in Amsterdam
of all the Pops that I did was I found
an amazing uh Black Diamond afino yeah
it was peppery it was Frosty it was
extra extremely potent
um and I still think about it was it one
of the purple ones it was not purple oh
it was darker yeah it was darker but it
was not purple
um it was very beautiful it had a really
nice kind of long running Cola
um I uh I didn't let the time even
realize there was like three or four
versions of black domino yeah I think
they made that apparent no it wasn't
really apparent but I bought it direct
from Scentsy in late 90s yeah you know
and um I had uh I had the Warlock
yeah I really like the Warlock a whole
lot
um I you know I lost this I in I lost
the super skunk yeah
you know
um I've lost most things here and there
yeah I luckily I share and I don't hoard
and close friends have held it but I
haven't been able to find
um the super skunk since yeah
um and you know skunk VA and some others
and stuff we've been hunting for it for
a long time and uh the cough I should I
saw the cough lives yeah
I don't know about if the cough two
lives isn't it I thought this was the
cough too maybe we could ask homie if
he's on here but I think yeah I think
it's cough
and I think cough two is the one that's
gone
um but
you know one of the things about that is
that sadly if you're I don't know if I
don't know who who made that comment or
where they're located but
um
You Know It uh the the nl5 aces have not
been nearly as possible or popular on
the west coast as they are on the East
yeah that's for sure so they don't get
circulated very much the stuff that got
circulated
um on the west coast was more jet was
more the poly hybrids the Jacks the
super silver hazes yeah those are big
the the really famous uh
there there he is cough two is gone
that's what I thought okay so [ __ ] two
is the one yeah so you know so a lot of
the really famous ones the only the only
famous one that really made its way to
the West Coast was when the the Electric
Boogaloo got renamed the dog [ __ ] yeah
that one's on the west coast almost all
the other Famous Cuts started and stayed
somewhere east of the West Coast I think
even like um one of the versions of the
San Diego campus is like a super silver
haze we saw a lot of that but not yeah
not a lot of the nl5 case
yeah and uh somebody just asked uh you
know how did I lose the super skunk uh I
got in trouble
yeah and they didn't let me keep
anything yeah he got caught at the rest
stop it was a real [ __ ] up it was it
was a messed up I mean I lost it took me
I got the vast majority
as far as clones go I got the vast
majority of what I lost that day back
um I did not uh the super skunk has been
gone forever since
uh the super dog
which was my buddy and I's project to
blend super skunk and and chem together
that was gone the black domino was gone
um other things like the Flowrider and
the Mendo p and
um you know the LA the the headband and
sours and stuff like that I had those I
had enough stuff spread out that it
eventually all came back to me yeah um
but there was some stuff that was half a
dozen things that got lost
um you know shame but it does it does
force you to move on and uh go down
different Avenues which I think is
always a plus yeah and I got we I got
from another mutual friend of ours we
got what we thought was the Super Skunk
back
yeah um and then I I got evacuated and I
lost it in the 17 fires again
so Jesus Christ yeah it sucked I God
damn it I thought I I literally drove
out of that property with like the LA
between my legs and the chemd by my feet
and dog cutting right next I mean I had
like six one gallon pots you know and uh
that's what I could fit as I fled so
yeah that's [ __ ] Wild
it happens yeah you know but it sure
does um I mean there and there's a bunch
of uh Mac and talk there's a bunch of
famous SoCal stuff
um you know that we joke about quite a
bit but like the bull rider yeah um the
Hogs breath
um you know there was some things that
were kind of common yeah down there at
least in terms of being sold and this
and that and they've got their Legend to
them and they're gone yeah luckily still
around but it's always been kept super
tight until the last Maybe
five years now it's been getting out
everywhere but if for a long time it was
kept very tight but bull rider I've
never seen bull rider like I've gone
down you know been lived down there for
over a decade in San Diego and it wasn't
around even by the time I got there the
bull rider was gone
um Afghani bull rider was still there
but you always still hear these stories
about like the original bull rider and
how good it was
um the closest we have is apparently old
Betsy
um but yeah if it's anything like old
Betsy it's probably like a skunk one and
I'll fly face type I think Matt can
speak to this Afghani bull rider I think
is a descendant of the bull rider I
don't even know if it if it's been
proven to even be a descendant it might
be the same thing with a different name
no no definitely isn't the same thing
um but I don't know if they're
necessarily even descended from each
other
I might have just been two things that
got similar names yeah yeah I would
think so I mean I I don't really know
much about the dudes who've made bull
rider or uh Afghani bull rider I mean
there's Jeff Tech and then there's other
people who say they did
I don't know I don't know but I mean if
if bull rider is anything like old Betsy
then Afghani bull rider was totally
Afghani dominant and had no traits like
the old Betsy if that makes sense and I
think lots of regions have
um you know uh stories like that of
there's plants that are popular that are
everywhere
um I mean you know we're gonna save the
purple story for another episode and
we're gonna try to get our buddy on here
to chat about it but yeah
um but I can say that you know in the
mid 2000s
like most of the commercial Growers
indoor Growers especially up by me and
Mendo and Southern Humboldt they all had
purple yeah or purple was everywhere for
a long time it was everywhere and then
it becomes unpopular yeah like and
there's like four Dudes that kept it
yeah I mean I might be exaggerating you
know maybe there's no but there's so few
so few people kept it yeah but that
that's kind of what happens is is
everything's so popular people can never
imagine it going away yeah and then you
can't find it
yeah you know and what happens when
that's the case
and then you know there's there's an
aspect to it now where it's like uh
um
oh the wheelchair
uh that's interesting that JJ had access
to the wheelchair we used to grow the
wheelchair I had some buddies of mine
from Chicago that ended up moving out to
Boulder and Longmont and some of that
area and they we all have the wheelchair
back then and uh I don't have any idea
what it was uh that was kind of an era
in the 90s where there was a lot of
variety and my my interest in lineage
hadn't sprouted super hard yet
um but that was a pretty famous thing in
Colorado there was a Colorado AK-47 that
smelled smelled like sandalwood and
yielded incredible
um you know there's there was a bunch of
good cuts that uh that went away
um in in a way uh all the name strains
that started with the purple craze in
0405 they've all been I've said it
before they've all been bad for
diversity
as soon as everyone could grow purple
and sell it that was bad for diversity
yeah it was afterwards when everyone
could grow sour or cushion sell it that
was bad for diversity too cookies
very bad for diversity Skittles you can
basically name every Super popular
strain and Not only was it bad for
diversity but then once the feminized
Revolution happened everybody crossed it
into everything else yes
and so the era that we're talking about
like in the 90s and the early 2000s that
was sort of like the last era where all
good weeds sold yeah right
yeah like I mean you can talk about I
mean maybe I'm wrong but like if you had
a bunch of bull rider today how easy
would it be for you to even find a
market for it I I don't like based on
what old Betsy is I don't think there
would be a market for it
right you know so it's like some some of
these legends that are amazing it's like
try to sell them yeah
you know the gar somebody said the
guards the gar might live actually the
car was like an 11 week garlic Bud uh
that was in the SoCal kind of Santa
barbara-ish area uh and it was really
good yeah it was really good I bet so
um any the Trinity the Trinity lineage I
know it exactly uh it's it's bag seed
from a bag of headies that a glassblower
got in Trinity
um selling some glass pieces
bitter said they won't take Shoreline is
Shoreline not selling it doesn't
surprise me but I mean like if they
smoked it they dig it but yeah I guess
based on what they want in the way bud
looks that's what's sad people say they
want [ __ ] until they have it and they're
like I don't know man
yeah yeah I mean we we're in an era
where looks and height matters more than
effect
and a lot of our friends I see a good
friend of ours posting on nobody wants
cough you know there's a there's an
aspect of it where a lot of my friends
hold on to their favorites
not because they're marketable
yeah but because they love them
you know yeah
um
and nobody wants them
bastards
and you're like you you know you grow a
room of it you grow a crop of it and
then if you are going to sell it they're
going to try to hammer you down on price
because it's not
you know zookies yeah he just said they
won't take it because of the name of
Shoreline
they won't take it because of the name I
guess it's not Shoreline
flambe or Shoreline cookies or yeah I
don't know about the San Diego Green
Crack I can't really speak to that I can
say that green crack is most likely a a
skunk one Fino yeah that makes sense you
know
um
you know but I mean it's it's one of
these things where it's like and that's
a that's actually an aspect of like the
the current market is
um a lot of you a lot of people if you
buy uh if you buy from dispensaries the
dispensary has to want to buy that weed
for you to be able to buy it yeah and a
Distribution Company has to be willing
to buy that weed to offer it to the
dispensary or so there's a lot of good
weed that people don't get to see
because they're like oh that that name
is weird
I don't want it
yeah you know but I'll take your I'll
take your Starburst yeah or I'll take
your cake or I'll take your whatever you
know
um
you know so uh I mean like with the with
the green crack with what uh best was
talking about too and you like whenever
I I hear mango the first thing I think
is usually skunk one because that's it's
almost everything I've ever smelled with
mango has some skunk one dominance in it
of some sort for the Terps
um it may not always be the case because
I've had like mango uh or a cantaloupe
mango type pure Afghani from her app but
typically I would say a skunk one is
what usually trips that mango Turf for
me
someone just mentioned you know is is it
because the buyers at these dispensaries
are only in their they're in their 20s
no uh that's not it it might be part of
it it's it's a lot of it is because the
dispensaries exist to make money yeah
and they want the best deal they want to
make the most money off their shelf
space and so even in the 215 era there
was a lot of stuff that people didn't
want to didn't want to sell
um because you know you can't really buy
a bunch of good sativas and dispensaries
you couldn't sell J1 in San Diego
because it was like the at least during
the era I was there all of the
collectives called their like their
worst of the worst they just called it
J-1 like around the downtown area so
people just would not buy J1 anywhere in
San Diego after that they just ruined
the whole name for a whole city and
somebody mentioned this too you're
probably right if if our homie uh you
know
um lived in New York City or somewhere
around there where that could be his
Market cough might be popular yeah
because there's a there's a there's a
there's a decent market for nl5 haze
type Thanos over there
see if this has salt in it
no salt
uh um snow cap was yeah the
AK-47 the Pez still exists
um there's AK-47 that still exists snow
cap is kind of a just a big chunky
Afghan I don't know if that one's still
around it was really grown a lot in
Mendo for a while I think we're putting
the Pez in um in the nl5 hybrid ground
yeah hybrids uh our buddy CSI still
holds it yeah um I had it for a while
um but yeah I mean there's uh
you know there's the pith is really nl5a
is this kind of really unsellable unless
you're on this section of the East Coast
you know it's not popular in the west
it's not popular in Colorado
train wreck uh we could save the train
wreck story until for CSI we'll have
that we'll have a buddy on yeah
um and uh you know
um
but yeah there's a lot of stuff that
that that comes out that has its it has
its name and has its time in the sun
um and uh the Pez is probably an alfino
yeah that I believe that's what he said
there's an elephant that's why we're
moving in the nl5 stuff yeah that's an
alfino it's an old nlfino and a lot of
this stuff is good they just uh you know
it just doesn't it just loses just loses
popularity and then someone's like I
want whatever I'm growing I want someone
to come to my house or if I go take it
somewhere I want everyone to buy it
quickly
I think someone's confusing pif with HB
13 in there they're not the same thing
definitely not the same thing definitely
not
um
I don't know if Brooklyn really likes
sativa because they want to be more
productive I think
Cubans and Dominicans and you know
various groups up there sold it a bunch
and a bunch of people smoked it and a
bunch of rich people and and Elites and
and stars back there wanted it and then
it kind of fueled a haze wave in New
York much like uh wealthy people fueled
a cush wave in La yeah
and then it eventually it kind of it
gets a life of its own yeah you know and
I'm not saying that like people might
not prefer it but it's just like that's
the thing is it's like it's got a market
there yeah and obviously for a long time
I used to joke that like you know you'd
go into a dispensary 10 years ago in in
LA and there's like which one we have 42
strains and 38 of them are kush yeah
which one do you want
because it was just endless
you know icky hey what's up Dickie he
said Haze is rap weed God damn it I mean
you know Hayes is uh yeah Washington
Heights
um you know that kind of area like uh
the Cuban black uh you know the the
brown the Dominican the there's a bunch
of different names added to it and slang
uh some of it was grown in Florida and
shipped to New York
um and uh you know it was kind of one of
those things uh heard of the Ingrid
heard of the Ingrid I don't know about
the Ingrid what do you know about the
Ingrid I don't know anything about
knowing I don't know anything about the
engraved I mean the cool thing about uh
the cool thing about sativas
um like nl5 Haze and stuff is they do
have a different buzz and so they they
they you know um they basically like hit
you differently
yeah and so they're they're really
that's the cough all of them they all
have a really good effect a lot of times
people feel warm they feel happy they
get a different kind of buzz
um a lot of times they're ugly
in injured colds I think it's injured
called the Ingrid coal
injured gold
yeah so pith is not an nl5 Haze and
different than HP no piff is probably an
nl5 Haze and HP 13 is not related
there you go
so you know yeah I mean there's there's
a bunch of different stuff and so like
on the west coast it's like a lot of
people [ __ ] on A's because most of the
best Pinos of it never made its way out
hey Gene what's Ingrid do you know
anything about it I never just say his
buddy had it huh yeah
um is pif the same as Cuban black it's
hard to say there's a number of phenos
that float around
um and a lot of times you know names get
used independently
um and uh of each you know or
interchangeably I should say yeah so
um I used to think that pif Cuban black
Heights Haze I could name four or five
other names were all kind of names for
the same strain and then some people
from back there were like oh no this one
is this and this one is that this is why
this is that and so you know it's just
another more more compartmentalized
knowledge
um here I'll do this one can you explain
the difference between HP 13 G13 and
88g13 HP uh yes
G13 HP is a hybrid with G13 in it and HP
13 is related to neither
there you go yeah Cuban black Haze is an
nl5 Haze
uh mostly yes you know there's a number
of different nicknames for it
um you know lizard hashplan I have no
idea
um you know but I mean I love old weed
you know
um Puck and u-dub
uh Puck is an old hash plant
um they used to call it Puck because it
got uh dude used to carry it around in a
hockey puck container it was like a
bubble tape bubble tape bubble tape
container yeah yeah type of thing and so
they ended up calling it the puck
um it's an old ugly
um hash plant looking thing
um and it's mostly famous for uh being
old for being old and people keeping it
back for no reason
yeah I mean there's I you know we have
some buddies from that part of Colorado
and like out of the half a dozen strains
that those guys used to run the puck was
one of their least favorite didn't mean
they didn't like it but it's always been
short hard to grow notoriously hard to
root
um but one of it is old
you know yeah
um
how old is the G13 clone that's floating
around G13 is one of those things that
has a bunch of Legends to it
Neville claimed that the G13 that they
sent out to Europe got sick and died by
93 or so
um there's been a lot of claims most of
the G13 that people talk about is
actually G13 nl2
which was sold as a line by Neville for
some time I think Matt even got some of
those beans yeah from Neville yeah
um but G13 and we should deal with this
now too it's like with the NL or G13 or
Haze or any of this stuff there's all
these the 90s are long ago now or these
Legends people pop up with this
legendary name
yeah
right and even if you're a casual Stoner
you might have heard of these legendary
strings
yeah and then someone pops up with seeds
or a clone or this or that and you know
a funny story
yeah
um and you know they never tend to pop
up with the unpopular old weed no they
don't it's always the most famous
G13 nl2
um it's a specific selection from G13
nl2 that was looked most like the G13
clone
we had a buddy who very well might have
had a very old old G13 in Ohio it got
infected with the virus and I was lost
but there was an old G13 floating around
Ohio that supposedly tied back to the
80s uh I think Fletcher said that that
one was airborne
but there was yeah there was an Airborne
cut and um what was the other one named
um
Pacific Pacifica but they called it
Pacific G13 but that I did I ran I ran
all of those
um I ended up making s1s at the Airborne
and sending those back to Neville to do
projects with
um
I really wasn't a fan of the Pacific G13
motor Rebel and uh breeder Clips used a
bunch of that stuff and I just ran
through a bunch of it and didn't like it
but the the Airborne I did think was
pretty [ __ ] cool it was a thunder
[ __ ] is a famous name
um I I got some quarter pounds from a
guy on dead tour
um who mailed them from me from Denali
Alaska and I don't know 93 or 94 or
something and I loved that weed and
every every Thunder [ __ ] I've seen has
been nothing like it since
yeah here's the Thunder [ __ ] was like
kind of a catch-all name
kind of like Maui Wowie
yeah maybe and that there was any number
of different things grown under that
label
um
so uh yeah vessel that's that is exactly
right it came from the Forum days the
Airborne it was a selection of G13 and
all two
yeah I mean I even remember uh people
like hempy and Vic high and all that
arguing back and forth over whether they
were different and what the provenance
on it was and all this and that it was
it was uh it was a hot debate for a
minute you know yeah
um
for sure you know and my buddy sub Rob's
from Alaska from that area and he's been
shouting from the rooftops forever that
like look dude no one ever had the same
Thunder [ __ ] even if you lived during
that time in Alaska no one ever had the
same Thunder [ __ ] twice it was never the
same it was never single cut yeah
um and you know the Thunder [ __ ] that I
had I I dude on if someone asked me what
the Terps were like
um I was in my teens then and partying a
lot and traveling a bunch I don't
remember I do remember that it was nicer
than most of the kind bud I could get at
the time yeah
I have fond memories of it yeah um but
do I have a clear memory from 1993 1994
of what it tasted like yeah no I don't
like I and you know I don't
um and mostly just because it's really
hard to describe Terps and no's it's
like one of the hardest things in wheat
we have a lot of language for visual
stuff we have poor language for smells
yeah in my opinion
you know most of the time when we talk
about now that there's like some
terpenes coming up people start talking
about serpentaline or mercine or this or
that but most of the time people talk
about smells not about like the actual
smell but what it reminds them of
yeah this [ __ ] smells like linoleum
or pencil shavings
or poop
or a guy's dick like or skunk you know a
guy's dick oh man you know so I mean
yeah you know you probably missed the
era to name a strain famunda yeah it's
probably it's probably not the time I
could see a few dudes doing it you could
see a few dudes doing that but yeah you
have to relate it to something else you
know some of them are really easy like
yeah Citrus is really common you can be
like oh that's Citrus and everybody
knows what what it's like yeah you know
some things and and not everyone when
they smell things remember oh that
smells like pencil shavings from when I
used to sharpen my pencil in grade
school
yeah not everybody has that memory
I never I've never seen the Dewberry
you know CSI describes one of um the
Mendo purposefinos is I want to say it's
either King Snake [ __ ] or coral snake
[ __ ] I've talked to him about it yeah
yeah like that king snake has actually
got a very distinctive kind of poo yeah
it's specific it's coral snake [ __ ] and
it's very specific but unless you've
smelled it I mean yeah that's kind of
what we laugh about with all the Euros
is like skunks don't even exist in
Europe yeah so they've never broke
they've never smelled roadkill unless
they traveled over here yeah you know
most Americans have smelled the Dead
Skunk at some point yeah you know
because you drive by and it's very
potent
you know
um
you know but I mean that's kind of like
as far as like strains that were lost I
uh
a lot of the hazes I've been kind of a
haze freak for a long time and I used to
think I honestly the first four or five
times I went to Amsterdam I was pretty
convinced that they had bunk
but it was all a great marketing kick
and then like my friends and the hippies
and the dead tour kids that I knew we
had way better weed
than anyone in Amsterdam yeah right
and then I met some folks and I ended up
smoking some of the famous Haze cuts and
I was like oh
okay yeah he's never been the same since
okay you know
um and uh you know and so but those
things those things are legends they you
know they started circulating in America
the last couple of years
um
but I think nl5 Hayes is famous for a
reason
um here's
a good one for you how do you feel about
Shanti Baba's work these days
I will admit that I poke less holes in
shanti's work than most of my friends
uh I would say that's probably accurate
yeah
um you know I I think that one of the
cool things that Shanti Baba has done is
he has not really mixed a bunch of his
work with everything new
you know
um and so if you want to get some stuff
that at least has a bunch of old
genetics
um there's a lot of that on offer
through him yeah you know it might take
more work to find something that you
want out of it
um it's it's a huge debate as to like
what he still has and what he's lost
yeah
you know
um
and there was always a lot of junk in
the Amsterdam stuff yeah Amsterdam stuff
in my opinion had a low floor and a high
ceiling
you know which is not how people like it
today people like a high floor yeah I
want to get a lot of average weed or
just above average weed that looks
pretty nice yes there was a lot of [ __ ]
I popped from same as seed banks back in
the day that was ugly and shitty
yeah but then there's Finos that popped
out of that did people still hold today
that are amazing
you know yeah
so I can't really I can't really say I
think that there is real stuff amongst
uh Shanti Baba's work
um I think there's a bunch of junk in it
too I don't think that's like an
indictment of him necessarily
um it's indisputable that he bought
Neville's old seed stash yeah and it's
also indisputable that he worked with
Neville and Neville gave him a number of
breeding Cuts yeah so he's one of the
few people that can actually claim to
have access to some of that old stuff
yeah
um but I also think the uh you know the
times have passed them by
and people don't go to him very much
anymore and they're not searching
through his stuff very much yeah
um and uh you know
he kind of I mean if you think about it
he came out with Neville's Hayes super
silver haze and mango Haze and what was
it 97 or 98 yeah somewhere around there
so he's and he came out with White Widow
he's made some really big contributions
to the Cannabis world they're just
mostly multiple decades old
yeah you know which vashanti I found it
like if I want to to find a longer
flowering line that that is going to
have some um
gonna have some uniqueness to it
turquoise and and genetics wise he's a
great place to go granted you'll have to
to dedicate a lot of space to a good
sized pop because it is older stuff it's
not like it hasn't been bred for the
past 30 years [ __ ] just for resin
production and just for THC potency and
testing and but if you want to find good
old like heady sativa [ __ ] his his stuff
is some of the best places to start I
agree with Gene the he said the mango
has Haze is fire fire yeah
based off of is my favorite cut of nl5
haze I would love love love if it ever
appeared in America
um you know and you know his his white
widow especially in the 90s and his
white family kind of changed the game
yeah um I could also you could you could
say too that since since regular seed
lines are becoming rarer and rarer
uh if you wanted to actually start doing
some back Crossing and you needed a male
pollen donor
he offers all regular seedlines yeah um
and what I was going to say is that when
it comes to his Afghani lines and his
more Indica type stuff
I have not had as much success with that
stuff as I have with his uh lines I like
the hazes somebody uh somebody just said
his shanti's [ __ ] line is White Hot Fire
uh I'm glad you found something you
liked yeah yeah because I ran through
some [ __ ] and I thought it was pretty
shitty yeah um but that just skunk one
that just that just goes to show yeah
that you know uh you know that um you
could run through a few hundred seeds
then it's all bunk and then one guy gets
one pack and finds something that they
think is amazing yeah and and some
people will find like like pop skunk one
stuff that haven't experienced skunk one
so much and be like this is fire you
know it's possible totally and
definitely if you're looking for sativa
based lines
um that are that are workable Shanti has
that yeah and uh you know it's um you
know it I like him more than most
you know but we all have our like we all
have our favorites I liked him until
that last dealing where I wanted to buy
some [ __ ] and he was all weird yeah you
know I mean he he uh you know I I tend
to think I mean but that's it's you can
you can get a bunch of us together and
start talking about about which old
character from the 90s you think is the
least shady and it's hard to get anybody
to agree yeah that's very true I tend to
Lean Into The Shanti Neville camp
yeah
there's people that are very into Dave
Watson Sam Skunk Man
um there's you know it's you know
there's people that are very into a lot
of these old guys
you know it's kind of like imagine
people debating all the people that we
know 20 years from now yeah you're gonna
have your camps yeah for sure
you know
um okay so real quick someone asked
about the nl5 stuff because I'm getting
tired I'm gonna have to cut it kind of
early but um animal five stuff so we
have three main cuts that we're going to
like let out a little bit
um one of them is the bubble gum Fino
that I've talked about before
um it is more bubble gum than bubble gum
the the cut that that me and CSI and a
bunch of others use
um it is extremely pink bubble gummy and
loud with the pink bubble gum then we
have a lot of pineapple a lot of
tropical there was a specific Citrus cut
that we kept Cuts up and
um well we kept cut to everything but as
far as like things that we thought are
our Keepers in terms of what is
considered Keepers nowadays or the
bubble gum the Citrus and then one that
we just called The Ranch tank just
because there's no good way to describe
it yet but it's it's
rank as [ __ ] so those are the three main
like if you're going to be pulling for
really cool [ __ ] that you want to find I
I both all three of those are pretty
[ __ ] rad
um the the taste transfers a little bit
better than the uh Indiana bubblegum
kind of we'll say that but
um those are the three main ones that we
kept but there's a lot of different
offerings in it is it is a very varied
line so yeah hopefully that helps um if
you're a part of the patreon if you're
part of the breeder Syndicate patreon
um you can go right now and buy it you
just have to have backstage access if
you're part of the patreon and you still
can't see it on rights eco.com and get a
hold of me and I'll make sure that your
account is hooked up so you can do that
and yeah me and Gene just made a comment
that I think deserves to be highlighted
maybe he said I don't believe in people
I believe in dank yeah uh
we have we have this phrase we use all
the time that plants don't lie yeah and
so some of them are like chem dog talk
and some of that other stuff that we
were doing earlier uh in previous
episodes was kind of about our
speculation on like what the plants are
telling us versus the story yeah and
dank is dank not everybody agrees that
every cut is dank obviously
um but most Elites a decent amount of
people think this weed is fire yeah you
know
um and you know in all honesty you're
you're no comments on the Elvis uh I
don't think anybody really knows what
the Elvis was I ran the cut for a long
time gave to skunk Master Flex and never
saw it again but
um as far as what it was it could be an
nl5 Haze but just nobody really knows I
um I don't have a lot of backstory on
the Elvis it's one of those ones it's
not like we're trying to ignore it
um you know but uh you know it sometimes
it's it's not like we're an encyclopedia
on just about everything
um Elvis is a famous cut
um but you know got passed around I
don't think have you ever grown it yeah
yeah
I've never thrown it so I have I have
very little actual like intelligent
discourse on that one so we're not
ignoring you mine came from Ms Elvis on
THC farmer back in the day who is a dude
that had um he had the regular Elvis cut
and then he had one called the the
pink Cadillac cut and he gave me both of
them and it I thought it was dank for
the time but I don't know if it would be
considered date nowadays and I think I
don't know we can talk to we can talk to
CSI you know he takes a ton of pictures
um there could be some pictures coming
of uh more pictures of the NL oh yeah
there's tons more coming to the nl5s and
different ones of the various of the
various rooms that's one of the coolest
things about CSI is that he's pretty
transparent
um about uh you know about his process
and stuff like that and so people will
be able to get to see fenos yeah and
things of that nature fairly soon
so
um what's dank nowadays
um to me I'm more of a Classics kind of
person
um but what's dank is what you enjoy
smoking yeah
honestly that's really what it is
whatever jives best with your brain
chemistry this weed is dank yeah means I
like smoking this weed and then if
enough people decide that wheat is dank
It generally gets popular and becomes an
elite of some kind Yeah it's gotten
confusing uh with legality because
everyone wants to have the Dank and
everyone wants to have white hot fire
and everything that they're growing is
an elite of an elite
and all they get is [ __ ] wedding cake
so [ __ ] them so it's you know so yeah
it's it's it's become a lot modern
marketing rather than like crowd testing
yeah
probably should have a better term you
know
um and uh
you know they uh you know a lot of the
stuff that that I have and some of the
stuff I've been sharing with CSI and
others and stuff like that it's just
like old favorites
it worked with me really well so I held
on to it you know
um and I mean it's a shame it's a shame
that we don't have a catalog of
all the old strains and all the old eras
and Seed stock and cutting saved and all
that because the collection we would
have of diversity from even 1990 to now
yeah which is only you know 30 years
um or 32 years Jesus but we're being
pretty insane
yeah
are you feeling hella old after saying
that
you know what made me feel old is I saw
this thing that said that right now the
we're far we're as far away from the 90s
as we were from the 60s in the 90s
oh and that made me feel old yeah
that'll do it that made me feel old
um you know I have a I have a a 23 year
old daughter and she does a great job of
making me feel old yeah all the time you
know I'm regularly reminded how ancient
I am you should feel all year old
but I'm not that old really I'm only in
my 40s you know no that's the new 20.
but when I was 22 I probably I thought a
45 year old dude was hella old yeah dude
I thought 40 year old was hella old
until I was [ __ ] 38 then I started
thinking rethinking that yeah you know
and so but I mean that's what's cool
about it right is that there's a lot of
people now
maybe we'll I don't know if we'll end on
this but I should just say it but the
90s the 80s and 90s and the early 2000s
are long enough away now
that we are getting a deluge of ancient
amazing lines and seeds and cuts from
all over the place right and somehow
when I was searching for these things
like crazy 10 years ago I couldn't find
most of them anywhere yeah because they
were unpopular and nobody could make any
money off them and they were [ __ ]
nowhere yeah now that there's like a
whole new generation that you know
um all of a sudden it's like all this
ancient stuff that you heard about or
you read about in High Times or is you
know like skunk one is New Again
the hell what's this what's that what's
pith even this even this like laughable
debate over who's got real Sour or
[ __ ] you know sour is old enough
now that there's a bunch of smokers that
grew up in the you know if you came if
you started smoking weed in the last 10
or 12 years
you were in the cookies Skittles cake
dessert era yeah you might not have
smoked a bunch of and most people Sour
Diesel they think the real Sour is the
first one they smoked yeah it doesn't
mean it was the real one it just means
it was their first personal experience
you know
um
yeah I mean green Merchant you know uh
most people don't know that green
Merchant they rated every hydro store in
the United States
um we used to go to hydro stores in a
friend's car who didn't grow
in case our license plate get got
written down yeah
there was it was a real issue you had to
find a friend who you could pay who was
willing to take some risk and drive you
to the store because no one ever wanted
to be in near the store where the
license plate tied to a girl yeah
yeah you know
so part of the gig part of the gig
you know right I'm trying to think if
there was anything else I had to plug
I'm so [ __ ] tired
um
that in all five's up um 805 will be up
for Monday for everyone who else who
wants to buy it that's not a part of
patreon it'll be up on Monday so check
the right seed code.com site for that
um pretty soon we'll have some Hawaiian
lights stuff as well as some um crosses
with some of not so stuff on Hawaiian
lights so keep posted on that and I
think other than that I think for uh
check out speakeasy.com uh they've been
helping us get these podcasts up and
fast or check out their stuff anything
else not so from your end
I mean obviously we you know normally we
chat longer Matt's tired we'll cut it a
little short tonight which is fine but
we're we're going to be doing this every
Friday and we're going to be trying to
bring people together we're super open
to ideas yeah jeans next Friday jeans
next Friday everyone go go DM them about
it he wants to come on next Friday okay
so yeah I mean we're we want to bring
friends on we want to bring community on
we basically just want to [ __ ] about
weed and try to get a bunch of
advertising out there and sort of flip
the script which is like 98
self-promotion and two percent history
and kind of reverse it clipped it we
flipped it it's 98 history and
bullshitting and two percent two percent
self-promotion two percent
self-promotion you know and uh because
you need a little self-promotion to keep
the whole movie going yeah we do but in
general but in generally speaking
um you know the um
uh csi'll have a bunch of pictures up
about he ran multiple rooms of the
Northern Lights he'll have a bunch of
pictures of Finos that he's popping up
as him and Matt start to sell some of it
he saved a bunch of the work he crossed
to various selected fianos he's got some
open pollination work he really is a
very thorough man when it comes to
reading
um so we're trying to lock all this
different stuff in and um you know and
you know so yeah ask us questions you
can ask us questions on the Discord you
can always DM us you can ask us
questions in the posts and we really do
take those into count when we're trying
to think of what we want to talk about
because we want to talk about stuff
that's interesting you know yeah so
that's all we care about so it's going
to be a little shorter uh hopefully next
week if we'll lock in gene
and we can talk about a bunch of stuff
like that next week plan on it Gene you
know everybody say this you know Gene
lives in I I don't want to call it my
neighborhood but like we live in the
same county
um I've lived here since 98 he was born
and raised here uh you know his his uh
his parents were weed farmers and so
there's a certain amount of history and
just sameness that comes with growing up
in the same era yeah and the same people
and stuff like that so maybe we could
talk a little bit about some of his own
work or some of the gorilla stuff or
some of the phases of what it was like
trying to get away with it we're
definitely into the same kind of dudes
which I appreciate they always have a
similar taste in men yeah we have we
have a similar backstory yeah there you
go similar we came from similar eras and
a lot of those eras they're only stuck
in your memory yeah so if you don't have
other people to talk about them they're
just stuck in your own head there you go
anyway ask a bunch of questions ask a
bunch of follow-up questions hit us up
on our Discord on the Breeders Syndicate
Discord hit us up on IG on the DMS uh
questions that pop into your head from
any conversation keep it going keep it
talking you know yeah and and even if
you think that we've said something
wrong question it question it yeah 100
question everything we're not we're not
talking down to anyone or anything like
that we're trying to get information out
there and debate yeah and I'm often
wrong nothing I'm all I'm often wrong
though so question everything I [ __ ]
say I'm half awake
all right indeed cheers everyone good
night everyone
[Music]