welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
cannabis strain history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
hey everyone welcome to reader Syndicate
I'm Matthew here with my co-host
thousandfold and today we're going to
unlock and unfold some of the
nomenclature with some examples and
hypotheticals on different strains to
try to give people a better idea past
just the the term F1 and F2 and all that
and just brief ideas of what it means
yeah yeah because last week we you know
we did a fairly textbook overview of
various Concepts in breeding Theory and
Science and so this week we're
definitely getting
um
more concrete we're definitely getting
into some of the actual real life
examples
um of breeding and different real life
scenarios
and yeah I thought I think one way we
can begin is we did talk briefly about
uh for example last week how
we don't
it's rare to find a true F1 hybrid in
cannabis for example and we talked about
how
um that mendelian model of uh true F1
hybrids
and then F2 gen with uh
genotypic segregation
doesn't happen really in cannabis so I
think Matt wanted to address some of
that and we can start with the F1 Matt
yeah you know
um what are examples of f1s in our world
and how to actually make them
so I'll start really with what they
should be and how they would be made in
terms of uh actual agricultural breeding
versus cannabis
so the definition of an F1 we went over
that last week it's it's Crossing two
distinctly different genotypes
um together essentially right like
you're Crossing two stabilized genotypes
together is the idea but um yeah two
distinctly different specifically that's
very very key because in cannabis it's
used differently so in this idea you
would want to take a Thailand race
um something very very long flowering
tie for example or Burmese or any of
that kind of stuff and cross it to
something traditionally more Afghani
that's interbred or um in this example
let's say any Afghani will do any
Afghani will do from like uh a land race
region so that would be a real F1 hybrid
and by Crossing those two inbred lines
that's where you would get hybrid Vigor
and that's why people when people talk
about hypervigor and cannabis and it
doesn't really necessarily apply because
cannabis is naturally vigorous anyways
and most of the things that we see in
cannabis are poly hybrids so what we see
in cannabis when we see f1s typically
and even I use this this way because
it's it's how it's commonly understood
in trying to
make it anything different even by
calling it a polyhybrid F1 it would
totally confuse everyone and it does
when you do it
um as people understand it is that it is
just two different strains crossed to
each other in cannabis simply put two
different unrelated strains uh and in
some cases even related
yeah yeah and technically though that is
correct to still call those f1s
um we're just distinguishing that from
the
uh true F1 hybrids type F1 right correct
I mean it's it's a commonly accepted I
don't know if it's correct I don't know
if it's even correct to call it correct
but it's accepted I think it is yeah I
think it is I I think I did look that up
to be like
for police
for like yeah heterozygous or polyhybrid
crosses I think they're still
technically f1s but uh okay we'll just
say that we're not entirely sure but
yeah yeah I mean it's just it's just
because f1s have to be two distinct
genotypes I don't know how they just
scrub that for heterozy I guess
because it's a major question
I think that F1 still designates the
filial Generation generation regardless
distinct from yeah yeah exactly okay so
then it is we if if that's the case then
it's being used correcting cannabis if
that's the case and um yeah so in this
example
um most people would say like
uh OG Kush cross to purple Urkel
whatever if they're seed lines you know
male female seed lines you would call
that an F1 in cannabis
um a great example of a real F1 in
cannabis is I see it would be something
that CSI is currently working on which
is his uh land race Burmese that was
from preservation dude and Crossing that
to the Christmas tree Bud
um IBL line which is it is to the point
of where if you if you pop seedlings
from it and you run clothes of those
seedlings of each different seedling at
the clonal level they all look pretty
uniform you know it's it's different
when they're seedlings and seedlings as
most people know seedlings like as they
grow up and mature and you take clones
of them they change they like the Clone
is not usually the same exact plant that
this evening is it's very rare and in
clonal form they all seem to line up
pretty well looking like clones of each
other so it is it is a
I think IBL by definition for cannabis
so that would be a good example of a
true F1 hybrid in cannabis
yeah yeah and just to clarify I think
what we're trying to point out is that
when F1 is
when the term F1 is used there are
actually two possible
interpretations or uh meanings
one of that is the true F1 hybrid in the
mendelian sense that Matt's trying to
get at and then there is F1 in in in
designating the filial generation
and nothing beyond that so in cannabis
most of the time it is the latter
uh but yeah they are exceptions like the
one that just gave yes there's always
exceptions to every rule on that and
cannabis it always finds a way to have
an exception
yep
okay
um how about an F2
so F2 essentially is taking uh the the
progeny the resulting seeds or progeny
um of that F1 hybrid popping those seeds
selecting a male and a female or
essentially a male and a female
um to keep it simple a male and a female
and Crossing them together
foreign
the second filial generation and and as
it goes on to F3 F4 F5 it's just that
same process each Next Generation
selected male or female but the next
generation and hopefully you're
selecting for traits if you're working
them Generations
um that usually helps take it a
Direction
yeah
um is there are there good examples of
f2s or like F2 is being used for you
know particular
reasons okay so um uh an example of an
F2 would be like with the blue bonnet I
got so few seeds of the F1 to pop that I
wanted to immediately do f2s of it
um and that was to open it up and see
what what's actually in the blue bonnet
um yeah that that's that that's the
perfect example of why you would take
something to an F2
um and I didn't necessarily want to open
up the whole thing per se like by doing
an open pollination because I already
knew the direction I wanted to go and
they were already showing those traits
so
hopefully that helps make sense with
that yeah and and then if twos like
we've mentioned before that's where
you're likely to see a greater
proportion of recessives
um and greater uh
a greater kind of uh variation in the
permutations of of genes right like
anxieties
yeah yep
cool
all right I think the next one we want
to move on to was the S1
S1 and I think there are many many
examples of this yeah so that would be
specifically self and a lot of people
get this confused they think all femini
seeds are s ones
whereas all s1s are feminized
it's true vice vice versa is not
um so an S1 means self it's when you
take a
essentially take a clone of another of a
single plant you take two clones you
reverse one using any number of methods
to to cause it to show male flowers you
pollinate another clone of itself and
harvest the resulting seeds that would
be a self-generation good examples of a
self-generation would be like the the
chem 91 s1s from CSI
um the heirloom Afghani s ones that I
did
um and essentially it you do get to see
the recessives despite it being
self so a lot of people like to compare
the S1 generation to the F2 Generation
because you're seeing the recessives
however you're still narrowing stuff
down while seeing the recessives in an
S2 whereas in an F2 that's not
necessarily what's happening all the
time you might miss one right nice too
yeah yeah yeah
God I'm gonna suck it's gonna get these
yeah well I was going to say as well
while you are also likely to find
recesses in US ones you also have a
chance of finding things very much like
the plan you're reversing
you have a chance to find things very
similar
um a lot of people understand it to mean
that you're going to find exact copies
of and that's that's definitely not the
case
um but you'll find things very similar
and some may look identical you know but
it doesn't necessarily mean it's an
exact genetic con I mean it's worth
saying this right like any any seeds
that you make regardless of how you make
them you will never ever get genetically
identical
progeny yeah I mean and it's like this
with humans when I impregnate myself the
resulting babies don't look like me I've
tried this and it doesn't work very well
I I struggle to imagine what they would
look like beautiful though they're
beautiful
okay
all right um and also you know uh worth
mentioning we have obviously addressed
reversals uh and not just reversals
we've addressed self in quite a bit so
yep if you want to hear more about it
definitely reference the last two
episodes we we talk about selfing in
both of them and the next set of
examples the S2s
twos
um
trying to think you know actually I as I
gave an example for S1 for the chem91 S
ones more than likely those are actually
S2s
yes I want you to point that out too so
I I think while it is a great example of
like
a release of an S1 I probably should
have referenced something like
Jesus not even I was thinking geez the
last ones but that's probably an S2 too
so it's like there's a lot of things out
there from clones that we buy as s1s
that might be S2s but because
uh history hasn't quite proven out bad
out to be fleshed out like for sure
they're labeled as what we know them to
be which would be the first true
self-generation that we can prove right
so that's in that case they would be
referred to as s1s but in theory some of
that stuff is S2s and as a good example
probably Ken 91 because it's so uniform
as an S1 is a good example of why it is
probably an S2 but you don't see a lot
of real S2s being released or sold
um so that's why I'm kind of stretching
it a bit to try to find something that
really fits in right there
I think there's there's a cool General
point in there though which is that
if you don't know what you're starting
with you what you what you're like um
starting material actually is what
generation it actually is uh the best
you get in cannabis land is a relative
kind of designation so a reboot not
knowing what the chem91 actually is or
we can say when yourself is that it is
an S1 quote unquote but in actuality it
may be interesting but you know because
we don't know and in reference to that
the blue bonnet itself was supposed to
be a a blueberry Pure Line worked you
know and if you go by who had it you
know DJ's short I think to Vic or to
Tony from Sager math though to Vic High
to Lone Star to me that's a lot of
generations that were worked in there I
mean DJ released it at F4 and supposedly
um you know I mean there's many
generations in there so
it's it's really hard to say on that
like
what generation it really was
yeah
yeah and coming back to this twos um has
our old mate Caleb
done this to work or is he I know he's
talked about it before yeah he has but
it's not often released so it's kind of
hard to reference it but yeah there's
been there's been several things he's
done and taken to S3 where the the
population of seed seems to just be
unviable like they don't pop at S3
um I don't think that's always the case
but it has happened
yeah yeah
okay very cool
all right next one is the f1r
f1r so yeah what is that that's a
designation that we use in cannabis
specifically and it's only to denote
reversal so that when us as breeders and
like this is not science talk now this
is like for sure our own nomenclature
that we instituted right so it's it's so
when breeders are looking at stuff we
know if we're referencing if I'm looking
at someone's writing I know if they're
referencing a male in their line or if
they're referencing a reversal on their
line by that designation so it's
something that we started doing so that
we know in each other's work what we're
referring to if we're going to work with
each other's work and hopefully more
people will institute it over time
because it's very helpful and it's
important and it gets more and more
important as more people come in I mean
just as important as trying to
illustrate that you put the mail second
you know you never put the mail first it
always comes after the female but even
that isn't like
strictly adhered to that I see in
cannabis but I mean we're trying to
Institute some things to make it more um
easier to read or legible scientifically
legible for all of us
well yeah I mean when you have a
consistent set of terms that makes it
actually possible to communicate
effectively with other people yeah
exactly and not not having that I mean
that's how we got here right messy messy
state that we're in right now
um and while well what that's saying is
true it's technically not part of say
the mendelian science it's still very
important to designate in the discourse
of practitioners like in the community
of practitioners so yeah yeah cannabis
is so different than a lot of other
plants and because it's been kept out of
the science room for so long due to its
illegal classification a lot of us were
the ones trying to write this stuff and
understand it from a point of view of
people who are not Collegiate you know
but just trying to do the best we can
with what we had and
um it's interesting is that runs
headlong into science and trying to
adopt that in and seeing how seeing if
they even give a [ __ ] on anything we've
done which is not very likely
yeah
and it's not an uncommon thing you know
in other fields of practice there
especially ones that are not science
based
um
it's still very necessary to come up
with your own taxonomy instead of terms
for the reasons I mentioned earlier
a good example of an f1r would be when
we had the sour dub and we reversed the
Chisel to it
um Diesel and sourdough are not directly
related and uh yeah that's it made for
amazing progeny and we find that that
happens a lot
um Rascal OG Rascal made his career
making a lot of uh like reverse hybrids
reverse feminized hybrids like that some
of the best earliest reverse feminized
hybrids were his so yeah
um modern times you have cannarado doing
great stuff with that as well
yeah and um I would say that f1rs are
very common right yeah very very on the
market now yeah especially now
okay
um next one the BX or BC back cross
okay so we did touch on this last week
yes but yeah and it's essentially
um just taking
trying to think of how to word this best
uh I can do this one because I think if
you want it pretty well yeah so the goal
of a back cross
is you are trying to bring in one stable
trait into an already stable parent
uh that parent is called the recurrent
parent it's the one that you are back
Crossing to
um and you have the introgressive parent
which is the one that you're trying to
take that one trait from
that was really good
that was really good I'm impressed yeah
so an example of that cross one
would be something like uh let's see
what would be good bx1 to use as an
example
I don't want to keep using Blue Bonnets
so I'm going to switch it up and go to
like our strawberry cream strawberry
cream was a line developed by CBF work
several generations and was pretty close
to to breeding true especially with the
Clone we had even when we outcrossed it
strawberry was very dominant and that
was the trait we wanted to lock in
um we knew that we we happened to have
been growing Santa Cruz Blue Dream right
next to it and noticed that they were
very similar the Santa Cruz blue dream
was a female and at this point I wanted
to have a regular seed line of
strawberry cream and CBF had gone taken
a Hiatus and I didn't have any regular
seeds of it so we took a male Johnny
Blaze which was a blueberry Neville's
Haze which is similar to the blueberry
Super Silver Haze that was used for
Santa Cruz blue dream and we outcrossed
that and then brought it back to the
strawberry or that cross we brought back
to the strawberry cream clone and it
produce consistent strawberry Turks so
that would be an example of an effective
uh back cross one
nice
yeah
okay and the final
one that we wanted to touch on for this
uh warm-up was an in Cross are you
breathing between two different filial
Generations right yeah so it's it's not
dissimilar to a bat cross in many ways
um a bat cross is an example of an in
Cross however usually an in-cross is
referred to in cannabis specifically and
again this is one of those the the
nomenclature from Cannabis
um is referring to like taking uh an F4
and Crossing it back to the F2
Generation a selection from the F4
generation and uh let's say you have
traits you like that are showing up in
an F4 male but you had an F2 female that
you really liked
um that in that case you would use the
F4 male and the F2 and that would be
considered an in Cross
um an example of this uh we had DJ
shorts blueberry
um seed line and we had a selection from
it that was very blueberry but very
modern DJ shorts blueberry which to me
means
um like the the butthole turfs like the
nasty Terps with um slight Berry but
very beautiful to look at purple
um short squat indica
and
we cross that to the blue bonnet which
is in my opinion a hybrid of blueberry
but very very dominant for the blueberry
terms and so in doing this my goal was
to make one that looked like DJ's Modern
Line they had the smell of everything
everybody wants from blueberry and a
much stronger high and in order to do
that I did a what we called an in Cross
because that's the best way we could
Define it as since it was given to me as
a pure blueberry line even though my my
suspicions are that it's the Bonnet is
not
because it was given to me as that I
I have to consider it and cross because
I don't want to just like say that I
know something that someone else is
saying is incorrect but I don't have
proof
I think that's a really good example um
could I press you to generalize and tell
us like what are the overall benefits of
using this method
I mean the overall benefits are if
you're not seeing certain traits pop up
in the F2 let's say you run a population
of the F2 Generation you don't see
anything in the males from that
generation that you necessarily like but
you've already like you've already taken
things Generations out like in high and
lowest example or in his case he has his
Appalachia and he worked that to I think
F5 F6 and then didn't like necessarily
what he was seeing so he went back pop
more f2s and at this point if he doesn't
find anything in you know
in those F in that F2 realm that he
liked he could have popped some of the
F6 looked for mail in there showing the
traits that he liked and used that and
hoped that it bred like he liked
wow that's super interesting I don't
think I've actually
um thought about this that much this
this particular uh strategy very cool
yeah
um I think that brings us to the end of
this little intro section let's sort of
warm up
um was there anything else you wanted to
add uh on any of these met no I think
that's it I think that was a I just
wanted to give a quick jaunt with some
like examples hypotheticals maybe I
don't know
I think that I think was really good uh
all right and I think in the next
section we're gonna take it one step
further in terms of uh
uh examples and scenarios and we've got
a bunch of questions from the Discord
that's right um we are going to begin
with screwstone Scarecrow so he's got a
he's going to keep a triangle choke
individual
and um in his words it brought the best
trades from each of the parents had the
amount of high quality resin and a nice
high from the TK great blueberry flavor
from the Bonnet diesel bringing great
flower structure
um and also um augmenting the smell and
flavor
so
he doesn't want to use this keeper and
Crosses yet as he's scared to lose that
particular combination of traits and
what he's thinking about
is going through more packs to find
another similar individual to the keeper
that he's got and maybe doing a sibling
Cross or maybe an f2r now what do we
think about his proposed approach if his
goal is to produce more homogeneous
stock that represents his keeper
so there's a few steps to this that I
that I would ask him first and it would
be are you sure that this is the
ultimate expression from that line you
want to see like is it as extreme
blueberry is it as
potent is it as resonance as you want
and I've seen I've seen examples of this
and it's fun it's an amazing example so
in this case knowing what his example is
I'd say go ahead pop more seeds and look
and if you don't see something
immediately in there
um that you that you think can be cloned
and and you know grown more and then and
might compete or be better I would not
do any of those and I would probably not
cross it and I would uh I would probably
self it I mean if you wanted to have a
uniform homogenous line of that specific
expression
taking it through the generations
through regular seeds would be a little
bit trickier because you're going to
have to pick a male that lines up with a
lot of those traits or you're just going
to be constantly constantly like taking
a step back taking you know two steps
back one step forward two steps back one
steps forward
um it's very easy to have that happen
especially with a line that is a
polyhybrid like that so I really
recommend selfie for that example and
it'll take it more homogeneous quicker
in the direction he wants and you won't
have to pop as many
to really keep narrowing it down
yeah
yeah so
I was also wondering if he did make s1s
and okay let's say that he did pop out a
few more from these other packs that
he's got yeah and he did find another
similar individual
is there anything else you can do with
that to help this kind of homogenization
or is that just not ultimately going to
be helpful like could he self both and
then cross the S1 it's like
you know what what does that do so the
only way that I would recommend only the
reason I would recommend that is if he
found another one that say had such like
drastic potency but was equal
and smell and resin production to the
one that he was keeping but it was
drastically more potent but or maybe it
was slightly less smelly than the other
one but along the same lines and maybe
slightly less resonance but along the
same lines if they're close in that case
like I could understand crossing the two
to try to absorb one of the traits and
not wear out the other two but even that
still just
I mean you're still risking just opening
it up again right like yeah so I mean I
would still probably just S one the the
best of the two
you know or the best of a five or
however many of the keepers are very
similar or what have you
cool yeah
okay and he's got a follow-up and
this one is a bit broader
um he's asking
I think he's asking you in particular
because obviously you know the parents
and he's he's wondering like do you have
a sense of what would outcross well
um to his his triangle choke individual
I think so okay he does say something he
says
um yeah having experience with the
parents and having actually sampled it
uh they're types that might play well
with it I.E
um other plants that may not dominate
um but would still complement it well
yeah so
this is like a lot of the reason I was
doing some of the blueberry or the blue
bonnet like
um hybrid cross work like where I was
taking
um the the blue bonnet Skittles that we
had made and Crossing it to the the blue
map one that we made
um
Crossing The Punchy blister to the the
silver Pearl Blue Bonnet the cream that
we made
to try to see how those two cross
together and every single time it seems
to be moving forward the the blueberry
chirps very heavily except for in the um
in the silver pearl one the silver Pearl
tended to dominate mostly but the Bears
still moves forward like you can still
find them in there it's just not as
dominant as a silver
with that said like I really think like
the first thing that comes to my mind if
you don't have any males that you like
um they immediately show all the traits
like I said it's really hard to select
for and to know if you don't know the
line real well
um
things like the white bonnet
complement that real well because it'll
keep the resin production the potency
and the males from that I've already
found males that are dominant for the
the blueberry
scent expression and flavor so I know
that it can dominate the wife things
like that immediately come to mind but
again that's bringing in more genetics
it's bringing in more outside genetics
but if you're like if you're insisting
on having a regular seed line I would
either use the triangle choke mail and
really hope for it there or if you're
trying to drive in the blueberry chips
which I know he really wants to do I use
something like another Bonnet hybrid of
the same line like I said or something
like the white bonnet
I don't think I knew you you had a wipe
on it just saying yeah I didn't really
sell them much I just passed him out
gotcha yeah
okay I think that is more or less
screwston's
question
um is there anything else you would
recommend or want to add to his
kind of set of parameters or
no I mean any other kind of like weird
Parts you could go down for fun or like
I mean you can always try the mail
selection like I said it's it's I
recommend everybody do it because that's
the way you learn the line try it yeah
um but other than that like selfing
because I know his goal and what he
wants to do it's hard to recommend him
to do anything else or because I know
exactly what he wants to get done with
it and it's a great cut like of of all
the um
the stuff people have sent me in
like that's one of the ones that made me
sleep like hardcore put me out it's
pretty good it's pretty good
very nice okay so I think we can move on
to our next question
and this one's from Kyle Terrell okay he
has a pack of banana tires once and
maybe before we go any further would you
like to tell us what the banana tire is
okay so the banana tie was a juicy fruit
tie that came from a local place and uh
when I picked it up it was a it was a
local club and I just thought there was
no way I thought there was no way that
these people would know what a tie was
or what Juicy Fruit tie was
um but it did look very quote unquote
sativa typically sativa so I took it
home and it was definitely a Thai
dominant plant that had been worked
um probably I my best guess would be
Scentsy seeds type Juicy Fruit Thai
um and it smelled like Juicy Fruit gum
it could be taken anywhere between 11 to
14 weeks depending on where where people
take it like where they like it but it
was explosively Speedy hide it is not
not play around happy Thai weed like I
assumed it would be it is very potent
and the banana tide was that cross to
our Platinum banana OG vx1 mail
very cool okay so continuing on with
Kyle's question he's got two keepers of
uh his banana tires once
um one keeper has a no ceiling High the
juicy fruit smell and taste but POI
structure yeah the second keeper has
better structure and yields uh tropical
fruit and banana chirps but a lower
ceiling for the hive which he doesn't
like yeah and so what he's hoping is to
bring the structure and yield from the
second one into the first one
and what he's thinking about so that's
the goal right and what he's thinking
about doing is reversing and then
combining the two keepers in both ways
and then maybe also selfing each of them
to look through that's yeah I mean
that's great
that's actually a really good example I
think of
of how to do that
how to how to lock in both traits and um
that Line's a hard one that Line's a
really tough one because it uses it
incorporates banana ogu and I've talked
about banana OG a little bit in the past
on the show but
in banana OG there are some beautifully
banana smelling stuff there's some
beautifully OG Kush smelling stuff
um there's combinations both and then
there's like this 60 percent ratio clip
of just blando skunk one just planned
land I mean it's it's got a decent high
but it's just so blanded it's not really
super appealing to anyone not super
resinous super Bland
um in the Juicy Fruit tie in the
outcrosses there is a lot of that too
there's low odor
um low terp
like just semi-sweet plants in there but
they're like that clone example just
ripping and it has a beautiful smell
so in that banana time I knew there
would be stuff that would be variant and
I knew it would have a like what we talk
about a high ceiling low floor as far as
what to expect not necessarily high but
what to expect from the the progeny
um so I ended up giving them away for
the most part
um but then the demand got pretty big so
we auctioned off a few after a few years
of it being out but in the s1s
um we use really good examples of it so
in the s1s
it should be easy enough to do like uh
sister crosses of the s1s and lock in
some traits that way I think it's a
great idea
yeah I guess it'll also be interesting
to see how easy it will be or not to to
reverse some of these as well absolutely
yeah because you just never know you
never know what's going to drop pollen
or not
I should point out by the way that uh we
did not uh manipulate people into using
Matt's work for any of these questions
that is just
yeah from this like we're all from the
small community and so you know people
are growing a lot of people growing mats
work and that's why it goes we're not
doing some kind of like uh underhanded
marketing although I think Matt will
still take it yeah I'll take it I mean
you know if you do a contest if people
want to but yeah
I feel like um organizing contests
online must be really difficult it's so
hard man it's just like even doing like
the small giveaway contests like on IG
we found that like there was almost no
way to do it without a second person
immediately complaining that they want
to
like we just never had it happen without
that happening it was crazy it was like
immediately we're in kindergarten we're
like ah I was first I was first it was
on my screen first you know so it's hard
it's like hurting cats you know
I think even like uh even more
complicated like the idea of like trying
to run like a little like mini cup you
know and like getting samples sent
around and just thinking about all the
different steps in the logistics and how
much could go wrong at every step and
like not being able to guarantee like
much really
um but I remember one of the Adam Dunn
cuts
one of my friends mailed in his example
and it got it got stuck at the post
office and we didn't know why we did not
have a clue why we just knew that we had
to go there and pick it up at the post
office and he had to present his ID to
do it and I remember looking at him like
are you gonna really go do this like as
we pulled up the post I was like is it
really worth it like we don't know why
they're keeping it it turned out they
were keeping it because it was like
short a dollar like I'm postage but like
it was one of those things were like do
you really think you're gonna give you a
[ __ ] lead back bro so yeah there's
all kinds of things that can go crazy
with those competitions just that alone
you know
yeah I can only imagine
I mean I would I wouldn't mind seeing
someone try but I I'm not gonna I don't
think I'm gonna get involved yeah yeah
it was wild
all right
well Okay so we've got another question
from scientists and um this one my
apologies I don't know I I hope I've
interpreted his question correctly there
are quite a few uh moving parts to his
one so I'll do my best
so his story is he was given some seeds
a few years ago
um a set of blueberry seats from one of
his friends
um and I believe he said it was from the
90s
um so
he's essentially wanting to extend his
buddy's blueberry work
um and see what kinds of traits exist in
this lineage that his friend has been
working with okay
um and part of the way that he wants to
learn about them is by Crossing them to
other other lines so
in addition to his friends 90s blueberry
suits of unknown relatively unknown
provenance he's got a bonnet F2 pack I
think according to what he's saying he
has two different pre-98 Barber Cuts
Maybe
and he's also got some peaberry
yeah
so what he's trying to do just to say
again he wants to try them out in
different combinations to learn more
about his buddy's blueberry that he was
given
um that's his initial question
okay
um
is that a question
I think so
uh like I think what he's trying to ask
is like
do these crosses make sense like so it's
on F2
yeah okay what can you what could he
possibly learn doing it actually so
um he listed a few different Bubba
clones right and that
and that's right listed that he was
growing
Bonita
Bonnet f2s then I think he said P Berry
which is the catsup loop on it and I
think he said the pre-90 above a blue
bonnet which is the Bubba Kush
and you can learn about all of those
I mean if he knows Bubba really well
those are excellent ways to figure out
what's going on with his homies uh
blueberry first if it's related to DJ's
blueberry is a good question is it is it
related to DJ's blue run it run it out
um or run out a bunch of these these
Blue Bonnet f2s see if anything's lining
up at all see if there's any traits
laying up
um and if he knows Bubba really well
like finding
those bubble Blue Bonnets are so stable
um
um expression wise that like they're a
great cross to outcross to anything to
bring in potency and blueberry Terps I
know um sub Rob from San Diego's finest
Cuts is it's one of his more favorite
lines is the blubber kush for that
reason for male selection and breathing
so
yeah I know I think it's a good way to
learn I mean like to to learn about it
if he knows Bubba those lines will tell
him more you know
yeah and just to clarify as well I
imagine
uh just to leave like no stone unturned
so to speak I imagine what he is going
to do is actually first run all those
things out separately right like yeah
he's not just gonna like immediately
cross them all yeah and then try to
figure out what's going on because that
would be pretty crazy yeah yeah
so that's not the way uh the way is to
run each of these uh packs lines uh cuts
out look at them all separately and then
maybe after that you can try like
Crossing some of them and see what
passes and like those lines are great if
he knows Bubba
yeah it's like it's really easy to pick
out the Bubba traits from the blue
bonnet ones to me but I know Bubba
really really well so that's why
you sorry you may have actually covered
this but his follow-up was
the peaberry help or would it just
confuse things and slow slow things down
his goal is not to make seed for
production but just learn about
that blueberry strain
um so anything you want to say about the
peaberry in particular the only
difference between the peaberry and like
the 398 Bubba from Shaw is
that the peaberry I think that that
katsu Bubba is a hybrid of Bubba so it
is different than
Bubble Kush traditional it's beautiful
it's purple
um but it is slightly different so I
think that's I mean if you know the
katsu Kai it's still very bubba-ish but
it has different like the way the bud
formations are is different typically
than both then Bubba Kush but the Terps
are very similar it goes from that
coffee
um chocolatey coffee to to the Soapy
cushy depending on how you grow it
I mean it's very similar I think both
are really good
um directions it it's so dominant bub is
so dominant in katsu that you know a lot
of people would argue whether it's a
hybrid or not but I'm pretty sure it is
okay
um
I've got he actually I didn't see this
but he actually had another Point that's
kind of a wrench uh to this plan in my
opinion and maybe it was good that I
skipped over it but now he's now I've
noticed he said he's limited to six
flowering plants per run
yeah I sounded well I mean you could do
it it's just going to take a long time
be patient
so how how do you approach that just
kind of do it in parts right like yeah
just yeah in parts and keep a lot of
clones
yeah yeah
I mean I can relate I can relate buddy
like yes it's not easy no it's not it
just takes time
yeah
okay so anything else you want to add to
this whole Enterprise of like
or do you think we've covered enough uh
for scientists questions I just I just
really like it because like um one of
the initial things that I was running
with the blah blah blue bonnets the
white bonnets and a few others they're
basically Afghani dominant Bluebonnet
crosses
um
that was where I wanted to initially
take a lot of the lines because itself
bonded is very traditionally cushy
Afghani dominant so it's a good it's a
good partner for it essentially so yeah
I like his idea
I think the other thing I like about
this question is that in some ways he's
actually not really that concerned about
making seeds or or
um breeding per se in this one scenario
he's actually just talking about wanting
to learn as much as possible yeah which
we did talk about last week as being
extremely important and like
it's also extremely time consuming and
um resource intensive so it is admirable
I think that somewhere it's like yeah
I'm not I'm not actually about seed
making right away I actually just want
to learn
um and that's quite rare there is there
is one thing I'll add to this and it's
just the the one thing from the past two
shows that I've noticed in the comments
that nobody like maybe they have maybe
haven't communicated it well but the
playing when I refer to playing which is
crossing unknown to unknown or known to
known and just seeing what happens while
I say that's not breeding it isn't um it
is an essential part yes so learning to
breed it is you can't really breed if
you don't know what you have like in my
opinion and it is an essential step but
it's not breeding proper because you're
not doing necessarily having goals with
selection you know it's like not gold
there's not an end goal here we're just
seeing what happens and learning but
learning is a part of it you have to do
that it's a major step so I don't want
to Discount that part as part of
breeding it's a major part of it but
it's not
reading proper if that makes any sense
yeah I think I can I can paraphrase that
um which is that
um the sing what [ __ ] sticks Vibe is an
important part of breeding but breeding
itself is not reducible to that yes
exactly yeah
exactly and I want to make that clear
because it sounds like like I'd see
people's comments saying no it's
important I'm like I never said it
wasn't it's totally important I spent
most of my career doing that you know
like that's that's
you know and I can't shoot on that
yeah yeah I think um
I think
when people hear
someone uh putting conditions around
something
um it does like uh some people can be
quick to assume that that means that
they just shouldn't do it but that's not
that's often not the case often what all
we're just saying always saying is we're
pointing out the limits of something uh
there is never just like something is
outrightly good or outrightly bad or
outrightly useful or outrightly not
useful yeah each each thing each
technique each strategy has its own
trade-offs and limits
yeah each strategy is good for looking
at times
female times there we go
oh I we really need to get some not so
yeah we do
if any of you guys out there get bored
and hear this and want to make little
MP3 clippies of the best nazoisms I'll
toss them up on the sound board for sure
oh that's a really good idea Community
please get on it and help with that I
almost did some
if I had like another couple of hours I
might have tried to get some but yeah
someone else please do it yeah there's a
few I want to grab
um we could also put his face on the
screen what we're playing those oh yeah
I could just make a not so mask and wear
it
that's terrifying yeah it is made for
Halloween I'll make him one for me and
I'll play each other
we should do a Hello
yeah we should
that would be funny
make him okay do imitations of me and me
of him
he has brutal I wonder if it's brutal
imitations of me dude brutal I'm really
I was actually gonna say I didn't think
not so was like would would be down
would is like the you know that he could
do impersonations necessarily I don't
know why but that's cool
yeah I'm not saying they're accurate
but it's more the things that he thinks
I would say that are [ __ ]
yeah
it's worth it all right all right let's
get back to the questions shall we yeah
um okay we've got a pretty pretty good
and open one from quasia he's actually
got a couple but we'll start with this
one so he these are hypotheticals I
don't know if he
I assume that he's thinking about this
but he's not actually started on
anything yet
um he says so let's say he starts with a
pack of Femme seats and he has a few
possibilities here one is csi's Big Bad
Wolf I think that is the chemd n91 is
that okay if I'm not mistaken there's a
TKS ones
or he says one of the recent La Kush
Headband hybrids okay so starting with
one of these what steps would you take
to get a male with as many traits from
the Femme pack as possible
and the follow-up being with the
starting Femmes change the process and
if so how
um yes so they're all different from
each other each step in that
the chemd chem 91 would definitely be
different from
ATK S1 selection since they are variant
dks ones its selection would definitely
matter I mean some are creamy some are
not like OG Kush at all
some are very OG cush type you know
um and what was the last one
uh it was one of the recent La cush
headband crosses from not so in CSI okay
so mostly like diesel super skunk type
hybrids we're in there most of them
though some were like bubble gum and
Bubba Kush or Mendo perps that were very
different so it really does depend on
what the starting material is before we
can dive into the mails but let's assume
let's assume he's
um wanting to do
diesel types
or actually no let's go cam just because
he went with Cam 91 cam D is the first
one let's do that and assume he wants to
go for chem uh types what where would he
go for a male for that
so you know it just depends on the area
you're from and the stuff you have
access to like I would immediately for
any kind of regular chem
breeding hybrid I would immediately
think of uh mad Elite's work with the um
like the chem 91 KMD I-95 specific it
was just so
heads and tails above any other regular
chem work done by me done by anyone else
that I've ever seen it was just so
precise to chem 91 and I don't know how
he did it
um it was just really lucky and good not
just lucky but it was he knows cams
really well and some of it was luck but
it was good selection you know what I
mean like it had Legend OG in there it
had star dog had triangle had all that
stuff in the I-95 and then you add in
chem 91 and chemd which are two
different plants
um but knowing that
and knowing that it's very chem 91
dominant I would definitely advise
quasiya to probably track something down
similar to that
um it's
tracking down chem stuff takes knowing
really reliable sources of it and
there's only a few people I trust on
Earth with chem stuff to know what it is
to know that they don't have fake cuts
to know that they never got fake cutted
any of that um there's only a few people
that I trust for that and I don't want
to throw people under the bus so I'm not
going to name all of them but I really
like Natalie stuff too
nice nice and I think that that work of
his is pretty pervasive now you still
see it used quite a bit don't you yeah
some people have it um we he never sold
it ever you let people have it and if
they were doing auctions for like
Charities or whatever if there was
homies doing auctions he would toss them
in and he gave me a bunch to like sell
and toss in for freebies
um so they've made it out there but like
not everybody picked him up so no that I
mean people use them but they're not as
pervasive as they once were I mean I
know Dynasty uses it I use it and that's
about it that I know of right now
okay just for fun and for the sake of it
would you would you be Keen to then now
move to like say he's starting with the
TKS once and think about what mail would
work for that so a lot of wedding cake
stuff pops up in that um TKS ones when I
say wedding cake type stuff that means
stuff that is like
kind of creamy May Terps to me and just
very resinous very productive very dense
um
you can find that in let's see
what's a good one bodhi's um love
triangle is a good example um you can
like that that triangle ADHD 13 hash
plant though a lot of people thought
that the G13 cashback was too dominant
in it for a uh triangle Kush type back
cross it would be a great one I think
and keep the um maybe hopefully help
with the wedding I don't know if it'll
help with the wedding cake terms but
it might
am I dude well you weren't joking when
you said you could just do this off the
top of your head eh
um I I did it for so long on Instagram
every night for hours
you're doing free consultations with
people yes free always always free yeah
okay all right well how about now
starting with the LA let's assume it's
going to be a diesel type cross
um you know what the sort of wrench in
that Let's do let's not do a diesel type
cross let's do
um
well how you know you know what yeah
let's see a diesel type cross because
that shit's going to be so dominant in
there because it wouldn't make sense I
was going to say let's do like Mendo
perps or like bubble gum maybe but I
don't think that's gonna necessarily
dominate I think a lot of the bubble gum
when it does it's just earthy and not
pink I'm smelling so um diesel let's do
diesel
so again diesel is a hard one because
there's still a few people I would trust
to know diesels
um
for regular diesel lines
God damn that's hard yeah I don't know
if I can think of them easily I'm trying
I'm trying to do stuff that's not blue
bonnet related or blue bonnet adjacent
and I'm trying to think of other people
who make regular seed lines of diesel
that I would highly recommend that I
know for sure are using good diesels um
I know chaco's um let some of his sour
crosses out those are great
um
I'm sure there's some it just really
takes a lot of research and I don't want
to throw anyone under the bus and then
there's certain people I would recommend
that just don't deserve it because
they've been Pricks lately so I'm trying
to think
how about this how about this man make
it be easier what if you didn't have to
find another what if you couldn't let's
just say you couldn't find a diesel mail
or diesel type kind of regular line what
other line would you go to if you could
have
um so I would recommend Super Skunk so
look for like a diesel regular seed
hybrid and now there are those out there
um from other people besides myself and
it's not too super rare to find just
avoid anyone with 420 in their username
because usually those people have fake
diesel cuts
yeah yeah yeah so just to be clear
because Matt's being a bit um
Matt has a bunch of like regular diesel
crosses so yeah yeah and yeah other
people do too but yeah there there's
definitely out there
okay and it's an excellent Super Skunk
type and sauer's a super skunk and
Diesel is more like
um more like diesel than it is like a
chem in my opinion
yeah
okay so within I guess within within
this uh project like in terms of stiffs
you know are there any particular kinds
of steps you would recommend him taking
or
um you know since it's all regular
reading I I really recommend
um bat Crossing one time for the trait
that he wants and then working it
forward
pick a trade start with the trait you
know pick a trait
um you can't have it all
sometimes I mean I shouldn't say you
can't have it all sometimes you get it
all
very rarely do you get it all but
sometimes it's in managing your
expectations
because I mean that did throw me a bit
when he said
um
what did he say he said uh with as many
traits from the fempack as possible like
that's an interesting qualifier for me
where I'm like yeah that's interesting
yeah
yeah I mean sometimes you get good
breeding work done in the pack that you
receive right like the blue bonnet was
red to go
um CSI does great work so sometimes
you'll get you know it'll be that easy
um lots of times it's pick a trait and
stick with one because that's that's the
best you could hope for
um but yeah but yeah it happens
yeah so I think there's a difference
between
something unlikely occurring and you
planning your process relative to what
is likely to happen
um and if you are planning your process
likely to what is uh planning your
process relative to what is likely then
you should try to focus on like a single
trade
um at each step because
you're you're reducing the odds I mean
sorry you're you're helping your odds I
think I was trying to make a point of
that last week yeah I had a really
really skewed understanding of breeding
how it worked how traits work what a
phenotype was all that coming up I
didn't have anybody to teach me
specifics on that I didn't really like I
didn't go to college for this I didn't
pay attention in high school to Botany I
just didn't care like about any of that
[ __ ] right so I had to learn as it went
and it just none of that stuff comes
common sense and that's the one thing
we've been trying to drive home is like
Murphy's Law plays out heavy sometimes
you know expect the worst to happen and
like I I ran into a lot of Murphy's Law
on my way up that doesn't mean everybody
does but I did so that's why I always
like have these qualifiers of like you
know this is the I try to give the worst
case scenario what to expect because
sometimes that's just how it plays out
I mean I felt like in some ways and I
know I'm being uncharitable about our
content but in some ways I saw last
week's episode as just an extended
[ __ ] disclaimer you know in a way
um I don't think that's inaccurate yeah
because
some of this kind of thinking is not
intuitive as you're saying like people
uh becoming accustomed to how you deal
with probabilistic outcomes that may not
be intuitive
um using terms like
low flow high ceiling those are terms
that you use around probability and how
you think about probability that's a
good point
and when you are dealing with
probability uh probability it's not
enough to just say well it can happen
it's like yes any of these outcomes are
possible
but it doesn't mean that they are
probable so just because it happened for
you once doesn't mean that it's
repeatable and that it can be consistent
you might just have been extremely
extremely lucky like uh in the chat
yesterday in Discord in the in the voice
chat people were talking about their
positive experiences with pollen
chucking
um like in the open like hitting Rand
not hitting random branches you know I'm
like hey I could do this it's nothing
big you know I did it you know it's like
just because you were able to do it in
the tent with your you know that one
time doesn't mean that you should like
make that a habit
because I promise it won't happen that
way every time yeah
I mean man you know we're chatting a bit
about gaming which I don't think we've
ever done before uh before we started
recording and it it kind of comes to
mind for me in in the
in the world of games as well where you
might make a ridiculous move that works
for you that one time yeah but if you do
it a hundred times it might work like
three or four times or you know
something some kind of terrible success
rate
and there's a difference between
something being reliable and repeatable
and something that just worked for you
just because it worked for you that one
time exactly exactly yeah
that's actually a really good way of
saying it and uh illustrating
you know like sometimes I play games and
it's like playing with like actual kids
and they annoy the [ __ ] out of me and
and they do something stupid and like
you shouldn't have done that but they're
like but it worked right
yeah but uh you know and then give up
and then they walk outside and get hit
by a car and then they're telling me to
go touch grass or whatever I'm like yeah
I'm old I know oh my God how do you deal
with it how do you deal with them like
cuss I cuss so much
you don't have a full brain I'm gonna
just forget about what you just said I
just want to ignore you yeah okay okay
so we can come back to quasia's second
question which is also quite interesting
okay
um
so his hypothetical scenario is finding
a plant that has some really unique
sense I think he specified like you know
low concentration high impact scent
compounds about essentially he's saying
he's found if he finds something with a
unique scent that he's I don't know if
he's guessing is a recessive trait or if
he's maybe discovered that it's
recessive or has a uh premonition that
it is
um but that that scent is otherwise
getting lost in the overall like nose of
the of the plant right and also it
doesn't translate to flavor
how would he go about breeding to make
that rare scent component more prominent
in the overall nose
and translate better to flavor
he says it's fine to bring in other
specific flavors as long as the overall
package is high flavor and that the
original recessive scent component the
one that he was talking about at the
beginning
um comes through
ultimately
it seems like a
I think nailing both of those things
seems really hard maybe even just
talking about how you try to get that
one draw that one cent out is maybe
enough for one part of this question
so like for me the when he says like a
high impact low
occurrence or whatever low concentration
concentration so like something like a
volatile sulfur compound or something
that's
um dissipates pretty fast I would assume
this way did you say Roadkill
I'm just kidding yeah yes no no never
um no guys I think that's what he's
referring to
um and it's probably the example I'll go
to on how I tried to do it a few
different ways
um we had
two what I think for Super Skunk
adjacent lines in um like Diesel and
then the heirloom Afghani which had a
lot of um typically more sativa
Expressions but
it is mostly Afghani and structure and
that's what we were told it was and it
played out that way but what most people
like it was more narrow Leaf in some
Expressions so I think people would
typically classify that as sativa but I
don't see it as that but I do think it
has super skunk in it or something like
that or it's a similar type of Afghani
um so I tried doing s1s of
The Afghani
and it had a very very high volatile
self-compound
um like you could just smell it like it
was just wild wild strong
in the outcross is what we saw or not
I'm sorry in the self line what we saw
there's a lot of variation uh we saw a
lot of variation in
expression being that it was it would go
from because when you would smell it the
the the combination of all those smells
smelled kind of skunky but like
individually it would be a combination
of like ammonia piss you know um burnt
rubber tennis ball and then
whatever that component is in diesel
that is skunky whatever that component
is that that you would describe is that
in super skunk and jeseling in that kind
of type or sour even
um
it had that but in those three
combinations together it just smells
loud like loud like burn your eyes skunk
um but we saw like each of those
individual Expressions laid out we'd see
stuff that was just pissy we'd see stuff
that was just uh burnt rubber when she
stuff that was more like Savory skunk
but it's really hard to nail the the
trifecta of all three in a in a very
potent form like the initial mom was
super hard
um so I tried that way and at the same
time another location we were doing a
diesel cross to a or sorry a sour dub
cross to reverse chisel
and in doing this I was testing the
super skunk the theory that like if we
double up on the Super Skunk being that
sourdough has super skunk in it by the
sour and
um
uh so no Diesel and then diesel has
super skunk in it probably being a super
skunk self line uh accidental bag seed
and what I found was that more
consistently the skunk spray can seemed
to
and that was the name of the line
um direct it towards the the sourdough
uh diesel seemed to go more towards
keeping it consistently in that super
skunk Savory buttery skunk range
and not veering away from it whereas the
heirloom Afghani S1 would go the pissy
range and more of the burnt tennis ball
range if that makes sense so that's how
I did it
um in approaching that
project in a similar method now moving
Terps into it is is really hard
initially like when I think of bringing
in any kind of Terps to things like
extracts I immediately think it's
herphinoline
because like that terminoline to me is
turned up the volume on most fruity
flavors Berry flavors stuff like that
um I don't know that terpenolene
terpenoline would necessarily be a great
driver of skunky stuff but it definitely
helped in the Fairfax four-way so
there's no reason that it couldn't help
with this and actually translate it to
even more flavor
um but trypanoline is known to dominate
so heavy so you'd get a lot of stuff
that was on later paneling with no
volatile skunk compound or sulfur
compound and uh it would take a large
pop or a lot of luck to find but that
that would be my first thought
yep very nice and I think from a
theoretical point of view like
uh like he was saying it obviously
depends a lot on whether or not
uh in reality this is actually trying to
combine
um a few different traits
um or if it you know from say like a
mendelian perspective it literally is a
single trait that's recessive then
technically again in from a theoretical
point of view if it's a single trait
that is recessive you need to find
another plant that also has that trait
that is and also recessive that's the
only way you will see much of it the
double recessive yeah yeah yeah so this
is from the next like I think Matt did a
better explanation of actually
practically how you would try to
approach it and that's and but by doing
it and everything we've done and also
okay a little bit the big bad wolf and
other um other of these Cam and super
skunk hybrids we're kind of figuring out
yeah it seems like that that that smell
in the Super Skunk lines seems to be a
double or recessive it seems to be
recessive and when you when you do the
super what we call the super skunk
double up technically is it it seems
like it is a double recessive and
locking it in that's why when you do it
it consistently shows
cool very nice I think that one will be
very interesting to a lot of people
okay so um I actually had a last minute
Edition I don't think I got to go over
this one with you Matt but I think it's
I think it's pretty reasonable
um so it's from dougnus
um he's got a male Sour Diesel unknown
provenance so sour diesel quote unquote
um he describes it as being uh
well-structured sturdy vigorous good
gassy stem rub
I'm assuming that he doesn't actually
know he's he's not run progeny out from
it before so just qualify that
um he's doing stem rubs
doesn't specify so maybe we can make
some assumptions uh we're gonna assume
no
okay if you're doing stem rubs you don't
even smell the flower
yeah yeah you're probably right
um so he's also got two female keepers
of Limelight
um that is Key Lime Pie
um by mbbk sorry I'm not as familiar
with this one
um
he says that they don't have the
greatest frame but they grow well they
smell good Pine skunk hint of lime and
ultimately what he's trying to achieve
he wants to put a studio frame on the
Limelight and maybe add a bit more gas
to the back end maybe maintaining or
increasing potency he's made the first
cross already okay so I was mistaken he
has made a cross and he's about to run
through the first generation to dig
through to see what's being passed
um
the questions he's got if I find a male
or female Keeper in the F1 pop
should I go to F2 as well
um or should I just try or what would be
the best course to try and lock in those
like
um traits that he wants in the cross
um
so structure is one of the easiest
things to breed for
um true that's a good point because I
mean hemp is very has great structure
and that's like cannabis and it's
you know like so that's true yeah
um so and when he says it's Sour Diesel
with great structure I immediately think
that's not sour pencil because that's
not and I think he's kind of aware of
that I think he's saying that like you
know that's why he's calling it but you
know it's yeah yeah and that and that's
typical though that's not even a crack
on it because that's that happens a lot
it's a male Are You Gonna Know
um yeah so I I guess maybe his mail he
wasn't able to get much more than stem
rubs off of the smell which also can
happen with males
um
if he's run through the progeny and he
sees what he likes I mean uh
S1 it there's no reason to F2 if you've
already got everything you like with the
structure and the progeny
um unless you think it's not quite good
enough and it's not cheaper enough for
your case like if you think there's
something better in there then of course
you can have to do it
oh good good
I was going to say that his extended
question was basically like
I saw you may have already answered it
he's basically saying yeah how far down
the generation should I go and should I
like consider back Crossing as well kind
of thing
um I mean
like I said people have this want to
like
work a line or think that they need to
work a line but it if you've already
found what you like there's really
nothing else to do with S1 unless you
really want a regular sheet line of it
I think that's a huge point yeah
you don't have to keep working it you
don't have to
you don't need to keep looking if you
found like your ultimate keeper that you
like like it Nails all the boxes you can
always like I said explore look through
the rest and be sure okay maybe there is
something way better you didn't even
know existed but um ultimately when you
find that one that is a keeper well
unless your goal is to have like just a
bunch of regular seats backed up for it
um
then I just don't know any reason
to do anything other than S1 or self it
so a paraphrase of this is
work forward if you are looking for more
yes
but if you have what you are looking for
then
it is less less reasonable to do that
yeah it's just why why
yeah
Yeah Yeah from a learning point of view
maybe but otherwise yeah why it's like
when I see bx6 or bx12 or F12 like if
you're doing real selections on this
stuff you should be able to lock it in
in four moves like at least the trait
that you want or multiple trades if if
we yeah people do bro people say crazy
as [ __ ] dude like people be making seats
for two years and say they're F12 and
you're just looking at them like huh
dude I was watching um I was watching a
BBC documentary on the history of apples
in Britain yeah
I'll say first of all it's [ __ ] most
British thing I've ever seen like it
sounds like it dude um it was it was
actually really cool
um and they were talking about what it
actually took to develop some of their
new varieties and it was they literally
were taking like a decade
oh yeah because sometimes they're doing
um they're they're waiting for sport
mutations which is like a clonal
mutation on a branch to pop up like
that's that that's just waiting on luck
and nature to take its course and time
like it that doesn't it's a random
occurrence you know like um my favorite
apples are what they call them Cosmic
crunch I think they're called and
they're a um or Cosmic crisp I'm sorry
Cosmic crisp apples and they are a sport
mutation off of the Honeycrisp apple and
when I first got them I was like [ __ ]
I'll just get the seeds out what the
hell and then I was like thinking about
I was like wait a minute I know that
that's not quite how it works in apples
it's not just fantasy do you know what I
mean so I looked it up and yeah
absolutely if you pop those seeds you
may get nothing close yeah yeah it's a
sport mutation so it's not going to
occur at all like normally
yeah they still rely very much on um on
clones as well yeah grafting yeah and
the actually I'll say this I think it's
it was it kind of blew my mind this was
the one part that wasn't
um expecting at all they breed
rootstocks
like oh yeah they will they will have
separate kinds of root stocks and then
grasp things onto them and I just didn't
somehow I mean I knew this was a thing I
know especially in Citrus
it's a thing but I was just kind of
Blown Away by the idea that like they
basically have like a cloned rootstock
that they will use so that brings the
consistency I actually wonder if what
that would mean in cannabis because I
know glasses we do it people do it we do
um oh yeah yeah like OG cushions have
really really weak root structure who
was doing this the other day I was
talking to you someone I was talking to
was doing this the other day
um oh I know exactly who it was farmer
Dan um but he's been working on it with
some of their stock and um yeah OG's
have really weak root structures and
they're known for it if you graph that
onto something like a Bubba that has
like really that rich structure like any
any
solid bro you can pound it out with some
OG so yeah
it reminded me of another like quite one
of those like
uh one of those weird like peripheral
projects that you get to see on the
forums
um where it was like
basically like rootstock with multiple
graphs from multiple different
individuals like onto the one mother
kind of like weird Hydra type plant they
always have those emerald cut bro like
the blue dream with OG on it and like
[ __ ] like nine other clones grafting
onto it it's like bizarre novelty plants
I guess yeah like
um kind of cool I guess I wanted to buy
an Apple One Yesterday they have a three
in one apple plant or tree that they
were selling at Home Depot that I think
I like I assume it was crafted
I don't know how are they also they
doing three in one no it must be yeah
apple trees but yeah like but it was
funny because like I see some of them
that would like look smaller than the
others and not be as branchy and they
would they would be advertised as three
in one but there would only be two tads
showing that like so one of the branches
got knocked off that was a whole other
graph so it's really a two in one but
they still wanted the same price
obviously it's Home Depot
I guess the going back to the the the
kind of uh Hydra Hydra like multi multi
Branch multi-individual graph thing I
guess if you were like
you live in a Prohibition country like
me or under prohibition conditions and
like
maybe it would be a very ambitious kind
of mother project where you technically
would be had one mother plant but it's
actually many plants maybe absolutely
absolutely I mean that's that's that's a
that's a solution to a lot of people's
problems I think
um you can't keep many mothers keep a
monster mom hide your mom monster Mom
all right anyone in the Discord who's
Keen please do it I want to see it
um you know my friend Racer X who
um used to be one of my like he's still
around but like he was really integral
in our company early on
um he would do amazing like graph Branch
like grafting like monster branches
um it's like tree grafting branches and
he would do like monster clones like six
foot clones just to see if he could do
it in like air pruning which is where
you know you moisten part of the branch
and like kind of little bit so Roots
come out and they would like running
grow into the soil on its own like he'd
have these yeah
he had great pictures of doing all this
stuff back in the day but I haven't seen
it done in a while
I mean I think I guess the broad
I mean I know this was just like a fun
tangent but I guess a broad a broad
learning from this for me is like don't
hesitate to look outside of cannabis
for examples for information for
inspiration because like I pointed out
last week the information space in
cannabis is basically like ruined and
if you I mean apart from us of course
we're perfect but yeah
but uh otherwise if you want to learn
about breeding definitely like look at
other crops like you know human
civilization has thousands of years of
history of breeding so there's no reason
why we can't learn from other uh types
of agriculture absolutely and and but
one thing I've also learned is um that
like in scientific data specifically
when they are trying to apply say hops
or hemp to drug type cannabis they often
do that and don't qualify that or people
don't understand that it really is
qualified as another
type of this plant and um
I mean it can work backwards too where
like you overqualify it with cannabis
where it doesn't necessarily apply but
you should always look outside of
cannabis always there's so many outside
of the box things that you can bring
from other agriculture into cannabis
that will apply but do remember not
everything always applies
um yes yes yes this would be a
speculative thing not like uh you can
definitely just bring in anything
wholesale and assume it's the same yeah
definitely I was reading a paper the
other day and and this is something that
I experienced myself in reversing like
large populations of hemp
um but they found that hemp reversed
relatively well compared to drug type
cannabis consistently so even though
they are the same plant because one has
elevated THC drug levels for whatever
reason it is much harder to reverse than
like the CBD like plants fascinating
yeah
okay
okay well coming back I think this is
the this is actually a follow-up to
dudes question and it's probably the
last question we'll get to for today
that's good in terms of breeding
scenarios we have a couple of like
miscellaneous reading questions we'll
also answer at the end okay so dudeness
uh his follow-up
I'd like to try to reverse the sour
diesel mail the quote unquote Sour
Diesel mail to possibly get a nice
female individual to pair with
once self how many crosses of the
progeny would be ideal to get a decent
look into them
um
well first of all like what is the
benefit of reversing the sour diesel
mail like I I don't know much about this
so maybe you can speak to that
so in reversing males you use a
different chemical than you would for
reversing the females because we're not
blocking ethylene we're trying to get it
to you know have a lot of ethylene in it
um
when you reverse a male just like when
you reverse a female
you don't just get a perfect male
version of a female you get a male parts
on a female bud structure vice versa on
a male you get email parts
on a male bud structure
and what you can make seeds with this
not all seeds are viable done this way
and also you're not getting a full male
line either you're getting a regular
seed line when you do male reverses so
there's two things to understand there I
mean if you want to understand what's in
your mail I I it's definitely worth a
shot definitely do it worth the shot to
see what's in the genetics of this male
you have you know if you think it's our
reverse them and try to make the seeds
see if they're viable give them a pop
and see what's in the line
um yeah it's doable it doesn't mean that
it's going to be remotely easy or it's
always going to be viable but it's
definitely doable
yeah yeah and I think the rest of the
question is quite similar to the
previous one which is like if he does do
this
um
how far should he take
working the progeny and I guess it just
comes back to what we said earlier well
it depends on what you find when what's
your goal
yeah and what your goal is
um which yeah he didn't specify so I
think maybe then our response is mostly
about the male reversal and what yeah
you know
yeah gotcha gotcha is there anything
else interesting to say about male
reversals I mean most people do it not
to make most people do it not to make
seeds they do it to see what the terpene
profile like to make the male produce
more essential oils or Oils so it could
so you can see what kind of traits maybe
it might be passing you know like oh I
can identify this is the mail trick
because I smell that in the mail the
resin glands on the mail that we did on
the reverse mail I can smell that there
and that wasn't in the female so I know
that's coming from the male side or it's
most likely coming from the male side
um that helps in some scenarios
um maybe okay I just I have my own
question about this
um
let's say you you had you know your
Bluebonnet male the you know now almost
like mythical Bluebonnet male could you
have so technically you could have
reversed that on like you could have
self that
yes and we'll get out of that like would
that have been
probably something similar to
a f
if I know in the line it probably would
have been something similar to what I'm
seeing in the blue bonnet the X1 or the
F2 is realistically because it's already
so uniform
so it it just really didn't really serve
a purpose in that sense in that scenario
cool nice okay that clarifies it for me
okay
um
so I think those are the scenarios that
we have for this week okay I don't I I'm
not assuming sorry I'm I'm assuming that
we will have more episodes if people
have more
uh scenarios to suggest sure um so if
people still do
um please keep sending them to me in the
on in the Discord uh on the in the
content suggestions Channel
um for future episodes I think yeah man
I haven't really decided like how long
this breeding series is going to be so
yeah just playing it by ear
playing it by rear
thank you
um okay so I guess we've covered all the
breeding scenario suggestions we've got
Matt was there anything you want to add
at this kind of like wrap up of this
section
no not yet I don't think so
they were pretty cool it was I think
what I can say is that I can tell you
that the vibe for this this week's
episode is so different from our very
academic Vibe last week and I'm already
enjoying it not that I didn't enjoy last
week it's just very different yeah it
was just more
um I think more brain power involved in
last week's for sure
yeah for me it was this is more heavy
it definitely was for me as well yeah
and it's nice to kind of have that now
as something we can reference and like
point to but I'm also about it and that
we yeah me too have done it
I'm glad we did it too baby
[Music]
it's not over yet Matt I wonder if I
wonder if M.C white out liked me
Whispering that into his face right here
I love that mind cover that's why I do
too isn't that awesome
um
okay so we can wrap up with a couple of
quite interesting questions about like
they are about breeding but they're also
more about like the supporting
infrastructure so McMuffin for example
kind of wants to know like how different
breeders stay organized
I think he specifically had a mention of
like notes whether there's like you know
you've developed your own like shorthand
for things you know I know that you
might have some stories from yourself
and from like maybe CSI yeah how what
what's organization like as like a
commercial breeder so like me and CSI
are the perfect like Polar Opposites on
organization
um
and I I didn't really understand this I
mean I've seen like you know people talk
about taking notes and notations and
stuff but I don't really understand how
organized someone could be when it came
to breeding until like he started
showing me like his paperwork on like
when he would go through and do testing
on different things you know like I'd
watch it was just so detailed everything
was so detailed and you know you know
like has everything written down
cataloged pictures
catalog like and when it came to me
I am the opposite like I might organize
my organization my life is just chaotic
pure freaking chaos so I have never
written anything down everything's been
in my head and like I always kind of
used the reasoning that like well if
anything ever happens like I don't want
to have anything out there to you know
be incriminating or anything crazy but
like in the end it really was just me
being lazy because like I'm just not
organized so I've tried doing it in my
head which it worked for a long long
time until
now when I'm getting older and like I'm
not I don't want to say I'm getting
older like you know like other people
but like I'm further in my career and
it's getting harder to remember a lot
it's really getting hard to remember
certain details and I see why he does
what he does and I'm trying to
incorporate it more in my life now too
and uh this last round of The Punchy
stuff it took better notes you know and
and it was because of what I learned
from him but yeah he's a he's definitely
a good Mentor to have when it comes to
how to take notes and notations and he
does have somewhat of a shorthand
um it's usually by tag number by look
smell taste I you know and it's detailed
it's very detailed because you want to
be able to reference all those fine
nuances and then and anything that can
be construed or bred with as a trait you
want to write down
um and that's not always readily
apparent early on the the one thing that
I did used to do when I was super
interested in breeding purples is that I
took notes on all the tags and I would
always write down the color of the
cavaliens or however you say it I don't
know
um I'd always take uh take notes on
whether they were purple green to start
with to see if there was any correlation
to that and flower and yeah that was the
the first notes I'd ever taken on
anything just because I was interested
but I can continue that terribly long
too far in
yeah I think
yeah for me it's like someone who comes
from like you know information
technology and like and all that like
I'd be I'd have spreadsheets have
[ __ ] database I'd be like I'd be
going hard
yeah man we can collaborate on something
yeah
but yeah and now that you're growing to
know me do you see why like my
personality is like I have never kept
[ __ ] I just don't like I'm so scrappled
at that at the same time I I feel like
for you to have the kind of recall that
you do you must have
internally some some kind of like yeah
internal structure that your brain is
using
to yeah and I'm curious know what how
that might be so like I've tried to stop
doing it but like on the live feeds I
would do it a lot where I have to like
when I think of something I'd close my
eyes real quick and I go to my file
system and my brain that I've tried like
visually doing and accessing it that way
but um
yeah I got a lot of brain fog now so I
don't it's not as easy to do that
anymore it used to be very visual
everything was very Visual and crypto
and now I can't really do that anymore
there's a lot that isn't there
yeah so you're doing some kind of like a
little bit of that like Memory Palace
type
stuff you heard of that were you yeah
yeah yeah I've never been able to do
that I don't think but I think it's my
form of that maybe
yeah I think everyone has like some
structure in their brains I see
screenshots
screenshots but they're not even visual
screenshots they're just
I just think about it and it just places
it's [ __ ] weird I don't know it's not
even visual representations of anything
it's just [ __ ] no maybe I just
closed my eyes and pull it out my ass
I'm not sure but somehow it works
it's interesting maybe I'll go and like
build some little thing for this for fun
it'd be fun
okay yeah I mean I can easily see like a
a very very simple like Breeder's notes
kind of tool which is not absolutely not
far beyond like a spreadsheet but you
know maybe made it it's not far beyond
what you've done with the Codex to be
honest with you it's not either no it's
not yeah I could see like a
I mean a lot of that would cross say
this to you as well I did say this to
you as well that the Codex even though
currently it was intended for historical
plants and projects there's no reason
why you can't use it to design projects
either or track your actual projects so
definitely something for us to think
about for the future definitely
that's cool okay
so kind of related it's still to me
about like
information
and I it's it's one that many people
have asked like it's this one's from
Humble FC in particular but my friend um
Bud Goodman was also asking me about
this which is
clarifying some of the terminology so I
can just say this off the top of my head
right you've got strains you've got
strands you've got cultivars varieties
you've got clones you've got individuals
in general
um yeah you've got phenotype
um you've got lines
and okay I will say this I'm actually
not to me some of this stuff is still
really blurry
um some of it is not for example like I
think I can immediately say that a
phenotype does not designate an
individual plant correct it is a
particular expression of a single trait
um
that is what a phenotype is but yeah
what about stuff like what is your
understanding of like cultivar or
variety or like so so I I've always
understood like cultivar is a cultivated
variety and that like the the simple
definition is a plant variety that has
been produced in cultivation by
selective breeding
so a lot of this to me is very hard to
call a cultivar
by the most stringent standards of the
word and like I'm not handled that a lot
but some like verbiage I'm super anal
about so it's hard to call
a lot of these things cultivars but some
might be
yeah
yeah but most like most cultivars are
done with like root and stem cuttings
um cell division
um grafting
like careful selective seed production
and that's that's a very very specific
qualifier for a cultivar
specific selected carefully selected
seed selection
so yeah some things I think would
qualify and others wouldn't on cultivar
how about everyone's favorite strain
right because I think we can immediately
say for example
chemdog 91 is not a strain is anything
actually a strain like in cannabis like
I know okay from a technical point of
view I know that like strains I use for
like viruses
yes
um in a technical sense right but for in
cannabis land people use it as just like
a captural term for like anything that
has a name almost whether that's like a
like a cross or an actual individual
keeper people will still just freely say
it that's a stream or like that's a
strain or
um
I think so there's a few different
definitions of strains out there right
like most people in their foot
restraints are referring to like
diseases viruses
um or like
strains of endomycorrhizae or bacteria
right but there is also a definition of
a strain and it's
and it's in connection with uh what is
it like just
I'm trying to think of the the word
a plant that has been modified through
selective breeding or through breeding
not say selecting through breeding so
yeah it applies in cannabis it actually
does apply and is correct
um while the strain seems to apply to
most things because it doesn't
necessarily specify careful super
controlled selective breeding it just
says done with Selective reading and
that can be many different things that
can mean many different things to many
different people so I think it more
applies overall than cultivar does
specifically
until they're blue in the face on that
but yeah that's my take on it I can say
this from the point of view of like the
English language at large and like it's
used in different practices and Fields
just because one term is used in one
field doesn't mean you can assume that
that is the correct definition in every
field yeah there are many fields that
use the same terms in very different
ways so just because you've heard the
term strain in like virology or I don't
know I'm not I don't actually know what
those things are called but you know
just because you've heard that term used
in another technical context doesn't
mean that that's the only meaning that
it has
correct um
so I think that goes back to to what
you're saying about strain okay in terms
of like separating an individual plant
from a line you know what would you say
about that like what do you mean
sometimes you know in a cross you'd see
like
um
uh
uh this parent by that parent but like
that's obviously an individual it
doesn't Okay represent the entire line
right like that kind of thing
so when I say expression I it could be I
use it very Loosely when I say
expression because it could be like
a trade expression but I tend to use it
for plants overall expression how it's
expressing in that and by the reason I
say that is because it's it's how its
overall expression is in that particular
environment with that particular
stringent set of variables so expression
works well with me like that's that's a
that's a term that does work but a lot
of people say that phenotype that's the
phenotype from that line
and phenotype is refer referring to a
specific trait expression not the
overall plant the overall plant is not
the phenotype you can say the genotype
is XYZ and that's relating to the genes
behind the X the physical expression but
the genotype isn't something you're
necessarily visually seen it's something
that no underlying genes no by
definition it's not what you are
observing by definition yeah yeah and I
think the other term I've heard that I
think I use with when you're talking
about the plants and just to use the
term individuals
this is a that's great too bubbleberry
V2 individual yep yeah and that applies
very well very very well um and and
strand things like that you know
obviously that's not what it's called
that people do it anyways um there's
also like the other things I hear are
Providence
instead of provenance like there's a lot
of terms that people have tried to move
on in or use and adapt and don't quite
fit but yeah those are the two big ones
Strand and Providence
I I think that when you get strand out
from strain I think in linguistics it's
called like a it's a kind of slippage
that's what they call it um if I'm not
mistaken
um but yeah you know I don't know I
think one one thing I'll say is that you
have people on one end who think oh [ __ ]
it does it just doesn't matter like as
long as generally people know what I
mean it's okay and you have people on
the other end who are like almost like
unwilling to communicate with you
unless you have like locked everything
down and we're never gonna get to that
end either like it comes back to what
you were saying Matt about like
there's unfortunately unfortunately a
bit of a blurry line between the
established scientific terms and some of
the terms that we consistently use as a
community of practitioners
yeah and we unfortunately are going to
have to deal with some of that
ambiguity
because language just isn't perfect and
we definitely don't have perfect
language for what we're doing yet
um hopefully one day we will get closer
but I think so I just think that either
end of their spectrum is not for me like
it doesn't really make sense either way
like you can't just say anything goes
and you can't say like we have to have
it perfect before we can talk
there's obviously some kind of Sweet
Spot between those two and that's where
we are
I think so as a language person I just
want to say that yeah
yeah
okay
um those are the two questions
miscellaneous questions I thought I
throw in there to wrap this episode up
um maybe I did want to gesture towards
some possible future episodes okay like
I said we might just have another
episode that's kind of similar to this
so people have more
um scenarios that are different enough
from the ones we've covered today maybe
we'll do another episode
um there's a possible suggestion from
quasia to do a separate episode on
baselines oh yeah when when we say bass
lines I think Matt has referred to that
in the past as like the big names like
Haze skunk uh what else is in there
there's Durban
this there's a lot of there's a few
overalls but like majority speaking
skunk one or lytase are the big three
yeah so the kind of major precursors
that um kind of like the Upstream
parents uh the Upstream notes to a lot
of the uh cannabis that we see today the
majority of the night majority yeah
yeah and that could be cool uh for an
episode oh yeah uh the the other
exciting uh possibilities we may get
high and Lonesome back for
another episode because he did tell me
that he would be quite Keen to speak on
breeding for recessives
and also to speak on his Appalachia
projects which obviously you know is a
is a big story and has you know many
twists and turns so that would be very
fun to do yeah
so there's plenty plenty for for people
to look forward to in the upcoming
episodes
absolutely and um let's see we also have
the uh C2 custom glass
just I I think tomorrow I get to see the
Breeders syndicate versions of their
glass pieces for the first time so I'm
super stoked man like I think that's one
one thing like I've talked about it like
you get leveled up every once in a while
um in certain things and like glass is
not my forklate right and I didn't I
don't I didn't really understand it
being anything more than just a thing to
get from point A to point a tool a tool
right to get from point A to point B
smoke to lungs but I didn't really
understand that like there are certain
techniques that can be used in glass for
making things clear fast and like these
are overall so much better than any
piece that I've ever had like the fact
that we get to have like for your
Syndicate random ones blows my mind
that's that's end game in-game caption
so Props to them I'm stoked to show them
um show them to everyone and make them
available too to everyone which is rad
it's Epic so yeah I was joked about that
I do want to add one more thing uh while
we're doing this kind of like outro like
I've been watching our stats and I'm
really really pleased to see that the
engagement for the last few episodes has
really gone up like we're getting the
most comments that we've ever gotten
really like Yeah in our recent episodes
you know I'm not counting like very very
old videos that have been around for
years
um we're kidding like as almost as many
comments as those in the pit in the
space of like a couple of weeks so yeah
um I'm really stoked about that
keep commenting keep keep interacting
you know like I like engaging with
people in the comments because it's fun
like it just it just takes the episode
further and learning further and I
actually some of the comments like if
you go through there like you'll catch
like old vets talking in there that'll
say who they are and you'll realize oh
[ __ ] that's that person you know like
people chime in that are really cool
yeah it's also the place where like if
you're not in the Discord because
obviously people can use the Discord to
do this but it's also the place where if
you
um disagree with anything that we've
said or you have more questions like
definitely bring them up there because
like I said last week we're not gonna
always be perfect and we're gonna make
mistakes we're gonna miss out on some
things so he's gonna keep prompting us
because I don't
keep prompting us because we can always
follow up
like actually I'll mention that like for
example uh it wasn't in the comments but
not so actually popped up in the chat
last week to kind of clarify that
applying can actually be true breeding
just for a one trait
yeah um and that that's not the same as
a plant being crew breeding for a whole
bunch of significant traits
um and that's true that's true so you
could have one trait that's uh your plan
could be breeding you know homozygous
dominant for one trait and that's
technically a true breeding plant for
that trait but you could also have a
plant that's like you know homozygous
dominant for a whole bunch of them and
then you have something that's
more like a quote-unquote IBL right in
that in that set of terms so yeah sorry
random example of like
you know good little follow-ups here and
there yeah it is
all right so with that I guess uh let me
see don't forget to join the Discord go
for Clinton or forget to click like
subscribe share all that good stuff the
uh things you're supposed to do to be
supportive the shows you like I guess it
does help it really does help like it
does
so please do that and um or hit dislike
if you [ __ ] hate it that's that's
cool too
um uh I think that is it anything else
you got
I forget that's it for me
thank you everybody
cheers thanks for uh us here at reader
Syndicate we'll see you next week
once I could catch you
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out