welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate hey everyone I just wanted to
take a quick moment before we enter into
this uh awesome awesome episode with
more members from the can of command let
you know our blue
Revolution is in stock the blueberry in
cross that we've been working on for 5
years now is finally at its uh what I
feel is a great completion point for it
uh a true breeding line for blueberry
scents and
flavor um it was our most popular
selling line on the original release
when we released the first Blue Bonnet
crosses I didn't make a whole lot of
them because I really wanted to explore
what was in them before I did a major
release uh we were at that point and it
was uh originally a DJ Short Blueberry
from DJ shorts early early work where he
would sell the seeds at different talks
that he would do across California at
collectives uh buddy resin lung picked
up some packs he gave them to me I went
through them and found the best
representative of what I thought the
most beautiful blueberry was
like but it didn't have the exact scent
that I wanted when I saw that in my
mind's eye and I was as I would look at
it I would picture beautiful blueberry
Jam TPS and flavor and scent just all of
it and they didn't have it so we made a
mission The Last 5 Years to make this a
reality and something where you could
pop a pack of seeds and it would be
almost identical for that tur profile
we're there they are now released on
Riot seeds.com the pre-orders over
they're already shipping out we also
have something called The Modern Blue um
that we didn't really release we did it
on our uh patreon so definitely check
that out our 50 tier patreon ended up
getting the Lion Share of these with
their monthly package and it was the mac
daddy cross to Blueberry incross Mac
Daddy from a company called ouse
genetics and then my personal favorite
out of the uh hype strains as it were
that we are kind of uh merging with some
of this blue stuff so that we can bring
it into the modern generation and get
some of the new kids interested the
sherb cream pie phenomenally resinous
great hash maker great yielding nice
long high for a sherb cross which is my
biggest problem with Sher cross to our
blueberry in Cross and we call that one
blue cocky and um yeah triple on Tandra
there U we have bluy because it's Blast
for me to use something like runs for me
but the white runs out of all the runs
stuff I found to be the best runs cross
with the most potent High we did a
blueberry incross cross to that bringing
heavy heavy blueberry jam turps to the
white runs we also have trop Berry which
is the Dosey trop uh Tropic trop Cherry
I believe cross to the dossey do cross
to the blueberry and cross all of these
are currently available on our site um
when they're sold out they're sold out
and that's it um wanted to make sure
you're all aware of that and without any
further ado let's get into our show and
welcome curbside and some of his homies
from the
cabet Welcome to Breer Syndicate I'm
Matthew and today I'm here not with my
co-host he's uh busy doing work so today
I'm G to be the one hosting it and we
have some of the other crew from the
Canon Cabana we got Oki we got Chris V
is that how you say it yes sir and Kirby
The Man Behind the new version of can
Cabana and today we're going to talk
with each one of these guys about how
they got into everything um what their
Specialties are what they've done with
it uh the different areas they've
traveled and not only that but the
future for the Canada Cabana because you
know we really want to instill from from
the Breeders Syndicate side how
important Forum culture was and is and
will always be to keeping like
everything correct straight and keeping
that part of the culture alive because
that's that was been a major part of the
culture for all of us so with that um
Oki you want to start tell us about
yourself brother how' you get
started uh yeah I got started in the uh
uh weed Biz by uh pretty much not having
any access to to good weed in Oklahoma I
was tired of uh kind of the the Mexican
brick that I was used to getting and I
kind of figured hey I might be able to
grow better than this and uh so yeah
that's where I got started back in um uh
2002 in Oklahoma uh in my closet and uh
after that you know we moved to Denver
which is where all of us met and uh you
know kind of uh gradually scaled things
up over time where did you get your
seats from early on when you uh your
your first genetics man you know I think
it was do you remember it was like uh
Heaven's Gateway or something heway yeah
yeah yeah yeah that one um I got some um
the first the first seeds I ever grew
were I'm pretty sure it was uh Brothers
grim c99 and then it was a
G13 uh hash plant cross and real nice I
mean I was a shitty grower at the time
so it wasn't that good but uh you know
it was a nice place to start yeah dude I
mean it's like a a different look from
the Mexican brick weed obviously I grew
up on the same like I was a had definite
meth Mexican brick weed smoker you know
growing up and uh I appreciated it for
what it was until I found real dank and
really quickly realized there is a whole
this is a whole another level of weed
bro so yeah I appreciate that how about
you Chris tell us some of uh your early
Beginnings yeah I I grew up in Florida
um pretty much similar story to uh to
Oki you know started growing in my
closet when I was in college
uh started smoking when I was like maybe
12 or 13 kind of on the regular by by
late high school you know um and in
college I actually found myself like you
know I went to a big Florida College
like everyone partying and I just
couldn't like hang and drink like
bothered my stomach and I soon I soon
figured out that like cannabis was my
social in it was my way to talk to girls
and my way to hang out with people and
you know because I couldn't hang on like
pounding beers night after night yeah so
um so it kind of just became my thing I
started selling weed I started growing
weed and um you know I met some good
people early on that that got to put me
on got you know guys that had a bunch of
grow houses going and just put me to
work as like a as a grunt basically and
you know we just had the old speed trays
with the Rockell slabs and you know this
like early early mid 20000s you know
similar timeline 2003 2005 and uh and
you know had couple spots eventually got
my own little spot going cranking out
and uh and then we all got
raided and uh and then ended up laying
low for a couple years and uh you know
spent a lot of time in Amsterdam going
to Europe a lot and uh you know and then
went to California in
2009 was in Oakland ended up getting
like robbed and just everything fell
apart it was just like an Oakland story
you know this was 2009 when things were
just
bro yeah and I had a cousin in Denver
and I was like you know Colorado is not
that bad and they're like legalizing
like Cali is so I just went there and
like kind of started life over in his
basement and he let me kind of run his
grow and uh you know within less than a
year of being in Colorado I had a a an
investor a warehouse a spot you know I
was just kind of just just in it meeting
people and you know it's a good thing so
what were some of the early strains you
saw when you were for barely starting to
grow um the guys that I got put on with
just were growing this hash plant this
Florida hash plant that you know I've
heard the guys from Swamp boys a couple
people that were in that scene in that
day talk about um I you know some people
said it came from the cense SE hash plan
from Amsterdam but nobody was really
sure um some people some people say it
may have been the white before we called
it that oh sure yeah because it had that
you it was squatty um it was real hashy
smelling like that mirene kind of really
cut through um and uh yeah it it was
just about pumping that one plant out
and it was super dank but I feel like
like I never saw anything like that
again I think that cut just disappeared
like everybody got busted and it just
didn't make it you know yeah Florida had
some dank bro Florida had all kinds of
over there running around in different
little uh circles pretty wild yeah was a
big indoor scene up until 2006 when the
you know there was Federal funding to
like get everybody busted but they they
said that was more indoor in Florida
than the California I believe it yeah
yeah they held down like you know the
triangle Kush the white like you said
the Gainesville green there's all kinds
of stuff that came out of there that was
just absolute fire and and changed the
world of cannabis as far as I see it yep
okay Kirby
cbide
let's see uh probably like mid to late
90s I started smoking weed swag weed
that I was stealing from my dad
you um you know so and he uh he didn't
have the highest of standards for
himself so it wasn't very good for sure
yeah and uh but then I I had a buddy um
real good friend of mine who had went to
Amsterdam and he came back with some
seeds believe were uh some Neville's
Northern Lights number five and oh nice
he grew that and we smoked that for
years we called it CLE brand and uh that
was kind of like he he was the first
dude uh of our of my friends that was
growing weed
had um you know did it from seed all of
that and uh had another buddy had
another buddy who was a big smoker who
had a hippie friend who always had like
the fire like the best weed that we had
seen at the time and uh he had some
Strawberry Cough one time I remember
Yuck Mouth from the loonies was in town
and we got this ounce that we were gonna
go sell to yuck mouth and uh he looked
at it it was like the best weed we had
ever seen too we were all just like oh
we shouldn't even sell this to him and
then he takes one look at it he's like
oh this is some fruity [ __ ] I I want
this and like
talk and we were all just like what the
we're just like crying over here trying
to figure out how we can get this weed
back from him yeah right but
uh yeah so we just started smoking he
was you know I started learning how to
grow a little bit of weed from him I was
always you know hustling some weight on
the side and
uh early on my favorite uh I mean back
in the day when I think of like early
2000s weed and it's still I've talked
about it several times favorite weed all
time cat piss it would stain your pipe
it would you know you you'd be smoking
something different three weeks later
and the resin in your pipe would still
taste like
catpiss just so pungent
and um what area of the country were you
living in I was in Denver Aurora you
were in were you born and raised there
born and raised Aurora Colorado okay
cool cool all right I didn't know that
part so uh yeah that's
uh early on
uh right when Chris kind of moved out
there it was probably around 2009 surely
after he got out there we linked up
um online somehow I can't even tell you
specifically how it happened end up
working with Chris in his first
Warehouse that he even had up there in
uh Boulder it was uh behind a strip club
called the bus stop and uh it uh there
was always some entertainment provided
and sure standing out smoking your joint
outside of work you
know so yeah then uh just you know Chris
he's so good at uh networking and
meeting people and he travels around all
the time like so many people that I've
met and become friends with or you know
mutual acquaintances with is from Chris
traveling around meeting everybody and
one of the best introductions that you
could make you know back in the day in
the weed game was like oh I'm such and
such from the Cabana and it was almost
like you know the locks and the doors
just opened up and it was like you were
almost already kind of verified and uh
so you already had the Cabana stamp of
approval so a lot of people were more
open to
uh meeting you and you know talking to
you and working with you and stuff
so that's how uh it started early
on yeah dude I remember you know I think
me and you first met I don't remember
who it was through maybe Phil Phil Rojo
but I remember we first met at a strip
club uh uh Shotgun
Willies every 420 back in the
day uh canado with throw a big um event
at Shotgun Willies and can't remember
what it was he had some kind of loose
connection to Shotgun Willie so yeah
just a few loose connections there yeah
something where they allowed all of us
to go in there and run rampant for the
day but yeah there there were h a couple
of really good years where we had a lot
of people uh I remember the stat bills
bro stacks of twos from
kiry if you were there for the $2 bill
year you were there for a good year oh
yeah I was there the year I don't know
if you remember this me and Joe scho
decided we were going to start smoking
inside Shotgun Willies and the cops
[ __ ] pushed us all the way into the
back and we're kind of surrounding us
slowly but surely because they weren't
quite sure if we're going to [ __ ]
fight and what we're going to do and all
of a sudden like a hooker back backed
her Lamborghini up over a cop car and
that was it dude like they all B out the
front we were able to [ __ ] scur on
out them boundaries
bro and uh it's just crazy because like
events like that man just the Six
Degrees of Separation that so many of us
have yeah you know what what do you call
the Kevin Bacon Theory or however it
it's like for sure and uh we and out in
Colorado man it was cool because there
were several
uh
um I gotta I might have a special guest
for us later man we just mentioned his
name he actually just texted me here so
who see if we can get Rojo on here man
oh my God that would be killer dude
would be
killer where was I at I lost my train of
thought there uh just you know seven
degrees separation Kevin Bacon how we
all kind of went through there and oh
yeah out in Colorado there was kind of
like you know we all knew each other we
all had gone to you know motive uh
motive 303 he used to throw a bunch of
uh great dude barbecues and Gatherings
at his house so we'd go over to motives
I would do some at my house we'd come
over to mine we'd go to skitty's house
we'd go to Bobby O's house we'd be at uh
Ho's of course that was kind of like
the um the home base I guess you would
say and uh but you know there there were
people that hung out with you know cops
and Paco and Rojo those guys kind of
always hung out you know with themselves
and then motive and you know I might be
getting you know getting things wrong
and who hung out with who but everybody
had their own little clicks and you Roo
yeah Rojo and Paco and cob oh yeah yeah
um because they all used work together I
think um at a spot down here in Denver
there was also the Adam Dunn Cannabis
Cup event events you remember
those at all yeah when they started
doing those me and Mitch originally had
planned those out for an event we were
going to do called the Breeders ball and
it suddenly got like co-opted into Adam
dun's kind of gig but those were kind of
fun too because like you'd have breeders
that [ __ ] wanted to kill each other
at those events and we would all just
kind of put all our our weapons down as
we came in the [ __ ] event and smoked
and there was a period in time with the
events
probably it's this probably 10 years ago
now where it's like 10 years ago I'd say
was like the height of cannabis events
and then then they started kind of
getting flooded and uh there was too
many of them and they were too expensive
and all of that they kind of drowned
themselves out and then covid came and
you know nobody wanted to hang out with
anybody exactly right it's still uh it's
still recovering now I think as far as
like a smoking cannabis scene and it's
it's a little different I mean a lot of
people are you know still you know just
sit down and Blaze with anybody but I
don't want to go to a cup and just smoke
everybody's weed anymore I've been and
I've had cup cough I don't want to you
know yeah we we have events um for our
group like me CSI bod a bunch of us out
here in California and I'd love to get
you guys all to come out for it um if
possible I know it's a you know hell of
a trip but we do it out in the last time
we did it out by Yos rented a big ass
Mansion crashed for a few days and just
smok tons of different kinds of weed
from everyone and it's you won't have to
twist my arm very hard man yeah it was
it was in the like I really took it from
like the nugs and jugs events the [ __ ]
korado did even some of the Adam dun
stuff like it was all inspiring to me to
be like I think we can pull this [ __ ]
off where even if people don't
necessarily get along we can get along
for three days smoking weed and talking
weed and being [ __ ] nerds for a
little bit and it's it's been [ __ ]
insane one year we had like you know
Josh D all the triangle guys come out
the Irene crew came out it it was pretty
phenomenal so this next round I really
would love to have some of you guys come
out I learned from the events that uh
the booth is like the magic spot you
know if you have the booth where you
know and when I was working with the
Lazy Lion we would always go out of our
way to have one of the biggest booths
and to have extra space so people could
hang out and to have that social aspect
of it and I would always tell all these
breeders like you don't need a booth you
can come set up at my at my booth and uh
sell seeds make money you know we can
combine the traffic of everybody over
there and it it it worked real well for
a long time and every everybody was
always welcome and we made I made some
great friends that way yeah dude um and
met a ton of people and acquired a ton
of seeds gave a ton of seeds away you
know so
uh it was good times back in the day and
I I hope uh the industry can get back to
there at some point there has to we got
to kind of level out at some point I
think I think like what we're trying to
do with the show too is to bring back
some of that culture um teach some of
the younger dudes that this [ __ ] did
exist does exist can exist and that
there there is something deeper than
just like trying to strain hunt the
newest cookies and flashing your and
flexing your [ __ ] on Instagram like
you're some big baller like there's a
lot more culture involved in that like
love and Brotherhood yeah very deep that
last last decades and span decades you
know that they can become a part of and
be involved in if they're good
people the newer generation too I think
uh they're spoiled in the sense that
uh we gave them so much stuff that they
didn't have to work for at all yeah very
true very [ __ ] true you know these
events like they were kind of taboo for
a while there and it's like people were
scared to go to cannabis cups like early
on because it's like they didn't want to
be associated with them or seen at him
or something and just the the whole
shift of how how it's changed over the
years and the Dynamic of how people
approach them and how they're utilized
and stuff is uh it's interesting to see
you know I miss I miss how Emerald cup
was out here because we get a lot of you
guys out here for Emerald cup and like
getting to see guys like Rao you know
you guys and interacting and it it was
super [ __ ] cool because we don't
living across the country we don't get
to see each other to often and and a lot
of that culture has been lost with the
emerald cup how Corporate it's gone not
cup used to be kind of the the thing
that
everybody was it was looked at as kind
of like the equilibrium where it was
fair playing ground and the best of the
best was going to go there and then it
turned into sponsorship dollars yeah and
seed companies would make like their
their money for the year there dude like
that's make a chunk there and that and
it would feed a lot of people I've seen
uh I've been at the booth you know yeah
right with with people and seing uh well
end of the six figures come in over over
the weekend for sure you know those
weekends I don't know how many of them
there are these days but back in the day
there were some good weekends yeah dude
there there really isn't anymore I mean
like um if you're not like a registered
licensed company you're not getting in
and that's just that so a lot of of us
just don't give a [ __ ] about that part
of it you know not me of course I'm
totally legal and uh follow every law so
you know yeah I thought I thought
Emerald cup probably peaked in like
2016 and then after that it just kind of
got like you know more more just
corporatized and more about the business
than than actually an event for Growers
um because it was always good going out
there because like as a grower you know
you yeah you can go to all these other
cups and you know High Times Cannabis
Cup or whatever was going on but you
didn't really have access to like the
genetics and what was really happening
but you know Emerald cup whatever I go
see a doctor for five minutes right
there in line to get in and he checks my
arm and then I'm going in the back
medical area and you know and I get to
like talk to the Breeders and they have
jaars of the flower and I could open it
touch it smell it before I buy the seeds
like you couldn't do that online could
do that anywhere you know so as a as a
grower it was the number one event
because like you could touch and feel
the genetics before you grow it that's
so that's a that was a game Cher and
when they got rid of that I was like
there's no point in going anymore yeah
that's way I felt I stopped
participating myself everyone always
used to bring their special drops to the
emerald cup too like you know their big
crosses and their big drops and exive
drops bro I mean I
used my my Emerald cup budget was blown
every year and far exceeded on uh uh
beans and stuff that I would come back
with and then and people are always
gifting you know coming to the booth and
dropping stuff off and things like that
and uh just
so the genetics
uh that the Amo cup provided
man hands down the best event I would
say absolutely there were some good can
High Times cannabis cups in you know
Denver and I was out there the first
year for that and it was pretty decent
first year for the Denver one yeah the
very first Denver canas cup yeah it w
those ones were good I think uh I can't
remember if uh if that was the year I
brought cornbread Ricky out it was the
year Karma actually won the cup okay
yeah his very first cup and it was like
[ __ ] one of at the time I thought one of
the good guys won but he ended up
snitching on me so karma did oh
yeah sure [ __ ]
did yeah right
it goes that's the other hard part man
is
uh you know everybody has their list of
people that they don't [ __ ] with man and
whereas Cabana I've been trying to make
it a place where everybody
can you know be friends with everybody
and I've been I've been trying so hard
to make that happen and I have
encountered a couple of walls where it's
like oh
so and so this and so and so that I'm
like bro grown man this is the internet
ignore him like yeah yeah it's not too
[ __ ] hard you know like even for me
who's a very aggressive personality and
like really have a hard time shut in my
mouth like it's kind of nice to have the
Cabana and and like I've even dropped
some beefs with people that I [ __ ]
hated since day one um you know people
that trolled the first my first trolled
bro and we reached out to each other
just like dude how old are we now let's
just [ __ ] chill you know it's been
nice for that reason and and it's opened
up a lot of bridges for me but like some
of us grow over the years and and get
used to that [ __ ] like even with the
karma thing like that was a big deal but
like at the same time I'm past it it's
just whatever you know yeah there's
always extenuating
circumstances that was one of the
benefits I felt like of the Cabana was
that because you had to go through this
invite process and they were more strict
about you know starting [ __ ] that you
didn't have just like trolls like I mean
we were all on like IC mag and all these
other sites before that you know and and
you could just create another account
create another email whatever go on
there talk you could talk [ __ ] about
yourself as a way to Hype yourself up as
a seed brand because just to get drama
started or whatever abely do that you
know but you couldn't none of that was
flying on the Cabana because I got
booted so many times
bro yeah and it was you and you had to
like beg you know beg to get back on
there yeah dude you know I'd have like
long conversations like three four hours
with with hoe with the admins of like
all right I'm sorry you know yeah yeah
there were Zero Tolerance policies and
then there were Cabana Zero Tolerance
policies man and they took them to uh um
another level back in the day but they
were actually needed at the time they
really were they really were and it
offered uh it made the bana a place that
uh for I mean for so many reasons but
that one specifically made it different
than the other places man because
somebody got in there and mouthing off
like it it was it was deleted it was
reported he was banned it was never an
issue yeah you know and I never I never
held any hard feelings because I always
knew it's like that's the old guard at
the Cabana and they don't put up with
that [ __ ] so I never hard feelings I was
like yeah I probably [ __ ] too far on
that one you know like you kind to know
you got to self check a little bit but
they've always been even after that
though they were always [ __ ] cool to
me you know what I mean so it's always
been a place close to my heart even with
the Cabana and me you know there was I I
did a lot of things that weren't exactly
like uh Cabana friendly activities sure
so I wasn't on there actively for a long
time but I I'd still be belly boating
with hoe on the weekends and going
fishing and at all the barbecues and you
know
so I I I don't have many posts on the
Cabana I I was never like the most
active guy on there
and but it's
because I was working with seeds boom
I'm working with all these breeders I'm
doing all these things I'm doing all
these testers and boom they don't like
seeds I'm you know growing weed for this
giant dab bar where it's like a smoke
facility and yeah yeah you know we don't
want to promote that to the to the crowd
and so there's just things I was doing
that uh weren't Cabana friendly but I
was still always around with the Cabana
and um you know skdy I give him a ton of
props because to this day I still grow
just my own version of Skitty Tech you
know it's all yeah yeah essentially the
same um kind of technique I I switch up
my nutrients and I've done things you
know tons of different ways where skdy
is pretty tried and true and he does not
yes he does deviate from his script very
often and uh Still rocking it with
tremendous success to this day you know
so and skdy was the first dude that I
met like years ago this like
2011 where he's like yeah I only got got
like 3.1 per light on this round you
know I'm going to do better next time
and it's like everybody used to throw
those numbers around on the forums and
we're like yeah bro whatever Forum right
and but like I had the you know I'd see
his garden i' see how meticulous he was
in his canopy and I even went there just
to trim for him a couple times and just
to see what it was and I'm like bro
these really do weigh what he says they
do like like wow and and you know he was
you know like curb said there's a lot of
just consistency there and um you know
he he he just was like he just had his
method and uh I mean it was kind of like
early crop steering before we knew what
it was because he'd be watering them a
couple times a day by hand you know go
back you know yeah skinny steering there
you go you know but yeah sometimes he's
hand water four times a day you know so
um and and we didn't understand that
then like more water more equals more
yield like really like you know like
isn't it already wet what does that
matter yeah
right you know but but yeah he he he
really proved that because yeah because
I mean back in the day like on the
forums everybody like said whatever you
know it was hard to prove anybody's real
yields and everyone's setups was was it
was primitive you know so it's not like
we had deuses on the ceiling and like we
just slap job and even even even bigger
bigger grows 100 lighters I mean we were
using residential AC's and like we
didn't really know what we were doing
then you know from an engineering like
design standpoint at least so um so it
was just cool to have that open sharing
of knowledge but but like what was
different for the Cabana was just it was
so genetic centered and you know like
like curb said at the beginning like you
know it was all it's just like open a
door like you know like The Gatekeepers
had finally opened the gate to like all
the hoarded clone ones of the time that
you only read about that you know like
we were like ah it's finally my turn to
be the cool kid you know right and you
could finally see pictures good grows of
some of these things that you'd only
heard about and and you know I mean when
you look on IC mag you'd see people
growing it it'd be like nine obviously
different plants that weren't related
but finally on the Cabana you could see
legit [ __ ] being grown and that was
something special I think and uh and
it's and it's one of the things I'm
telling people now like why should you
visit the cavana because you can finally
see that [ __ ] you can finally go look
and see all that stuff it's there you
know like this is this is important
historical
documentation I do encourage people to
dig through these forums man and look
through some of these old posts and you
will be shocked at who you
see chiming in And discussing things
like back in the day when it was like uh
you know ghost OG was the hot thing it's
like I knew we had the real ghost cuz
how we got the ghost from Ghost you know
what I mean and it was like
uh there was never any question about it
and the authenticity of clones when
people really started
like trading
genetics it was a blessing and a curse
at the same time because you got the
people who got the real genetics and
will share them and get them out to
people and then you got other people who
will take any old thing and just say oh
this is sfv yeah Kush and uh when you're
somebody trapping out a 10 lighter or 20
lighter or and that's your main thing
you got your whole garden riding on
this riding on this sfv OG clone or
whatever it may be and then it's some
boof [ __ ] that's not the real thing you
know even if it's good but it's not sfv
it's like you know that was the hard
part was confirming things but the
Cabana everything was like already
confirmed I see mag THC farmer
everything came like with a level of
skepticism there's so much [ __ ]
shenanigans on those places bro I can't
even there's not a lot good I can say
about those places to be honest I mean
granted I love those and I encourage
everybody man I want every back in the
day I was on THC farmer IC
mag
um troll it up I I was never on roll it
up but uh Ivan from Jungle boys had his
own little Forum like there for a minute
I can't even remember what it was called
right now uh can of collective I think
um oh God
yeah that might have been a seed bank I
can't remember yeah that was that was
the uh after that that Forum pot pimp
went down it became can of collective
you remember
pool the UK group oh [ __ ] what a dumbass
name for a forum there was another one
that like um like cornbread and a couple
guys were on that was uh bunch of Cali
guys were running it like Sway and those
guys from like Sacramento um and
everybody would always be in the chat
room what was the name of that I can't
remember it was another one I don't know
was invited it was like trying to be
like the Cabana but it never really took
off other than the chat room and the
chat room was just people like late at
night talking [ __ ] while their res was
filling up basically yeah you know like
I was always formally disinvited from
these places bro like uh what be it IC
mags I wouldn't sell my seeds there and
then logic in the farm there's a actual
like when you Google Matt Riot first
thing that pops up is Matt Riot is a
total douchebag on the farm like yeah
they love they love my ass
there
yeah there were actual like Forum
Superstars back in the day and Forum
villains and yeah I would definitely fit
the villain mold yeah you might have
been a villain man definitely a
villain yeah you kind of guess it like
uh you know whose troll account you're
interacting with you know yeah right we
we knew we knew a few pretty infamous
trolls ourselves K
do we uh we have a buddy who he might he
he could be up there and uh top
trolls which one on the forums in the
game man but still still too big I think
was his name still too big still too big
yeah he he's a a real life troll and uh
he's also one of the best dudes in the
world he would give you a shirt off his
back so as trolls go he was our Troll
and yeah for sure yeah I think he
disseminated more genetics that were
supposed to have restrictions on them
than anybody I ever met he was just like
he was like what I'm not supposed to
give this to anybody all right I'm gonna
give it to like 50
people you don't give him a cut with
conditions forget it right something in
your garden with conditions like Okie
was saying like don't even tell him
because the second you tell him like oh
you can't have this one that's the one
he's taken like
bath he's going to do whatever he's
going to go down God bless and then he's
going to come up the stairs and tell you
hey I just stole that clone from there
man I'm going home the up yeah he have
it in his ear like a like a pencil or a
joint he just have the Clone there like
out so I want to start getting into some
of you dudes like what your Specialties
are Okie what's your specialty like
where did you take cannabis where did
you find your niche in this uh WI world
man um you know that that's a tough one
to to answer um I think like if I do
have a specialty it's just uh you know
being able to uh put a concept together
and you know get people excited about it
and then you know follow through on the
execution um you know for from a growing
perspective uh uh a lot of the stuff
that we're working on now is all to me
like the the crop steering stuff you
know all of the science associated with
that and uh you know uh we're we're all
uh uh used to growing in the basement
and then you know I had a a brief uh a
bit of greenhouse Growing Experience but
uh yeah no the the legal and uh
commercial stuff is like fairly new to
me yeah and how's that been for you oh
it's good I mean uh uh the there there's
uh good and bad with it I mean I don't
have to worry about anyone kicking in my
door anymore but um you know going
through uh testing uh sucks a lot and uh
you know uh dealing with metric and just
you know the stress associated with uh
running a legal business is uh on a
different level than uh anything
Legacy how has um hlv affected uh
anything that you're doing
uh you know knock on wood uh no effects
so far but um um you know we uh we we've
done a lot of our uh own feno hunting um
you know we try to to we try to you know
do a lot of our stuff from seed just so
that uh we're able to find out which
genetics are really working in our
facility and our environment you know
for the practices that uh we're we're
implementing so and the genetics that
fit your grp dude like that's something
a lot of people don't understand is you
know like you hear about the hype
strains and you want them for sure
you're going to make it work and it's
not always how it goes you know so you
have to find ones that fit your grow fit
your environment or that you can morph
just a little bit to grow with the
strain but at a certain point you know
you're
you're it's just fighting to try to make
something fit and if it doesn't fit you
must not AC quit you know what I mean
for sure I mean I mean all we're doing
right now is just kind of you know
genetically throwing [ __ ] at the wall
and seeing what sticks you know it's
like uh it we we got to understand you
know not only what is going to work in
our facility but what is there a market
for as well which always uh easy to
determine so what what kind of stuff do
you find right now what kind of stuff
are you interested in right now in your
facility that seems to be working for
what you're doing um well I mean we just
did a uh a seed run of candy fumes which
uh I'm pretty excited about I mean we're
still waiting for testing to come back
on that but we've got several fenos that
look pretty
promising um this next run we're going
to be putting in some uh we've got three
different fenos of lim and Marino from
Swamp boys that yeah we're going to be
committing a little bit more space to um
and uh
yeah that's good to hear I mean like I
anytime you hear some of these old dudes
like swamp boys getting some respect I
like to hear that and making their way
into the the modern Market you know
mhm Oki has been
uh um a notorious good feno selector too
over the years whenever he pops some
beans he usually finds something pretty
good so I need to send Oki some [ __ ] too
I would leave him off the list yeah I
mean I know yeah if you if you're wanted
to run through some insane blue turps I
got you you
bro love blueberry yeah me too I'm a
blueberry fiend and it's I've made it my
mission to make the best blueberry
possible on Earth sotally I think we're
there so I'm
stoked how about you Chris tell us about
some of your journey now and what you're
doing now yeah
um it was up until like 2016 2017 I was
still in the you know Legacy gray Market
whatever you want to call it CU it's a
different name every year traditional
Market
traditional you know and uh a buddy of
mine who's who's also from the forums
and you know around older cat kind of
got me into
Consulting and uh was always into a lot
of the nutritive side of cannabis um had
been you know been making my own custom
nud formulas you know dry salts and uh
eventually kind of did a lot of stuff
with soil soil analysis really thrown
some science at soil techniques rather
than just you know just guessing um and
uh you know I was lucky through through
Consulting that you know I got to step
into some pretty big facilities and
start to learn you know kind of how to
talk to talk with those people and and
and gain some business Acumen and and um
you know uh soon after that like 2019
20120 uh really up until last year uh
that whole period that that you know
four four five years um I've spent in
various just director roles around the
country um at at larger commercial
facilities um you know nothing really
stuck unfortunately um and and and a lot
of places you know I was just grinding
myself to the Bone um and it was either
like you know it just wasn't a fit as
far as the chemistry with the owners or
they were just like I came in as their
like fifth grower and the place was a
mess oh yeah and you can only fix it so
much because they're broke or they're
going through a lawsuit or you know what
I mean it's just like that's the hardest
position to be put in it is um and uh
you know and I met some good people in
that world as well and you know kind of
learned how to manage people a little
bit better and uh manage my time manage
you know tasks and software and and and
uh you know just do other things that
you didn't really do as a grower yeah so
uh but always kind of going back to the
nutritive side always like focused on um
efficiencies you know both Oki and I are
both Engineers by you know academically
so it's like you're always thinking
efficiencies and and um you hopefully
not the sacrifice quality but just
asking like the the hows and the wise of
a lot of the things you're doing and um
you know and and taking that approach
and so right now I'm working with hor gr
Coco um which has actually been great to
be in something ancillary not running
one of these facilities myself what's it
what's it and uh Hort Grove Hort
Grove yeah they're they're based in uh
Santa Cruz
Watsonville um and you know small
company I'm employee number two on the
on the US side I'm basically doing all
the the the product business development
for the Cannabis side of it working with
a lot of Growers um back in
2019 uh I was running a big place up in
Washington and we were burning through a
couple different brands of Coco you know
that's when like Coco I feel like Coco
was really blowing up at that time
everybody wanted to grow in Coco was
like hype legalization was spreading
everybody's building these Mega
facilities and uh and there was a lot of
just Fly by Night cocoa brands that were
salty or had rude fits or
whatever yes so you know so we all went
through it and uh and that's you know I
started flying different like Laban off
and different things to to Coco and um I
always just went back to horrow I was
like this is actually a really good
product small company I could text the
CEO he'll make something special for me
if I want and just circle back to them
and you know started just like working
with them at mjbiz and some of the
conferences just to interface with
Growers and you know be someone
knowledgeable for them and uh yeah this
January this year they asked me to come
on fulltime with them and it's been a
total pleasure it's been you know it's
funny that my my social media has like
grown way more in the in the Cannabis
cultivation Community like working for
them than it did as like a trap guy with
like even with like all the breeder
connections and everything I have none
of that matters you know so yeah so it's
it's been a blessing I'm grateful for it
yeah dude I'm a Coco fiend and and we
need to talk hell yeah yeah get I'll get
you some samples I'll hook you up yeah
we also got the Cabana code for anybody
uh on the Cabana you can go check out
the Hort girl Forum over there Chris
will answer any questions you got you
can get a coupon code so if you order up
some H grow you get 15%
off yeah dude we'll do the same if if
you want we could do the same with
breeder Syndicate too and [ __ ] push
some people your way because a lot of
people like to grow like I grow and I'm
a Coco fiend bro Coco fiend a
purist not get 100% vouch for Hort grow
uh Chris and I were actually working in
a facility out here in Oklahoma together
last year or the year before I can't
time flies two years ago now yeah yeah
two years ago now and we ran the whole
thing on uh one gallon expandable cocoa
pots from hrow and they were awesome
that's [ __ ] awesome yeah using right
now what's that uh that's what we're
running in our facility right now as
well the Hort grow one gallon open tops
that sounds [ __ ] awesome too so what
kind of trains are you working with
right now what what's your newest stick
over there you're
running um I've got a uh a pheno of uh
triangle Queen from
um um Relentless uh genetics that's
really nice really uh really uh triangle
dominant feno that just has like a
little bit of cherry uh on it and uh we
really like that one um it's uh um you
know it's it's taking a while for the
market to uh Discover it just because
it's not like you know bright purple
yeah uh but uh but a lot of people are
discovering it and I think it's going to
be one that we kind of become known for
man we're going to bring green weed back
in24 man yeah man it's NE did but no
like Relentless like that's one of the
few dudes that came in after I did and
like I I really did a bad job of like
keeping track CU so many people came in
like you know when I first started there
was maybe 50 people doing it big
worldwide like selling seeds in ma yeah
and now there's you know 10,000 Zed
companies via Instagram and Relentless
was one of the few that I I actually
respect the dude quite a bit real super
nice dude I I appreciate what he's doing
and he's doing good work really his uh
rotten crosses if you come across his
rotten cherries or um rotten bananas or
anything all of his rotten crosses that
I've seen fire fire right yeah I've
heard a lot of good [ __ ] about his work
so he's one person I want to collab with
in the future just because I I I like uh
I like seeing the the Next Generation
take it to a new level and he's one of
the people doing it
yeah all right so let's talk about some
of the Cabana stuff and where what kind
of stuff are you going to be
implementing how is it going to change
from where it
was uh when I you know was on it for a
while and then off and then on and then
off and then on and how's it going to go
into the
future most important thing for everyone
to take in is that we are open to the
public now so you can go register right
now um set up an account and you'll have
full access to everything there's no uh
tiered memberships you won't have to pay
for anything everything is completely
free to the community and a lot of old
school knowledge on there I'm trying
hard to get the new generation to come
over and check us out and I think
they'll find you know some educational
things and some information that uh you
know it makes worth uh checking out the
Cabana on a regular basis the link
scrolling across the bottom of the
screen for anybody watching so you know
should be no question where you're
headed
to the other things that we're doing is
uh pretty much all the rules and old
restrictions that were once there
um are gone so if you are a breeder and
you are making seeds like man come tell
us about these seeds come post them up
come trade seeds with me because I might
offer I might want I might want some of
those beans you got [ __ ] in your [ __ ]
Vault so yeah yeah so I want everybody
to know that uh it's a seed friendly
Community man you can sell some beans
you got people hitting you up in the DMS
want some beans by all means man I I
want everybody
to uh be able to utilize the Cabana as a
tool and uh make it a valuable asset for
him man and the great thing about the
Cabana probably more maybe not just in
just sheer numbers cuz places like icy
mag and some of these people have like
so many registered members because
they've been open for 20 years yeah but
uh we have so many breeders on the
Cabana and people who have just been
making beans in their closet for 20
years and
have uh a seed arsal that would you know
make most of us sweat if we looked at it
you know and uh
so I'm going to make it so those those
seeds are going to be available to
people I want to give the small guys a
way
to um get their beans out into the
community and
um so we're GNA work on that we're GNA
have a store coming um I'm stoked man we
got uh lots of breeders already involved
and the Breeders that uh it's going to
be easy to get more involvement from
these breeders as we get more
involvement from the community you know
so some people are like oh they're not
on there that much well they will be if
you know if there was a reason for them
to be there they'll come you know
nobody's up on there just because I
picked a company that I thought was cool
no I talk to everybody everybody's down
with the mission and it's just a matter
of getting our traffic up and
uh you know getting the vi back to where
it kind of used to be and how we get
there and how we do that I'm still
working on it we're throwing uh lots of
ideas out and so if anybody's got ideas
or you got an idea that you think like
oh this would be dope if the forums did
it like this I want to hear them you
know what I mean let me know so like I
want this forum to
be for us for the people who appreciate
the for like let's make it so you know
it's the best form it can be for us you
know for uh 420 I don't know if you guys
are down for it but me and CSI both uh
worked on some gel F and uh my new
blueberry [ __ ] let's give some away dude
let's do a little contest something
let's do it actually inspector just sent
me a bunch of gear and there was some
diesel crosses in there man yeah that's
part of it dude I'm gonna get
there yeah and uh let's see other
things
um
you know with the Cabana being open to
the public it it gives everybody a
chance to come check it out and
everybody can register and be a part of
it but I really like that even doing
that and we've added over a thousand
members and stuff since we you know been
open for three months now
um it still maintains like the old kind
of Cabana Vibe everybody's being super
respectful you you know we don't really
have any trolls
um if we did like I don't really have
you know tolerance super high tolerance
for internet Dumb [ __ ] I'll just you
just delete it move on yeah not going to
be a big argument or scene about it and
uh that's what we've been trying to do
and everybody uh everybody's liking
every
day um hearing from new people that you
know going to come come back and check
it out like you know last week I was
having breakfast with katsu and um he
you know he's like uh he's got his own
forum and he's got his own store and
that's the other thing everybody's got
their own discords everybody's got yeah
Instagram everybody's got Facebook
everybody's got half a dozen social
media profiles that they have to
maintain and so we're just fighting for
our space and we have to prove our value
to um get everybody to come but uh
the old school people like we we got
them and I think there's going to be a
new appreciation
for the old school and what they had and
what they had to offer because I think
these Exotics
are kind of running their course right
now everybody everybody uh is kind
of I'm hearing gas and Cam and Diesel
and everything that I like everything
that I like kind of making a Resurgence
yeah you know and even ha yeah even hay
bro even
hay I don't want any Haze but bring it
back you know Phil Phil Rojo had some
killer Haze crosses I mean this man had
some killer [ __ ] he probably still does
get him let me send Phil this link man
let's get him in here yeah let's get
Phil on here because this is the man
that was in National Geographic he was
one of the that you know what honestly
he was one of the main reasons I went
out to Colorado when I did I really
wanted to meet this dude um who had done
so much and made such an impact during
those years in Colorado when he was
really thriving and I knew he was going
big places and like when I'm one of
those guys where I really believe like
attracts like and if you want to be
successful surround yourself with people
who think successful and are optimistic
and taking themselves forward and he was
one of them you know and he always
shared his time with me very
respectful um I have a lot of respect
for that dude
Lots yeah that's cool Phil is awesome
and I don't know I honestly I can't even
remember how I met Phil it
was through through the Forum somehow
but when I met him uh he W he had a big
Warehouse over off of I70 in Denver and
I go over there and I used to buy seed I
was buying seeds like oh yeah dude
notorious for it yeah I I I was buying
seeds non-stop B money
bro it was coming from somewhere and
uh but uh I just want to
inter K used to give me crap when I
wouldn't spend like at least 6K a month
on seeds you're like bro what are you
doing with your life right now I'm like
wasting your money ons like that but go
ahead
continue no one can ever say I haven't
put my money where my mouth is when it
comes to se that's for damn sure yeah
but I would buy seeds just to give them
to Rojo and just so he could pop them
there big pops and you know he would let
me store moms over there and you know
there's been there there's been some
people who you know really want to throw
anyone under the bus but
uh there's been people who have stolen a
lot of genetics out
of that facility that have gone on to
start companies and uh all of
that we can go ahead and say it Colin
ethos genetic egos egos I
think Os Os genetics yeah yeah so he uh
you
know he worked over there for a while
and he got some stuff then he ended up
working over at my other
buddy's uh facility New Age Medical and
yeah got a ton of my stuff and boom EOS
seed collection was formed not long
afterwards yeah he's not well liked bro
but Phil was always awesome
because he he was the first person that
I think he really recognized in me at
least that like I was was about that
Seed Life yeah dude and one year from my
birthday he came over to my house and he
popped up with a ziplock bag full of
beans and they were all Tom Hill Hayes
crosses yeah yeah and um Bubba Tom Hayes
bro yeah Bubba Tom Hayes skunk Valley
Hayes um he had so many [ __ ] rockhead
hay so many things in there and uh I
gave him away for years he told me he
was like man just you know anybody from
you anybody who wants these just you
know get them in their hands and I did
that for years I would do auctions to
you know help raise money for various
people on Instagram boom I'm sending
them 1020 seeds you know or 1020 packs
of seeds not yeah um one year for the
cup I gave uh I did these breeder bags
and it was like 60 bag 60 packs of seeds
in them I collected I had a bunch of
beans that obsolete had set on a bunch
of beans for me
um I had a bunch of stuff from La Plata
Labs yeah he's a great dude too yeah you
know Joey yeah yeah he's great dude he's
awesome he's actually uh sweetheart not
far from me in Oklahoma out here right
now you tell him I said what's up dude
like he's always been really [ __ ]
cool I like that I will and man he's one
of those dudes who I think is also super
slept on because
he was making beans and packaging up
beans and kind of grinding on the
Underground State Side scene like before
most people were man yeah and uh he had
he's got some great stuff man yeah he
had a Durango OG I think it was called
it was really good fire fire OG had some
white Voodoo and some big white and
lemon aliens and he he had some good
stuff back in the day yeah lots of
respect for that dude yeah he was for a
while he started getting really big but
I think he just kind of backed off a
little bit from the scene and uh slowed
down but yeah the respect still there
definitely for him from uh people I
think he started doing uh some hemp
stuff and I know he was doing some stuff
uh um internationally as well so good he
stays busy man he posted up some picture
he's one of those guys who can go away
and you don't hear from him or see
anything from him for like three or four
years and then he posts up picture of
like some Mega Greenhouse that's
going 400 yards full of
[ __ ] more than my ass that's for
[ __ ] sure yeah so he always stays
with a project he's a worker yeah I dude
that's cool that's really cool but yeah
so Phil would give me tons of stuff when
I went to the lion um Phil also hooked
me up with uh a guy named Mike Finelli
and uh he does a ton of
uh
um like grow design he he'll get your
room all set up he was working with uh
oh man kick myself he uh these old
controllers what were the old
controllers
called before the troll Masters
everybody had one of these I can't
remember what it was called but uh he
helped design those and then he worked
with a guy named Bo who owned
chlorophyll up here in Denver which is
just like a nutrient you know just a
little uh Hydro shop and he plugged me
up with so many people that
um
just because I knew Phil took extra good
care of me you know so I was getting the
plug on nutrients I was I got the plug
on the room design and the buildout and
stuff I mean these guys came down and
they moved into the warehouse with me
down in Colorado Springs and we're like
building this thing out 24 you know
around the clock so they grind
and that just comes from his kind of his
work mentality yeah dude I I really
think if he would have stuck with the
black market scene at least he would
have been uh much more on the CSI level
in respect you know what I mean um but
dipping away you know a lot of people
don't remember him as well and I think
he name deserves more respect and should
be back out there you know he's one of
those guys too who's always doing a
breeding project and exactly probably
got
like Walkin freezers full of gear I know
I need to see that I need to get up in
there I need to get my hands on it I
need to man I've already been asking him
I was like hey remember when you gave me
all those beans you should do something
like that again so I
can right right so
um but man Phil is awesome he's probably
one of my biggest
uh I mean he's like somebody I actually
looked up to in the weed like a mentor
of sort yeah you know he always did it
uh big and as I started getting into
managing commercial facilities
and um bigger projects and stuff like
that you realize like the undertaking
that they actually are you know I mean
everybody everybody can grow good weed
but can you do scale can you do it at
scale and growing it at scale is
uh
just bigger challenges bigger risks
bigger losses you know what I mean
something goes wrong and uh your four
lighter it's a lot easier to recover
from you know a 40 Lightroom you know
issue that's why you're looking at a
bunch of bald guys right now
yeah right so yeah and I don't think I
probably would have had the confidence
to
do
uh um these bigger facilities if I
hadn't been able to spend the time
asking questions and seeing Rojo's
facilities and how the things that he
was doing
to uh
just make everything run smooth and just
well oiled machine and that's what you
got to have on a commercial level you
know so I kind of got a question for you
Kirby when we first met you were
curbside extracts right I was you talk
about some of that
[ __ ] you feel comfortable talking about
any of that I've always been curbside
service ever since like middle school
and then uh and then I was curbside
concentrates I was always I've always
curbside service like my little brother
gives me [ __ ] because I just do
everything under a flag of curbside yeah
always known he Kirby yeah yeah so like
um you were the dude I did back in the
day I got I everyone
started my boy
brought a five gallon bucket back from
California and it had like honey oil in
it like B honey oil we're talking Home
Depot five gallon bucket i' never seen
anything like it and I was just like and
nor had I smoked
anything like it at the time either yeah
and I was just like man this is from B
Joe this is like I started doing all
this research and on the Cabana there's
a guy OG Legend his name is Greywolf and
oh yeah yeah if you've ever done any
form of B extract um I'm sure you've ran
across some something that led you to
Greywolf at some point yeah but he put
me on game to this place back in the day
called Glacier tanks and I want to say
they were up in Oregon or Washington or
somewhere Northeast and I started buying
all these stainless steel tubes and
uh my dad uh owns a welding company and
got a machine shop and stuff and so like
when I had an idea it was easy for me to
execute like oh let's try this let's do
that and uh I would get these stainless
steel tubes and I had like 50 of them
and three feet by an inch and a half and
you could pack them with a half pound of
weed and
um I started
ordering um tin and I was in Colorado
I'm pretty sure I was the first person
had that license right that wanted
entain because when I was asking General
Air which is like the biggest gas
supplier out in Denver across the
country like man I need some butane and
they were just for what what what could
you possibly
need you know a bottle of butane for for
yeah and uh they had to do some research
to even find it to see if they could get
it and they ended up getting it from
Texas and I'd have to give them heads up
um um when I need it and then I started
just telling them I was like here's your
heads up like I need it like yeah just
keep shipping it up here like have me on
a
rotation and so I had I had quick
connects and I just boom turn my bottle
of butane on blast through a tube fill
it into a one gallon glass
pitcher pour it into a pie pan
and for a long time
I don't want to say a long time for a
short time I was getting more money
doing 5050 splits with people than I was
like on a regular crop someone would
give me their crop and I was able to pay
them more for their crop off of their
50% sure
than they could even get selling 100% of
it in flour there was so damn much need
for it at the time that market mive and
it
was there's not a lot of markets that
I've hit at the right time where it's
like I got in like right at the right
time that was the right time I wasn't
one I was early uh so not a lot of
people had volume like I had somebody
might had access and all of it yeah yeah
so yeah to this day to this day one of
my best friends who's you know he was
out in Oakland he was up on the hill you
know 15 years ago
and he he went out to one of kiry's
Barbecues in Aurora and when when KB had
first built like the first Clos Loop and
he was like bro even to this day like my
my buddy and Cali be like your your boy
Kirby was like ahead of the curve ahead
of everybody on the cloth Loop Tech yeah
that's that's the one thing I I think
you're pretty legendary for in my mind
like when I think of Kirby I think of
all those like V trays all that [ __ ]
just never seen anybody do it so it once
the the closed loop Tech 2 came from the
forums yeah and it all
started I can't I can't remember who did
it or the name of the what even Forum it
was on but it was
a uh some pressurized paint cans that uh
I did my first clothes Loop out of man
out of Harbor Freight pressurized paint
cans and yeah so I've I've done it every
single way possible uh good ways and bad
ways so yes yeah I did the bad ways
early on the open blasting and [ __ ]
yeah and then it got to a point where it
just the science of it all outgrew me
and these new guys with some of their
Clos Loop texts
and um the things that they're doing to
clean up the fats and the lipids and all
you know all the things uh it's amazing
man and um one of my boys went the other
way to rosin yeah right I went to rosin
man freeze dried rosin bro that that
that's another Phil Story another Rojo
story is
uh I was going out I was going to his
warehouse and um kind
Bill uh was working there doing the
extracts and
um they were telling me about this new
thing that they had done man they're
like oh man we we've invented live resin
and um it's uh it's so good and the tur
profiles are this and it's just like
that they started showing it to me and
they were like telling me how to do it
and I was like oh all you got to do is
freeze it and then just yeah yeah do it
do it the same way you just got to
freeze it beforehand like yeah I was
like well [ __ ] bro I can do that and uh
so they were telling me they're like
yeah you got to you got to get a cryo
freezer and they're this expensive I'm
like oh [ __ ] but they didn't even have
the cryo freezer at the time like they
were just telling me like they were
gonna get it I wasn't even I don't think
I'd even started my car up from the
parking lot before I had ordered a cryo
freezer used off of
eBay and uh so for 500 bucks off eBay
man I had a used cryo freezer shipped up
here and um
I started doing live resin and uh I
taught my boy Lord rude booy how to
blast and process material uh when we're
at the lion and he's one of those guys
where it's just like when the student
becomes the master because he just took
it to a whole another level and he can
do it all disate rosin you know he's
he's a hashm can you real quick explain
for me the definition of live resonance
something I've never been able because I
know you were at the base of it what is
the true definition of live resin as it
was originally meant to be live res I
mean to me it's just the preservation of
the freshest turps possible by freezing
it as quickly as possible when you cut
it down and I always I always assumed
like they were taking the live plant
still in the pot like smashing it that
way and that's the only way I had no
clue what it meant well that's why you
want the cryo freezer cuz it gets colder
faster so you can cut your plant down
and there's less wilting and things like
that uh in the freezing process how much
of a difference does it make um it does
make a difference because you get less
condensation and you get less water
build up
uh um but did the resins mature before
you do that no not if you're like
literally cutting it down putting it in
the bag getting it in the free do that
make a difference to some degree it's
literally how fast you can do it you
don't want to cut it down let your plant
sit outside for an hour two hours before
it gets bagged up and put in the freezer
it's like you want to chop it get it in
the bag get it in the freezer get it
Frozen and uh that sounds like a forum
argument already though you know someone
like no bro my shit's so dank it doesn't
matter I'll leave it out for a day still
make better hatch than your [ __ ] well
like I think about it like with
blueberry like a lot of the blueberries
need to cure for a month before they get
their blueberry TPS back in full form
and I'm just wondering how difference
that would be how different that would
be with live resin and if it would be
worth it to do with that well man it I
think it's totally worth it to compare
the differences between a live resin
turp and a well cured turp um
cuz they're going to be totally
different you know if you're harvesting
a plant on harvest day when you're
cutting it down it smells different than
when it's smoke day after it's cured
absolutely same principle with live
resin like you're cutting it down with
that tur profile that you're preserving
at that moment in time and there was
stuff like strawberry cream though that
smelled like strawberry straight off the
bush bro that would be perfect for live
resin oh
manly I had uh
uh obsolete had sent me a bunch of his
orange crosses when he had first made
orange juice Bud the orange juice bud
and I had you know the orange juice Bud
times sour dub times ghost OG
times um
GSC I can't even remember all of them
but that's what we were doing the the
dab bar down in Colorado Springs at The
Lazy Lion and yeah that's kind of like
what made us famous man was these live
resin orange turps that we had down
there because like people were kind of
just getting into dabs and they would
take a dab of you know some regular dab
and be coughing and like oh sure almost
a painful experience man but then like
when people started like you know turp
started coming through on dabs and you
know the live resin and all of that like
it changed how people were smoking it
man it yeah especially with orange juice
but that [ __ ] Citrus is [ __ ] from the
jump oh undeniable flavor it's one of
those uh you know obsolete just posted
up on Instagram that his orange apricot
got voted like best TPS and yeah they're
still doing like the legend orange
apricot stuff like uh jaing on them yeah
yeah and uh those TS definitely need to
be preserved for sure but unfortunately
those original crosses and I know OB
still has a few packs of The Originals I
tried to get them off of them man and
he's kick him down
OBS no he needs to hold on to him he
needs to do something with them but
uh those TPS man out of that batch those
were probably some of the best turps
that's come out of a of
a public seed release and I don't even
know like how public those were I don't
know if he really sold them or if he
just kind of gave orange cookies was out
there a bunch yeah but uh man probably
some of the best TPS to hit the market
in a noticeable while yeah yeah they
were good man they real good
orange I just wanted to take a quick
moment and thank everyone for showing up
again Kirby and all the homies from from
the Cabana um they're always amazing
episodes these guys are real passionate
true seed collectors and what they're
doing at the command we're really
supportive of again the canic cava.com
is where you go to sign up um you can
also go to Riot seeds.com again to pick
up our blueberry Andross stuff there's
there's multiple hybrids of the
blueberry incross also for 420 which
we're going to announce on 418 we got
the high and lonesome's new mango Haze
drop and we finally have Matt Elites uh
different camd I95 hybrids I am so
stoked been working on it for years they
are in my opinion the best chem 91
regular seeds where you can reliably
pick out like Amplified chem 91 TPS
along with a bunch of really true
breeding through OG cush seed lines and
regular lines so you can make your own
OG Kush seed lines with the Mals from
this stuff U mie stuff is above and
beyond it's why I've hounded him for
years there's only going to be a few
packs available of each he wants to he
doesn't think there's going to be a a
lot of interest because he's missed the
seed Market the last I don't know four
or five years I know you'll love it so
please go check that out at Riot
seeds.com we also have Riot seeds seedco
Europe we have Girt by seeds in
Australia and then of course lifted
seeds in California um takes credit card
processing great guy carries can
Illuminati members couldn't recommend
him highly enough um we're going to try
to get the blueberry incross out to
Australia um possibly Europe depending
on you know how everything works out
maybe Brazil the Brazil drop is coming
very soon very very soon we're going to
have a bunch of our fem stuff over there
and uh yeah don't forget we have the jel
fem stuff on the site there's multiple
different jel crosses some of the
skunkiest stuff going to find um we also
have stuff from sub Rob under seed trip
in the fem section we have a skank dog
and the
sssdh which is his 98 Super Silver Haze
cross to sour dub sour dub is a dank
[ __ ] clone if you miss it you miss it
it's all there is again I always say
this I can't reiterate it enough when
things sell out people ask me where it's
at they finally get into it with their
Johnny lately and it's gone you have to
go to other people's seed Collections
and pay a premium so go get it now and
if you're a member of our patreon you
get an automatic 30% off on all the
blueberry incross stuff that I'm doing
and uh yeah we also have um goat farms
new drop with some of his blue dream
crosses which are also available for 30%
off if you're a part of our patreon so
please go check that out join our
patreon um this weekend's UFC 300 and
we're all watching it so be there or be
square and with that thanks for coming
to the show thanks for watching it the
Cabana is really important to me it's
important to CSI we want everyone to be
a part of it we want everyone to use it
and uh yeah we plan on it being our
sister website and and accomplishing the
goals that we have set um we can only do
this as a community and it's a great
Community there with that lots of love
and we'll see you next week for part
two want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
my G and it's an amazing resource for
old cataloges and knowledge we hope you
join our Union of readers and Growers
come check it
out