you don't believe what i'm filming by
the way i'm sorry uh while you're
talking i'm feeling the most incredible
thing
there's a bright orb running the length
of my pond
and it has a tail on it my lord thank
you for this
my voice is shaking
you're not gonna bleed this video i'm 24
seconds in
now it's responding to our conversation
guys and this is this is amazing i'm
telling you
um
it has an aura around this orb a tail
is shaped like a v
and it's very big and it's
this
orange pinkish orange
is still
meandering down the length of my pond
i mean this is incredible
this this is something very touching
uh connected to your
your loss and your daughter this very
well could be
a sign for you jim
this is amazing i'm telling you you're
not going to believe this when i share
it with you david both of you
we're talking amazing i mean it's
i just
i can't explain what i'm looking at
right now
but i'm going to show you lord willing
this video
oh lord thank you my lord wow
wow
did you see it wow
you want to believe what i just filmed
it came straight at me and dipped down
in the woods while i'm filming this huge
orb
with the tail
this is amazing you you both are going
to be blown away when you see this
thank you lord for this
and now i got an orb appeared above me
another one
this is crazy
my voice is shaking it's turned and it's
heading
just above the trees now this huge orb
with a tail huge tail
amazing