this thing on
hey man right it's me it's me your old
friend
Peabody you know before I got locked up
he said you going to help help a g out
you said you know hold my head high and
I had held my head high and the whole
time I was in there doing my bid locked
up you know what I'm saying
I was having the [ __ ] you know one
toilet between like 30 other cats the
whole time every time I was [ __ ] I
was thinking of you bro and I thought
like man he really promised me a job in
like a career when I get out he's a good
dude I know he's a good dude like
probably one of the best there is you
know and I want to say thanks man for
inspiring me to do greatness you know uh
but I was going I was kind of wondering
if you could like spot me like you know
a like a couple thousand dollars or
whatever and some lights some PL some
tests or [ __ ] like that or whatever I
know times were tough or whatever for a
G out here and [ __ ] but like you know I
would appreciate that [ __ ] I told Mom I
told Mom like I I would ask you or
whatever she didn't want me to and [ __ ]
but like I don't know so I appreciate it
if you didn't tell tell her or nobody
else or whatever all right uh anyways
love you B bro