Matt
right
just I think it's [ __ ] on I think I'm
figuring out this camera [ __ ] bro you
got to forgive me I've been locked up
for some time this shit's wild bro cell
phones and 6GS or whatever it's called
nowadays [ __ ] like that but reason I'm
calling you bro cuz you ain't really
picked up yet or whatever and my last
video or my call video call whatever I
left I kind of talk some [ __ ] and I want
to say sorry or whatever and I wanted to
thank you for everything you done for me
on real you know Mom said I got to keep
my cool and [ __ ] I'll be locked up down
in that pin again you know what I'm
saying so I got to make sure I can keep
that cool head or whatever you know what
I
mean so I just blaz in some of that cam
dog my my my homie big cat he done hook
me up with a little cam dog I know you
ain't you ain't [ __ ] answering the
[ __ ] out me out whatever it's cool but
um I just was wondering bro like I ain't
looking for hand out
no [ __ ] like that today I just wonder
you could you know spot me a few clones
or some [ __ ] like that or whatever that'
be dope you know get me started or
whatever I I don't need lights or no
nothing like that no more but some
clones I was [ __ ] around with these
Russian cats you know saying down the
road or whatever and you know like a
dummy I hooked him up with my only
little $150 I had and they're going to
talking about how they gonna give me
some good clones and [ __ ] and bro the
dude this big [ __ ] I I would
have anybody else bro you know on God
bro I would have [ __ ] just deck his
cat right in his [ __ ] mouth showing
up with some [ __ ] like that just
disrespecting you know me and really you
I know we ain't [ __ ] with each other
for a while whatever but he showed up he
brought he I was like man you I was like
damn you a big cat bro he didn't even
say nothing he just said some [ __ ] and
russan he pulled out this little bag I
was like what the [ __ ] bro where's the
Clones at he looked at me like cold
blooded bro I you know me bro I'm I've
been locked up held down for a while you
know what I'm saying I scrap with
anybody you know I mean on real but he
he bought out that bag bro and [ __ ]
this the [ __ ] he gave me bro I'm I'm
[ __ ] God bro he said this [ __ ] the
this are clones bro this is the [ __ ] he
gave me straight up I was sitting there
like
what I want to like I said I was about
to deck his cat but now I was like man
he a he a big [ __ ] you know what
I'm saying like I mean swo up on like
that I'm sitting here looking up at them
like that so I was like [ __ ] it ain't
even worth it bro I just got the pen you
know little $150 or
whatever it is what it is dog but I was
hoping you know you could help me out
bro you know send me some [ __ ] on on you
know for like old time sake you know
what I'm saying we ain't really talked
or whatever I know we ain't been close
but it would it would help me out bro
and maybe like I can kick some [ __ ] back
on you you know what I mean help her G
out I help you you scratch my back I
help you scratch your dick or whatever
you know anyways play uh like