this
on hey Matt R man why why ain't you
answering your [ __ ] phone bro I ain't
trying to be a dick and I I ain't try I
feel like I ain't being rude or anything
like when you said you got me all them
years ago bro like I know we ain't talk
for like seven eight years and I've been
locked up [ __ ] [ __ ] gets weird you know
what I mean like ain't nobody came saw
me bro you didn't come see me [ __ ]
pissing me off the only thing I'm asking
for bro is a little [ __ ] handout dog
I don't get it bro he's trying to piss
me off on some real I got a [ __ ]
little list here all [ __ ] over the years
that you [ __ ] owe me for and we're
going to go through
it all you had to do was pick up your
[ __ ] phone
man instead we got to do it this way all
right first on the list 17 bck
lighters sorry I'm out of the camera 17
big lighters and no cheap
ones uh looks like 17 cases of
beer uh four half gallons of Jose quvo
and says anywhere from $5 to
$700 for food at like you know
McDonald's and [ __ ] like that when we're
you know hanging out and
bullshitting then we got look
like about
$44,000 in you know just weed money [ __ ]
like that you you know you owe me for
smoking you out [ __ ] like that I know
like we said [ __ ] was cool but like now
that I'm thinking about it it ain't cool
and I'm gonna need some money for this
[ __ ] bro like on the real like real
[ __ ] fast just answer your phone bro
I need I could go on for days if you
could just hook me up with a cool you
know six I don't know just like some
lights some tester [ __ ] I see you on
your little podcast you know or whatever
maybe you could hook me up with a job on
there or something uh I see you making
that sweet bread bro and I'm just
wondering like why can't you help a g
out [ __ ] like that I thought we were
homies and [ __ ] thought we were tight
but you know lock I know I've been gone
shit's [ __ ] up all I'm wanting is a
little Kim dog bro to get me through the
day few lights some testers [ __ ] like
that get back up on my feet you know
[ __ ] like this bro It's Hard Out Here
for for a cat whatever but it just a
even [ __ ] I don't even know if this
thing's on I've been sending you texts
anyways bro and [ __ ] I told Mom like the
[ __ ] Matt ain't answering and [ __ ]
and I thought we were cool but it ain't
looking like we are he's just being like
a little baby [ __ ] or something like
that trying to dodge my phone calls bro
I'm living in a [ __ ] Shack but damn
near I need something to help bro just
answer your phone now Chucky poins don't
forget it AKA body in the cell I just
got locked up my life's hell I need your
help oh well