welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
Syndicate welcome to breeders Syndicate
I'm Matt here with my co-host
thousandfold and our constant stay guest
Mr farmer [ __ ] Dan now you can see
his face too wait I'm not supposed to
cuss the hold on hold
on within the first 30
[Laughter]
seconds
all right uh welcome to Peter Syndicate
I'm Matthew here with my co-host
thousandfold and our friend farmer Dan
who's been a main stay on the show
welcome my friends um today we're going
to be talking kind of revisiting our our
uh cookies breeding with cookies and and
the dead ends of cookies and whether it
is a breeding dead end or not um I
decided and actually we kind of as a
group decided to revisit this a little
bit
uh I was rewatching the episode that we
did and I think it was super informative
at the beginning but um there's a few
narratives that got spun in it that just
don't ring true and I tried to kind of
put that put that out there during the
episode while we were recording it but
it doesn't seem like it was heard very
well and now like I'm seeing stuff pop
up on social media that XYZ is
responsible for cookies and this and
that and it's just not true
and and of all things that we want to do
with this show is combat misinformation
like first and foremost it's it's not
good it's it's it's the opposite of our
mission to make it about an ego thing
like I'm responsible for this this and
this and no one else you know like all
that is is the opposite of what we want
to do and it is our biggest episode and
uh it was a hard decision but we're
going to go ahead and redo it reshoot it
and try to keep it as accurate as we can
for the time being and again if things
change we'll do another one you know uh
as much as all of us are kind of sick of
talking about cookies and all its
derivatives it's uh un necessary thing
and it just seems like people only heard
the last I don't know two minutes of the
episode so with that thousand you want
to kick it off and and tell them where
we're taking
it yeah so I think where we start um is
looking at the major components at least
that we are aware of of cookies so I
think out of F1 derb cherry pie uh GDP
purple urk and OG Kush maybe we start
with the F1 derb what do you think Matt
okay so the F1 derb is a very unique
plant uh it was not passed around a lot
there's a lot of um debate be it from
Kenny flowers or Powers
um he says that he's never passed the
cut but we know like he doesn't really
gr and like he has other people make
seeds for them so of course he has to
pass [ __ ] cut um but you know there
was a guy named Cookie Monster who kept
the F1 derb for a long time and he was
responsible for the F1 derb account on
Instagram and that's the exact cut that
we have in the circle um yeah it's it's
a unique cut it obviously has a lot of
the structure that you see in cookies
the really unique structure um the
bubbly bra very very specifically um the
knobby look that cookies has comes from
a lot of the F1 derb stuff uh it's it's
debatable on whether it's an S1 or not
again it's one of those things where we
just won't know there is another cut
called we call the the Durban Bay or the
bay Durban that um CSI got from Green
Dragon uh I think five six years ago and
he was growing him side by side because
we've been doing our F1 derb projects
together and he was grown him side by
side and thought somebody screwed up the
cut because in veg they were so
identical that he was sure someone
screwed up like one of his workers
screwed up the cut so he was all pissed
off and then they start flowering and
they're almost identical looking except
one is green and one is a deep black
purple um there's differences in the tur
profiles but we'll see over time like
how at you know acclimatizing and being
in the same room over time being fed the
same stuff over time we'll see how much
those tur profiles like either get you
know similar or if they break further
apart or they stay where they're at but
as of right now it seems like one one is
a descendant of the other one is a
sister of the other bag seat of the
other hybrid of the other we just don't
know um it's a really really unique cut
and as much as I've always taken what
cookie fam says with a grain of salt
because none of them are breeders barely
any of them are Growers um it does seem
to hold true that F1 derb is a major
component of forum cookies proper and
probably thin mint as well so yeah I
don't know Dan what do you have you have
any takes on F1 derb at all I've never
even had a chance to see it I've never
come across the Clone I've got more
thoughts on the next few okay so one
other thing I'll add is this is one of
the main reasons I'm redoing the show
too is that you know there were some
rumors going around that the anus cut um
or anise you know you can call what you
want I call it the anus um is the mother
or is F1 derb um yeah there's no
relation um when that claim was made the
person who made that claim had never
smoked grown seen F1 derb so it was kind
of a bold claim
um but going off what me and CSI have
seen there's no way uh it's just not
it's just not there um it does anus does
look like a a uh meno pers type um
whether F1 der is a meno pers type or
not known it's it's very different
looking than F1 derb I'm sorry than than
men perss um yeah I'm going to leave it
there uh that's that's one of the I
can't believe how fast that spread and
when I'm a part of something that's
misinformation I gotta cut it yeah with
that one I I don't feel like it was ever
like explicitly said too cuz I kind of
filled that Gap in myself as well and
thought that for a few months there
where I was just like oh I don't think
he wants to say it out of like humility
or or something but like I completely
fell into that trap too yeah and and in
In fairness like I got to watch from
behind the scenes how that Nar that
narrative started evolving and it
started with like hey I think someone
else saying hey I think this the meno
perss is in cookies and then it just
kind of slowly evolved into connecting
this Dot and string and Dot and string
yeah but without actually any additional
data points yeah zero data points no
more grows no more flowers no more
nothing else Anis Cuts not around to be
even compared now like there's a whole
lot of stuff that was missing from that
um yeah that that data point so I'd
rather I'd rather stick to what we know
and what we've seen and what we've
experienced and I've actually grown F1
durb sourced it very early on used it
bred with it ran the plants from it the
progyny uh chased it back down via Frost
boss and and Stony rest in peace um yeah
I mean it takes it takes growing stuff
smoking it learning about it their
progyny their supposed progyny to really
try to make educated conclusions on
stuff like that just saying it and isn't
enough and that's probably where I'll
leave the F1 dur conversation app for
now I did want to ask you one more thing
Matt which is what was your anecdotal
experience with it like um I'm not
asking you to obviously make any claims
but maybe like you know what are your
speculations on it based on what you saw
of its traits or you know anything
interesting that you noticed
um so when I grew it it was very like
what's the word for it like it had a
champagne Mero type smell there's some
pissin but I never caught the
gingerbread end of it and I think there
is some sort of gingerbread end to it
that other people smell um it's very
Herm prone that's that's like the first
thing you notice when running it very
Herm prone
um it's looser than it looks uh like
visually you look at it you might think
it it's more dense like cookies
but it's not at all um is it a Durban
Poison is probably one of the questions
I get the most I would say there's no
way in hell it's a pure Durban Poison um
it's got a lot of Afghan type traits to
it which Durban Poison is
a well there's a lot of different things
called deran Poison it's an area in
Africa um there's a lot of things that
come out of that area um traditionally
there's the Dutch Passion Durban Poison
that most people think of there is the
NorCal Durban Poison which is ultra
um I believe it was the Mel Frank Urban
Poison cut that was all an you know like
aniseed
so this isn't necessarily that um with
Kenny Powers he said a few time a few
different things he said that F1 derb is
the derb crossed to
F1 and what is an F1 he said it's like a
Formula 1 race car and that's why we
called it that and then he also later
said it is is Durban cross
to Durban cross to something cross to
purple pain which was like a purple from
the bay area which is probably like an
Urkel GDP but hard to say hard to say
don't see a lot of Urkel in it so yeah
that's that's probably the most I I
could say about the traits other than
what we talk about later on in its
relation to other things yeah super
interesting and obviously people are now
starting to grow out some of those
crosses so we might
might learn more over over time okay so
we can move on to Cherry Pie you want to
kick it off
Dan yeah I started seeing it in like
20145 I think um the Clone was at hprc
in Arcada and so that's where I picked
it up at least and um I grew it a little
bit I kind of wasn't a good grower yet
and so I got like little popcorn buds of
just like rock hard it was like green
with marbling like Stripes of purple
through it and how hard was it rock
hard sorry and uh it was really nice man
I remember that a pound of it was like
the size of a football yeah it was the
smallest pound I think I've still seen
the date and so um it was really killer
I enjoyed it the smoke was kind of me
like it was tasty but didn't get you
that high compared to like the diesel
headband OG that kind of everyone
cropped out at that time it was just
another one like that people kept a few
plants of in like their outdoor patch
just as like variety but like it wasn't
like a bulk produced plant that I I
don't think I've seen anyone ever bulk
produce it yeah so my first experience
with the Cherry Pie was on IC mag uh
lump status had just gotten a hold of
the cut and was growing that and some of
the other cookie fam cuts and I remember
looking at the Cherry Pie on there and
just thinking this is so gorgeous and it
was a The Forum was he was also growing
The Forum publicly on there and it was
very unique looking but cherry pie
really really like is it Cherry is it
like a cherry pie like that all was very
intriguing and looking at it it was just
it looked like more of what I wanted to
grow uh versus The Forum and I remember
reaching out to him we weren't friends
yet and I reached out to him and I was
like hey dude what do you want for that
like what do you want to trade for that
cut and uh we ended up doing some sort
of Exchange giving him right bar G or
something like that like my mom cut of
that and um a a mutual friend of ours
who I'll shout out Gail from PNC ape
radical dude I mean back in the day in
San Diego he ran a place called people's
nursery care PNC and he had some of the
most legit he's where I saw strawberry
cream originally from that clone um the
soul assassin number three and one that
was nice Source from him La
afy just all kinds of stuff dude like he
was so responsible for so much ending up
in my hands um so shout out to Gail
Gail's legit and like there were so few
clones that I ever gotten I was like I
don't know about that one from him he
was so much before his time doing great
uh provenance of research serious about
it and he had a good business down there
really good business and uh he's still
up and running somewhere I think I don't
know what he's necessarily doing now but
he's still out there kicking it and he
came and brought down cherry pie along
with some other stuff and uh it was
about
2011 and my first time running it the
first thing I noticed was oh my God this
is gassy like there's a lot of gas to
Cherry Pie not just the sweet end but
there's a gassy end that you could pull
out of it um reminded me a lot of like
an OG gassy type when you pull gassy OG
out um what else was there beautiful
purple colors that you can pull out of
it uh structure s very I I'll bring this
up right now it there's a structure so
remn inent of the F1 derb that it's
almost hard to ignore that they're
absolutely related um I would venture to
guess URL GDP type uh with the F1 derb
makes sense to me um but there is some
kind of gassy OG Kush to it and there
there's some speculation like with me on
on F1 der maybe having OG cross to it at
some point um or inside of it um yeah
that's I think that's most of the Cherry
Pie tail unless you guys got any
questions or to add yeah anything else
you wanted to add then or any other
questions just remember it had like
little like triangle buds yeah you know
like it was all popcorn it was very
similar to Forum in that regard where it
was like all small buds that were like
very very dense and you could tell they
like looking at them even as clones when
they were growing that they were
probably directly related in some way as
well the for and the Cherry Pie I also
vaguely remember it growing pretty slow
and shitty
I don't know if it was growing slow and
shitty at the time because it was so
young at that time it hadn't been passed
yeah I'm not I'm not sure I can't
remember really um but like when I think
about it I I vaguely remember just like
kind of a
shorter um slow growing plant which
would kind of lend itself to something
like a an Urkel or a GDP oh let me add
in intersects inter big time Big Time
and and if it is related to uh the F1
derb then that's probably why um that
trait seems to be pretty heavy in
cookies and Cherry Pie and and a lot of
stuff so yeah for
sure I kind of want to foreshadow at
this point that we're probably not going
to get around to constructing any kind
of timeline and that this is kind of a
that these genetics are like a crazy
Circle don't know you know inbred nested
uh ring of whatever uh cannabis Human
Centipede Vibe um
yeah but yeah we can move on to
GDP oh GDP so there this is another one
has I don't even know if I want to go
into the history of GDP so much as kind
of reference it I know CSI like his
opinion on GDP has changed a lot on what
is GDP what is Urkel which I don't even
know if he's brought up publicly but
it's it's it's interesting real
interesting and I'll leave that to him
maybe when uh he owes us an episode and
I reminded him just this weekend you owe
us an so buddy and Kush apparently Kush
of the Giants and little Hill are both
going to try and add some pressure as
well I don't know if it'll help or not
but he he knows he knows what's up um
GDP so there is a wonderful video with
Ken Estes talking about the history of
GDP and I remember a long time ago on
the forums I transcribed it so people
could actually read what Mumble mouth
was saying and essentially he said that
he was given the Clone by Native
American
shamans in front of some headlights at a
ceremony of sorts and uh because he was
such a cool white man they decided to
gift him this magical clone that was not
only skunk but like from Vietnam and all
this other stuff and it was most purple
weed he'd ever seen um yeah I mean GDP
reminds me a lot of an Urkle type and
they seem to be directly related in some
way I don't know if one came before the
other uh back in the day almost
everything was called GDP whether it was
Urkel whether it was gra Vape whether
all those names were so interchangeable
that it became really hard to tie it
down to a specific clone there was the
Ken GDP referring to Ken Estes that was
super purple um and then he made a
seedline that he called Granddaddy
Purple which really screwed everything
up and all of a sudden everybody had the
real GDP Ken's GDP because he put out
the seed line of seeds um as far as
relation is I don't see much difference
between it and Urkel and how it breeds
to really say again which came first the
chicken or the egg but they're both so
heavily involved in thin Min in in Forum
u in my opinion that they could be
synonymous and used interchangeably in
that way grapey purple slow growing um
super Afghani Outdoors they have more
narrow leaves than they would Broad Leaf
so some people would confuse it for a
sativa Outdoors but I mean it's short
squat short inter node spacing um yeah
super grapey um but in veg both the GDP
and KKL are some of the absolute
skunkiest
Cuts you can have when you take cuts of
those things it fills up a room and
smells like just straight skunk spray um
but when flowering about week six they
go from that skunky smell to
sweet grape and it it's a big change up
but yeah that's what I got I don't know
if you have much experience with it Dan
no so I've never actually held like a
verified cut of any of the real purples
um they were a little bit before my time
like I remember buying bags of stuff
called GDP and there's really good
purple weed in it you know um but one
thing that I've always thought was
interesting was I saw this um uh peer
reviewed paper that where they had
collected a bunch of clones out of
American grows and um you know done the
gene correlations and made a
philogenetic tree and um all of the
purples were clustered together yeah and
then all of them were also very much
more basil so like you have the tree
going off of like all the modern cuts
and you see like OG and you see c99 and
all the [ __ ] just on this main branch
and then out of nowhere from way more
basil the purple shoot up to the top and
to me that kind of lends itself to the
stories there's a few stories that we've
heard on the show of um people being
given seeds from the 70s yeah um and
I've heard a few of those stories myself
outside the show as well and I think
that's kind of where most of them arrive
from is from like afghanis and like you
know cuts from the from the East over
there and um them getting stored and
then popped by people in the 90s and I
think that's where most of these Cuts
come from and it actually showed that
Grape Ape was the most basil out of all
of them does that mean like the the
parental yeah like further Upstream
right is what you when you say basil
yeah yeah exactly like it it would be
like Grape Ape and then like a branch
off of that and it would show GDP and a
branch off of that and it would show URL
um and like I can't remember the
placement of each of them in regards to
each other but it also depends on like
what the named cut that those people
collected were because I've never been
able to tell the difference when someone
says oh this is purple kush clone this
is a GDP this is a purple Urkle like
they all are really really similar in my
opinion and
um uh yeah I think that they're all
probably very closely related if not
renames of cuts or bag seeds of each
other yeah the SR71 Purple Kush was a
big one and I had that growing side by
side with Urkle back in the day and that
was sourced from Blue Sky C
or SR71 which became Blue Sky Cafe later
on and I could never tell the difference
between the two like sometimes we'd say
oh the SR71 is more hashy more earthy
hashy but like it could have just been
different you know just small little
different I don't even know bro like
they were all so similar all of them GDP
they all grew short squat short intern
node spacing um had less trouble with
grap ape I always thought it was kind of
prettier and had more narrow type but
I've seen URL perform that way too um
yeah it's I think you're right too I
think it's just an an introduction of
old purple afghanis
um yeah I don't know like it's it's one
of those things where it was so many
clones were passed around in the same
area of California with these different
names obviously Urkel didn't pop up as a
name until Family Matters was a TV show
but before that it had other names you
know like just purple purple bud skunk
you know things like that were around um
GDP was named what it was because it was
supposed to be the OG purple the one
that came before all the other ones the
granddaddy of them you know but whether
that's true or not or just like someone
trying to push a narrative again like
trying to find that original called it
would be damn near impossible to untie
that unless you find someone that's had
it with good provenance going back
however
long yeah I was going to I was going to
prompt this next one which is uh we're
going to obviously talk about OG as well
but we've also seen uh We've also seen
oal hybrids of OG uh Ural OG hybrids out
there uh made by other people like
obviously Caleb's got T1000 and I can't
remember the line that that was from
what do you guys think based on looking
at just straight OG oal type hybrids and
how they might resemble cookies or not
you can get really really close you can
get damn close to cookies with it
um it's not the most common expression
but you can get really damn close
without without
the without the F1 derb essentially but
you've got a little bit different of a
structure you'll always get a more OG
type structure um I do still think that
it's part of the reason why I think OG
is in F1 derb though because it's only a
little bit of a hint of a difference
between an URL OG hybrid and what we
knew as forum per se you know um yeah
the The Thin Mint to me was always more
narrow Leaf which I was kind of wondered
where that came from as opposed to this
URL OG hybrid and it may just be that
difference between what's dominating in
there and that's the F1 but F1 durb also
looks pretty broadleaf in many ways so I
don't really know um yeah Caleb did a
lot of uh urk and OG hybrids before he
made it up to T1000 he had the Savage
purple which was sfv per uh f sfv purle
um there was God's Gift back in the day
which was GDP OG that was real famous in
in California I used that early on um I
think I even did some but a lot of
people were doing that combination you
know OG was hype and purples were hype
and that's what people wanted like the
solo assassin number three looked like
an urk OG looked just dead on like an Ur
OG G didn't have the same na'vi
structure or bubbly cxes that um or bra
that that uh cookies has but the resin
production was absolutely insane there
was a lot of gassy skunkin to it um it
was short low yielding like popcorn
structure it had a lot of the it ticked
a lot of the bo same boxes really really
high THC testing really dull High
yeah Dam any thoughts on that one yeah
like I've seen some OG hybrids with
different purples and the only thing
that makes me go back to Meo meno per is
the the Anis and the licorice TPS
because those turps are they're so
prevalent when you breed with cookie
stuff and like it's I think one of the
main components that makes that sherb
Aroma as it's like referenced you know
oh yeah that's good point and I don't
really get a lot of like when I've bred
with this stuff I don't really get
skunky or grapey ever you know it's
pretty pretty much always like some
creamy licorice type thing with some gas
and uh that's the only reason I think it
in some way in the most incestuous way
possible leads back to meno per as the
the donor for the purple and um Al also
I mean it's hard to say though because
meno perss also its purple traits are
true purple you know versus the other
ones they're very um uh climate
dependent you know like the temperature
dependent and so um that's like the
counter argument is that it's like oh
well there's not a lot of true breeding
purple in cookies lines either you know
it's always kind of that gray purple and
it comes on late whereas like meno per
and some of its hybrids will like purple
out in a hot room in week two and so um
it goes back and forth I see data data
points that point in both
directions you know and meno perss
another thing about that is that it has
a lot of Magenta in it that's true
breeding as well like yeah it's hard to
shake magenta out ofendo pers hybrids
down the line and I just never see that
in the cookies on its own I just saw it
but it doesn't mean that you can't
directionally breed you know what I mean
like it could always be a directional
breeding and and manage to avoid that
magenta trait it's just it's like with
uh the other place I see it is in
chatral and like double purple DOA stuff
like that from the Blackberry and
there's always been some kind of um
theories on whether you know BlackBerry
was related to meno perss or not it meno
perss may be one of those old purple
afghanis that was floating around and
God knows where it came from I mean I
don't know if I necessarily believe
every story I hear now but I do think it
was a base for a lot of the purples I do
um how it got to be that base whether it
was a sister whether it was one cut
whether it was bag seeds going around um
NorCal and it wasn't even necessarily
the first thing called mesino Purple
there was other mesino purples earlier
sure yeah
so we were gonna do an episode on that
too right like we were GNA do
a for pink magenta maybe oh yeah yeah
yeah yeah we were huh see I'm all making
fun of you yeah we were gonna do that
instead of this yeah that's right we
were yeah originally yeah but this
needed to be done for
sure so we've sort of talked about OG
already is there anything else to add um
on the OG side of things as far as this
goes like with cookies like um a really
good example of an OG dominant cookies
would have been something like animal
cookies to me it was it was the the more
OG end of forum I mean they almost again
they almost looked identical in veg they
almost looked identical in flower except
it had more of an OG Kush structure and
more of an OG cush scent and that was
probably one of my favorite cuts out of
all of them because I really like OG
Kush um I don't think you get cookies
without OG cush I don't think you get it
I don't think so you can get OG KB OG
Kush breath looking stuff without OG but
I don't think you can get the gassiness
in ogkb and the potency with just Urkle
or with just like an Urkle type you can
get the mutation you won't necessarily
get the gassy and all that stuff with it
though yeah I look at it and I see the
structure and like the leaf ToBD ratio
where it's like basically just like a
two little leaves that are at the base
of the bud and then it's all flower
above
that is like the modern structure that I
see and I think all of that comes from
OG from my own breedings with it and
it's it's the number one thing that gets
pasted even if you miss by a mile on the
turps um you still end up with that
structure and that look yeah
definitely yeah it's just a major
component of what we're talking about I
just don't think you have it without the
OG
essentially
nice well uh coming up we have we have
another cut or at least another name
that we've covered quite a bit the sherb
I'll let you run with this one Dan and I
guess it's like yeah which Sher are we
talking about I guess you can go into
that too I only talk about Sunset when I
talk about Sher because in my opinion
it's the main one that matters like the
whole green sherb thing and Skittles and
all that is it's fun to talk about but
like Sunset sherb to me was like the
first one that was like a really really
good cash crop plant that came out of
all these lines and you could get great
weight great potency a variety of Aromas
from creamy to like pure fuel on the
same cut um and uh I have pictures from
some grows that I did of it in I think
2017 um that are just like whole rooms
just filled with donkey dick buds just
swaying in the fans and um I love that
plant I wish I still had it but um as
far as like what it what it's made of
like I don't really believe the story of
OG Kush pink panties I mean we've seen
that picture of pink panties now that
we've passed around to each other and um
I maybe I could see it but it's uh it's
so
purple yeah you know like it's a turd
bro [ __ ] turd it's not it's Airy
again Herm
prone turs like no resin
production and
this can kind of go into the last one
too of the pink panties like Buu
conversation it's like I don't see how
you could like cross a burmes to an OG
and have that plant in one hybrid I just
don't think it's
possible because a burmes would be like
a 20we flowering like e equatorial
Southeast Asian sativa and so maybe
something went around called burmes at
that point and they crossed it to an OG
but I don't it looks way more like it's
some sort of of like an F1 derb
derivative to me there was a Burmese
that reeferman passed around that was
predominantly like Afghan like it
obviously was not a you know High
Burmese land race at all stretch yeah
close enough though right um I could
definitely see that be in buku um it was
also very Herm from but there was a line
from Vancouver called the black burmes
that was definitely super purple
definitely super Herr
and using re I'm pretty sure it's reer
man's burmes I don't know if if he got
it from the dude at VC or they traded it
or one came from the other but I'm
betting it's the same one and God it was
trash and that's the only thing I can
see with pink panties with sure my my
biggest problem with it is there's a
scent in sherb that goes through every
single thing that has sherb in it I can
always smell it it's it's a lot of it's
pretty smelling but it's like a
pepperine note that I don't like and and
I don't really hear people mention it
but it's just like a it's so hard to
explain but it's a no it's like what
biscotti has yeah yeah I mean it's but
it's so prevalent in everything that
sherb is touched but it's I I just I
couldn't I just never liked it it was
one of those ones I can't like like uh
rs1 has it like it's a big component of
rs11 the scent that I'm talking about
but some people love it you know it's
just one of those personal subjective
things yeah it's um Sunset sherb is also
responsible for what I would say is like
the majority of like the modern hype
cuts at the moment like jealousy and all
that it's all from like sure biscotti
incrosses of one type or another and so
I think it's by far the best breeding
out of all of them like if you want
pretty consistent plants that throw big
buds that are purple have these modern
tur profiles like it's probably the one
you actually want to use I don't think
using the gelados I haven't seen it
really go anywhere besides making more
gelato
yeah you know same whereas like and same
thing with Sher but sher's just better
and so maybe it's just like that one
step removed farther back that makes it
breed slightly better I don't know but
um I have not been a fan of breeding
with gelato for really
anything good segue because we were
gonna go into that you know I don't know
if it's fair to call that next
Generation but gelato wedding cake I
don't know like you guys know the tonomy
better than me so wedding cake to me me
is it you know like a lot of people lump
that in with cookies but to me it's more
of a triangle type of plant you can find
that tur profile that and to me I just
call cardboard tur profile some people
think it's like creamy you know add a
creamy component but I just think it's
Garb Garb profile and um you know
everybody always shits on me because I
naysay all this [ __ ] but like I really
don't like it's to me it's the the One
Direction I would not want to take
triangle it's the midy uh commercial
version of triangle to me and someone
locked it in and called it wedding cake
I can't remember jce Ley something like
his name's one of those
names but I'm not really so into it I
spent a lot of time trying to like map
this stuff with the last job that I had
because like I really wanted to see like
what directions you could go down by
like mixing and matching some of these
cuts and like the um there is like a
very big gap between like where everyone
went with gelato and the sherb cuts um
which I would consider more similar
versus like the animal mints hybrids
that jbzy made that's honestly kind of
like its own side shoot and um it's just
as incestuous you know what I mean like
look up like ice cream cake to wedding
cake to animal mint like it's all the
same cut basically just reworked a
thousand different ways but um they are
separate lines in my opinion I think
that wedding cake and gelato are two
different things
things yeah I just yeah if you forced to
like oh sorry Mt go ahead go ahead I was
going to ask Dan like you know he
mentioned that like he could see these
like broad distinctions across these
broad groups like if you could if you
had to put words to those distinctions
what would they be do you think um well
like wedding cake like Matt was [ __ ]
on CU like it was a seedline originally
that was released and so there's I've
barely ever come across the same cut of
wedding cake twice you know same thing
with gelato 33 you know it's just like I
think it was originally a seedline that
was released or like maybe he did like a
gelato 33 BX or something like that and
so um oh great my power's
fluttering um and so uh it
uh what am I trying to say it uh there's
just so many of them I've had really
nice cuts of wedding cake that I liked
that I bred with and um but it's just
one of those things that um wedding cake
is creamy huge buds some purple not
always um potency is meh same and
they're they're honestly just like
flavors of the same thing or the same
family but that they were taken in
separate directions and then ran with
you know what I mean like wedding cake
doesn't have in those lines they don't
really have a lot of overcross back into
gelato until you get to ice cream cake
because that's like wedding cake times
gelato 3 I'm pretty sure um and actually
I loved ice cream cake I thought it was
a good cut as a good cash propper made
me some money over a few years and so um
it's not something that I miss that I
now that I don't have it I've never it
or smoked it ever I kind of look at the
three main categories as like the sherb
gelato the green sherb Skittles and then
the animal mints wedding cake stuff
those are like the three main groupings
in my
mind that you can actually like map out
as separate for me like wedding cake the
way I look at wedding cake is the dead
end of triangle whereas gelato would be
the dead end of urel triangle to me like
like that once you hit that point like
you can make a whole bunch more wedding
cake type stuff and name it whatever you
want it's always going to be very
similar to wedding cake and I think
that's what 99% of the market is is
either the dead end of gelato and once
you've got to that it's almost like uh
having a a trinoline haze once you get
there you can't really wipe out that
well you could try but it's always going
to be there I mean I was trying to do it
with blue bonnet and wedding cake and it
just to me it just made like a man
creamy commercial Blue Bonnet it was not
novel unique um and it when you start
inbreeding you start back Crossing and
not knowing what you're doing that's
kind of where you're going to end up in
my opinion or or or bad seeds a bad
seeds a bag seeds and bag seeds in the
same direction you know like gelato yeah
in my opinion so you're essentially in
like a genetic C
at that point right yes that's the best
way to put all this like I I always say
it's like a [ __ ] breeding dead end but a
genetic culdesac is probably a nicer way
of putting it
yeah yeah and so really the question I'm
just paraphrasing you is like why like
there is no real value to taking those
things any further like within within
those constraints right well what you
end up seeing what you end up seeing
nowadays is that people take things from
outside these lines or from like more
basil regions and then they try and
reflavor it while keeping the look the
structure the trim ability like all that
and so they're like well now we've got
Cherry gelato yeah now we've got Z
flavored gel you know what I mean with
runs kind of thing and um it's all still
the same [ __ ] whether you throw a little
you know like you're were saying like a
blue bonnet like oh yeah my blueberry
gelato now you know it's but it's still
midy and it's still like has all the
problems and it you can't take it
further really because like you start
ending up with all these negative traits
like the little aborted seed pods that
are in they're in everywhere in these
lines like you can't get away from them
and so like if you hybridize like a
bunch of gelato and Skittles together
like or a permanent marker Skittles
whatever these crosses you want to make
together you end up losing like 50% of
it to a lot of these negative traits
even if it's good smoke It's usually the
best cut too where you're like oh this
smells good this has actually got some
potency to it and you grind it up and
there's like a million little aborted
seeds in in your you know little pile of
weed and so um it just depends on if
that's like a deal breaker for you I
guess or not but it's not something I
want to see yeah for sure I just I just
wish that people would do more novel
stuff than like gelato runs gelato OG
gelato gelato you know like and it and
to me just the that's 99% of the market
that's what people have been told that
they want is buds that look just like
this and that's what I mean to me that's
what compound was was gelato gelato
gelato and just ran with it and it's
still being run with it's I just it's
people what the reason I really really
dislike it just from a breeding
perspective is because so much was
dropped in place that was novel unique
old because the market was demanding so
much of that
crap that like like I've been talking
about a lot of breeders are asking me
hey do you know where I can get a good
OG cut because there's no there's not a
lot of OG cuts out there anymore because
people wanted gelato and demanded it so
much that OG just wasn't in demand bags
wouldn't sell of OG and realistically it
costs money to keep moms of something
that you cannot make money with so it's
either done out of like a sense of Duty
um a a love for
collecting uh or monetary car and if you
don't have all three in some cases it's
just not going to fly and it seems like
that's what's going on and it's it's
hype at its finest marketing at its
finest and easiest and sheepish to me
and people are get so mad that I say
that but it's it's all I see it another
phrase comes to mind for me which is
that these again paraphrasing both of
you like these these names are just like
all like false alter alternative
Alternatives yeah I can see that yeah
it's the illusion that you're you're
choosing between varying things but
actually you're not really choosing at
all and I mean realistically of choice
with with all the cookie stuff like from
day one like none of this that didn't
Girl Scout cookies doesn't smell like
thin mint cookies doesn't taste like
thin mint cookies chocolate you know
like Andes mints what the and and it
just carried on whether you're talking
about sherbet tasting like like orange
sherbet no it doesn't like
uh wedding cake to me creamy yeah is it
sweet creamy battery no
like just I it's marketing it's
marketing and it's just so dishonest and
I don't know why like I specifically I
remember when animal cookies came out
and before I had it there were a couple
of um gentlemen I don't remember who
they were talking about it and reviewing
the bud and they're sitting smelling
like oh my God this smells so much like
animal cracker
oh my God I was like godamn that would
be [ __ ] awesome animal cracker Bud
like that would be the [ __ ] I like the
smell of animal crackers and so it got
really built up until I grabbed it and I
was like this is not crack this is OG
like [ __ ] you know like a lot of false
promises get sold but at some point that
expectation was just wiped and people
didn't have the expectation for a name
to have anything to do with the scent
taste or there's something psychosomatic
going on where they're convincing
themselves that yeah it's totally animal
crackers you know either way tards yeah
you can influence people's perception of
Aromas by the marketing of its naming
and all that you know if you say like
hey this is you know smells like cookies
people smell it and maybe they get some
of that battery an and they're like oh
yeah it kind of does smell like cookies
and I'm like what [ __ ] cookie is that
you know what I mean that's not
chocolate chip man that's not that's not
peanut butter cookies you know yeah
blows my mind bro yeah but it's like you
really you can influence people's
perception of Aroma very easily and so
like when I want people's opinions on
like what something smells like in a jar
I don't tell them anything because if I
say like do you smell the lime they'll
be
like yeah actually I do you know what I
mean because your brain is filling it in
you know yeah when you I think when you
experience uh a field of complexity or
noise it's very easy to project things
onto it kind of like looking at clouds
right daydreaming looking at clouds and
stuff and your friend goes oh do you see
do you see the like Battleship and
you're like yeah I can see that and it's
like yeah sure yeah the human mind is
very malleable in our like perception of
reality yeah unfortunately some people
have it worse than others I guess I
don't know uh you have to have a certain
certain sense of skepticism to to get
past that I think like just be an
inherently skeptical person to not have
your mind made up before you something I
guess yeah I mean same as Dan like yeah
if if my if my Partners bought us some
new coffee I'm I don't want to read the
bag because it's going to say that has
apricot
strawberry you know whatever I want to
try for myself and then see what they
said about it afterwards just so I can
compare you know it's like yeah
otherwise it is too easy I can't imagine
those things too easily either you're
the kid that sniffs your friend's finger
when he says smell my finger or you're
not that's down to well and like most of
the time without any information like
that's why I love showing my wife weed
cuz like she's just like yeah smells
good and that's like how I am with most
things if it's like if I'm smelling a
bag of coffee I'm not thinking about
like all the other things it could
possibly smell like or taste like I'm
like oh yeah smells good and you make a
cup and you're like yeah it tastes
pretty [ __ ] good but yeah then you
you read the bag and you fill in like oh
yeah notes of caramel and you know like
all the things and like suddenly brain's
like oh yeah yeah for sure I tasted that
the Starbucks graham cracker coffee
really does taste like graham crackers
though oh yeah because they probably
purade some [ __ ] graham crackers in
it so good
bro so good I'm glad to be able to drink
coffee again that was a long time I
couldn't drink coffee without
puking yeah dude I'm I'm there with you
if I have more than one cup I'm like B
yeah it was bad for a while so was it
worth us talk I mean you guys already
you know reference permanent marker and
rs11 and jealousy like is it is it worth
talking about those at all yeah you go
ahead Dan yeah I've bred with them in
the past year like pretty extensively
with the last place I was working with
and um permanent marker I think is
actually some pretty good smoke it's not
something I would take to a desert
island with me but it's like good
variety because it takes that like sherb
Anis profile and it's just like cranked
up you know and it's not that potent but
it's just it's really really amazing
flavor like I think I sent um I sent
someone on the server a couple bags of
like I think it was a skittles S1
permanent marker and um a few other
things I can't remember off the top of
my head and even he agreed he was just
like the permanent markers like even
compared to the Skittles it's like a
very similar profile it like has
elements of the same thing it's just
like turned up to 11 and so um I thought
it was really nice it was the first like
cookies directional thing that I had
smoked in a long time I was like oh I
kind of actually [ __ ] like this but
it lasted a day the tolerance part you
know what I mean like that quick cookies
buildup of a tolerance to where it
just you know you see it in you see it
in the lab analysis too it's like not a
very diverse sample as far as like any
accessory canabo or like small amounts
of different um Turpin that you look at
it's it's kind of just like cool um and
it breeds they all breed very dominantly
because they've been so like
inadvertently linebred by multiple
different people over the last you know
15 years yeah um and so permanent marker
is very much like rs11 and that like not
that they breed the same but that
they're very consistent in their
structures that they pass you'll see
like when I crossed permanent marker
everything looked like permanent marker
and it just depended on whether the um
the other plant had like a more dominant
Aroma profile or something so like I was
crossing it to some fruit punch type
stuff and the fruit punch just always
came through and it looked exactly like
permanent marker and I was like this is
[ __ ]
boring terrible same thing with RS 11
rs1 does like like a nice gelato
structure and then these like thin
little finger buds that are just like
you know A small collection of kix's
just like stacked on each other and um
it was all garbage in my opinion I
looked at it and I was just like oh let
me take notes on another [ __ ] plant
that's exactly like the last one and um
they're very predictable and that's I
don't think people get is that these
things may be massive poly hybrids but
they've poly hybrids with the same base
components and so things actually do get
fairly fixed over time and um It's
usually the bad stuff and um pretty
looks you know low potency pretty looks
some a lot of cardboard TPS but um
they're very consistent in what they do
like rs11 like unless you cross it to
something like a bully like a train
wreck or a blue dream or something like
that like I can tell you exactly the
breakdown of like the types of
Expressions you're likely to see because
it is so consistent um but it's
consistently
bad like the the really nice clones that
get pulled out of these hyers are the
exception to the rule So when you buy
these seeds and you're like oh it's you
know zope times this or that like you're
going to find mostly trash and like you
may be the one that gets lucky that
finds like a really nice tasting one or
one that has unusual potency for the
line but um they rarely all line up in
one you know like I'll run 50 to 100
seeds of some of that stuff and just be
like oh my God why can't I find one that
has the looks the potency and the aroma
they're all segregated in different
combinations and I cannot find them
together and um it's really frustrating
work to do and what if low population
breeding what other than other than just
inbreeding I wonder if it's just low
population pops bags population pops
yeah for sure like things can get fixed
inadvertently and be kind of like bred
quote
unquote completely unintentionally and
you can have traits that get fixed you
know and some of them can be good and
some of them are bad I I just like the
reason it made me think of that was like
DJ's blueberry like I always go back to
that almost all of my my thoughts on on
stuff like that are uh what I've seen in
blueberry from a low population playing
around type situation where you know was
three plants in a room one Herms on the
other one one pollinates two other ones
you mix up the seeds and then for the
next four years you cross the sativa
type to the indicia type so you're
inbreeding small population yeah even
though it just and it turns into variant
but
inbred low floor you know yeah and and
you can fix it it's very easy to fix
throughout Crossing to the right thing
but not everybody does that yeah
no and like I at this point I really
like like uh for like the future of this
kind of stuff like I don't really think
there is one it's like what hasn't been
crossed to one of these cookies things
like what are we really going to find
like I've done it where I like take a
nice cut of Blue Dream and work it into
some of these lines and like you know
what it's all trash the best ones are
always like oh yeah it's like basically
Blue Dream yeah the best on light
reflavoring you know but like I don't
think that there's anything you can like
cross to this stuff to really make it
new and exciting for me at least like
I've Just Seen A lot of it and um the
further back you go the better it is not
forward at all and so yeah I had a
question originally that was like oh how
do you you know quote unquote fix or
Counterpoint it but I think you that we
saw a good example of them trying to do
this using bod's congales Kashmir like
yeah much more like unique and wild than
the Congo cash I got to run it you know
so I got to see what it was like it was
unique but even in doing that I've not
heard of anything like insanely amazing
coming from and that's not just [ __ ] on
bod because he's a [ __ ] amazing guy
doing cool [ __ ] it's just that's where
cookies was at I think yeah and like
what they end up wanting is because like
I've been in these rooms on these
breeding panels where like you do the
work and then someone else gets to pick
through it and [ __ ] and like catch muu
yeah yeah and like you do the work you
try and make something new and unusual
and you know what they do they pick the
one that's most like the modern parent
yeah and it'll be the worst cut out of
all of it you're just like that's trash
I didn't even want to show you that jar
but I had to because the way this works
and like like why did you pick that and
then they want to breed with it
afterwards and they're like look at this
new thing we made and it's just not true
it's all it's all trash most of it at
least and like maybe you can find
something that has like a novel Aroma
but most of the time it's just like a
jack Aroma from one of the parents and
then you added it to this structure and
this like thing that people like but I
think people need to get away from that
it's like the structure of the weed like
doesn't matter at all just like if I
need a seven gram jar to put an eighth
in it because it's larpy but it's really
good really nuanced tasty weed like why
does weed have to be Rock little little
rocks little Pebbles and dense and like
why does it have to be purple and like
why does it have to have this dessert
name attached to it and I think that
people just don't even especially the
younger people I talk to like they don't
even really know about like real
diversity in weed they think that
they're looking at all these names
permanent marker sherb jealousy and they
think that they're all these distinct
things from each other and they're just
not at all it's all marketing and so
like the way forward is to just like ask
for new things like actually new things
maybe don't buy your weed from a
dispensary if you have the option you
know what I mean because like there's a
lot of people that still grow in their
homes and in their backyards that don't
give a [ __ ] about what's popular popular
and what sells because it's just for
them and their family and their friends
and um that's the like move that I'm
trying to do is just like I'm going to
grow things that I like make things that
I like and then I'm G to find the people
that jive with that you know I don't
care about making sales and like growing
something that's guaranteed to make me
sales because at the end of the day I'm
not a one- trick pony I don't like need
to make money off of weed it's just nice
to like do the work and feel rewarded at
the same time or like have it not just
like cost you money for having this like
very life consuming hobby um yeah but
yeah we need to get away from this like
fixation on color and density and I
think that would solve most of the
problems you know you can still cross
GDP into other weird stuff and like some
of these more basal components um and F
get really interesting weed yeah this is
more or less where I wanted to where I
wanted us to conclude which is maybe
just for fun speculating or reflecting
on what those possibilities are even
like for example whether it's we talked
about uh different uhal OG hybrids
earlier on but even like thinking okay
in an alternate his in an alternate like
timeline where instead of URL there was
Blue Bonnet like what would that what
would have happened you know something
or any other thing that's like equally
distinctive Jolley CH trolley u double
purple Dojo was a big one during like
the the late 2000s double purple Doo
based on BlackBerry or Blackberry Widow
whatever they were really using um a lot
of that stuff is so different and far
removed from what Oracle types are um
there could have been a lot of Novel
cool [ __ ] done with that like even
subcool as much as much as people know
my contentious relationship with a human
being was when he was around um the
double purple DOA was insane like it was
a basically a purple like a Blackberry
version of Apollo 13 and we don't really
see a lot of Apollo 13 types anymore
especially now that that TGA is
temporarily gone but we're going to see
a Resurgence soon but uh like that was
cool that was way different than than
any of the cookie stuff and you still
got like the novel purple maybe not as
much Leaf resin maybe it wasn't geared
as much to Bubble has and that's another
part of it is like people just see resin
and they think oh hash bro you know yank
it but
you got the colors you got unique TPS
you got really potent highs in many
cases um chatr has very similar
beautiful magenta colors and it's just
so far out of the realm of what people
are using today you know a base
Pakistani which is essentially you know
very similar to an Afghani um slightly
different
elevations that could take things in so
many different
directions just randomly as well like
even if you kept URL like why would be
like to not use OG right like we we've
seen we've seen URL kimd yes dogs Walts
is that what it
is I mean Loosely tra dog sorry so not
exactly but you know like that that even
that's quite different and quite
interesting yeah yeah dude that's a a
lot of people's favorite cut it's a cool
it's a cool cut um urle what I did like
an a GDP bubbleberry that was really
unique back in the day it was one of my
very first crosses um there's a lot of
different things you could do at GDP and
um even like an Urkle tie like you know
like the like the like banana tie or the
Juicy Fruit tie that was in banana tie
cross the URL be insane it would be
really really neat um two totally
different types it's not I just it's
like to me URL wasn't the problem it
was
really not not unique thinkers the the
everybody trying to do the same thing
and capitalize on the same thing really
easily like for me cookies was very easy
to grow it made everyone look like they
could grow really well because you it
grew itself you know and um that in
itself made everybody start growing it
too like oh I look like a rock star look
how Frosty this is I'm a dank grower bro
I can feed this nitrogen like a tomato
all the time and it still blows up
Frosty yeah and there's so many
different directions and people are just
so sheepish I hate it it's it's what's
turned me off in general I realized I
when asking uh alternative to cookies
I.E like the rest of
breeding yeah I mean not asking anything
yeah it's just a small niche of it even
outside of cookies though if you really
think about it it's like people think
that nowadays people would think
breeding with OG is probably original
and I'm like once again like what hasn't
been crossed to OG I can't think of a
single thing you know and so like if you
look back we are actually still just
using the pieces from previous Hy Paras
where it's like the purple cuts and the
ogs and then now all the modern stuff
and so like that's the only thing I
really care about nowadays is stuff that
predates almost all of it yeah because
the rest of it's already been done and
it was done well a lot of the times too
and like you're probably not going to
have the same access to the versions of
the cuts that the people that did it
really well when it was around um did
and so um I just look for 90s weed now
you know I want to Super Skunk
everything like yeah right the thing
yeah but to me also like but that's
almost like a little bit like souring
everything up or like cheeming
everything up or oging everything up I
think there's it's the same component in
all those three they give it like the
soapiness sometimes when you explore the
s1's in different directions um so it's
really not that novel or unique but it's
taking a step back to where you can see
all the other components that are in
those things and then stuff that you've
never
seen yeah yeah it's going to be
interesting inter to see where everyone
goes cuz it's like it's so standardized
now you know like things only get
selected when they grow a certain way
and they flower in a certain time frame
and they respond to nutrients that
everyone uses the same now and so like
like what we've seen now is and I think
it's already there is like like we're
all drinking Budweiser yeah you know
what I mean like it doesn't matter where
you buy it from and like it it can have
all kinds of different names but it's
really the iction between like Bud MGD
Miller you know what I mean like it's
like all the same cheap shitty beer it's
all the same cheap shitty weed and it's
grown with no love and like a lot of
times because of the way testing
standards work you would be appalled to
look in the rooms that these big
companies with good reputations have and
so um need a whole episode on that bro
yeah there's just like it's it's
terrifying like people that actually
love this and actually care about what
they consume and what they give to other
people like you would all hate to see
where it's gone and um they can spin it
whatever the way they want with their
marketing but there's a lot of really
horrendous things that you'll see in a
modern grow nowadays and the absolute
lack of caring the only thing that
matters is the schedule yep it doesn't
matter what the plant wants what would
make it Excel what would make it a
better product it doesn't matter there's
a schedule to meet there's pounds that
need to
like shipped out on this dat to these
people and um it's the beaster era all
over again just with fancy new packaging
yeah a lot more money involved lot more
corporate money involved lot more Chads
and that's the only difference
yeah way I see it too brother yeah it's
a sad time for commercial weed but once
again just don't buy like if you have
the opportunity like don't buy weed from
a shop like if you have the opportunity
with your backyard or your garage or
whatever like gross some plants for
yourself like even on your first go with
some some plants or some seeds that you
can buy commercially or as a as a home
grower like you're probably going to
like that weed so much more than what
you're paying 4 to $60 an e at a store
for most people would be surprised with
what they can do for sure it's been made
to look very inaccessible you know like
seeing all these like 90 lighters 200
lighters it looks really inaccessible it
looks really expensive but uh it's not
there's there's better there's there's
ways to do it small and efficient and
better you know better controls yeah no
just a little you don't have enough
space you need to see Migra yeah exactly
man like or if you like live in an
illegal State still or an illegal
portion of the world like people do it
man you're even more lucky like
realistically like you're more lucky
because then you could get some some
some money for your [ __ ] make it worth
it you know spot also yeah I mean I'm
you know you guys know I'm not in that
I'm not advocating doing a little Stu by
the way oh never but even being so
remote like we don't really exposed to
even like those Market pressures or
those weird demands like yeah no for
sure and those are the those are where
the pockets of diversity usually Thrive
is where there isn't this substantial
Market pressure and like and what the
Last Frontier in America is the the
homeg grower you know and so like we all
need to keep keep going with this and so
I don't know maybe there's some
opportunity to like form just like weed
appreciation groups in your community
kind of thing where it's just like hey
like it doesn't cost you anything to be
a part of it or it's a very small fee
like on a a patreon thing or a Discord
thing and just like hey we all meet up
in person we share jars we talk about
weed we all love it maybe a little clone
swap here and there but like we need to
get back to more
Grassroots methods like that and just
like Community Based stuff because if we
just give it away to the corporations
they're going to make you pay more than
full price like I don't remember paying
$60 for an eighth at a shop during the
215 era like they were there you know
what I mean there was a few but it's
like by the end of the 215 era you could
get [ __ ] $35 eights a top shelf
anywhere in California and it was
absolutely killer diversity just
anything you could want you could go
into a shop and pick from a 100 jars and
how did we got from there in a short
number of years to basically all the
same weed with different marketing
packaging you know and it's all full
price more so than when it was illegal
even though it's more over produced than
ever like it just doesn't add up to me I
call [ __ ] like artificial scarcity
you know I mean but like this is what I
keep trying to drive home in all these
episodes like you vote with your dollars
you literally vote with your dollars
there is and trying to explain to people
people that there's maybe like seven or
eight people on Earth with these big
collections with good provenant on these
clones that's shrinking so fast they're
having to make hard [ __ ] choices and
if you keep if you if you're ever
interested in smoking something that's
not cookies or gelato if you're if
you're you know one of those people who
doesn't just follow the straight line
like vote with your dollars that's it
it's all it's left and if you don't
it'll be gone and that's s yeah and what
sucks is that like the kind of
connoisseur part portion of the American
weed Market is heady Bros who buy
expensive [ __ ] dab torches and and pu
puff Coes and [ __ ] and like they love
the newest greatest drop from [ __ ]
compound and [ __ ] whoever else like
whoever the big name of the day is you
know yeah they're only like I don't
understand how The Connoisseur portion
of the market is run by people who love
the most midy [ __ ] possible even if it's
grown well it's just like well dude
that's not that great of weed like yeah
it was tasty but like like I want to get
[ __ ] up like I think people forgot
that the point of this is to not smoke
weed all day and not get high it's like
no I want to take one bong rip and like
sit down for four hours and like forget
about like the hard [ __ ] in my life and
you know what I mean like that's like
what I go for at least with weed I don't
want to have to get up five times during
a movie to go re up again just to be
high and like suspend disbelief and
enjoy the show you know and so remember
when Exotics meant something from like
another country that you couldn't get a
hold of that was wild types yeah now it
zah like yeah defines cookies crap
almost like the
opposite almost the opposite exact for
sure smoking mirrors right in your face
boom yeah and so like I don't know yeah
I I hope people see through these games
that people are playing to take your
dollar out of your pocket and give you
the dumpiest version of Something
possible for and then ask them to say
thank you you know
like it's just like yeah I did want to
prompt you both so yeah I think you know
good nice reflection on the state of the
market uh at the end there but I think
we're also coming to an end uh with
regards to cookies was there anything
else that either of you wanted to say
about cookies um parting thoughts
parting
shots I mean for me it's just like
it's not it's not what that last episode
said it was and we were really doing a
good job of laying out like what it is
and what it isn't and it kind of got
crushed so that's why we had to redo
this so apolog you guys are sick really
great job by the way I think I think
what we got this episode is yeah more or
less what I wanted last time yeah yeah
yeah it was the direction it was going
so hopefully hopefully this will be a
good marker for it for people to return
to um another thing is like
I've read the comments every time we do
a cookies episode there's cookie Bros
coming in calling me a [ __ ] hater and
all that [ __ ] I was one of the first
people using it and breeding with it so
like while I don't enjoy it and love it
I have contributed to the problem and
I'm very transparent about that and um I
didn't realize I was doing it at the
time it took a while uh but I get it
like I get why some people like it
because it's novel and new to them but
from a breeding pers I speaking about
everything from a breeding persp
perspective and a lot of people don't
understand that because they don't breed
they don't make seeds they don't explore
different lines from a breeding
perspective it is a dead ass end and
that's all there is to it and whether
they like it or not I'm still gonna say
it y now that's all I have to say too is
that it's like we've got a
mean pretty but shitty girlfriend and
it's time to dump her yeah yeah you know
like so let's move on collectively as a
market and you know try and find some
cool new [ __ ] because it's out there
yeah very
nice okay uh Dan you got anything you
want to plug at
all um not really I've got some things
in the work so I have planned out I'm
still stuck in this remodel behind me um
once I get out of here and the next
couple weeks and get done and moved into
this place then um I can actually start
working again and uh doing cool [ __ ]
that isn't permanent marker hybrids so I
mean have you even talked about it on
the show that you're just doing your own
thing now no I haven't yeah no I got La
La Land yeah you got yeah I I got dumped
by the corporate Bros um oh well I was
too real apparently you're still too
nice to to like really pull weight on
him I still think we should Flex on but
you know that's up to you always at the
end of the day man like they've
tarnished their own reputation it's just
going to be fun watching them release
stuff that I made uh for probably the
next two plus years you know and so I've
already heard a few murmur from people
that I know that still work there and um
they're like oh did you make this this
was [ __ ] amazing and I'm like
yeah it's not like interesting to me
though none of the work that I did there
was interesting to me at all and so uh
I'm more stoked on the stuff that I have
going now and some of the projects that
I have planned for the near future and
so um yeah maybe maybe a seedline drop
um which I haven't done in years and uh
I don't know we're still fiddling around
with the reversal sprays and stuff so um
we got to get back on track now that
I've lost my workspace but I have
already built my new one so it's just
more a Time allocation thing so I'm
proud of how you handled it I I you know
like I've lost jobs where it's your
livelihood whether you loved it or not
it's your livelihood and you have to
make big changes and you handled it like
a [ __ ] man so proud of you yeah man
thank you no I mean I bought a house a
month before I got fir
yeah and I got to keep spending money to
like make it nice you know so it's like
one of those things where it's just like
yep but luckily I've already got new
work and uh uh out of the weed industry
and so it's much more rewarding and um
I'm already happier so all that matters
bro yep all right thousand what you got
but couldn't have done it I've got
gotten a lot of support from the
yeah um love you I don't think I have
too much to add yeah I'm uh by this
point Matt would have had an out well
Matt would have mentioned the 10K
subscribers thing so I'll just like but
in reality when we're recording this
this has just happened so bit of you
know timey wiy stuff um yeah so still
thinking about that still stoked about
that very satisfying I knew we would get
there of course it was just a matter of
when but yeah I'm stoked about that
um I wrote this really long nice thing
on Instagram by the way follow us at I
think it's what is it the. breeders.
Syndicate I believe that's the one that
I have now um or I'm sorry breeders.
syndicate.net we
put yeah we'll put it in the description
um IG sniped our page because people
obviously report us because what I say
conflicts with their money making and
that's how it goes you know um so we
lost everything that had to do with the
podcast on there but we do have the new
one up and uh I I wrote about doing like
a nice you know a a cool contest
giveaway with everybody who's following
on Instagram do something cool to you
know for the 10K subscribers on YouTube
do a do a contest there and then one for
the patreon as well something really
cool for all our patreon Discord people
just to celebrate like hitting 10K that
was a big big milestone and uh yeah I
mean thousand was the driving part
behind that like I that just seemed so
unrealistic when he first came in to
like 10 thou okay bro that'll be like
nine years whatever KCK around [ __ ] till
then you know but um so thank you for
that I just I did want to say I think uh
just quickly in the response to that
like I think when I started helping out
I just knew that all I had to do was
keep going for a bit longer and it would
work I just kind of was fully confident
that if we could still have some of our
good people around us and still make the
show and make it more sustainable that
we would just get there and I think we
actually doubled the subs in six months
I think um when I first started helping
we were at like four or 5K yep and so
yeah I I I I'm still pretty amazed that
we got there in half a year um but I was
also hoping that that's how long it
would take so yeah yeah no I mean like a
lot of people don't know but I was ready
to clock out like on the whole show I
was done I was like I'm not happy with
the direction I'm not happy with what's
being said I'm not saying anything uh
and it wasn't just about me it was just
a lot of misinformation and I couldn't
stop some of it and um I was done I was
really done
and without thousand the show wouldn't
exist right now and I could say that
confidently super confident I wouldn't
have kept doing it it would not be
consistent um I was done so that's why
we're here so yeah and I will say as
well like uh I'm also just a proxy for
people like Dan local ER uh little Hill
Kush of the Giants
peaches you know probably many other
people i' I've forgotten to mention but
you know
everyone everyone helped me too you know
so and helped us and so being able
to um get our friends on and and help
them support us was just huge as well
and I think once we made it more of a
group effort um it just changed the vibe
as well um yeah in a nice way I think
yeah made it easier for me too and it
gave me a lot more hope for for the
future Generations like I was jaded as
hell like it's really easy to get very
jaded and stuck in your ways and like
just being like I don't want to talk
about new stuff I don't want to meet new
people I don't trust anyone like it's
all gone bad every time every time
anything's grown it went bad so um it's
it's it's a nice surprise it's been
really awesome a great
experience so yeah with that for me um
we have the sub Rob drop on Riot seeds
um for those of you who don't know sub
Rob is like one of the most legit dudes
I know from IC mag back in the day San
Diego's finest him gryll his crew um you
know sour dub went through there gg4
went through there all the earliest [ __ ]
he did a a release of um the super
silver haze 98 cut cross to sour duub
and then a skunk dog S1 cross to sour
dub we're calling the uh SSA SSH super
silver Hayes cross to sour we're calling
it sssdh why because we
can snitch named it the other one and um
what else do we got we got pack doing a
new Blue Dream Drop soon and he's done
it on his own page so give him support
direct support he's got him out right
now go check him out um what else is
there by that time we should be having
the blueberry coming out fairly shortly
after this episode airs um that's my
proudest blueberry work was the
blueberry stuff in Cross that's means um
we took it another generation and I'm
super stoked on it I'm super stoked and
I and I got to stoke someone else out
who is a super blueberry head from
Oregon and he didn't believe in any of
that that like it was really possible
that this blueberry existed and he's
like dude I doubted you and I am mind
blown so that that's the kind of [ __ ]
that Stokes me out when like you know
you can bring something back to someone
like that and have it be true breeding
in a line where you can pop you know
seven seeds in they're all like that you
know yeah um so that be out uh I know
there's more I don't know um there's
come there there yeah yeah um oh yeah
yeah there's a lot more to come um the
the Resurgence of TGA the spa space dude
uh crosses coming out probably around
that time too uh that this airs or
shortly thereafter um go check out ger
by seeds he's our homie out in Australia
um we have lifted seeds uh California
takes credit card we have righty Co
Europe a very very trusted good friend
out in Europe for the people are having
trouble getting seeds into Europe um
what else do we got uh we got my
spray Dan's got a spray soon that we're
gonna be marketing somehow someway what
else do we got I think that's mostly it
I don't know oh go join our Discord the
patreon Discord is where we all hang out
we shoot the [ __ ] um we watch fights
together we do all kinds of stuff it's
it's pretty awesome it's a great
Community um I've met some of some of
the best friends that we have now there
just by people coming in and hanging out
and it's a safe space and if people are
[ __ ] we kick them out because that's
just how it rolls you know even if they
threaten to kill
me yeah there is that and uh with that
you guys got anything else or is that it
no that's it that's it for me thanks
everyone thanks everyone lots of
love want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it
out