[Music]
foreign
ER Syndicate where we explore the
history of a clandestine scene Through
The Eyes of the folks who lived it I'm
Matthew owner of ride seeds I'll
occasionally be joined by my co-host not
so Josh breeder and grower from
Mendocino
welcome to the underground
[Music]
now what's up dude
I exist
yo you look like you're not dead yet I'm
definitely not dead good deal good deal
not good I'm in need of a haircut
so
what's up with the third party uh
waiting for him wait we're waiting for
him for a few minutes I should talk to
him he'll be on
fantastic yeah so I was just telling
everyone we're going to be going over
the Forum era post overgrow so 2006
roughly and on and uh I was explaining
how there are a lot of forums still up
that were around during that time like
the farm
um I see mag
troll it up some of the some of the
others that came around that time
um but there are a lot that are not up
and people that like to pretend that
they're around back then
often reference the ones that are still
up that they can go back and like reread
and pretend like hey I was I was there I
knew what was going on but they're
missing like 90 of the conversations
that were going on because those aren't
even accessible any longer
one of one of the things I notice about
that era uh is that
you know a lot of times we catch people
on stuff
um because people go back to [ __ ]
yes and they read uh you know threads
and things like that to pick up years
and tidbits and information that like
make their their stories sound better
yeah but they weren't there to know who
was who or like who to take seriously or
what was misinformation even then yeah
you know and so a lot of times it's a
tell
it's a big tell but to someone that
never read any of those forums you can
come out and confidently start jabbing
about a bunch of stuff yeah and sound
like you were there yeah um not I'm not
gonna say anybody's name but uh someone
made a post the other day that obviously
was not around on the forums and said
you know X person got cloned from y
person got cloned from Z person and it
was just super off like the most off it
could be I mean we I'm that's learning
from me I try we try not to name names
when it's not but it was pretty funny
the chain of custody yeah that was
asserted
you know you you just had you just had
to laugh at a certain point but yeah I
will say even back then
like uh you know I don't know exactly
know how to describe it but I would say
that like like overgrow even had some of
the best commentary but also some of the
worst
like you kind of the forums really
helped figuring out what you were doing
if you already went in there with some
connection and some ability to discern
yeah you know cannabis world was a
little bit more like where the adults
gathered yeah uh over a girl you could
have like everyone from like some 17
year old kid [ __ ] posting you even
though we didn't use that term back then
yeah to like Chimera and Sam Skunk Man
and phds and breeding talking [ __ ] in
another in another area of it yeah so it
really was like a cross-section of weed
in America
my main my main thing would be like I
would compare that to like grass City
from my era grass City and um roll it up
we always call it a troll it up but
those two were like what everybody would
say like that's where everybody
everybody had an account on those pretty
much because that's where everybody
started during that era and then slowly
you'd see people migrate but then those
the ones that hung out in that area kind
of never really seemed to go anywhere as
far as their knowledge or making any
Headway with anything really that's how
I saw it yeah I mean and you know it it
should be said too that like you know
there was different different forums had
different
I don't know different ethics maybe is
the best way to put it yeah you know
some some were more lightly moderated
and things got left up
um you know obviously like hate speech
and and various other aspects was was
eliminated
um you know or but a lot of times you
know unlike IG or whatever
um you know if you didn't like the
threads got let they might get locked if
arguments got too heated but they would
typically be left yeah where in today's
environment on IG a lot of times people
just get rid of it yeah oh yeah they'll
just it's all it's all uh what do you
call that curated it's all curated as
soon as it starts going off the rails or
as soon as they start seeing information
they don't want out there yeah um
they'll just delete comments or they'll
delete the whole thread or they'll turn
off comments yeah right away
um you know and then you know I see mag
you know there was you know there was an
In Crowd and an out crowd
you know definitely I was the app crowd
I I think I had a record uh for being
the person most banned from every forum
and it it I think that I mean I even had
my own forums back in the day that
people rocked on you know it got bad I
mean it was interesting in the sense
that like in the beginning an overgrown
cannabis world and stuff I was super
excited and I got on there to share
information without with a bunch of
people
um and then you know but I was always
nervous about doing any kind like you
know I lived in Mendo or whatever so I
didn't really need to like meet new weed
people yeah but I liked learning what
other people far away knew yeah but a
lot of people used it in the DMS to
trade clones and do all this type of
stuff I never really did that I was more
like an in-person kind of kind of guy
yeah um and then when obviously When
Heaven Stairway got in trouble and they
shut all that down yeah I got scared
so
um you know this era that we're going to
talk about like 2006 on it really is CSI
and Matt's era yeah it really is where
you know I might have been lurking a
little bit and poking around here and
there
um and even some other friends of ours
that aren't going to join like uh our
buddy high and Lonesome oh yeah yeah you
know there there were some people that
were that were extremely active in that
area sure and know a lot of the the who
you know who was who was a jackass who
who was kind uh who was a problem back
then you know where stuff came from
and one of the interesting things about
weed is that it reinvents itself every
five or ten years yeah so you get all
these new people coming in and people
get to Rebrand themselves yeah now it's
happening every six months it seems yeah
well it's modern fast turnover yeah
modern marketing I mentioned that I
mentioned this before but it was kind of
like what the uh what the old deadheads
told me about how dead tour used to be
before the Grateful Dead had Touch of
Gray a big hit yeah where it was small
everybody knew kind of got vetted in you
know things didn't change that much and
then
um you know oh my God Big Ups to Danimal
okay so then and then and then there was
a top they had a top 10 hit and
literally hundreds of thousands of new
people showed up yeah and how do you
assimilate them into your community that
fast
yeah thank you yeah you know it becomes
difficult so a lot of times like
Old-Timers or whatever they feel
overwhelmed
because like the Norms of their
community and what they could expect you
know and instead of being like a
respected Elder somebody's like who the
[ __ ] is this guy yeah why do I have to
listen to you
yeah you know where before when it was
smaller like those people might have had
respect yeah yeah it's a much it did get
very different and I want to say it
wasn't quite at cookies where everything
took a big swing but it wasn't much long
after cookies came around that that the
Forum the whole idea of forms kind of
changed but I think that also had to do
with Instagram which is also why cookies
kind of even got even more blown up I
think uh social media
um yeah the kind of the difference
between the I would say the forums were
mostly writing with some pictures
where Instagram flipped it 180 degrees
to being almost all pictures with a
little bit of writing yeah so you see
some of these old write-ups that people
have and their paragraphs and you know
they're like a small essay yeah
right where people ask me stuff all the
time on IG and it's really hard because
it's like what are you going to write a
novel in the comments yeah yeah it's
kind of looks like you're trying to
write something that's like this long
like what can I yeah it's like a haiku
yes how can I get my my thing across in
like you know x amount of syllables or
four sentences yeah yeah you kind of
have to especially if you're on Twitter
right and then and then you end up and
then you end up leaving out a lot of
nuance and detail we're on the Forum era
people could like write three or four
paragraphs each back and forth and some
like empty could write really really
just
bad really bad un illegible stuff for
paragraphs and paragraphs I mean when
you write paragraphs you really realize
why we invented punctuation yeah for
sure you know why we invented paragraphs
in the first place spacing periods
commas all the various aspects it really
helps because yeah you know one one of
the things that hurts you online is that
um Nuance gets lost yeah does are you
being sarcastic
yeah being funny what's your body
language
you know all those types of things
you know
um yeah that was actually a good point
uh you know in the overgrow era digital
cameras
um you know didn't exist yeah
I mean I was talking I was actually
talking about that in the in the one
that you missed because you were you
know you were otherwise occupied where
it was like people documenting their
stuff really Advanced a lot more when
digital cameras came out oh yeah and
then exponentially wants uh phones had
cameras yeah once phones had cameras
it's all bets off the era where you had
to get your own stuff developed
that's unsadly it's not oh yeah I can
only imagine it's not very documented I
mean I was it I was at csi's house I
don't know half a year ago or something
like that we were looking through a
couple of boxes of his um uh Polaroids
right yeah but they fade yeah that cat
sucks
you know and maybe if he would have kept
them in some kind of like a perfectly
sealed environment with the right
humidity or something like that you know
but yeah you're looking at Polaroids
from 95 or six or seven or whatever and
a lot of them the colors are bleeding
into each other and it's hard to make
it's not
it's not you know it's not shark
yeah
you know yeah that sucks that sucks bad
I would have never guessed that until he
told me that yeah I mean you know he's
got a couple shoe boxes full yeah and I
was busting his chops to get him [ __ ]
scanned I was like you got to get those
scanned at least for history he's like
don't do any good
I mean I you know I had my I had my my
uh my first daughter in 09 you know and
I think and I can look back on my phone
I think you know the first real camera
on an iPhone came out in 08
oh wow wow I don't remember yeah later
wait
you know and and that's kind of that
that was a revolution in itself oh I'm
sure because then you can just pull it
out of your pocket and be like there's
my weed plant click
it's always amazing that with all these
cell phones we don't really see many
like real documented UFO picks I know
I'm it's kind of off tangent but I just
thought about that
well I will say as a as as a you know
somebody who's pulled a lot of tarps in
their day
that you know a lot of times when you
pull tarp on you you're doing light
depth you're you're pulling tarp at six
or seven o'clock at night right yeah and
then you go back out there after dark
which in June might be 9 30 or 10
o'clock at night right so pull the tarp
off so everything can breathe because
you only want to darken it for as much
as you need to right oh yeah and you
don't want to trap in all that moisture
and all that right so you got to go out
there and you know Mendo or whatever in
the woods and sometimes I would see the
most beautiful Skies the most beautiful
moons just yeah and your phone could not
show you what my eyes could see oh yeah
for sure I would take I would take you
know pictures and you know and it would
just never and I'd go online and look
how do I take better night photos yeah
and it's just not a camera with like a
nice lens and you know the ability to
like you know it's just not it's just
meant to show dicks and tits that's all
you're supposed to be taking pictures of
fellas ladies you know and yeah and so
you know there's there's an aspect to
that where it's like I can bet like if
you can't see like nobody can imagine
how beautiful this full Moon is tonight
yeah and you can't capture that well
how are you gonna capture like I'm sure
there's like this is there's a weird
thing in the sky it's really not rich
you know especially back in 08 or 09 how
am I going to pull out my two or two and
a half megapixel camera yeah on my phone
yeah I'm gonna like capture it
no you know it took a long time for
phones to even begin to catch up to like
what 35 millimeter could do you're
busting my skeptical comments not so
you know refreshing my skepticism
I fully believe that there are aliens
I just disbelieve most people that tell
try to tell me a bunch of facts about
them yeah yeah there are I just don't
know if they've ever been near Earth you
know like I I have I that that's where
my skepticism comes in when people start
writing getting like very long YouTubes
about all kinds of specifics you know
yeah
I get weird yeah yeah I mean
I'll say this you know and then Caleb
and then he's officially [ __ ] late
yeah but
um you know when we were talking about
the the early the early 2000s or
whatever I you know I did that whole
episode when you weren't here yeah I was
hunting so hard for old stuff then stuff
from the 80s stuff from the 70s hell
even stuff from some of the 90s yeah and
it was a royal [ __ ] and nobody cared
about it and I and I searched for years
and years and years and you know like we
have a pretty good network of friends
yeah you know and it was really hard and
now within the last five years as
ancient stuff has become popular
and I'm not please don't take this the
wrong way if anybody's holding anything
but I've never seen so much like 79
blueberry 72 you know Brotherhood of
eternal love Acapulco Gold you know 74
oaxacan you know this that like all
these 70s and 80s strain all the famous
strains of your yeah hey
hey
it's not dark it's just blur
red
camera on purpose
you know
so he flew a lot on the camera
but wait the sun's going down so you
know
good to see you dude thanks for showing
up right right
so yeah we were just talking about
um the different you know what was kind
of going around post 2006 it was the end
of the overgrow era end of the Cannabis
World era and maybe maybe uh you could
talk about some of the things that you
saw during those those uh that integral
period between the end of overgrow and
the beginning of things like the farm
foreign
what kind of strains were people [ __ ]
with around then what was the hot [ __ ]
uh are are you talking about like 06 on
oh six to like 006 to 08 somewhere in
there yeah yeah yeah yeah I mean I think
that's when chemdog really started
becoming popular yeah
um Kim d uh came out I I think I
honestly think that that's the year uh
you know Mass G uh posted up on icy mag
although yeah that threat is gone oh is
that thread going I did my research I
think it's like is that the the creation
of sour D1
no no no that was the overgrow that was
okay
so yeah that that's well long gone
unless somebody has a archives yeah who
would have that [ __ ] I don't know
so do you remember like around overgrow
what kind of the strains uh what kind of
strains were mostly popular around that
time like in the in that end of overgrow
era
Amsterdam strains the Dutch Dutch [ __ ]
yeah
BC stuff yeah it was kind of it was kind
of like a lot of the stuff that
um was at some of those Ron parties
yeah yeah yeah right we're we're
actually we're we're Caleb and I first
met um you know it was a lot of White
Widow and blueberry and
um a lot of the work coming out of
Switzerland was big then so like the
Sweet Tooth the blockhead the Louie
um uh genius
yeah you know
in c99 were around back then for sure
genius c99 you know I forget his genius
Apollo but you know the Apollo 11 and
13.
hybrids of all that stuff and it was it
was pre uh pre-reversals you guys hadn't
really started your Revolution yet so uh
it was all males well uh
I mean we were borderline starting it
that's yeah I was just kicking off I
mean hybrid Hyde was selling his exe way
back in like I don't know what O2 maybe
even earlier yeah over on a cannabis
world and uh I did my first you know
um real reversal in o6 the intentional
reversal intentional reversal I
one reversal where you know I took a
bunch of pollen from that Urkel back in
like 304 and uh yeah yeah that was oh
um and uh pollinated a bunch of stuff on
purpose yeah
but that that was just that freak thing
so yeah now it's counted up it can't it
kind of counts it counts it does count
it was with intention yeah yeah I mean
they're they're I did have some friends
that I mean we didn't use I did we
didn't know anything about any of the
any of the chems you could spray on
Plants but people used to try to torture
their plants to get them to free if it
was if you knew it could herb sometimes
you could put it into too small of a pot
you could let it get dry you could beat
it up a bit you could try to collect see
if it could throw some that was like the
that was like our our way of
you know right can you beat it up enough
to get something off it remember uh
Soma's Soma's way you just flare them
out for like 80 or 90 days and get a
couple bananas yeah
rhodolization yeah yeah
and I don't know where you got that term
from for it but yeah I remember yeah
yeah he's a special guy actually I did
like as when his book came out or
whatever I do like the Soma beds
I don't know that they were interesting
they were interesting they're just
they're just deep indoor beds on Wheels
you know is basically what they were
um you know with with you know some
drainage in the bottom and some layering
you know maybe they have some rocks and
they have some like and then they have a
layer of of uh ground cover or something
and then you put soil on top and and
they have never seen
huh they had the air tubes on them in
all four corners where the air came down
to the lower Roots you would put like
big pieces of PVC with holes drilled in
and you would put those on the side and
those would go all the way in the
corners to the bottom yeah so that you
would actually and that would connect to
the gravel at the bottom so that you
could bring air yep yeah yeah it wasn't
the worst idea no no no I've done that
much and especially for well it's not so
much you had to go trees you know I mean
you know look now look at look at a
bunch of you could you could actually
grow a bed with it you know homie Style
with 25 or 30 plants if you wanted yeah
right right right you know and then you
didn't have to worry about individual
ones dying right right because you just
water the bed and everything stays alive
oh yeah I used to use those no drain
beds way back in a 2000 or so and no
drain beds it's just shallow like six
inch deep beds you know
how'd that worked out
I did pretty good yeah yeah yeah
um definitely some interesting stuff
that was back in my not so organic days
it's not so organic
organic not so organic
I mean I I used I used to know this used
to be pretty funny where I used to know
a lot of guys in Mendo that were organic
like April through August
and then come August they're like not or
September they're not quite seeing their
buds get as big as they want
and then they figure like well what's
one big tub of pink powder gonna really
do to my organic it's it's basically
organic yeah yeah a little just a couple
a couple doses of the zero fifty Thirty
it's gonna get me where I need to be and
it's gonna make it happy and I've been
organic for five months already you know
so it'll all flush out at the end and
it's definitely still organic uh yeah
that stuff was rough
yeah bud blaster
three cheers for grow more yeah
but Blaster was the was the the Canadian
heady version yeah
it was Canadian it was it was it was it
was one of those you know powdered
whatever it was all this it was all the
same there was a bunch of people that
came out with zero fifty Thirty and
tried to make it seem like their Sierra
50 30 was special
the one thing I'll say about the the bud
Blaster is that
they had a they had their own special
grinder
so their powder was super fine and it
actually dissolved
some of the cheap stuff you get there in
like a thousand gallon tank or whatever
and you're up on a ladder and you're
dumping stuff like that in there and
then you get some softballs at the
bottom that you're like wondering how to
hit with a stick to break up
because it wouldn't actually dissolve
yeah you know all right so but that's
off topic you know I suppose you should
probably ratchet back around
um so we gotta convince we gotta
convince Caleb and Matt to talk because
this is really their Arrow yeah this is
0.607-0809 this is not my online
presence right so the various characters
the various things that were going on
the the stuff that was happening it's
pretty much this is when these two
uh you know uh CSI used to be known as
uh uh you know white trash redneck
but yeah you know but that but that's
where I mean
you know uh archive was doctor or the
doctor
yeah right yeah yeah you know it's where
a lot of the Monica a lot of the oldest
nicknames and monikers
uh people still kind of reference each
other like by some of those first names
yeah
I don't know nobody's real name
you didn't need to ain't no purpose it
is you know yeah and unlike IG you
didn't you never a lot of these people
you never saw
what's his name I'm like I don't [ __ ]
know where the [ __ ] would I
would ask him that you know that's just
weird yeah she thinks I'm a freak for
not knowing anybody's first names after
all these years I'm like I don't [ __ ]
know
I don't know who am I gonna do his taxes
for him what the [ __ ] I need to know
that for
it was very it was very similar to that
on like on detour and stuff like that
because everybody you know everybody had
a nickname yeah yeah
you know everybody had a nickname so
um
but you know I mean maybe maybe you guys
could talk about like you know uh who
who who were some of the big I don't
want to say the word influencer maybe
but who are some of the people that were
sort of like driving the conversations
who were you excited to hear you know
posting on stuff like and then maybe
just like how hard it was to get
information back then because a lot of
these forums you know you guys were
talking about the chem dog you know
there was an aspect where the reason why
you know somebody like you know skunk VA
has his name or chemdog 101 or any of
these things is because at some form or
another on icmag or whatever it was the
first time these things started getting
argued about and debated
Yeah by people outside and a lot of
times
what happens too is that these things
become references because then you've
got this guy comes out and says this
thing on I see mag at this year
and then three years later on whatever
on roll it up let's say he's saying this
and now on IG he said this and this
you know and they always they always
want to be like this is the most current
story this is what you should believe
yeah yeah and in some cases those forms
don't exist anymore and they're very
fortunate that they don't and you know
one of the one of the ways that uh CSI
got his reputation as inspecta is he was
really good at at using your own words
against you
but I just mean in the sense of someone
would like confidently say this this
this this and this and then he would be
like well why did you write
in your own words that faster this right
how do you make these two things come
together I've got a bunch of swerve
quotes I can share oh yeah
you know and and that's a lot of things
most people probably don't even know who
swerve is but there's been there's been
a bunch of people
you know that come the you know flashing
the pants that come and go yeah they
come up they have their moment they they
they spew a bunch of [ __ ] they make a
bunch of money all of a sudden their
stories start to implode
right yeah
and you know and in some cases they
Rebrand themselves
and so again to the to the new batch
right right you know
um who I looked up to is going to be a
lot different than maybe who Caleb
looked up to because when I first
started coming in it was way different
than when Caleb started coming in you
know so who like who are you looking up
to during those years or who who is who
do you think was influencing really well
that that had some respect during those
years
um I mean I liked you know just Just for
information you know alone I liked Joe
brand I liked uh you know chem dog math
G uh
uh you know skunk VA yeah and then on
like the the OG side of things you know
I was I always liked uh you know big
Ricky uh he was old family red back then
I actually a lot of people don't even
know but uh I named my old family purple
my first TK hybrid kind of after his old
handle old family red you know oh I
didn't even know that that's cool
yeah I gave him a lot of credit
um you know Chrome that was those were
the years Chrome was starting out with
the white you know yeah he actually was
growing some of my my hybrids
um and then he introduced the white when
he was growing them so yeah that's when
that started
um
I I think I was mostly into Bubba's ogs
and chem dogs back then yeah but uh
what what were your your main main
interest though
so when I popped in you know like Shanti
baba
um was still pretty big and and still
had a good name a lot of the stuff I was
looking at when I came in was was Dutch
stuff I really didn't focus a lot on
Americans at the time because it just
didn't I wasn't hip to it you know I
hadn't right when I came in I wasn't hit
to the fact that all those dudes were
white labeling and most of the Americans
were making their seeds or Spanish or
actually back then I don't even know who
was making the [ __ ] seeds you
know right but yeah I mean it was very
different I mean uh Greenhouse hadn't
been totally trashed it was still kind
of under the radar for new people at the
time that that they were doing anything
you know untoward DNA was massive during
those years uh they were why I started
doing six seeds a pack because their
[ __ ] was six seeds a pack and they were
the ones selling the most so I was like
okay I guess that's what you do you know
what I mean right um yeah and then sub
cool of course it just started [ __ ]
taking off and I was fortunate that I
met Sunny Chiba very early on so I
learned very quickly oh maybe that guy
isn't someone I should be looking at for
breeding tips you know right right it
took me a while but I got it but yeah
that's it was it was a much different
take
yeah it's interesting then because
that's kind of when everybody first came
out of the Shadows yeah and you could
walk out of the Shadows with any stories
you wanted
about yourself or the strains or
whatever else and a lot of times you
were the only person
um you know from Sam's man on
yeah you were the only Pro you were the
only person telling the story about
those strengths right right I mean do
you remember huh the audience was so
small finding people who are actually
there you know was was very difficult
yeah it was it was a lot smaller than
now I just don't you think people that
that came later can grasp how small the
community was
and how slow information was
now it's pretty rapid fire
right you know and a lot of people
connect all the time
um oh yeah somebody said crunch bubble
you know uh that guy I mean he that guy
used to move massive amounts of what was
it Blue Dot
through the third floor in Oakland you
know he had all those warehouses of 600
watt hps's on hydro tables
bumping out a bunch of stuff for third
floor but it was you know what what's
funny about that guy is that some of
those pictures were like some of the
first Warehouse scenes that people were
willing to like throw up on IG on on the
internet yeah most people were growing
in closets or bedrooms or greenhouses or
in the woods or wherever and all of a
sudden you see a 40 lighter
right and for a lot of people that was
the first time
right it might look rudimentary now
yeah now but yeah but even just then 05
or 06 or something like that you know
finding people and I think too that like
what most people don't understand maybe
is that a lot of the a lot of the
Breeders like that got famous later like
a couple people on the show or whatever
like almost all the Breeders were
European or American or Canadian yeah
right and the people that were working
breeding in America were generally doing
it through friendship circles
there was a lot of trading and Via DM
amongst friends and amongst
contemporaries it wasn't like like on
you know at least from what I remember
it wasn't like oh I've got a big drop
coming next Friday here's the fifth
here's the 15 here's the names I made up
for him here's the hybrids here's where
you can get them here's how we're gonna
sell them all
it was like you know you'd trade scenes
when you saw people or if people were
trade selling them via DM or something
like that like but it was different
um I remember as far as Americans went
there was not a lot of Americans doing
direct sales on websites you would never
really see that like it was all done you
know DMS or like on weird little auction
sites they were floating around but
other than that there wasn't a really
good way to Market yourself as an
American breederer without mostly giving
seeds away to people I mean did you have
that experience CSI
I I didn't get involved in any of I
wanted to back in the 06 08 era I looked
into it but
um you know I was I was still way too
paranoid to do any of that stuff yeah
I I should have done it you know like
you know DNA and sub cool and hell even
swerve you know yeah
you know uh I mean all those guys you
know made huge names because there
wasn't competition yeah there was no
competition you didn't really have to
have a whole lot of talent to be very
successful so what you said Mr Soul
handled all of sssc in the 80s
foreign
well you know so I mean what's
interesting about that is that you know
there's been a lot there's been a lot of
talk about American sssc right yeah and
you know Matt and myself got to
interview uh the owner uh who was very
cool and you know all that kind of stuff
got put to rest yeah hard it wasn't
there wasn't any American help no but
not for maneuver but it goes but it goes
to show how you know in our world you
can kind of step out of the shadows and
be like oh I mean there was a lot of
people uh that you know they came out of
the shadows and they were the first time
that people were like you know oh I'm I
this is my cut
yeah and then it turns out that they
just got the cut early
yeah but they got a few years of like oh
if you want to use my cut you got to
give me 50 of the proceeds of the seeds
or you gotta pay me or you gotta this or
you got a that it's my work it's my my
my and then it comes out later that they
just got it from these other people
early but they were the first one to go
public
right you know and a lot of times what
happened is is that the first person to
go public
um you know got credit
yeah
yeah you know
um you know they got credit and their
story was the story for a minute and
sometimes other people would get upset
and get online and start you know I mean
I actually think that's kind of what got
uh you know you were talking about uh
Kim that's kind of what got cam online
was you know skunk VA got online a bit
you know and started talking about
different things
and then people were like oh my weed's
famous I should talk about it
that got Joe brand and and Peabody and
other people that hadn't really met up
or like even linked or even realized
what was going on after 15 years to
connect
right because of stories 707 seed bank
uh Shabbat he's the one who you know got
uh skunk VA on to overgrow and icy mag
to actually post about that stuff
otherwise I think there'd be a
completely different chem dog history oh
yeah if he hadn't done that you know do
we remember what the very very first
claim of the chem dog seat not
necessarily the first one people
remember but the very first claims of
Kim dog who was the first one to claim
that string was it even Greg or were
there other people popping up as it was
getting popular going that's mine I've
read that [ __ ] I don't remember anybody
claiming it
um lots of people claiming they had the
91 or oh yeah yeah sure and it's just
like well I don't know how all these
different cuts could be the right one oh
you know because it's purple that's how
you know when it perks
I I saw a few chem dog cuts and they
they uh uh some of them look like a mass
Super Skunk chem dogs yeah
but that that just basically means
somebody bought some weed that was was
called chem dog and it had some seeds in
it and whatever had pollinated that chem
dog you know chem dog's not a bad
hermaphrodite just by itself I mean not
so nice
you know no and so usually if you find
seeds in your chem dog you know it's
been pollinated by something else
yeah well there was there was also a
thing too that was that was really
confusing I think and this isn't
anything against Greg or chem dog but
you know it's it's like for people that
want specific lineages
he was pretty famous for you when you
buy weed you're buying chem dog weed
from chemdoc
it didn't really matter exactly what it
was
it was weed from chemdog and so I think
that created confusion too because
everyone was like oh it's this one
specific thing
you know
um but it really was chemdoc yeah just
branding I mean back then branding was
branding you know it was it was it was
early it was an early form of branding
yeah for sure you know and people
weren't and a lot of these guys were
young and nobody knew especially then
when things first started getting famous
I don't think anybody knew that some of
these strains were going to be so
lastingly famous
so a lot of times they wrote down
various stories or this or that and they
didn't really expect it to get become
part of Canon or become part of the the
fabric of the tail
and then they have to look back and
defend it
you know
um and you know it's hard for people
sometimes to say you know my memory was
a little that's what I remembered at the
time
you know after more after more
information came out and I talked to
more friends I kind of revised a little
bit because other people had it's hard
for people to say that a lot of times
people would dig in their heels
yeah and then you've got two or three or
four versions of the story and you're
trying to figure out which one works
which one is the most believable
right right you know what what's your
favorite wildest story
um from The Forum errors that you knew I
mean you that that you knew was kind of
like that's too [ __ ] stupid to even
be possible do you have any that stick
out where you're like that was a bold
[ __ ] clave and really what wonky
what comes to mind when I say that uh
okay so I hate to keep bringing up my
boy swerve
it doesn't really have a whole lot to do
with him but the guy he got pretty much
most all of his early OG cuts from in
like 0607.
um this guy
uh had an account on icmag and then he
made up another account and I think this
was an 07.
and uh he made up another account
pretending to be his own Mentor you know
with all the same spelling errors all
the same you know type Styles all that
and
he made a whole thread on it and acted
like you know he was the original
creator of the OG Kush blah blah blah
and his boy right here his little
student you know he's he's best student
I ever had and four of our boy and we we
hooked him up we laced him with all
those those cuts we've held since the
80s
yeah that there's still that story on on
uh icy Mac it's still oh my God you know
and I'm I'm up in there with a bunch of
other clowns just laughing away
stupid you know but that that one right
there was it was pretty much the tops
for for me back in those days I got one
for you I got one for you uh little old
lady with Asian fantasy oh that was a
really good one too I like it was a good
one yeah yeah that one was was it uh
there was a string called Asian Fantasy
Made famous I think I think it's fair to
say about the can of Bible Jason King
pretty much made that strain very much
so yeah known it wasn't a well-known
strain I don't think was it no no no no
no
and you know he he talked about the
Rarity and how this guy never lets it
out blah blah blah few years later
um a person that we we know who it was
but I don't think he'll ever admit it
right went on and tried to say that she
was the the wife of the man who held
Asian fantasy and he has died and she
wants to get those genetics out there
you know and ended up I think he's
pretty sure it was NYC kid
um kind of big upping himself trying to
give himself some provenance on a cut he
never had access to well we don't
honestly we don't know that part of it
because
who
have you or anybody ever seen this Asian
fantasy keyword fantasy outside of the
candle Bible and NYC kid and his crew no
I mean it's kind of a fancy yeah yeah
and yeah and in fact African black magic
I mean there's some there's some
pictures of it or whatever but I mean
Jason King even talked about how homie
wouldn't give it out to anyone and you
know was it was a massive hoarder of it
you know and so there's an aspect to it
there too where it's like people people
can hoard something so much that it
doesn't become famous
yeah right you know because nobody ever
sees it like before before this forum
time that you were talking about there
was probably like you know four or five
people or something in California that
had the chem 91. oh yeah and someone
just said I have Asian fantasy s1s from
th Gods so he's still doing it Go NYC
kid you go but yeah I mean it was like
one of those things where like if you
know if if OG Kush if some of the if
some of these famous things don't slip
out and people don't start cropping them
you know there was an aspect where it
was like for a long time there was only
four or five garages pumping chem 91.
mm-hmm yeah so like every you know so
how much weed is that not very much it
doesn't really give you very much
opportunity to try it doesn't really get
give you an opportunity for like a fad
to you know like if OG hadn't snuck out
if all those guys hadn't been money
hungry down there in L.A and it had
snuck out it probably wouldn't have had
that kind of impact
yeah because it has to be there
you have to be able to get that even
even if you have to pay a lot for it you
do have to be able to access it
right so Asian fantasy is one of those
things where like it you know
um it never got out and then so as a
result of that it allowed scammers to be
like this is it
right and how could you tell the
difference
hey um
you know you you still you still buddies
with the with old Jason
Mr King
um I haven't spoken to him in a minute
but we're cool yeah he lives on Maui I
know uh I wonder if you can uh ask him
kind of maybe some because I talked to
him before I like met you met you yeah
you know he he uh he affirmed that you
know all my information was right and
then he was like where'd you where'd you
find all this stuff out you know
I mean he might know some some
background details that you know
definitely didn't make it into the book
about yeah I bet one of the one I've
been actually thinking about reaching
out and talking to him because one of
the things that's interesting is that he
probably has a [ __ ] ton of pictures
uh of weed from myself and my and some
and friends and then people that I don't
know obviously too but
um that didn't make it in the book yeah
because you know you might take you know
dozens or hundreds of pictures or
something and then two make it
yeah you pick a couple
um you know uh and and all that but he
um you know and I think I think the
Asian fantasy that he was talking about
was in Hawaii
I want to say I remember and I I could
be totally wrong so maybe I shouldn't
say it but I think I think Bodie knows
the Asian fantasy person maybe
I might be wrong hmm
oh no I'm gonna ask him so figure it out
I mean to me it's one of the it's it's
one of those like legendary strains you
know that like just never I mean you
know I'll mention another one do any of
you guys have any uh any um uh
experience with Elvis
yes yes but I don't know if it was I
don't know how real it was it was just a
cut called Elvis because there's some
really famous stuff out there that just
it was never in my crew never in like
the extended Circles of cruise and you
hear about them for a long time and it
got famous in various aspects but it's
just like you know I also thought I had
Albert Walker too though so there is
that you know like who knows who knows
never got it from a good source that
that could say yes this is where I got
it none of that [ __ ] and last one I had
I passed off to skunk bastard flex and I
don't think he backed it up and your
Albert Walker was the orangey one right
yep Diego Walker yeah good old day go
yeah
um
did you ever see the mothership come
through I can't remember if you said
yeah uh-huh yeah so I told this story
before but like it got mailed to one of
our spots uh-huh so uh Jason King's I
don't think it's Shady to say this but
his girlfriend at the time was this
chick named Rebecca yeah and she was
from Asheville area of North Carolina
and so she you know he used to Rave
about that cut all the time and so she
finally got some of her friends to send
it to us
yeah right and dude it was like uh our
Buddy Holly Lonesome has a terrible
story uh but
um it was kind of like that in the sense
where I was expecting to get this tiny
little box with some clones
and we got this box that was like you
know this big by two feet tall or
whatever and it was two Mothership
plants in one gallon pots with steaks
and each one was about 18 inches tall
in O3 or something like that and it was
like so all those pictures in the can of
Bible that you see of Mothership
those all came from those two moms that
got mailed to us yeah and then we mom
those out
and uh you know it got they got grown at
Eddie laps and they got grown to various
friends houses and stuff like that so I
actually had I actually I had the
mothership for four or five years I
think
um and uh it wasn't I think it was a
super unique plant uh it wasn't one of
them I didn't have it didn't have the
nicest flavor I didn't really like the
flavor that much but it had a pretty
cool high and it did this weird thing
where it would fall half over but then
hold itself up
so like you know how most branches if
they flop they flop it would like flop
but then it would like raise itself up
and it would grow sideways through your
garden
hmm almost kind of a little like train
wreck
it would yeah it would catch itself
and and just like and it had like these
it was a really odd sativa
um it had thin leaves and it was big
branchy thing
um but you know I mean I honestly like
compared to all the other [ __ ] we've
been talking about like Bubbas and chems
and you know super skunk it was it was a
little Mitzy
you know uh in all reality but it was
one of those things that probably like
was genetically very different
than everything else
so I like I like you know we like those
weird things yeah real quick to touch
back on Elvis since you were you were on
THC Farmers stuff for a long time right
Caleb or at least attentive to it
um
I was on the outskirts of the devil's
Harvest crew
um back in those days too and uh there
was there were some of those guys that
one circulated through that crew a good
bit and it it started uh I think erock
from maybe like I don't know if I should
say a stay eh that's a long time uh
you know uh I think he's he's circulated
Elvis for a while through there I
wouldn't be surprised if a doctor maybe
had grown it because he uh he was he was
real good buddies with a lot of those
cats and I mean the whole time I was I
was online I only I only traded Cuts uh
through the mail maybe uh I only
received cups through the mail twice I
think
um yeah like you know 40 50 plus you
know uh packages of cuts but I only
received twice I did all my other
business just in person up and down the
West Coast so that's me I'm very
remember I'm in person
do you remember uh Miss Elvis from the
farm
I wasn't very active on the farm at all
very very little it was a person who
showed like they were the main person
showing the the Elvis cut back then
there was something called like the pink
Cadillac cut and then there was the
Elvis cut
um that's that's the only person I ever
got it from but I never
they disappeared like not even a month
after giving it to me but they were the
ones that were always documenting it on
the farm but I never knew if that was if
it's just someone from that [ __ ] and
made their way through because they
disappeared so fast
was it super incensey
uh no it was exactly like what they
talked about like a vinyl smell
vinyl this artificial vinyl
hmm yeah not infancy at all
one of the things that's kind of
interesting about that era too is it's
kind of like the last era before like
the the Clone name dominance thing
started happening where everyone's
growing OG or everyone's growing sour or
everyone's growing all that kind of
stuff so there was a lot of these odd
strains you know not odd in the sense
that there's anything wrong with them
just odd odd random strains that were
easily sold you know and so they they
people liked them and they got traded
yeah you know people weren't looking
necessarily for like oh I need to get
this specific cut because I'm going to
be able to move it and it's going to go
for X price you know they were more
interested in like the legend or the
history uh or whatever of said cut or
the person behind it and you could get
on there and start talking about your
cut and all of a sudden drum up a bunch
of Interest
and especially like if we wanted to go
back
um you know when we were talking about
how small it was I mean think about how
revolutionary you know just some some of
Matt's favorite some of blueberry stuff
got you know and how it looked
there wasn't that much competition there
wasn't that much stuff outside of Europe
or Shanti or Scentsy or you know uh
Simon from Sirius or some of that stuff
like there wasn't that many American
breeders so the few people that were
doing it like like Mr Soul or or DJ
Short or whoever that we're willing to
to show their work I think it kind of
got like outsized
you know outsized impact
you know like Cindy 99 probably got way
more famous than it should have
[Laughter]
you know just to be just to be just to
be perfectly honest I don't think in
today it would have the same lasting
impact right no not today no it wouldn't
it wouldn't have it wouldn't have been
able to break through but it was like so
I do think because it is is like when
you try to think of an outdoor plant
that's fast enough and still considered
sativa to most people I think that it
would be very hard to find a replacement
for c99 that's at fast with those type
of high qualities and I think that also
had a major effect because it was it's a
perfect outdoor plant for blasting fast
you know and it could be grown indoors I
just mean it got like all his work got
real there wasn't that much competition
so there wasn't a lot of time to talk
about you know like not only Cindy 99
but like we're like the genius or the
Apollos or this or that or whatever or
like you know everybody got plenty of
time to debate the four or five things
that DJ released
yeah because there just wasn't that
there wasn't that many different things
you know there wasn't that many now
there's there's thousands of breeders
and so standing out is very hard then it
was like you know what was what was
there like you know a dozen big people
doing stuff
yeah it was a lot easier for people to
[ __ ] keep other people down too like
the ones at the top since there wasn't a
lot of competition and they they held a
lot of sway they could really cut
[ __ ] throats real fast and it
happened a lot too and it was a lot
easier to do that you know I would have
probably got cut then if I had even
tried to start back then
dude I I like I said I was banned off
every forum and it got to the point
where I was like [ __ ] this let me start
my own Forum like Mr Nice I I never got
banned from
um I got asked to leave after a picture
contest because the the right Berry
pictures beat out one of Mr nice's and
he thought that was kind of [ __ ] of me
to put it in
um but yeah all the rest of them it was
really hard because uh a lot of the ones
a lot of people that were running those
forums also had a seed company
right and most of those seed banks and
seed companies would eventually start
[ __ ] people and if you were one of
those people to speak up
yeah you're done you know they don't
want you around yeah I mean I I see mag
definitely had some of that aspect to it
too yeah there was The In Crowd in the
outcrowd you know for sure as as far as
that goes
I'm I'm just surprised that forum is
still alive after everything that went
on with it yeah see people somebody
talked about that people talk about 89
Super Skunk there was an 89 Super Skunk
one of one of the things that gets that
that annoys the hell out of me uh
honestly and this isn't to call out
Whoever has 89 Super Skunk but just in
general is like they'll take the first
year that something was ever released or
named and be like I have that weed from
a year or two before then yeah that's a
big problem like so the first time super
skunk ever got used was in the 1990s
seed bank catalog yeah that's when it
had a picture and that's when it had a
name that's when Neville released it
you know
um and so people were like oh I've got
the 89 super skunk
well how
you know and then they're like oh you
know then they got to come up with like
well you know it was all that
pre-release special [ __ ] because I my my
uncle was buddies with homie who gave it
down on special kick down or they'll be
like you know you know I got that 95 93
Scentsy star I actually have pictures of
that 1989 Super Skunk and they look
awful cookie-ish it's pretty pretty but
you know it happens all the time and
then you see a lot of these old Cuts
right now the years keep getting earlier
and earlier yeah
you know I mean one thing and this isn't
you know this isn't to you know
obviously uh bodies use this or whatever
else right
but there is no G13 hash plant in the 88
catalogs
no no it came out in the 89 catalog
for the first year 89 and 90.
you know but 88 is much better it sounds
nice
you know and I'm not trying to throw any
shade on it or anything like that
there's plenty of people that have found
nice weed and you know buddy made a
bunch of hybrids with it and it came
from ndn guy I think right yeah yeah uh
origin originally or whatever you know
he reproduced it but it's like it got
released in 89.
right right but everyone calls it the
great you know the 88
right close enough you know all details
like those that you know some of that
first piff some of that first stuff they
talk about
um they'll call it the Great 88. yeah
that [ __ ] got released in 89.
so there's a bunch of stuff out there
where people will be like this cut is
from a year or two before this line ever
got released here's a quick question
though I mean I have zero experience in
this uh because I was living in my you
know whole and Humboldt but um
uh you you were there so
or maybe maybe you were there years
later what was the possibility of them
doing uh releases of their seeds
um at the canvas cups
um absolutely so that is true it is
possible like for instance the first
Cannabis Cup I went to the was the Jack
Herrera cup uh and the whole thing was
themed on him right right and it was all
about like it was the whole like all the
festivities were all about the emperor
wears no clothes
and they released Jack Herrera seeds
um you know from uh uh in 95
94. yeah 95. they released them but they
it was you know it was late November
right
um but it wasn't in the catalog till the
following year
right so it was like literally it was
literally the first time for instance uh
Jack was dropped was at the camp was at
the Cannabis Cup
right in late November so I suppose you
could have gotten it Jack Herrera at
least six weeks before the year turned
right right you know
I mean uh
for example Salmon Creek big bud
um you know uh you know homeboy homeboy
from Salmon Creek you know he bought
those seeds at the cup the year it won
the cup and then smuggled 50 of those
seats home in his little belt you know
Hideaway belt thing
and that's you know his selection from
those uh Scentsy big bud seeds or
whatever is what made Salmon Creek big
bud
I mean that's that's definitely possible
a lot of times
um a lot of new seed releases would get
dumped in late November then because
because it was like an industry
Gathering right right and there was tons
of and honestly there was tons of custis
there
I ended up hating going to Amsterdam for
the Cannabis Cup I went three times and
then never again
mostly because it sucked
uh and the reason it sucked was that uh
Amsterdam is pretty far north
and so it's cold as [ __ ] in late
November there right so you can go in
summer and it's nice and it's beautiful
and you're on a bicycle and you're
cruising around all stoned or you can go
when it's sleeting and 29 degrees
and that's not as nice you know and then
all the best weed would get saved for
celebrities that were coming in and
who's who so there was worse weed to get
because it was all getting saved for you
know Snoop Dogg or you know Sam skunk
man's friends or you know whoever
whoever the High Times crew or whatnot
and then on top of that
you could buy tickets to go to the
Cannabis Cup out of High Times
right so you go to Europe on vacation
and the coffee shops are full with all
these dudes from Jersey and New York
yeah screaming about wanting to get the
best bud in the world so it's like you
you fly 12 hours away from your house
and you're surrounded by a bunch of
obnoxious East Coasters and there's not
as good weed and it's crowded and it's
cold and it's raining or it's snowing
and it's like I much prefer going there
in summer
you know just because it was nice and
chill
you know but it was like an event that
was like the it was it was an event then
you know
um and you know really like The Story
Goes you know uh Neville didn't even
want to release Jack Herer that year
um he didn't think it he didn't think he
didn't think it was done but they wanted
something new and hot that they could
call Jack Herer mm-hmm
and isn't the story of of [ __ ] uh
Cindy 99 that that [ __ ] dude bought
Jack Herer in a coffee shop and found
seeds in it
yep and then took him home and started
his whole cubing [ __ ] princess
whatever thing that he did I don't think
Rick did anything like that
story yeah you know he found bag seed
and uh in buds that he bought at a
coffee shop yeah yep yep yep you know
c99 and genius or are both uh Jack
Herrera at best hybrids
yeah and really like and you know I
think back then that was even earlier
like we weren't using the improper term
back cross yet or you know BX uh you
know they were talking about [ __ ]
wasn't it cubing yeah yeah it was it was
he was cubic you were cubicle you were
like [ __ ] and they had all those like
long-winded posts on on [ __ ] the
forums about what percentage and how
much it was increasing with everyone you
did and laying it all out you know yeah
there was some really bad breeder Tech
being shared that seemed Cutting Edge at
the time
people still repeat that [ __ ] [ __ ]
like like uh Mantra oh you gotta bat
cross it four times and you can that's
as good as an S1 that's a clone man and
I saw and I saw somebody talking about I
like the super silver haze better than
the Jack Herer
um the whole reason Super Silver Haze
exists is because
um Neville didn't feel like the Jack
Herer project was ready for prime time
he just released it due to you know Alan
and Ben dronkers from Scentsy we're
businessmen and so when he left he kept
working on it
and then a couple years later I think in
97 or something he they released mango
and Neville and Super Silver Haze
because he felt like you know they'd
actually gotten somewhere
right right right but they still did a
couple and I actually think that was the
last big release that Neville ever did
right
um but I mean I smoked that that super
silver haze cut because two I went in 90
I was basically like every other year
like I went 97 and 99 too to the cups
and those last two cups that super
silver haze was all over the place
because that was that was in that was
like the first and third year at one
it was like the hot [ __ ] over there
right right it really was it was the hot
[ __ ] I mean it was super there was afino
of it that went like 14 weeks
uh will the community let res back into
play uh Rez is doing his own thing you
know uh what most people don't know
about res and are are a couple of
buddies remind reminded me of not that
long ago was like before all the
[ __ ] with the with the law
enforcement and all that
um he was a dick online anyway
right big time he was a big time troll
jerk generally a pain in the ass to get
along with not a pleasant homie
yeah despite despite any of the rest of
the bowl whatever you want to believe
about you know all the mess that
happened legally or whatever uh he was a
he was an early troll
he was a jackass he had a huge ego
I mean he still does he he had a decent
level of intelligence which would have
been I think much more appreciated if he
hadn't had so much ego with it yeah a
little humid you know I mean not you
know a bunch of ego and a bunch of
rudeness
mm-hmm you know there was some root
there was some rude people you could put
up with a little bit better but they
were like borderline geniuses
right right right you know like Tom Hill
could be a real dick if you asked a dumb
question
I would know anything about ass being
rude that's yeah I put up with it you
know or or Sam skunk man he could be a
dick too because you know you get tired
of I've told the same story five billion
times right right you're gonna question
me
you're 23 shut the [ __ ] up you're a
[ __ ] you know yeah eat my dick you
know basically
yeah rude kind of rude you know but it's
hard it's hard to have patience
you know and let's face it right a lot
of us are weirdos
a lot of us don't have the greatest
interpersonal skills to begin with
you know yourself but it really is I
mean speaking for me I probably have a
little bit more than your average grower
just a bit yeah you know but a lot but a
lot of them it's like you know we're
kind of harsh edges people that live in
the Hills don't talk to people hang out
with plants and they're really good with
plants and they're not so good with
social interaction
right right so you put those people on
the forums and you put those people like
you know on IG or whatever and it's like
it's not the easiest thing
I did have an adjustment period that uh
I will admit I had an adjustment period
of where
I may have been a little meaner uh in
responses and talking to people a little
Snappy maybe a little bit of ego
you know it happens but some of us grow
into beautiful smiling faces like this
well I'm also still banned from breed
Bay for uh picking on sub cool it's also
it's also the way I look at it is like
you know I mean everybody has the
natural inclination sometimes but it's
like are you trying to get your point
across are you trying to [ __ ] argue
on the internet
right oh here's this dude who says his
dad created dog bud I remember that guy
he's trying to dox me I think I'm gonna
block him okay there you go I mean the
thing the thing about the one thing
we'll say about dog bud and then we'll
move on is that Joe brand and Peabody
were buying and selling weed on dead
Tour all the time for cash to go see
Dead shows right and this one weekend
they sold some weed and then they mailed
Greg some more weed
and then 15 years went by before they
even heard anything cool came out of it
uh-huh
right they literally they they never saw
chem 91 or anything like that until 0-6
until the reunion when the forums got
people back together they had no idea
they're on dead tour right they met this
you know you know these guys
uh Greg was in it was a teenager from
the east coast and they sold him some
weed in Indiana
right which was just one stop on summer
tour
and you're buying pounds and you're
selling eights and quarters and halfs
and ounces and it ran out and you buy
some other pounds and you just keep
doing that and you did that for a while
and one of these sales turned into
something
and now you want to hey 15 years ago do
you remember uh it was summer uh on dead
tour do you remember this one couple
pounds you had that you were hustling
for like a weekend
do you have any clear memory of that
because it's kind of important
well I think uh I think he might have uh
remembered just because he
um hit Joe brand up you know gee hit Joe
brand up again and had him mail him some
more weed I think right two ounces and
we don't even know if the seeds came
from the Deer Creek show
or the seeds came from the weed that Joe
sent him later
it's I from based on the stories I've
kind of deciphered I I think it it came
from the ones that was sent that one had
no seeds but then again we know geez
stories are a little up and down I mean
you know not to I like two of my
favorite cuts of all time coming out of
geez little rooms but I will say that
um all of us on this thing have tried to
uh have tried to interpret what he meant
by rejuvenating the 91 after it got
tired in 94.
them rejuvenate yeah the the
Rejuvenation he had to let it go and
rejuvenate it that's how you fix it from
seed and that [ __ ] never got explained
you know
um and so I don't I you know there's
when it when any time you have a
situation where you know we can even go
back and take you know like ancient you
know ancient Virginia skunk bud grown
for sssc or Mr Soul you know working for
sssc you know you you create these
ancient legends and it's like how do you
disprove them yeah in a lot of cases you
can't prove or disprove because they're
so old
well let's get back to the forums I got
a question yeah yeah
um what was the first place do you
remember where the first like seed bake
the first seed bank that carried your
[ __ ] when people could actually buy it
which one was it
well we don't talk about that okay so
it's an unmentionable
I ain't friends with that guy anymore
my fault that dude a little Loco yeah oh
okay gotcha
you gotta remember I didn't even uh
start my seed company until 2014. yeah
yeah I remember
yeah I I made I could say one thing is
that my buddy that I never mentioned his
name but Staten Island when we were
doing all the super dog work and we were
doing all those hybrids that made it
into the Cana Bible he had Big Dreams of
realizing that you could probably make
more money like off of an eight lighter
of seed than you could off an eight
light or a flower
and he saw what was coming I honestly
didn't believe him
you know I didn't think I didn't think
that we you would ever be able in
America to like package up and sell
enormous amounts of seed or anything
like that because at the time we were
making all this stuff and we were
literally giving it away to good friends
and stuff because we had more than we
knew what to do with and there wasn't an
outlet for it
um you know the era that that Caleb
talks about getting involved is one of
the earlier eras where you could really
actually start to sell it
it wasn't simple in the beginning even
even if you were an active breeder
finding out how to get it to the
community wasn't very simple
no at all you had to trust I mean like
even even with me I started the um
selling seats directly really early for
for a U.S person
um but when I first started you still
had to really put your trust in someone
in Europe for the most part if you
wanted any kind of traction for your
seeds if you wanted any
I mean you had to work with seed banks
for people they'd eventually know who
you are if the seed bank didn't care you
you probably weren't [ __ ] important
and that's where everybody looked at it
we were about to go into CSI after dark
yeah
but yeah I mean uh you know a good bit
of that was in the 90s
you know when DJ Short wanted to get his
blueberry seed out there he had to give
it away
to uh two different groups in Europe
yeah first he had to give it to Tony at
sag Martha and then he had to give it to
Dutch Passion I don't know if he
intentionally gave it away but I think
that's how it ended up working out I
think he did huh didn't didn't he
purposely give them to him and maybe he
purposely did I think he thought that he
would still retain all control and this
and that that's where he was probably
mistaken but in order for him to even
like get money for his seeds he had to
send them to an established seed bank
yeah in a different continent
that's how hard it was to move seeds
then
yeah but you know when he I think sag
Martha they had his seeds in what like
you know the mid 90s or something like
that
um
uh right around there yeah the internet
didn't even exist then really
right right
I did but uh
level that you were going to be able to
use it for that yeah yeah I think
overgrowth started in either 98 or 99
so like the first forums the first being
able to exchange stuff like how would DJ
have even set up an internet was going
to set up a geocities like [ __ ] you
know web page and sell illegal beans
you know
um I mean up until up until they passed
the the 215 in in late 96 I think it was
it was it was illegal in all 50 states
there wasn't any there wasn't even a
legitimate reason you could possess any
of it yeah
and I think he feels burnt he felt
burned but you know what were you going
to do when you gave it away to the Dutch
right if he didn't know that those those
Dutch guys were going to do whatever the
[ __ ] they wanted with it then he was
just he had just done his groundwork
yeah
well yeah that that's a blueberry is
almost a a a a full day's topic just by
itself it is but I just met in the sense
that like just to use it on the example
of how hard it was to sell seeds if you
were a small American breeder yeah he
had to work with the Dutch just to get
it out there there wasn't an Avenue what
were you gonna do
I mean you know
um you know even like early even early
American you know seed sellers or
whatever used to try to fake that their
stuff was based out of Europe
right right
you know I I mean one of the things that
IG did and and the middle and and the
sort of the middle era of two middle
late 215 was things opened up enough
that people felt free
to be able to like you know you could
have a swamp boys
you could have a CSI humble you could
have a you could have just these people
that were like I'm gonna make my own
Packaging I'm gonna make my own beans
I'm gonna go to these like gray area
cannabis cups swap meets and hustle
seeds I'm gonna start to mail
um I can say back in
02030405 I mean my buddy from Staten
Island would tell me about this stuff
that he wanted to do and I would laugh
at him
I was like oh you want us to all go to
jail
that's what it seems like you're talking
about to me you know yeah when I started
I I was one of the P I think I was one
of the few people that pretended that my
website was in Amsterdam just to like
try to hide under the shadows you know
just because no one was doing it it's it
[ __ ] was a big red flag I'm just
waiting for that hit even having the
infrastructure set up to be successful
yeah and and that's kind of why there
was so few breeders back then
because it was generally done out of
love
and you were trading amongst other
people and there wasn't something like
there is now where somebody can be like
Oh I'm gonna drop my Mac one drop and
I'm gonna make 200 Grand and you know
I'm gonna I'm gonna I'm gonna hype it
yeah you really couldn't hype it there
wasn't marketing there wasn't an ability
to reach a big audience right right I
don't think
you know no it took a while
and uh in in in the era you know 06 you
know through 08 even 2010 I mean most of
the marketing most most of the
availability was all based on internet
forums right yeah you know that was yeah
and people should also remember that
when overgrown cannabis World got shut
down they got shut down because of very
big uh you know seed vendor got raided
uh Heaven's stairway
that was and that scared a bunch of
people
and there's still repercussions and
ripples hidden from that [ __ ] bust
you know and you know and then you know
and and you know and people even in
Canada and stuff like that you know Mark
Emery you know uh I mean he he went to
[ __ ] he went to jail
did you have any dealings with Mark
gamer Caleb interactions
no no interactions at all but uh
um you know I was I was getting uh
cannabis culture or cannabis Canada from
pretty much like the first issue you
know I've always been a historian so I
mean I have hundreds and hundreds of
Canada books and I was you know for
years I was getting every single
magazine that was put out on on
everything so I've always been way more
of a reader than a talker yeah you know
it helps put details together sometimes
yeah it does yeah
but no no no uh direct you know dealings
I mean uh the stuff I liked from from
those magazines though and and him were
like the ABC stuff from back yeah late
90s and then the purple Indica Purple
Kush stuff that was in those early
issues as well but uh and then Emery was
working with the same purple Indica
that's around now or at least a relative
uh it wasn't Emery uh there was an
article uh based out of Snohomish County
yeah okay in Washington and it it
basically dated that that stuff back
into the you know at the very least you
know early mid 90s yeah that's cool so
there was a question we were talking
about the other night and I was like oh
I need to ask not so that and I can't
remember what it was it had something to
do with uh
how did Kim do you make it to California
not so oh yeah how did it make it here
yeah who brought it oh that's that's
pretty simple story so it ties into the
forums so people start in 06 people
started getting excited about uh chemdog
and the chem dog story because it
started getting posted uh like
um uh Caleb was saying Shabba had got uh
got
um skunk V8 to start posting about his
you know Recollections and different
stuff like that and and then you know
that's kind of actually what started to
reunite
um uh people like Peabody and Joe brand
and uh chem dog all they all started
chatting I believe they even called like
the the seeds that ended up being the
one through four the reunion seeds or
yeah the number four they uh named The
Reunion Fino specific reunion Fino
that's what it was right because it was
like they had all they'd all kind of met
up as this you know like different
people were like hey dude they're
talking about your story on the internet
right and so
chem dog hadn't actually had the chem 91
in quite a long time
um he had gotten in trouble and lost it
and he had been working with some of the
uh chemdog Super Skunk hybrids that he
had and bag seed and different things
and when it got famous again he wanted
it back but nobody had it
so he got
um he got skunked he got skunk VA to go
back East with it
and he was like if you bring it back to
bring it back to me and I've got this
different one that you guys don't have
out there and
um I'll give it to you
so he went back east and and saw a dude
and gave him the and gave him the dog
and then uh Greg gave him the D
and he came back and mommed it up and
that's how uh me and uh I see Collective
both got it so is skunkier that did it
brought it 100 oh cool and that was it
it was him it was it was all it's he's
the reason it's he to me he's the reason
it's on the West Coast
very cool uh he put forth the effort he
went back East to see chemdog uh he gave
he gave the dog to chem dog he got the
dude
if I remember too
um uh I believe that
um
chem dog tried to give him back the MSS
yeah he just said that but it was the
shorter one that was in the high times
and it wasn't what uh homie remembered
it all that makes a lot of sense too
yeah so then yeah so then he came back
and he grew it up into a mom or whatever
and then uh I see Collective and myself
got it not that long after that and but
to me it's like the reason it's on the
west coast is is skunk VA well on Greg
uh on G's tour
um
he uh he he dropped it off uh in the you
know LA area with swerve the chemd in 06
but this is awesome he
um and swerve traded him a bunch of fake
cuts for it you know no big deal and
then he also stopped at uh he stopped at
um you know obsolete's in central cal
um on his tour and then he stopped at
Joe Brands and then he headed up into
Oregon and stopped at some other folks
place and I think he might have given
them the chemd too but he he stopped a a
good handful of places giving cuts out
selling weed at dispensaries all that
kind of stuff on his you know reunion
tour of sorts and this was like first
week of August 06. so it sounds like uh
skunk VA went over there
earlier in the year and and and got
the same or similar cut I don't know
seems like there was a few cuts that got
passed out that year yeah
yeah I mean it so but that's that's kind
of that's how that's how the the and
that led to a bunch of stuff that led to
the one two three four
getting popped and starting to get
traded around
um that led to the D that that led to
the one through the four and the D and
all that starting to get added to the
mix
um I don't know that the weird thing
about the the chem stuff is that my
buddy disliked the CIS quite a bit he
thought it was ugly and he didn't like
how it got him high so he never brought
it West
and so it never really percolated around
our crew
um you know we way later we saw some of
the s1s
um but not the actual not the actual
first one
you know yeah
so
but yeah I mean that's and I you know
I'm pretty sure uh you know he I I never
I never lost it after skunk gave it to
me
um yeah I mean that and that's that's
the kind of thing like you know uh CSI
and I talk about it all the time it's
like are there strains where like the
chain of custody wasn't broken
mm-hmm
right right because once you lose the
chain of custody
um you know it's hard
it gets hard you know like
um because who knows you know you try to
you I lost the sour diesel you try to
get it back it's not the same thing you
remember you lost this you try to get it
back it's not the same you remember
um you know so on and so forth so
yeah
kind of like when uh 707 uh Shabad got
his Bubba back from me
um I I I don't think I did it on purpose
it was an accident it got mixed up in a
flat because I was bringing a ton of
people a bunch of stuff at a party and
uh then like a year later he's like yeah
in inspective Bubba and I was like
what's this inspector's bow and he had
bomb threat and not oh [ __ ]
I was like oh my bad my bad I'm trying
to give you you know the fake that's one
well not fake but you know yeah but yeah
that happens all the time
I think I'd take uh bomb threat over
over original maybe you can always get a
new bomb threat if you have that that's
true that's true that's a good point you
know
just a question for you since uh we've
kind of meandered away from the Forum
stuff but do you CSI do you do any work
with Jesus are you planning any work
with it
uh
maybe if I could find a math Super Skunk
yeah yeah that was for YouTube really
yeah
I was telling him it's night that I
think he should because I think it's a
it's a rad clone but it is it is very
finicky and it does make it a lot harder
to to pull off reversals on unhappy
finicky [ __ ] right it would it would be
really cool to kind of
uh attempt to remake like
um a sour type from you know building
blocks I mean yeah you know we all have
the the 91 but you know what building
blocks you know it might not have to be
the exact thing but what could you get
close enough to to make a sour diesel
out of you know the original building
blocks yeah you know
I think jesel leans closer to a sour
type than it does at chem type
personally
oh yeah definitely definitely yeah I
think so it's a cool one yeah yeah all
right so people want to hear something
about Irene I don't know what they want
to hear about Irene I think we've
already told the story of Irene but do
you have any good Irene Tales
oh I don't know I mean
she's cool
I think
um I I had Irene for a little bit
um and didn't realize she was she was
you know as as nice as she was until I
think I grew her Outdoors uh in maybe
2008 I'm thinking
yeah
I don't want to fudge the fudge the
dates though
um but yeah she came out so nice back
then you know
good old-fashioned Atlanta
's finest yeah it is a special one yeah
I mean it doesn't have a whole whole lot
of a story you know yeah just another
another backseat really
that's where the golf ball is down to
it's just another [ __ ] bad seat I
mean that is one of the most humbling
things about breeding
is that a lot of the most famous strains
are total accidents
right and then you put a bunch of time
and work and effort into stuff and then
you know your air conditioner goes out
and some [ __ ] Herms and the seed off of
that is better than anything you tried
to do and I think a lot of times when it
comes to like these stories the The
Accidental weed is so good it's what
makes people want to try to like shoe
horn in that they had some intentional
part of making it
not so much that I was just there or we
got late they don't want to say well I
just got lucky in my room
they want to be like oh well I did this
and I did this and I did this and then
that happened and yeah now it's all the
weed that you all love Well everybody's
got to work their stud isn't that how
it's done you know but but really it was
more like you know I was I had my room I
ended up partying for a few days I
[ __ ] off I walked in there there was
some bananas I found some seeds trimming
that's like 99 of bag seed stories yeah
that that's kind of why I believe uh uh
Matt Berger and Josh D story because
it's not impressive it's not a you know
it's a Herm you know in a little closet
under the stairs story and it's just
like who makes that stuff up that's not
right
that's just oops Yeah I mean you know I
it it that's very humbling but I I also
do think that a lot of that 90s weed it
just goes to show that when you're
Crossing things that like aren't when
you're Crossing real fire
you know
um it's a lot easier to get you know
like was was Neville an amazing breeder
or did he just get to get the best of
the best from America and cross it
together for the first time
right right you know what I'm saying
there's a there's an app there's
arguments to both
you know he was the first person to
cross NL and skunk
right you know
huh
what do you saying I'm rude no uh no uh
I was thinking you should get uh Tom on
and try to get uh uh figure out a little
more details about pine tar and all that
kind of stuff because I'd love to
you know I don't think he even knows who
I am to get him on
or he's not likely
I I think he's banned off I see mag so
uh yeah I mean let me ask you like a
real question do you think that he would
be better for a live or do you think he
would be better for a a lightly edited
uh podcast or something oh probably a a
heavily edited podcast because I mean we
definitely Matt and I have definitely
interviewed some like knowledgeable
Old-Timers right then like
yeah
Tom's a character I like him but man
he'll yeah
off topic
yeah you know yeah so there's there is a
question everybody is asking and it's up
to you if you want to talk about I don't
even know if you want to deal with this
one right now or save it for a full
episode Caleb
backstory on Z what do you think
oh man
um I don't want to like
say saying yet because yeah let's say
you want to save it for a full show of
some sort later well I I still have some
groans to do on that whole thing but
yeah man
I I wouldn't be surprised if it's not
just an S1 of of uh that green Sherbert
cut yeah
um there's there's just two too many
similarities
and the whole you know uh heterozygous
homozygous thing between the two of them
really kind of leans towards it just
being a that's one of that yeah but I
don't know um
uh I yeah I could go on and on on some
comparisons on you know how some of that
stuff could uh
could potentially make sense
um yeah but I don't know I don't know
yeah we'll save it for another time but
yeah that's a that's a good answer one
thing one thing that is done
about that is that
um uh CSI and I and Matt we all talk all
the time about how when you compare
stories to what the plants tell you
uh how they breed what their s1s look
like
um what what they look like when they
get crossed to different things and how
what your eyes tell you lines up with
what the story is
right right you know and sometimes it it
sometimes it adds a lot
in terms of what you see
um you know like about I have a heart I
have a really hard time believing that
the the the CIS the 91 the chemd and the
one through four all came out of the
same bud
yeah yeah you know um they're just too
vastly different to me
um you know but that's I wasn't there
either
you know and a lot of this stuff is like
the most famous stories
they almost because almost all of them
come from accidents and because a lot of
them come from other people it's like
the people that marketed stuff or
marketed Skittles or marketed cookie or
whatever like they probably you know
different people get it maybe it doesn't
get quite as famous
you know
um you know and they should get great
credit for marketing it to the point
that they did
yeah right oh yeah
I've never disputed that um you know I I
give lots of people accolades for Mar
successfully marketing and you know
building you know clones that would
never have been anything up you know to
what they are
uh what I've always you know frowned on
of course is you know people being
dishonest doing it I think you can do it
honestly and still be successful sure
you know having to just make up big old
big old you know fictitious backstories
or yeah like you're the one responsible
for it that's why instead of you know I
mean there's cats like you know Josh and
Matt who are like oh yeah it was a Herm
accident under the stairs and then
there's other cats you know who are like
yes we created that from our
multi-thousand plant grows aren't we
awesome yes yes we popped we popped 15
seeds and the 20th was the best so you
know
um you know I I think the the truth is
is the the biggest factor for me yeah
and yeah and there's an aspect where and
and you know we should say this too is
that truth is a most people Everyone
likes to say they want the truth but
like people that really care about it
it's like a really small percentage yeah
oh most people like truth if it helps
them burnish their money or their
reputation or whatever else sure and the
truth is usually boring you know people
who are looking for excitement from the
truth
they're gonna be like oh well that was
lame yeah something up I don't care
especially when the answer is 99 of the
time oh it's a bad seed yeah
or yeah or you know or it happened in an
accident at my buddy's house
of this or I was you know like you know
you were early involved and you know the
story even just knowing the story is
cool
right but then people want to be part
like they want to be this active
component that was critical to the story
you know
right and I I did forget someone earlier
that was really important when I was was
you know coming in and it was that was
doing reversals before I was and that
was Rascal I I think I would be remiss
not to mention him because he was doing
good things and had legitimate Cuts you
know for the most part uh as far as I
know like he was doing good [ __ ] work
and he was doing it at a time when it
wasn't popular when people were pushing
back against feminized seeds so I give
that guy props too all the stuff that
that guy made between whatever it was 09
and 12 or whatever yeah all those
hybrids are fire yeah there was some
good [ __ ] in there I mean he really
maybe not all but like the vast majority
of the stuff he had some really nice
cuts and he was crossing them together
and they led to some really nice things
yeah I mean white fire you know a lot of
people don't even know like about the
white anymore like not a lot of people
talk about it but that was the essence
behind the white fire that was [ __ ]
cool right right yep
that uh
that's one I'd like to touch on too in
the future
um oh yeah they they uh you know the the
swamp boys uh big Ricky in particular he
uh he's alluded a lot to knowing exactly
what the hybrid of the white is because
it's supposedly a TK hybrid
um but you know he he likes riddles and
secrets so
riddles and limericks I call it a haiku
hillbilly Haiku oh there he likes
sometimes I wonder how long he takes to
craft
uh some of his Instagram posts and how
to make it like you know he because he's
got his own language
correct when it comes to that you know
have you seen have you seen stuff like
the white inside the TKS ones yeah yeah
there there was a there was one plant in
our our first run of them where
um actually there was there was there
was four plants that uh we pulled out of
the first run
um and uh one was a green Girl Scout
cookie like a green form cut
um other was a plant that looked just
like the white you know not oh but so
similar yeah it was obvious and then
there was the number 50 and the 51 where
my which were my two actual favorites of
the whole bunch and
then you know I I smoked both those
heavily and the 50 turned out to be my
absolute favorite of the whole bunch and
so that's the one I kept and still play
with from the first and then I did
another 100 plus you know TK S1 pop and
you know got other selections from there
yeah so Caleb what do you think about
cookies
uh great question someone asked what do
you think
uh I think that goes into the category
of
2000 uh what 2010 and on for 2010 2011
yeah
people people ask a bunch of that and I
think I mean it's a story
you know and it's a story that like
there's a lot of pieces that aren't
known that well
um but it's definitely one that's going
to create a it's you know it's a super
popular brand there's a lot of money
involved there's a lot of rep involved
and uh it's one of those things if you
don't get it exactly right it's going to
be gunning for you here's a relevant one
here's a relevant one for you Caleb I
get an S1 any of the ml selections
I was going to leave that up to you
buddy yeah I think we might I think hi
I'm gonna see how it goes
uh uh yeah no I think they'd be worth it
I think they'd be do that you know I
like my feminized so
I'll grow it up there I'll grow some of
Matt's uh s1nls
hell yeah
there we go well we've kept him here for
God damn a long time so I know he's got
a busy night I gotta get back to packing
um anything else anybody wants to talk
about
so what's what's the next drop Caleb and
where where can we find it oh I don't
know if I'm
dropping dead maybe yeah the next drop
is dead
I'm I'm good for now yeah okay well go
check out humboldtsi.com correct
yeah
humboldtsi.com keep your eyes peeled
he's always putting stuff up on there on
and off he doesn't often announce it so
just keep checking back
um I'm still waiting yeah cut those next
drop
what's that I'm still waiting on natto's
next drop yeah where the [ __ ] that at
natto it's slowly developing okay good
it's actually developing through you
know I'm not that I'm not that public of
a guy uh it's changing though you know
yeah both of you uh basically like if if
the two most important people for you
guys seeing my face on a weekly basis is
the two people on this uh talk tonight
guaranteed without them I would not be
showing my face or chatting about stuff
they both pushed for quite a long time
to get you to tell stories and talk [ __ ]
um so really it it really is they gave
me the confidence to say you people
would want to hear it let's chat let's
talk history and you know and there's an
aspect to it too where it's like a lot
of this stuff we're talking about with
you guys this is what we've all been
doing amongst each other privately for
[ __ ] ever
yeah so we've all heard each other's
stupid [ __ ] stories 100 times you
know and and all that and so this is
this is really how information gets
information and cuts gets saved and
shared and you know history survives and
generally the point of all this is to
get you know versions of History out
there and gets passed along
it's just not a wash and [ __ ]
and everyone keep your eyes peeled for a
sterling was it Sterling Green Drop
eventually
yeah eventually mentally eventually when
it when it comes around everybody's
asking about it so I figured I'd plug it
and there's a bunch of good questions
today we didn't get to uh as always if
just because just because you asked him
we didn't chat
um you know doesn't mean it's not it's
not worthwhile you can always message us
about them uh we're always looking for
different things to chat about what
people have interest in you know so uh
keep all that stuff coming we always
appreciate your guys's Friday night
for 100 so yeah and go go check out the
breeder Syndicate patreon you got to go
to Google type in Regency patreon go
check it out go some show some love to
speak easyseedbank.com they're who edits
and and gets these things up for the
podcast version so show them some love
and uh check out right seedco.com and
humboldtcsi.com and we will see you next
week probably at the same time exactly
good one
want more breeder Syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to Google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret Discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsseeds.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
foreign