ready go
so
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
[Music]
hello bastards and bastards how we doing
so
um as you saw i think we're gonna have
csi humble
come stop by
uh
whenever i he may not show up at the
very beginning but he'll be here at some
point and we will go over
what he saw in the nl reproduction
so we'll keep our eyes peeled for when
csi pops up
you guys let me know
wasabi i need to teach you how to use a
camera
what do you mean teach me how to use the
as my own head's cut off yeah this is a
professional
i'm just analyzing my [ __ ]
you're just super anal
dude i like logged in and like your [ __ ]
was like aiming at the wall
i know i i started i start off with a
scenery of my
my ceiling
you do
yeah because nobody wants to see my
[ __ ] face the first time they jump in
i want to traumatize anyone i i want to
be i want it to be smooth
yeah
all right
so
um
trying to think of how to start this
uh well i don't know what you said
because i just popped i haven't said
anything
we're hoping
uh
managing technical difficulties and
whatnot that we might be able to get a
csi on to chat about some stuff
yeah um
and uh
this uh
this friday evening we kind of decided
that we were going to maybe sort of
merge
uh something that's current
uh going on right now with some
historical [ __ ]
yeah right and we had an excellent
opportunity to do that
in the uh in the nl5 project
that matt and and csi have been up to uh
and nl5 probably needs uh no
introduction
in the sense that it's probably like one
of the most famous terms in all of
cannabis
yep uh but there's a lot of legend
behind it and there's a lot of
misinformation behind it and so we
thought for this episode maybe we could
sort of like take you guys through
like how it started some of the history
to it and a lot of this stuff has been
chatted about in various ways and shapes
and forms but we thought it might be
interesting to sort of like coalesce it
all into one show
yeah uh and start from back then and
sort of bring it into the now
bring it in because modern times yeah
because you know so i mean i've done
i've helped with some like 90s stuff and
uh it makes me feel old but you know the
90s is like 30 plus years ago now
uh and the 80s when all this [ __ ] was
happening was 40 plus years ago now so
most people in cannabis have heard about
nl5 but it's mostly just legends
and there's a lot of misinformation and
a lot of funny cuts and a lot of odd
stories and so we kind of thought we'd
just
chat about those kind of aspects a
little bit
and sort of merge the history with uh a
little bit of the project that these
guys are doing um because they tie in
together
so
yeah i mean where do we want to start
uh you know we can start with um maybe
i'll start maybe we can start with just
the generalization you know and then
we'll start with some history so the
reason why everybody knows what nl5 is
in my opinion
is because of neville
right
uh neville
uh popularized it he picked a selection
uh and he used the nl5 and a bunch of
famous crosses
one of which was probably the most
famous line of all time that nl5 hates
yes uh and then
other groups and canadian seed banks and
all these different things started
using the name nl5 and l5 right yeah and
it just sort of became part of the
fabric of cannabis history yeah if you
will
right and there's a lot misunderstood
about it or whatever but it's probably
one of the most recognizable terms in
cannabis yeah i think even people like
my parents my mom my dad was who he was
with weed but my mom had nothing to do
with it she wanted nothing to do with it
never learned it and even she has sort
of northern lights as a street
and northern lights and northern lights
five and all that and so now what we've
got going on is as i've joked on
previous episodes or whatever that like
when i was trying to collect
uh a lot of old stuff it was almost
impossible
um but now we're kind of in this wave of
you know famous things from the 80s and
90s you know or in any form they might
exist in has has got a resurgence yeah
of popularity and interest
and people want to see what's up with
you know what was once common becomes
legendary yeah
right it's really is kind of what it
boils down to and so for anyone that
came into the weed scene later when ml5
was already kind of a myth
um you know uh
you know hopefully we can like clear up
a bunch of stuff because there's a lot
of
there's a lot of people that are talking
about the name
yeah
right yeah so
when we tell this tale let's go ahead
and start
with there was a man named herbie
sure
and herbie uh
went to a certain
hair salon where
the northern light crew hung out
and he would go to they would go to this
hair salon and commune and smoke weed
and talk stuff well this guy named
herbie came in and he was a veteran and
he
um
wanted to
be able to
grow
and make a living for himself so they
set him up with some lights and some
some of the original steve murphy
afghani seeds and he had some of his own
um different hybrids he was working with
mostly colombian and mexican i believe
that was the uh quote
um
yeah and and he he was the one who
selected this
nl5 clone from
er from his own work with the steve
murphy afghan and the hawaiian
so yeah i mean probably the the way that
people can understand it the best is
that
there was a loose collective
group of friends you know you know
acquaintances whatever in the pacific
northwest area yeah um herbie was one
there was a guy named some some people
call him the indian
uh was another one um steve murphy was a
different one um there was uh
you know a um there was a number of
different characters all involved at
various points and so
it was a mostly
everyone has to remember that in that
time in the early 80s
almost everything in america was still
sativa
and
blends of different sativas because all
the
all the weed that came into america
was
seeded sativa weed
right
so the core of everybody starting to
breed was you got free seeds with your
sativa weed lots of
lots of them and the rare [ __ ]
was indica
because indica made hash hash didn't
come with free seeds
and so indica seeds were really hard to
acquire
uh they came from people on the hippie
hashish trail people like sam skunk man
and neville and others made trips to
afghanistan which
in that era was extremely difficult to
do
and dangerous it's dangerous and they
started bringing back small amounts of
seeds so unlike sativa that was getting
sativa seeds spread out all over america
in every kilo that was sold
indica seeds were hard to come by yeah
so the nl story starts with a very small
handful of seeds
of pure indica that came from this dude
named steve murphy yeah
right and then of course just like
anybody um the group in the pacific
northwest up there started making
hybrids of this stuff they crossed it to
itself they crossed it to everything
else they had
and the the famous numbers of nl
basically
you know connotate like the lower the
number the more indica and the shorter
it was
yeah so the one two three four were pre
pro you know predominantly indica based
and smaller and you start getting into
five six seven eight nine ten eleven and
they start getting more and more sativa
now
matt's already interviewed one of the
main characters uh in the for in in this
thing and he basically stated that they
took that steve murphy afghan and they
crossed it to every sativa they could
get their hands on
so hawaiians
mexicans colombians
thai indians you said indians yeah
blends of those things hybrids of those
things all back and forth right
so
the nl5 they had this buddy named herbie
who got involved
and
uh herbie had a hawaiian
okay
and this hawaiian was
um
you know he crossed he it got crossed to
the steve murphy afghan
and
the it got called nl5
uh for its position and the height and
the blend of sativa versus indica or
whatever
and they found a fino that they really
really liked so
nl5 initially was a seed line created
within that little crew
and then herbie gave back to the nl crew
like this select fino that he was super
excited about
and so the as best we can tell
it's a pure afghan from steve murphy on
the one side
and a mexican colombian we believe on
the other side
that was called a hawaiian because it
was called a hawaiian because it was
grown in hawaii but there is no
indigenous hawaiian weed yeah most
hawaiian weed was mexican colombian a
blend of those two or a blend of those
two with afghan right
so
um
you know and then as you know as the
story's been told uh this gentleman
um sent
neville
uh a uh a whole bunch of seeds all
numbered
right yeah and uh i don't know if you
have any of those catalogs handy but
neville's story
is that
neville's story is that he
was um
you know he did a lot of work with them
and a lot of them
as we found out were a mess because they
were a blend of indicas and and sativas
yeah but in this one seed of nl5 out of
a bunch of indica sativa hybrids and a
mass he found this plant
that was what he called the pure indica
throwback that showed
zero
sativa influence yeah it was short it
was squat it was leafy it was covered in
frost
it didn't have a lot of smell
um and so he started crossing this to
things
and it crossed amazingly well
with basically everything he threw on it
yeah so
the legend of nl5 was born
because he crossed it to skunk one
and he crossed it to
nl he crossed it to hayes
and he crossed it to ml2
and he crossed it to a few other things
uh it started showing up in poly hybrids
he made like silver pearl yeah and it
just sort of became one of the building
blocks of his
genetic library and since he was one of
the first dudes
that had a seed bank
anything that he had that he threw into
a bunch of crosses kind of went
everywhere
yeah right and all these things are
winning high times you know stuff and
it's getting big glossy pictures and nl5
haze was the most popular strain they
sold
so the legend of it just took off
now
there's a debate here because
what what's indisputable is that he went
to the states
and he got uh the pacific northwest hash
plant and
the um
and the g13 through friends of uh
another guy who's pretty famous named
jorge cervantes
some friends of his hooked him up and he
arranged for
the cutting
that the guys in the pacific northwest
were growing as nl5 to be shipped over
right yeah and so they did this they did
this clever thing
where they shipped this plant over in a
terrarium of other plants
and they took scissors
and they cut the serrations off the
edges of each of the pot leaves
so it didn't look like wheat that's sick
huh that's nice
they just shaved all that off so it
looked unusual
and
if neville is posted uh back when he
used to post on mr nice
that he didn't like that one as much
because it wasn't as consistent of a
breeder as the one he found amongst the
seed line yeah and so he didn't use it
yeah so right there you have this
massive confusion where everybody thinks
nl5 is the same thing
where it is kind of the same thing but
there's a seed line that never got out
there's a clone that they selected from
that seed line that was popular in
washington
yeah and there's a clone that that
neville found among seeds they sent to
him
and they all got called nl5
yes
and that's where a lot of the
confusion lies yeah so people think
they'll be like oh i've got the same
clone that neville used and all of his
breeding but it never left the west
coast
yeah
well no because neville says he found it
in seat
yeah
you know so there was there was two
select cuttings even early
um and you know most people don't
realize this but neville says his was
like a total afghan throwback
and the one that that uh the seattle
crew describes
had like two foot colas on it right yeah
big long running lime green colas well
yes and no yes and no if i remember if i
remember it was stated that they
combined different buds to make it look
like it had a massive cola for netflix
oh jesus yeah so that there was some
fun stuff going on there was some
shenanigans perhaps yes shenanigans
abound there was some shenanigans so
there's a so yeah i mean there's an
aspect where
um
i'm sorry i'm looking down for a second
because matt didn't have his catalog
handy i know i always do too but i do i
don't know if there's a bigger version
of this but if everyone wants to look
that picture right there
that is a picture of the mother cut
taken in amsterdam and put in the
scentsy seeds catalog
taken when it won a cup in 1995 it was
printed in the 96 catalog that is a that
is one of the few existing pictures
of an actual growing
nl5 that neville used
and you can see it's short it's squat
it's leafy as [ __ ]
you know it's got all these things going
on to it
um
and so
you know uh
so nl5 neville said that nl5 was prob
nl5 hayes was probably the most famous
and best-selling thing in his whole
catalog both at his seed bank and later
at scentsy yeah
um the nl5 skunk one got renamed it's i
don't know if it was renamed shiva shiva
skunk yeah i think it was renamed shiva
skunk at scentsy seeds but it was sold
the whole time
um so probably it was sold from 87 or 88
all the way through uh
you know
1999 or the early 2000s still probably
to this day but it's not the same [ __ ]
yeah um and nl5 hayes was sold
consistently so
you know it just kind of entered into
the lexicon everybody knows nl5 hates
yeah and it's gotten old enough now that
a bunch of people are like oh i have it
i have the original cutting i have the
this i have the that so
you know
um you know and uh
and and you know it it um
someone's saying nothing about the nl
crew telling neville that
i mean neville you know neville spoke
about the nl but he basically like has
said that he just got
um he just got these labeled seeds
and he made his own inferences about
them
you know so yeah
you know he had he had to make it up
basically like he had to think what what
am i seeing yeah um and then you know
the guys back then there it was in the
80s and they were all scared of getting
busted so they didn't really take
copious notes
no and that's either that was stated
several times you know and we actually
know a bit more about the nl5 than we
know about a lot of the other nl numbers
because of what herbie was working with
and what he said he crossed to the steve
murphy to get that nl5
yeah
so it's like a lot of things you know i
mean a lot of a lot of
a lot of breedings are collaborative
it's a small group of friends doing one
part at my garage and you do the next
part of yours and this and that and
everything else and who's responsible
for it there might be one or two people
that gets known for it but in reality
there's a whole little group that's
involved
yeah it was a kind of small group yeah
right yep
so
you know uh and then you know when it
comes to nl5 haze
uh neville claims that
right before he left scentsy about
95-ish uh they lost the mother of nl5
dope
it died
and it makes kind of sense because if
you like there's a bunch of nl5 haze
cuts that still are kept
in
in america especially in the new york
region and in amsterdam
and they all are basically from 88 to
95.
yeah you know there's not really people
aren't really like oh i got this one in
um but there was a lot of fire in those
seven or eight years that they were able
to marry those two plants together yeah
you know and then you know uh super
silver haze and stuff like that was kind
of neville's attempt to blend the three
most famous amsterdam lines together
uh which was nl skunk and haze
and so you know now we have this whole
thing where
everything gets different names and
different nicknames
and tons of [ __ ] has nl or skunk or haze
blended into it yeah but you might not
know because it doesn't have that name
attached
yeah you know
uh no someone said i assumed it was
phenos of one to nine no it was
different hybrids
so
nl1 was almost pure afghan
nl2 was another afghan that they
actually got like a kush type afghan
from the indian
and they blended that to steve murphy
yeah three and four are sort of lost to
time nobody has them but they were also
you know they started increasing amounts
of sativa and 5 through 11 were just the
nl crews crossing
that afghan to different sativas yeah
and you know the more the higher the
number
the taller the plant the more sativa
influenced yeah
right yep that's how we know it
so if you look around
uh at some of neville's early catalogs
you can see him playing around he uses
the eight he uses the five he uses the
nine he's got the one and the two you
know all these different things and then
after three or four years he decided
basically that he was only gonna breed
with the one the two and the one cutting
of the five that he found yeah and so
all these other hybrids kind of go away
because probably because they were mixes
of extreme sativas with indicas and they
were probably a lot more of a pain in
the ass for a breeder to tame
yeah and he did have high high as far as
his keepers he did use a uh
a rigorous selection so he didn't keep
he went through a lot of seeds to find
out what he kept and the indian i
believe the indian was native american
but i can't say that for sure but he was
he was native american but he was he was
part of the pacific northwest crew yeah
and a lot of these guys aren't aren't
well known and don't want to be the
well-known because in the 80s especially
in the late 80s there was a series of
rolling busts and they all got in
trouble
yeah uh so it was a hard time to be a
cultivator
you know uh cleaning up green merchant
yeah yeah and all that it was there was
a lot of persecution back then there was
a lot of secrecy back then that's part
of why they didn't keep copious notes
because they didn't want them to be used
against them in a court of law later on
um and so
you know but basically i see i think
it's fair to say that the reason why
everybody knows nl5 is because of
neville that i think that's fair i think
everybody agrees with that too because
he
and even like the seattle guys will say
that if they hadn't sent it to neville
it likely would have been lost yeah
because they went through a rolling
series of busts
and had issues
yeah you know so it so it was sold at
neville's seed bank
for a number of years
and then it was sold at scentsy for a
number of years after that
uh never pure
right uh always a hybrid skunk one haze
nl2
silver pearl other poly hybrids blended
together but never really by itself yeah
so there was a pure seed line of nl5
but nobody got it
it wasn't sold it didn't make it to out
of amsterdam it was given to like a
couple people and even like even gret
you know uh even like some of the
seattle guys said that there was a
couple of cuts that got out
the eight the nine and maybe one and
maybe one of the twos from the indian
but nothing else yeah so the five
survived because it went to amsterdam
basically yeah that it's that's the only
reason it survived that's the only
reason why it survived so
if you listen to the seattle crew they
had one version of nl5 that they kept as
a cutting and kind of cropped out
uh neville found a breeder that he kept
you know
yeah and
you know it kind of it kind of went into
it kind of went into legend
um you know and so
you know uh and so yeah i see all kinds
of people what's up with this person's
nl1 what's up with this nl5 what
happened is is because it became so
famous okay two things happened one
is that in amsterdam anytime anything
gets famous people get seeds of it and
they white label it
yeah right and they offer up their own
versions of it
okay
and then on top of that when the
canadian seed companies got involved
they ended up buying a bunch of stuff
from amsterdam blending it to canadian
strains and claiming
that they had these things for sales
purposes
yeah
you know so you get and and they all
have sort of dodgy history
yeah
when it comes to provenance what i've
what i've told you so far is pretty much
factually agreed to
by the people that sent it to neville
and neville yeah and people around
neville
yeah you know and then it gets famous
and there's a proliferation of people
and seed banks that claim to have
various stuff
but they weren't passing out this
cutting to other people no they weren't
sharing it just so other people in
different continents could like
make their own seeds with it
it wasn't like today where people were
trading seeds back and forth
you know and
clones back and forth especially to
competitors
you know the dutch are extremely
business oriented
very
they're not going to just like grow out
and yeah that's why matt's laughing
because they very are very much business
oriented if they have a cut and everyone
else wants it and they're breeding off
it and making money
there's not really a chance they're
gonna share that [ __ ] thing and
there's a definite chance everybody's
gonna say that they have it yeah there's
a definite chance that everyone's going
to say they have it and they're going to
use that any name that becomes famous
in cannabis
gets used
yeah
you know so someone asked about you know
and so um
that's kind of like that's kind of where
nl5 you know just got crossed to some
very famous things and neville made some
very [ __ ] famous lines off it
and there wasn't that much weed strains
back then and the combination of that
and high times
being like the premier magazine in the
90s and you get all these high quality
glossy photos and all the
the cannabis cups and there was only one
cannabis cup a year yeah
so this [ __ ] got
hella famous
legendary
you know yeah
and um yeah
and what about another one what's that
what about nl1 oh denali's question
oh i didn't see it i mean ml1 is is
probably the closest thing to steve
murphy afghan
um it's it's it's got a little bit of
discrepancy between the guys involved as
to what exactly is in it
yeah um but
you know it's that's kind of irrelevant
because what actually got sold is what
got sent to neville
and everybody should know that neville
got it in
in uh in 8485
and spent two or three years
seeing what he had so if you bought
northern lights in 85 or 86 or even 87
from his catalog
it was a [ __ ] hodgepodge of any of
the lines
all blended together yeah it wasn't
until about 88
that uh
um it wasn't about i'm gonna turn off my
light because people are bitching it
wasn't about till 88
that uh
he started coming out with nl1 nl2 and
nl5 yeah
right
and uh
you know and so and then so then these
numbers get attached i think
1989 late 88 is when nl5 hayes got
released
yeah
and nl5 skunk one
and nl5 this and so
nl1 and l2 you know when it went to
scentsy um you know they just called 801
northern lights
yeah and they called nl2 hindu kush
uh and so lots of people got nl because
it was one of the most common things
sold
yeah sorry i had to screenshot something
that's funny
no
yeah it's hard i mean people ask
questions sometimes i'll get it
sometimes not it's really hard to like
pat your head and rub your stomach at
the same time so like
i try to chat about something and sound
like you know fairly have a have some
flow and then i read a question and i
think about it and all of a sudden i'm
not talking and i'm just staring at the
screen so forgive me uh for all that you
know if i it's a little adhd yeah if i
miss your question i'm i'm sorry it's
just the way it works so you know i've
chatted about this a bunch before on
some of the previous podcasts and a
little bit more detail
but
that's what got it famous
right that that is the story that is
that is that is the story and so now
anytime anything becomes famous
you know it's kind of like music or
fashion or something like that it gets
[ __ ] recycled
right
and most people don't know about it and
then all of a sudden people are like
i've got this ancient nl5 cut and i'm
making beans with it
i've got this this this you know um you
know and maybe maybe matt you could
explain the boof cut or the
the new i
i don't know i i've never talked to
bodhi about that one and i keep meaning
to ask him because people ask it a lot
but i don't know the the history on that
one
so i mean people
you know and you know people asked about
bob hemphill and you know uh and and
ella and stuff like that and so people
have been people you know
it's really hard when you get seat when
you get seeds and lines that are that
are 25 30 years old plus
uh provenance on it becomes difficult
right you know um apparently you know uh
hemp hill used to work with uh the
coastal seeds collective
uh and apparently you know he got it
through some friend of cogus
you know um but nl1 was sold for you
know what probably 20 years yeah for a
long time for a long time it was it was
sold it was and there was never a
specific cut
i mean neville had some breeding males
that he used uh nl1 and nl2 and
neville's thing was almost always males
yeah they were part of his breeding
males and so it wasn't like nl5 well
while never neville just had one cutting
that had to be kept alive
yeah nl1 was kind of like a line
yeah and so any like urban poison or
something right yeah so anytime there's
a line it's a lot harder to lose the
line
than it is when you're dependent on one
specific cut
to stay alive and keep going yeah and
the other thing much easier
just because these these [ __ ] dutch
guys are such businessmen when you're
not sharing a cut amongst your homies
and your good friends
it exponentially increases the chance
that some kind of disease or accident or
drought or worker error is going to kill
your [ __ ] cut
that greed will get you and then you
haven't shared it so it gets lost
right yep uh and you know and so
uh ben and alan drunkers aren't generous
people
no they weren't sharing they weren't
sharing [ __ ] with anybody
you know
um and uh you know so i don't know i
mean it it uh
nl5 is super famous nl is super famous
that we went through probably a 10 year
period where nobody gave a [ __ ]
uh probably starting right around the
kush sour going into cookie era yeah uh
where old things were just old and
unpopular
right yeah that it's just yeah things
like northern lights skunk one
these were cheese things that that like
people are kind of looking at now like
oh they got the [ __ ] cheat they got
they like if i saw that in a in a store
with tons of cool clones in you know the
early mid 2000s it's like
huh
give me some of that new [ __ ] nobody was
worried about that because it was so
abundant oh you know i mean we had it i
can't remember who said it but it's
absolutely true
you know 15 20 years ago you you bought
seeds from nirvana gypsy nirvana and you
got free skunk one seeds because he
might as well because you had so many of
them and it was so common
it was you know you had to give them
away yeah because nobody wanted to buy
them yeah it was super abundant and so
there's a thing where everything's so
common
why would anyone want it and people's
tastes and change you know people's you
know taste changes and then it becomes
rare
and then people want it again yeah but
most people in cannabis don't hold on to
anything unless it's currently
profitable
so what once becomes we've we've seen it
over and over and over and over again
um you know where something that was
once abundant
yeah becomes uber rare or lost to time
like i'll say it straight up if it you
know hopefully he pops on here this
evening but if it wasn't for csi loving
the urkel and breeding with it a ton
most people wouldn't have access to it
yeah his prolific breeding is probably
the reason why that genetics survived
yeah and i'm not saying he's the only
person that held it
no but it but yeah it got down i used to
know i mean we're not going to talk
about purples very long here tonight but
like i used to know
dozens upon dozens of growers 15 years
ago that ran herckle
and you and then
diesel and kush gets popular and like
six people held onto it yeah
literally yeah it's yeah that's how it
goes dude and it's not and the reason
why i brought that up is because that's
how super skunk became almost extinct
that's how nobody can find the the the
dead skunk terps that's how all these
things become rare or hoarded or extinct
is they're so common nobody thinks they
need to care to preserve it and then
hippies and growers start looking around
at who's got that old school
and they can't [ __ ] find it and a lot
of times the name game happens it'll get
a different name or you know someone
makes seeds with it and it has a
different name that it carries on with
so people don't even know to look in
that direction for
said
one of these baselines yeah we've talked
about that before too where i love the
counterculture aspect of americans
giving weed nicknames yeah but for
lineage it's a real pain in the ass no
it's terrible because we take whatever
the name of the actual thing is and it
gets a nickname
and then it goes to a different crew and
they give it a different [ __ ]
nickname yeah and then it goes to this
other crew and they give it a spin on
that name
yeah and then 20 years goes by and
you're trying to trace what the hell it
is yeah plain telephone and you gotta go
through four or five nicknames back and
then you get to the core thing
and then you and then the trail goes dry
so you know
i mean uh
so now
after 10 or 15 years of nobody giving a
[ __ ] about northern lights
it's hot
yeah people want to try these ancient
things that they grew up when they were
kids reading about
or these the first wheat the first like
true famous wheat
yeah you know they want to see what's up
they want to see what's up with it and
uh you know and so now because there's
interest
now all of a sudden where there's
interest there's economy and people
start popping up with it
yeah
all over the place and most people
probably don't know that there was two
completely distinct cuts that were used
one from america and one from holland
yeah and there was a seed line but it
was given out to nobody and then you see
stuff where i've got nl5 pure
well how
yeah lots of that right how
yeah you know
you know i mean you can you can talk you
can you can know that that neville had
it pure
because the guy that made it says i sent
it to him pure along with the rest of it
yeah
and neville says i got it pure from dude
okay they both agree
here's when i sent it it exists but did
you share with anybody no
so everybody has a bunch of hybrids
or canadians got it and sold their [ __ ]
and then people get it and it's got a
name attached and they're like
you know um
there it is
yeah
you know and because we're cannabis and
because all of our stories are kind of
black market or underground or
prohibition
it gets really difficult to
sometimes it comes down to who you
choose to believe
yeah and that's a lot of the time with a
lot of these strains and so some people
will get like nl and they'll and the guy
will be like i've had this for 30 years
and never left the west coast it's it's
this
yeah and they're like great it's this
that's all the proof i need
let's start breeding with it and it's
this
and now it's labels all over the place
and people are buying it and is it that
one thing one thing i also noticed was
that during the philos era
um a lot of people would get said clone
that they got with dubious heritage or
whatever they submitted to philos
and
by doing so say that
philos verified their clone is
legitimate you know god yeah yeah that
happened that started happening a lot
too and that was a real problem because
and as we learned um
allegedly
yeah philos couldn't
tell people
any kind of plant relation with any
consistency
that maybe we should say this
about csi is that it doesn't matter what
it is but csi sent and fi this is how
matt myself and csi discovered that
philos was really really really full of
it um we had some evidence before but
this was kind of one of the big kickers
was that uh csi had made a cross
uh and he sent in both parents
and i don't know if he wants the story
out so much no yeah no i'll shut up
about it then i didn't even mention what
it was but i'll just say this we we
discovered that their genetic sequencing
wasn't as strong as we would have hoped
yeah yeah it was it was definitely
disappointing with the consistency of it
you know and so people thought that
their genetic testing was like american
genetic testing
yeah where you can have 23 and me or
some [ __ ] and be like oh my god i'm five
percent norwegian
and you know grandpa was from germany
and this guy and i'm like and i'm part
african or whatever yeah and we were
hoping that same kind of accuracy would
be transferred into weed
yeah and i'm
trying to move caleb
well we'll see
caleb click the thing and say request to
join if you can
if you if you see how to do that
hit the request to join button so i can
uh add you in
when you got time
all right go ahead
yeah so i mean it it um and you know in
order the other the other thing about it
is is for like talking about human
genetics is geneticists can go to like a
pure norwegian or a pure japanese or a
pure chinese whatever and they can start
comparing dna
yeah and seeing these different things
and they know how to sequence it if it
would be amazing if dna evidence had
existed
in holland in the 80s
and
neville and and sssc and and scentsy and
these early groups would have been able
to like put down markers of what was
what
yeah
and then we could have seen their
descendants because you'd have something
to compare it to
yeah
but that's not always the case that's
not always the case so absolutely you
know uh so it remains a dream because
here he is
sir your lighting is terrible but if you
just you look like you look like you're
on 60 minutes and you're one of those
like grayed out you know like guys under
the witness protection program it's too
bright in here it's too bright there
yeah
too bright
yeah yeah
i ain't trying to you know
oh you look beautiful oh thank you thank
you
so maybe i talk a lot so maybe i'll do
like an introduction
not that one's needed and then i'll shut
up and get out of the way
so part of the reason why we did we we
decided to do this selection tonight was
because it blends
uh something that's currently going on
with something that's extremely famous
and uh has a bunch of history to it so i
just spent a whole bunch of time
chatting about the history of it
and the simple and maybe like you know
mellow way to talk about it is that uh
in in our search of history we started
getting in contact with some of these
uh original northern lights crew people
and hearing their story
and as part of that uh we got we got
some seeds
uh matt got some seeds and
um matt uh and and caleb here uh decided
to collaborate on it uh and and caleb
donated some space and some time and
some energy and they
uh did a bunch of stuff uh both growing
out phenos looking within the line
making hybrids and all that and so
uh i was i was involved as much as
listening to them talk about it so i'll
shut up
and turn it over to them because uh they
are about to offer up some seeds of what
they have going on
uh and it might be you know some of the
first real nl to come on the market in a
while
um so matt and caleb why don't you chat
about what you found and what you saw
and what interested you and
da da da da well first things first you
know i'm you know when i post it up on
ig
you know there's there's a few people
who are like you know
what
what did matt have to do with any of
this
you know and
their question i wouldn't even be
growing these things if matt khan you
know had all that dialogue with you know
mystery man
and you know he he's the one who you
know put all that together he's the one
who sourced these seeds essentially so i
wouldn't be growing nothing without matt
you know
making that first step so yeah
maybe maybe i'll throw in one more thing
so everyone knows
when you know breeders like us get
together it's super common
for some breeding to be a collaborative
process
right right this guy's got some seeds
you know they both have an idea this
other person has some room that they're
willing to put towards the idea or a
greenhouse or some indoor space they
come up with a plan
and you breed together
right and people might not hear the jj
of the transaction but but every but
everybody everybody you know lots lots
of friends who are breeders kind of
collaborate on little things like that
all the time
it's super common just so people just so
people know so
you know um
you know matt had the seeds
uh you know csi had the space in skill
you know and skill and you know and
ability uh we all had the interest in
the history behind it and really wanted
to see what was in there and so it you
know the project happened
right and uh you know some people know
some people don't that the very first
you know clone i ever grew came from my
dad and that was northern lights back in
you know so tell us about that one dude
i mean you know i remember
i mean i rocked it on and off until
about 2002 when i lost it
and uh it was a cola plant super frosty
a decent density you know not not like
rock hard girl scout cookies or anything
i
i describe the nose but i'm absolutely
horrible at describing you know
the smells so when people ask i'm like
it smells good i don't know
that's not my forte i
i'm more of a visual you know oh it
looks like this you know similar to this
in the looks department blah blah blah
you know other than you know it smells
great or whatever whatever
i'm not the dude for for the sniffer
yeah
um
but yeah yeah i mean
when you lost it was it something you
kept looking for like when you when you
were picking up clones
oh yeah oh yeah yeah no it was one of
the things that you know
uh family and friends you know all had
it and then you know i lost it and i
went looking and nobody had it
everybody lost it you know that's how it
goes
yeah but people are asking if it purpled
no
not not the one i got from my dad um
yeah
i don't i don't really recall it
even remotely having any type of purple
to it at all yeah and and these these
you know nl5 seeds that you know
i just ran
there was very very little if any you
know
actual purple to any of them so yeah you
know um but then again uh
sometimes when you're making seed uh
you know the purple traits trying to
kind of tend to take a back seat yeah a
lot of a lot of purple things will be
halfway green you know or all the way
green you know
uh when they're making seeds so i mean
uh mendo purple does that you know where
it's
you know more green than purple even
under cool temperatures and everything
when it's full of seeds yeah you know so
um but i think the plants have different
uh processes when they're impregnated
versus not
right right you know
they do they do very different things
their their goal is different at the
time
and and i didn't even think about this
but i'm i'm feeding seeded out plants
you know nitrogen [ __ ] all the way
through yeah yeah i'm not trying to cut
off their nitro source you know early
like it would a flower so yeah the goal
is is healthy mature seeds not
attractive flower
exactly flower is just the carrier for
the seed so it's very different it's a
very different feeding regimen
uh to get where you want to go yeah and
flower
which is why when you have a failed run
and a bunch of flour and no seed
that smoke ain't the best yeah right
you already said maybe maybe i should
mention something is that uh you know
csi has actually you know he has some
pictures of some of these old gardens
and stuff like that um but unfortunately
since it was all prohibitiony back then
um they were on polaroids and uh you
learn with polaroids that they fade over
time
you know so uh they become the the
colors start to become washed out the
edges start to become less distinct
so you know he cataloged some of it and
uh you know you can you can get a
general idea but it's not the sharpest
of picks right i i have thousands of
these polaroids you know
for you know the better part of a decade
and
now
now they're uh
not much to look at yeah that's a bummer
dude that's such a buffer
right right it's just something you
didn't know at the time
who knew that over 15 20 25 years
polaroids would would fade
right a regular picture developed at a
you know you know old school style will
stay good for a long time right
polaroids don't you
know should have scanned them all while
i had the chance
yeah i mean you know we all should have
done things differently when we were
younger
uh yeah you know that's the common theme
right right
your camera's slowly but surely burning
out bro
well you know so the best thing is i was
having i was having a conversation with
with uh our buddy pip
uh who is gonna drop some seeds soon and
he might come on here and chat with matt
and i but he didn't really want to show
his face so i'm definitely going to show
him this csi tech
yeah right here
because it's exactly what he's looking
for
a disembodied voice coming out of coming
out of the darkness isn't that how they
always used to do yeah right this is
very 60 minutes in the 90s you know
i just need to now i just need the voice
tech yeah i need that voice
yeah yeah um tell us what you saw man
tell it tell us what you saw in that
room okay so yeah
the the the seeds that
riot and i have available
um
are basically an open pollination
uh from
47 plants
27 females 20 males just open pollinated
and uh you know there was there was
definitely good bad in the ugly in there
there was one plant that was near
identical to the northern light i grew
you know from 94 on from my dad
um smelled like it looked extremely
similar to it
you know all of that um
and you know i i had a one of my good
old old buddies from you know
from that area you know uh
you know check checking things out with
me as it was progressing and he was like
yeah that's that's just like the plant
we we used to rock you know 25 years ago
so that's wild that that's definitely a
good sign um there was a lot of variety
in there um
one of my favorites of course uh was
this one that was super frosty kind of a
popcorn nugget thing a really good
stretch um
and it was kind of bubble gummy i that's
how i ex you know describe it but
i don't know maybe other people would
you know
just describe the smell different
but it was really nice um and we're
definitely saving that one and then the
one that was
um
i just have it written down as stinky as
[ __ ] but
it it's
it had
like 10 different smells
you know top middle bottom
and i i can't describe that kind of
stuff but you know there's there's guys
with noses who are like oh yeah that's
blah blah blah blah blah blah blah you
know and list 20 different smells on
something but
all i know is it smelled amazing too
yeah and that one uh that one's
definitely a keeper and then there are
some other ones that
you know ranged uh
you know this way in that way
and you know my my end up being keepers
might not definitely going to give them
a couple few
runs to decide on which ones are going
to kind of make the cut for future
projects you know
so
that's what i'm stoked about is that we
get to see them as clones not just see
seed moms you know but as clones and
they get clones of every single one it's
it's pretty expansive and it was a it
was a cool it was cool that
and i know you know he he he credits me
with getting the seats and stuff but it
was it was really cool to be able to to
look inside
uh csi's mindset as he did these
selections what he was looking for how
he went about it how many clones he was
keeping of each i learned a lot i
learned a lot from dude during this so
um he put in the work
no matter what he says he put in the
[ __ ] work on this stuff
right
yeah maybe and maybe i should add
something in where caleb and i chat a
bunch about like you know
phenos he's found in seed lines before
um that didn't survive like you know the
the backup clone didn't survive and he
lost it and he's like well you know i
got x amount of these seeds i can find
it again
so
uh maybe you know how excited were you
dude to find something that was pretty
close to the spitting image of your lost
plant
i i was stoked on it um
but you know uh
i was all honestly more excited with
some of these other ones that you know
because
you know back in 94 your
the the reality is you know um it's just
a traded clone
you have no idea you know where it came
from how many speeds it got selected
from you know anything about it you know
and that's the thing with traded clones
is you know it might be selected from
one or four or
ten or a hundred you know
um i just like you know having the
opportunity to actually select from
better than one yeah for sure i think
too that like there are things for all
of us now that we're all older where
some of the strains that you grow first
and you build your first relationships
with as a grower
right in your mind because you're
learning so much then
and this is your kind bud plant
right right you know and they really
stick with you those
and you know you think back like oh what
could i have done
uh with that plant when i actually had
some some knowledge
when i had that plant i was an idiot you
know i was 19 or something and i didn't
know jack and now i'm like you know what
could i do if i had it now
right right
yeah yeah yeah
yeah
i'm a little interested too and i know
this is an nl talk
but are you do you want to talk about
any of the pinks and perf stuff you're
seeing too since that's a big project
you have going on right now
oh we could touch on it just a little
bit yeah yeah
you know uh
had me amped
yeah i'm definitely gonna uh
you know
try to post up a little bit more on that
soon
just because uh there's there's some
interesting stuff in in there um
and uh
yeah that one keeper i was telling you
about uh
it smells better than 99 percent of
weed i've come across so
that's wild
you know um
definite it's not a purple pheno pure
green you know no purple traits
to it whatsoever but man the smell
is just so overpowering uh
i i think it could be a a passed around
keeper as long as it's over five percent
thc of course yeah for sure
well you know we should mention that
some of the terpius things
tend to be lower thc
right right there's a ratio there's a
there's a there's a ratio there that's
not fully understood but a lot of times
things that are extremely human
perception terpy
don't tend to be the most potent there
are things out there that have both
but a lot of them don't so we'll see
and uh
have i told you
much or anything about this uh
this pinks and purple plant
uh uh i i heard it through
your comment you and matt chatted about
it and he called me all excited yeah
yeah because it's rare that you sound
that excited yeah something that you
found so he was i'd never hear him
overstate anything about anything dude
[ __ ] thousands of seeds so when he
tells me dude
like this is special like yeah i mean i
think i think homie told me something
like he he thinks it might be like the
best pheno he's found
which for some for someone like you to
say who pops literally like thousands of
seeds over a number of years and
searches through them that's really
something oh yeah you know
and it really is
i like to give to give credit to you
know uh what what plants you know kind
of produce these kind of things
yeah and uh
uh this particular plant you know it has
mendo purple in its background but
there's no purple traits to this plant
at all but mendo purple has this strong
uh mango
um trait that pops up in the ones and
this thing is that mango times a hundred
you know
it's it's just
the strongest mango i've ever smelled
wow
you know as you know and a bunch more
fruit too
but uh
you know i i know it gets that mango you
know at least you know a portion of it
from from the mendo perps
so you know
could be cool
as long as i don't lose the clone
ganja boners yeah i mean one one of the
things that the mendo p certainly has is
it's got pretty wide genetic diversity
so there's a lot of terps in there
right right and so then you throw it on
something else that's also terpene maybe
wide and you can get
these unusual things that have a
potential to pop up
right i mean that's kind of like people
should know this too and maybe i should
say it right now where it's like if you
cross something to like that uh you know
to but to i don't know to deep chunk
you're going to get a lot of deep chunk
right and it's going to be really
consistent you know and there's certain
things you throw certain things on
cookies and it looks very cooky
right and so people get frustrated when
you cross two very wide things because
you can get a bunch of junk and you can
get a bunch of this and that and it's
all like unpredictable oh yeah but then
every once in a while amongst all that
stuff there's this gem
because it's so wide and unpredictable
and you're like oh whoa
what is that thing
right right so sometimes the frustration
and the effort pays off
because a really wide base of things to
look through
and maybe i should say this too is when
you know when caleb was referencing when
he did the open pollination that there
was some gems
some mids some junk
that's 90s wheat
if you have a wide genetic base
you're going to get
amazing midzie junk for all in combo and
also uh on that pinks and perps one uh
you know i i was i was i always forget
this but
um
i i grew up when i i made those and
found that one i was growing out 180 of
those things so there was only one like
it out of 180
yeah you know so i wonder how it's going
to breed because it was such a outlier
right
were there other other phenos that were
more consistent and like popping up more
often oh yeah the the
the purple ones were predominant you
know to find an actual green one in in
this hybrid was actually the rarity you
know most most everything was you know
some form of light pink or lavender you
know all the way through you know purple
to almost black
yeah you know but uh yeah the the green
ones were were rare
you know and and i i probably kept out
of the 180 i probably kept about 20 or
so of the
of the darker purple ones and just the
real terpier ones the you know
but they're all i don't think i i have
any other uh green ones out of the whole
all all the purples and the blacks
that's wild man
yeah that it was so consistently that
and then this one pops up
right
so and so maybe i should throw this out
there just real quick before we totally
lose the thread on it is
on some of these ones that you found
that that the one that's super frosty
and smells to you like bubble gum and
the one that kind of reminds you
strongly of your dad dad's dad's nl and
such
um you're probably planning on doing
some more breeding with those select
females correct oh yeah i'm already
working on that too uh
so the the first round of course was the
open pollination and now um i have a
room that's a couple few weeks into
flower
and
that's all the keeper females and my
keeper male my favorite male out of the
whole bunch
which is
um i don't know it's it's like almost a
milk chocolatey smelling male and he's
super pungent and he almost looks like a
bigger uh version of purple indica
you know
that's a throwback from the same you
know washington areas these seeds came
from you know
so
you know there's there's something to
that
and uh like i've told uh
um told matt i'm not sure if i i told
you not so but uh
um
when
the the northern lights i used to have
um you know occasionally i throw a a
late nano or whatever whatever
and i grew out a bunch of s1 seeds
well
i gave you know some of these s ones to
my buddy you know uh clones of the s
ones anyway
and uh
um he uh
accidentally crossed it to train wreck
and
when that stuff was grown out it had
that same chocolatiness that i'm
smelling in this thing you know when
grown outdoors so
i don't know if it's just coincidence or
or what but
you know
it it could just be
same same similar genetics the power of
accidents
the power of accident so maybe i should
throw this in there too so
if
with with the these seeds that uh matt
and caleb are offering up this open
pollination
uh what that's going to give you
is
you know that's going to give you your
own ability to hunt through the line and
it's going to be very wide
you know but you could find gems just
like he found yeah
uh you could you could absolutely
perhaps find one you wouldn't know that
look you know there could be bubble gum
smelling ones there could be this ones
there could be there's a reasonably good
chance that somewhere in there is those
phenols pop up again
and then
give them x amount of months to do some
more breeding and we'll get the chance
to see if some of these selected females
breed true for the traits that he liked
because those will be on offer too so
that's kind of like for people that
don't know that's kind of like when you
get old seeds or seeds that you want to
preserve one of the best things to do to
keep the genetic diversity of the line
is just to open pollinate everything
right and then
you know you can set aside you know some
seeds from selected phenos and you can
keep certain phenoes and start breeding
with them and intentionally
and seeing where it takes you
so that's kind of like the that's one of
the processes of
um
taking old seeds and trying to both
preserve the line but then take it in
certain directions
that's kind of how i and you've done
that a number of times with like various
heirloom strains that you've come across
you know
always open pollinate step one and then
you know you can do whatever you want
past that you know directional this way
that way or the other
you know and
everybody else can too as long as you
know you share the seed
all that you know
yeah
are there any other projects you're
super stoked about past that like any
femme projects coming up that you're
you're you're pumped about
ooh i got that patient zero common
patient zero is on its way
uh i don't know that that one's gonna be
interesting um
i'm not sure how that was gonna turn out
but you know we'll see
it could be cool maybe you could explain
for people because you have so many
names uh because you're so prolific
about things what is patient zero no
patience zero is a
you know uh
um basically it's the just the urkel
across the pakistanis to troll kush and
i grew up a hundred and something of
those years ago and my absolute favorite
planet
uh that one was a
was was the one i named patient zero
um
and you know it's it's kind of
as long as you like a little tropinoline
on your diet it's pretty all right
and so maybe i'll add that to it too
where it's like a lot of modern breeding
today is
one-offs where people hybridize
something and then just toss it out to
the public um
what he just described is what's known
as like multi-stage breeding
where he made a cross he grew out a
bunch of phenos he picked one that he
liked and now he's doing further work
with that pheno itself
probably crossing it to itself
and crossing it to other
uh cuttings that he has in the stable
that he thinks might blend well with it
right
um one of my favorites i actually have
uh flowering right now um
is uh
the mendo purple number 54 selection
from you know growing out that last
hundred and something of those
the urkel 103
you know s1 and then you know those you
know um i reversed the 103 slapped on
the mendo man those are uniform i mean
as uniform as you can get really yeah
that's cool
interestingly uh the mendo is extremely
dominant on it uh really yeah they're
all they look more like mendo purple
plants
then
you can barely see any urkel to them and
the both of those selections were made
out of that room that i came and visited
you and saw before you uh
the s1s of urkel and the s1's and mendo
p
yeah yeah yeah yep
but uh
yeah yeah
um definitely interesting though
um
i don't know
yeah i was excited too like about i
don't know if you want to talk about any
of the purple punch stuff or if that's
you know what i mean like the
the findings in that you're kind of
saying that are unique yeah yeah um
the
we we've talked and the most surprising
thing about breeding with purple punch
is
how [ __ ] stable it is i mean mentally
right
when you're working with you know it
doesn't matter what you know ogs diesels
chem dogs girl scouts you know
and then all the popular stuff based off
all those yeah you're gonna find a nice
portion of you know
hermaphrodism you know
more so if you know
your your environment's not a you know
perfect but you know even if you have a
perfect environment there's always going
to be a percentage of those
but the purple punches
have almost the lowest
uh levels of hermaphroditism i've seen
in
any hybrids
so
i mean that's that's useful that's
something people look for and i think
like the fact that it popped up in an og
gdp was kind of shocking you know
yeah yeah
and you know i i was i was the
i wasn't a huge fan of purple punch i
didn't even you know start growing until
a couple years ago you know
i i kind of ignored it and was like i
got plenty of my own oracle hybrids i
don't need another one yeah but uh you
know it has traits that it put puts
forward and
you really can't argue with it you know
yeah that was the same way you know we
both just kind of dodged hype for a
while with like the [ __ ] the the
gorilla glue and that and then end up at
the end like [ __ ] that shit's kind of
good there right
last one to the party that's an
interesting that's an interesting aspect
that people maybe should hear about is
sometimes you can have an amazing cut
that checks a bunch of boxes
and it breeds like [ __ ]
right it's all over the place it throws
a bunch of junk and it yeah the quality
inherent in the cut itself
doesn't seem to translate to its
children very well and then other times
you can take something like purple punch
that they're just talking about that has
a lot of nice traits but kind of lacks
high or whatever else and you don't
think that much of it
and then you cross it to things and its
children come out incredibly amazing
with a bunch of traits that you like
right so sometimes a breeding parent can
actually be kind of a crappy
crappy plant in some ways like
uh caleb likes a lot of the s ones of my
mendo p
quite a bit more than the mama
oh yeah
you know the mama is amazing for
breeding but as an actual plant itself
there's some aspects to it that are
unpredictable and and it's low thc
right right um but some of its children
and some of the things that it throws
and when you breed
um and sometimes you might take
something like purple punch that people
make fun of and you breed with it and
you're like wow this thing is amazing
it throws all these traits consistently
that are useful
right
i mean like you could talk for a minute
about how stable
that bubble gum cut you have is
why you use it in so many different
things because it throws like rock you
know it it doesn't rot very easily it's
got incredible structure it densens
things up right
right right
well i don't know about
it's really not the densest cut out
there but it's it's uh
it's definitely a um
you know as as rot resistant as you can
you can get a plant you know
um on on my worst year you're ever
outdoors i think i was aiming for like
700 pounds or something and
then we had six inches of rain the last
week of september
you know first week of october and i
lost 50 to 60 percent of that garden to
mold
and the only thing that came through
that garden with probably less than one
percent rot ratio
was that bubble gum cut yeah
you know
so you know tons of people are like you
know what's your best you know
mold resistant you know blah blah blah
well
right there you know
so that outdoor queen
yeah so someone sometimes those traits
like they were just talking about like
you know
caleb does an enormous amount of
breeding so for him to say
that the purple punch is some of the
most non-intersex stable thing he's ever
worked with is saying something
right you know when he says that like
this plant is almost immune to mold and
it's the most mold resistant plant i've
ever seen
and it passes that trait to some progeny
that's useful information
right yeah
i see a lot of people commenting on the
purple punch strength and like when
breeding has changed um from where it
was maybe 10 years ago on what we would
select for potency-wise what we wouldn't
use what we would use certain one of us
you know um purple punch all i'd ever
heard about was how weak it was so i
just never
i never got into it however
it is a is a very extract
centric community now
and with extracts pretty much
everything's [ __ ] strong um so so a
lot of things are are more chirp-based
now where people are are checking out
what kind of terps are being passed how
they breed and uh yeah i mean
some people won't want to won't want to
[ __ ] with anything that doesn't lay them
out me i i like all kinds of ranges of
different highs and i don't like being
laid out so for me purple punch is
[ __ ] perfect
oh yes
yeah
you know weed weed affects humans in
different ways
some of my favorite strains to smoke on
a regular basis the other two guys that
were checking that you know they don't
like it that much
they agree it's it's a super quality cut
but it's not something with their body
chemistry that really adapts all that
well yeah i have friends that only like
incredibly potent indicas because they
want to be hammered down
and a sativa makes them crawl up the
wall
yeah i have other friends that smoke a
sativa and they relax
right that would be me
so yeah so cannabis and cannabis and
individual strains uh don't think that
the way it affects you is the way it
affects everyone
there's a range there
yeah
that's why i like keeping so many
different you know
cultivars because you know i i like a
whole spectrum of different things and i
know other people too you know like
different things so you can't always
breed for yourself
definitely not
does the does the purple punch reverse
uh yeah yeah it reverses fine
interesting so it reverses easily but
won't ever throw intersex traits
yeah yeah that was kind of odd in itself
right the the s1 i got grown now i don't
think i found a single ball
or or or a manner on any of them
yeah which is almost unheard of oh yeah
yeah
you're usually going to get at least 10
to 20 percent you know and i i say 10 to
20 and that could just be one ball down
low or one you know
a late man or something but there's
always going to be like 10 to 20 percent
yeah
and then there's certain things that um
herm
but reverse
right right you know i mean we've talked
before about we're not going to get into
it too much but you know they uh you
know the old sour cuts are famous for
not reversing oh yeah
or getting a handful of seed but they're
also famous for the wrong conditions and
they they throw manners that can see i
create seed in your room for flower
production yeah it's really easy to grow
it buffy
i had a add some sour some sourdes in a
in a fully seeded room just recently
and
you know completely full of seed and
about week four it just starts balling
up just hanging all kinds of sour diesel
balls
even though it's fully seeded so the
whole room was completely seated so it
didn't have any risk of pollinating
anything but you know it still felt the
need to you know
throw out just a ton of balls
like what are you doing with those you
know
i didn't see any pollen off of them but
you know
yeah
yeah i mean the you know the um the the
what i consider to be the original but
you know it's the one i got the chem d
cut
uh is pretty famous for throwing a bunch
of nanners at week three four
uh but they're sterile
you know they don't really they don't
really uh you know uh
they don't they don't really make seed
yeah and that kim d or just chem d's in
general it seems yeah they they throw
bananas like they're going out of style
yeah
and it's a trait that goes there and so
i've had any number of friends or
helpers or whatever on a light depth
greenhouse come to me panicked
because half the greenhouse has bananas
popping out all over
right i'm like oh calm down calm down
it's it's the d we're gonna be fine
you know and we're fine you know you can
find a bean
yeah
but you know you do that with cherry pie
or something and you have beans
everywhere
right
so certain things certain things are
different different risky you know
there's different levels of risk
yeah yeah yeah very so i mean maybe we
should maybe we should chat about this
maybe we should reel it back in for a
second
um part of the reason why we did this
nl5 chat uh both starting in the 80s and
going through some of the history and
then bringing caleb on was to talk about
the project that that him and matt have
going
and uh
they they just dropped the seeds i
believe
yes or were about to or just did no no
they're dropped
caleb's caleb's site is humble
csi.com correct caleb yeah that you
could buy them on there or on right
seedco.com
yeah and so it's a it's a it's a
riot and uh and caleb collab
um and it's a big open pollination of
genetics from
um one of the people that was intimately
involved in the old nl crew
uh so the the provenance is excellent as
far as like who it comes from
um and you know but then on top of that
too the proof is in the pudding
so you know um it uh
it's a chance for people to maybe hunt
around if you have if you're a little
adventurous and look through something
old
and something famous
you know
uh and you know caleb found a few things
in it that he was super excited about
and so hopefully you you guys will too
uh and one of the ways
that we're gonna make sure
that not everything is skittles og
cookie cushman's
whatever
is by people taking effort and reviving
some of these old things and making
fresh bats batches of seed that are more
viable
and then getting them into people's
hands
so the gene pool stays wider
yeah yeah so not only is it a cool old
project to something that's extremely
famous
uh and there's potential in it
but you can better believe that most
modern breeding with a few exceptions is
the same 30 or 40 cuts blended in a
bunch of different ways of the last 10
years
and this harkens back to a much older
time so there's a possibility there that
when you out cross things to something
that aren't like each other if you take
these nl5s and you start throwing it on
different stuff you have
you might get some unusual stuff you're
not expecting that's good
right
you know spring's [ __ ] with me sorry
guys no it's like because that's because
that's the thing is a lot of breeders
say that like sometimes you know
crossing two very distinct things
together
is where you really get quality pop
yeah
you know and you're certainly
introducing something older in the gene
pool that was very common 20 30 years
ago but now is many generations in her
bread
and so uh by these guys doing this
project where it's kind of getting
thrown out there again where it can get
bred into a lot of modern stuff
and people get to see what happens so
you know you'll you'll get more
opportunities to see what csi is doing
with the work
uh in future breeding projects that seem
like they're already engaged
um and hopefully people are going to buy
a bunch of this stuff and start posting
and trying them out themselves
and it's one of the ways you can keep
cannabis history alive
right and making the words with the
stuff yeah yeah
you know mixing it with modern things
and seeing what happens
right right
so
what do you guys think would be the
best
you know available
uh plant line whatever
out there to cross to the nl5s
you know
i i personally i want to see the hogs
breath in all five i think that would be
cool if if we could track that down and
do that again it's been out of my hands
for a while but i think that would be
interesting just because of the terms
how about you not so
you know i actually think that um
it might cross well with something like
the dog [ __ ]
um okay okay
you know
kind of a potentially almost a back
cross potentially almost i mean a back
cross has to use the the technically the
same cut to go back to but
maybe something that is very nl
uh because one thing i'll say about that
dog [ __ ] grown indoor is boy does it
look like 90s weed
like lime green with bright orange hairs
and it just has that like nl type of
like like look
i was going to say hydro but uh caleb is
purely organic so i don't want to insult
him it's just that like
that like big sack of hydro nl that you
would get you know that's just super
frosty and stuff like that and so
um you know but it might give it some
stretch and some vigor and it might kind
of like and that's kind of like what i
like one of the things that i get
interested about is crossing
two different things that you think have
similar parentage behind them
yes and then you see if you get some
throwbacks
because both parents have it
yeah i i do have the dog [ __ ]
in uh my my latest round uh
so you know but it it's it's getting
across to that that chocolaty um
nl5 male and
honestly uh i think there were better
uh there were males that
kind of looked more similar to dog [ __ ]
but uh
um i you know
i i didn't use them personally for this
round
um
because i liked that you know particular
you know chocolaty one and if i was
going to throw out one more
recommendation and combine the old with
the new
um one of neville's most classic
combinations was uh nl5 and skunk
and
i kind of view
uh the diesel family as
cert what we have is surviving modern
skunk
not that there's not cheese and a couple
other things like that but
i kind of view like sours as american
skunk
right or very very skunkish so it would
be kind of cool to see
like what we have now is skunk and what
we have now is nl blended back together
right um because that was one of the
most classic best-selling and they
combined super well
yeah
i definitely have cheese in there too so
you know
you know at least junk one are you
talking skunk one or
skunk
i mean i that's
cheese is fine that's obviously pure
skunk one that's really old i was just
thinking of certain diesels just because
i consider
i consider certain diesels uh modern
that to me that even though it doesn't
have the name i consider a diesel to be
like a skunk skunk skunk oi type plant
right right it's tall it's rangy you
know it's it's got that kind of skunk
type growth to it it's got these very i
basically think of like gas and diesel
as it's not like roadkill but it is on
that skunk spectrum
it's like different angles of the same
terps
yeah you know yeah it's kind of how i
see it so
you know
um
but yeah and then the other thing too is
that you know you know you cross it to
things you hope
are gonna cross well and then you cross
it to some things that are just random
and sometimes those random ones end up
being the best ones because you really
don't know and you really don't know
what genes are gonna pop
right right right and you really don't
know what recessives are in there true
true right like so to take it back to
humans
unless both parents have the gene you
can't have kids with blue eyes or green
eyes
you know you if if one parent has the
recessive the other parent has the
dominant it won't combine
right blonde hair is the same way both
parents have to have the blonde hair
gene or the red hair gene or it won't
pop
and so sometimes if you take two things
that you think might have similar genes
you might get some recessives that pop
and all of a sudden something unusual
comes out
you know
yeah yeah so
yeah well i promise to to
not hold caleb too long i know he's got
some [ __ ] to do tonight too so i i i'm
thankful for you coming and talking
about the northern lights i know
everybody's super stoked to be able to
hear about it firsthand
um
but yeah is there anything else you want
to talk about before we all balance
uh i think i'm good i gotta go wrangle a
five-year-old beast
at least yeah we know you know uh friday
night isn't the easiest night for you so
we super appreciate you coming on and
shooting the [ __ ]
and all that you know and uh
you know i briefly saw your face in the
shadows there for a minute before the
pitch black kicked in
um but yeah you know um that's that's
kind of it we wanted to chat about nl we
wanted to chat about the history we
wanted to clear up some misconceptions
and we wanted people to hear
about some of the specifics of what was
available how it was made what you what
we saw in it um and let people go from
there
so as always everyone thank you for
giving us part of your friday night
you know caleb where do you where where
can people find your seats again
uh humble csi.com
there you go yeah humble tsi.com we'll
grab the nl5 please
okay go experience it make sure you let
them know about yours too
yeah i got it too but but you know
support the man
yeah so you know both both both guys
have it you can get them both off each
of their individual websites
um they were communicating a bunch
during the during the grow they were
talking about what he was seeing
sharing pictures and just
you know and all that and so um you know
it's how a lot of it's a lot of passion
projects get made today is with uh uh
people that have similar interests
collaborating and making it work
so support it if you can if you you know
it would be great
uh and it would spread out some old
genetics and it would keep them alive
and you could do your little part to
make sure that the gene pool stays wider
and hopefully find some fire
yeah
you know
you know everybody enjoy their friday
night uh as always there's a million
questions we didn't get to um but you
can always hit us up on our discord menu
we're on our channel
[Music]
patreon yeah matt and i chat up there a
whole bunch we're pretty responsive to
questions
and all that and so
you know every every friday night we'll
try to bring you something new and
pertinent and interesting and bring on
various friends we have
uh and all that and uh kind of just push
the history and the info forward
and at the very least you can see not so
naked all right thanks everyone
enjoy everyone you have a great night
[Music]
you