welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate so yeah so how yeah so we had
questions about from people about this
too so yeah just go for it so you know a
lot of this is your you know you don't
you can't test your weed at home you
don't know if it's exactly 20% or 23 or
18 um so if you're going to use flour I
mean you can look at your flour and make
a a good guesstimate of like what you
think if you're getting a 20% THC flour
and so with flour you can look at it
where okay so 1 G of flour is going to
have 200 mg of THC in
it and then that's how you can you know
then you can figure out okay if I got
you know this many grams of flour than
that you know you can do your math from
there
um when I use
hash like uh bubble
hash uh or even dry sift um and not and
I'm talking about dry sift before you
clean it up uh would be at a ratio where
I figure about you're dealing with the
50/50 you're going to have probably 50%
heads and others in 50%
THC when you're dealing with just hash
or dry SI
so for every 1 gr you're going to get
500 mg of THC with those two now when
you move to rosin it's more along the
lines of like with the foo where it's
going to be up around 60 to
80% of THC um I know when I wash I've
had several batches tested now and my
hash comes in at um over 80% THC um um
that's not the case for everybody like I
saw somebody's Temple Ball results and
that Temple ball came in at only 60%
THC um but that's because it wasn't made
into rosin it was made from the the the
hash and that's why I said that hash you
can figure in at 50% and you'll be
probably safe with your guesstimate so
rosin you can
figure 60 to 80% if you're doing a good
job as far as like like the 1 G will
equal 600 to 800 mg of THC for every
gram you put into
something um and that's how that's the
math I've always used it seems to be
pretty
accurate um you know without a bunch of
lab testing and all that we can't be
scientifically exact but my bro science
has worked that way so far good yeah I
mean I would even call it bro science
right like you you just being consistent
within what you yeah I I think just
knowing that like how would I put
it partly it's because you know what
you're working with right like you know
the flower you're working with you know
it's consistent you know the hash you're
working with you know you know it's
consistent and I think everyone just has
to develop that sense of you know their
own material and and and consistently
working with It
ultimately
um and yeah like some of those I think
are just broadly good tip like thinking
about uh the material working within
these little chunks and just trying to
estimate like okay if x% of this chunk
is going to be you know this mass is
going to be THC then you know roughly
this that um but yeah like you said as
well ultimately no guarantee uh without
actual testing um but you can like
you're describing definitely find a
process that's consistent for you I
think
okay uh
any you you did of course mention the
fact that like again different kinds of
material you know uh flower versus hash
versus Rosen um any any other tips there
I think we had someone who was asking
about dry sift in particular like is
there anything you know that you could
say to that or is it you know ultimately
the same same question I would say that
uh if now if you static Tech your dry
sift you're going to get a better ratio
of THC cuz you're you know pulling out
mostly heads but if you do a dry sift um
I always go with the 50/50 it's half
half it's going to be 1 gram is going to
have 500
milligrams um of THC in
it yeah cool is it really easy to I
shouldn't say easy is
it is there a standard for guessing how
much THC is in something like I see a
lot of stuff being like okay there's 500
milligrams of THC in here but with all
the strains testing different and having
different ratios of stuff like how does
that work it's all a guessing game
unless it's going to a
lab I mean it it really
is uh cuz you can't you know like I said
unless you're getting that flower tested
first and then or you're having hash
tested you know then you don't know you
can only guesstimate based on you know
what you see in your hand um the quality
of your flow the quality of the dry sift
um you know it all it it's just like
with hash the whatever quality goes in
is the kind of quality you're going to
get out from it [ __ ] in [ __ ] out as I
always say
yep yeah yeah
yeah and and again I guess it just comes
back to having whether or not you have
some kind of sense of internal
consistency at least like within what
you're making and at least then like if
someone is buying or consuming your
product at least you have some kind of
internal measure that you're like using
at least your base units are sort of
consistent I guess yeah yep yeah yeah
okay interesting
one um maybe a tangent off that is uh
how much of a hassle is it to get these
things tested as someone who doesn't
live in the US and can't do that ever
like what's it like to get you know
products
tested it's it's a it's
expensive yeah very very um I haven't
even had a chance to get my Edibles to
Market to be tested yet um I do know
when the last thing I was working on was
the uh water soluble drops that we made
and uh oh my gosh I had to I think we
sent it to testing three different times
because you can only have 100 milligrams
in the package so we had to do the whole
formula where we
knew how much THC was you know per mgram
of
the drops and then we had a 10 MGR
package and so we had to figure out how
much we had to mix with water in order
to get 100 m into that 10 mg
package and uh so we did that and then
we had it tested and one of them was off
by a little bit and one of them was
exactly on like perfect so that's the
exact ratio but then the other one so we
had to readjust
it and send it back and then it tested
over so it had to come back and be
readjusted and sent back and then it
tested at the right level
that sounds fun yeah
right I never knew I was going have to
do so much
[Laughter]
math math you're really in like uh
chemistry territory almost much more so
than like a regular grower would be
right in some ways um because you're
both in extracts and Edibles and I
realize as well that your greatest enemy
is chlorophyll in all of it one of the
one of your biggest enemies in both
sides is
chlorophyll
definitely and you know the thing is is
that chlorophyll actually does have
benefits it's an anti-inflammatory I
mean it does good things for you it's
just there's certain things like you
don't want it in your hash and you know
if you don't like the taste of weed then
you're not going to like the taste of
chlorophyll
so do you make uh trim smoothies are you
into
that Che
your salads uh no because since I don't
like the taste of it what I do do is I
make I juice the leaf and then I freeze
dry that juice and I powder it up into a
capsule oh that's smart yeah damn nice
okay so I have and again is this to get
some of that like thca quote unquote or
like why would you do this why because
the actual raw cannabis plant is amazing
it is is so good for you like it's got
anti-inflammatory properties it's cancer
fighting just 15 raw cannabis leaves a
day is enough to fight off any type of
cancer and so since what part of why I
did the capsules is because like for one
you can't always have fresh cannabis
leaves around and a lot of people don't
have access to cannabis leaves so um and
by juicing it I got it down to where I
can juice it and then I freeze it and
freeze dry it and powder it down and I
have it down to where I've got 15 leaves
into one
capsule so you can take one of these
capsules and freeze drying doesn't uh it
leaves you with 97% of the nutrients of
the plant so it doesn't degrade it like
when you uh dehydrate something or let
it dry naturally it doesn't degrade the
nutrients in there there and so you're
still it's like taking that raw cannabis
still but it's in a powdered form that
you can just pop and take and have
anywhere with you any time of the day
you don't have to be harvesting it
doesn't have to be right now
so there was a time when I would top my
plants and just eat the tops like
immediately but it was a pretty full-on
experience like the flavor is intense
it's so gross it's really gross you
should try the juice like a weird ritual
I made Buckshot try the juice from the
juicer and he was like oh
no yeah that'd be bad that'd be like
drink wheat grass ju I'm G to try that
so grass like drink grass so gross so
gross probably worse man probably even
more intense than that oh man have you
ever drank wheat grass like I've had
people give me shots of that before to
like I feel like I have not for a long
time it is so foul and and bitter like
the worst kind of bitter like just
instant it triggers my instant gag
reflex so B people enjoy drinking it
though it blows my mind when I've had
full leaves uh the main thing I think
that that gets me is they often taste
very peppery to me um and that is like
quite a
full-on uh yeah
anyway uh okay well was next
so you another point about oils into
capsules uh yeah that's a great way okay
like um for example uh electric ladyland
ask about uh the
RSO concentrate and um this is a great
way to go into that because uh and
address his question as well is in my
opinion uh when you make the RSO or F
whatever you want to call it um and you
evaporate the alcohol it then becomes a
concentrate it's not in my opinion what
I would call a tincture at that point um
if it was still in the alcohol it would
be like a tinure but when you evaporate
that off it concentrates it down and I
will take that RSO and put it into MCT
oil and then I put those into capsules
because um for cancer patients sometimes
the well for one the taste of RSO is
horrible
it's sticky nobody wants to put it in
their mouth I know some people put it on
toast or crackers they do all kinds of
stuff um and if you use the concentrate
itself too it's really hard to get it um
into a capsule of its own and so if you
put it into uh like I like to use MCT
oil um and then it can go into a capsule
just like you could uh take your rosin
pucks after you press your rosin and you
can soak those in MCT oil to extract
what's left in there out and then you
can turn those into capsules and then
you have something that you can uh have
a you know titrated dosage of uh like
with the RSO I can get them to where
there's I want to say like 150 Mig per
capsule so that somebody wants to make
sure they take uh th000 milligrams a day
they can take you know they know I going
need to take 10 of these capsules a day
um so yep that's why I found the
capsules to be helpful cuz a lot of
people are used to taking pills anyways
and uh they don't mind it and that way
you don't have the taste uh or any of
the inconvenience of dealing with the
actual FICO or RSO
itself yeah I think capsules in general
are a great way to make it look less
scary like I even though in a much more
amateurish way you know make my own oil
and occasionally we give them to friends
who are not into smoking at all but
because like you said they're in capsule
form you know it's a lot less I don't
know scary or something yeah I mean
something they're more comfortable with
in a custom sure exactly yeah and they
loved it yeah all of them loved it um no
good tip uh anything else about that
capsules uh I don't think so
what's this one actually the
preservative a good way because okay oil
when you mix stuff in oil you have a
tendency you know especially if you're
using Leaf um you're
introducing stuff into the oil that
could cause it to go bad faster and so
you can choose to use a preservative you
can do this with your gummies as well
cuz gummies have a tendency to go bad
quick uh Lorraine candy sells a mold
inhibitor um that you can buy and use
that in your product um it's the same
thing they use in all kinds of different
things to preserve stuff on the Shelf um
and then uh if you want to get more on
the natural side of things there's a
rosemary oil that is a preservative that
you can put into the oil before you make
the capsules so they'll last longer so
you don't have to worry about them going
bad if uh you like you make a bunch of
oil to start with um it would keep your
oil from you know expiring if you didn't
use it within a couple months or
something uh and especially if you're
using the capsules and you want to do a
bunch at a time you'll know that it's
okay they CU if they'll they turn cloudy
in the capsule you know that's bad don't
take a cloudy
capsule um I've seen
it yeah sorry no I finish this yeah
sorry I had somebody that Miss messaged
me they weren't my capsules they had
gotten them from a weed for warriors
donation and they sent me a picture of
them and I was like do not take those
when that oil in those capsules turns
cloudy that means it's expiring and it
could like botulism could be in there
there could be all kinds of stuff in
there um cuz you put plant material in
it so I always caution people that if
for whatever reason your oil turns
cloudy or your capsules just it's you're
going to have to take the loss and not
use them I had a question about spoiling
cuz um like I mentioned you know I'll
make like a big batch at the side of the
year and I'll Chuck it in the fridge um
I really see it go off but is that
partly because it's in the fridge um are
are we talking about products that you
know lie around at room temp or no
technically something in the fridge go
off you know just as easily but maybe
take longer the the fridge will keep it
preserved longer like I I was that's
definitely a great Rec recommendation uh
for any cannabis product um to make sure
it lasts longer because anything that
sits out at room temperature um is going
to go bad faster especially those
oils so even if you have capsules yeah I
tell anybody I give capsules to put them
in the fridge you know they'll stay
fresher that way and last a lot
longer yeah I haven't thankfully haven't
seen capsules turn cloudy yet but that
doesn't sound
good not ideal
no
okay
um I I don't know did I mention this on
the while we were recording I can't
remember but uh I know at least before
the recording we were talking about how
this might just be part one um in a in a
sense of like a series potentially
because you know we could obviously ask
peaches to talk to us about the various
you know products that you know she
actually has experience with but I think
today was mostly about getting some of
this foundational stuff um out but we
did have a kind of like last little
section maybe before we get to some of
the community questions on was it was
your idea like
broadly baking um and temperature and
time with respect to baking paches ah
yeah like CU I've been doing Edibles for
a long time and before there was a bunch
of research like I remember whenever I
baked anything I would bake it at like
200° for way longer cuz I didn't want it
to get over a c certain temperature and
uh now you know everybody's done some
more studies and you know you can bake
your brownies at 350 in the oven cuz the
actual internal temperature of your
brownie doesn't get to
350° um and
so uh but you have to keep in mind cuz I
see people uh who will like be frying
things in oil in medicated oil and the
fryer oil is medicated and they're
frying in it and I'm like okay that
temperature is too high all that THC has
been
like fried out and converted you're not
going to actually get high from frying
something in the
oil um
yeah uh just the one thing I've learned
with baking though is that uh I used to
have to bake things at a lower
temperature and now I found that you
know you can just bake them at the
regular temperature um for your regular
length of time I do have a tendency
though like I don't always buy it when
something's over 400° I have a tendency
to turn it down and cook it for longer
um with you know certain baked items but
uh
uh I have found that just leaving it at
regular temperature is fine cuz it used
to take me a long time I used to do uh
snicker doodles were one of my favorites
to make and man it would take like an
hour to bake a thing cookies at a low
Temp and it's just funny to see how
things have you know come for Full
Circle when you've done something for so
long and now there's new information out
there and we used to all be so careful
about not getting it too hot and now I'm
like oh I'll just put my brownies in at
350 they'll be
fine very good
tip
um well technically we're kind of out in
terms of the the points that you wanted
to address peaches but I wonder just
because we've mentioned it quite a few
times and just to give maybe everyone
almost like a sneak preview could you
give us an overview of the gummy making
process just a broad
overview uh yeah or your one
anyway the recipe I mean I have two cuz
you can make it you can make rest
without gelatin and do it with fruit
juice and stuff like that those ones are
a little more difficult they take a
little more setting up in time uh my
favorite go-to gummy recipe is just with
some gelatin Jell-O and glycerin it's
really basic and simple and and you can
whip it up and have gummies ready like
in 2
hours nice yeah uh that one you could go
ahead you go sorry um you could use
either oil or um alcohol or glycerin
with it um I I will post like if we want
to start a thread I'll post the actual
recipe up um for everybody with the
ratios um but I just use a one it's a
small box of Jello-O and uh two packs of
gelatin and then your carrier oil and
then I like to use the mold inhibitor
because gummies will mold quickly um and
you just heat it up on the stove melt it
all and you pour it into the molds and
let it set and chill them and then you
keep them in the fridge and there like I
said in like 2 hours you got gummies
ready to eat jeez okay I thought it was
for some reason I thought it was way
more drawn out of process than that so
essentially it's assuming you have your
oil or your glycerin MH um it's just a
matter of mixing it together and putting
in the molds is that right yeah the yes
the process you're thinking of is the
one where like if you're going to use
instead of gel like cuz some people
don't want to use gelatin um or Jello so
you can use
um the
pectin uh you can use
agar um yes I was going to say that too
yeah okay those are two different
options and yeah cuz somebody had a
question about pectin and it being
having containing pesticides which uh is
a you know excellent point I do know
that they do offer a certified organic
apple pectin um and then the agar is
another option if you want to avoid that
stuff but that process is more drawn out
that's when you use the fruit juice and
you got to warm that up and then your
carrier goes in and you got to you know
add your pectin or whatever you're using
and cook it and do it and then those
ones usually have to yeah they sit out
and like they have to dry it's a whole
process those ones have to be
sugared um yeah that sounds like a lot
of work
um I mean I assume that people are
staying away from jalous because they
don't like the fact that it's from what
horse Hoops or horse Hoopes um uh or or
there's one other thing though is
korium use that
you know what that is what's that
castorian ohar with
this no it is it is in a lot of like
gummy worms and stuff like that it is
the um it's something extracted from the
anal gland of a beaver oh yeah that's
where they get raspberry extract from
there you go there you go everybody eat
Beaver [ __ ] yep from
Beaver I was just waiting to say that
awesome that is awes I mean I kind of
find this stuff fascinating because like
so many things come from Super strange
places like you know those like uh
there's that particular is it the red
color that they get from the shell of a
particular like Beetle or something and
they' crush them oh yeah yeah yeah and I
kind of remember yeah this stuff
fascinates me honestly um story him
buddy look before you eat be a butt Beav
a butthole okay and it's like the anal
gland too on top of all the gland even
that's awesome even from the
[Laughter]
gland well it might be a good time for
us to get to some of those Community
questions I think we we addressed some
um but yeah there are a few more uh I
will say that these questions also cover
some extract stuff because you know um
peaches is our resident you know
extracts and Edibles person so okay I'll
just start from the top we had one from
herbs SD on gummies I don't know if we
cover this already is there an easy way
to turn rosin into gummies what's the
best F oil to use any trick and getting
them not to
separate
yeah uh well I would get sunflower like
and that'll be your first thing to make
them not separate um the other key when
you're going to use oil is doing the
stacking method so you're not like so
you can use half a cup of oil instead of
a cup cuz cuz the less oil you use the
better um so if you can stack that batch
so you get more into it then you're
going to be better off um I find that
the
gelatin gummy recipe works better with
the oil um than the other one does in my
opinion and uh you just you need an
emulsifier to make it
work yep nice LSD do you find different
cultivar give different effects in the
Edibles I assume yes right but yes
definitely without a doubt yeah
that's can be one of those ones again
where it's like super complex and yeah
never really know I guess until you try
it well yeah and it's you know it's
really hard to always have one cultivar
in a certain specific edible because
you'd have to grow so much of that
specific one you know so it it's kind of
hard in that sense unless you know
you've got like I have before like I
said made a batch of tincture from all
strawberry banana and I can tell you
that batch of tincture smelled just like
the flower it was quite
amazing was that Mt say it again is it
that that's cool that it actually tasted
my mind yeah I want some now I want some
blue I want some blue Edibles get on the
map yeah yeah I'm I want to try that
that sounds
awesome um kind of closely related I
want to know why Edibles are Hit or Miss
for some people like why they work
sometimes and and sometimes not it's I
mean do you think this is partly
cultivar related peaches or is there
something else you think um well I would
say the first thing would be the
decarbox because some people don't know
about that so it's possible that someone
has gotten Edibles that weren't decart
oh my God now if they're from the same
source
and you know they worked that yesterday
today they didn't seem to work the same
uh there's a couple of factors uh the
time that you ate them uh if you have a
full stomach it's going to take longer
for you to process that through your
system whereas if you eat it on a empty
stomach it'll hit you faster um your
metabolism plays a role
some people you're going to fill it in
30 minutes other people it's going to
take 2
hours
um the other thing I always tell is
sometimes people's math is off what they
think is 500 milligrams is not so it's
possible that you just got a lowd dose
edible and you're used to it um then
there is the whole fact where cannabis
is totally metabolized in the liver and
it's done uh it's called the micro romal
cytochrome and that is what helps that
makes you get hot um it delivers it to
your blood system so some people have a
gene variant in that uh specific cyp 2c9
receptor and it doesn't allow them to
get high it doesn't process the Cannabis
into their system so they don't get high
from it so just to clarify you mean when
they eat it right um but these people
will still get hyp from smoking it yes
because that's different effect yeah
that's right cool and then the whole
other thing uh is so we all have
cannaboid receptors so we can use
cannabis that's why it works on us um
some of us have 10,000 receptors some of
us have 100 so when you eat the Cannabis
if you have a 100 then your system's
going to get flooded because you only
have so many but if you got 10,000
receptors that same amount of cannabis
is not going to work the same on you as
it does with someone with a 100
receptors so that's one of the other
facts besides that liver enzyme that
plays a role as well as when you eat it
and all that factor
um whether it's
decarbed I think that's all the factors
that would go into why it would or
wouldn't
work very nice it's yeah it's it's kind
of as
complex maybe arguably more complex
because they're more layers um uh as the
question of like why some cultivar might
get someone high and someone not or you
know why affects someone differently
there's so many variables here um down
to the process down to the flower itself
down to our bodies you know so yeah very
similar I think
um okay 's
next next question would have
been um this one's about washing and I
wonder if actually I might just direct
them to checking out your the first
episode we did with you this is from BL
blaza uh newbie intro to washing kit uh
someone more wanting to learn to wash uh
do do we cover this in the first episode
I can't even really remember I'm sure we
did um I don't know his thing was about
like essential equipment
right um I would say just to touch
quickly your essential equipment to wash
at home would be you need
bags um at least 5 gallon
buckets
um something to hold ice you're going to
need Scoops something to wash with
that's your basic something to dry on
want some screen
um I think that would
be
um oh a sprayer for spraying down your
bags yeah that you've mentioned that
before yeah that's a good one I think
that would be your like main Essentials
and then as far as like if uh I think
you ask about with Edibles too um some
of the main things I use regularly is
the double boiler uh my convection oven
my other oven before I had the
convection oven uh
thermometer
strainers um my nut Mel bags and a
scale yep
yep um I think we covered mountain
flowers hemp's question which was on uh
pekon yeah in
gummies I gotta add that in he has
really good he has really good hint
mountain flowers very good very good
uh that's cool yeah I did not
know um we got electric ladyland yep you
covered that question and even I think
uh Zaza Papa I in the win uh how hard is
it to have repeatable product yeah we
covered this kind of about uniformity
again as well um yep and we did talk
about being consistent with your process
some of your measurements But ultimately
it does come down to testing and that's
the only way can give you an absolute
guarantee but otherwise yeah Pet's did
Cover what what she tries to do to
ensure
consistency y um those are the questions
that we've got did you get sub
robs oh yeah yeah yeah sorry yeah thanks
for reminding me very detail pull it up
yeah he did let me read it
out okay Mr subb asks if using ke for
baking do I just melt butter and stir in
ke and will it spread evenly throughout
baked goods that way how much per stick
of
butter um
yeah okay so yes you can put ke into
butter but you're going to want to
decarbox it
first
um and you're it's going to be spicy the
thing about ke is it is spicy when you
eat it yeah when you use it to make
edibles it it's spicy
I've made Edibles with Keef that are
almost almost hard to
eat can you explain I don't get this one
like how is it different from you know
other extracts it's just heads right and
stuff why is it different I think I
think it's just I I'm not positive I you
know I haven't researched it very much
but there's definitely something about
cuz like to me the rosin is kind of
spicy but not as spicy and I think maybe
it's cuz it's been processed and
squashed out um May it helps hold back
maybe some of that material that you're
getting in there cuz like with Keith um
you still got you know the stocks and
others in there when you make keth it's
just it happens that's why I said your
ratio is about
5050 for THC to the heath ratio so
um I think with rosin when you press it
that stuff gets trapped in the bag and
so you don't like to me rosin Edibles
taste more like rosin um then they and
hash then they do weed uh where ke to me
doesn't taste like weed but it tastes
spicy and like you said when you ate the
weed plant the top of the weed plant it
tastes spicy to you so I'm assuming
maybe it's in the stock of
the THC head you know like how you you
want to set the rate the head but you
have the stock so in my opinion maybe
that stock is what is
spicy that's cool I mean Kei is but
rosin
isn't probably another good prompt for
people to chime in in the comments if
you've if you've experienced this let us
know more data um yeah I find that
really
interesting and as far as the amount you
would put into that butter it would be
on how much how strong do you want your
brown need to be and and and it will
once you melt it in there it'll disperse
evenly you just want to mix it in really
good um but it would depend on how
strong now I would do the math that I
have one gam of Keef and that's going to
be 500 mg of THC so let's say you're
doing a brownie batch most brownies have
nine in the pan if you want you know
each brownie to have 500 mg well then
you're going to have to add you know n g
of ke to that butter to make that browny
have that
much if I'm doing my math
correctly I'm sure you are better than
mine I'll take your work for
it I'm sure somebody will point it out
to me if I'm wrong definitely
definitely um those are all the
questions we've got but I because okay
by the time this episode comes out I
think it's going to be January or
something but when we're recording this
it's the 20 well 21 no 19th for you guys
20th of December for me and probably
gonna be the last recorder for the year
I think Matt so I kind of wanted to take
the opportunity to ask uh peaches what
what she has in store for 2024 just for
fun um well uh I'm going Peach crazy
crazy on the hill this year that's for
sure that's awesome though I love it
know that was a big chase for you it was
it's been like five years now that I've
been actually searching and so finding
it is is pretty cool yeah I'm going to
be definitely trying some breeding this
year um with that peach Veno and
um that I have some some plans that I
want to try and um and I'm hoping that
this year they I just got a message from
my boss up there talking to me about
moving up a trailer cuz they're ready to
start ramping up
fulltime um which means I'll be working
up there 5 days a week and so um we'll
see I I have my finger crossed that all
goes through and works out and um it'll
be all worth the while that I've spent
the last few years you cut out a little
bit can you I think you're cutting
she out oh it's me okay my bad it's all
right that's
okay so yeah hopefully that goes through
um we have an investor lined up that's
supposed to bring a good amount of money
to the table and if so then that means a
regular paycheck for me on paper and
it'll be a whole different
world that would be nice right I hope it
goes through I I truly do me too it's
been a long road yeah fingers crossed
deserve it
thanks you make me
proud thank you I try you definitely do
you definitely
do yeah I mean uh that's more or less us
for for today for this one for the year
I think
um peaches like I mentioned earlier May
welcome back for uh the next outdoor
growing episode EP so stay tuned for
that whenever that happens
um
and that's kind of it for me really
anything from either of you shout outs
wise or anything else to add to this
this this
episode uh no just at the
end I was just going to say if anybody
has any questions uh they want recipes
or stuff we can either start a thread or
message me um you know come check it out
on Discord I give away a lot of
information on there to people
help you guys make your medicine um so
come join the Discord I'll help you out
and hook you up with some tips where it
goes
down yep yeah
absolutely all right do you have
anything El yeah not really uh apart
from um you know best wishes to everyone
over the New Year break again by the
time you see this that would have passed
already but hope you have had a happy
holiday um and otherwise we are on the
cusp of hitting 10,000 Subs which is
pretty cool wow man and I have a small
wager uh about when that will happen I
think Matt saying it will happen janary
when when was it Matt you go January
beginning of
January I said specifically
beginning ambiti feel like you've made
it even more ambitious now I thought you
I thought you were saying it was like
mid gen now you're saying it's the start
of gen okay beginning of January bro we
are hitting 10 ,000 and if we don't I'm
stopping the show and nobody gets show
quit this is over everything just ends
yeah damn them all don't need
it it's All or Nothing guys um so you
guys better do it or or no more show
essentially it's where it's go Step Up
server is going down just close it you
know we're all quitting weed Never Gonna
smoke again exactly that's it done done
I'll get a new career teaching kids I'll
teach kids how do you like that go back
to my old
job math or
English history
history history back to special ed
that's where I really belong so that's
where I need to
be hey that's man that that's doing
God's work I don't know that's it it was
hard it was definitely challenging but
it it was never challenging really
because of the students it was always
challenging because of the parents I
will say that I love the kids
absolutely love
it
respect all right man hand it over to
you to to sign us off all right well um
if you enjoyed the episode be sure to
leave some comments below I try to
respond to everyone but I definitely
read every single comment that comes
through as I'm pretty sure thousand does
too we both are uh big on reading the
comments and responding um what else do
we got so by the time this comes out the
jel drop should have happened the jel f
hybrids and s1's Riot seeds.com we also
have the blue dream s1's out and a few
of the hybrids but there's going to be a
lot more coming with the blue dream ones
uh from goat farm so check the site for
that um we have some of the silver
Mountains from high and Lonesome the
silver Pearl Appalachia insane insane
stuff um you can get our spray at the
site um also check out ger by seeds for
Australian carrying um of of the breeder
Syndicate stuff which includes all of us
um there's also what do we have lifted
seeds uh in the US as well he's a good
friend of ours carrying all of our stuff
and we have Riot Seed Co Europe for our
European fans for the riot seed stuff
and hopefully we can get him some stuff
over from the rest of the Syndicate as
well um I think oh there's a codex go
check out our codex I need to add some
more to it and hopefully over the
Christmas vacation I'm gonna have time
so that'll be uh another fun adventure
maybe we could do a little episode on
whatever you end up uh updating as just
even just a Roundup uh you know of of of
the changes you've made or new
information you've gotten I think also
going through it like one by one on the
screen with it on and like going through
and talking about things that maybe I
don't even add on there because they're
too controversial but that I'd like to
add you know things like that that would
be fun yeah I think it' be cool even I
could even see that being like a live
stream kind of vibe too uh oh yeah we
wanted to yeah I have a I have a bad
habit of like deleting my live streams
after for whatever reason I just get I
don't like what I do I don't like what I
not yeah I I you know how I am with
editing myself like even when I'm
editing like there was a long period of
time where I just cut out everything I
said just one of those
things I know the vibe I understand yeah
I was actually gonna say that though
even those uh Instagram lives that you
do those would you could just slap those
on YouTube and you know people would
probably enjoy just
I [ __ ] hate myself on that stuff hey
now you can use streamyard for it too so
that's right you know and uh yeah that's
that's a good point I should be using
streamyard for the live Fe shouldn't
I anyway sorry like nextstage stuff um
but this is anyway that's the end of the
episode the end of the episode screw it
and thank you so much peaches for uh
sitting with us we always enjoy your
company and you're Fountain of Knowledge
when it comes to ex
tracks like Edibles everything so we
really appreciate you and appreciate
your time and I hope you and buck have a
happy holidays yeah thanks appr holiday
too I appreciate you guys well with that
go check out the patreon and the Discord
if you want to be a part of the Discord
got to go through the patreon and uh
it's very cheap very affordable we're
keeping it that way for now so yep and I
think that will be it thousand you also
have a happy holiday holidays and I'll
make sure with my atheist ass to not
open a
present with that love y'all cheers see
you next
yourish peace want to sit at the table
with The Syndicate check out our patreon
and our link tree or description below
our merch site is officially live we
have all sorts of shirts hoodies and
goodies to sort you out and shipping is
super fast and most importantly the
quality is topnotch I've been saving old
designs for years for this purpose so
please check it out out Syndicate
gear.com we also have an underground
Syndicate Discord where we get together
and solve old strain history together
daily it's an amazing community of
learning away from IG and it's an
amazing resource for old cataloges and
knowledge we hope you join our Union of
breeders and Growers come check it
out