welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to reader Syndicate
I'm Matthew here with thousandfold and
today we are here with peaches and
thousand what are we going to be
discussing so we had Peaches on last
season to talk about extracts um in
general and today we have R to talk
Edibles because that is the other the
side of what peaches does um and yeah
very excited we've had a lot of demand
um a lot of people ask peaches you know
on the on the server all the time like
how she does this and that so naturally
we thought we'd have her on the show for
for this one um so before we got into it
though I just thought it would be cool
to break the ice a bit and ask peachers
about how her outdoor season
went actually you talk better broadly
paches yeah uh it went great actually
everything uh came off we had a
staggered Harvest uh from anywhere from
you know seven weeks out to the 11 weeks
for the sour and uh it went good we got
rained on a little bit but nothing got
moldy and the most exciting thing for me
is I actually found my peach turps so um
from all the way through I had one
Barber red feno that had Peach turch she
smelled like it while she was
growing uh after harvest she smelled
like it and now that she's been hanging
and curing she still smells like it and
the other day I was smoking a joint and
I was like oh my goodness it tasted like
I ate a peach fruit
cup and it was shocking it had to wrap
my mind around the fact that I was not
eating a peach but I was smoking a joint
that tasted like peaches so I Love Weed
like that it was amazing and I managed
like I don't know we were three weeks
from Harvest or so maybe four months I
don't know she was fully budded when I
took the Clones I was so behind and uh
got those clones and they managed to not
only root but reved and now I have two
fully vegged plants and gallon pots
ready to go so very nice it was a good
year yeah maybe later on we can ask ask
you what what uh what Edibles those
might go into or what you think might be
a good fit for that
flavor def I have a couple things in
mind does that that kind of flavor carry
through to the
Edibles H I don't know yet because I've
never had one uh that had Peach chps I
know that like when we do the when I've
done the tincture the glycerin tinure
with strawberry banana flour it smells
like the strawberry banana flour those
tur
come through all the way through the
cooking process and everything those
those TS hold strong um unfortunately a
lot of turps burn off at different
temperatures so you'll lose them during
the edible making process um but uh so I
haven't I haven't tried the peach one
yet I'm interested to see I've got a
couple of peach treats that I make that
it would be interesting to see how they
add to all that I'd love to see if blue
works Works its way into in in like that
for flavor that would be cool see BL all
that
stuff yeah I'm glad Matt that you asked
that question I I realized as soon as I
said you know asked about the peach
thing yeah I had no idea either um about
how turps make their way through that
whole process um yeah but we will we
will be approaching that um maybe any
other highlights peaches from your
Harvest apart from your your Peach plant
um
well the bubble Berry from you know Matt
did excellent I was really stoked on
that one uh they they all did really
well everything you know it was uh you
water every day and you put effort into
it every day and you pluck leaves and do
all this stuff and it it just came out
really good this year we have really
good tur profiles um on everything good
bud structure and absolutely no mold I
mean we got a couple times of rain rain
where it just rained and nothing broke
we had great structure on everything it
was it was just an overall good beer for
the Harvest good love to hear that yeah
it doesn't always go that way that's for
sure no not
always Matt how's your outdoor have this
G uh I just knocked it down all but
except one two three plants so the um
pry punch f2s are G to be harvested in I
don't know two weeks whenever I whenever
it's all dry and then I have the uh what
was it FL Flo no F1 der fler I have that
one in flour and it to be honest it
smells like cookies dead on you know
like dead on um yeah and then there's uh
I think I have some something from
Professor P out there too which is a
miss universe that got hit by the creamy
punch and yeah there's one more creamy
punch to harvest that's all black purple
and it was the only one that went that
extreme black purple but I I don't love
the TPS on it so I'm not sure that I'm
going to
do it's only one did wasn't extremely
Blu smelling out of all those can you
repeat that last bit Matt I think you
cut out for a little bit it was the the
the blackish purple one was the only one
that didn't have extremely blue turps
out of the creamy punch much more along
the silver Pearl so I'm not sure if I'm
going to even keep that one like or or
the seeds from it because I I'm really
partially hard Blues out of that
stuff definitely interested to hear more
yeah as you as you go along smuggling
that outdoor grow information out of me
evil I know sorry I love doing it we're
gonna have to KI you out the episodes I
know for to the outdoor side true
outdoor grower
bro all right well I think we can get
started let's talk about decarbox
everyone's favorite yeah yes so many
opinions on this one yeah what what
comes to mind when you when you think of
this it's essential uh for Edibles if
you don't DEC carboxilate um you're not
going to get high you're not going to
get the same high because technically
thca does have benefits and it does
things for your system it helps with
pain and inflammation and stuff like
that but it doesn't create the high that
people want when they eat an edibl so if
you don't do that decarbox where you
convert it mostly over from thca to
THC um you're going to have a different
effect and people are going to think
your edible doesn't work um I have one I
have one little question here on TDA and
something that I've never really you
know I'm pretty ignorant about it if you
try to infuse a bunch of material
without decarbox silation I is there a
purpose for that like I mean you're sort
of implying that there might be a
function well yeah
because uh the thca is still a canabo we
still can take it and use it but it
doesn't allow us to get high it creates
a different High um and then it works
more um on your pain receptors than
anything so if you were going to make
yourself a TC a tincture you would just
know that you're not going to get that
same cerebral high that you would get
from one that's been decarbed as you
would you know that you're just going to
get some more pain relief um than you
would just getting
high just like if you had um a strain
that had more CBD in it and you didn't
decarb it um then you're still going to
be fighting that high you're not going
to get high because like when people
take Edibles they expect this you know
body high to get tired you get that
cerebral high as well as just like some
people get couch locked you know um and
so if you don't decarb it then you're
just you'll feel something but you're
just not going to get that locked
feeling where you're just like oh I'm
high yep that makes sense yeah yeah so
in terms of uh THC then and and that
conversion what kinds of you know yeah I
think in the outline you wrote
temperature and time like what kinds of
parameters do you think work well or
have worked for you um I like to keep it
at 200 degrees for at least an hour um I
like to use my uh convection oven
uh to do it but you can use your you can
use anything a double boiler a regular
oven uh whatever you got to use to warm
it up but I prefer I go for 200 once you
go over 200 once you hit the 210 stage
you start to convert it to
CBN um and so you don't want to do that
you want to you know keep it as THC so
you don't want to take it over 210 so I
go with 200 for at least an hour
um and that's with whether I'm doing
flour hash dry sift
rosin um anything a lot of people like
to uh put their oven on and then they'll
put the flour in there first and like
roast the flour to decarb it before they
put it in the oil or into a butter or
anything whatever carrier they're using
um I have found that when you do that
with the flow first it creates kind of
like a roasted flavor almost like when
you vape flour you know that uh how the
old you know like when you vape and you
get your stuff out of the thing it has
that weird popcorn smell to it yeah yeah
totally okay so if you do the flour
first in the oven you're going to get
that flavor with if you just put that
flour and oil in a mason jar with a lid
on it and put it in the oven you're
still going to decard that flour but you
will not have that
weird roasted taste so just so I'm clear
on it in this situation you are
decarbing and infusing at the same time
more or less yes M yep that's how I do
it like even with uh rosin I'll put the
rosin in the jar with the
oil um or whatever you're going to use
um you know if uh you're going to decarb
it into
butter you know I don't use a jar for
butter that's a whole different one
um but a lot of yeah all my decarbing
usually happens during the process of
infusing whatever I'm going to
use um to
make because previously I just thought
that there was no of you know no
difference quote unquote between
separating the stages or doing them
together but yeah that's a really good
point about the flavor or you know what
um doing the cup separately might you
know it might have consequences in those
in those
ways um I had another question here
which was does your approach change
depend what kind of uh material you are
decarbing like whether it's flour
whether it's an extract uh does anything
change for you not with the temperature
and time no it's all to you know cuz
it's all you're trying to get that THC
to convert so whether it's the flour
you're using or the concentrate it all
takes the same
process um the only thing that changes
uh that the only thing that's different
about all those ones is the when you use
leaf or flower you get more of that weed
taste yes yes that's right and I think
yeah well yeah that's because people I
think people have asked you before I've
seen them um asking you like how do you
how do you minimize that right and I
think this was your one of
your yeah it was one of the questions
from um somebody who was
it just over the last day look yeah they
uh posted about it in the
um let me see oh appy Hills Hills yeah
um I would say it using hasher rosin
makes the least wheaty um hash and rosin
it's more spicy than it is that weed
flavor um because I can't stand the weed
flavor like I it'll make me gag I love
it horrible I can't stand it I think it
makes everything way better no there's
times when I'm like out of habit you
know you cook stuff and I I try to taste
things to make sure they taste right if
I'm making brownies or a cake or
something like that and every time I'll
go to taste the brownie but and then I
regret it
immensely every single time this is
quite random but do you remember me and
Matt talking to you about pandang that
that leaf from Southeast
Asia yes I do weirdly I think that kind
of Aroma would actually work really well
with yeah I might have to try actually
now now that I'm say I might have to go
and try it I think you should because
that's that's more on the side of like
vanilla coconut
already those flavors might might
actually kind of work with with the
flavor of so
good it's also green it's already green
as well anyway sorry but total
tent um in this I did want to ask Matt
as well another tangent Matt how much
Edibles have you made like how much
experience have do you have like making
stuff Dex I've done it like three times
total I have a a machine we bought um
supposed to it's called is the the
purple one no no
it's God tip my tongue but it's this
little machine that decars it for you
and makes like I don't I don't even know
what we never used it um yeah I've only
done it a few times and the way I decarb
is in the oven done it that way but I've
made awful animal awful I'd let it burn
up and it was
horrible which is not good not good at
all
really stunk up the house too that was
the other hard part was how much it
stinks up the house when you do it wrong
I don't know if it does does it stink
that bad when you do it
correct uh it stinks no matter
what yeah it's just that it's that smell
it Wass even if you put it in a jar with
the lid on it you still get some
smell makes sense yeah see weirdly it's
the smell of it puts me off more
especially if I've been with it like if
sitting with it all day then it it does
start to get to me
lot
yeah okay that's cool okay so was there
anything else about decar oxolation that
you wanted to talk about
peaches no I think that covers it
honestly it's really a simple process
it's just I think sometimes people
forget to do it sometimes people think
that rosin is already decarbed because
you press it at a higher temp but it's
not on
for it to happen um so it's important
that if you are making Edibles that you
take the time to do this because
otherwise you're gonna you're G to be
sorry yeah
cool and I think something that you did
say that I'll just repeat or highlight
again the different canono do actually
have different uh points at which they
convert so yes um I think you mentioned
CBD is it lower or is it higher or um
not sure about the exact temperature of
what when it converts to CBD I'd have to
look that up um I do know that it two at
210 is when THC starts to convert to
CBN and that's the one that gets the red
color and it makes you more tired than
anything
um sorry yep yeah that's that's what you
get when you like uh you know a lot of a
lot of people will do their already
Vaped Bud right
iag that's a lot of CBN right yeah
exactly or like older weed that's been
around like sitting around for a year it
contains higher levels of the CBN
because it's aged and it's converted
over time and
oxidization
yeah um okay well the next interesting
topic is actually going to be carriers
and this is this is is interesting to me
so different fats or different oils have
different capacities to absorb or
hold um the can
canono um peaches yeah what what do you
have to say on this
one um yeah when you're going to make
edibles you want to use something that
contains fat as your uh either fat or
alcohol um because you need that fat to
help transport it into your system when
you digest it and all that that's part
of what happens in your body body is it
it latches onto that fat Mo molecule and
that allows it to be absorbed and taken
into your liver where it's processed and
allows you to actually get High um so
it's important to use a butter a milk a
cream um you know you can use the MCT
oil because it's a medium train chain
triglyceride um which it makes it easy
for you to absorb it so it makes it a
little quick more quickly bio available
to your system
[Music]
um and then like the alcohol well we all
know alcohol absorbs
THC um oh yeah that one I didn't have on
the list yeah that's you know like well
I people so you know now the whole
conflict between RSO and Foo um you know
nobody makes RSO with napsa not that I'm
aware of anymore um Even Rick I'm pretty
sure made his with um grain alcohol you
know that's what people had access to so
I A lot of times refer to it as RSO and
have to be told well no you don't make
it with Napa you make it with alcohol so
it's considered Foo which is full
extract cannabis oil yeah so you know we
have to be terminology correct
sometimes
definitely um so you mentioned that some
of what distinguishes these carriers are
like the capacity to hold and store you
know the canabo and then also the way in
which they make those canono available
to your system once you've ingested them
um what do you use the different ones
for or do you use do you use like a
range of them or do you have you kind of
gravitated towards you know a couple of
them um does it matter on your
application um I I have different ones
that ief f for certain ways um like when
I'm going to make a tincture um I love
to use the MCT oil um because it it's
just it's a great carrier um and then uh
the milk or cream works great if you
want to make uh flavored coffee um ice
cream
puddings um you know anything that
contains milk that you don't want to
have to try to substitute oil in for you
know because a lot of people have you
know make oil and then they will
substitute it in for something um the
butter I love that for your basic cookie
recipes um brownies work great with the
oil because you always put oil in
brownies you know
every brownie recipe calls for like a
third cup of oil as it is so you're not
adding anything extra to that um and and
then uh now when you want to do
chocolate a lot of people like to put
the butter into chocolate which is great
you can make a grap gach with chocolate
and all that but butter in chocolate
will cause it to expire faster so that's
why I recommend uh using cocoa butter if
you're going to infuse chocolate or a
coconut oil um but some people have
coconut allergies so that's when you
want to look into if you got somebody
with a coconut allergy you can use
avocado oil um and then you can use the
cocoa butter um also and then it goes
into the chocolate and you're not adding
anything to the chocolate to make it
different chocolate already is cocoa
butter um and I think people forget
about cocoa butter a little bit because
it's a solid that you have to melt um
but it still will Infuse and works great
to put into
chocolate very nice nice
you know and then butter you can cook
with on the stove uh avocado oil too
when you infuse it you can use it to
dress your salads make a salad dressing
um you know season your vegetables it
just depends on how you want to consume
it or eat
it yeah that Mak sense yep
absolutely um I just trying to
think anything else anything else about
like uh making your your choice about
which carrier um beyond what you've
mentioned already any anything else that
comes to
mind um
well I would have to say that in my
opinion butter has the strongest taste
out of all the carriers like when you
put cuz butter probably it takes the
longest and to make and I think uh you
end up with more of that weed flavor in
the butter so if you're trying trying to
stay away from that that might not be
something you want to make and use yeah
I will say that in my you know my my
personal experience that is the one that
um that is the one that has the the the
greatest tendency to make me like uh I
don't know just feel quite grossed out
just by being around it all day um it's
butter and and weed for sure because
it's so it's already so rich on its own
butter you know when you're heating it
up combining it with the musk of
cannabis is just like full on very
potent that's for sure yeah yeah okay no
that's that's excellent I had one this
is more of a tangent because I know this
is an Edibles episode but if you were
making a topical what what kind of like
what kinds of Base would you what kind
of a Bas would you use for a
topical um I like to use a mixture of
shea butter and mango
butter interesting
okay yep I do a a 5050 mix of those two
and then uh I also use
a uh with those two Butters I use a
Jehovah
oil um an MCT oil and then
glycerin and then I use vitamin E as a
preservative yeah I was I was fully
considering making some for my
girlfriend for Christmas she's got like
sore neck and stuff but I I might have
to wait I might have to like um follow
up on this with you and and get a bit
more info I'm down to try it and maybe
another episode too unlike topicals
perhaps yeah most definitely and if
you'd like I'll send you my recipe the
actual breakdown of the um weights and
stuff and it comes out really good it's
not too greasy I've got it down to where
it's more of a cream type it's it's a
whipped cream uh and it's pretty
effective so if you'd like I'll send
that
to yeah absolutely yeah I would really
appreciate that you you can't you don't
get high of it right like my girlfriend
does not like does not like I don't I
use it and I don't um I've never had
anybody tell me they did I did have a
lady who used one of my bath teas and
salts and fell asleep in the bathtub
cuz she got so relaxed she didn't drown
no she didn't drown but she fell asleep
in there her husband had to come find
her now this is making me want to like
make some some topical cream and and try
rubbing it on like in like the inside
and stuff to see if it will get in me
anywhere but I don't know also just I
assume that it's like a localized thing
right if you rub it on your arm most of
it will not get into a bloodstream so
yeah yeah I don't I think it would take
a lot to actually you know get all the
way into your bloodstream and to you
know I do know they do know make those
topical cannabis patches now so I know
it has to get into there some to some
extent but I don't think it's in there
enough to like if you it was like eating
an edible where you'd be like oh [ __ ]
I'm high
yeah because she would be really mad if
I gave it to her and then she got high
off it like she'd be pissed I could
understand so
I've missed the I think I've missed the
window to make it for for Christmas but
I'll do it for another
time well Valentine's is coming up yeah
there's that too
[Laughter]
easy okay um if we're happy with the
carriers you had another point you did
already touch on it but did you want to
go into the glycerin tincture again in
more detail
maybe uh yeah we can do that for sure
what so what do you use this for because
I've never really myself I've never
really heard of this what is this
glycerin is awesome because glycerin is
water
soluble and uh so you can also and you
can use it as a topical um you know it's
a hrant for your skin it helps keep the
moisture in uh that's why I use it in
the lotion and then also it doesn't
affect your the insulin as much as
sugars do um there's some research they
did about that um so the cool thing
about the glycerin is that you can use
it like I like to use it to make gummies
I prefer it to make gummies way more
than oil oil to make gummies is a pain
in the ass um so glycerin makes great
gummies it uh you can mix it with just
rubbing alcohol and use it as a topical
um you can drink it straight you can put
it in your coffee you can put it in your
soda you can put it in anything you can
drink it straight if you don't mind the
taste um so that's what was you know
awesome about it the reason uh we chose
a organic vegetable glycerin and we
first did this recipe when uh Buckshot
was on uh fentanyl Soma
celibre uh LCA all those gnarly drugs
they had him on for his back pain uh
when he went to get off those we
developed this glycerin and uh it works
uh it just takes time you you have to uh
it's not one of like a lot of people
think with the glycerin uh you either do
it like you would do a normal decarb or
you have to let it sit for six months
which is one way to do it but nobody
wants to wait around for six months to a
year for your stuff to
infuse right um so he
uh had some
research with uh that he had done and it
was skunk Farms put out a article about
how to do the glycerin
tincture and uh
so uh in the middle of learning how to
make all this is that that's how he
figured out how to do the formula so
that you can actually extract the THC
into the
glycerin um and so our ratio is you get
a gallon of Glycerin and you can use
anywhere from 4 to 6 oz of flour it kind
of depends like you know if you have big
buds that are bigger then you're going
to
um uh want to use 4 ounz per gallon but
if you have the smaller ones you can get
away with six um it's important that
glycerin poures way better when it's
warmer so if you warm it up before you
pour it over the flour um it works
better and then uh what I use is a it's
a little induction burner thing you know
it only works with certain pans and you
put it on there and you set it um to run
at 190 to 200 same thing you don't want
it to be going over 200 and you run it
um on the heat for 4 hours and then you
pull it off and you put it into an ice
bath to cool it down and if you don't
have ice or you don't want to buy the
ice you can let it it at room
temperature but it takes longer um so
you let it cool down and once it cools
down to room temp you put it back on and
you heat it up for 4 hours again and you
repeat that process six
times and during that time you keep
stirring it um frequently so it doesn't
burn to the bottom and you're you know
making it kind of like when you're
washing hash you're you're forcing the
glycerin to go through the buds and you
know absorb through and pick up all the
THC and so you do that for six times of
warming and Cooling and then you strain
it um I found some nut bags for making
nut milk um they're like 200 Micron and
a couple other 180 I think
Micron and 100 Micron and you use those
and you strain it through and uh you've
got glycerin that you could put in your
bathtub because it's water soluble so
you could take a bath where the THC
actually goes into the water and doesn't
float has oil on top that's wild that is
wild yeah and then it is it's pretty
awesome and we've actually had it tested
and it tested to where we got 1,000
milligrams of THC per ounce of Glycerin
at that
ratio and you know so it it makes good
medicine and you can put that right into
a drink too and uh you know or like uh
those Sparkling Waters um I also put it
in just a bottle and I'll flavor it like
lauran has some great candy
flavorings um yeah that you can put into
it and then you got a watermelon
flavored tinure or cherry or grape or
whatever flavor you
want so just to be really clear here do
you ever use it alongside a carrier oil
or no it's it's instead of most of the
time I use it with uh oil um when I make
my uh
topicals because my topicals have an oil
and glycerin in it and so I like to use
both of those
medicated into the
batch yeah gotcha but that's the
exception generally it's like uh like
you were saying because I guess the the
ultimate product is like a yeah
waterbased thing so you want to use
glycerin for that instead of of the the
oil but yeah okay no I get you now
that's cool no thanks for telling us
about that I don't think I've ever heard
of yeah that's a new one for
me yeah it's a pretty awesome product to
have have you seen it used uh any other
ways that you youve came to try out
yourself oh yeah I was a saltwater taffy
you use glycerin to make saltwater taffy
so I'm in I just haven't had the time to
make it from scratch yet but that's one
thing I haven't made yet that I've been
interested in trying it
in
yum right I just need a Taffy puller
yeah right everybody's got one of those
laying around right just right there
simple Taffy
puller um okay or anything else about
glycerin otherwise we can move on no I
think that's it on that one oh if you're
going to uh uh a lot of times not only
like when you if you want to press the
like if you use the flour to press the
flour to get the glycerin out of it um I
like to use a wine press back in the day
I did have to use a potato racer cuz I
didn't have a wine press um but those
are the two pieces of equipment that
come in handy when you want to like you
know extract anything like if you're
using oil even or even if it's glycerin
oil butter and you want to strain your
Leaf out and squish it so it comes out
uh I recommend a potato racer or a wine
press excellent info a lot
easier how about sunflower lein or
however you say that um i' I use this I
I I never questioned it I I just read
about it early on and it seemed to work
never never tried it
without yeah there's the whole thing
that helps you uptake the THC there's
that part of it that it makes it more
bioavailable and helps it carry into
your system the other thing about it is
that is the key if you want to make
gummies with
oil uh okay let me let me pause you here
because what you said was was already
something that I was quite interested in
which is at least the initial point
which was
um have you have you side by side tried
uh an edible with with and without out
and like have you seen the difference in
uptake because for me you know you know
typically you hear people making Edibles
especially back in the day when we just
baking you know brownies and whatnot
people would say that it took ages to to
kick
in um but when I when I have used
Lin I feel like it's it it kicks in
really quick but that's just anecdotal
like have you seen you know yourself
this
effect I honestly I haven't experimented
with myself cuzz the only time I use it
is when I make
gummies um gotcha okay okay so I would
I'll experiment on Buckshot
though yes I like this I like
poor all
right
captive yeah sorry go
ahead sorry I was just making jokes at
shot expense um gummies talking about
gummies with lesser than yeah um well
cuz it the not only does it help with
the hive but it um it's an
emulsifier so if you want to use oil yes
to make gummies you need an emulsifier
or you're going to have a horrible mess
it's no fun like oh my god I've had
horrible experiences with the oil and
the gummies so um you the oil just like
starts leaking out of them is that right
if you don't do
it out yep it will leech
out and so not only do you lose that and
then they like to mold easier it's just
it's just
gross um but I found uh they sell it in
liquid and powder I've only worked with
the liquid but I did find out a key with
the liquid sunflower was that I had to
let it bloom in the water like gelatin
before I used it cuz otherwise sometimes
it would Clump up um interesting that's
a good tip yeah it it took me a couple
times to figure it out but if you let it
Bloom the liquid Bloom um then you don't
have that issue and then I use it when I
made uh I prefer to make like I said my
gummies with glycerin but there's times
when I've had to use oil um sometimes
I've had to use alcohol just cuz that's
what I've had on hand and that sunflower
leathan helps with uh the oil one
immensely I just had to make one with
oil the other day and they came out
perfect you couldn't even tell they were
any different than the ones I made with
glycerin great
tip um yeah because for me like I
usually just make a big batch of oil at
the start of the year you know every
year and I just historically I've always
used lissan and um
yeah seems to seems to be good yeah let
me let us know if you get to experiment
with
buck I will tell us how it
goes okay anything else about that that
additive it's a good tip who haven't
heard it for sure no I mean you could
use it you don't have to just use it in
the gummies you like you use it in your
oil you can use it in anything to help
with that um it's supposed to be the
same thing like you know if you eat
mango it helps enhance the high it's
that same
idea actually this is a good one for
people to go try uh comment down below
if you have tried leathan and if you
especially if you've gotten to do a side
by side of some kind I'm I'm definitely
curious
um okay so you had a point here about
making full spectrum oil we kind of
talked about it already is there
anything to add PES to um well I I
recommend um if you're going to be
making that if you can afford it and
get it um I like to use uh it's by
extractohol and it's 190 proof uh it's
sugar
cane made from sugar cane and uh it's
organic um but I know everybody has
different budgets and stuff but the
higher proof you can use the better
because then you're getting a better
extraction of just the THC and less of
the chlorophyll and all that stuff um
the other thing when making it uh the
longer you let it soak the more
chlorophyll you're going to have in
there um you actually alcohol works very
quick at uh dissolving THC so you don't
have to let it um sit for hours you cut
out for a little bit in the middle of
that can you say that again that last
sentence uh yeah that
uh the longer you let the uh cannabis
sit in the uh alcohol the more
chlorophyll you're going to get out of
it uh the alcohol is very effective at
dissolving THC and so it doesn't have to
sit in there for hours at a time just to
get the THC it can just be I think like
the minimum is 5 minutes um and you'll
have your extract and then you can you
know
strain and uh get rid of it and that
stuff is supposed to be dabbable if you
do a 5 minute
scratched um so I like to do it let it
set for you know 15 minutes to an hour
in the alcohol and then strain it out um
the other thing with making it is you
can do uh what we term as stacking a
batch which is where you put your 4 to 6
oz of weed into a gallon of alcohol you
soak it let it do its thing you strain
it and then you add another 4 to 6 oz of
weed to that same Al alcohol and you let
it sit and extract it and then you
strain it and go from there and then you
get a stacked batch because you can't
put 12 oz of flour into one gallon
alcohol it doesn't work it's too much
your ratio is off but if you do it in a
stacked batch you could get a stronger
batch and uh not have to use as much
alcohol um also make sure when you're
making it you use a thermomet ometer to
keep track of your temperature um you
don't want it going above the 200 Mark
uh all the same conversion stuff like
with decarb and all that um then you
don't want it to burn uh and then uh
same thing using uh the wine press to
get it all out of the material and the
nut bags to strain it um I even there's
even we even use those uh gold cof
filters as a double strainer on top of
the nut bags it's like I don't know five
times filtered um and that the bottom is
the 25 U
screen underneath the nut bags and then
you'll get some very very clean um full
extract cannabis oil from that and it'll
be uh at about I would say 80%
THC um at that ratio if you make make it
like that that means like for every gram
you have an estimate of 80% of that gram
is THC so when you're making an edible
and you use one gram of that FICO you
can say okay well that's 800 mg in that
batch there is yeah I kind of one of one
of the sections in here that we wanted
to talk speak to was dosing and and
potency um was there anything else to
add to the extract oil otherwise I
thought maybe that's a good segue into
talking about like nope you know how how
you measure or estimate your do that's
the perfect way to Segway that was
everything and with that we end this
episode I wanted to thank uh peach first
and foremost for uh coming on and we're
going to have her again next week for
part two uh wanted to thank thousand of
course for always showing up and always
arranging these shows um we have some
real nice ones L down in the future so
uh other than that check out our patreon
and Discord um we hang out there every
day and it's it's a family it's pretty
pretty freaking cool and we nerd out we
watch events together we do all kinds of
stuff together and uh you save 30% on
Riot seeds and uh and uh goat farm gear
too um we also have
our reversal spray for those of you who
want to make your own femin seeds that's
available there as well just made a
brand brand brand new batch um we also
have uh ger by seeds in Australia if you
want to check out Riot seed and some of
the other breeder Syndicate members we
have Riot seed co- Europe for my Riot
seed stuff over in Europe with gold cut
we had lifted seeds lftd seeds on
Instagram he he carries a bunch of the
uh the the the breeder Syndicate members
too so go check him out we also have CSI
Cross or CSI collab with breeder
Syndicate what yes CSI collab with
breeder Syndicate uh with the gel drop
is very limited and dwindling and you
can save 30% on that too as well if
you're a patreon member so go check that
out and that's also available on CSI
humbold site directly um we are giving
out the sour gel seeds free with each
jel order um any of the packs so get in
on it before they're gone that's just
while supplies are limited and they are
very limited but we're also really proud
of it you're one of those people chasing
skunky notes it's there people have been
asking is it dead Is it alive it's there
get it get it while you can or you're
going to be out of it and trying to
trace down clones from a bunch of
scammers or God knows what so yeah go
get it and with that we'll see you next
week at The
Syndicate want to sit at the table with
The Syndicate check out our patreon and
our link tree or description below our
merch site is officially live we have
all sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies
to sort you out and shipping is super
fast and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out