welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
[Music]
revolution
welcome to breeder Syndicate I'm Matthew
here with my co-host thousandfold and
today we're going to be talking about
outdoor growing from beginning to end
and go ahead
thousand yep uh specifically we're going
to be talking about beginning to end of
flowering Matt so we welcome back booze
cush of the Giants little Hill um each
of them have featured before on various
respective episodes so I'll try to
remember to add links to each of those
in the description but yeah so today we
are talking about flowering outdoors and
of course we have uh Kush of the Giants
in little Hill um in California and
we've got booze actually from Australia
so that will be an interesting uh
contrast for one um but otherwise to
kick things off I thought we could just
go around and each of you give a brief
outline of like what your outdoor
growing situation is like uh you know
your respective area um and you know
what you're growing what you've grown
this season I should say um just to
start things off uh maybe we can start
with uh little
Hill okay great
um let's see what I'm growing this
season or where I'm growing I'm in
southern Trinity uh 3200 FT elevation
I'm in a mountain
valley um that's kind of a R thing up
here it's very mountainous territory and
there's not a whole lot of
Valley um flat sort of level Valley
areas up here so uh I'm kind of Lucky in
that aspect
um uh 3200 feet coastal range like deep
deep in the Coastal
Range I
uh feel like my season's shorter than
most because of that um like we we get
freezes into June
sometimes uh we'll definitely start
freezing at some point in October
usually uh hasn't happened yet but we've
gotten close um and then that we
actually got some good weather right now
coming up on the forecast but we've
gotten a lot of rain this year so far
more than usual um which has we'll talk
about it but it's definitely had made me
speed things up a little bit um as far
as what I'm growing I think we covered a
lot of what I used to
Outdoors um in the last episode that I
was on Betsy and heart attack and
pineapple and stuff like that purple
wreck
um and then I kind of stopped growing
outdoor for a few years as legalization
kind of moved in and I and I
transitioned to that um everything I had
was in green houses everything uh I was
depping everything basically and then
replanting for a second run usually
under like full-term
Sun um but now this this this past
season I've I've got to expand and and
the cheapest way to expand is just
building some outdoor beds so that's
what I did um they're they're only six
inches deep um and then the native soil
underneath them is all tilled and
amended so maybe I've got 10 inches of
like loose soil between like the native
soil on the bottom and potting soil on
top and then of course the potting soils
all amended with dry
amendments and uh I tried a bunch of
different strains kind of like
everything every strain I had on the
farm I kind of gave it a bed just to see
what's what because this is all new
genetics for me in in the outdoor
environment in the in the green houses
like it's kind of controlled so some
things don't matter like finishing time
and stuff like that but on outdoor full
term it absolutely matters and what's
going to mold what can withstand the
rain what can withstand the cold um what
yields still like this what like what's
the final product look like and is it
marketable you know as an outdoor plant
um I
also planted very small plants like so
each 5 by 96 bed has is is a row of
three with like 50 to 55 rows of three
so there's like whatever that
is 70 plants in each bed or something
like that a give or take like the
numbers vary but it's about that so
they're only like at most say six foot
tall plants um single colas for the most
part uh very tightly T grown in very
tightly um so they're smaller plants
they're not Giants um because plant
numbers mean nothing at this point with
legalization
um uh so strains I'm running I'll just I
can kind of see my garden from the
window here
um I got some compound genetics uh none
of which I'm that stoked on Jokers
grapple pie and carbon
fiber um I've got my cut of uh T1000
triangle um from CSI uh that I selected
several years ago that's just gun killer
so far I've got a lot of that in there
ice cream
cake um papaya bomb
an OG Kush S1 from
CSI uh two different uh selected phenos
of uh 707 Kush and 707 OG from 707
Seedbank and I feel like I'm forgetting
something but I can't think of it right
now um but so just a huge variety I
don't usually grow that many different
things next year it'll be like three or
four strains in that whole area instead
of instead of the mish
mash no that's amazing and um you know
one of the reasons why I wanted to get
three of you specifically the three of
you is because each of you are actually
growing on um very different scale uh so
I think that's going to be really
interesting to get to later on and the
other reason that um I really wanted the
three of you on because each of you has
a great Instagram um in all honesty and
each of you are
actually in my opinion like really
really good archists and the way you
document your grow and all that is like
amazing like I love I think both little
Hill and booze you guys both do really
nice like running commentaries on what
you're doing like on on like audio and
then Kush does these really cool
writeups so anyway that's just kind of
extending the intro a bit but um yeah
thank you so much for that little Hill
uh maybe we go to Kush next you know
tell us about your general outdoor
growing situation and you know what
you've been growing yeah so for me it's
it's real similar to little Hill um just
like opposite County of him across the
valley um about 3,400 elevation and uh
again similar with I have a little
Valley on the side of the mountain where
generally it we don't get a lot of flat
ground to grow in so the benefits of
that and being right next to a little
creek up in the mountain too um helps a
lot with with what I'm growing and my my
growing situation now is um you know it
started with wanting uh to get weed
without having to pay for it so when I
first started growing that was that was
my initial goal and then uh I eventually
got some customers and grew enough and
people wanted some so it turned into
growing weight and then around 2008 18
or
2019 um people just stopped buying
weight so much and so I I just started
turning to what I liked and not only
what I liked but started popping stuff
that I've never had the chance to grow
before and I just wanted to see what
what performed well out in my area and
uh it it's it's it's been an explorative
Journey since about
2018 um mostly popping stuff through CSI
and his unreal Vault um you know you
order a little bit of seeds from him and
you end up with more than you can pop
and that's that's kind of what I've been
doing now is just just going through old
populations of stuff that people talked
about in the past stuff that I used to
get but never got a chance to grow
myself and it's um it's been really fun
exploring and testing the the limits of
these strains especially in the uh mold
and the mildew and the the late season
uh strength of of these these
plants and as far as what I'm growing
this year um it's the biggest variety of
plants that I've ever grown this year
and it's for more seed more guys from
The Syndicate and a wider variety of
breeders that I've ever messed with this
year um I got Pax atw hybrid that are
just absolutely gorgeous pure tealing
with all those berry flavors coming in
behind them which is which is really
cool for the tealing I like that a lot
um I got that blue resin Kush from Matt
going she's a little late but man she
smells amazing right now and growing
some uh what else are we growing pull up
this um oh yeah the sweet 16 hybrids so
like I don't know shoot it was late into
the season and CSI hit me up he's like
hey man I got some of these seeds we
grow these out for me I was like well
it's pretty late man but they look good
and
I tried the sweet 16 before so let's
give it a try and man I'm just blown
away I got six different um sweet 16
hybrids and each of them are completely
just just wonderful Frosty all the
unique smells T profiles that I've never
encountered before just just strange
stuff like just like the blackberry wine
had had its own uniqueness that you've
never never smel before in the the sweet
16 um doing some appy stuff from uh high
and Lonesome all the mangoe goodness
that comes from those I've been really
impressed with how those perform
Outdoors the structures there the the
resins there the outdoor hardiness is
there I'm seeing a lot of the Green
Crack influence from the uh Appalachia
that that just holds up those
plants um what else are we running this
year oh yeah some of the snitch free
sour d from our buddy Louch and and his
buddy that plant just a a volatile
freaking chemical lime smell that that's
just beautiful I can't wait for her to
finish up and uh see what else we got on
Deck I got some of that cream some of
the 2016 bag Seed cream that she's uh
you know she's getting hit pretty hard
by the mold but it makes sense when her
buds are freaking the size of softballs
you know they look like old Salmon Creek
big bud stuff it's insane how big she's
getting um yeah other than that
not much else that's growing in the
garden this year um I got that Isn't She
Lovely from uh our buddy anaki genetics
up in Washington that it's a pretty
impressive strain I I wasn't expecting
much out of it at first but she really
blew me away the uh the mixture of grape
and pining which I've always had the two
separated I've never had grape and
pining uh Shar a a a compound before
which it's really really taken me back
by surprise I like that plant a
lot that sounds really interesting yeah
grape and pining together yeah yeah it's
Unique the first time I got my nose and
I was like what the that's those are two
two I haven't smelled before together I
really like that yeah that's unique very
cool that's cool also that you both you
and little Hill seem to be dealing with
more variety this season maybe than than
normal so maybe we'll touch on that
again later on right um yeah we can go
to booze so booze obvious in Australia
uh different timings um but yeah boo
tell us a bit about your your general
situation growing Outdoors there and
what you've uh this year I'm doing a
little bit of a scale back approach I'm
I'm planning on moving down south in
like five months or so so I didn't want
to go away with doing anything too crazy
um plan to move is to be able to do a
lot larger outdoor pops cuz somewhere
where land's a bit cheaper be able to
set up some poly tunnels and um get away
with that but yeah man I've pretty much
always grown Outdoors I only started
cultivating indoors last year with about
eight years of Outdoor Experience prior
to that so it's my love man I'm I'm
pretty tall dudes I don't like being
cramped inside a little small tent space
you know I don't have a room or anything
I've just got a couple tents so when I'm
Outdoors I'm yeah in my element I love
it everything bird song all that [ __ ] I
re are all three of you big I feel like
all three of you are like pretty big
guys that's pretty funny I'm pretty tall
yeah sorry like outdoor man I don't know
but yeah man um this year I've just got
a greenhouse so I'm in a rental I've got
like a three oh [ __ ] what's that in feet
maybe like a 10 foot by 10 foot
Greenhouse out the back um and so I'm
doing what have I got at the moment I
got some stuff from Crybaby I've got
Cedar Throne which is a Rings another
friend of ours gruesome of that out look
pretty good um that's like Afghan skunk
from Mr Nice cross to like cheese sour
Lemon Thai and then jel onto that so I'm
getting some some really cool plants out
of that that just running clones I've
got a Jager S1 from CSI so I ran a pack
out of those last year and this is the
what I kept out of that man it's not the
most potent knock you on your ass thing
but it's flavor is phenomenal for me
it's really medicinal plants it's
helping a lot with nausea and stuff like
that indigestion Etc and just the flavor
on it man that like licorice mango
little bit of like rotten garlic sort of
smell it's it's really complex super
turpy um what else have I got I've
popped some a friend of mine from the uh
the forums back in the day so I didn't
know him there obviously I'm young dude
but from the Mr Nice forums bucket bong
he was a guy on there and I linked up
with him uh he got me in touch with a
few Aussie breeders who I've got on the
seed bank and I got some seeds of uh
Bazooka Joe which is like a face off
bubblegum thing cross to MOX which is
the malum Oaken nl5 Hayes so I've got
like five of them they're fem seeds so
I've got uh five of them going got some
stoned AP from high l which is the gg4
cross to
appy uh what else have I got I got some
oh and I've just done a whole pack of A5
uh Blue Dream cross to A5 bc1 and that's
from doc d so I've got 12 of those so
it's as I said a bit of a scaleb
approach usually I like to utilize my
long season so where I am I'm in uh
Queensland so pretty similar climate to
I guess parts of Hawaii like I'm fairly
Coastal a lot of humidity pretty much
just year round uh we have about an hour
and a half of Devy in um in daylight uh
Hours come summer so say like 14 and a
half in summer 11 and a half in winter
so there's a little bit of a variance
but for the most part man you can crop
like all year round like I've got clones
out there right now and it's starting to
you know obviously the Daylight's
changing daylight hour is getting longer
now and nothing's really revegging it'll
probably be able to run its course but
yeah like what little Hill was saying
with the light dep that's what I want to
get into in the future like I'm I'm too
sketched at the moment like [ __ ]
getting out there at night and pulling a
top like even when I was doing like
supplemental light in the greenhouse
it's just sketchy man [ __ ] neighbors
and [ __ ] I got like no fences um but
yeah one day like once I get my my
property what I'm aiming at down south
that's what I want to get into doing
full season and light dep because it's
not really nice flowering [ __ ] out in
summer like unless I'm going to be doing
like some Colombians or like some of
this like Wally Wally duck gear or white
buffalo um flowering out like some
indicas in s it's just [ __ ] mold man
mold City a lot of the time so I like to
get a run done in
um yes man so that's yeah mostly what
I'm I'm doing this year outside and my
little
situation nice man thank you um yeah
definitely we're definitely going to be
talking about mold today I'll say that
um but yeah thank you everyone for this
little intro little Icebreaker I thought
now we could kind of pivot towards the
topic and for me uh this episode like
I'll be pretty light touch I kind of
want to get you guys started but you
know I think feel free to start asking
each other questions as well but I'll P
you along uh so again today we're
talking about transitioning to flower
and and and really all of flowering uh
so maybe if we think about it from like
a chronological point of view so you
know you're at the end of veg you're
aware that like things are about to
season about to turn um where does your
mind go first in terms of like what
you're concerned about what you might
need to prepare you know at this like
late maybe at the point of like late veg
early stretch um can go back to little
Hill de side us off so that's like into
July moving into August your your plants
have been out for a month or two um by
that point you know if you're if you're
planning like early June give or take
um so I mean just the way I grow
I don't really think too much about
nutrition because it's all in the soil
that I mixed in in the
spring um at least I shouldn't have to
think about nutrition um if something's
out of whack or something in in which
case yeah but um before that stretch
happens um if you're using trellis
netting for support um you got you got
to get it on early so that the plants
can kind of grow through
it you know as they begin to really I
mean they just explode in August between
you know August 1st and August 31st like
the amount of growth you get is is is
it's the most growth you're going to see
in the whole season so um you got to
have your support ready so the plant can
grow through it you can't do it after
the
fact
um I mean or you're going to break stems
and it's just a hassle it takes
forever um and that and that goes for
any type of support whether it's like a
fence a fence or something a cage um or
trellis netting or or whatever it's
going to be bamboo
steaks um I'd say that's the that's the
one thing you need to you need to get on
if you haven't done it
already
um other than that
like if you want to boost them with
nutrients and and capture as much growth
as you can you can maybe supplement with
a little extra uh nit Esten to really
capture all that stretch and get all
that size you want to get on them
they'll eat it up um if you give it to
them and then at some point like back
off and and and and give them maybe a
boost of phosphorus towards the end of
August um I'm I'm I'm a big proponent of
giving if if your liquid feeding is is
high phosphorus early early on in flour
if not before right before flour and
then and then backing off and and
transitioning to something higher in
potassium um middle middle of
flour um just from everything I've
learned and been told and seen that's
that's how that's how you crank them uh
but many years I I won't feed anything
and I'll just adjust my soil mixes the
next year if I feel it needs a a
different
mixture um everything's in the soil and
I just try to make it available te's and
whatnot but
uh I mean yeah that's that's August the
days are super hot
um you know making sure they're getting
watered they're they're going to be at
Peak water needs at that point um I'm
sure for one thing I did want to ask you
and this is kind of like even from your
episode with mat that I was like really
curious about what is like a typical day
for you um like you know what time do
you get up and like you know what is the
shape of a day and
is but yeah I mean in August like we're
talking outdoor but like I've got dep
green houses being harvested so um
usually maybe Harvest we like in the
middle of AEP Harvest um early early
August or or or at the tail end of it
maybe um so like if we're still pulling
tarps um it's day starts at 7 with ping
tarps um 700 a.m. and uh that's a great
time to start working because it's nice
and cool outside and so unless we're
doing like harvesting which might happen
all day um we we we work from like s to
to
lunchtime and you know we'll we'll get
in a good chunk of work in in the so
those morning hours and then um quit
quit at lunch take a long lunch just
take a break in the middle of the day
because unless there's stuff that
absolutely needs to happen or it can
happen indoors like it's just it's just
so hot that like you're just going to be
spinning your wheels and it's hard to do
that every day to to work through
through midday what do you do on that
lunch break do you have a nap or
like if I need a nap I'll take a nap um
uh do something inside like with
legalization I have [ __ ] to do on the
computer
um you know sometimes people run to the
river and and go and just go to the
river for three four hours in the middle
of the day which is great um it's really
refreshing
too
uh I mean just regular household chores
like doing laundry and [ __ ] like that
cleaning up
um like it's it's a good time in the
middle of the day to like take care of
your own personal
stuff um um besides like eating or
something and and uh you know you want
to be inside or in the shade and and
like you know if we have to work through
the heat we will but um if you don't
have to and you can come back at like 3
or 4 o'clock and work for another three
hours or whatever I mean I think I just
think it's way more efficient
um to you know for it's a marathon it's
not it's not a Sprint so you got to like
not wear yourself out and yeah keep it
sustainable right so you know sometimes
there's indoor maybe you got bucking to
do inside and that's that's all air
conditions so so it's not as bad but uh
or or whatever the case may be you know
but uh um I would say that's sort of a
typical day now on a you know if it's a
harvest day you know we'll just we'll
probably work and and maybe just take an
hour lunch and just work through it just
to get it done um it just depends on
kind of what's going on if there is any
need to rush or anything like that or or
whatever the case may be but you know um
a lot of days I got to leave the farm
and go to town and do Logistics and get
supplies and I'm so far out that that
takes all day um to do that and other
times like maybe I'm running product to
town to distribution or or picking up or
or whatever the case may be so
um you know it could it it it varies a
lot and other days is just uh like do a
morning walkthrough which is my favorite
thing to do and figure out like your
priorities for the day like is there a
big transplanting that needs to be
done um is there anything that need like
is immediate need like does Something In
The Water System need to get fixed you
know or plants aren't going to get
watered that would be like a higher
priority thing that needs to get fixed
right
away um but yeah I mean it's it's
farming so like I could be a plumber one
day in electrician the next day and you
know one day I might actually get to
like tend to my plants you know it's
it's always kind of like what needs to
happen first you know and then like if
there's nothing else like crazy going on
or nothing broke then you can actually
like tend to your plants and and and do
that that sort of stff stuff no that's
really cool I'm glad to hear about this
because I think sometimes we get into
these like uh you know more technical
discussions and it's easy to lose sight
of uh the more human side of it you know
what it's like to work on this stuff
throughout the day and like what it's
like to deal with human stuff life stuff
alongside it all um yeah so sorry not
I'm going off my own script really but I
I did that was that was cool to hear
about um kach how about you man like
where do your thoughts go when I say
transition to flower um you know just
initially and then maybe you could tell
us a bit about what a typical day looks
like for you too yeah yeah yeah so my
thoughts are when I so August 1st
generally everybody's thinking about you
know stretch is either in full swing or
your plants are are starting to push uh
push stretch you can see them see him
doing that and for me it's uh the first
thing I'm looking at is do I put up a
second cage um I always internal cage my
plants because if I don't um with like
two or 4 inch um gauge fencing with with
big big squares in it um and if I don't
my plants get eaten alive by a deer they
they will get chomped all the way down
to the stock and um so so when I'm
looking at that stretch phase about to
happen I'm looking at the plants that
are going to grow out and wider than
those 65 gallon pots if they're going to
need that external arm structure because
their natural inclin is going to be to
go out and up and having that secondary
cage out for the plants that don't have
their own Vigor to hold up their weight
at the end of the season that cage makes
things so much easier um and and there
are some Tail taale Signs in in
structure and in Branch Vigor that you
can tell if a plant is going to need
that that secondary set of support um
and once uh once stretch is in and it's
either going into one or two of the
cages my main goal is training and
personally what I like to do is uh the
branches natural in cinity will be to
pick a square of the cage to go through
and what I'll do is I'll work it either
one or two rungs lower than the hole
that that Branch wants to stick out of
and that that keeps everything down and
separated and allows for more
breathability and with that I do get a
little bit of rub the I I deal with 20
to 30 m hour winds on a on a weekly
basis at least once a week I get an
updraft up the mountain and so so with
the cages there's some downsides you get
a little bit of rubbage and anytime you
have necrotic or dead material it could
promote mold under the right right
conditions so um the cage is it's a it's
a musthave for me I've never tried the
trestling I've just I've been complacent
with what's worked for me in the past um
and yeah right after stretch I'm not
thinking about food um I'm practically
Just Add Water my soil has all my pre-
amendments and if I if I see the ladies
asking for a little more nitrogen I just
I brew a tea and I I I reactivate what's
in the soil and make it more readily
available for them um so so
transitionally for me I'm not thinking
about anything different with food I'm
still just I'm still just adding water
and and playing playing water truck for
the plants um I think right around that
time I'm also and you guys have seen
this if you you check out my Ig is I'm
balancing my uh my cropping method
between rocks and hay and trying to get
a decent medium to where the plants are
drinking the so the water out of the
pots at at a at a rate where they're not
being evaporated out of it and usually
end end of July through August and the
start of September is when my plants are
drinking the most I gotta if I don't get
out there and water them before like I
don't know like 9 or 10 a.m. they're
gonna I'm going to notice a little bit
of droop I'm going to notice them saying
hey man I'm I'm [ __ ] thirsty you know
where's where's my water at um so and
and that changes drastically too as we
as we move on further into flower to
where I mean I I'll have plants that
won't drink for three to five days or if
we have a heavy rainstorm it it feels
like even longer than that sometimes um
yeah so I'm I'm paying right after
stretch is happening I'm paying
attention to the water retention how
much the plants are drinking um because
I I hand water everything each each each
pot is is hand watered with the hose um
and I I adjust a little bit here and
there to what to what everybody's asking
for nice yeah um in terms of like a
typical day for you what does that look
like yeah um early morning um it's two
it's a it's a two-day visit um I don't
grow at where I live I I have to drive
to the property where I grow um I have a
separate piece of property for it it was
tedious at first but the more I the more
I weigh the benefits of it I actually I
actually prefer doing it this way um and
my indoor stuff I do at my house but uh
it um it's it's one visit in the morning
and sometimes like uh when I know that
there's work that needs to be done I'll
do a visit in the evening usually two to
two three four hour visits in the garden
um spent time just you know it just just
like little Hill said um it's it's very
subjective when I walk when I when I
take that quarter mile walk and not
quarter mile it's like eighth of a mile
walk down through the valley and into my
little jungle the first thing I do is I
look at the plants and say all right who
needs help who needs what you know it's
it's a general assessment it's an
open-ended question every time I walk
into my little my little patch down in
the
valley I like that image a lot yeah walk
through the into the valley yeah yeah I
I could take the quad down sometimes but
like I like walking it it's uh it's kind
of like a intuition from hunting my
whole life like looking at track and
seeing what's been walking through what
deer what bear have been coming through
like getting boots on the ground is yeah
I like it's like yeah it's like a ritual
yeah yeah absolutely very very
ritualistic very very uh meditative each
morning walking down not just spending
time with the plants but the journey
that it takes to get to him it's uh yeah
it's a little bit of a remote hike
no that's really cool thank you for
sharing um NY
booze yeah I get jealous as [ __ ] looking
cush's
feed man like this path and it looks
like there's a river and [ __ ] Serene I
got like three steps out my back door to
the shitty little plastic
greenout sitation like I'm going to get
into my current situation not not what's
ideal for me because obviously like my
biggest concern right now is just
running numbers and looking for for
decent clones so I'm cropping is just
whatever like I've got a daytime job
like ideally one day I'd like to be able
to get into cultivating whatever but you
know legali is the way they are Etc um
so yeah like I grow everything in
[ __ ] 10 or 15 gallons or maybe even
fives if I'm trying to like cram a few
extra plant in there so I'll start
everything off in small pots um almost
let them get rootbound a little bit with
the more sativa stuff and then just
transplant them into like a two gallon
to start off with just until I can see
sex cuz you know I can't really be
putting in real estate like three or
four into a 15 gal and then get two
dudes or three dudes so I'm sex and
everything first similar to indoor um
and then I I'll transplant to my big
containers so I've got 15 gallon 20
gallons I I don't really have a set
method like uh deviate between using
like bagged soil that allowed amendments
and stuff to or just making my own [ __ ]
um big into making composts and stuff
like that as well so really when the
flowering starts I'm just got got to
make sure that [ __ ] ain't going to
stretch out of the
greenhouse sorry so when I was um
growing Outdoors so not in the
greenhouse just in the open air it
wasn't as much of a concern I pretty
much just transplant [ __ ] to the beds at
you know couple of nodes and then just
let it stretch out and sort of have fun
with it from there um but yeah at the
moment I I grow multiple plants in
single containers uh it's not ideal it's
sometimes uh can can lead to some pretty
shitty results um something will be
underwatered and over rewarded but for
the most part you know from the same
same packet of seed so it ends up like
not too bad um but yeah man that's the
ideal that's the current situation and
um yeah a day for me uh just getting up
my indoor [ __ ] because it's so hot I
pretty much run indoors just at
nighttime um so I'll get up at you know
5: sometimes when the lights are still
on get in there feed whatever needs to
be fed um and then get outdoors and I
love being out there in the early
morning or at night so I've got like in
my rental I've got fuckle f FES and I'm
back on to like a nature reserve so
there's like hiking trails and [ __ ] so
it's just sketchy so often I've been out
there at like you know 9 or 10 at night
doing fol year and stuff like that and W
it's when you know people can't see me
or just like bringing plants in and out
of the the greenhouse for pruning or
this that and the other whatever yeah so
um yeah I don't have as big of a sitch
as the boys obviously so it's it's not a
big part of my day growing in soil as
well sometimes I can go like a day or
two without even going in there you know
cuz I know nothing needs to be watered
and and that but yeah man that's mostly
it for
me that's cool man yeah
um so each of you actually touched on
like you know different aspects of
growing and do you have any questions
for each other like regarding what you
just heard
like
um if not you know one thing I'd maybe
extend to you all um is like in general
with flowering you know what do you what
do you like the most about this entire
stage relative to you know
vegetation oh I I got one for that
um once the plants have resin they have
smells yeah you know so you can
start say what that's when you start
becoming like increasingly obsessed with
them at least for me right yeah
especially when you when you're growing
from seed you're growing a new strain or
something that you don't know quite what
it's going to smell like um and and
smell does change over time as it
develops but like for the most part like
you can start getting a picture of what
that plant is uh once it gets a little
bit of resin and the first resin is
usually on those pre flowers so I I'll
rub pre flowers you know waiting for to
get some type of smell that isn't just
um chlorophyll or something
and uh that's I mean that's that's I
like I like that the most about them
starting to develop flowers it's uh is
is you get to smell them that's what
that's a huge part of it yeah same for
me I mean I follow my nose man my nose
has gotten me gotten gotten more things
right than it's gotten wrong and like
the first bit of identity that really
stands out amongst these plants post veg
is that that first bit of resin yeah
there's structure but I mean when you
first get that introduction of of the
compound and you start either relating
it to other plants or you relate it to
the the parents of the hybrid or or uh
you know you you just get a you get an
identity for it and that that to me is
like that's one of my favorite parts of
that yeah I think that's the magic of
growing these plants is that at it's at
that point where they stop becoming
sorry where they they're no longer as
much of a black box and you're actually
starting to see like what they've got to
offer you
um the puzzles start to come together
yeah it's beautiful cuz with a rose like
I've got I've got a bunch of roses as
well so you know when a new rose pops up
I always stick my nose in and it's
beautiful you know nice thing to start
the day but it's always the same that's
why with flowering plants man it's just
a mystery right every day it reveals
itself a little bit more and even like
the structure of the flower if you'll
grow a packet of seeds and you'll start
to see that diversity so oh okay this
thing stopping the stretch it's starting
to throw out some reasonable size
[ __ ] puff balls and then oh [ __ ] this
thing ain't even ticked over yet it's
still stretching it's barely even
throwing pistols like it's like I love
it and just every day they seem to
change at that stage too like Sun's
pretty intense here at that time of year
so watching everything transition and
and yeah all the Aromas man and watching
like trying to gauge what a flower is
going to smell like off the stem and
stuff as well it's all fun especially
when it's like you know something you've
been passionate about a waiting all year
to pop just for that scenario like the
outdoor because I save a lot of things
just for outdoor in particular because
it's my preference
really yeah I think I said before like I
I don't think I've encountered another
plant or any organic species that
carries as many smell profiles like in
one single species it has a an almost
uncountable amount of of compounds that
that and not only that but a lot of
those compounds are subjective to each
individual person like so when and that
was something that at the party man
we're passing around jars and people are
picking up different notes out of the
same jar and we're finding similarities
but we're also defining them by
completely different experiences it's um
I don't know I've I've never ran into
something so complex for for the old
factory um system and it it just adds to
the reason why I think some of us love
it so
much I I'll bring people down into the
garden and I'll be like man I smell I
smell Menthol and blueberries and and
all this complexity and some people
would just go man I just smell weed and
I'm like well well then I you our noses
are different bro yeah I can I can hand
Brinn like straight up blueberry bud and
have her smell it and she'll say oh
peppery you know just some people just
smell things totally different yeah yeah
I was that that actually leads me to
want to ask you guys another question
which is like and again this is more on
the human side of things but
how many people do you get to share this
with like how many people in your lives
get to witness you know what you doing
um uh too many I should be [ __ ] more
tight lipped about it to be honest [ __ ]
man like for all my friends it's a trip
so I mean I keep a pretty low profile um
I don't have like too many people in my
circle or whatever but um for the most
part my friends haven't had exposure to
this [ __ ] so like my one buddy that came
to Amsterdam with me um that was his
first time seeing anything except like
you know compact [ __ ] the pgr the
the the Brick sort of stuff um yeah so
that was his first exposure to that and
so every time I bring something new he's
just stoked man and for most people you
know you're showing them [ __ ] that
they've never even seen or smelled so I
I love variety so you know I'm not
really cropping the same clones so every
time it's something new and you know
friends will get a couple bags of
different seed plants and stuff and it's
just a trip and I love it it's it's fun
and I love it when you can get um that
um correlation like if you smell
something I like with my Ms I'll do it
I'll always give her a bag and be like
what do you smell and if she you know
says the same thing as me it's always
like [ __ ] yeah you know confirming it's
cool I keep hearing uh boo about pgr and
I feel
like it's a it's it's so it sounds like
it's like a it's a pretty good issue
down in Australia right now yeah man
it's less now less of a concern like I'm
not really for the medical Market but
one thing that actually the good that's
come of it is people are getting all
this stuff from the chemists now so less
people are having to go to the streets
to get weed but man for the longest time
like I don't know if it was a clone that
was passed around like all of Australia
like so the theory was most of it was
grown by like Vietnamese gangs but I
mean I saw a lot of it come from like um
biker sort of circles as well so I'm not
sure where it was being cultivated but
yeah man it was a trip like for 10 15
years you'd find the same weed like the
same smell same look same like shitty
effect everything and yeah it was just
grown with these blood
blusters yeah it seems like every
developing cannabis Market goes through
that phase for a while
where you get maybe like the less
scrupulous Growers um who are really
just in it for the
money uh kind of blowing it out and they
of course they they pgr the [ __ ] out of
everything so they can yield more and uh
it you know it's the quality is so bad
and then the market sort of like we had
Canada doing that and that all came down
this way and a lot of people were doing
it here in probably the early 2000s into
the
mid1 and then kind of like the market
got well for one you had like you did
have like the regulated market testing
for it so that helped and you started
having medical dispensaries testing for
it so that kind of helped but like also
the market just realized that look with
less resin but a huge Bud super dense it
wasn't that great a weed like it looked
better than the Mexican brick they were
getting before but it's people just
realized it wasn't that great and it
started to not have the value for the
people doing it and it seems like every
Market's kind of gone through that pgr
phase and uh I don't know just it's just
interesting to hear it down in Australia
as well man I think the interesting
perspective
yeah that it's like a um almost like a
stepping stone for every developing
Market sorry boo go for it no sorry
brother I'm just say people are like
apathetic towards it like I know people
that actually like enjoy it like people
that will still buy it week in week out
just because of the price because of the
availability or it's what they're used
to because most people like it's the
only weed they've ever smoked so that's
the whole so depressing oh dude yeah and
yeah yeah I mean then you can show them
some of yours and probably blow their
mind yeah yeah yeah sometimes man
sometimes it's yeah I don't know I think
people just get get used to that sort of
effect it's weird I don't know
interesting that effect what's that
migrain I don't know man microl [ __ ]
whatever's going on there those headache
turps
yeah that's funny anyways sorry that was
a side note no brother
we showed it to I we showed a picture to
Matt on the uh cannabis around the world
episode and uh was pretty funny dude it
trying to describe what it looks like
little Hill it it looks like you know
how when nugs like when it's grown super
bad like it's all nothing but hair yeah
it looks like that but even
worse dude it looks like a Jim Henson
puppet dud ites it literally it doesn't
look like weed it does not look
like that's that's not the beers we used
to get that was super PG no no no this
way different maybe in the private chat
I can find a I'll find a picture for you
little Hill later on like um as we go on
there was certainly stages of it there
was stages cuz like I was getting some
at some stage that was like little Hill
talks about just big old chunks like
half ounce [ __ ] buds big compact
things and they were less hairy but
still they were like gray like [ __ ] all
resin glands but then yeah there was
like sometimes people would come around
with the stuff that was full on like
yeah little dingleberries man like
little stamped on you know hairy [ __ ]
red and gray balls like yeah was crazy
I'm putting a link in the chat I don't
know if you can oh no that's not a link
that's a
yeah that's not a link don't worry about
that okay well I'll I'll try to get that
to you at some point in this chat but
Chris did you anything to add on the PGI
note uh no no I don't have anything to
add on to that okay okay well cuz the
other thing I want to ask you guys again
broadly before we start like I'm going
to start prompting you all to kind of
start drilling into like mold and stuff
but before we get there and it's
probably a natural segue to mold but
what are the things that you all dislike
about this stage or like what do you
what concerns you or worries you or you
know what are the downsides for you when
you're getting into
flowering um
downsides jeez I don't know that there
are any
um maybe downsides is a bad term but
like yeah what things do you start to
worry about
maybe smell for me so it's like I won't
it I know was gonna stank like oh jeez I
got a neighbor like two meters
away yeah I don't I don't have those
concerns
anymore
um I'm I'm sort of like wrapped up in
dep Harvest and that and that kind of
takes priority and
attention um for things going on in the
other Garden as far as like workload and
stuff but I mean back in the day just
the same [ __ ] like I still wasn't
worried about smell but I mean
helicopters and and what's going on um
up here they they usually do bus in like
um Late July August um so sort of just
like where they are that day where where
the whatever the
um the task force or whoever it is
rolling around the Convoy um on the
roads uh other than that
like I don't know it's just yeah I mean
it just everything's fixing to get
started and uh I know I know later on in
flower like when you get into like mid
to late
September um and everything's too early
to chop it's just like you're just like
hanging around there's almost nothing to
do on the plants for the most part it's
just hitting your watering but
like there's enough on the vine to like
for thieves to come yeah and they'll
still they'll still take it so it's like
you can't chop for like another three
weeks but you know there's nothing else
you can do and it's like in September
you got all this like I almost feel like
there I always needed a September
project to do something to take up my
time or at least to take up the cruise
time
because like there was really nothing to
do dep's already down and out the door
um you can't start harvesting yet but
you know you have this huge workload
ahead but you can't you can't get
started early on it so you just kind of
nervously fidgeting before yeah deal
with the paranoia and and just and just
maybe do do a September project like
we've done things over the years like
build a treehouse or or uh maybe work on
a new space if we're EXP Bing the next
year working on a fence or something but
like that's that's that's how I kind of
take up that extra time
yeah that's so interesting so yeah for
you I guess one of the problems is also
just thinking what you would do with
that free time when you have it um yeah
it's are you guys lollipopping and [ __ ]
like are you stripping a lot of the lows
off not a lot lot
um definitely lower branches for sure um
but I don't I don't lollipop a whole lot
one it it that the time it takes is
enormous at at this scale and yeah um I
don't feel like I'm not totally
convinced and it varies strain to strain
for sure um but I'm not totally
convinced how much it helps
Outdoors because
I don't know you know the sun moves over
the sky you know and hits the plants
from both sides um over the course of
the day and all those smaller buds at
the bottom like I can sell those
too um if they're dense at all like
they're still they're still worth
something
so I mean as long as the the bottom
branches aren't laying in the soil you
know trim those up um make sure they're
not in the way of like if I'm using
sprayers make sure nothing's in the way
of the sprayer spraying you know over
the circumference of the pot but
lollipop and just takes a ton of time um
I do do
leafing um in in my Depp green houses
and just to Deo filate as as they call
it now but I just call it leafing or big
leafing um just to just to get better
light penetration on certain strains but
uh n not a whole lot of
lollipopping yeah I'm I'm not
lollipopping either like the most growth
cleanup that I'll do is if I'm looking
through the internal structure of a
plant and I can't like stick my hand
through it without like it turning into
a jungle or hitting every branch and
leaf on the way in then I'm going to do
a little bit of cleaning up in there but
if she's breathing just fine like if a
big gust of wind comes through and I
could see that it exchanges air on every
node all the way up I'm not going to I'm
not going to clean off any of the inner
growth I'm not going to take what people
call the suckers or those little
branches um I I leave all that stuff but
if I can if I can see a plant choking
itself out if I can see like actual fan
leaves like decaying on the internal
growth because of partial
cannibalization but also a complete lack
of sunshine then I I'll clean up some of
that inner stuff the uh the cream bag
seed that I popped this year had some
inbred mutant stuff going on and she had
some internal jungly growth that no
matter how much I trained her outwards
there was still internal growth that was
in shade almost all all day all day long
so it's it's strain strain dependent on
whether or not if I'm doing a bunch of
cleaning up on the uh on the fan leafes
or the internal
growth cool yeah I'm pretty much the
same I'll just open up the center of the
plant similar to like cherry tomatoes I
mean like you said as long as I've got I
don't know if I've got four or five like
main cers as long as there's a nice Gap
in the center where air can sort of move
around I'm cool with that yeah
breathability yeah I w't grow something
like I've seen pictures of URL and like
deep Chunk in Bubba where they grow like
a ball leaves everywhere so I won't grow
something like that I mostly just like
the long flower and [ __ ] in the
greenhouse yeah don't top your deep
chunk
plants those varieties you just named
are are notorious for having just tons
of nodes and tons of lar on the inside
and I'm not growing anything like that
um besides maybe some poodle nuts which
is kind of similar but um if that was
the case yeah I'd have to rethink it
because they've just got you know a node
every you know inch or so on the inside
and it's just so much extra foilage and
they lar up so bad and I I feel like
that much extra is definitely going to
rob from your your top buds but uh you
know when your when your nodes are
further apart it man I I just look at it
as like I there's a whole Smalls market
so everything that's not big enough to
go in your bag of like a buds goes in
the bbds or or Smalls and they're
there're you know they're easy to
machine trim and you know sell them for
you sell them for less but you can still
sell them so and you're machine trimming
so you're not really paying a trimming
cost like like you are so you know I
just look at it that
way yeah I was so mad over here it's
like 2004 whatever in Cali like it'll
all go all those tiny little buds on the
bottom of the stem CL that off that'll
go yeah yeah yeah that's man that's a
good ERA to be in right
now it's a good place to
be it isn't it it' be nice
bro um we kind of got here I think we we
talking about like uh light and air
penetration all that um let's talk about
PM mold bet tritis all those things get
into it okay uh so I'm I'm guessing me
and and thousand full are kind of in the
same boat where we have pretty dry dry
climates and good wind I I I've got
pretty good wind at my spot too and you
mean oh yeah sorry kush yeah my bad uh
and like it's pretty constant you know
uh a medium to heavy wind and yep and uh
I mean that's great for all those things
um I I know people closer to the coast
um do do a bit more lollipopping and
thinning in the inside of their plants I
don't really get PM
Outdoors
um you know something about the UV from
the Sun really suppresses it what I will
see later on in the
season um on the north side of a plant
you might see some PM starting but by
that point point you've you've usually
already started Harvest and you just see
it forming on a plant you're not going
to do anything else with at that point
besides chop it down and and maybe chop
it up or burn it or or whatever you do
with your
stems um in the greenh houses for sure
I'll see pm and and and and it's just
part of our routine if you're foiler
feeding with minerals or or uh you know
some type of like zyme product or
phosphorus
product um that usually suppresses it
pretty good for me um without like
specifically spraying for
it
um I found over the year just spraying
anything helps with PM
honestly so um yeah I don't know
something about the UV I think really
really does that work for you yeah I've
never and like I said we're not that far
we're basically just on the opposite
side of the valleys of each other with
very similar similar locations um I I
the only time I've ever had to deal with
PM was because nearby uh wisteria bushes
were like overhydrated and were just
dripping water on on my plants and had
they not been overhung by them then
there wouldn't have been any pm to be
created on them uh no yeah it it I I've
always described my area as like almost
Desert High High desert like it's very
Aid very dry and very windy until it's
not like the second mid September hits
it just it comes it's it's almost always
an in if there's a rainstorm there's a
day where it's an inch of rain um my
little my little side of the mountain up
here we have a a perfect little storm of
that
southern the the southern cold winds
blowing up the valley mixing or the the
hot southern winds blowing up the valley
mixing in with the cold air that comes
down off the Foothills and I live right
at that congruence um it makes for
amazing thunderstorms and 60c 120 second
long Rolling Thunder but it also brings
with it some crazy storms
so um yeah PM is not something that I
battle with uh generally but the mold
when when I'm start getting those days
where you know plants have absorbed you
know an of rain over like a 6 hour 8
Hour 12 hour period it's that's when I'm
I'm going out the next day and I'm
shaking down every plant and trying to
get as much moisture off of them as
possible um because I because I know
what's going to come if you leave enough
moisture and um I I'm no expert in
dealing with gry mold or or botis but
from my
observations I notice it grows best and
initially off of necrotic material if
there is a a dead plant cell even if
it's tiny and the right moisture with
the right um lack of of UV contact it
seems to just create itself
instantaneously and so in the last
couple years I've tried changing
something because I notice um when I'm
defoliating uh dead cannibalized fan
leaves normally I'll just hand pluck
them I'll grab it by the leaf and I'll
just rip down or I'll rip up and I'll
pluck it right off the pl plant and then
I'll come back uh and late flower and
that exact node where I plucked off that
fan Leaf is right where the botis the
gry mold has started is where where I
plucked that off and then two years ago
instead of hand plucking I started
taking the scissors and just snipping
the end of those those Leaf uh branches
off and stopped plucking and I noticed
that those botis the grey mold areas
where it would normally be attacked
where there was dead necrotic material
it wasn't happening near nearly as often
so knowing or at least observing what
I've seen in my garden um how it it
likes to attack the necrotic and dead
material uh it's changed how I defoliate
um my
plants that's that's that's that's right
on um I I've noticed similar stuff too
um and
uh it yeah it does like those Dead
Leaves if you got a dead bud leaf for a
or a parched one devoided nutrients um
it'll like to start there
um yeah I don't do a whole lot for mold
besides try and grow strains that aren't
going to mold before they finish yeah
and um you like strains like sour diesel
don't mold but they go so late that I
feel like they can't finish very well
where I'm at I don't want to run
something past Halloween or even up to
Halloween uh October
31st um it's just too late for me it's
just too cold usually every day every
night for them really to finish up right
right um but they don't mold I've done
it before and I mean they go through
storms and and they just don't freaking
mold which is awesome yeah um you know I
I've never had a big mold problem up
here I've always ran strains that finish
up before mold's going to come in before
the before that next storm comes in it
seems like clockwork every year we get a
storm in late
September um and it's and it's too early
for for mold to really set in and that's
fine you know it washes the plants off I
mean I like it honestly it keeps the
dust down it you know it makes
everything smell fresh and new and it
really feels like Harvest Time when that
happens but yeah um generally I I take
all my tops first
anyways
so you know once the that second growth
is it's not those fat colas like like
the top so they they don't they're not
going to mold up as easy but um it just
depends like this year we're getting a
ton of rain for September and October
more than normal y so and I'm running
all new strains that I don't know what
they do or how they perform or even when
they were going to finish so I I have
seen more mold than usual that's that's
a combination of running strains that
aren't tried and true and more rain than
usual like we had yeah I mean we've had
more rain already in October than
probably the last you know two three
years combined honestly at least for the
first half of October so you know I I
kind of already decided what I didn't
want to run and it was it was a lot of
those super super center big giant
centerca fat buds but kind of just like
meh on the turps from
compound um those things are breed those
things are breed you know indoors
insults you know with probably with LED
lighting and it's just
not it like that kind of breeding
constantly is just taking genetics a
certain way where even though a lot of
our genetics are were bred
indoors um I feel like you do another
selection when you move Outdoors and so
you figure out okay this is what I like
but let's see what works for me in this
environment and you do selections off of
that you might do breeding off of that
other breeders up here especially like
707 Seedbank like he's really bred for
like NorCal
outdoor um climate and a lot of his
strains um do well do well in that
situation um so so I I growing a lot of
his strains but like I know he's done
that and and uh I do my selections like
I I I'd rather run run a bunch of clones
and figure out which ones work for me
and which ones don't and just select
select you know clones that
way yeah I definitely want us to return
to particular plants or indiv or you
know lines or individuals that um have
and have not done well for you guys um
but maybe we'll let boo
yeah Finish First about um whether he
has to deal with pm and molds so not pm
and I I may be off base but I think PM's
more of like a cooler climate thing
maybe like cool temperament Coastal cuz
I'm in the subtropics so we don't have
those cool nights in summer I I don't
think I've ever seen pm on cannabis
except perhaps once when I was growing a
cucumber in the same bed which I just I
w't make that mistake again but yeah as
long as you're in veg super [ __ ] easy
to De with just like lacto billus or
like a milk spray or something like that
but um yeah boisterous is a big big
concern so like the photo that's in my
little DP that was that year that we had
monsoons um so the weather here is just
[ __ ] man it'll be inconsistent
generally we can assume that in March um
which is I guess your September uh we're
going to have so like Autumn you know
we're going to have a lot of rain so it
always rains at Easter time um but this
year was particularly bad so we had
roughly 95% humidity and just torrential
downpours for like two weeks straight
and that was about you know 2/3 of the
way through flower so you know big
[ __ ] handr fun yeah it was [ __ ] out
so there's like in that picture there
there's a massive top over that and I
was out there most days or even when it
was raining really bad I was sort of
standing under there with like a broom
every 20 minutes I just [ __ ] push the
top up it was [ __ ] like never seen
rain like that we had thousands of
houses destroyed floods and [ __ ] yeah
but that year was cool man I only lost
like a half a pound so that was like you
know a tenth of that crop went to mold
in the bin and the rest of it made it
through which was good but that was the
genetics too that was like that sweet
skunk uh S1 crossed jel so it was um
yeah it was good for the for the
conditions but yeah I've um one mistake
that I've made I always assume that our
climate was the same as California but
you guys don't get a lot of rain in
summer right it's it's mostly like
winter time or fall we're a we're a
Mediterranean climate here in Northern
California well really all of California
which is a a West Coast phenomenon so I
think you guys do have a mediter
Mediterranean climate in Perth yeah um
but like that's you know the only places
that happens
is on West Coast like west coast of
South America around Chile um Perth
Australia and then I forget where in
Africa they get it but they Africa has
that as well and then obviously the
Mediterranean area up in
Europe but uh yeah that means warm warm
dry Summers and then mild
Winters so where could we have a similar
climate to in the states like orgon
something like that do they get a little
rain in the summertime or still not
really yeah but they don't have they
they don't h i mean maybe even further
north um you might be more like an East
Coast climate
because they get they have a lot of
humidity and then they get it the
humidity just builds and builds and
builds and then they get a thunderstorm
like Florida or something like that
probably even yeah maybe more like that
I've never lived out there so I don't
know
but if you're if you're humid and and
and and get a lot of rain in the in the
summer like I think that's more of like
an East Coast type thing yeah yeah it
can be rough at times some years we'll
get a good year but yeah I I mostly
prefer like I'll start my [ __ ] later
like I love to have things finishing
around the May period so obviously for
you guys it's too late snowing and [ __ ]
by then but I yeah if I can stretch it
so starting things off say like November
December instead of like September it
gives me just the extra few months so
I'm flowering when it's a little bit
drier and cooler and stuff like that
especially in the greenhouse wait so
what would your may be equivalent to for
them in terms of one before June so may
is like
November yeah yeah yeah so that's like
the beginning of winter really for us
yeah too late see CU When I was buying
seeds ini I do have a few packs of stuff
from Sha I've got uh old Betsy cross to
the Kush cleaner so I'm looking forward
to them but I was man I've seen those
grown out there's there's good stuff in
there for sure fruit Jam yeah I got two
packs man so that's that's on top of the
list for when I get the new spot sorted
it'll be cool I've got some Betsy across
to appy from um high and loansome as
well so yeah be some cool [ __ ] I got
some of that sitting in front of me
right now cured and ready to smoke oh
man to burn down right after this damn
smell a vision yeah yeah what kind of
nose you uh Pine Citrus a little bit of
mango not heavy mango and like a little
cream little creaminess in it but lots
of Pine and lots of mango damn CU yeah
that one sounds like it' be a mango bomb
with the GC and the and the Betsy
yeah youna say something that have done
notoriously well in Northern California
oh yeah the the the cush cleaner is well
but um I don't know like tons of that's
been grown up here just the structure of
the plants the finishing time the look
of the nuggets the yield the quality of
the bud like those were big like popular
commercial producers up here I'm
thinking I GNA get me some skunk dog
because I've seen um gray skull in uh
Hawaii with the skunk dog and that
apparently seems to do really well with
humidity similar thing to the the bubble
gum oh oh yeah ABS absolutely they they
definitely have humidity out there that
would be a good thing to uh to look for
is like so they're breeding for the most
part they're breeding Outdoors out there
I think like I I would assume most of
them are are are growing some type of
Depp or short season plant um so that
would be yeah sourcing some of their
genetics Joey weed or is is it
Joey P them yeah they be indoors as well
but I think yeah yeah totally totally
that those would be good genetics to
look into for for what might work well
for you and they've got and dude and
their weed out there is is tremendous
they've
got I mean you
know just the quality they're they're
growing and and and and what they're
doing out there especially those people
is it's it's it's the highest quality
pot out
there even from the can like hp13 and
like the sour PE and stuff like that man
it always looked really good have to get
something like that going oh add some M
Frost cost a TK man friend of mine gr
from Ochi um goat and monkey yeah it was
the I think it was yeah reversed TK onto
that molai Frost and that was some good
smoke man that was like yeah I wouldn't
say skunky but like certainly like
rotten fruit I could get into it it was
beautiful nice do you do you make your
own
seed not yet man hey I've um mostly just
looking for clones I got some advice
early on like you know just get a bit of
a library going first which um okay yeah
so I will be once I've got the space
definitely like doing more preservations
but I'm doing my first little project at
the moment I don't know if it's going to
work I did a I tried to reverse a clone
I've got it's um thread cutter from CB
so it's Rubber City chamd Afghani cross
to jel and so this one's pretty rank it
Stacks rather hard it's got a it's
pretty Hardy like it's been in the room
of things that have like got some might
damage and stuff and it just chugs along
um yeah really ranked nose super
cerebral effect so I'm trying to reverse
that onto a couple of the sativas that
I've got just to try and find a plant
that'll throw down some chunks outdoors
and have some nice stank to it so that's
like my first little thing that I'm
doing but never really made
seed nice okay this is a perfect segue
by the way because I was going to prompt
yall to talk about like yeah like I was
saying earlier lines or individual
plants that have typically done well uh
but also maybe you guys could talk about
individuals that did particularly poorly
um yeah kind of already there so open
open to anyone so Kush I noticed you
grew some some train wreck hybrids this
year yes sir um I I've grown a few
myself over the years and um the biggest
yielding plant I've ever had is a train
wreck to West Coast dog
and the the size of the colas were that
I mean they were as long as my arm just
dense all the way just the whole thing
I've never had colas you can't see on
this the screen but like the length of
my arm is like the cola and then it
branches off and goes into the plant um
by far the biggest yielding plants I've
ever had um the quality was just like me
it it was like big dense
uh West Coast dog nugs not quite as
dense as West Coast dog with like a
little bit of train wreck smell right um
so it was that terpinolene sort of smell
um super mids but total mold
bomb uh like molded up like nobody's
business and I've grown West Coast dog
out here um it finishes early so mold's
not a problem and it it it smells like
hay but it looks beautiful in the bag so
you know it's just matter if you can
sell it or not but
uh
um that's that's something and I've
grown train wreck and I've grown uh
train rck backat crosses out here which
all do great um they really need a lot
of support though because they're
basically rubber um rubber stemmed um
but uh yeah they bend over and twist
like without like like not
we five or six yeah but they're just
heavy you could be that's and I think
that like honestly of all the train
wreck stories I don't know what's true
or what's not true but like of all the
train wreck stories I've heard um the
fact that you could grow a big plant
outdoors and have it just basically
laying on the ground yeah looking like a
mess like a train wreck basically I'm
thinking that's where it got its name
because if you don't support those
things and way back in the day like when
train wreck first came came around or at
least first got out there that's like
you're talking like late 90s and nobody
was growing you know 99 in full sun at
that point and I'm thinking you know
they're they're growing them you know
under a tree somewhere and like not you
know setting up cages and trellis
netting and all this stuff and it's like
those plants are looking like absolute
train wrecks because they're laying flat
on the ground without a broken stem on
them right but just laying basically
just laying on the ground growing like a
like a ground cover I would assume and
that's how it's got its name that's my
guess like it's it makes total sense I
love that I would have to agree out of
all the names that or the reasons I've
heard the names you know like people
pick the names and all the wild [ __ ]
people said like it seems really obvious
to me that that's probably the Genesis
of at least that name for it because it
does look like a mess like it's
considered creeper style like if you see
Neville's old catalog and he talks about
the creeper f types that's supposedly
what that look is where the apical Bud
grows like lower than the other buds you
know just kind of like that and and
that's kind of like that mother [ __ ]
NATO is talking about that they also
mention in the can Bible I never saw
that I never saw that one but I was
always interested to see it just because
of how it grows yeah yeah that always
held myh Fascination to no one knows
what the train wreck is right like I
spoke to pack and he said he thinks it
has Tai in it but would anyone have any
idea like just a Thai afghan that
someone kept or I figured if Caleb
doesn't know then probably no one's
going to really have a good grasp on it
because he's had it for so long and
really searched out the history and it
predate does it predate a lot of the
seed bank [ __ ] because it's from like
the 8S right or 90s we're not sure 90s
or ' 80s I think we don't even know the
the true Genesis of it but it's old than
I don't think we know the I mean the
first I heard of it was probably around
99 or 2000 yeah and so that means even
if it makes its way down to the Bay area
where I was just south of the Emerald
Triangle that's like the first named
weed I ever knew and I loved it it was
it was awesome it was so much different
than what else was out there and there
was you know there was still good weed
out there but
um so like if it took that long to get
to me like when I'm like 17 18 years old
um I'm guessing I'm guessing it had been
around since at least the mid90s but
more likely before that even just before
it like it gets released or gets off of
that Hill wherever it
started um the the the TPS on it like
train wreck TPS or Jack TPS or
terpinolene or whatever that may be like
yeah that's super common for all those
sort of
like like narrow Leaf varieties maybe
not so much the tie but like definitely
some of the Panama definitely some of
the
Colombian um
but like the look of it I haven't seen
anything that that looks quite like it
yeah same pretty those those
specifically the large conical-shaped
buds the way that they they perect
they're not triangular but they have
cone they're almost a cone shape at the
base that goes up it's um yeah it's
funny you mention that cuz the the
outcrosses of train wreck that I see
seem to get like a gigantic
like when it uh the train wreck on its
own it has decent it has decent sized
buds but when I saw it cross to Calo um
two years ago and when I saw it cross to
Salmon Creek big bud about five or six
years ago that I grew they both were
soda can like mad dog like 40 ounce soda
can colas that were were obnoxious and
um I just it seems that when when you
when you cross her out to something she
she just takes off with that that
genetic and you can see it in her you
can see it across multi like the second
I popped that Calo to train wreck from
CSI I was looking at this and I was like
man my my brain says train wreck I'm
looking at the way these buds are
forming and it uh it just like two a te
followed in with it and I I see those
same things um from P atw so through
csis hybrids and the S1 all the way over
to what um what pack is is dealing with
there's there's the similarity of that
conical shaped um just like it it has it
has that that recognizable pattern to it
that I don't see in a lot of other
places is there any like sense that you
guys associate with something that will
be mold
resistant a s PM or mold resistant
either
order
uh
nah I think it's more like floral sh
definitely bud structure yeah so so the
one thing i' that I've seen hold true so
far is
strawberry tends to like even stuff from
erdbeer erdbeer is known to be super
super uh mold and PM resistance and you
know it was built out in Switzerland
where it's really really humid and it
needs to finish Fast um and uh you know
all the way to Strawberry cost up it it
breeds true for
uh all sorts of PM and mold resistance
so I I always wondered if that was like
because it carries so heavy with
strawberry if there were other scents
that may also kind of do that wasn't
sure are there any I haven't noticed
anything scent related yeah I can't I
can't make correlations with I can make
correlations with uh peppery and and uh
with uh really spicy spy plants that
have uh pest resistance uh I've grown a
couple of different ones that smell like
black ground pepper or white pepper and
they are almost Untouched by by
insects
yeah that that's interesting I didn't
know that part um that That Girl Scout
cookie uh Savage purple that you and Bri
uh Bren tried um that thing smelled like
pepper and yeah when I microscop it and
when I'm I'm taking a closer look at it
I'm not seeing a a single bug no no uh
no exoskeletons no no FR you know Left
Behind from any wings or anything it's
like they just don't don't even want to
touch it that's
interesting I'm I'm trying to find
something goer proof like I've been
fighting these things I got I got these
this pole thing called a gopher Hawk you
guys ever seen this
sh yeah like it's I'm battling these
mother they're tearing my yard up and I
want it plant
I can't dude I'm so catty Shack right
now I love that Mt is like quietly
growing Outdoors but no one really knows
that right now I was gonna say I saw
those cherry tomatoes you were growing
son put a auto out there or something
yeah I don't even I don't count my
outdoor because I suck at outdoor like
I'm still learning so I don't count this
as growing this is just learning it's
not my it's not my
specialty yeah fair
enough learning curves to everything
especially in a brutal climate like
Bakerfield bro and and you've even just
talking to little Hills taught me a lot
like I was trying to bring in the indoor
method to outdoor and just like of
course I'm going to put it in a five
gallon why the [ __ ] wouldn't I but
that's not like realistic if you're
putting it out at the beginning of the
season in a five gallon pot and thinking
you're G to get dank like and I'm bottle
feeding out like there's so many things
I'm doing backwards so it's been a
learning learning cve for
sure especially trying to grow anything
if you're putting in the black pot on
cement or something it's just like yes
it's 150 degrees at the root ball I had
him right next to a a brick wall too so
my neighbor couldn't see anything on
cement so it's just cooking like there's
so many common sense things I didn't
take into account that that that aren't
common sense for indoor and I've been so
indoor Centric for so long like none of
it was checking out until like after a
season of it I'm going oh my God I'm
such an idiot so most of this episode
I'm just tuning in and listening because
I don't really have much of a place to
speak here I want to
learn yeah I I would plant late honestly
um put put them out at the beginning of
August and and then pot them up into
into whatever size you want them to
finish and so like if you veg them up in
six inch pots you know pot them up into
like a 10 gallon in August and that way
like it won't really get root bound too
bad or or or if it does happen it'll be
you'll be well into FL already because
you want those roots to be able to
stretch as they as the plant stretches
you want the roots to be able to stretch
as well yeah and uh so not not going too
small on pot size which also helps
regulate the
temperature and not having it on cement
or or or uh shading the pot with
something yeah like you were talking
about yeah putting a board just leaning
a board up against it um or against up
all the pots or whatever uh but like I
like the L the late planting like
there's no reason to get out at like you
know Solstice or right before Solstice
in June um if you if you don't have to
like back in the day when we're trying
to grow big plants up here because plant
numbers was such an issue yeah like yeah
you want to maximize all your veg time
and try and get 10 pounds on on a plant
but um nowadays like if it's a
misdemeanor regardless so put out a
thousand if you want like in a you know
and you'll do fun or whatever the case
may be like it's just so hard to keep it
happy that long and like if you're not
going to go all out and put it in a 300
gallon pot or something like that then
yeah you might as well just wait till
later and like you're going to get like
the quality of your Bud's going to be
way nicer than it would be off a 10
pound plant oh for sure you know if you
just throw a little half ounce plant or
excuse me a half pound P or whatever the
case whatever the case may be that's why
I'm growing like smaller plants in uh
in my outdoor is is is one because I
want a smaller
stem and I want it to look more like de
or more like indoor ideally right yeah
but also like it just works perfectly
with my system like we're busy planning
my green houses in April and
May and then like I guess even into June
we're still planting green houses
sometimes and then once those are
planted then we can work on the outdoor
crop and get the next wave of plants
like cloned and grown up and plant the
outdoor and then I'm in no rush to get
in the outdoor like at the same time as
I'm trying to get into everything else
because I got to get into my green
houses early to pull off two
crops um and and take advantage of like
the sort of season extension a
greenhouse gives you and because I just
once you lose Sun it doesn't matter and
then you know it just works perfectly
into my system and then and then I kind
of get the best of both worlds in a
sense and uh I don't know just for me
that that's that works super well and
and honestly I'm sure people would have
been growing like this a lot
sooner um if plant numbers were never an
issue and that's the same reason I
didn't go super deep on my beds you know
it's six inches of potting soil with
like another three or four inches of
amended native soil
underneath and like they don't they
don't need 18 in of soil
of potting soil to uh to stretch their
Roots out like they they they they do
fill those beds out by the end of it but
I want that and then the maybe the roots
will start going deeper to find extra
water but uh I mean that's all they need
I don't want them to well I guess the
other side of this is a rootbound
plant's going to trigger and start
flowering earlier and sometimes that can
be to your advantage but like usually
usually not because you're you're
fighting this uphill battle at that
point point to keep the plant with
enough nutrients and watering it four
times a day or whatever whatever even
more with like 114 yeah yeah it's gonna
be drying that pot out super fast so you
know it's just like manipulating certain
things to to your advantage but not
letting them be the variable that really
like ruins your season like you know
trying to grow a a fullterm plant in a
five gallon pot it's just you're going
to be fighting uphill and I I see PE I
mean people you you'd be surprised how
many people do this not really realizing
thinking that 45 gallon pot they planted
in June is g to be enough yeah and it's
it's not like unless you want to feed it
four times a day and and have to pump it
full of salts because you know there's
there's not enough there's there's not
enough nutrients in your soil there's
not enough soil um you're not going to
have like all all all these things
together um I mean I've had friends do
this over I've watched them and it's
like they never listen to me and then
and then they go through one season you
know on their backyard grow and they
realized what I was talking about like
don't veg your plants out to six feet
tall in February and then put them out
in June in the 100 gallon pot thinking
you're gonna end up with a 50 pound
plant it's not going to happen you're G
to end up with a shitty ass plant that
grows ugly Bud because the plants sick
the whole time you'd be better off
waiting till June and put out like a one
foot tall plant you know that you veg
for a month or whatever or or maybe less
and you'll end up with more and it'll be
better weed at the end of the day yeah I
was trying to play mostly the game that
I have a Snoopy neighbor and like I
wanted to be able to move the plants you
know move keep them moving essentially
so wherever like CU he likes to get up
on ladders and look just be a little
[ __ ] so I like to keep them moving and
you can't really do that in smaller pots
so I was trying to play the indoor game
of being stealth outdoor when
realistically just the smells in the
morning alone like ruin all stale for me
you know yeah and then if you got them
vegged out all summer like that's more
time for for him to see him where if if
like one like there's nothing until
August and then all of a sudden there's
like a little screen over your patio or
something come AUST like going to flower
out and you're going to be you're G to
you know they're going to be done by by
then you know so yeah I like I I I heard
of a guy I've never seen it myself but
he told me about it a long time ago he
would root a clone upside
down so that the branch you know how the
branches want to come up like this off
the stem yeah but he would root it
upside down so he could so it would come
like this and he could bend it horizont
Al yeah that work yeah I know Mak sense
it was rooted upside down and then it's
easier to bend those branches and get
them going horizontally along a fence
and keep them low then to bend them you
know that way and have them split you
know what I mean how did the roots grow
that way done it did they try toow
technique I heard about like did they
try to grow down and around the pl top
of the plug when he was hanging did he
hang them upside down and have the tray
upside down to root them
no I think he just turned the Clone
upside down to root instead of
rooting you know the like he didn't have
a top on the he just branches yeah so
then he just turned it upside down left
a l bunch of stem I guess it's hard to
say left a bunch of stem on the top to
root that yes and then the and then the
branches were already coming out this
way so then they easily go
horizontal instead of a a regular plant
with the branches like this and then
trying to bend them back down where
they'll split so and he he did all of
that to Trellis it along a fence so his
neighbors couldn't see so essentially
what you're saying is like it's a normal
growing plant like this he cuts the top
off Cuts this off right here flips that
[ __ ] upside down and Roots this part
without the top Roots yeah Roots the top
stem with the two branches on it the two
branches over here fully leave yeah
that's wild wild man yeah yeah just to
just to bend them horizontally
easier he said it worked I believe them
you know yeah I know I mean like it's
it's a novel idea it's Unique it's out
of the box yeah I haven't seen that one
but I've seen like all that kind of [ __ ]
like my um mate's dad who was like one
of my best mates and taught me growing
and stuff um he used to grow a lot of
like Southeast Asian sort of weed so
nothing super crazy but it was just he
imported from you know 70s 80s 90s
because he's in his 60s um and then just
the remnant seed he just you know pull
seed out of each butt each year and just
keep it in a in a jar so it was
basically like some sort of op but
nothing too great but man because he had
like pretty small fences he would do all
that [ __ ] so like layerage where you're
getting like branches and burying the
branches in the ground to get like more
um more roots and stuff on them so
you're getting like more water he'd do
the almost grow it like a grape vine
have like a single stalk and then just
like grow it sideways so that would have
been an advantageous doing the Clones
like that like anelia yeah like yeah
yeah yeah similar to a grape vine you
know you'll get like it'll be 3 m long
and only like a meter tall it's crazy
that's that's also a giant pumpkin uh
technique to grow
your grow your pumpkin plant you know
obviously you're chopping off all the
other pumpkins except your one but then
you bury the the vine again to grow
roots and then let it come back up so
that you've got this huge root system
for this one pumpkin on this giant plant
I mean the the pump the Big Pumpkin
Growers they have these plants that take
up like you know a th000 square feet or
2,000 square feet it's one pumpkin plant
but it's got vines that have been
continuously buried to grow roots and
all that energy just ends up at one
growth site that's so
crazy PP yeah CSI CSI wants to jump in
on the pumpkin growing scenario has he
talk to you about
that I know he's into it I've never
talked to him about it he used to do
some some some funny games back in the
day with uh guess how much this bed will
weigh yeah bet I uh but I don't know
they just uh the record just got broken
for uh for the giant pumpkin down in
Half Moon Bay 2700
pounds saw that recently is insane and
it's uh it's it's just amazing it's it's
and they're just it's just organic like
super pumping their plants tons of
microbes tons of Rich Earth tons of
compost
um I I don't know what else they're
doing I mean I'm sure the guys have a
lot of tricks but like that's that's one
of them that that is just super
interesting gourd that's
interesting get
it one thing that booze did gesture
towards that I I wanted him to talk
about a bit more is actually some of the
nld Leaning stuff that he likes to
run yeah you tell us a bit more about
what you experiened so far with those
outside yeah man it's more of just the
climatic concern for me I mean I like I
appreciate the high more as well like I
um when I was in Amsterdam that was
mostly what I was buying just like the
sativas and the various Haze crosses and
stuff like that so it's my preference in
terms of smoke um and yeah it just
happens to grow well here as well so
generally yeah man um my best success I
guess is probably that um the Death in
Venice that I did so that was the sweets
Gunk S1 cross to the jel um was that
sort of super tendine bombs hazy effect
that I like um yeah aside from that man
I'm working on getting into some of the
more nld stuff from White Buffalo like
I've got a shitload of packs they're one
of the people that I distribute through
the seed bank so I've got a shitload of
packs from them just like seeds man
Hayes cross the Colombian black like
bunch of nepes stuff all sorts of
different things like that so I've done
a few indoors like I grew a Band-Aid
Haze plant indoors and um a har dreams
as well which is like a 11 weaker it's
like blue dream cross to a pi S1 um and
they did pretty well indoors but
throwing them Outdoors Man you can see
that that's where they want to thrive
they'll just keep going and going so
yeah that's um going forward I want to
try and move into like doing some
outdoor breeding like I I don't really
hear about it too much like the only
time I've heard anyone sort of talk
about it is breeder Steve said that he
used to do like a selection or two like
a round or two of selection outdoors and
then bring them indoors so it's
something that I'm interested in because
like um little Hill you mentioned that
sha does a lot of outdoor breeding and
obviously um mean jeene as well does
like outdoor stuff but are there a lot
of breeders breeding outdoor seeds and
then people are taking them indoors like
is this a concern that indoor Growers
have that people will breed their seeds
out like it is for me that's
interesting you can do whatever you want
with the plant right and a lot of what
Growers are
growing is is just if you're an outdoor
grower you're going to want to
make combined outdoor plants that you
think would go good together that work
for you if if both mothers or or both
lines do well Outdoors then hey put them
together and maybe something cool happen
out of that or maybe you want to take
like one strain that's like very hyped
up but it's like you know whatever the
Market's like really wanting like a
gelato or something and at least they
were wanting that um
and then and then you know combining it
with like blue dream or whatever outdoor
strains you're running that that that
maybe breed good stuff for outdoors like
green crack or the Appalachia like
bubble gum those are just those are just
super winter outdoor plants and yeah you
can always take them back indoors but it
just seems like there's already like
indoors is like controlled environment
it's the same around the world so it's
not as necessary
and it seems easier to take breeders
that are exclusively breeding you know
IND out in rock wo under LEDs to just
run those genetics are probably going to
do what you want as opposed
to you know
outdoor strains being bred for their
outdoor qualities doing what you want
Outdoors but you can do both and and
it's not like you're not going to find
something from the outdoor varieties
that's going to work great for you
indoors because they were all outdoor
varieties eventually or originally and
then they went indoors and indoors bred
for something specifically and then we
went back from indoors to outdoors and
oh what works well Outdoors like you
know it wasn't that Dutch stuff it was
the stuff they already had growing in
the Hills here and you know people would
run the same strain indoors in their
warehouse that they were growing
outdoors in under the trees and like
it's such a mix but like you just got to
figure it out and like if I was going to
look for strains to run in a warehouse
like I wouldn't necessarily go towards
my outdoor genetics I'd look for what's
like what the market wants out of out of
that stuff and but if you know for my
environment if I'm looking for what's
going to work out there like I gotta
remember what the market wants but like
I also got to remember that like I just
grew out a bunch of stuff from compound
and none of it's impressive and these
are and these are pheno these aren't
like seeds I'm popping these are like
selected phenotypes that were selected
in an outdoor dep or greenhouse and I'm
still not that high on them I'm still
not stoked on them like I see I have
other better stuff in my garden so you
can go either way I just think you know
when you're selecting genetics you
should think about what your environment
is and where these where these
selections came from I think that's one
of the most important things is like
looking at your environment and choosing
genetics based on that uh perfect
example I'll cite CSI on this because
this is his more his uh area but when he
was talking about the purple Hindu Kush
this is a plant grown exclusively mostly
out in Oregon or NorCal right and it um
does real well Outdoors doesn't have a
lot of interex traits however when you
bring anything indoors and and breed
with it it's constant Herms indoors and
what he's been telling me is that you
can almost always take indoor stuff out
and if it's Herm prone it's it's going
to Herm less Outdoors it'll still might
Herm a little bit but when you bring
outdoor bread Stu indoor it's a lot more
variable on how well it will take
sexually and stress wise um the other
consideration I take into outdoor
breeding is depending on where you're at
if a lot of people around you like
mesino humble are also growing Outdoors
there's a it's a lot harder to control
pollen contamination and po we've
learned pollen travels miles if it wants
to it's lighter than air so that's the
only other things I I would take into
consideration but you're dead on bro
like people should really be considering
their environment and what genetics are
known to work best for their environment
instead of trying to force stuff into
holes that it doesn't necessarily fit in
right that that hermy thing is
absolutely true um like poodle nuts is a
great example yeah that nuts all over
the place
indoors I mean it can be it can be
suppressed and and but it can get out of
control too I've I've had both sure and
uh but like I've never seen one hermy
pollen sack on a uh on a pood nut's
outdoors and I've grown it in green
houses I've grown it in in uh full
full-term plants like nothing nothing
ever and so like yeah that is true like
generally you can
take indoor genetics in that that might
have hermy issues or might
not and not you won't see them outside
you won't see them under the sun really
cuz even in death you won't see them
yeah but then if you do a selection out
there and then bring it inside you might
have selected something that that
hermes's all over the place indoors for
whatever reason I don't know why but
that's always held true yeah yeah that's
pretty significant my Jaga S1 does that
[ __ ] throw down like it'll throw down
big chunks it's beautiful take that [ __ ]
indoors herm's like a [ __ ] like early
and late like week three and then again
at like week oh
no not you want to run with indoors
don't don't blow out the whole tent on
theer definitely that's why I was
outdoor bre we know genetics of joer
joer is purple Hindu Kush isn't it
that's what they claim
yeah maybe we don't know anything
about [ __ ] to me but um yeah the the
Jagger as far as we know is Millerville
um uh prop Kos I think that's what's
supposed to be or what they say
okay yeah okay um no one's ever really
seen the Anis to even other than not so
and a few other people to to compare it
and I don't know that he's grown Jager
to compare it to say for sure yeah my
one's I love it as a smoke the S1 cuz
it's got like a little bit of a cushy
flavor to it too but mostly oh it's
multi fasted everyone that's got us been
like damn the nose interesting so it's a
unique one keep around ni ni and like I
wonder if you could like acclimate the
Clone indoor like if you have a
selection that does Herm if you can keep
running indoor and in you know Time
After Time After Time again if it will
ever acclimate to not I don't know maybe
sort of bond with your room over time
and how you grow even the flower too
though like the flower threw out these
real spindly little buds like the most
skinny buds I've ever seen like little
[ __ ] pinkies but then outdoor it
throws like chunks like I got it that at
the moment it's like these big you know
thumbs so I've seen that a lot bro I
remember I saw that a lot with um early
on when I was buying seeds from like
like Canada when I'd see purple stuff
cuz it was at the time it was so rare
and I was like oh it is purple it may be
say may say that it's all like outdoor
but what the [ __ ] do I know so I'd order
it and indoor it would be complete trash
like hermy trash it was all Airy but
outdoor it's solid just a rock and and
beautiful and that was another thing
that I experienced that like indoor
lights don't necessarily dense up lury
bud at all like sometimes it just does
the opposite for for certain strains
that are Gil geared to
Outdoors yeah yeah totally I don't I
don't know what the variable is like is
it intensity is it
Spectrum root temperatures like I have
no idea what that variable is I'm sure
it's got it almost seems like indoors
it's like you've got someone that's like
imuno
compromised and you take them outdoors
and they're [ __ ] eating dirt and
worms and you know all
that yeah I don't know there's a grower
out here that that has always and I've
kind of seen it myself um
he he kind of like preaches to take your
mom's outside and let him let him get
some of that Midsummer Sun yeah and T to
sort of revitalize them before he take
him back indoors again um he's always
preached that and that makes perfect
sense to me because I mean the plant
really does want that full spectrum and
whatever it is in the sun you know
that's not getting replicated well
enough indoors like it really it really
cranks them and uh and can bring back
their health for sure
yeah outdoor some sunshine therapy right
it's I've always said it's like it's
impossible to match the the Spectrum
that's coming off of that burning ball
of helium there's there's probably
factors there that we can't even
quantify that's happening I like how he
called it a burning ball of hel I didn't
even consider the sun was helium thank
you sir mostly mostly
helium just noticing that we maybe got
another like 15 20 minutes until we hit
the 2hour mark and um one thing I wanted
to ask you all is does anything change
towards Light Flow because I think okay
today we're probably not going to get to
like Harvest and post Harvest maybe that
would make a good next installment do
Harvest and post Harvest but um what
about like late flour specifically were
there any other considerations or you
know changes in like what you guys have
to do dayto
day I would say one one easy mistake is
if you use timers which I I've always
used timers and on valves to to do um
irrigation um at a certain point on my
outdoor it's on a timer and it's it's
whatever it is it's every other day
usually they get
watered um when the temperatures drop in
whether it be September or October make
sure you reduce the watering and so
you're not overwatering plants now that
aren't using as much water because the
night temperatures usually cool down
first and then it takes you know it
takes more time in the middle of the day
for the plant to sort of wake up and
start drinking water again um that's
that's one thing I think mistakes people
make and especially on those longer
flowering strains you you could end up
overwatering them all of October and I'm
I'm sure that just leads to petritis
issues and and and and just not not
capturing the the uh the best part or
the most important part of the flowering
cycle so that's that would be my little
tip y very nice Kush anything about late
flowering comes to mind for you um man
it it used to be a big concern for me
like you know super cropping the black
cherry soda where I was mostly worried
about weight but like the late SE it
like a lot of lot of big concerns don't
crop up for me anymore I mean if I get a
plant that I can see is susceptible to
mold and you know like five or seven or
eight of her colas are are being
attacked by it out of like you know 50
or 60 there was a point where I would
look at that and go [ __ ] you know I I
want to harvest this I want to stop it
before it happens any further but you
know as my as my goals change and as my
needs for for what I was growing changed
uh to just supplying myself and having
enough for some friends and some family
to hand out care packages um you know I
look at those things and now I'm not so
concerned about it and now it's more
like well how much can I push this plan
or how like one of my favorite things to
do is after I harvest a plant I leave on
about an ounce of mids and Littles uh
just left on the stem and I'll leave it
out there all season until the Snows
come and I'll check on it and I'll see
all right what got really attacked by
mold what what what's out here Way
Beyond Amber tricomes where stuff will
naturally Decay and still doesn't have
mold on it um it it allows me to
experience harsher conditions with some
of these plants and and what they can
really stand up to um I did a living
dead girl from CSI two years ago um
Pakistani chitrol Kush Urkel and Girl
Scout cookies um mixed together I left a
bunch of I bet I left some lar and some
Littles on it and I came out like a
month and a half later and I'm looking
at flowers that have no mold on them
whereas the other skeletal structures of
um some of the Urkel some of the the
more
half Urkle strains that had basically
baseball-sized Co baseball bat colas all
of that stuff is moldy top to bottom
turning brown already decaying past the
point of of life being in it and you
know I'm looking at this other planet
it's like yeah bring on more what what's
mold you know is it
terpinolene no no it was a it was
another um it was the pinear not pinear
the Living Dead Girl that specific one
was the peppery hashy one that um when
you ground it up once you got past the
the initial smells then a little bit of
fress came out in it but on the nose
pepper pepper like uh
spices um that was the one that was very
um pest resistant as well it was mold as
well as pest resistant um and she got
put to the test she was sitting in you
know she sat through a couple snowstorms
um she you know she endured some stuff
the another another really crazy one
that endured as much wet weather as
could have was the uh bubble gum to the
Albert Walker makes sense she that
bubble gum yeah after here in CSI talk
about his huge outdoor Bubble Run where
80% of it just endured those those
rainstorms it's like well [ __ ] I I'll
put it to the test and I Had It Outdoors
last year till
October 9th and then we got hit with
five inches of snow and she was such a
big plant that every all like the way I
tie my branches to my cages it created
fulcrums and every Branch broke right
where it was tied to the cage and I was
looking at I was like man I didn't want
to pull this plant down yet I wanted to
see how far she could really go in the
late season but you know she can't do
nothing about snap branches like that so
the real quick the blue resins flowering
super late right like it started late it
is it started late and it's flowering
late and it's um I'm looking I was
looking at it this morning and I'm
looking like at another another two two
and a half weeks before she's yeah it's
crazy man she's she's taking her sweet
time why what do you what causes that
late flowering trigger do we even know
it so it it's hard for me to nail it
down because I moved my garden from I
moved it like 150 yards down further
into a little bit so I have a little bit
light difference and uh it's a little
bit more of a corridor and I'm not
getting as as full sunlight as I was in
the in the spot before yeah so I there
there's two or three plants that I'm I I
expect August 1st by August 1st or
August 7th I should see I'm expecting
plants that are I can obviously tell
they're stretching this year some of
them it wasn't until the second or third
week of August where I was like oh yeah
this this lady is like really reaching
out there for the Sun so and that that
was one of them I mean she's freaking I
was on top of a six foot tall lad the
other day and I still couldn't get to
the top of her it's it's unreal how how
tall she is and just that skinny super
tall profile man I'm very interested in
the mold part of that too because the
bonnet's been extremely mold resistant
Kush is known for being a mold magnet uh
I was just looking over this morning I
only saw one little bit of Decay and it
was on a lower nug and it was uh it was
basically the Sugar Leaf not even a fan
leaf or an internal it was just an
external little bit it probably came
from a caterpillar [ __ ] on it or
some other it wasn't it wasn't like yeah
it wasn't actual mold created from PL
its own plant Decay on itself yeah I
think it was external this is a good
test for it too for me like to have it
be so late season up in your area to see
how it'll finish for mold I mean that's
killer yeah I mean if it was last year
the plant wouldn't have lasted it's
October 17th right now and I'm looking
at the weather and like we don't even
really have a big storm coming on the
horizon in the next seven to 10 days so
it's it's all smooth sailing for for the
rest of
that yeah dude looking forward to it
yeah that bubble gum oh sorry to to get
back to that bubble gum um
it was brought out to humble and it was
grown on the coast for years and if if
you can grow on the humble Coast like
you're definitely gonna be mold
resistant and it yeah and I guess it was
it was brought from like Indiana or
Michigan or somewhere and yeah and uh
those guys did great with it on the on
the coast which which just means it's
mold resistant and uh um it's it's
interesting to hear about it doing well
at higher elevation um I I already it
also finishes early that's another thing
fast um I've never grown it myself and I
haven't grown any hybrids of it
but um yeah all I hear is good things
about it Outdoors for just a good yep
bulletproof plant abut somewhat early
finishing extreme mold
resistance flavor y yeah totally totally
what I'm really sad about is the bubble
gum those bulk parts bubblegum turps
rarely ever transfer over to the final
flower you'll smell it all the way
through but when you go to smoke it it's
like dude I wish that Bazooka Bubble Gum
was still there and yeah yeah it's rough
on that part totally I got some of the
uh sweet 16 to bubblegum that I didn't
pop this year but I was given this year
from CSI and I think because all the
sweet 16 so far has this candy sweet
Rosy things I'm I'm wondering if that
bubble gum to the Sweet 16 doesn't
bolster those yeah lock it in and keep
it there cuz man all these sweet 16
hybrids dude it's just like it's like
walking into a candy shop it's
ridiculous how how good these plants
smell my money's on terpinolene turning
it up the only time I've ever experienc
pink bubblegum um flavors uh was with
the um old centi star the the Superstar
from Delta 9 Labs with they called the
95 ceny star the there's a specific
expression in there that's pink
Bubblegum and trinoline and for whatever
reason it translates to flavor super
well so I do have a bunch of the Durban
bubble gums from CSI that I'm probably
going to run this next year just to see
how that does you know how well that
translates out yeah a little bit of Anis
little bit of terpinolene right on top
of it that'll be good
yep thousand you around the bubbleberry
indoors
right yeah I rent it over summer no
dehumidification it was great it was
great it was yeah I would normally have
expected some Bettis under those
conditions but it was was
Flawless pretty chunky right yeah it was
chunky too and it did finish early too
your photos your photos kind of got me
wanting to pop them for next year I got
some from Matt at the party and I'm like
oh I want to do that Outdoors they kill
It Outdoors bro they kill It Outdoors I
got some to an Aussie guy um sold a few
packs of yours Matt he's in our Discord
actually Creep Show he oh yeah yeah some
of the craziest [ __ ] grows of it I've
seen man it was beautiful looking plant
so yeah I'm looking forward to running
It Outdoors too I think it'll be a good
one I did the Blue Sour last year so it
was those mystery seeds um yeah I did
that outdoors and that was the same like
uh really really [ __ ] hot conditions
I guess like 115 120 Fahrenheit high
humidity and like not a click a mold now
some good smoke that's St killer I get
some more that's awesome
yeah and guys yeah this has been a great
chat we've got to touch on like lots and
lots of different aspects of this um
like I mentioned we'll probably get to
come back and talk about Harvest and
post Harvest because that will be kind
of an interesting topic in of
itself um for now was there anything
else that you guys you know wanted to
mention before we wrap up one thing
before we wrap it up um if anybody has
any comments um about outdoor growing or
any tips anything we didn't cover that
you want us to hear be sure to leave a
comment below because uh yeah we're
always interested and we've been getting
amazing comments um from everyone
watching so be sure to leave a comment
yeah anything else from any of you that
you wanted to
mention before we wrapped
up no specific yeah it was a good chat I
liked I feel like there's so much more
we can cover too so I feel like another
episode definitely got to be on the way
for sure right on yeah totally Harvest
Harvest post Harvest uh topics and that
and that works for indoors too
absolutely y that would be interesting
to uh to see how other people are doing
it but like dealing with dealing with a
lot of harvest at once is has always
been the outdoor thing of it's all I bet
you have some crazy
stories yeah I mean yeah
you one one thing is you learn to be
ready like I've seen people drop the
ball on getting their Harvest rooms
ready or setting up some giant legal
grow
with Consultants but then not
understanding that their their plants
are going to do a lot better in southern
Oregon than they did in Colorado so
you're gonna have 10 times as much weed
oh yeah you know and now you've got
nowhere to dry it so you grew all the
weed and and it basically just rots on
the vine because you got hor yeah [ __ ]
them [ __ ] I I've seen people do that in
meno too where like br you know you're
trying to set up another carport to dry
in and that's already not ideal yep yeah
it's just like what were you thinking
like how how do you not think about dry
space like most girls will be like oh
man that's great where are we gonna dry
it like yeah how are we gonna dry it
like that's like that's part of it so
that's I don't know yeah this is the
trailer for for next yeah the next
installment right yeah
yeah uh any shout outs from any of you
for anything otherwise we'll shout you
guys out obviously hey shout out to you
boys thanks for organizing it
all yeah thanks for together
knowledge yeah this has been really fun
and um we're getting a really good
response from both the outdoor growing
and indoor growing episodes um maybe at
some point you guys have to have a dance
fight off against each other um uh but
no it's actually been great we've had
really good engagement on these um it
also gives me and Matt like more time to
look at like you know codex episodes or
like strain history episodes so it all
works out really well just kind of like
having a really good balance of content
at the moment um but other otherwise you
know just wanted to say yeah uh little
Hill is on Instagram little Hill
cultivators um Kush of the Giants on
Instagram Kush of the Giants again I'll
try to get links into the description uh
Matt booze uh also running grit by seeds
and has a podcast um remind me the name
boots of your podcast uh it's all about
trees but um we're talking about it you
and I know about that yeah yeah yeah and
we're gonna see booze on to help us more
as well uh in General on our show so
yeah hell
yeah nice Matt anything from you Matt um
no just the usual stuff go check out
reds.com for all all your femin seeds uh
spray and all of your seed needs um go
check out lifted genetics um you can
find him on IG we have ger by seeds at
Maddie and we also have right SE Co
Europe for international central
European uh we have our Discord patreon
and dude I've just been loving the
comments people have been leaving and
all the interaction we've been getting
on the videos um so yeah be sure to like
share subscribe it helps like when
people don't it actually does hurt and
it's free so just compl like share and
subscribe and uh other than that oh I've
got a couple little things so we're
about to hit 8 8,000 subscribers which
is awesome um I looked at the stats and
we I think we gained almost 5,000 this
year alone is kind of
amazing um and the other thing I'll
mention is do check out the Codex if you
haven't already we're already getting
some pressure from people to like do
more they're like hey going add more
stuff and it's like I'm sure it's like a
full-time job just doing the show but
but yeah we'll try we'll do it um but
yeah that that was all for me sorry just
want to add those things now get on a
thousand you got like 9,000 gelato cuts
to [ __ ] archive bro I want them on
there I want every last one no no no no
no gelato one through 80 the 22 was
popping all right with that I guess uh
are we done here is this it yeah we're
done thanks everybody thank you so much
everybody ADI later
[Music]
want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it
out