welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
weird before we get started too much I
got to tell you Francis
you tend to either cut off your head or
your chin
it's like very common
you know and you do have a very like
long you know oval shaped head but still
like try to back up off the camera a
little bit so that don't happen
I mean every now and again you'll like
reach in and it'll be like this
awkward moments yeah what really hurts
me is that like if I put on my glasses
it's like a really awkward distance so I
can't see that well without them but
then if I put them on I have to be like
way far back and that's awkward too so
well I'm sorry you know I don't I'm like
all sweaty and don't have petrified
bones and stuff like that but you know
I'm a cultivator not like a show
personality like exactly exactly yeah I
I just left the garden seconds ago
compared to compared to most shows uh
Matt and I are pretty Bare Bones yeah we
try to make the content speak for itself
rather than like all the fancy
accoutrements that come with it Gabby
and I used to go to so many concerts
together and we would often have like
joints of like dog and super dog and
different hybrids with us and it got to
the point where like often people would
like that were standing next to us it
would smell so good they would want to
share it with us yeah and him and I used
to have these like running debates if we
should like share or not because we had
literally been at events where like we
shared a few times and like people's
knees would Buckle because they got way
too high and then like security would
have to come and like help them you know
and so like yeah we got to the point
where because I can tell some stories
like that
today
um you know like the dog was like I mean
it still is but like it was really a lot
stronger than what most people had
access to
yeah so we smoked it every day so we had
a certain tolerance to it but there was
a lot of people that like two three hits
and like they'd be in a space they were
a bit uncomfortable in oh yeah
okay I'll start by telling a story I'll
start by telling a
story when the chem dog ruins somebody's
day
let's hear it um so I went to a Blues
Traveler concert at the Greek Theater it
was I believe it was 1991.
uh can't be sure but it was in the early
90s and I used to see Blues Traveler
when they were just a bar band in New
York City you know playing like small
clubs of like 50 people
and you know then they got big and they
opened for Jerry and you know we're
playing the Greek Theater and so I went
to the Greek Theater early to wait
online to get in to get a good spot
because you know if you're out from out
here you know the Greek Theater is
generally general admission which is
awesome
and so I'm you know waiting online and
I'm talking to people and I meet
somebody and you know I'm smoking online
which I always do and this guy you know
he has you know man can I try that it's
amazing
so he takes a hit so it takes another
hit
and he went from being this like really
excited like jovial character to like
just completely like
and not saying anything and
like he got so high
that when the show let in
like he sat down before the line went in
and when the show let in he didn't go in
oh no I'm like bro let's go they're
letting us in and he just sat there and
I'm like [ __ ] I'm like well I'm going
he like he waited online for hours to
get a good spot at the show
and then I don't know if he ever made it
in because that's hilarious he got so
high from two hits of the chem Dawn
then I had this other experience this
one was at Phil did a show at the
not the maritime all yeah maybe it was
called The Maritime Hall it was called
the philharmonia it was a sing-along
and I brought my camera
and I was taking pictures at this show
and of course I'm smoking the dog
and this lady behind me asks if she can
hit my joint so I'm like sure let her
hit the joint I and I wonder at this
point because I had already had this
experience with a few people just like
oh no I smoke every day you know I'm
good so
she takes a couple of hits off the joint
I'm not paying attention she was behind
me right
and I've been taking pictures and I got
this like film camera around my neck you
know with a strap
next thing I know she collapses because
like falling on top of me and I'm like
what's going on so I spin around and
when I sping her and spin around my
camera spins around and clocks are in
the head it was like it was like a
one-two punch
she was going down from the chem dog and
then my camera
and she had to get taken to like rock
Med over there and they're like what is
she on what happened and I was like it's
just weed
and like you know so so yeah I've had a
number of times when I shared the chem
dog with people
and it didn't go good and after a while
I started just telling people like
Francis said like you know I'd be like
no sorry you know and
that just makes him want it more like
people people thought people thought we
were being dicks and like Gabby and I
would be having these conversations like
are we going to ruin this person's
experience by being cool yeah you know
it was like an on it happened
I've been telling everyone I'm stingy
it's like a thousand people
you know on Discord that things that
Gabby is [ __ ] just stingy holding on
to it all Gabby
right I mean I uh
that's funny
I will say I don't know I don't know if
you heard this part uh yeah but you put
I I have mentioned a few times how like
when we were doing all of those when we
were making those like super dog hybrids
and we were playing around and we were
doing all those outcrosses and stuff
Gabby was honestly like one of the
people like earliest people amongst my
entire friend crew that sort of saw like
the future American Seed sales coming
and he used to talk to me and be like
dude we could we could take this eight
lighter you know because we did Big seed
runs you know we take this eight lighter
and he's like we could make so many
seeds with this eight lighter it would
just blow anything you could do with
flour out of the window yeah like we
could sell so many seeds and it was like
so early it was this was I don't know
when it was probably early 2000s or
something it was so early it was long
before you know seed companies in
America and IG made it like feasible I
honestly like we'd get into arguments
and I was like I don't see it dude I
don't see how to be able to do it I
don't see how we'd be able to have
customers all these take money and all
these people
no we couldn't at the time
but you were right you saw what was
coming and I was like you know later
it's not it's not gonna work and then
like 10 years later I was like man we
were just like too early business models
that are built on volume
and there's business models that are
built on scarcity you know and the
margins are very different you know if
you have huge volume you can have
smaller margins
you know if you've got big volume if
you've got big margins you don't need
huge
yeah I mean it's crazy because it's kind
of the same thing with clones right now
except it's more like people taking
advantage like selling [ __ ] for like
fifteen hundred dollars a piece that's
just like a garbage cross you know just
because they made a good name for
themselves and like at the emerald cup
people will be waiting online for like
the entire Emerald cup to pay fifteen
hundred dollars for for clones that
ended up having virus
yep you know like yep it was just you
know I mean it's part of it is
successful branding and then not being
honorable about it yes very much so I
mean it sucks because I think it's a
flawed business plan because as soon as
you build up your business to the point
where like you have all these people
that respect you and think that you're
awesome
and then all of a sudden you [ __ ]
everybody and the word gets out and like
it's so much worse now I heard a lot of
stories about deals that went bad with
them I I mean I don't know if you want
to cut this out because I ain't trying
to talk [ __ ] about people but um you
know he had contracts with people that
he had to give them like they had to
give a certain dollar amount for that
crop and their crop got completely
ruined because it was all virus yeah and
he still wanted his money
yeah like he destroyed these people's
livelihood by giving them like
infected and I'm not saying he did it on
purpose but like you give people
infected genetics and then you sue them
for not giving you the 200 bucks that
like you know they you know and
meanwhile these people couldn't get 300
bucks or 400 bucks for like quality herb
that was you know yeah
it was just like I mean the thing is is
like Francis and I said the seeds are so
cheap
right and if you have a problem
like this is an opportunity to show
people that you're solid or that you're
a scammer exactly that could have
happened to anyone that you know the
seeds were no good whatever
they just need to be like look we stand
behind you know our name and our product
and anyone that bought that is going to
get you know not just their seeds
replaced they're going to get extra
stuff and yeah you know wasting their
time make the customer feel good because
in the end the seeds don't cost you [ __ ]
yep you know and like you took so much
into making your reputation
how do you just screw so many people
over let the whole world know that that
you're terrible and [ __ ] over your
entire business I don't understand how
people do that I run into this all the
time Gabby when we chat where it's like
a lot of times I will talk in
generalities about like certain things
that go on in the community because even
just telling stories that are true
people get mad but if you mention like
when we if I mention somebody's name
specifically as an example their friends
will like cut out that 15 second clip
and send it to them and then I'll have
like furious people in my DMs all mad
that I'm like trying to like [ __ ] with
their wallet or destroy their way of
life or like disparage them in some
fashion you know okay so one thing that
I want to say that's not really a story
I don't know if it was not so dog or
someone else in the Discord that said
that what people appreciate me is that I
didn't Flex
yeah and
you know I thought about it and I said
to myself
I'm not opposed to flexing yeah for [ __ ]
that actually I can Flex about I don't
feel I don't feel like I'm that response
for it and there's other things that I'm
so much more proud of like yeah my hydro
store the garden spout you know I I had
the first
real Grow shops in Mendocino County
there was Spare Time Supply but they
sold lights in the back of an ocean
container to people that knew about them
yeah
I opened up
I opened up a grow store in Willits at
the time Highway 101
stopped being a highway and just was
like a one lane in each Direction Road
through the town of Willards so anyone
traveling north would drive straight
through town
yeah and I got this little store on Main
Street what I was saying was that when I
put my store up it was right on Highway
and I literally lit up the highway with
the orange glow of high pressure
frames and it was the Talk of the Town
like nobody could believe that I was
being so ballsy
to like put these lights up in the
street
yeah you know and
um
you know one by one you know the locals
from the hills came down and they heard
that they could trust me and that I
would deliver soil to them holy [ __ ] I
delivered soil in the most dangerous and
not like dangerous like gun dangerous
like the roads were just psychotic but
if I would have known I never would have
done it you know you get like committed
to this drive and now you can't turn
around yeah driving this like U-Haul
style box truck looks overloaded with
soil through like 10 creeks and [ __ ]
you're like oh my God
but um I taught a lot of people how to
grow weed and I taught a lot of people
how to grow better weed than they were
already growing
and
brought new products to our Market
and that's the stuff that I'm really
proud of
and
it's not that I um
I didn't always love cannabis and always
grow cannabis but for a long part of my
life
okay so let me take a step back here's
how the story went
when I was growing before working and
and owning hydro stores
I was paranoid
and I wasn't making friends
and I wasn't talking to people about
growing weed which is what I realized I
really like to do is talk to people
about growing weed which is one of the
reasons why me and not so dog got along
so good like because that's what what he
wanted to do too
and um
what happened was one day the hydro
store that I was shopping at it's called
Hydro Depot
the guy asked me if I wanted a job
and at first I was like no I don't want
a job you know I'm doing pretty good
doing what I'm doing
and then I realized
that if I got this job
and I worked it for a few months I could
make a legitimate income and then like
maybe work towards buying a house
instead of like you know renting my
entire life
so I started working at the Hydro Depot
and that's when I realized that as much
as I have a passion for growing
have a passion for talking to people
about weed and teaching people what I
know about weed and
I really felt like my calling
was to do that
because not only was I making a good
living
I was loving every minute of it you know
when when clients would come in
I would love talking to them you know
like
you know I let other people handle the
inventory and the you know
all the you know boring stuff of running
a business and I would just talk to
people about growing weed
and I was always really honest with them
and that's why people came back
you know because they knew I wasn't just
trying to sell them some [ __ ] because
oftentimes people would come in and be
like should I buy this and I'd be like
absolutely not don't do it
you know perfect example was LED lights
before they were ready
you know when I opened up my store it
was a 2002 there was already people
trying to sell LED lights
remember the UFOs Francis oh yeah you
know I mean they were garbage they you
couldn't successfully grow basil with
those plants let alone a fruiting crop
and um and they sold for a lot of money
and I used to tell people if this
technology worked
I would make so much money because
everybody would want to change everybody
with high pressure sodium would
immediately want to buy these these LEDs
I would kill it yeah but I couldn't with
good conscience so even though people
coming in like wanting the lights and
I'd have to be like no it's a bad idea
you know and so I'm proud
and this is a very minor Flex that I
feel throughout the years I made a good
reputation for myself
um with Growers
because I was honest and I was a place
where they could come for information
and
they felt safe yeah you know people felt
safe at my start
and
you know so when we're talking about
flexing it's like
I think I can Flex about that a little
bit I'm proud of proud of that I hope
that that's you know
it's going to be a part of my legacy you
know when I'm gone for sure the chem dog
thing is just like
you know well I don't think I mean I'm
blushing and you know like kind of like
it makes me smile that I'm getting this
attention about it but like
Greg he's the one that popped the seeds
people that he distributed to like what
are they getting credit for like where
do you draw the line of giving people
props sure me is it you Francis is it
Jason and Ben or like people 10 10 rows
past them that got it that
maybe did better [ __ ] with it than all
of us
well you know I mean
I look at it a little different you know
um I'll I'll talk about the chem dog for
a second and then I'll move on to the
store because I actually think there's
some parts about the store that people
would not really realize today but I'll
start with the chem dog obviously I
think that
you know for whatever reason even though
it might be like even though people
might play a small role in something
that role could be super important like
it turns out somehow that the cutting
that you brought West seems to be the
one that survived
and it got and I'm not sure if it would
be around if you hadn't come out to
California with it and then eventually
shared it with a few close friends uh
like skunk VA or IC Collective or myself
or whoever and so you know like that
might be small but it's also important
because it was a critical step like when
they wanted it back on the East Coast
they had to get it from the West Coast
because that's where and in prohibition
right where people get busted and people
move on and things change a lot of cool
things got lost
right and so I kind of feel like my only
part of the chem dog story is really
like hearing the stories early
right and maybe helping to preserve it
at a time before it was famous
and then
like and so perhaps like on the on the
the store thing people might not realize
this but one of the things that Gabby
was talking about which was critical
back then was that information on how to
grow good weed was really hard to come
by
and most people that knew how to do it
wouldn't talk to you so in stores were
also super rare like Gabby is right when
he opened up his store he was the first
go ahead if you want to make me blush
Francis you can repeat yourself all
right so so I do feel like things about
me as as Gabby mentioned when he opened
up the store in in Mendocino County
there was like Spare Time Supply which
was a big player but they were
predominantly a garden store and an
outdoor store and an amendment store
there was no indoor or Greenhouse
focused store going on at all and stores
back then were actually rare
right
um and and there wasn't very many of
them and having someone in a store that
was knowledgeable and willing to talk
right was huge and it was kind of a
risque thing and even though proposition
215 had happened it was still very much
in the shadows and so he's he I think he
sort of opened up your shop at the very
beginning of like the 215 medical green
Rush era where there was all these
people coming to our County and coming
to Humboldt in these different areas
that were new they had no idea what they
were doing and they were like I want to
set up a garage in a greenhouse and I
don't even know what to get
and so for a long time it was like
eventually stores became like who had
the best price and people were more
knowledgeable but probably for the first
five or six years that Gabby had a store
it was I mean he sold stuff but it was
also like it was tons of education on
what stuff those people needed so you
know the store in the early years was
basically like a massive educational
model and then as Gabby and then you
know educated people they bought things
from him
yeah because they literally hadn't they
didn't know how to wire stuff they
didn't know about like you know lighting
boxes they didn't know about fan
movement they didn't know about any of
that and so it's like they'd have money
and they're like What's the best set of
equipment for my set of circumstances
and so you have this whole County that
was starting to really blow up and grow
but the funny thing about it is all the
stores that opened up they were all my
customers first yeah like I literally I
literally taught them everything that
they knew about the business people
don't realize it today but
like information
was the thing that was super important
people literally they had money but they
had no idea what they were doing and
like what's weird about it too is that
you start like if you spent time there
you learned a bunch because people would
come to you not only to get set up but
they would come to you with like every
problem imaginable
yeah and you would have to and Gabby
would have to sit down with them and
figure out how to solve it
and then the more you help people solve
it the bigger your like information or
expertise or knowledge base grows so
when someone else brings up that same
problem like you have right and so I
don't think people today with all the
all the forums and all the information
and all the internet and everything
really understand how hard it was
to talk to people that knew how to grow
weed even on the basic level
like and so probably the first five or
six years his store was open it was a
boom time where everyone in Mendo and
Humboldt and all these places were just
constantly setting up new stuff whether
they were indoor whether they were
greenhouses whether they were light
deprivation it was just an enormous boom
of economy and no and very and maybe 10
of the people knew what they were doing
and would come in and like would have a
good idea of what they wanted and battle
on price and stuff but often they would
come in completely oblivious
you know and so and so I I just wanted
to mention that I don't think into in
2023 people understand like Dragon Ball
Z having a hydro store was and being
willing to openly talk about
you know about growing with people
you know I mean that was the era where
like you walk into a head shop and you
say the word bong and they toss you out
in case you were undercover and they
were going to shut down the real shop
for real right yeah um you know there
was you know there was a so it was
pretty risque it was like pretty out on
the on the on the Cutting Edge of things
if you will uh to do that type of stuff
and so there's an enormous amount of
people that got their start buying
equipment and buying soil and buying all
kinds of stuff I mean one thing I could
mention is like when you opened your
shop dude uh we were still all growing
in like in um you know in like a light
Warrior or you know or perlite peat moss
mixes and stuff like that Gabby was one
of the first people to really like
preach about cocoa fiber
and how it was going to revolutionize
like growing
and you know people had no idea what it
was that's wow like at all you know and
it was brand new okay go ahead so what I
remember is that you know cocoa fiber if
I if I remember correctly the reason why
it became popular was in Europe they
decided that they wanted more
environmentally friendly medium to grow
in right and Rockwell wasn't it and so
they were looking around for something
that was biodegradable and a renewable
resource and they realized that there
was these giant piles of cocoa fiber and
Sri Lanka and India and other places
that were just waste products that they
shredded off the cocoa to get to the
coconut yeah right
and so they realized that if they
started buffering it and treating it the
right way
that you know
um it could be an excellent grow media
yeah and then Gabby got some
and there was stuff that was from like
because in Canada that was RHP certified
which basically meant it was regulated
and it was guaranteed to be a certain
level of quality and we started growing
in it and I remember Gabby being like Oh
my god dude like we'd pull pot he'd pull
plants out of pots and be like look at
these roots I bet like literally like
look at how white and happy look at look
at and from that point on he was kind of
like a little bit of a prophet about it
and no one had ever really heard about
it and his store had it
um and I think we he got lucky and that
he was getting it from reputable sources
yeah and there there was other people
that were getting it cheaper but they
were getting it full of like sea salt
and it was unbuffered and people were
having nightmares in the beginning oh
sure right
um but I mean his store was open right
at the time that like cocoa fiber first
started percolating around and no one
had even heard of it
you know
um and you know people back then they
didn't even know you know it was even
simple stuff like why 600s were better
than thousands because they were cooler
and they gave you more points of light
yeah you know
um there was a lot of stuff that people
consider basic now which was like
essentially in my opinion like hidden
knowledge
and so he's right he would just talk all
day long
to people
and they would write out all kinds of
lists of stuff they needed and then he
would hand the list to like an employee
and they would start filling it and he
would turn around and he would talk to
the next person
and so he just talked about growing weed
like here's the reality
Francis was way better than I was really
yeah well you know he was like yeah
he had patients
I'm just like always like I'm trying to
help people
I mean I wanted it wasn't like I was
rushing him out the door I wanted to
make a comfortable environment but I was
just always busy too one thing like I
tried myself in so my hydro store was
based on largely
a Dutch model
and the Dutch model was I went to
Holland
and I went to the growth stores
and they all had espresso makers there
and
I had this idea
okay because when I was working for
Slavic
she would always say to me gabby I want
them to buy and get out
and what I try to tell him is that the
longer they stayed
I got opportunities to sell them more
stuff yeah you know he would see he
would see it as I'm just talking to
these guys you know for 45 minutes about
growing you know and that you know he'd
rather maybe sweeping the floor or
something else yeah but in the end what
I was doing was building a repertoire
with the customers you know that it
would trust me and then they would shop
exclusively at our store and you know
it would trust me so when I opened up my
own stores the garden spout
you know I put a coffee bar in and I had
shares there for the customers to hang
out
and that was pretty unheard of for a
growth store was to make a place like I
wanted it to be a cool place
where people want to hang out yeah you
know and of course some people abuse the
privilege and got annoying and we'd have
to ask him to leave of course but for
the most part like
it wasn't only me talking to people
other people would like hear what people
were saying and then they would like
interject and it became like almost a
gathering point
you know so as far as how I got involved
with the cocoa it's because that's what
the Dutch were doing okay and I met
people while I was in Holland
um at the Hawaii Fair which is like a
traditional AG show yeah and um
and then when I opened up my store they
had heard about it they came and visited
me and you know so the first one we
would buy because Coco
and then Canada Coco and then you know I
started trying to Source some myself
from some of these reputable companies
but
like I said like those are the things
that I want to be proud of
you know to me that that's like
a much bigger
you know I think that's my minor Flex
you know I think it's a one thing I want
to say about the chem dog Flex go ahead
how much of an [ __ ] would I look like
if I did Flex about my part with the
chem dub
I mean I think I'd be in like I'd be
looked at like an [ __ ] like like
you're saying other people think others
are [ __ ] who are doing that Flex
yeah you know the only one who's got the
real Flex is Greg yeah you know and like
anyone else past that it's just kind of
like all right you have it what did you
do with it yeah and you know like
Francis said people did good [ __ ] I
think Jason made beautiful crosses with
the condo
you know and um who else did you oh yeah
I see yeah them too so I mean people did
great stuff with it and and that's their
Flex
what they did with the chem dog not
their like part of the chem dog story
like they acquired it okay
you know and having said that like
I don't really care like I don't look
I'm happy
for Jason
and Ben
that like
this could help them in any way
you know like
it's different like
yeah
yeah I mean
I love this yeah I think it goes back to
a different era
where the way you got Cuts generally
speaking back then was like you honestly
became good friends with someone and
then what was that like and then you
shared things and then you did things
together and you now people would call
it a collaboration but back in the day
it was more just like you know friends
doing cool little side projects together
you know like friends sharing Cuts so we
could help keep them alive because there
was fires and accidents and busts and
different things that could happen where
you could lose something and it was much
more informal so it was like you know
um you know sometimes people would be
like well how do you get cuts and it's
like I don't know you like become
friends with someone that has Cuts but
that's not the reason why you became
friends it's like you have an honest
relationship with someone and then that
leads to other things yeah you know so
it's almost like organic in the way that
it like it developed
you know uh and um
I don't know that's just kind of how I
see it but I think I think it's very one
thing
it's not necessarily a flex but I think
it's very very
um special to be someone who inspires
someone else who does something quite
remarkable it changes a culture whether
it's sour whether it's cam whether it's
getting to the West Coast
but helping inspiring other whether
you're teaching growing any of that to
be able to like know on your deathbed
that you've left something behind that
has inspired someone else and made their
life better then that's that you know I
mean like that should be good enough
right that's ultimate I think so that's
why I said like if you called up and
said hey Gabby
I was talking with not so dog and we
want to talk to you about the garden
spout and how you you know accomplish so
much and then it'd be like all right
yeah I mean like I'm proud of that and I
can actually like you know
you know but like this idea that I had
such an integral
part of it I mean I had a little part of
it I brought it out to the West Coast I
don't want to minimize it either like
because I know if I didn't bring it out
and it's not out here and maybe it's
lost but um products that we did I wish
the breeding projects that we did
produced more of like what I actually
wanted yeah you know like more of a chem
dog you know tramping profile because we
we did some great [ __ ] but it just
didn't turn out that dog-like and so if
I would have done that then I could have
been proud of that and then I could have
felt like I had more of a part of the
chem dog history because I took it to
the next step and maybe that is a reason
for Jason and Ben to flex because that
is what they're doing right sure they're
taking plants that
pretty much it would be a mistake for
most people to grow it period
you know like unless you're looking to
use it for breeding
you know like growing this for the
flower
you know and having said that I want to
grow it for flower again because
I feel like I have knowledge and tools
available to me now that I didn't have
then
and maybe I could get it to show me
something
you know better than back in the day
absolutely you know
um the one thing I was mentioning in the
Discord is leaf tissue sampling yeah
yeah that blew my mind I hadn't even
thought of doing that with it
yeah so I've already done this at
facilities that I worked with worked at
and
so
I don't know who to give credit to but
somebody mentioned to me that you know
we've been looking in books at this is
what this deficiency looks like this
what this deficiency looks like
but generally what that means is this is
what a plant looks like when it has zero
nitrogen or like it's not deficient it's
just absent yeah and all and also
or extreme deficiency right yeah and
then also those photos never show you
what does deficiency look like when it's
a number of elements yeah that's true
you know like because what it's going to
look like is going to look different
and you know for years
the standard thing was oh I had more
calmag yeah yeah it doesn't look right
well what kind of whatever it was just
add more calmag it always makes
everything better yeah it always makes
it green
plants like calcium and when I did my
testing
the testing showed that I needed more
calcium okay but at least we're not just
guessing yeah you know the testing is
really inexpensive it's like 75 to 100
per sample okay okay and so it's very
inexpensive and it gives you a lot of
information and with the chem dog being
a plant that wants to consume itself
prior to harvest like you know two weeks
before you're supposed to cut it you'd
have not a single Green Leaf left on it
yeah no no it was so hard to keep this
plant yeah
um
with uh with the leaf analysis we can
learn how to feed it a little bit better
and maybe keep it Greener a little bit
longer and action you know actually get
a product that
is more like what we've been looking for
all this time
sure one of the one other thing I I
might mention if we're gonna like uh
Flex for Gabby here or whatever is
that's not what timing this is is it I
know but but I thought we did enough of
that you know I used to go I used to go
into a bunch of different hydro stores
um for various reasons and I think Gabby
was the first person that I knew that
was really pumping tissue culture not
like the meristem stuff but like the
proper like the cleanliness and the
propagation and all that and there was
this guy
um Bill Graham bill yeah still around
and he had these and he had these kits
uh and he Gabby used to have milky.com
for people that want to work for it he
used to come into the store and Gabby
would have him do demos
of how to sterilize like a tub how to
get clean how to like take clean cuts
and like bleach and sterilize the cuts
and then get them into solution and I
can tell you like as a as a grower it
looked like some Voodoo in the beginning
I bet you know like at the time nobody
was doing that nobody was even thinking
about it like nobody was nobody was
applying that to cannabis but I by any
means yeah
um and you know he had a whole shelf on
his store and he would invite bill in
and he would and they would do Demos in
the shop and he would get people to try
it and wow and all that type of stuff
and I mean that was literally in the
early 2000s
uh long now it's become like a big the
only reason that made me think of it is
as you were talking Gabby about Leaf
tissue like I kind of feel like because
weed was so illegal for a while we were
reduced to observational stuff and we
didn't really have access to labs and we
didn't really have access to some of the
scientific stuff that regular AG did
because we were too scared and the labs
didn't want to deal with us so we had to
like work off what we saw
and talking amongst ourselves and now
he's right in the sense that you can go
get tissue analysis and you can get hard
data that backs up your thoughts
right yeah
um but you know tissue culture was like
some voodoo
you know taking these tiny little
plantlets it seemed very extreme at the
time like why would you go through all
that trouble when you just clogged it
seemed extreme but now knowing more
about diseases you know hops latent
viroid and stuff it's I wish everyone
would have been using that method and
you know Bill Bill would come in and and
you know Gabby would tell a bunch of
good customers and friends and stuff the
dude's gonna come in and he's going to
give a demo and he's going to teach you
how to use this stuff because it was
like especially to a bunch of Growers it
was like some straight Voodoo it was
Advanced so let me say something real
let me let me say something real fast
so I sold a bunch of those kits
yeah and I honestly believe almost no
one took it out of the box I believe it
because it was still it was still too
like intimidating like the kid didn't
cause [ __ ] I think it was like 135 bucks
yeah yeah something like that you know
it was really inexpensive but they had
to go buy a pressure cooker and make the
gel and like you know I was able to sell
it
but like most people were still a little
bit intimidated to do it and I remember
I was
in one day Bill Graham
Grant store and we do it
and then every single day
I was doing tissue culture in my store
in front of people that were just
walking in and
you know
even though they didn't do it
they were still like inspired and it
made them excited about something you
know exactly so
um
but yeah a few people actually did it
I really thought I was gonna
be adopting this and doing this
and it was kind of like the seed thing
they just weren't ready yet yeah I mean
the same thing is interesting in that
you know I I talk about this on the show
quite often where it was like
you know Gabby and I and some other
close like we honestly were just trying
to make better wheat and all the seeds
we made all the projects that we did
everything like that especially because
of what like flower prices were back
then it was a terrible financial
decision because we could have just been
blowing up rooms of flour and getting
top dollar for it way back then you know
so it was literally like a labor of love
you know and it was it wasn't
necessarily about like oh what do we
think people will like it was like what
do we like personally and can we make
stuff that we like
and you know Gabby I I was thinking
about it because
uh Matt and I have been blessed in a way
to talk to some of like Neville's good
friends that were close to him in the
last years of his life
and it's funny because one of the things
Neville said is like I wish I didn't
fail so much
right I don't know if I did if I don't
know if the best stuff that I got I
improved on it at all I wish I knew now
I wish I would have known then what I
know now and I had a different shot at
it
and so I think that thing that you
expressed is very common in breeding
where people that breed are very
self-critical
and they tend to Discount what they did
when they did it
because they wanted it to be better
and they had their own goals in it and
then every failure I mean there's a lot
of things if you take it serious there
has to be a lot of failure because you
you'd just be hitting you know numbers
all day and that's that's just not how
it works that's not how I mean I I don't
think you I don't think it's failure in
the sense of you produce Something
Beautiful
it's a failure in the sense of you have
an expectation of what you're going to
produce and you have a lot less control
of it than you know because that's just
ego you know either that or it's really
expert breeding
all right really anal attentive people
like I just I mean
you would think like so when we did the
F1 cross
you know with back to the chem dog right
and then we grew out so many thousands
of these seeds
you would have thought that some would
have like really been dog-like yeah they
just weren't
you know so you would think like you
know when you when you do that first
cross you get the most diversity and now
you just gotta do the hunt
but the the skunk was so dominant
that
you know
there was traces of it you know like
yeah it's not like it doesn't
yeah yeah of course
[Music]
dogweed
you know the other thing the other thing
I think we should mention because like
the game is flipped now go ahead no go
ahead uh is that when Gabby and I were
doing all this all the feminized
reversals and stuff like that were still
years away we kind of thought that like
at times that like hermaphrodism and
like accidental pollinations we're gonna
lead you down the wrong path
all the stuff that we did was with
regular males and so you had to create
hybrids and then and back cross and all
that and you know we had to grow out the
seeds to see if what we did did what we
wanted
there was no idea that we could take two
females and reverse one of them and add
this it was all regular well we knew we
could do it but would never consider it
already selling seeds by that time
feminized it's just we are delighted we
thought that hermaphrodism and seeds
from hermaphrodism were risk
hermaphroditism
because you were going to infect your
line with more traits that were bad
and you know and and that was just kind
of like I don't know in the not late
that in the early 2000 like that was
just the the Common Thread then I think
I'm still on certain I was talking to
Matthew about this the other day like to
me like
it's
you know it's weird it does it seems
like it's very common well I know it's
common I know it's oh I and I know it's
commonly done but I still feel like
doing this has to pose some type of risk
no I mean it's common for people to feel
like you do
what do you think we're wrong
yes I think I think you're totally wrong
but but
to an extent this is proven by genetics
like by genetic mapping yeah yeah yeah I
mean maybe it's just hard for males to
accept it like we might become
irrelevant
I mean it's it's actually normal I would
accept that I would accept that more
than
now we've gone to a point where regular
seeds are you know unicorns almost in
the Cannabis world and almost everything
is feminized reversals of some fashion
yeah you know uh when Gabby and I were
doing it like you know the only
feminized seeds we knew of were
um uh you know accidents
essentially
yeah I mean yes 100 I'd never heard of
reversals I'd never heard the only
reversals we had ever heard of then was
like you stressed the hell out of the
plant too
hermaphrodite itself you put it in a
small container you gave it drought you
messed with the light sky cycle until it
freaked out and did some weird stuff
there was nothing there was no sprays we
ever thought about trying to like induce
anything it was like you basically like
tortured the plant until it did what you
wanted yeah that was the tech that we
knew of back then I think
and it just seemed like the wrong path
yeah like I said it's very common for
people from Air era to still have that
that mindset everybody we've talked to
on here from your exact era all have
that same opinion still to this day and
it's like you know and it is
I've so I always say that you're old
when you think you know everything
and so I'm glad that like I'm not
confident about this and that every day
my opinion might be going more towards
towards yours Matt
um like in a conversation we had
um
I feel like selfing could be more
problematic or it seems like it you know
could have more potential for problems
but um so one thing like we're talking
about Colin from ethos
like he said something and it seems so
obvious it's like how can I go my whole
life and not think of this
but when you cross two females
you have a so much better idea of what
you're gonna get oh for sure and like
trying to judge trying to judge what
male was the right one to use
it's like
I don't you know
you have to be very very Adept or very
very little repetitive yeah
you have to do things over and over
again you know and then do a lot of
testing which is almost impossible to do
yeah like how does one grow out
thousands of seeds and preserve every
single clone of everyone trying smoking
every female
yeah I mean we would do
Gabby and I would do this thing where we
settled kind of like when we were doing
the super dog stuff is like I think we
picked out like our seven or eight
favorite males based on like books and
certain traits and then we put them all
in the room not so usually like the ones
with the cute butt cheeks yeah we put
them all in the room and then you know
they get to a certain point like you
beat them with a with a you know a
bamboo steak or something like that and
all the fans are on and you just like
the pollen would just spread everywhere
and we're like well it's gonna make the
hunt harder
but since we don't know which male is
doing what did you find was the one we
wanted to just find the one and we
wanted maximum diversity
and that's how that's how you're going
to get it trying to be so arrogant that
like you can pick it
that wasn't us you know so like having
having three or four males in there
it was a big yeah of yeah finding that
needle needle in the haystack
but we presented it when we gave them to
see they're all going to be good
you know they're two phenomenal plants
crossed together it's just like they're
all gonna be good but you know
you've got to grow a bunch of them and
you're gonna find
you know a few that are super amazing
yeah
do you remember Gabby the one of the
final one of the final breedings we did
I I was trying to I was racking my brain
for their names and their names really
aren't important I guess but you had
these buddies of yours and they gave us
a version of the black domino and they
gave us that Warlock
um and that those two things because we
did this we when we did the like the one
of the final super dog greetings we
basically put these like I don't know
seven or eight different males that we
had picked in there with all of the
super dog females that we liked and then
literally like every good cut that we
could get access to so we had the dog
and we had the super skunk and we had
the and we had the you know the Mendo p
and we had the Warlock and we had the
black domino and we had
I'm got I mean like literally every good
female cut that him or I had we kind of
gathered them all up and we put them in
there
so if you found the one you didn't care
what made the one you just needed to
find the one
yeah I mean knowing what it was knowing
what it was would have been helpful to
to try to do more things like that but
like for instance I don't remember who
gave me the black domino
but I remember the reason why we bought
it
was and I think that was like from
Scentsy seed or yeah we purchased seed
from from some Seed Company the
description said extremely spider mite
resistant ah yeah you know so the weed
was garbage it really wasn't that good
but if we could make our weed you know
we could cross it with a you know not so
dog and get a plant that was good
quality and Spider-Man resistant yeah
that was a good thing yeah you know so
that's why that that's why that one was
in there what was the other one that you
mentioned the remember the Warlock they
both came from the same people
I can't remember who gave me them yeah I
remember the weave yeah they were they
were your buddies neither no yeah
neither was that good
yeah if you're comparing to chem dog I'd
imagine not I mean the funny thing is
like there's things where I felt exactly
how Gabby felt and then years later I
was like man I was just like discounting
too many things because they weren't
like my favorite doesn't mean they
weren't valuable it just means that like
they weren't my top couple you know and
as I got older I appreciated different
qualities of weed you know where in the
beginning it was kind of like
I don't know you know you wanted that
weed that tasted amazing and like hit
you across the head with a two by four
yeah in a way
you know
I I wanted to cover sour a little bit
more uh we talked a little bit about how
you met klopp but what were some of your
impressions of sour
honestly I didn't have
many till much later on
when was your first experience I mean
and
we used to grow a lot of it
you know
um I don't remember exactly what it was
it was one of the deal with it was
it was a highly productive strain of
beautiful weed
that we could sell easily yeah and you
know
I was I was on the Discord
and somebody had to remind me or tell me
that most of the people in the Discord
are really small Growers like yeah they
grow in a tent and it's for personal use
and you know
there's a big difference between that
and even somebody that grows in his
garage
you know has a 10 lighter in his garage
okay now you do need to make some money
to pay for your expenses and the whole
reason why you put up 10 lights in your
garage was to make a little money in the
first place exactly so
you have to you have to do what's
marketable
and that's part of the reason why we
gave up on the chem dog in the first
place
yeah well you know when you're getting
such a terrible yield
you know often this plant like
we couldn't justify like we'd have to
sell it for 50 to 100 more than we would
to sour
yeah we weren't getting that much more
for it
you know so like we would keep it and
we'd grow a little bit for our head
stash and like Francis said you know
somebody was growing it and we would all
you know share a little bit of it the
[ __ ] would never get sold because we're
growing such a small amount of it that
you know it didn't make it to the to the
marketplace
so and
you know
I want to I want to publicly say this
sure I love cannabis
should I say that louder I love cannabis
I want to make a living working in
cannabis
and to do that it's like a total
different thing
than when you're just trying to grow for
yourself whether it's in your backyard
or in your tents
you know it is if I was growing just for
myself
I would just grow ogs
that's really what I like to smoke yeah
you know whether it's the chem dog or
you know other really nice ogs that's
really the palette that I like
yeah you know and actually I should say
this please want to have a diversity
but then there's that always the staple
that I go to every morning but then I'll
mix in some other stuff like I love
sativa turps I love Citrus turps you
know I you know I love to have a variety
you know so I as I was telling you guys
I smoke these
um soft spots yeah and I have like
30 different types of terpenes some of
them are so aggressive that it's
shocking like you smoke them it's it's
almost offensive like it's too much I
bet but it's still awesome you know yeah
and um so but still I still always in
towards the OG's is what I like now
right now
in California in the commercial
Marketplace
um
it's hard to sell a lot of OG
wow you know and
it's a first in the
um
that's been going on for a minute you
know and I think you know you know like
in the Discord people are hating on
gelato
right oh yeah yeah but [ __ ] that's what
that's what that's what big farms wanna
buy right now
you know like they're missing the market
lots of gelato
yeah
yeah but so let me tell you a mistake
that I made
okay
having a new Nursery right and I have
all these genetics that are super
awesome but nobody knows anything about
yeah and so you try to sell people on
this stuff
but with today's market they need to
know that they're getting a home run
yeah and so it's so hard to get them to
try something new
you know when right now they can sell
all the Lemon Cherry gelato they can
Grill exactly yeah so after so like when
when I started this I didn't have a
Lemon Cherry gelato I was like by the
time I get this thing in mass production
it's gonna be like the um
ice cream cake or yeah yeah or you know
like nobody's gonna want this weed
anymore
yeah you know and so but like it's
managed to have lasting power as far as
the demand for the flower and the Clones
so if you're growing a pen lighter
in your garage
you're really better off you know
growing something that people want
you know and then maybe a small section
of it for your own personal
which is what Francis and I did yeah you
know we we always do a little bit of a
Ken dog but like we had to go to a
strain that was more productive
and that people wanted to buy it
you know the funny thing about the term
the super skunk is the most beautiful
weed
like the chem dog is the best the super
skunk
like I think that weed is the most
beautiful weed
I love the way it looks too yeah
yeah it was green and Frosty and it
smelled like crazy and it was super
pungent and it's a kind of Aroma that
like is very universally recognized by
Americans as like crazy smelling
um
you know and I also think too that like
to the point that Gabby was making it's
weird in that if certain strains don't
leak and they don't get out to a certain
amount of people then the demand for
them can't grow which then makes selling
it much harder because we would try to
sell the chem dog and they would be like
ah this is kind of like some like
backseat OG or something like if how
good could it be if I don't have access
to it yeah and since there was only like
a few garages or something like that in
our Greenhouse or two that was trying to
grow some it was like Brokers want to
buy a home run
and to them that wasn't a home run and
it was before the Forum Fame and it was
before it got like a really big name for
itself in public and so people just
wanted things that was going to be
something easy for them to flip
there's always a device so there's a lot
of marketing decisions I mean the I was
just gonna say that a lot especially in
Mendo you know in Humboldt and stuff
like that a lot of times what broker
what Growers grew what was what they
heard the Brokers wanted and was easy
so there was a few years there like for
instance if we wanted to go back and
talk about
um like uh you know Gabby's store like
every Big indoor grower in Mendocino
County was growing some kind of purple
Urkel or granddaddy purps or something
like that right you remember how many
Laytonville indoor gardeners Gabby were
growing miracle and Urkel because it was
easy and the BR and
Urkel yeah granddaddy perks you know all
those type of things and and then the
market shifted and it went to sour and
Kush
and all those Growers dropped the
purples and went right into what the
Brokers wanted
and so there's a you know there's a lot
there where it's like you might end up
liking a strain but you end up growing a
small amount of it for you and your
friends and a lot of times you end up
growing what the you know the majority
of what you grow is what you think the
Brokers or the market wants to absorb
relatively easily
so here's my new strategy
I want to have
30 percent of exclusive stuff
that you know I'm bringing to the market
you know one way or another I want to
have 30 percent
of you know
up and coming from known people
and then 30 percent that only ends up to
90 so 33 of each 33 of stuff that people
want right now
you know that way I can
I can sell people what they want now
while creating a demand for products
under my brand as well as Partnerships
with existing brands
you know but thinking I could do it all
with like exclusive stuff that nobody
knows anything about even though like
it's Fireweed that won the emerald cup
and it's like
that that takes a little bit more today
than it uses it takes a lot it takes a
lot yeah and a lot of legal a lot of
legal Farms they're sort of drowning
under upfront fees and costs and taxes
and operating expenses so they real
their margins are a lot of times quite
tight
um so they really want home runs because
they're worried about survival
you know um it's not for at least
especially for you know for most people
it's not a particularly lucrative time
in cannabis
it's kind of more of like a stay afloat
time
and the the more it's like that the more
people want certainty
and so that leads to sameness because
people want it hurts the quality it
hurts quality and it hurts diversity
because people are just trying to
produce an already popular thing at a
low cost
and get somebody to buy it
and it's risky like he was just saying
to try to promote fire that you
personally think is amazing but the
market might not think that yet and so
do you have the capacity to like
convince them or are you just going to
sit on it
it's different than when your Market was
you were showing your friends your weed
and smoking some with them and you know
then it was easier now it's like selling
it in bulk to whether it's a distributor
or a broker
you know
everybody
it's too far from the final person for
people to be taking these risks
and so
they're just pumping the gelatos
you know and realistically like
today I think in California
most commercial Farms they have some
type of gelato in their rotation
you know because
the market is calling for it you know
and the consumer the consumer
I don't want to call them idiots but
they're uneducated
that's the best word for it well it's
also to be fair to them Gabby it's also
hard to make new decisions when you walk
into a legal store and everything that
you want to check out is in a sealed
opaque mylar that they can't touch it
smell it smoke it or get excited about
it they just have to like spend a bunch
of money on it and then hope when they
open it up it's something good
and a lot of the way these mylars are
designed you don't even see the Cannabis
inside it until you've walked out of the
store and purchased it
they just look at what percentage THC it
is whatever it has the most they take
that
that's what they've been told and then
even if a farmer even if a farmer wants
to take risks it's not just on the
farmer the distro and the dispensary
also has to be willing to promote that
to the customer
so the farmer often time doesn't even
have control over whether or not the
customer is going to get educated
properly on why they think it's so good
yeah I really really try our best to
reach out to Bud tenders with this show
as as crazy as it sounds like they're
the the the last point before the
customers and we want them to be at
least be the most educated out of the
whole ring because they're the ones who
interact the most with the customers
you know you know what I was I was
remembering Gabby and uh I don't know
this is a totally random story but Gabby
and I did a project together where we
built this greenhouse on a property he
had
and we we thought it was we thought it
was a huge Greenhouse at the time but
now it's like laughably small
um but do you remember when we grew uh
the Maui dude and those buds were so big
we took those pictures where your head
was behind the cola and all you could
see was your ponytail and like your ears
sticking out because there was these
giant
High Time the classic High Time
submission photo yeah right yeah you
know that's that's what you know we'd
see in high cons is like a butt in front
of their face because you know we have
these Giants we had you know we grew I I
mean we had Urkel and Maui and Superdog
and various things in there those things
probably burned in your fire but at some
point we had all these pictures
and that's hard too because I was
thinking about it and it's like before
phones had cameras on them there was so
many less pictures taken there was so
many less you know
um Gabby had some nice cameras and so we
took some really cool photos of various
things that we were doing
um but all it took was a fire or a bust
or an accident or something like that
and all that history would be lost
you know
yeah we got yeah I always remember that
I always remember that like of Gabby's
head Behind These Maui Buds and all you
could see was like he used to have this
really long ponytail and you all you
could see was a part of the ponytail and
maybe the corner of one ear because the
bud was like you know because my ears
are [ __ ] big
but I mean it was pretty risque I mean
like you know I think like we started on
it the greenhouse was gonna be 20 by 50.
and Gabby thought that was enormous so
we shrank it to 20 by 30 and he was it
still seemed like it was ballsy
you know within it was on the very top
of it was on the top of the hill in an
open field
and you know a few years later that kind
of stuff was a little bit more the norm
but at the time it was coming out of the
tree lines and it was coming out of the
indoors and it was coming out of these
tiny little scenes and it seemed Giant
it seemed giant oh yeah for sure
you know in that regard
and uh you know even the idea that you
could put something like you just said
in like an open field
and you wouldn't get in trouble
yeah you could actually get away with it
that always blew my mind about up there
in the Emerald Triangle that anybody
could do that because like you could you
cannot do that here still there's no way
well
it's it's it was always a game of cat
and mouse
huh
like
I was thinking on it was so there was
like a generally like well-known or
maybe it was wrong but we always thought
like as long as you have under a hundred
plants then it becomes the like the feds
aren't going to want to deal with this
and the local cops they're dealing with
much bigger people so
with the greenhouse
they could never actually and actually
you're allowed to medically have 25
plants at this time you know yeah so
with the greenhouse it was like you
can't really see what's in there
mm-hmm you know and so if you can't see
what's in there
then
you know we felt a little safer maybe it
was just you know we were kidding
ourselves even though you could smell it
yeah but you can't smell it from a
helicopter and if you could you wouldn't
know what you're smelling because
everyone was growing up there I mean it
was a remote the whole idea was just
like wait keep it keep it kind of small
and
make it not worth
the trouble of that now the issue that
we never thought of is we had a perfect
landing pad over there they could have
like random 10 helicopters up there
right so it wasn't like the Shady like a
sketchy Mountainside terrain like they
have no place to put it was not like
they had like a flat mode off [ __ ]
landing pad over there
it would have been bad I mean yeah I'll
bring this up just because I I just
thought of it but like when we were
growing the skunk
you know like that spot we were just
talking about was remote enough it
really didn't have neighbors that you
were too worried about but when we were
growing the skunk inside it was kind of
before the carbon filter era it was more
like where you had like uh you know the
uov Nair like the the ozone generators
and stuff and you'd grow that skunk and
like two weeks before it was done you'd
pull up into your driveway with your
windows down and you'd be like oh my God
it smells for 50 yards in every
direction around my house like I'm
slaughtering skunks like I'm gonna get
in trouble
oh my God it reeks and we used to do all
these things like Caulking and like
venting and trying to do all this
different stuff and it just beat every
effort we had to try to contain the
smell it was uncontainable and so in
some people would get rid of it because
it was too fragrant it like caused Panic
you know which one was like
the skunk
ah there you go so it was the skunk
yeah correct princess yeah that's what
you're talking about
anybody else
he knows that he knows it might have
been super skunk or skunk
I mean the thing about it is for me is
that I always thought Gabby that like
you know that you know you get when I
when I when you gave me clones it was
like you gave me the dog and you gave me
and you gave me skunk
and okay just by your stories I've been
thinking about this too
okay and I you know and I know how
important this is to so many people so I
don't want to get it wrong
right yeah but
I explicitly remember getting the skunk
from the dude in Virginia
right
and that that plant isn't the one that
looks just like the uh
the Scentsy Seed Catalog
and we had gotten we had gotten the
seeds from Scentsy and that's how we got
our original crops that we were uh that
you know then we got the males from to
to make everything else
like super dog and that stuff so that so
that so that so that's the way I
remember it but as such an important
part of History you know yeah I'm not
signing in no but that's David's or
anything like that exactly but that's I
mean that's all anyone wants you know
what I mean like if you don't quite have
an answer and it's best guess
that's the best guess that's that that's
just that's more advanced than we were
before
I will repeat the same story the next
time I speak to you like you said that
somebody was telling the story and every
time they told it it was a little bit
different I don't think I'm gonna tell
it differently no no no no this is this
is a lot different yeah I'm also not
swearing to accuracy you know no of
course I smoke a lot I promise it's a
it's a it's a long-ass time
it's literally decades ago yeah
so yeah let me ask yourself the question
Francis didn't we get the seeds in order
to make the first cross
yeah here's the thing is that when we
were talking earlier you were like oh we
just used the males
right but we had that problem from the
Census
but we had that one female
right that you that like that you gave
me so I don't know how that one female
came to be because by the time that I
came into it like you gave me the skunk
you gave me skunk and dog the same day
you don't have it anymore correct
I lost it when I got in trouble and you
know whatever that was anyone give a
[ __ ] it's a gun
because because because one of them one
of them is probably in sour and one of
them is probably in chem dog D and
Diesel and they're very important I
think so I think that's true
but I mean if we don't have it then like
but we have the we have the last two and
we would like to know
kind of which one went where because
people don't believe us on that on that
little part of it like that's what I
believed I don't know I don't so what
part is not believed that uh like the
chem dog D it would would have the same
Super Skunk chem 91 connection
okay they still think it's sisters
they don't believe us
yes we disagree with them
probably neither of us will ever be
proven right or wrong
and we can just enjoy this debate for
the rest of our life
I mean I mean like you don't have ideas
we don't have the source material Beyond
people's words that's true you know to
do it right like we need to have all the
genetics Maybe
right if we had all the genetics and
futuristic technology
right but we we already don't have all
the possible genetics because it's lost
who knows I could I could identify it
from a photo of a bud if somebody was
growing it like the weed is so unique
and it looks just like the [ __ ]
Scentsy Seed Catalog photo
like it's the only weed that I've ever
grown
that you could do that with yeah I'll
send you I there there are people that
think it's I mean this causes all kinds
of debate because what happens now Gabby
is that people people get get excited
about old school famous strains and then
there's opportunists that are like I
found it now I'm going to sell you
clones for high dollar or I'm gonna make
a bunch of hybrids with seed and you'll
be able to get it in seed form and so
there's a bunch of fakes that
proliferate about various stuff there's
all these there's all this Politics the
buyer must be where they must be where
and like and that's and that's why you
buy seeds from a reliable source like
riots you'd go right
um because
if not
it you know like you know the buyer must
be aware and you know if you're only
paying you know even a hundred dollars a
pack 150 a pack you know you can roll
the dice when you got situations like
companies that should be remain unnamed
that are selling packs for a thousand
bucks or something like that then you
really want to know you're getting
something I I think genetics are worth
that much yeah when you're actually
getting
what you're promised if if someone's
saying this is what you're getting this
is what you can expect this is what you
know I think you know genetics can be
worth thousands of dollars
um but
when you're dealing with unreputable
people and the thing about unreputable
people is
they get called out pretty quick
you know like the other person we were
talking about before well
well what happened you know what happens
is Gabby is is that
honestly because we don't have genetic
testing and because we don't have the
guaranteed what we have is we have
stories
right and these stories get you know
like there's people that are like they
buy into the story and then there's
people that are like that guy's a
scumbag I don't buy his story at all
but Francis you know we answer if we
answer these questions life would be
extremely boring and some people would
have no lives I get it dude that's true
you know it's just like like what are
these people gonna do when they stop
arguing dog or or the skunk is right I
mean there's funny things where like
when I would tell when I would tell
those stories on previous podcasts there
would be people that would get all mad
at me and would be like you don't know
the dude that brought him West you were
never really friends with that guy
you're [ __ ] making it up and I'm like
I don't know I mean I don't know what to
tell you dude I don't know so why didn't
you call me dude
yeah it's here now
you know I mean I was honestly like even
with that I could help I would rather
people that are just stepping in
what Francis said was pretty accurate
the anything that was inaccurate or not
completely accurate was maybe some
timelines and Minor Details that really
don't change the story much at all
you know like the the basis of the story
is the same yeah so
I mean honestly I think you did a better
job than I would have been able to just
because
you know you've been thinking about it
for longer and you know you've spelled
it out in your mind and possibly on
paper what you thought about it yeah
obsessive yeah
all those stories just come from like a
million times of like me and Gabby
sitting on a couch somewhere stoned
shooting the [ __ ] about wheat yeah
that's where it all came from like it
just friendships sharing stories about
this or that or whatever and like that's
honestly like why I believed
Gabby so much more than some of the
later stuff that came up was because he
didn't have a reason to lie yeah it was
way before the fame it was years and
years before skunk the a got on the
forums and anybody knew chem dog like
the the public hadn't heard of it it was
just stories amongst friends
and he was able to it was always the
same story no matter how big right you
guys were
yeah it was just us it was just friends
sharing stuff you know and yeah and you
know and Gabby and I had a very similar
view on weed in the sense that like we
both liked really good weed and we both
wanted to make better weed if we could
you know I almost did I almost didn't
say it dude but like way back in the day
I liked sativas and like Gabby hated
them because he was like dude I'm so
high strung I want weed to like calm me
down
he's like maybe you're so calm you can
get like a little anxious or a little
bit higher he's like I don't want to do
that dude I need to mellow out like
you're mellow enough you want to smoke
sativa and get all Zippy fine not me
down you know I need to be brought I
need to be I need to be mellowed out
people were telling me to chill out too
people like Gabby chill the [ __ ] out
well I mean I'm gonna have to I'm gonna
have to stop this in a minute but it's
all right we're gonna continue again
tomorrow yeah is that you know I'll say
this is that California is a bunch of
you know there's it's a lot Chiller you
know Gabby coming from you know being a
New York Jew coming West he was loud he
talked fast people thought it was
aggressive but it was like where he came
from everybody talked like that yeah
that was normal as normal it could be so
it was just like you know it wasn't
anything weird it was just you know
there's cultural differences you move
from the East Coast or New York to
California it's not culturally the same
when I moved from Chicago to you know to
uh to Mendo I was like oh my God
you know I mean I'll end it on this
because Gabby's gotta go but like uh uh
my best friend growing up that became
really good friends with Gabby too he
passed away a long time ago but you know
he used to do this thing where he'd call
it California nice
and he'd be like if you want to tell me
[ __ ] you just tell me [ __ ] you
don't be nice to me about it I'll take
it fine yeah just tell me you know same
way I have no interest you know piss off
let me everyone think to that before you
go before I let you go go ahead I
remember uh when I first got to
California it totally freaked me out
when like a cashier would start making
conversation with the person in line in
front of them like in front of me I'm
next in line I'm next in line and this
lady's like how you doing yeah it's a
beautiful day but you know like hope you
have a great weekend and I'm just like
thinking just [ __ ] ring her up so I
can get my [ __ ] and get the hell out of
here no like exactly like now now I say
hello to everyone at the supermarket and
that now I'm not going yeah you enjoy
the rest of your day buddy love you tons
all right I love you too thank you
tomorrow thank you
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out