welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
before we get started too much I got to
tell you Francis
you tend to either cut off your head or
your chin
it's like very common
you know and you do have a very like
long you know oval shaped head but still
like try to back up off the camera a
little bit so that don't happen
I mean every now and again you'll like
reach in and it'll be like this
awkward moments yeah what really hurts
me is that like if I put on my glasses
it's like a really awkward distance so I
can't see that well without them but
then if I put them on I have to be like
way far back and that's awkward too so
I'm sorry you know I don't I'm like all
sweaty and don't have petrified phones
and stuff like that but you know I'm a
cultivator not like a show personality
like exactly exactly yeah I I just left
the Garden in seconds ago compared to
compared to most shows uh Matt and I are
pretty Bare Bones yeah we try to make
the content speak for itself rather than
like all the fancy accoutrements that
come with it Gabby and I used to go to
so many concerts together and we would
often have like joints of like dog and
super dog and different hybrids with us
and it got to the point where like often
people would like that were standing
next to us it would smell so good they
would want to share it with us yeah and
him and I used to have these like
running debates if we should like share
or not because we had literally been at
events where like we shared a few times
and like people's knees would Buckle
because they got way too high and then
like security would have to come and
like help them you know and so like yeah
we got to the point where because I can
tell some stories like that
um you know like the dog was like I mean
it still is but like it was really a lot
stronger than what most people had
access to
yeah so we smoked it every day so we had
a certain tolerance to it but there was
a lot of people that like two three hits
and like they'd be in a space they were
a bit uncomfortable in oh yeah
okay I'll start by telling a story I'll
start by telling a
story when the chem dog ruins somebody's
day
let's hear it um so I went to a Blues
Traveler concert at the Greek Theater it
was I believe it was 1991.
uh can't be sure but it was in the early
90s and I used to see Blues Traveler
when they were just a bar band in New
York City you know playing like small
clubs of like 50 people
and you know then they got big and they
opened for Jerry and you know we're
playing the Greek Theater and so I went
to the Greek Theater early to wait
online to get in to get a good spot
because you know if you're out from out
here you know the Greek Theater is
generally general admission which is
awesome
and so I'm you know waiting online and
I'm talking to people and I meet
somebody and you know I'm smoking online
which I always do and this guy you know
he has you know man can I try that it's
amazing
so he takes a hit so it takes another
hit
and he went from being this like really
excited like jovial character to like
just completely like
and not saying anything and
like he got so high
that when the show let in
like he sat down before the line went in
and when the show let in he didn't go in
oh no I'm like bro let's go they're
letting us in and he just sat there and
I'm like [ __ ] I'm like well I'm going
he like he waited online for hours to
get a good spot at the show
and then I don't know if he ever made it
in because that's hilarious he got so
high from two hits of the chem Dawn
then I had this other experience this
one was at Phil did a show
at the
not the maritime all yeah maybe it was
called The Maritime Hall it was called
the philharmonia it was a sing-along
and I brought my camera and I was taking
pictures at this show
and of course I'm smoking the dog
and this lady behind me asks if she can
hit my joint so I'm like sure let her
hit the joint I and I wonder at this
point because I had already had this
experience with a few people she's like
oh no I smoke every day you know I'm
good so
she takes a couple of hits off the joint
I'm not paying attention she was behind
me right
and I've been taking pictures and I got
this like film camera around my neck you
know with a strap
next thing I know she collapses and it's
like falling on top of me and I'm like
what's going on so I spin around and
when I sping her and spin around my
camera spins around and clocks are in
the head it was like it was like a
one-two punch
she was going down from the chem dog and
then my camera
and she had to get taken to like rock
Med over there and they're like what is
she on what happened and I was like it's
just weed it's really good weed and like
you know so so yeah I've had a number of
times when I shared the chem dog with
people
and it didn't go good after a while I
started just telling people like Francis
said like you know I'd be like no sorry
you know and
that just makes him want it more like
people people thought people thought we
were being dicks and like Gabby and I
would be having these conversations like
are we gonna ruin this person's
experience by being cool
yeah you know it was like an on it
happened
I've been telling everyone I'm stingy
because like five thousand people
you know on Discord that Gabby is
[ __ ] just stingy holding on to it all
Gabby
right I mean I uh
that's funny
I will say I don't know I don't know if
you heard this part uh Gabby but I I
have mentioned a few times how like when
we were doing all of those when we were
making those like super dog hybrids and
we were playing around and we were doing
all those outcrosses and stuff
Gabby was honestly like one of the
people like earliest people amongst my
entire friend crew that sort of saw like
the future American Seed sales coming
and he used to talk to me and be like
dude we could we could take this eight
lighter you know because we did Big seed
runs you know we take this eight lighter
and he's like we could make so many
seeds with this eight lighter it would
just blow anything you could do with
flour out of the window yeah like we
could sell so many seeds and it was like
so early it was this was I don't know
when it was probably early 2000s or
something it was so early it was long
before you know seed companies in
America and IG made it like feasible I
honestly like we'd get into arguments
and I was like I don't see it dude I
don't see how to be able to do it I
don't see how we'd be able to have
customers all these take money and all
these people
no we couldn't at the time
but you were right you saw what was
coming and I was like you know later
it's not it's not gonna work and then
like 10 years later I was like man we
were just like too early business models
that are built on volume
and there's business models that are
built on scarcity you know and the
margins are very different you know if
you have huge volume you can have
smaller margins
you know if you've got big volume if
you've got big margins you don't need
huge
yeah I mean it's crazy because it's kind
of the same thing with clones right now
except it's more like people taking
advantage like selling [ __ ] for like
fifteen hundred dollars a piece that's
just like a garbage cross you know just
because they made a good name for
themselves and like at the emerald cup
people will be waiting online for like
the entire Emerald cup to pay fifteen
hundred dollars for for clones that
ended up having virus yep you know like
yep it was just you know I mean it's
part of it is successful branding and
then not being honorable about it yes
very much though I mean they it sucks
because I think it's a flawed business
plan because as soon as you build up
your business to the point where like
you have all these people that respect
you and think that you're awesome
and then all of a sudden you [ __ ]
everybody and the word gets out and like
it's so much worse now
I heard a lot of stories about deals
that went bad with them I I mean I don't
know if you want to cut this out because
I ain't trying to think about [ __ ] about
people but um
you know he had contracts with people
that he had to give them like they had
to give a certain dollar amount for
their crop and their crop got completely
ruined because it was all virus yeah and
he still wanted his money
yeah like he destroyed these people's
livelihood by giving them like
infected and I'm not saying he did it on
purpose but like you give people
infected genetics and then you sue them
for not giving you the 200 bucks that
like you know they you know and
meanwhile these people couldn't get 300
bucks or 400 bucks for like quality herb
that was you know yeah it was just like
I mean the thing is is like Francis and
I said the seeds are so cheap
right that if you have a problem
like this is an opportunity to show
people that you're solid or that you're
a scammer exactly that could have
happened to anyone that you know the
seeds were no good whatever
they just need to be like look we stand
behind you know our name and our product
and anyone that bought that is going to
get you know not just their seeds
replaced they're gonna get extra stuff
and yeah you know wasting their time
make the customer feel good because in
the end the seeds don't cost you [ __ ]
yep you know and like you took so much
into making your reputation
how do you just screw so many people
over let the whole world know that that
you're terrible and [ __ ] over your
entire business I don't understand how
people do that I run into this all the
time Gabby when we chat where it's like
a lot of times I will talk in
generalities about like certain things
that go on in the community because even
just telling stories that are true
people get mad but if you mention like
when we if I mention somebody's name
specifically as an example their friends
will like cut out that 15 second clip
and send it to them and then I'll have
like furious people in my DMs all mad
that I'm like trying to like [ __ ] with
their wallet or destroy their way of
life or like disparage them in some
fashion you know okay so one thing that
I want to say that's not really a story
I don't know if it was
so dog or someone else in the Discord
that said that what people appreciate me
is that I didn't Flex
yeah and
you know I thought about it and I said
to myself
I'm not opposed to flexing yeah for [ __ ]
that actually I can Flex about I don't
feel I don't feel like I'm that response
for it and there's other things that I'm
so much more proud of like yeah my hydro
store the garden spell you know I I had
the first real Grow shops in Mendocino
County there was Spare Time Supply but
they sold lights in the back of an ocean
container to people that knew about them
yeah you know I opened up
I opened up a grow store in Willits at
the time Highway 101
stopped being a highway and just was
like a one lane in each Direction Road
through the town of Willards so anyone
traveling north would drive straight
through town
yeah and I got this little store on Main
Street what I was saying was that when I
put my store up it was right on Highway
and I literally lit up the highway with
the orange glow of high pressure
frames and it was the Talk of the Town
like nobody could believe that I was
being so ballsy
to like put these lights up in the
street
yeah you know and
um
you know one by one you know the locals
from the hills came down and they heard
that they could trust me and that I
would deliver soil to them holy [ __ ] I
delivered soil in the most dangerous and
not like dangerous like gun dangerous
like the roads were just psychotic but
if I would have known I never would have
done it you know you get like committed
to this drive and now you can't turn
around yeah driving this like U-Haul
style box truck it's overloaded me with
soil through like 10 creeks and [ __ ]
you're like oh my God
but um I taught a lot of people how to
grow weed and I taught a lot of people
how to grow better weed than they were
already growing
and
brought new products to our Market
and that's the stuff that I'm really
proud of
and
it's not that I um
didn't always love cannabis and always
grow cannabis but for a long part of my
life
okay so let me take a step back here's
how the story went
when I was growing before working and
and owning hydro stores
I was paranoid
and I wasn't making friends
and I wasn't talking to people about
growing weed which is what I realized I
really like to do is talk to people
about growing weed which is one of the
reasons why me and not so dog got along
so good like because that's what what he
wanted to do too
and um
what happened was one day the hydro
store that I was shopping at it's called
Hydro Depot
the guy asked me if I wanted a job
and at first I was like no I don't want
a job you know I'm doing pretty good
doing what I'm doing
and then I realized
that if I got this job
and I worked it for a few months I could
make a legitimate income and then like
maybe work towards buying a house
instead of like you know renting my
entire life
so I started working at the Hydro Depot
and that's when I realized that as much
as I have a passion for growing
have a passion for talking to people
about weed and teaching people what I
know about weed and
I really felt like my calling
was to do that
because not only was I making a good
living
I was loving every minute of it you know
when when clients would come in
I would love talking to them you know
like
you know I let other people handle the
inventory and the you know
all the you know boring stuff of running
a business and I would just talk to
people about growing weed
and I was always really honest with them
and that's why people came back
you know because they knew I wasn't just
trying to sell them some [ __ ] because
oftentimes people would come in and be
like should I buy this and I'd be like
absolutely not don't do it you know
perfect example was LED lights before
they were ready
you know when I opened up my store it
was a 2002 there was already people
trying to sell LED lights
you remember the UFOs Francis oh yeah
you know I mean they were garbage they
you couldn't successfully grow basil
with those plants let alone a fruiting
crop
and um and they sold for a lot of money
and I used to tell people if this
technology worked
I would make so much money because
everybody would want to change everybody
with high pressure sodium would
immediately want to buy these these LEDs
I would kill it yeah but I couldn't with
good conscious so even though people
coming in like wanting the lights and
I'd have to be like no it's a bad idea
you know and so I'm proud
and this is a very minor Flex that I
feel throughout the years I made a good
reputation for myself
um with Growers
because I was honest and I was a place
where they could come for information
and
they felt safe yeah you know people felt
safe at my store
and
you know so when we're talking about
flexing it's like
I think I can Flex about that a little
bit I'm proud of proud of that I hope
that that's you know
it's gonna be a part of my legacy you
know when I'm gone for sure
the chem dog thing is just like
you know well I don't think I mean I'm
blushing and you know like kind of like
it it makes me smile that I'm getting
this attention about it but like
Greg he's the one that popped the seeds
people that he distributed to like what
do they get the credit for like where do
you draw the line of giving people props
for me is it you Francis is it Jason and
Ben or like people 10 10 rows past them
that got it that
maybe did better [ __ ] with it than all
of us
well you know I mean
I look at it a little different you know
um I'll I'll talk about the chem dog for
a second and then I'll move on to the
store because I actually think there's
some parts about the store that people
would not really realize today but I'll
start with the chem dog obviously I
think that
you know for whatever reason even though
it might be like even though people
might play a small role in something
that role could be super important like
it turns out somehow that the cutting
that you brought West seems to be the
one that survived
and it got and I'm not sure if it would
be around if you hadn't come out to
California with it and then eventually
shared it with a few close friends uh
like skunk VA or IC Collective or myself
or whoever and so you know like that
might be small but it's also important
because it was a critical step like when
they wanted it back on the East Coast
they had to get it from the West Coast
because that's where and in prohibition
right where people get busted and people
move on and things change a lot of cool
things got lost
right and so I kind of feel like my only
part of the chemdog story is really like
hearing the stories early
right and maybe helping to preserve it
at a time before it was famous
and then
like and so perhaps like on the on the
the store thing people might not realize
this but one of the things that Gabby
was talking about which was critical
back then was that information on how to
grow good weed was really hard to come
by
and most people that knew how to do it
wouldn't talk to you so in stores were
also super rare like Gabby is right when
he opened up his store he was the first
go ahead if you want to make me blush
Francis you can repeat yourself all
right so so I do feel like things about
me as as Gabby mentioned when he opened
up the store in in Mendocino County
there was like Spare Time Supply which
was a big player but they were
predominantly a garden store at an
outdoor store and an amendment store
there was no indoor or Greenhouse
focused store going on at all and stores
back then were actually rare
right
um and and there wasn't very many of
them and having someone in a store that
was knowledgeable and willing to talk
right was huge and it was kind of a
risque thing and even though proposition
215 had happened it was still very much
in the shadows and so he's he I think he
sort of opened up your shop at the very
beginning of like the 215 medical green
Rush era where there was all these
people coming to our County and coming
to Humboldt in these different areas
that were new they had no idea what they
were doing and they were like I want to
set up a garage in a greenhouse and I
don't even know what to get
and so for a long time it was like
eventually stores became like who had
the best price and people were more
knowledgeable but probably for the first
five or six years that Gabby had a store
it was I mean he sold stuff but it was
also like it was tons of education on
what stuff those people needed so you
know the store in the early years was
basically like a massive educational
model and then as Gabby and then you
know educated people they bought things
from him
yeah because they literally hadn't they
didn't know how to wire stuff they
didn't know about like you know lighting
boxes they didn't know about fan
movement they didn't know about any of
that and so it's like they'd have money
and they're like What's the best set of
equipment for my set of circumstances
and so you have this whole County that
was starting to really blow up and grow
but the funny thing about it is all the
stores that opened up they were all my
customers first yeah like I literally I
literally taught him everything that
they knew about the business people
don't realize it today but
like information
was the thing that was super important
people literally they had money but they
had no idea what they were doing and
like what's weird about it too is that
you start like if you spent time there
you learned a bunch because people would
come to you not only to get set up but
they would come to you with like every
problem imaginable
yeah and you would have to and Gabby
would have to sit down with them and
figure out how to solve it
and then the more you help people solve
it the bigger your like information or
expertise or knowledge base grows so
when someone else brings up that same
problem like you have right and so I
don't think people today with all the
all the forums and all the information
and all the internet and everything
really understand how hard it was
to talk to people that knew how to grow
weed even on the basic level
like and so probably the first five or
six years his store was open it was a
boom time where everyone in Mendo and
Humboldt and all these places were just
constantly setting up new stuff whether
they were indoor whether they were
greenhouses whether they were light
deprivation it was just an enormous boom
of economy and no and ver and maybe 10
of the people knew what they were doing
and would come in and like would have a
good idea of what they wanted and battle
on price and stuff but often they would
come in completely oblivious
you know and so and so I I just wanted
to mention that I don't think into in
2023 people understand like Dragon Ball
Z having a hydrostore was and being
willing to openly talk about
you know about growing with people
you know I mean that was the era where
like you walk into a head shop and you
say the word bong and they toss you out
in case you were undercover and they
were going to shut down the real shop
for real right yeah um you know there
was you know there was a so it was
pretty risque it was like pretty out on
the on the on the Cutting Edge of things
if you will uh to do that type of stuff
and so there's an enormous amount of
people that got their start buying
equipment and buying soil and buying all
kinds of stuff I mean one thing I could
mention is like when you opened your
shop dude uh we were still all growing
in like in um you know in like a light
Warrior or you know or perlite peat moss
mixes and stuff like that Gabby was one
of the first people to really like
preach about cocoa fiber
and how it was going to revolutionize
like growing
and you know people had no idea what it
was that's wow like at all you know and
it was brand new okay go ahead so what I
remember is that you know cocoa fiber if
I if I remember correctly the reason why
it became popular was in Europe they
decided that they wanted more
environmentally friendly medium to grow
in right and Rockwell wasn't it and so
they were looking around for something
that was biodegradable and a renewable
resource and they realized that there
was these giant piles of cocoa fiber and
Sri Lanka and India and other places
that were just waste products that they
shredded off the cocoa to get to the
coconut yeah right
and so they realized that if they
started buffering it and treating it the
right way
that you know
um it could be an excellent grow media
yeah and then Gabby got some
and there was stuff that was from like
because in Canada that was RHP certified
which basically meant it was regulated
and it was guaranteed to be a certain
level of quality and we started growing
in it and I remember Gabby being like Oh
my god dude like we'd pull pot he'd pull
plants out of pots and be like look at
these roots I bet like literally like
look at how white and happy look at look
at and from that point on he was kind of
like a little bit of a prophet about it
and no one had ever really heard about
it and his store had it
um and I think we he got lucky and that
he was getting it from reputable sources
yeah and there there was other people
that were getting it cheaper but they
were getting it full of like sea salt
and it was unbuffered and people were
having nightmares in the beginning oh
sure right
um but I mean his store was open right
at the time that like cocoa fiber first
started percolating around and no one
had even heard of it
you know
um and you know people back then they
didn't even know you know it was even
simple stuff like why 600s were better
than thousands because they were cooler
and they gave you more points of light
yeah you know
um there was a lot of stuff that people
consider basic now which was like
essentially in my opinion like hidden
knowledge
and so he's right he would just talk all
day long
to people
and they would write out all kinds of
lists of stuff they needed and then he
would hand the list to like an employee
and they would start filling it and he
would turn around and he would talk to
the next person
and so he just talked about growing weed
like here's the reality
Francis was way better than I was really
yeah well you know he was like yeah I
mean
he had patience
and I'm just like always like I'm trying
to help people as quick
as quick I mean I wanted it wasn't like
I was rushing him out the door I wanted
to make a comfortable environment but I
was just always busy too one thing like
I tried myself in so my hydro store was
based on largely
a Dutch model
and the Dutch model was I went to
Holland
and I went to the growth stores
and they all had espresso makers there
and
I had this idea
okay because when I was working for
Slavic
she would always say to me gabby I want
them to buy and get out
and what I try to tell him is that the
longer they stayed
I got opportunities to sell them more
stuff yeah you know he would see he
would see it as I'm just talking to
these guys you know for 45 minutes about
growing you know and that you know he'd
rather maybe sweeping the floor or
something else yeah but in the end what
I was doing was building a repertoire
with the customers
you know that they would trust me and
they would shop exclusively at our store
you know
it would trust me so when I opened up my
own stores the garden spout
you know I put a coffee bar in
yeah and I had chairs there for the
customers to hang out
and that was pretty unheard of for a
growth store was to make a place like I
wanted it to be a cool place
where people want to hang out yeah you
know and of course some people abuse the
privilege and got annoying and we'd have
to ask him to leave of course but for
the most part like
it wasn't only me talking to people
other people would like hear what people
were saying and then they would like
interject and it became like almost a
gathering point
you know so as far as how I got involved
with the Coco
it's because that's what the Dutch were
doing okay and I met people while I was
in Holland
um at the Hawaii Fair which is like a
traditional AG show yeah and um
and then when I opened up my store they
had heard about it they came and visited
me
and you know so the first one we would
buy because Coco
and then Tana Coco and then you know I
started trying to Source some myself
from some of these reputable companies
but
like I said like those are the things
that I want to be proud of
you know to me that that's like
a much bigger
you know I think that's my minor Flex
you know I think it's a one thing I want
to say about the chem dog Flex go ahead
how much of an [ __ ] would I look like
if I did Flex about my part with the
chem dub
I mean I think I'd be in like I'd be
looked at like an [ __ ] like like
you're saying other people think others
are [ __ ] who are doing that Flex
yeah you know the only one who's got the
real Flex is Greg yeah you know and like
anyone else past that it's just kind of
like all right you have it what did you
do with it yeah and you know like
Francis said people did good [ __ ] I
think Jason made beautiful crosses with
the Kendall
you know and um who else did you oh yeah
I see yeah them too so I mean people did
great stuff with it and and that's their
Flex what they did with the chem dog not
their like part of the chem dog story
like they acquired it okay
you know and having said that like
I don't really care like I don't look
I'm happy for Jason
and Ben
that like
this could help them in any way
you know like
it's just like
yeah
yeah I mean
I love this yeah I think it goes back to
a different era
where the way you got Cuts generally
speaking back then was like you honestly
became good friends with someone and
then what was that like and then you
shared things and then you did things
together and you now people would call
it a collaboration but back in the day
it was more just like you know friends
doing cool little side projects together
you know like friends sharing Cuts so we
could help keep them alive because there
was fires and accidents and busts and
different things that could happen where
you could lose something and it was much
more informal so it was like you know
um you know sometimes people would be
like well how do you get cuts and it's
like I don't know you like become
friends with someone that has Cuts but
that's not the reason why you became
friends it's like you have an honest
relationship with someone and then that
leads to other things yeah
you know so it's almost like organic in
the way that it like it developed
you know uh and um
I don't know that's just kind of how I
see it but I think I think it's very one
thing that
it's not necessarily a flex but I think
it's very very uh special to be someone
who inspires someone else who does
something quite remarkable it changes a
culture whether it's sour whether it's
cam whether it's getting to the West
Coast but helping inspiring other
whether you're teaching growing any of
that to be able to to like know on your
deathbed that you've left something
behind that has inspired someone else
and made their life better then that's
that you know I mean like that should be
good enough right that's ultimate I
think so that's why I said like if you
called up and said hey Gabby
I was talking with not so dog and we
want to talk to you about the garden
spout and how you you know accomplish so
much and then it'd be like all right
yeah I mean like I'm proud of that and I
can actually like you know
you know but like this idea that I had
such an integral
part of it I mean I had a little part of
it I brought it out to the West Coast I
don't want to minimize it either like
because I know if I didn't bring it out
then it's not out here and maybe it's
lost but um products that we did I wish
the breeding projects that we did
produced more of like what I actually
wanted yeah you know like more of a chem
dog you know tramping profile because we
we did some great [ __ ] but it just
didn't turn out that dog-like and so if
I would have done that
then I could have been proud of that and
then I could have felt like I had more
of a part of the chem dog history
because I took it to the next step and
maybe that is a reason for Jason and Ben
to flex because that is what they're
doing right sure they're taking plants
that
pretty much it would be a mistake for
most people to grow it period
you know like unless you're looking to
use it for breeding
you know like growing this for the
flower
you know and having said that I want to
grow it for flower again because
I feel like I have knowledge and tools
available to me now that I didn't have
then
and maybe I could get it to show me
something
you know better than back in the day
absolutely you know
um the one thing I was mentioning in the
Discord is leaf tissue sampling yeah
yeah that blew my mind I hadn't even
thought of doing that with it
yeah so I've already done this at
facilities that I worked with worked at
and
so
I'm I don't know who to give credit to
but somebody mentioned to me that you
know we've been looking in books at this
is what this deficiency looks like this
one this efficiency looks like
but generally what that means is this is
what a plant looks like when it has zero
nitrogen or like it's not deficient it's
just absent yeah and all and also
or extreme deficiency right yeah and
then also those photos never show you
what does deficiency look like when it's
a number of elements yeah that's true
you know like because what it's going to
look like is going to look different
and you know for years
the standard thing was oh I had more
calmag yeah yeah well what kind of
whatever it was just add more calmag it
always makes everything better yeah it
always makes it green
plants like calcium and when I did my
testing
the testing showed that I needed more
calcium okay but at least we're not just
guessing yeah you know the testing is
really inexpensive it's like 75 to 100
per sample okay okay and so it's very
inexpensive and it gives you a lot of
information and with the chem dog being
a plant that wants to consume itself
prior to harvest like you know two weeks
before you're supposed to cut it you'd
have not a single Green Leaf left on it
yeah no no it was so hard to keep this
plant yeah
um with a with the leaf analysis we can
learn how to feed it a little bit better
and maybe keep it Greener a little bit
longer and action you know actually get
a product that
is more like what we've been looking for
all this time
sure one of the one other thing I I
might mention if we're gonna like uh
Flex for Gabby here or whatever is
that's not what time this is is it I
know but but I know we did enough of
that you know I used to go I used to go
and do a bunch of different hydro stores
um for various reasons and I think Gabby
was the first person that I knew that
was really pumping
tissue culture
not like the meristem stuff but like the
prop like the cleanliness and the
propagation and all that and there was
this guy
um Bill Graham bill yeah still around
and she had these and he had these kits
uh and he Gabby used to have bill.com
for people didn't want to look for it he
used to come into the store and Gabby
would have him do demos
of how to sterilize like a tub how to
get clean how to like take clean cuts
and like bleach and sterilize the cuts
and then get them into solution and I
can tell you like as a as a grower it
looked like some Voodoo in the beginning
I bet you know like at the time nobody
was doing that nobody was even thinking
about it like nobody was nobody was
applying that to cannabis by by any
means yeah
um and you know he had a whole shelf on
his store and he would invite bill in
and he would and they would do Demos in
the shop and he would get people to try
it wow and all that type of stuff and I
mean that was literally in the early
2000s
uh long now it's become like a big the
only reason that made me think of it is
as you were talking Gabby about Leaf
tissue like I kind of feel like because
weed was so illegal for a while we were
reduced to observational stuff and we
didn't really have access to labs and we
didn't really have access to some of the
scientific stuff that regular AG did
because we were too scared and the labs
didn't want to deal with us so we had to
like work off what we saw
and talking amongst ourselves and now
he's right in the sense that you can go
get tissue analysis and you can get hard
data that backs up your thoughts
right yeah
um but you know tissue culture was like
some voodoo
you know taking these tiny little
plantlets it seemed very extreme at the
time like why would you go through all
that trouble when you just clogged it
seemed extreme but now knowing more
about diseases you know hopsilating
viroid and stuff it's I wish everyone
would have been using that method and
you know Bill Bill would come in and and
you know Gabby would tell a bunch of
good customers and friends and stuff the
dude's gonna come in and he's going to
give a demo and he's going to teach you
how to use this stuff because it was
like especially to a bunch of Growers it
was like some straight Voodoo it was
Advanced so let me say something let me
let me say something real fast
so I sold a bunch of those kits
yeah and I honestly believe almost no
one took it out of the box I believe it
because it was still it was still too
like intimidating like the kid didn't
cost [ __ ] I think it was like 135 bucks
yeah yeah something like that you know
it was really inexpensive but they had
to go buy a pressure cooker and make the
gel and like you know I was able to sell
it
but like most people were still a little
bit intimidated to do it and I remember
I was
store and we do it
and then every single day
I was doing tissue culture in my store
in front of people that were just
walking in and
you know
even though they didn't do it
they were still like inspired and it
made them excited about something you
know exactly so
um
but yeah a few people actually did it
I really thought I was gonna
revolutionize things I like people
adopting this and doing this
and it was kind of like the seed thing
they just weren't ready yet yeah I mean
the same thing is interesting in that
you know I I talk about this on the show
quite often where it was like
you know Gabby and I and some other
close like we honestly were just trying
to make better wheat and all the seeds
we made all the projects that we did
everything like that especially because
of what like flower prices were back
then it was a terrible financial
decision because we could have just been
blowing up rooms of flour and getting
top dollar for it way back then you know
so it was literally like a labor of love
you know and it was it wasn't
necessarily about like oh what do we
think people will like it was like what
do we like personally and can we make
stuff that we like
and you know Gabby I I was thinking
about it because
uh Matt and I have been blessed in a way
to talk to some of like Neville's good
friends that were close to him in the
last years of his life
and it's funny because one of the things
Neville said is like I wish I didn't
fail so much
right I don't know if I did if I don't
know if the best stuff that I got I
improved on it at all
I wish I knew now I wish I would have
known then what I know now and I had a
different shot at it
and so I think that thing that you
expressed is very common in breeding
where people that breed are very
self-critical
and they tend to Discount what they did
when they did it
because they wanted it to be better
and they had their own goals in it and
then a lot of failure I mean there's a
lot of things if you take it serious it
has to be a lot of failure because you
you'd just be hitting you know numbers
all day and that's that's just not how
it works that's not how I mean I I don't
think it I don't think it's failure in
the sense of
do something beautiful
it's a failure in the sense of you have
an expectation of what you can produce
and you have a lot less control of it
than you know because that's just ego
you know either that or it's really
expert breeding
all right really anal retentive people
like I just
I mean
you would think like so when we did the
F1 cross
you know with Matt to the chem dog right
and then we grew out so many thousands
of these seeds
you would have thought that some would
have like really been dog-like yeah they
just weren't
you know so you would think like you
know when you when you do that first
cross you get the most diversity and now
you just gotta do the hunt
but the the skunk was so dominant
that
you know
there was traces of it you know like
yeah it felt like it doesn't
yeah yeah of course
[Music]
dogweed
you know the other thing the other thing
I think we should mention because like
the game is flipped now go ahead no go
ahead uh is that when Gabby and I were
doing all this all the feminized
reversals and stuff like that were still
years away we kind of thought that like
at times that like hermaphrodism and
like accidental pollinations we're gonna
lead you down the wrong path all the
stuff that we did was with regular males
and so you had to create hybrids and
then and back cross and all that and you
know we had to grow out the seeds to see
if what we did did what we wanted
there was no idea that we could take two
females and reverse one of them and add
this it was all regular well we knew we
could do it but it would never consider
it exactly already selling seeds by that
time feminized it's just we are
delighted we thought that hermaphrodism
and seeds from hermaphrodism were
hermaphroditism
because you were going to infect your
line with more traits that were bad
and you know and and that was just kind
of like I don't know in the not late
that in the early two thought like that
was just the the Common Thread then
um
I was talking to Matthew about this the
other day like to me like
it's
you know it's weird it does it seems
like it's very common
I know it's common I know it's oh and I
know it's commonly done but I still feel
like
doing this has to pose some type of risk
no I mean it's common for people to feel
like you do
what do you think we're wrong
yes I think I think you're totally wrong
but but
to an extent this is proven by genetics
like by genetic mapping yeah yeah yeah I
mean maybe it's just hard for males to
accept it like we might become
irrelevant
I mean it's it's actually normal except
that I would accept that more than the
cannabis plant now it's it's like it's
normal cannabis plant male is the most
unappreciated plant on the planet I
agree now we've gone now we've gone to a
point where regular seeds are you know
unicorns almost in the Cannabis world
and almost everything is feminized
reversals of some fashion yeah you know
uh when Gabby and I were doing it like
you know the only feminized seeds we
knew of were
um uh you know accidents
essentially
yeah I mean yes 100 I'd never heard of
reversals I'd never heard the only
reversals we had ever heard of then was
like you stressed the hell out of the
plant too
hermaphrodite itself you put it in a
small container you gave it drought you
messed with the light sky cycle until it
freaked out and did some weird stuff
there was nothing there was no sprays we
ever thought about trying to like induce
anything it was like you basically like
tortured the plant until it did what you
wanted yeah that was the tech that we
knew of back then I think
and it just seemed like the wrong path
yeah like I said it's very common for
people from your era to still have that
that mindset everybody we've talked to
on here from your exact era all have
that same opinion still to this day and
it's like you know and I mean like
say that you're old when you think you
know everything
and so I'm glad that like I'm not
confident about this and that every day
my opinion might be going more towards
towards yours Matt
um like in a conversation we had
um
I feel like selfing could be more
problematic or it seems like it you know
could have more potential for problems
but um so one thing like we're talking
about Colin from ethos
like he said something and it seems so
obvious it's like how can I go my whole
life and not think of this
but when you cross two females
you have a so much better idea of what
you're gonna get oh for sure and like
trying to judge trying to judge what
male was the right one to use
it's like
I don't you know you have to
be very very Adept or very very
repetitive yeah
you have to do things over and over
again you know and then do a lot of
testing which is almost impossible to do
yeah like how does one grow out
thousands of seeds and preserve every
single clone of every one trying smoking
every female yeah yeah I mean we would
do
Gabby and I would do this thing where we
settled kind of like when we were doing
the super dog stuff is like I think we
picked out like our seven or eight
favorite males based on like looks and
certain traits and then we put them all
in the room not so usually like the ones
with the cute butt cheeks yeah we put
them all in the room and then you know
they get to a certain point like you
beat them with a with a you know a
bamboo steak or something like that and
all the fans are on and you just like
the pollen would just spread everywhere
and we were like well it's gonna make
the hunt harder
but since we don't know which male is
doing the right I wanted to find was the
one we wanted to just find the one and
we wanted maximum diversity
and that's how that's how you're going
to get it trying to be so arrogant that
like you can pick it
that wasn't us you know so like having
having three or four males in there
it was a big yeah of yeah finding that
needle needle in the haystack
but the way we possessed it when we gave
them to see they're all going to be good
you know they're two phenomenal plants
crossed together it's just like they're
all gonna be good but you know
you've got to grow a bunch of them and
you're going to find
you know a few that are super amazing
yeah
do you remember Gabby the one of the
final one of the final breedings we did
like I was trying to I was racking my
brain for their names and their names
really aren't important I guess but you
had these buddies of yours and they gave
us a version of the black domino and
they gave us that Warlock
um and that those two things because we
did this we when we did the like the one
of the final super dog greetings we
basically put these like I don't know
seven or eight different males that we
had picked in there with all of the
super dog females that we liked and then
literally like every good cut that we
could get access to so we had the dog
and we had the super skunk and we had
the and we had the you know the Mendo p
and we had the Warlock and we had the
black domino and we had I'm got I mean
like literally every good female cut
that him or I had we kind of gathered
them all up and we put them in there
so if you found the one you didn't care
what made the one you just needed to
find the one
yeah knowing what it was knowing what it
was would have been helpful to to try to
do more things like that but like for
instance I don't remember who gave me
the black domino
but I remember the reason why we bought
it
was and I think that was like from
Scentsy seed or yeah we purchased seed
from from some Seed Company the
description said extremely spider mite
resistant ah yeah you know so the weed
is garbage it really wasn't that good
but if we could make our weed more like
you know we could cross it with a you
know not so dog and get a plant that was
good quality and Spiderman resistant
yeah that was a good thing yeah you know
so that's why that that's why that one
was in there what was the other one that
you mentioned the remember the Warlock
they both came from the same people
I can't remember who gave me that yeah
but I remember the weave yeah they were
they were your buddies neither no yeah
neither was that good
yeah if you're comparing to chem dog I'd
imagine not I mean the funny thing is
like there's things where I felt exactly
how Gabby felt and then years later I
was like man I was just like discounting
too many things because they weren't
like my favorite doesn't mean they
weren't valuable it just means that like
they weren't my top couple you know and
as I got older I appreciated different
qualities of weed you know where in the
beginning it was kind of like
I don't know you know you wanted that
weed that tasted amazing and like hit
you across the head with a two by four
yeah in a way
you know
I wanted to cover sour a little bit more
uh we talked a little bit about how you
met klopp well what were some of your
impressions of sour
actually I didn't have
many till much later on
when was your first experience I mean
and we used to grow a lot of it
you know
um I don't remember exactly what it was
it was one of the deal with it was
it was a highly productive strain of
beautiful weed
that we could sell easily yeah and
you know
I was I was on the Discord
and somebody had to remind me or tell me
that most of the people in the Discord
are really small Growers like yeah they
grow in a tent and it's for personal use
and you know
there's a big difference between that
and even somebody that grows in his
garage
you know has a 10 lighter in his garage
okay now you do need to make some money
to pay for your expenses and the whole
reason why you put up 10 lights in your
garage was to make a little money in the
first place exactly so
you have to you have to do what's
marketable
and that's part of the reason why we
gave up on the chem dog in the first
place
yeah well you know when you're getting
such a terrible yield
you know off of this plant like we
couldn't justify like we'd have to sell
it for 50 to 100 more than we would this
hour
you know we weren't getting that much
more for it
you know so like we would keep it and
we'd grow a little bit for our head
stash and like Francis said you know
somebody was growing it and we would all
you know share a little bit of it the
[ __ ] would never get sold because we're
growing such a small amount of it that
you know it didn't make it to the to the
marketplace
so and
you know
I wanna I wanna publicly say this
sure I love cannabis
should I say that louder I love cannabis
I want to make a living working in
cannabis
and to do that it's like a total
different thing
than when you're just trying to grow for
yourself whether it's in your backyard
or in your tents
you know it is if if I was growing just
for myself
I would just grow oh Jeeves
that's really what I like to smoke yeah
you know whether it's the chem dog or
you know other really nice ogs that's
really the palette that I like
yeah you know and actually I should say
this
police want to have a diversity
but then there's that always the staple
that I go to every morning but then I'll
mix in some other stuff like I love
sativa Terps I love Citrus turps you
know you know I love to have a variety
you know so I as I was telling you guys
I smoke these um soft spots yeah and I
have like 30 different types of terpenes
some of them are so aggressive that it's
shocking like you smoke them it's almost
offensive like it's too much I bet but
it's still awesome you know and um so
but still I I still always lean towards
the oh geez is what I like now right now
in California in the commercial
Marketplace
um
it's hard to sell a lot of OG
wow you know and
it's a first in the
um
that's been going on for a minute you
know and I think you know you know like
so in the Discord people are hating on
gelato
right oh yeah yeah but [ __ ] that's what
that's what that's what big farms on a
buy right now
you know like they're missing the market
lots of gelato
yeah
yeah but so let me tell you a mistake
that I made
okay
having a new Nursery right and I have
all these genetics that are super
awesome but nobody knows anything about
yeah and so you try to sell people on
this stuff
but with today's market they need to
know that they're getting a home run
yeah and so it's so hard to get them to
try something new
you know when right now they can sell
all the Lemon Cherry gelato they can
Grill exactly yeah so after so like when
when I started this I didn't have the
Lemon Cherry gelato I was like by the
time I get this thing in mass production
it's gonna be like the um
ice cream cake or yeah yeah or you know
like nobody's gonna want this weed
anymore
yeah you know and so but like it's
managed to have lasting power as far as
the demand for the flower and the Clones
so if you're growing a pen lighter
in your garage
you're really better off you know
growing something that people want
you know and then maybe a small section
of it for your own personal
which is what Francis and I did yeah you
know we we always do a little bit of a
chem dog but like we had to go to a
strain that was more productive
and that people wanted to buy it
you know the funny thing about the term
the super skunk is the most beautiful
weed
like the chem dog was the best the super
skunk
like I think that weed is the most
beautiful weed
I love the way it looks too yeah
yeah it was green and Frosty and it
smelled like crazy and it was super
pungent and it's a kind of Aroma that
like is very universally recognized by
Americans as like crazy smelling
um you know and I also think too that
like to the point that Gabby was making
it's weird in that
if certain strains don't leak and they
don't get out to a certain amount of
people then the demand for them can't
grow which then makes selling it much
harder because we would try to sell the
chem dog and they would be like ah this
is kind of like some like backseat OG or
something like if how good could it be
if I don't have access to it yeah and
since there was only like a few garages
or something like that in our Greenhouse
or two that was trying to grow some it
was like Brokers want to buy a home run
and to them that wasn't a home run and
it was before the Forum Fame and it was
before it got like a really big name for
itself in public and so people just
wanted things that was going to be
something easy for them to flip
there's always a device
I mean the I was just gonna say that a
lot of especially in Mendo you know in
Humboldt and stuff like that a lot of
times what broker what Growers grew what
was what they heard the Brokers wanted
and was easy
so there was a few years there like for
instance if we wanted to go back and
talk about
um like uh you know Gabby's store like
every Big indoor grower in Mendocino
County was growing some kind of purple
Urkel or granddaddy purps or something
like that right you remember how many
Laytonville indoor gardeners Gabby were
growing miracle and Urkel
because it was easy and the BR and
Urkel yeah granddaddy perks you know all
those type of things and and then the
market shifted and it went to sour and
Kush
and all those Growers dropped the
purples and went right into what the
Brokers wanted
and so there's a you know there's a lot
there where it's like you might end up
liking a strain but you end up growing a
small amount of it for you and your
friends and a lot of times you end up
growing what
the you know the majority of what you
grow is what you think the Brokers or
the market wants to absorb relatively
easily
so here's my new strategy
I want to have
30 percent of exclusive stuff
that you know I'm bringing to the market
you know one way or another I want to
have 30 percent
of you know
up and coming from known people
and then 30 percent well that only ends
up to 90 so 33 of each 33 of stuff that
people want right now
you know that way I can
I can sell people what they want now
while creating a demand for products
under my brand as well as Partnerships
with existing brands
you know but thinking I could do it all
with like exclusive stuff that nobody
knows anything about even though like
it's Fireweed that won the emerald cup
and it's like
that that takes a little bit more today
than it uses it takes a lot it takes a
lot yeah and a lot of legal a lot of
legal Farms they're sort of drowning
under upfront fees and costs and taxes
and operating expenses so they real
their margins are a lot of times quite
tight
um so they really want home runs because
they're worried about survival
you know um it's not for at least
especially for you know for most people
it's not a particularly lucrative time
in cannabis
it's kind of more of like a stay afloat
time
and the the more it's like that the more
people want certainty
and so that leads to sameness because
people want it hurts the quality it
hurts quality and it hurts diversity
because people are just trying to
produce an already popular thing at a
low cost
and get somebody to buy it
and it's risky like he was just saying
to try to promote fire that you
personally think is amazing
but the market might not think that yet
and so do you have the capacity to like
convince them or are you just gonna sit
on it
it's different than when your Market was
you were showing your friends your weed
and smoking some with them and you know
then it was easier now it's like selling
it in bulk to whether it's a distributor
or a broker
you know
everybody
it's too far from the final person for
people to be taking these risks
and so they're just pumping the gelatos
you know and realistically like
today I think in California
most commercial Farms they have some
type of gelato in their rotation
you know because
the market is calling for it you know
and the consumer the consumer
I don't want to call them idiots but
they're uneducated
that's the best word for it well it's
also to be fair to them Gabby it's also
hard to make new decisions when you walk
into a legal store and everything that
you want to check out is in a sealed
opaque mylar that they can't touch it
smell it smoke it or get excited about
it they just have to like spend a bunch
of money on it and then hope when they
open it up it's something good
and a lot of the way these mylars are
designed you don't even see the Cannabis
inside it until you've walked out of the
store and purchased it
they just look at what percentage THC it
is whatever it has the most they take
that
that's what they've been told and then
even if a farmer even if a farmer wants
to take risks it's not just on the
farmer the distro and the dispensary
also has to be willing to promote that
to the customer
so the farmer often time doesn't even
have control over whether or not the
customer is going to get educated
properly on why they think it's so good
yeah I really really try our best to
reach out to Bud tenders with this show
as as crazy as it sounds like they're
the the the last point before the
customers and we want them to be at
least be the most educated out of the
whole ring because they're the ones who
interact the most with the customers
you know you know what I was I was
remembering Gabby and uh I don't know
this is a totally random story but
Gabby and I did a project together where
we built this greenhouse on a property
he had
and we we thought it was get we thought
it was a huge Greenhouse at the time but
now it's like laughably small
um but do you remember when we grew uh
the Maui dude and those buds were so big
we took those pictures where your head
was behind the cola and all you could
see was your ponytail and like your ears
sticking out because there was these
giant
the classic High Time submission photo
yeah right yeah you know that that's
what you know we've seen icons is like a
butt in front of their face because you
know we have these giant we you know we
grew I I mean we had Urkel and Maui and
Superdog and various things in there
those things probably burned in your
fire but at some point we had all these
pictures
and that's hard too because I was
thinking about it and it's like before
phones had cameras on them there was so
many less pictures taken there was so
many less you know
um Gabby had some nice cameras and so we
took some really cool photos of various
things that we were doing
um but all it took was a fire or a bust
or an accident or something like that
and all that history would be lost
you know
yeah we got yeah I always remember that
I always remember that like of Gabby's
head Behind These Maui Buds and all you
could see was like he used to have this
really long ponytail and you all you
could see was a part of the ponytail and
maybe the corner of one ear because the
bud was like you know because it was a
[ __ ] big
yeah
but I mean it was pretty risque I mean
like you know I think like we started on
it the greenhouse was going to be 20 by
50. and Gabby thought that was enormous
so we shrank it to 20 by 30 and he was
it still seemed like it was ballsy
you know it was on the very top it was
on the top of the hill in an open field
and you know a few years later that kind
of stuff was a little bit more the norm
but at the time it was coming out of the
tree lines and it was coming out of the
indoors and it was coming out of these
tiny little scenes and it seemed Giant
it seemed giant oh yeah for sure
you know in that regard
and uh you know even the idea that you
could put something like he just said in
like an open field
and you wouldn't get in trouble
yeah you could actually get away with it
that always blew my mind about up there
in the Emerald Triangle that anybody
could do that because like you could you
cannot do that here still there's no way
well
it's it's it was always a game a cat and
mouse
huh
like our thinking on it was so there was
like a generally like well-known or
maybe it was wrong but we always thought
like as long as you have under a hundred
plants then it becomes the like the feds
aren't going to want to deal with this
and the local cops they're dealing with
much bigger people so
with the greenhouse
they could never actually and actually
you're allowed to medically have 25
plants at this time you know so with the
greenhouse it was like you can't really
see what's in there
you know and so if you can't see what's
in there
then
you know we felt a little safer maybe it
was just you know we were kidding
ourselves even though you could smell it
yeah but you can't smell it from a
helicopter and if you could you wouldn't
know what you're smelling because
everyone was growing up there I mean it
was a remote the whole idea was just
like Point keep it keep it kind of small
and make it not worth the trouble of
that now the issue that we never thought
of is we had a perfect landing pad over
there they could have like random 10
helicopters up there oh no right so it
wasn't like the Shady like a sketchy
Mountainside terrain like they have no
place to put it was not like they had
like a flat mode off [ __ ] landing pad
over there
it would have been bad I mean yeah I'll
bring this up just because I I just
thought of it but like when we were
growing the skunk
you know like that spot we were just
talking about was remote enough it
really didn't have neighbors that you
were too worried about but when we were
growing the skunk inside it was kind of
before the carbon filter era it was more
like where you had like uh you know the
uov Nair like the the ozone generators
and stuff and you'd grow that skunk and
like two weeks before it was done you'd
pull up into your driveway with your
windows down and you'd be like oh my God
it smells for 50 yards in every
direction around my house like I'm
slaughtering skunks like I'm gonna get
in trouble
oh my God it reeks and we used to do all
these things like Caulking and like
venting and trying to do all this
different stuff and it just beat every
effort we had to try to contain the
smell it was uncontainable and so in
some people would get rid of it because
it was too fragrant it like caused panic
like
the skunk
ah there you go so it was the skunk
yeah correct Francis yeah this is what
you're talking about reaped
than anybody else
he knows that he knows it might have
been super skunk or skunk
I mean the thing about it is for me is
that I always thought Gabby that like
you know that you know you get when I
when I when you gave me clones it was
like you gave me the dog and you gave me
and you gave me skunk
and just by your story I've been
thinking about this too
okay and I you know and I know how
important this is to so many people
so I don't want to get it wrong
right yeah but
I explicitly remember getting the skunk
from the dude in Virginia
right
and that that plant isn't the one that
looks just like the uh
the Scentsy Seed Catalog
and we had gotten we had gotten the
seeds from Scentsy and that's how we got
our original cross that we were uh that
you know then we got the mails from to
to make everything else
like super dog and that stuff so that so
that so that's the way I remember it but
as such an important part of History you
know yeah I'm not signing in no but
that's David's or anything like that
yeah exactly but that's I mean that's
all anyone wants you know what I mean
like if you don't quite have an answer
it's best guess
that's the best guess that's that that's
just that's more advanced than we were
before
yeah and I I mean you believe that I
will repeat the same story the next time
I speak to you like you said that
somebody was telling the story and every
time they told it it was a little bit
different I don't think I'm gonna tell
it differently no no no no no this is
this is a lot different thing I'm also
not swearing to accuracy you know no of
course I smoke a lot I promise it's a
it's a it's a long-ass time
it's literally decades ago yeah
so yeah let me ask yourself the question
Francis didn't we get the seeds in order
to make the first cross
yeah here's the thing is that when we
were talking earlier you were like oh we
just used the males right but we had
that problem from the Census
but we had that one female
right that you that like that you gave
me so I don't know how that one female
came to be because by the time that I
came into it like you gave me the skunk
you gave me skunk and dog the same day
you don't have it anymore correct
I lost it when I got in trouble and you
know whatever that was does anyone give
a [ __ ] it's a gun
because because one of them one of them
is probably in sour and one of them is
probably in chem dog D and Diesel and
they're very important I think so I
think that's true
but I mean if we don't have it then like
but we have the we have the last two and
we would like to know
kind of which one went where because
people don't believe us on that on that
little part of it like that's what I
believed I don't know I don't so what
part is not believed that uh like the
chem dog D it would would have the same
Super Skunk chem 91 connection
okay they still think it's sisters
they don't believe us
yes we disagree with them
probably neither of us will ever be
proven right or wrong
and we can just enjoy this debate for
the rest of our life yeah I mean I mean
like you don't have I do Source we don't
have the source material Beyond people's
words that's true you know to do it
right like we need to have all the
genetics Maybe
right if we had all the genetics and
futuristic technology
right but we we already don't have all
the possible genetics because it's lost
who knows I could I could identify it
from a photo of a bud if somebody was
growing it like the weed is so unique
and it looks just like the [ __ ]
Scentsy Seed Catalog photo
like it's the only weed that I've ever
grown
that you could do that with yeah I'll
send you I there there are people that
think it's I mean this causes all kinds
of debate because what happens now Gabby
is that people people get get excited
about old school famous strings and then
there's opportunists that are like I
found it
now I'm gonna sell you clones for high
dollar or I'm gonna make a bunch of
hybrids with seed and you'll be able to
get it in seed form and so there's a
bunch of fakes that proliferate about
various stuff there's all these there's
all this Politics the buyer must be
where they must be where and like and
that's and that's why you buy seeds from
a reliable source like Riot seed go
right
um because
if not
it you know like you know the buyer must
be aware and you know if you're only
paying you know even a hundred dollars a
pack 150 a pack you know you can roll
the dice when you got situations like
companies that should be remain unnamed
that are selling packs for a thousand
bucks or something like that then you
really want to know you're getting
something I I think genetics are worth
that much yeah when you're actually
getting
what you're promised if if someone's
saying this is what you're getting this
is what you can expect this is what you
know I think you know genetics can be
worth thousands of dollars
um but
when you're dealing with unreputable
people and the thing about unreputable
people is
they get called out pretty quick
you know like the other person we were
talking about before well
what happens you know what happens is
Gabby is is that
honestly because we don't have genetic
testing and because we don't have the
guaranteed what we have is we have
stories
right and these stories get you know
like there's people that are like they
buy into the story and then there's
people that are like that guy's a
scumbag I don't buy his story at all
but Francis if we answer if we answer
these questions life would be extremely
boring and some people would have no
lives I get it dude that's true you know
it's just like like what are these
people gonna do when they stop arguing
dog or or the skunk is right I mean
there's funny things where like when I
would tell when I would tell those
stories on previous podcasts there would
be people that would get all mad at me
and would be like you don't know the
dude that brought him West you were
never really friends with that guy
you're [ __ ] making it up and I'm like
I don't know I mean I don't know what to
tell you dude I don't know why didn't
you call me dude
I got his [ __ ] phone number right
here
you see that nine yeah it's here now
you know I mean I was honestly like even
with that I could help I would rather
you say it again for people that are
just stepping in
what Francis said was pretty accurate
the anything that was inaccurate or not
completely accurate was maybe some
timelines and Minor Details that really
don't change the story much at all
you know like the the basis of the story
is the same yeah so
I mean honestly I think you did a better
job than I would have been able to just
because
you know you've been thinking about it
for longer and you know you've you've
spelled it out in your mind and possibly
on paper what you've thought about it
yeah obsesses yeah we're having really
all those stories just come from like a
million times of like me and Gabby
sitting on a couch somewhere stoned
shooting the [ __ ] about wheat yeah
that's where it all came from like it
just friendships sharing stories about
this or that or whatever and like that's
honestly like why I believed Gabby so
much more than some of the later stuff
that came up was because he didn't have
a reason to lie yeah it was way before
the theme it was years and years before
skunk the egg on the forums and anybody
knew chemdog like the the public hadn't
heard of it it was just stories amongst
friends
and he was able to it was always the
same story no matter how big right you
guys were
yeah it was just us it was just friends
sharing stuff you know and yeah and you
know and Gabby and I had a very similar
view on weed in the sense that like we
both liked really good weed and we both
wanted to make better weed if we could
you know I almost did I almost didn't
say it dude but like way back in the day
I liked sativas and like Gabby hated
them because he was like dude I'm so
high strung I want weed to like calm me
down
he's like maybe you're so calm you can
get like a little anxious or a little
bit higher he's like I don't want to do
that dude I need to mellow out like
you're mellow enough you want to smoke
sativa and get all Zippy fun not me
down you know I need to be brought I
need to be I need to be mellowed out
people were telling me to chill out too
people like Gabby chill the [ __ ] out
well I mean okay I'm gonna have to stop
I'm gonna have to stop this in a minute
but it's all right we're gonna continue
again
is that you know I'll say this is that
California is a bunch of you know
there's it's a lot Chiller you know
Gabby coming from you know being a New
York Jew coming West he was loud he
talked fast people thought it was
aggressive but it was like where he came
from everybody talked like that yeah
that was normal as normal it could be so
it was just like you know I it wasn't
anything weird it was just you know
there's cultural differences you move
from the East Coast or New York to
California it's not culturally the same
when I moved from Chicago to you know to
uh to Mendo I was like oh my God
you know I mean I'll end it on this
because Gabby's gotta go but like uh uh
my best friend growing up that became
really good friends with Gabby too he
passed away a long time ago but you know
he used to do this thing where he'd call
it California nice
and he'd be like if you want to tell me
[ __ ] you just tell me [ __ ] you
don't be nice to me about it I'll take
it fine yeah just tell me you know same
way I have no interest you know piss off
let me everyone think to that before you
go before I let you go go ahead I
remember uh when I first got to
California it totally freaked me out
when like a cashier would start making
conversation with the person in line in
front of them like in front of me I'm
next in line I'm next in line and this
lady's like how you doing yeah it's a
beautiful day you know like hope you
have a great weekend and I'm just like
thinking just [ __ ] bring her up so I
can get my [ __ ] and get the hell out of
here no like exactly like now now I say
hello to everyone at the supermarket
you enjoy the rest of your day buddy
love you tons
all right I love you too you can talk
more tomorrow thank you
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out