welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to reader Syndicate
I'm Matthew here with thousandfold and
today we are going to be talking
about thousand jel jel that's right one
of my favorite plants one of my favorite
uh clones it's been kept over the years
and we're going to give you a I don't
know how short or long it's going to be
but we're going to give you a thorough
rundown of the Clone uh more about it
where it came from Etc and with that
thousand you want to um Kick It
Off yeah well I think I was wondering
whether or not you want to start with uh
the kind of who did who said you know
who said what um when uh versus trits
what do you yeah we'll start with the
we'll start with the back history on
just kind of where it popped up from
yeah sounds good so jel came from the
chem dog crew originally now uh The
Story Goes that it was Kim dog Greg who
I believe his first quotes were that it
was the chem dog D herming onto the mass
Super Skunk clone which is different
than the VA Super Skunk clone different
than the mom of sour as best we know and
um we don't know what year I've asked
him several times but it's uh not it's
inconclusive as of yet unless he finds
his journal can I year yeah yeah when
you say it's different from the VA SS is
this do you think that it was just like
a Sensei SS like from yeah yeah so after
talking to Gabby um like we've always
had this assumption and knowledge a
little bit just from different people in
the group saying yeah we went we went
and bought more centy Seed Super Skunk
whether they went there to get it or
ordered it don't know but they had more
sensey Seed Super skun that they popped
at some point we know that for sure but
after talking to Gabby um he readily
confirmed that there was more CTI seeds
Super Skunk popped all over the place
between all those Crews so I'm not sure
if um they did that because the VA Super
Skunk was known as a super skunk even
though it was probably a hybrid
according to the guy who uh made it or
accidentally made it um M I'll call him
um but I don't know if because they knew
that super skunk was somewhat in that
first one from VA that was really dank
that they decided they were going to
start chasing super skunks up and down
there or if they just had smoked other
super skunks and said wow this is really
dank and we're going to go for it that
way but at some point they acquired more
um super skunk seeds um let's see what
else uh
so Kim dog said that he made it again we
don't know what year I'm assuming early
2000s to Mid mid maybe 2004 to 2006
sounds more accurate but I do think it
was around before 2006 pretty sure on
the chem timeline where is this relative
to
the
uh you know the the different seed pops
do you
know kind very fuzzy right yeah yeah I
mean it's a hard question because it all
depends on whose point of view you take
when it comes to the chem seed lines
like it is Kim d one of the original
seeds if not is it 91 Super Skunk which
Super Skunk was it the one from ceny
which I think it was if that's the case
according to to Greg that D was in the
room at least when Jesus was made so it
has to be later if we are going by what
he says and that's my friend I'm not
going to call him a liar or anything
crazy um if we believe that's what he
says then it would have had to have been
at least a later pop than whatever was
made to po if that makes sense um and
I'm sure it's going to confuse the [ __ ]
out of people who have but you just go
back and listen to our chem dog episodes
it it really goes into detail about
which one we think it is and again we'll
we'll reference the Codex later the
Codex also talks deeply about the chem
dog situation and what was what so
definitely check out our codex and we'll
link you in the
description but yeah I think uh yeah
that covers it with what was said um
there was another person in involved in
in Greg's close crew um in chem dog
Greg's close crew named Bundy and we
know that he was a uh a good friend of
Greg um and he was doing a lot of the
library keeping he was very into making
crosses he
was I would say probably more of the
strain nerd in the group trying to keep
um tabs on that kind of stuff and
there's some other sister lines that
I've been able to get a hold of I would
say not sister but maybe tangential
sister if that makes sense um like like
snow dog snow dog looks very similar to
jel it smokes very similar to jel um
it's much more resinous a little bit
more sweet um but I would gather it was
probably made around a similar time to
the uh gel they both kind of pop up
around the same time and in my opinion
Bundy probably had something more to do
with it because it seems like some of
the work that he was doing um
I had a question here because I don't
know that much about snow dog um is it
also considered a chemam quote unquote
okay yeah snow dog um what was it or
snow
bubbleberry cam snow Bubble cam I think
it was
called other yeah there are these other
Cuts around chemam that I don't doesn't
seem like it's very clear that it's from
them like I don't know snow dog jel
these are lesser known obviously Kim and
and I think also because like even
though some of them had like dog in the
name like snow dog snow dog was passed
around quite a bit because it had dog in
the name but jel kind of dropped to the
side it was one of the there was never
any hype for jel over all the years like
when I first got the cut there wasn't
jel hype nobody was chasing jel most
people never heard of it didn't know
what it was that's an interesting thing
to talk about as well like I know in the
past you've said you think that's partly
because of the name yes in my mind I'm
like but but don't people like diesel so
wouldn't they have thought oh gel is
like a diesel thing that sounds cool um
even based on but there was also another
line called chel out and most people
when you said jel were assuming you were
talking about chel so that was also
another issue you know the UK cheese
diesel by someone else I think uh maybe
that's a heath Robinson thing if I
remember correctly the cheel but um it
had nothing to do with the gel uh as
Greg told it to me it was G's diesel is
where the name came from Greg's diesel
yeah
so as he explained it it was his
favorite version of the chems and
diesels and that's why it was called G's
Diesel and as uh Manny from the sour
crew explained it to me as well they
used the term diesel to describe
everything and he thought it was more
like and since he was one of the people
that named the cam bag seed the our chem
bag seed that became diesel um he was I
asked him like where did you get the
name like he's like well Diesel jeans
were popular things like that diesel gas
like it all kind of came in at the same
time and that's kind of why the term
diesel popped up and plus chem weed
didn't really flow well with Organic
Growers they didn't like that term chem
weed so they preferred to call it diesel
instead and it makes sense you know like
the organic Growers can get real
studious about that you know what I mean
like even the name would bother him so
so funny enough I guess what you were
implying is that if he called it like
Kim F it probably would have sold Kim G
been chased forever I think I I say that
but then Kim one is not really chased
but it was also held back so tight that
nobody really got to grow it for so long
you know but yeah yeah chem1 isn't
really chased either so it kind of
shoots somewhat of a hole in my thing
but it's it's the best I can gather I
mean it it was available it was not
really hoarded the diesel clone like
people would pass it I passed it a lot
but um most people would just drop it
it's a hard plant to grow um now we
talked about what it's supposed to be um
we'll talk about what it is in a little
bit do we want to go into any of other
history stuff there any other questions
we have there is there any other context
that you think is interesting I guess is
maybe another way of you know um we
talked about the name we talked about
the
crew um it's it's been really it's been
really interesting uh most trying to
track down the dates because knowing the
dates would help this make a lot more
sense um of what it was what else was in
the room that was made um it would give
us more of a clue oh if if Kim dogd was
the the pollen contributor what else did
Kim dog time what else was made you know
um things like that would really help us
pin down um I have my own opinions of
course on what it is after running it
for over 15 years and uh running through
a lot of the s1s uh sold a ton of them
watched a ton of them grown too by other
people I have my own theory on what it
is um and just based on knowing a lot
about the D how it reverses and
whatnot I think that it was probably the
pure Super Skunk herming on itself one
thing we know about Chim dogd is that it
doesn't tend to throw live pollen when
it hers it just doesn't like that was a
big problem with it a lot of people want
to MDS ones over the years so they
torture hermit it just wouldn't make
seeds it just it's not a it's a sterile
pollen thrower for the most part unless
you use like STS or something like that
to reverse
it so looking at it the way the plants
come out it tends to stay true to all
the super skunk traits types TPS all of
it okay maybe we should just go into the
traits then yeah I mean kind of have to
um yeah
so the traits of gel jel is a long leny
plant a lot like the Diesels a lot like
you would see in OG kushes um it
stretches quite a bit in flour and even
as a veg plant it does need some
sticking because it's it's very very
lanky very lanky plant um it's not the
heaviest resin producer which I think is
another reason a lot of people didn't
keep it um it has a very old school look
to it and I wish we could show pictures
of it but that's how our videos get
flagged and stuff and hidden so
unfortunately we can't show the pictures
but you can go reference any of this in
the Codex under the jel um and and see
some pictures of old original pictures I
think OG Rascal's pictures are up there
so shout out to OG Rascal he had some of
the best original some of the first
pictures people were putting up online
of it that were decent grows um
currently there only a couple but I
imagine you have more oh yeah yeah we
have more I need to get more up in there
um what else do we got uh it's got very
very bubbly bra that's something that a
lot of people notice with it the the big
bubbly bra it almost looks like it's
holding monster seeds in it even if it's
not um they're very dense bubbly bracks
but the bud the bud density how the
bracks form isn't super dense it's it's
not Airy but it's right in between it
looks like it'd be super dense but it's
just not as dense as it looks which I
think is another reason people weren't
super chasing it you know it's not as
dense as 91 not as dense as d
um but the main trait the main reason
that I kept it was because it has this
wonderful buttery skunk and that's
quoting pip because I could never place
it always just said skunky like I always
said it's skunky I don't know how to
explain it you know but pip nailed it
down to buttery skunk creamy buttery
skunk like Savory skunk and I think that
is the most accurate term um you I would
say gassy but it's not necessarily gassy
but some of that like like the the non-h
harsh tones of gasoline like when at the
pump petrol um that smell minus the
harsh notes they're kind of too loud is
in there but with skunk um true to the
term skunk just uh you mentioned the the
kind of swollen bra earlier how would
you compare the flower structure in
general to like a
diesel which also has some of that I I
mean they they both have that super
skunk trait of the the bubbly bra like
that's one of those the the traits that
runs through and true through all super
stuns the other am I am I right in in
thinking that the jesel flowers don't
they don't seem to end up being quite as
big uh they seem almost but I don't know
I've only seen a few pictures yeah no
they're they're delicate like when I
grow it it's delicate small buds I've
seen people blow it up and blow it out
and get large yelds from it but I didn't
like it that way I felt it was always
more midy that that way and it liked to
be a certain um a certain look like it
it liked to be smaller to produce better
resin and the high was almost always
better if you didn't push it too hard
and when you push this thing too hard
she absolutely will Herm just like the
old Super Skunk um that was one of the
other things like in in my theory with
the the chmd versus the super skunk the
mass Super Skunk was a notorious Herm
like that was its reputation oh it's a
great plant smells great [ __ ] Herms
every everywhere and and loads up aruma
seeds like that was its reputation ever
since I've been around um so the
likelihood that a a chem dog D that
throws sterile pollen is in a room with
the mass Super Skunk that's already
going to throw live pollen on it like I
mean it it one is more likely than the
other and with how it breeds I would
have to say that it's more likely just
super skunk but to this day uh you know
Kem dog Greg definitely stands by his
story on that it was the chem D I don't
know how he's come to that conclusion
but um I I I tend to disagree on that
but he was there I wasn't so it's it's a
really hard one to disagree on and have
any kind
of standing on it it's it's one of those
situations and and we've run into this a
lot with Kim F and yeah that's with all
respect it's just really how it goes
what would you say about its effects
potency for you um for me
because like like we always talk about
effects are very subjective like it
depends on the person smoking it their
brain chemistry um set and setting like
they talk about when you're um dropping
acid or mushroom set and setting is just
as important with Canabis to me um if
you're in a bad mood have a bad bad day
it doesn't always like cannabis will not
always like decrease your anxiety not
every strain not every Grove every
strain will decrease your anxiety some
will amplify it especially for me yeah
um yeah jel just doesn't do that I I
talk about how blueberry I can smoke it
it has some anti-anxiety effects jel has
the same effect for me it doesn't have
the ass kicking potency of chem dog D
that can make you wi out or feel like
you're dumb speaking where like you know
when you're speaking and everything you
hear coming out of your mouth sounds
stupid nonsensical it doesn't really
have that effect for me but it does have
a lot of the um the well-being effect
you know uh super important reason why
you like it yeah yeah yeah it's it's
it's the main reason I smoke is for ante
anxiety I I get amped up too easy and
when I find something like that that's
very special you know and even when when
I was first given the cut by bod um he's
the first person to pass it to me back
in the day it was the first person I saw
actually growing it and making crosses
with it um it it wasn't the skunk part
that really made me hold on to it it was
the the actual high from it that made me
hold on to it uh during dur that time I
don't remember a bunch of people
actually actively chasing skunks skunky
smelling stuff uh when he passed it to
me but you know in a few years that
became very important and it always
baffled me that people had trouble
finding it I'm like it's right here like
it's been passed around it's still alive
it's not hard to find to this day people
still don't get that but um I think
they're starting to a little bit
unfortunately there are a lot of um
really bad Faith individuals selling
fake clones of it right now on Instagram
and wherever else online so a lot of
people's idea of what jel is is very
skewed very very skewed um which is why
it's important to talk about the trades
you
know um one of the other main traits in
all super skunk that I talk about are
the dog tongue traits and this it's
basically a the small I don't know what
you call those leaves sucker leaves a
lot of people call them but they are
rounded on the tip they're kind of
slightly like bent like this like you'll
see it in sour pictures yeah you'll see
it in 91 pictures you'll see in all
kinds of different shots and it's not
just that it has those it's the
Distribution on the bud in a pattern
that specifically leaves the look of
super skunk and that's like one of the
quickest identifiers for Super Skunk
stuff rarely rarely have ever seen
pictures of another plant that has that
trait uh that spefic specific trait I
have seen it on um oh I want to say it
was like a early girl clone from a High
Times magazine but as we know like High
Times use stock pictures and would call
them certain things so that's being as
that's the only one anomalous picture
I've ever seen I tend to think it was
probably a super skunk hybrid just being
pushed in the magazine is that that one
picture but I can't say for sure
obviously um historically Matt maybe now
is a good time to talk about what kind
of crosses did you think of well what
kind of crosses did you make with it and
what else have you seen other people
make with it that you feel you know has
stood up or has been interesting or so
some of the first crosses I saw with it
were um bod's um I think it was called
Isaac Hayes and now yo Sami has released
a line called Isaac Hayes but um I don't
know which one came first I mean it's
two different continents you know like
it could have been simultaneous for all
we know but the Isaac ha release by bod
was a jel cross to a seeds bangy Haze I
can't remember off the top of my head it
was like a meow
Thai Haze of some old's Haze maybe bangy
Haze was but um that was the first Cross
I'd ever seen of it you can see a lot of
Super Skunk types in that and everybody
that grew it absolutely loved it and
that's kind of what made me ask him for
the Clone in the first place was seeing
him make that cross seen pictures of it
it was absolutely gorgeous um when I got
a hold of it one of the other things I
was chasing at the time was a clone
called super dog um the first time I'd
ever seen pictures of jel wasn't the
rasal pictures it was actually in the
canab Bible from Jason King and along
with the jel there was also Snow Dog in
there there was super dog um and super
dog was supposedly a chem 91 Mass Super
Skunk which sounds very similar to me to
chem dog D so I'd assume it would be
something like that so one of my first
goals with the jel since it was very
similar was to recreate something like
the super dog because it wasn't
available anywhere in my city or anyone
I knew had the super dog um Bud would
come down of the Maui super dog to San
Diego but that was rarely and it was
pretty dank so I was like I I want to
recreate this with this this is what we
have this is the closest it gets so my
first seed line with it I believe was
the the the super dog 2010 I think it
was called maybe that was my first real
release with it and I was really stoked
with it it was in Skunk magazine um
another one that I did was the
uh jel cross to shite oh no it was jel
West Coast dog which is not related to
chem dog it was a scam cut line from
Paradise seeds mod uh tk1 he's had a
million names guy's probably still
around um
and that that's like a Bubba type but a
little bit different but it's a really
nice plant and that it was the West
Coast dog cross to the sug Knight OG
gbx1 I know again the sug Knight's been
really popular to talk about on
Instagram the other day I saw someone
telling a story that the sug Knight was
some clone that the rapper went to Nepal
to go get to bring back and it became OG
which is totally wrong sug Knight was a
forum member um he was making like nor
lights leopard Kush things like this and
uh the sug Knight Kush was a Bubba the
sug Knight OG was probably the OG Bubba
OG type back Cross of some sort if if he
even went that far with it I'm not sure
I didn't know Suge to know um how much
work he was actually doing or not doing
you
know so yeah that's I'm trying to think
of what else I've made with it um of
course have the blooper skunk the jel
cross to the blue bonnet Which is my by
far my favorite J cologne up until
current time and it's very very skunky
they they merge really well together
it's very true to keeping that beautiful
beautiful jel super skunk look but with
a lot more resin too um yeah that's
probably one of my favorite lines to
smoke with the gel in it trying to think
of what else I made with jel I I I tried
to whap it with everything every year
that I had it but um I think your the
other one I can think of is the triangle
choke right yes thank you the triangle
choke so that was during one of our jel
reversal uh jel reversals back in the
day we did oh yeah and there was also um
sour dub jel that my buddy Racer X made
and released with us that's one of my
favorites of all time too the skunk
spray cam just it has to do with the
theory that super skunk that skunk smell
is a double recessive so when you cross
two double recessives which would be two
super skunk types displaying that types
so like a sour to a gel it will almost
always just constantly throw that smell
and and skunkin and gas and it it locks
that in and it's it's it's one of my
favorite crosses for doing that um I
mean I can see why right it's if you've
got your blue locked in and you've got
the jel you know super skunk locked in
yeah it's nice and we had the triangle
choke jeel that was something I released
with chem dog Greg as a collab but
didn't sell nobody bought it I don't
know why triangle Kush was kind of
popular at the time but not as well
known maybe so like trying to trying to
hit a hike that wasn't there at the time
didn't really work so I popped them
myself and I found a keeper and that's
what we hit with the blue bonnet and I
was already doing some Sour Diesel Blue
Bonnet gel Blue Bonnet um there were all
sorts of different super skunks in there
uh motor breath 15 Blue Bonnet the K
sister S1 Blue Bonnet so I wanted to
throw in another one just to kind of see
how that distribution worked Crossing it
to Super Skunk and that's probably like
one of the most beautiful Frosty crazy
potent lines that came out of the blue
Bonet crosses and I think everybody
pretty much universally likes it and
finds something that they find to be a
keeper somewhere in that
line we have a bunch of pictures popular
recently yeah on our Discord there's
tons of pictures of it scrutin and and
Blu gr got beautiful pictures of it one
of my favorite looking cuts of it yeah
char as well yeah yeah
yep where are we at let's see um you did
mention s1's but I was kind of curious
what else you might have seen when you
did that where with in the s1's yeah in
the s1s so in the s1's there is there is
some heavy variation um I didn't think
there would be as much variation as
there was because if it is an S2 I would
expect it to breed more true to type but
in saying that there was like mango
versions of it popping out sweet
versions popping out it tended to keep
the same structure and look for the most
part but some of them did have more of a
a more conical skunk one type bud
structure um so it definitely showed
more of this recessive skunk one in the
S2s while
also or I'm sorry the s1s if it's a mass
Super Skunk S2 it's still showing the
variation of the super skunk or of the
skunk one inside of it um yeah I mean it
it stuck mostly to the the Savory skunk
The Buttery skunk and there was also
some mango types um but that's mostly
the the range it stuck around uh and in
Skunk one hybrids I tend to see a lot of
that sweet uh generic you say mango it's
not really mango mango but it's like a
sweet fruit tropical yeah it's it's a
generic sweet fruit
tropical yep yep no that's
cool um you did talk already about what
you what you thought it it is obviously
so I don't know if we
I mean yeah I I I still think it's a
super skunk um S2 I really do despite
everything that was said about it in
history it
just you know I could be wrong I could
be wrong but um and there's always going
to be some doubt there because I wasn't
there you know but I do think it is pure
super
scum well it's probably not a bad time
to actually just go into the into the
drop ah so yeah yeah so
uh CSI humble first got the jel cut in
2006 and ran it um we'd spoken about it
over the years he dropped it after and
and he was like yeah I don't know man I
I remember running it I don't remember
much about it probably you know I'm not
that interested in it he doesn't really
like diesels in the first place so it
was a hard sell to get the homie to run
jesel I was like dude you like skunky
stuff stop stop playing got to grow it
and eventually he did and that was a few
years ago and he hit me up like dude
just jel tell me more about it you know
and that's that that felt really good
because I like when when I I tell
someone something that I think is really
special and someone as experienced as
him agrees I mean he sees more stuff
than probably anyone else I know like
more different variations of everything
by doing massive seed pops making tons
of hybrids and he interested him enough
to to work with it and we decided we're
going to do a collab on it and he wanted
to make some more S1 since I was all out
of them and I don't know of any with
great provenant out there that exist
other than the ones that I did so it was
time to bang some out and we decided to
make some hybrids as well so we spent
some months talking about what would be
good pairings for the gel crosses and uh
yeah I think uh should I go through the
list of what was hit or what's available
probably what's available probably
what's available I mean we can go into
what was hit just to generate more hype
later but yeah it's true with what's
available okay so we had the bubus and I
think the reasoning behind that was one
of csi's favorite plants was a sour
Bubba one of my favorite plants was a
sour Bubba um and this is going to be
very close but I like jel more than sour
so I thought that this would be a good
direction for it so we wanted to do the
chmd gel just to have an idea um on my
theory if KD's in this plant it'll
either look like a chmd a feminized chmd
BX or it'll look like the first CHD
superum um and will we be I mean will we
be able to tell just by running a large
population I don't know but it was
something that we both liked the idea of
and wanted to see is it possible can we
tell is there any way to define this so
that's why that was thrown in there um
dog [ __ ] is one of the dog [ __ ] electric
bugaloo I should say it original name
was electric bugaloo but for all intents
and purposes we're calling it dog [ __ ]
because that's how it's colloquial mod
you know everybody knows it it's dog
[ __ ] so that's what we're going with um
dog shit's one of the most famous clones
that pretty much everyone universally
loves uh when they try it so that had to
be in the room it's a you know some sort
of probably nl5 Haze type maybe not
skunk Haze I I don't really know enough
about it but um like it's history or
it's it's a hard plant to nail down as
far as turps on what it could be but it
seemed like a good pairing for the gel
um what else do we have in there we have
before you go on like what do you have
any sense of what to expect from that
one or no it seems like a wild card
right a little bit that's a wild card
that's something that's more of a
question for CSI I don't have as much
experience with dog [ __ ] I've only done
one cross with
it it didn't I haven't run it a bunch
it's more of an older clone that took a
long time to get to me and maybe sorry
while we're on this note what do you
hope for from the Bubba jel you kind of
mentioned the uh what was the comparison
you had s sour Bubba yeah okay I mean
Bubba Bubba in itself is already like
when you grow it certain ways and nail
it it's you can see expressions of OG
cush in it you can see some of the Bubba
Expressions there's all kinds of stuff
in in Bubba when it's nailed it can be
super turpy and because jel is also
super super trippy itself it's just the
sour Bubbas that we've smoked before are
just Stellar absolutely Stellar High TS
and because I like jel more than sour
and I think it's more turpy and less L
noxious offensive I think it'll it'll be
pretty insane it'll be absolutely insane
so that's that's one of the Reas do with
that it's it's also the same reason we
went with Iran
Kush large large turp percents coming
out of it very turpy uh seems to merge
well with other plants and gel in the
s1s you can find OG Kush smelling is
plants not not identical but in that
direction so we wanted to see if we can
push Irene more in that direction of
find a more turpy skunky version of OG
Kush by doing it um in my mind that's
why I wanted to do it so I can only
speak for myself on that and it made it
through stoked um the pineapple gel I do
not know anything about pineapple that's
a humble NorCal type thing that's
something that inspector wanted to use
CSI um it's a large yielding outdoor
plant that smells pineapple I do have no
clue how that's going to combine we're
about to find out you know like I love
pineapple tur like the c99 pineapple was
like a tpine pineapple type thing um I
don't know if this is I don't think it's
a tendine pineapple I think it's just
pineapple uh I'm not sure if it's the
pineapple tie from Shaw if it's the same
cut or not it maybe may not be um I do
need to find out more about that one but
it is available and uh we of course did
the sour
jel the super skunk recessive double up
that I talked about earlier easy easy
money right there just bam easy you know
it's going to come out dank as hell
almost every time you mix uh two super
skunk types it happens and we wanted
something readily available for people
to find Keepers in in very small amounts
of seed pops we don't have room if
someone wants Super Skunk that's going
to be their ticket you know Sour Diesel
s1s have been very hard to make very
hard to come across this is really close
to what you would expect
that and um oh good can I ask you one
thing uh even though it's not on the
list and I don't I don't know if it was
even I did he did you guys not do an URL
I don't think kco was ready at the
time for the room and only reason it
wasn't in there a lot of that had to do
with what do we have available what's
you know what's in Cuts what's rooted
what do we want to throw in and of
course it was his first time reversing
jel so like he wasn't sure if it was
going to always it was going to be a
successful reversal too so now that we
know that you know he's capable of
reversing it in it really easy like I
did it it's probably going to be the
next round or a future round but yeah
that's kind of one that needs to happen
um R makes beautiful hybrids yeah I mean
I do see that he I mean I again I don't
know if this one is one of the actual
ones that's released yet but there's a
T1000 which I oh yeah that's you know I
I remember talking about it now that you
bring that up and that was going to be
our closest to heral because it was
disgust and we're like H 2000s in there
might as well you know run with that see
how it does makes sense and I think the
the last one on the list is the 5150
which is his select cut of the triangle
kushes ones big yelder super potent
super chirpy and again along the ideas
of the
Irene we wanted a large but this is more
like a larger yielding commercial jeel
that anybody who loves OG Kush loves
triangle will love this plant so that
was our idea behind that one and uh yeah
we just dropped these Christmas I think
it was we decided to drop them and
tonight I'm going to be packing and
doing all kinds of shipping so yeah so
to make it really clear they're
available on your on your website too
yes they're available on Riot seats.com
they're also available on CSI or Humbolt
csi.com so either place is great to grab
them from check it out um all the
freebies that are going to be with it
are the sour diesel jel or you can buy
it as well those are available to buy
but I'm be sending out Sour Diesel jel
with these first orders
very nice
yeah um so for outdoor people I would
probably recommend um the pineapple jel
because it's a proven outdoor plant the
dog [ __ ] jel another proven outdoor
plant Irene does pretty well Outdoors as
long as it's not too humid um Bubba
don't have
humid Outdoors again camd does really
well Outdoors too so all of those are
going to be good Outdoors Jesus does
well Outdoors too jel does Great
Outdoors it's not too dense it doesn't
mold too readily it's fast flowering I
mean we're talking eight weeks flowering
time we're not pushing it any longer
than that um she will Herm if if you
push her longer than that so it's like
it's the the gift that keeps on giving
from the mass Super Skunk is the uh
interex traits but when you get to this
point in growing like you learn to watch
your plants take care of and they're
easily remedied you know what I mean so
it's it's not not anything I take into
consideration and she does breed more um
consistently non-inner sex than the
actual plant is when you push her
heart um I did want to Pro you about one
more of the crosses that Caleb mentioned
but again probably not in the release uh
the
cookies times jel what what do you think
is gonna come out of
that um I mean it'd probably be along
the urle type and OG type you know you
probably see a little SE
po yeah but yeah there's also the like
the F1 der was in there or no no FL it
was the flow R OG in there there we had
the the the la Kush in there we had the
56 day headband in there Maui wow his
pure OG which is the first cut of OG
Kush that he ever got um from Elk Slayer
so like we actually have like the old
one of his older OG Cuts in there we
have the snow different kind of hash
plants sweet kind of hash plant across
it too uh chem 1's also in there which
is more of an nl5 Haze type of chem so
yeah there those definitely coming too
right yeah they'll eventually be some of
them we didn't get a ton of seeds from
so they may not be released and we're
just going to run them to look and see
um yeah but some yeah eventually will be
released like the bubblegum gel stuff
like
that cool very
nice uh I mean we've cover most of I
think of the information that we wanted
to cover uh was anything you wanted to
say about the Codex do we want to add
more stuff to it yes so I really wanted
to get to it over Christmas but like
some people know I've been dealing with
like some health stuff and I've been
figuring it out kind of what it is and
it kept hitting a little bit during
Christmas so I didn't get to do as much
as I wanted to with adding to the codec
but it's going to be a Non-Stop project
um if you want to hear some more in
detail about what what we're talking
about with like the different versions
of the chem stories what we think versus
what's been established the Codex is a
great place to go codex. the Breeders
syndicate.com
um our our goal is this to be the best
resource for historical clowns and
historical lines so you can go look at
it and it's not going to
be just my take on it it's going to be
several different takes on each thing we
Market as speculative it's if it's
speculative we mark it if it's for sure
and there's no argument about what it is
that's there you know like we tried to
think of all the variables that we could
to cover all the bases so people
understand the information that they're
reading and how reliable it is isn't or
could possibly be and um yeah I mean
between between both of us we've put a
lot of time and energy into it and I I
I'm really stoked about it I think it's
gonna be one of the most important
things that we do as The Syndicate
together I really do and I hope everyone
else don't I will say that uh this
episode is also I think the first
episode for the new year so happy New
Year everyone happy New Year and also I
was kind of doing like a recap of 2023
with my girlfriend last night and uh it
actually kind of blows my mind that the
Codex was just earlier last year um
yeah yeah last year went really quickly
and that was one of the big things that
happened last year um look how much the
the the show has changed and grown just
the last year just the last year and
just the last year I took it back
started producing it myself you know
like all that happened within a year
like it it just it went crazy in a year
and and where it's at versus where it's
at Now versus where it's at before I
really really am proud of how far it's
come and yeah it's it's a big
relief I think we've doubled the number
of subscribers in the last six months
I am pissed that my gamble of hitting
10,000 didn't happen but but it's still
the first week of January so we're not
done yet so everybody like And subscribe
because I want to hit the 10K Mark and I
told we hit it by January godamn it uh
beginning of January too with that so
let's not make a liar of
me let's do it let's
go I think I think that's mostly it to
cover for jesel um if you guys have any
questions or comments or concerns if any
of the chem F want to chime in the
comments are below I don't delete
comments you know like it I don't care
if they're they're counterintuitive to
to what I'm saying or disagree um it's a
good place to have a conversation we
want to have meaningful open
conversations and transparent
conversations with people I do sometimes
delete comments if they just straight
toxic and non-constructive oh yeah yeah
yeah th those ones if and if people are
being like mental and uh using it like
their diary to [ __ ] post yeah I'll
delete those I don't really care I'll
talk [ __ ] to them but other than that
like if it's if it's um topic relevant
it stays and uh yeah that's about it
yeah leave your comments please we need
the
interaction I have one shout out uh
before I hand it over to you Matt to
wrap up which is canak Cabana oh thank
you thank you canak Cabana is open and
wants you to get a hold of him um he's
ready he's ready to book the episode
yeah so we're going to be doing an
episode with the can caban crew um not
sure what we're going to talk about yet
exactly but it's going to be a fun one
yeah I'm stoked on it um for those that
don't know the canak Cabana is the
longest running Forum still active um it
was originally built as a refuge for
overgrow members after overgrow got
popped and shut down Heaven Stairway got
popped and shut down um it was a private
refuge and it was kept priv
mostly secret like still a lot of a lot
of people that are on the forums had
never heard of it weren't invited there
you had to be invited by someone and
vouched for to even get in um and as of
January 1 it's open it's open to the
public so go check it out the canac
cab.com and it's great people there uh
me and CSI are going to be really active
there as much as we possibly can and uh
the people who run it Optimus Prime Dem
man skdy and curbside um they're all
legends in their own right like all
legends so it's it's it'll be an honor
to have them on and to be able to
discuss something that was so secret and
private for so long out in the open is
is a real treat and yeah I'm looking
forward to that so go check it out go
sign up great people great conversations
there lots of old data pictures um
strain
info the the what was it the
free-for-all FFA is on there which is an
old Mass Super skun Cross it was really
dank um that most people don't know
about pictures of that are on there too
and it was called freefor all because
everybody would pass it around it was
freefor all but then it got locked so
there is
that I just wanted to add as well that
it might seem odd
to uh I don't know talk about forums in
2023 but at the same time they are so
Superior when it comes to information
than you know over social media there's
just no there's no comparison also the
ways in which people can actually
discuss things you just don't get in
like an Instagram post or yeah so you
know I mean we have our Discord that we
talk about our patreon Discord where we
do stuff like that but the one thing I
want to say is a lot of people that
weren't around for the Forum era and
weren't a part of the Forum culture this
is your way to understand that kind of
culture that we talk about a lot like
how we interact with each other how we
build relationships and share clones as
opposed to like always trading or you
know selling clones I mean a lot of you
guys hear me I don't like selling clones
I don't like I don't like when people
have to go buy them because I know how
many people are out there scamming right
now versus even five years ago um a lot
of that stuff was given in past as Merit
to show I trust you you're my friend you
trust me this is how we're going to show
our trust and that kind of culture is
still alive there and if you want to
want to learn about it you want to
experience it um it's very alive there
and I can't
I can't give a stronger wreck to a place
than the
can and with that I mean do do you have
anything
else no that was that was it for me damn
smashed it out right um so with that we
have our breeder Syndicate patreon that
I just mentioned go to patreon.com
breeders Syndicate it's $5 a month and
basically that keeps most of the trolls
out if they make it in we still boot
them um we're being more aggressive
about uh making sure that it's a fun
environment and not and not depressing
because you know sometimes some people
can can take it there and we're we're
trying to to keep that that Vibe really
really really good and a part of that is
by keeping out trolls a lot of people
don't like that there is a dollar amount
with it but we try to make it affordable
to like less than a Starbucks coffee now
you know what I mean like for for a
month and uh you know we watch fights
together there we also have our our tier
where you can you know get packages
every three months or so and it comes
loaded it's really cool uh different
breeders you know a lot of its uh
unreleased stuff or soon to be relased
stuff that you get a first crack at so
check that out that's the top tier um
what else we have we have our our codex
obviously that we talked about codex.
the Breeders syndicate.com it's a
treasure Trove of information that we
are going to constantly be adding to
until the day I stop breathing so I'm
very proud of it I know thousand is I'm
proud of his work on it and all the time
that he put into making that beautiful
um what else do we have what am I
forgetting I know I'm forgetting
something oh the SE Banks yes we have uh
gir by seeds in Australia we have right
SEO Europe for uh our European fellas we
also have lifted seeds great guy out of
the NorCal um you can get our stuff in
there other people from The Syndicate
stuff there and we have of course Riot
seeds.com where you can get my reversal
spray that's where the gel s1's and
hybrids are and uh yeah there's all
kinds of other stuff there and if you're
part of the patreon you can save some
money up to 30% just for spending $5 a
month so that's a big big savings like
people use that all the time and uh it
works great so I think that's it I want
everyone to have a happy and safe new
year um and be good to each other unless
unless people are scumbags and don't be
good to
them that's
I guess uh yeah with that we'll see you
next week and that's
it want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it
out