welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
[Music]
revolution
welcome to BR Syndicate I'm Matthew with
my co-host thousandfold and today we're
going to be talking about uh what are we
gonna be talking about thousand we're
talking about Harvest and post Harvest
and we have the combined indoor and
outdoor Crews or at least some of them
from both Crews um so just to get us
started we wanted to talk about when do
you harvest and maybe we can start with
little
when do I harvest
um so I'm a little bigger scale at this
point um Harvest really needs to be
coordinated with a crew to help
Harvest and
also sometimes dry space comes into play
um so like on a on a light depth if if
it strains I know and and everything's
kind of
normal
um I don't really look at Triads too
much anymore with with the strains that
I know I just kind of know when they
look finished um and
uh generally I really like to let things
finish fully um like I don't want to
take you know Sour Diesel before Day 70
and if I can let it ride to 77 I
will
um but uh there's other things to take
into account sometimes um like you know
if you got your Harvest crew together
and it's day 74 like fine that that
works for me um uh but with like shorter
shorter flowering stuff like 60 days
nine weeks um I I got to know the strain
and and I and I want to make sure that
that bud is fully
swollen at that that point um I will
look at Triads if I don't know the
strain and as long as I see him turning
cloudy and I'm looking for mold you know
if I'm not seeing mold I'll let it ride
if I see start seeing like mold start to
come in then it's like okay like there's
a point of diminishing returns I need to
take it um so who cares if you're
harvesting right right moldy buds it
doesn't matter so um I mean those things
I take account and then on like the
full-term
stuff um kind of same thing like I know
it's like you know beginning of October
it's time to start checking for mold
depending on weather and when you're
taking in large harvests
um you know I'll take the colas first
because those are the first things that
are about to mold get those hanging let
the rest of the plant continue to
develop um and I can kind of just start
start like mowing through the garden
like that by taking tops the first thing
and then giving the rest of the plant
another week or 10 days or depending on
dry space um this this year was a bit
more he hectic than usual with all the
rain we got in October mold really
started to set in at some point and so
it was kind of like it it's molding it's
ready it's it's not going to get any
more ready and uh and so that that comes
into play and just filling up the dry
room getting it all down filling it up
again getting it all down filling it up
again like you don't quite get to like
pick and choose your day based
on you know whether you want cloudy
heads or Amber or or what you know um
you kind of got to go in space and labor
available um within range like if you
cut early you're just shooting yourself
in the foot with quality you're shooting
yourself in the foot for weight um you
got to wait for weight and uh so it's
It's always important not important not
to get like trigger happy with taking it
down uh but at the same time like
sometimes you can't wait as long as you
wanted to because you're not going to
have space or there's rain coming
or you know maybe you're not going to
have a harvest crew you know on certain
days so I think I don't know man
probably not the answer that most of you
wanted but that's like the reality of it
is at a at a certain scale you don't get
to pick and choose down to the day I
mean if I had it a perfect world I would
have unlimited dry space and I would
Harvest all my all my harvesting would
be done at
night
and you know that's just not how it
works I think it is really important to
point out that beyond the kind of like
ideal finishing time for plants there
are all these other competing pressures
uh that are possible as well whether
it's like whether your dry space is
ready or yeah I I'm I'm curious to hear
about other people's like logistical or
administrative pressures outside of like
ideal finishing time as well yeah I
think like on the completely opposite
end of that I uh like with the endoor
stuff I do more of like you know small
Perpetual hobby kind of situation and so
um I have just like 2x4 ENT that I dry
in and um I just kind of you know I
don't know I look at other things like I
look at the Tricom sometimes but more so
now I kind of look at just like if the
plant looks like it's done like and I
just mean kind of like um is it drinking
slower you know does it I mean you know
there's there just comes a point like I
think like when you run when you're
running if you're running the plants
enough you get to a point where you just
kind of see that like they're not
getting better you know what I mean like
there's like a point where if you just
run them longer like they can go longer
and they might get more Coler or
whatever but like for me personally like
um I just kind of look to when the plant
looks like it's kind of drinking slower
and um yeah I don't know I I just think
you just kind of get like a Vibe for
when the plant feels done I know that's
like kind of a vague answer but like
there's a point to it where it's like
you need to just run the plants a few
times and just get an idea of like what
when it's in a good
range yeah I'm kind of in a similar
position um I usually tend to take most
things nine to 10 weeks on average and
then other things like they'll get
bumped to like 12
weeks um I'll obviously like look at the
flower tricomes I have like a little
jewelers loop nothing too fancy
um but I try to go for majority milky
with like I don't know 25%
Amber um or sometimes I'm just like lazy
and let things go an extra week longer
or kind of just want to see where things
go um but yeah there I guess I kind of
just look for sence um and then as ER
mentioned um kind of um when like the
plant stops drinking or stops benefiting
from any additional feed and
whatnot but yeah that's kind of some
some of the general cues that I look at
for Harvest local I wanted to ask you
real quick um what are the just
generally speaking the recognized like
signs of
sence um so I kind of like a lot of it
kind of starts with like General like
fading and stuff like that I like
um some of the lowers will begin to fade
yellow but like the remainder of the
leaves will sometimes depending the
genetics shift colors and whatnot um
your plants will stop drinking I mean in
my experience um I haven't particularly
seen it in like the case of like either
outdoor growing or seed making but like
I don't know the the plant just
doesn't like really want much more it
kind of
seems there's no additional bulking
either um uh from my experience after a
certain point I guess very generally
speaking the principle is that it's it's
like metabolism is slowing right
overall
yeah yeah yeah you can actually you can
definitely see it in the
plant because it's like an open dialogue
with your plant you've been talking with
it and communicating with it all year
and when it starts slowing down you you
can definitely you can definitely catch
on to
it well to to ern's point
like if if you have a have that and to
your point too Kush like if you have
that relationship with it like the only
thing that really matters when it comes
to harvest is the end user and what high
they're trying to get from it what the
brain chemistry is and where they like
it at the end because I mean like there
used to be the old tale of like oh it
better be like 50% Amber 50% milky you
and then learn Amber means some
degradation with CBN or whatever else
comes along with that and you know maybe
people prefer like all Amber you know
maybe they like that side of it maybe
their brain chemistry maybe that makes
them happy and less anxiety but um yeah
I don't as I've gotten older and further
into this I kind of realized that like
the whole idea of an exact flower time
on anything is kind of
arbitrary yeah it's very subjective
there is no right perfectly right or
perfectly wrong answer for it it's very
very
subjective yeah and for me my like back
back when I was growing 12 or 14 clones
of the same thing growing that I like my
my Harvest used to be dictated on what
the weather was going to do like if I if
I looked at the weather and I saw six
days of an inch of rain coming for each
day and specifically with the cream the
cream could be cut at 55 at 57 days and
people would still love it everybody
everybody loved that stuff but I really
liked pushing it to 65 to 66 days where
it really shined and put on a little bit
of purple and and got its finishing but
um and then as the market changed and
I'm not growing one clone outdoors and
and going for maximum weight I started
growing varieties and just letting them
run to their full extent not not
worrying about the weather and my
Harvest change and I picked up a tool
that I really enjoy using and uh if
people have it in their budget it's just
a live view microscope um battery
operated or you can charge it and it has
a 9 inch monitor a little 9inch screen
monitor that you can tote around you
could take it down to the garden and
live view microscope your your resin in
bigger profiles not just uh you know you
can you can zoom in really far you could
look at it from a pullback perspective
but that that tool to me looking
looking at the plants maturity is always
always been something that I use for my
harvesting but lately like from from my
perspective and what I've looked at and
seen in my garden is I noticed the onset
of of Amber tricomes usually start on
the sugar leaves on the outside and work
their way in towards the butt and you
know some years workload gets heavy I'm
not going to microscope every plant I'm
not going to inspect every single bud
and a lot of the times I'll wait for
that uh March that that forward movement
of Amber tricomes to just touch the butt
so when I can see that it's Advanced up
the Sugar Leaf and is now there's a
little bit of Amber showing on the
actual flower itself that's that's just
kind of a baseline for something when I
want to
harvest but before when I was being
super meticulous about it um yeah like
I'd think something that I would aim for
is like 75% cloudy uh maybe just a
little bit clear and a little bit Amber
and then before before all that advanced
Tech and microscope and people
would say you know 50% Amber 50% cloudy
that was like as Matt was saying when I
first started growing outdoor that's
what everybody on the forums was saying
that's what that's what other people
were saying and um it was just kind of a
general rule of thumb and
then yeah I'm trying to think of an
example where I I think my so I got got
a brother who grows and he likes letting
his resin go Amber and he he feels like
it gives him a lot more couch lock a lot
heavier a lot more medicinal value out
of taking care of he's a he's a faer so
he's got aches and pains that I couldn't
even begin to
describe and uh you know working with
horses all day so he wants something
heavy hitting that knocks him out
something narcotic so he likes letting
his plants Go full Amber and uh as a
testament anytime I smoke his stuff it's
it's strong Stone stuff every single
time and that could be due to him
letting his plants mature pretty full
you
know and it it goes back to subjectivity
you know what you want uh changes for
for when you should
Harvest yeah so potentially this
decision can be quite a complex decision
um right because you have all these
like subjective preferences your
relative experience with those
particular plants you have these other
competing pressures whether or not
they're like environmental for you
Outdoors um or they have to do with like
your workers if you have a team of
people working for you and when they're
available and when you have the right Dy
space and it is really interesting I
didn't really think about it from that
point of view like that practically when
you are making the decision there are
all these other practical things that
come into play as
well yeah yeah and you can always make a
plan but executing the plan it almost
never seems to work out the way you want
it especially when it comes to
harvest you know you always you always
think it's going to happen this way and
it doesn't lay out in the exact perfect
uh way that you'd wish it P you know
something comes up you know family
member shows up or something happens on
the farm and everybody has to stop
everything and you know well your
workload for that day is done and you
know yeah you got that now you got to
all compile that on the the next day and
when you're dependent on the scale of
your operation sometimes you don't have
that extra day is worth of work to to to
offer especially with weather impending
and and other
issues did anyone want to speak to this
idea of like preference when it comes to
harvest and like particular experiences
where you've divert from that like sort
of guideline of you know Amber trike
balance you know are there particular
plants that you any of you grow that
like you know that's not GNA be the
case um specifically last year I had a
black cherry soda seed from a random
seed company that I just tried and about
week eight before like she still had
another week and a half to mature I'm
looking at it and I'm smelling the plant
and I'm looking at the bud structures
and I'm looking at the resin content and
I can kind of just tell it's not going
to be flower that I'm going to smoke and
that I'm going to enjoy and what I'll
what I did is I I checked the checked
the live scope of it saw that the resin
was all clear and I turned it all into
fresh frozen I had a buddy who who would
take it and turn it into live resin and
uh I could have let it mature further
but the i i the tur profile that it had
and its immaturity before it had its
chance to fully mature was was decent on
its own but I could tell that the flower
wasn't something that I would desire or
something that I would be able to get
rid of so I I you know took it all and
turned it into live live resin and it
was it it it it got consumed way more
actually you guys got to try some of
that at the uh at the party that was
some of that from that plant the live
resin that you guys got to try that uh
that and that was a a shot call that I
made a plant instead of letting it
mature fully I took it early and and
used the live resin off of it and it was
much more enjoyable that way than I
think the the actual flower would have
been I mean that's a that's a good
General point about like maybe knowing
what ideal final form um the product
will take like you know are you uh if
you are doing extracts does it change
this
decision right for example broadly like
do any of you who are you know into
Rosen and stuff have any thoughts on
this does it change your decision or I
don't know washing or
anything
all of my all of my concentration has
been like low scale like really small
personal use so and I'm still just kind
of messing around with it playing around
with bubble bags so I don't have any I
don't have any personal expertise on it
um yeah we need peaches here yeah I was
just gonna say we need we need peaches
to come and talk
about fill in fill us in on that
yeah I was just going to say I don't I
don't make any special hashes but I
assume there's a reason why like people
cut their plants down extremely early
like you know to get like nice white
hashed and stuff like that I don't know
because that looks pretty um but yeah
I'm not
entirely I'm the last person to talk
about that stuff I I do I have been told
by uh Rosen Rosen makers to uh I've been
told both by people making rosin like
don't cut it down early cut it down when
it's
mature because they don't care as much
about color they say color doesn't
really matter on the quality and then
other people are like it does matter
let's let's chop it 10 days early let's
chop it a week
early um because it'll be lighter
colored and that'll help sell it because
for some reason I guess the custies want
you know that clear you know really
light colored Ros
as opposed
to um any anything that's darker or more
Amber um again I'm not really a Rosen
smoker so I don't have a preference but
mentioned that she didn't think it was
good like she felt like it was purely
like a fashion thing or like a you know
just what people expected kind of
thing I definitely in small scale
personal use like kind of stuff but you
know like I I have the press and stuff
so I've done a bit of it and like just
from like the general Vibe of people
like talking to people that are really
into rosin it seems like
um uh the harvesting for color and stuff
is literally just like something that
has been pushed by like big companies
like seven1 labs and stuff like that
that you know make rosin and sell it to
you know dispensaries and stuff like
that and that generally you know good
plants make like like stuff that you
would want to smoke in flow is what you
want to make rosin out
of yeah I had a i in two years ago I
grew some lemon parties and I had uh s1s
I grew five of them and I had two that
were fairly similar they weren't
identical but side by side they were
pretty hard to tell apart and uh I let
one of them go like 70 60 70% Amber uh I
let it mature and I let the other this
it sister plant next to it I pulled it a
little bit earlier and uh I remember
pressing rosin from both of those plants
and continually getting people telling
me that I should put a warning label on
the rosin that I let go 80 to 90% Amber
triome it was I continually had people
saying hey man that that stuff is too
strong my husband was passed out on the
couch for two hours drooling on himself
you know I had I had people telling me
that that I should warn them about
giving them that specific rosin from
that so uh there's a little anecdotal
evidence about you know choosing to let
the resin mature a little bit longer for
some of the concentrates but that being
said I see more people want the either
live resin or fresh press uh stuff
that's a little more battery little more
white has stronger tur profiles people
seem to be more interested in that than
and rosin that packs a heavy punch at
least from in from what I can
see I put myself in that category um
usually like when I'm assessing up until
like maybe even I don't know a month or
two ago I would find myself assessing
extracts why their scent like their
inherent scent of just smelling them you
know like oh this one's super tury but
as I found out a lot of these like the
scent is only like released once you
activate it like some of them are real
tur but you just don't inherently smell
that and I think since it's like most
people's first experience with hashes
you pick it up the first thing you do is
smell it that's probably why that's a a
big deal and seeing it obviously like I
guess they make machines now to strip
the color out of hash which blew my mind
that that's a thing yeah and so they're
I think they kind of push this narrative
that it's like clean quote unquote that
if your hash is um clear like white like
lighter colored that it's cleaner um and
I I don't know you can interpret clean
however you want to you know I'm not
really sure what that means but um yeah
I mean I think the general Vibe is like
if you're going to make hash like grow
your plant and to its maximum potential
make it the best that you can and that
will make the best concentrate that you
can
make the old theory of in out
yeah well it feels like we're sort of
like rounding out this section on like
Harvest timing I wanted to ask if yall
had any good stories about you know that
whether like uh horrifically early
horrifically late why I don't know
anyone like a a bad a early Harvest or
like a forced late Harvest or something
like that yeah I guess so yeah
uh and was there anything you could do
to like you know
uh mitigate it in any way or I don't
know soften the blow or I'm so used to
like early seed Harvest as opposed to
just like flower or late flower harvests
like getting the jump on harvesting
seeds was always my issue like you see
them forming and sometimes they look
more mature than they actually are and
like you know in the early days I would
just pick seeds off the top and look at
it be oh it's Brown mature okay hack and
then like you hack it all down and
there's like three mature ones on top
and the rest are just but as far as
flower it's kind of different
yeah yeah I mean say definitely had some
bad
Harvest what's your worst do you think
like out of all the uh the the worst
Harvest was a long time
ago um it was due to a cold room and I
had switched from soil with
Coco and it was the W the winter came it
was my first run in
Coco uh the plants were off the floor
but I the room was still just too damn
cold at night
especially and then it wasn't heating up
like it had been in the summertime
during the day so
uh and it was also the first winter run
at this place so yeah it the roots were
just cold the plants were just like all
leaf with like you know just
skinny skinny narrow
buds um real
bummer um real but my first that was my
first bad Harvest where like yield was
like crap quality was
crap um it was also my last Harvest at
that place I bet there for like a year
but yeah I mean lesson learned
um and uh moved on but
like yeah man environment was super I
mean I was I was fairly new to growing
at that point I was still maybe like six
years into growing now maybe like five
years four years but it was my first
time just dealing with bigger rooms and
and different envir this was a basement
grow so it was just cold in general so
like it would never you know the lights
were on at night but it still wouldn't
get that warm in there and then the
lights were off all day and it would
just be freezing in there yeah even
during the day so I don't know that was
my worst Harvest ever for sure I mean
that's not like
super obvious to a lot of people like
that you know if it gets super cold your
on your roots that you know it's going
to get a lot more leafy and thinner
shitty Buds and you know a lot of us are
used to dealing with the heat you know
right and that's what I was dealing with
All Summer in that place and working on
heat issues and trying to keep it cool
during the night cycle and cool during
the day or during the um light cycle and
man uh yeah cold cold Roots um I would
say is more important than ambient
temperature is your root temperature
yeah they're just not GNA metabolize
nutrients they're not going to dry out
as fast easier to overwater sure um just
all those things it's it's more
important and I found that even to this
day in in in the green houses is I don't
care how cold it as outside as much as I
care about the root
temperature and uh and getting that up
and and figuring out how to manipulate
that it's it's it's massively more
important than ambient temperature as
long as you're talking cold now if it's
too hot that's different yeah like an
ambient temperature definitely matters
but as far as coldness goes like I mean
it can be 55 degrees ambient temperature
but if the roots are at 45 you're
you know of the questions I get
uh in DMS about harvesting are can I
save like that my room is like 109 you
know can I do anything with these Buds
and I'm just like like you know
like it's kind of hard done yeah yeah
yeah yeah I was just gonna add that uh
ever since I transitioned to LEDs that's
like the first time I had to like
actually warm my grow space at night
especially like here in the Midwest
where it gets like cold um and
yeah I don't know it just it comes with
its own set of problems and and that's
one of them that I noticed as well is
just like having to keep the rooms warm
at night relatively speaking so you
don't run to those into those issues
yeah I've never lived anywhere where I
needed a a heater ever in a grow so that
growing in a cold situation to me would
be totally counterintuitive like I'm
always trying to make it cooler you know
so what's a dangerous or what would you
all determine to be a dangerous root
Zone temp a little Hill you mentioned
like 45 is that already like quite
extreme is there
a yeah that would be way too cold it
might vary in green between greenhouse
and
indoor I might be able to get away with
a little bit cooler um in a greenhouse
as long as I'm getting good
sunlight but I I would say like
55 55 is is good enough I mean you could
probably work with 50 but 55 and then
like in summertime it'll be over 60
65 um and that's that's fine I think I I
really don't check conversion too much
say what I just had to do a Celsius
conversion okay that's that's quite oh
yeah sorry I can't help you with that I
got we're Americans we don't use those
silly
things Fahrenheit all day
do you remember how like when people
wanted during the the first purple craze
like people really like were like
feeding ice water to their Roots yeah
yeah I remember that with ice and
Koolaid people pouring Koolaid during
the flush that's during the flush last
couple
weeks um I never did that um
but I did it work uh you know not really
not particularly um it had to be like a
per I was trying it on like OG Kush and
stuff like of course it wasn't going to
go purple you know no yeah they I heard
of that but then people got air
conditioners and I was in the Bay Area
at the time where where where I was at
in the Bay Area nobody had air
conditioners in their house because it
was never more than 75 degrees it seemed
and uh and it would cool off at night
always even in the summer so but yeah
then people started getting air
conditioners for their indoor setups and
could really turn the temps down on them
and I think that's all you really need
along with a good flush just the
flushing alone brings the color out yeah
it does and then you just add cooler
Temps at night and I think that's when
you really get them to purple up strong
and yeah and uh yeah the the old the old
techniques for purpling there's there's
a couple techniques out there I've
probably forgotten a few there's I had a
Dude any of it anymore they got I mean
with with genetics
now like
I I can light depth stuff where it's 95
degrees out every day and it still
purples up yeah yep yeah people people
have figure that out genetics wise have
you ever heard about the car battery
hooked up to the uh plant to shock it
purple what the yeah yeah that's
that's one I had actually heard like the
guy I think he interpreted shocking the
plant as far as temperatures and in his
brain he thought it meant shocking he
thought it literally me shock wow we
talked about this in the I think me ER
local and farm and Dan talked about like
different forms of
violence being applied to puns and like
what that
means that's definitely one definitely
one another thing too I've messed around
with just like you know in that same
vein is um in the winter time it gets
really cold here you know so I'll I've
like vented like pulled uh like fresh
air in from outside into my tent you
know like super cold air um I don't know
I'm not really sure if it you know I'm
not I I don't have enough experience to
be like this does this you know what I
mean it feels like you're doing
something though so it seems like a cool
thing to try I don't
know I think that sums it up yeah that's
about how it feels you know what I mean
yeah the same reason I put copper coils
in my this year
outdoor you know why not
all right I'm gonna move us on I'm gonna
move us on
to how do you harvest I.E so I think
kush or the Giants had a couple of like
questions here like what time of the day
you know and I guess for indoor grows
it's like do you think that it's better
to chop in the dark and this and that so
yeah we can move on to that that's also
the like do you wet trim do you dry trim
like all that stuff all that good stuff
BL washing BL washing okay who do I get
to start this let's go for Kush of the
Giants to start this one yeah yeah for
sure so um for me like what what I've
noticed in my garden is like if I go out
to my plants and I try tying them up
let's say in the the evening time or in
the middle of the day hottest part of
the day or in the evening time and I'm
tying up some branches and I get a
little too too handsy with one and it
snaps it's real brittle and it just it
just cracks um I've I've noticed that
that that
plasticity is it has more plasticity
after she's just had her water her her
her drinking so in the morning there
there's two times that I've noticed in
my garden um one is like maybe an hour
before direct sunlight actually hits
them they drink they soak up they all
perk up and then the Sun comes and then
they they endure the heat of the day and
then on my uh trail camera through my
time-lapse videos I saw right around
midnight 1:00 a.m. in the morning they'd
all do the same thing they'd all perk
back up they all the fan Leafs had lift
up and it looked like there was a second
drinking phase going on during the
middle of the night and um so in my mind
I like to chop after the plants have had
a chance to drink so whether that be the
morning just before the Sun hits them or
late at night after they've had chance
to get a drink in them the branch
plasticity they don't break as easily
they're not as brittle and in my mind I
think that there's just more hydration
there's more fluid there's more water
going up the plant and so in in hang
what we most of us like to do is we like
to get a longer hang out of our plants
so the the more moisture that you have
in your branches and in your fan Leaf uh
the the longer hang you'll get out of
out of your cure and so so to me I'm
maximizing how much uh how I can slow
down the process of the moisture and the
chlorofil evaporating out of my plants
that are all hanging on lines in my room
so I uh I've been aiming to harvest
after I've noticed that the plants have
had their drink when when there's more
plasticity in the branches when they
don't just snap and are super brittle
like I noticed in In the Heat of the day
or uh or in the late evenings before
they've they've had a chance to rest and
drink um those are the times that I like
to pull my plants down um as far as wet
trimming and dry trimming I used to I
used to take a lot of fan Leaf off um
before like I I didn't have any real set
methods I I'd read on the forums and I'd
talk to my brother and ask other people
what they do and everybody you know it's
very subjective everybody has their own
specific way and they think that their
way is the best way and I just started
playing around with different methods
and what I've noticed is uh harvesting
bigger sections of the plant uh and
leaving more fan leaf on gives me a
longer cure uh it lets me hang on the
line longer it instead of like a a nine
or a 10 day hang on the line it'll push
it out to 12 or 14 days hanging on the
line before I want to go in there and
and start bucking it down and taking it
off the line and getting it ready to go
either in a a big jar or a big old
turkey bag depending on how big my plant
is so that I'm I'm
processing um and then as far as like
um there's a little bit of a topic we
want to talk about people are thinking
about Bud washing but for me like you
know people dunking their plants and
cleaning it off before Harvest like I do
a lot of uh microscoping and I I spend a
lot of time looking in on the plants on
the flowers on the leaves on the butt
and I don't see near enough dirt I don't
see near enough insect uh shells or
frass or or husks I don't see enough
stuff on the plant to Warrant doing any
washing hydrogen peroxide dipping or any
of that stuff that I've seen people
doing so as for me personally in my
garden I get enough late season rains
that it it does a good job of cleaning
the plants off from the from the ambient
dust that that settles on them
how about you little
Hill um I mean
ideally I would do things different
but yeah I'd like to night Harvest
harvest in the cool air you know I just
think that's it's easier on people I
know Vineyards down south of me they do
a lot of harvesting um at nighttime and
a big reason they do it yeah there's
like they're dealing with the different
levels of the sugar and the acid but
like a huge reason they do it is just
heat like having the workers out there
all day in the heat is rough and yeah
and and for them it's also a marathon
it's not a Sprint so you can't you can't
beat the out of your crew you know
on a tough three-day Harvest and then
you know do it again you know and again
for like you know six weeks um so yeah
we start early in the
morning
um and we Harvest all day um just
depending on what's going on we might
take a break if it's if it's super hot
like we'll take a break in the middle of
the day for like two three hours just
during the hottest part of the day and
then Harvest till tarps at 7 um but you
know I
yeah I don't wash anything um um I do
like the plants to be I don't want the
plants to be parched at all um whether
they got watered that morning or the day
before as long as they're they're good
um I'm fine as long as they're not
droopy and Limp um I'm fine with that
um you know packing it in being
efficient with Space is really
important
um but
uh yeah I I've heard of people letting
the plants dry out like in in their you
know pots or you know like giving them
some I've I've heard of that um I've
never done it neither it just doesn't
seem right to me to have a stressed
plant it's not going to like whatever
potential it has of you know cannaboid
content
tpin I think it I think it would be best
to catch it in the morning when it's
nice and healthy and hydrated just
that's just what makes sense to me I
don't have any data to back any of this
up but my intuition tells me that yeah
um so I've heard I've heard you know
drought stressing at the end can help
bring out more you know maybe that's
true maybe it's not um but I mean if
they die on the branch isn't that like
oxidizing your
bud like because it's me it would that
process starts in the sun basically
that's you definitely don't want
light gold right totally
um uh what one thing about the bud
washing is like I mean that shouldn't be
a thing at all for indoor Growers but no
and honestly I don't know anybody that
does
it on any type of
outdoor um though I would question why
they do it but I have heard it actually
it increases oxidation
and your your turns brown faster
I've just heard that um I don't know it
for a fact but you know I've heard it
from people that tried it I don't know
like I mean peroxide is gonna oxidize
like Yeah by definition yeah totally
it's an oxidizer so y yeah I don't I
don't know about that
um you know what something all this all
this weed that I've been getting from
dispensaries all looks super hella
oxidized and I just realized that like
oh that's probably why you know
like it might just be
old that for sure is it outdoor or
indoor well it sold as it's sold as
indoor in myars but it was definitely
outdoor like part part of the time some
of this stuff is definitely outdoor I
know um like it's it's it's November you
can look at Harvest sometimes they have
the harvest date on the package you can
look at the harveste I the Harvest dates
were so close to when they were bought
that it was just like okay and I'm
looking at oxidized weed and Going H H
this is out none of this makes any sense
yeah what was Lo gonna say I was gonna
say that a lot of people remediate it
with like X-rays and like that um I
mean at least that's what I've seen here
in my state in the legal market so
they're doing it there they radiation
yeah so they do it to lower like tym
counts and bacterial counts um
I've been getting a lot of questions on
Reddit about that and the Australian
Reddit ask me anything I'm doing and
like they're like hey so what's your
opinion on irradiated weed and I was
like huh what what yeah I mean it just
like overall kills the character of the
weed in my opinion but it like gives
them clean results you know what I mean
and that's what matters in the legal
games that and you can grow a third
testicle after you
smoke yeah I mean what happens if you
smoke a bacteria any type of bacteria
nothing I mean right it's like we've
bought weed like that's likely been
worse than what we see like on these
panel tests you know and fingernails
come in my brick weed man yeah I'm
totally fine um I don't know it's just
people want to make money I guess it
like I don't know
look too much yes I
agree I was going to invite local to
kind of carry on just talk about some of
the other questions that you all have
answered about like when do you chop and
you know trim that um so one um I kind
of like to chop my stuff and the more
like not the morning but like once the
lights kind of go off so like that's my
morning I guess um just cuz like you
know I mean not directly after it's
turned off but once like kind of all the
heat has emitted from the room and stuff
CU there's like residual heat from like
the lamps and stuff um but um yeah I
kind of um I don't want my plant to be
entirely dry but I don't want it to be
soing wet um but I I like to do little
things to kind of prolong the amount of
time that it's going to take to dry so
like I won't like uh wet trim or
anything like I'll leave all the leaves
on um
you know I mean I have an AC in the room
so that really helps keep temperatures
cool that wasn't the case at my last
place um but that's like a game Cher um
it's kind of added like five it could
add up to five days te your dry if you
want it to you know depending on how
cold you get um but also like it was my
summer so it was cool but it was also
like not like humid but it wasn't as dry
as it should have been per se
um but yeah really anything to minimize
the amount of uh or maximize the the
amount of time that it takes to dry um
and I'll usually kind of um judge that
once like the branches not like branches
but like the the buds will snap from the
main branch itself because like I find
that that main branch holds some
moisture um and I don't want that to be
entirely dry because that just like kind
of signifies that the the buds that kind
of dry out I would say they dry out
faster than the actual
stock um but like I I don't want my
stock to be too dry but
like yeah I don't know um I like them to
have snappage a little bit of crunch to
the bud
um but yeah
um what's your take on
washing I've never had to wash bud
before um I could see why people would
do it outdoor like say there's like dust
storms or like you know the the fires
and in California like all the
smoke and dust particles like that can
make a need for wash but I don't know I
liked what um when we were talking about
this earlier what Chris the giant said
and if you want to repeat that a little
bit cuz the Giant's talking about the
logic behind dipping in the same Barrel
yeah so like in in the examples that
I've seen um washing it's generally a
guy washing all of his plants from the
whole harvest in a single like 40 or 50
gallon all of barrel drum and in my mind
when I see that my first thought is okay
your your argument is you're washing
dust off and you're washing insects and
and uh frass and husks and and wings and
shells of insects that have died and
left carasses on your on your thing and
my first thing is I'm watching these
guys and they're dunking them back to
back to back and you're not giving
enough time for the dust to or the dirt
to settle so it's it's basically a
slurry of dirt now your your water
hydrogen mix or whatever medium mix that
they've done um and then the second
thing is the corpses though that insect
frass is going to float to the top and
so every time you dunk your branch in
you're Brea dunking it on a pile of dead
corpses and then mixing it in a dirt
slurry just the whole the whole
Logistics behind it never made any sense
to me every time every time I've seen
those videos or those pictures it looks
like they're just all dunking it into
one barrel as fast as they can handing
it to the person and then putting it on
the line and that's that's just crazy to
me another thing I noticed in these like
the red amas were that a lot of people
don't understand that like before
they're big
like you know let's say someone has a
question about you know growing 20 acres
outdoor and they're you know they have
questions about you know like should
should I you know dry this or cure this
in glass or blah blah blah and it's like
you didn't think about where you're
going to dry that before you grew
it like that should be a major major
major thought where the am I gonna
dry all this you know but most
people it seems like a lot of these
Chads that started the hemp you know
and got into it they didn't even
take that into count like where
where are we going to dry it do we got
like a garage that could be enough you
know like right I don't know that's
something I've noticed too people don't
take that
uh that's that's been many pot growers
failure of harvest is not accounting for
where they're going to dry it or like
drying it in carports or Y yeah hemp
Farmers some of them thought they could
just cut it and let it dry
outside you know some of them some of
them thought that they could roll it
there was some company going out there
convincing people you could just roll it
wet into like this giant roll like a
bail of like a bail of hay or something
nice yeah I believe I remember that
company's not around anymore because it
didn't
work yeah but like I've seen people fail
i' I've seen people fail with yielding
more than they thought they would yeah
um and and and not accounting for dry
space and just having shitty dry space
like having to put up car ports to dry
in yeah and then just not having the
like gumption to realize that maybe you
should try and insulate it or you
know you're not even using that space
efficiently to hang as much as you can
in there and and uh it it's it's
definitely a failure not knowing where
you're going to dry and that and that
can happen indoors too you sure you you
know you you trick out your little your
grow tent or your room and then you
realize that like oh I got to spend 10
more days hanging it in here because
it's GNA stink at my house if I move it
anywhere else and or
uh yeah you need like a separate dry
tent you need you know just like you
need a separate veg area yes if if you
want to if you really want to to to to
to repack that room as fast as
possible um how much space would you
give like let's say you're growing let's
say it's a 10 lighter right how much
space would you want to incorporate for
this 10 lighter for your drying space
what would you guys
recommend I would say about a third of
that space so like if you're in a I mean
what's what's a 10 lighter like a 10 x
20 room or something like that something
like that um that's that's what 200 feet
200 square feet so a third of that would
be like 66 square feet yeah cuz if like
you figure you have one
canopy uh over 10 lights but if you
stack it three High then you should be
able to get away with thir space right
absolutely yeah yeah it's a good rule of
THB too there there's probably some
better calulations on that um I I I
really just kind of like got a ballpark
it like I don't even have any real
calculations on on on space like I know
when I have enough and I know when I
don't yeah and I kind of Base it off of
Old rooms old dry barns like okay I had
this many lines or this much like like
linear feet of line to hang on I need
that same to hang you know one green
house or two green houses and that's
kind of how I've gone in the past
general like ballpark guessing and and I
definitely didn't have enough
space hang dry room set up I just wanted
to let Erin answer the questions first
because then the next section is going
to be all on like the actual dry and
like quote unquote cure process um yeah
so er did you want to speak to the
earlier questions about chop times I
don't I don't think I have very much to
add I think you guys hit all the points
that I would hit as well as far as
cutting the plants I mean you know I
just want them to look Rick I'm ready
and I you know I like to just be
prepared have everything there and I
want to be able to be
like cutting them and hanging them and
all that stuff done as fast as possible
I don't want to be messing around with
the plants that's the only thing I would
add otherwise that's pretty much
it okay nice okay sorry little Hill yeah
we can now talk about like the actual
you know drying and you know quote
unquote curing uh dry room setups all
that yeah this is f so I I'll just say
that um I do my drying in the fridge uh
some of you know that I you
know am under like quite serious spatial
constraints so I can only flower a few
things at a time I can keep a few things
like a few more things than that but I
can really only flower a few things at a
time um and so I actually dry my stuff
in the fridge uh which some of you know
about um and on the Discord like there's
a whole Channel about drying in the
fridge and what that is um but just
wanted to mention that as like a point
of difference
here I was also gonna just answer that
question Matt asked about like Dry size
to like the size of your room on a much
smaller scale uh because I don't have a
tin lighter I just have a one lighter
and a five by five and uh I I go into a
two by4 with that which I think pretty
much falls into the a third of your
space um as well so I think that's like
a really Great rule of thumb just to hit
that nail on the head again y yeah the
third of your space is a great rule of
thumb but also like continually me and
me and little Hill were talking about
this just last night is like when you
when you're sizing up like if you have
the option to build your your dry room
always add like another 20 or 25% on top
of what you think you need like every
single time I've set up a grow room and
or I picked a spot in the basement and I
set up lines I'm looking at it I'm like
yeah this is good and then Harvest comes
and like I could always use like
two or three more lines there's there's
never been a time where it's like I
couldn't have used the extra space so if
if you have the ability to I would say
build it bigger than your initial
thoughts are and and it you'll see the
benefits of it I'm almost guarantee it
do any of us here have a different
opinion than drying slower and
deliberate is better like I know the uh
one of the episodes I interviewed
someone and they said they like to use a
dehydrator and um does anybody else uh
have a different method than slow and
deliver
it I mean I've heard of people using
freeze dryers for flow but I've not had
I've no never had it never had any
experience with it um but I think that
that is something that's out there as
far as a super fast option but you know
yes low and slow is the name of the game
I think yeah I'll add that that's kind
of the whole point of the fridge thing
as well I know that for some people it's
like weird Fringe idea and I don't I
personally can't say anecdotally that I
know it's any bitter than hanging um but
it's kind of what I'm constrained to
doing at the moment um but the principle
is the same the longer you can draw out
that process the better yeah you're ex
it's an exchange process and the slower
The Exchange process of moisture and
chlorophyll is the better the end
product is and that's that's not I'm not
saying this is scientific this is just
what I've noticed from my flowers from
my garden that I hang and I trim if they
have a if if they have a longer chance
to hang on the line before branches are
brittle enough to snap clean with no
fibers I'm the people will say oh yeah
it snaps clean and I'll snap it but
there's still a fiber hanging on I'm
like that's not clean no it needs to be
an ual clean snap like if you held up a
light and you moved the and you moved a
branch too much you're going to see some
THC flutter off into the air like it
should be at a point where it's that
that far gone in my opinion before but
at least that's what I like when I'm
trimming my stuff down yep um and me and
little were just talking about this last
night as well there there's something
that people don't uh don't consider is
you'll go into your hang room and a lot
of people use these totes I see them
everywhere this 55 gallon totes with the
yellow Lids they'll take their stuff off
the line stuff them into the totes put a
lid on it and say yeah I'm going to trim
this in an hour or two and then they
don't get around till to tomorrow and
that time it spent in the tote
rehydrated it and now you're working
with a little bit wetter weed than what
you would normally like to to trim with
like people you know so you can think
that it's fully out of moisture throw it
all in a tote and then it it starts to
rehydrate on itself a little bit because
it's now working with a smaller
atmosphere it's now it's now has more
moisture in a smaller area um yeah so
for me I've always aimed for lower and
slower um and it's just benefited me and
the last six or seven years I've had the
awesome benefit of when I chop like the
when I'm chopping it's also
simultaneously raining outside so my
barn gets a little moisture boost boost
and the the ambient moisture fills the
barn and then F also affects the the
grow room that I had built inside inside
of the barn so or the Hang room that I
built inside of the
barn yeah I mean and that's for me
that's been a benefit with the using my
like using like a 2x4 tent in my
scenario I I it's like a Perpetual thing
and I have the environment pretty much
controlled at a certain place that I
wanted at so I kind of just let myself
hang for um you know like it it may take
say two weeks to dry out but I'll let it
hang another week or two uh just hanging
in there and then um and then I you know
when I'm ready to that like like for me
what that allows me to do is like just
slowly work through each plant and as
far as like trimming or however you want
to you know do that and then I go into
like I like the mason jars that have um
they're like amber colored you know uh
to like cut out light degradation
um obviously if you're doing a ton of
stuff that's probably not they're like $
Five Doll a jar now so it's probably not
great but for my skill it's you know I
really like
them so no dehydrator tech for you er no
dehydrator I mean I'm shooting for as
long as possible but I'm not doing any
weird like burping or anything like that
generally speaking I I'm just trying to
leave it alone as much as
possible yeah so we all agreed generally
that longer and slower is better um so
with that what's the average in your
room setup like if and and there's also
there's also a little Aster to this
question as well because I my personal
uh hang room is like a 25 by3 room and
if I were to hang let's say only three
plants on one end of the room and don't
H and I don't fill the rest of the room
it's a totally different exchange of
than than if I were to stuff the room
complet
so um yeah there there's there's a
little bit of a Nuance to discuss there
about um the in your your hang room will
act different depending on how many
plants you have stuffed in there and
that's something that you should plan in
your Harvest depending on if you're
harvesting everything at once or if
you're staggered harvesting this is
something that you should and not only
that but let's say like in my room I
have uh 14 or 15 lines and I put them in
at the back and I harvest Pally and and
hang them in sometimes the plants that
are done in the back when I bring in a
fresh set of plants for uh on row number
eight or nine those back plants will get
a little moisture refresh and so the
question I want to pose is generally
what if if there's no outside
environmental factors about how many
days does it take in your room before
branches are snapping off clean and
you're ready to Buck down for me it's
about 12 to 13 and if I have rain
outside from the environment it's it's
usually a couple days extra on top of
that sometimes I'll get 14 14 days out
of the Hang before I'm going in there
and saying hey I should I should start
bucking this stuff down for me it's a 14
to eight like anal
21 somewhere in there for
indoor I think I'm more like I'm like 10
to
14 um the the I I've de I'll definitely
rehydrate the room at some point if I if
I like fill one half up wait seven days
then fill the other half up it's going
to be longer than 10 for that first half
yeah that happens all the time to me and
I don't mind it it just slows it down so
I'm fine with it I mean I'd like to get
things moving but you know you can't
really Rush that part yeah
um so yeah 10 to 14 I'd say I don't want
them to get too dry on the line it
depends a lot on whether like what kind
of plant you cut like do you have a lot
of thick colas or are they like longer
extended branches with just golf balls
up them good point because obviously
those dry a little faster um and and I
pack I pack my weed in so much that like
I might have you know six to 10 lines
vertically going in each section six six
to nine lines deep so it's like a wall
of
weed with another wall of weed nine
inches behind it and another wall of
weed because I'm only cutting like maybe
12 inch to to 18 inch branches at the
most yeah that's what like like that's
the size Branch everything is whether
it's a lower Branch or or a center Cola
so you know packing it in like you know
my my humidity skyrockets up to possibly
up to 80h and then you know it just
ticks down every day after that um
usually at the beginning I'll run an
extra dehumidifier or something just to
cut it a little bit faster to get it
into the 60s yeah and then after that I
slow it down because I don't want it to
get you know into the low 50s or 40s um
at least not for too long um right at
the end that's fine but uh you know if
you leave it in that kind of like low
humidity for too long it gets brittle
hly I think you're just yeah I think I
think I don't think you're you're
helping yourself you're you're probably
uh you're probably evaporating turpins
at that point and uh the temp
temperature- wise I'm I'm always in the
60s um usually mid to high
60s um I know a lot of people say that's
not ideal but like I've I've
Cur I've I've dried in all types of room
uninsulated um in wintertime you know
uninsulated in
summertime uh I've done it all different
types of ways and there's all different
types types of uh tricks to slow it down
but that but like you know I used to use
an evaporative cooler to cool my dry
barn and it worked like it would drop
the temperature in there 10 degrees and
it would add a little bit of humidity
too yeah in summertime when humidity is
you know 20 25% in the day like that
that extra humidity was almost nothing
but it was still something yeah and it
still was able to slow it down and cool
it down and uh you know I still I still
dried good weed in that Barn in
summertime and then it's the exact
opposite problem in winter time or or in
fall you're you're trying to heat it but
you're also trying to you got to have it
warm enough in there to run the
dehumidifiers because your dehumidifiers
might only work down to 50 degrees or
something and uh you you know it's much
cold colder than that at night so I
don't know just always uh I have a
climate controlled barn now so that's
like that's nice really nice it's nice
it was ALS it's also like it was also a
new thing to learn because I was I was
so used to hustling it and and back in
the day like that trying to keep your
barn warm enough like that definitely
you were slow drying and it was nice
because you it really worked out well
even though you're
you're you're hustling it the whole time
so um working with uh air conditioners
and and large dehumidifiers was also
something to learn because you can overd
drry your pretty quick oh yeah um
if if you don't stay on top of it and uh
so that's one thing I like to do is as
soon as I think it's ready there's
moisture meters you can buy I don't use
one anymore before the fire I did I lost
it in the fire and I just never replaced
it um they they're used to uh measure
the moisture of lumber or firewood yep
and if you really want to get anal about
it you can put the two little prongs on
that moisture meter on the stem on the
actual bud stem though just to see where
you're at so you can have a number and I
know people have used these things for
uh for helping their workers get the
feel for it oh interesting so they can
look at a number instead of just getting
a feel for it or get the feel for it and
then look at the number to corroborate
like okay that's what 10% or 12% feels
like um those were kind of helpful for
training people at one point I don't
really do it anymore I feel like the
people I have doing it have have have
the feel for it and I've showed them and
and they understand they understand the
whole thing about like what kush was
saying talking about where you might
have crispy Buds and your stems might
snap a little bit or maybe they don't at
all but just because your buds are
crispy doesn't mean your plants dry in
fact you want to slow that process down
because all your water is moving from
the main stem to the to the secondary
stem to the bud stem to the flow and
then out into the atmosphere as soon as
you seal it
up everything's going to redistribute
it's all the moisture is going to
redistribute evenly in that sealed
environment
and so you can all that so all that
little extra water is going to move
through the flower into the
atmosphere and so that flour is going to
get mushy
again and if you're trying to store weed
for any period of time if you store it
wet it's gonna oxidize way faster y it's
gonna it's gonna smell like hay it's
gonna turn brown fast and you just did
all that work for nothing
so figuring out when to seal it and it
can be used as a trick to get just like
a little bit of that extra water out of
the stem is just to seal it overnight
and then boom open it the next day draw
it out you know flowers might go from
mushy to crispy that's fine you only
sealed it for like you know 12 hours and
then seal it up again and then check it
12 hours later to make sure you're still
crunchy and then you know you're good
and you can do it again if you're really
trying to dry it out and store it for a
long Peri periods like if you know it's
going to be stored for multiple months
yeah um which is something a lot of
outdoor Growers do is they don't sell
their they don't sell their Harvest till
you know six months later after they
harvest it yeah and that's a good way to
keep the color keep the smell um but
it's it's definitely at scale it's
definitely a trick it's a lot of extra
work if you it up because then you
have to go burping you know 50 bins and
who's got space even to B to put 50
bends out you know space is a premium
and and uh so like hitting it and
checking it to make sure you did hit it
the next day is is really really
important and once they get sealed up in
those bins you got to make sure your
outside the bin environment is not extra
moist or extra cold um you of course you
want it cool but you don't you got to
watch the humidity yeah um I think out
outside humidity only really matters if
it's too High cuz they will it's not
really sealed like it's got time
everything's going to equalize between
your room your and what's inside your
bin because it's not really really
sealed um so you want to keep all those
things in check so it doesn't re go
regaining moisture which which which it
absolutely will do if you let it get you
know more humid in your room or
cold um also if you're sealing in
plastic jars are great that's why jars
are great because they're impermeable
you're not going to regain any moisture
but if you're in Turkey bags like you
need three turkey bags to actually have
it sealed for moisture and smell for
that matter and if you're vacuum sealing
you need at least two layers yeah I was
going to say I I've seen dudes like
Harvest and what they'll do is like you
know stuff it all in those really thin
plastic like Ziploc bags like the
sandwich baggies that aren't for a
freezer but like real thin and they'll
sell it like that and you know you get
it you put it in your jars and then all
of a sudden a day later everything's
like moist and because there's still
some air Exchange in those thin baggies
so keep that in mind too like if people
are putting in thin baggies like
it's not it's not a good measure for if
it's dry or not there's a lot of
moisture that can be kept in there and
appear
dry there are two things that I wanted
to talk about um one of them is um the
different types of Bud and the
preference in how wet or how dry I want
them when I'm trimming them for example
before before we go on this coach can we
hear from like local and Ern about yeah
absolutely for Lo um I was just gonna
say I I really don't have much to add
here um if if Kush was
gonna um go on ahead and speak but I'm
also not speaking for earn
yeah yeah I mean it's kind of the same I
wanted to Echo just what kush said about
like um how many plants you have in your
dry face because I'm sorry my dogs are
talking if you guys hear
that but um the what I used to try to
like Harvest out of my 5x5 and dry in my
5x5 and um like as your plants lose a
little bit of water weight you know
after like the first day or so it's like
they don't take up that much room in
there and I found that even if I would
like dial my environment in like on my
you know via controllers and stuff um it
would still they would dry out too fast
and I just like never could get a handle
on it and then when I went to a smaller
dry space it like really stepped my game
up with um drying my plants and stuff so
that was like such a big thing that I
learned early on and I just kind of
wanted to Echo it because it really did
help me a lot
yeah I also wanted to like just give a
little very short outline on what it's
like for me to dry in the fridge just
because I think some people might be
interested maybe you guys think it's
ridiculous I'm not sure I'm interested
yeah I want to hear about it I I mean
the principle is the same uh so the what
changes is that obviously you're not
going to put your whole plant in the
fridge and like as a single thing um
partly because it actually takes really
really long even if you had the space to
hang a plant in the fridge I don't know
what kind of like how long that would
actually take to try it out um I have to
remove uh I I do break my plant down
before it goes in um and even then after
breaking it down I'm leaving a bit of
stem on uh every bit uh it still takes
like two to three weeks so it's still
already quite a decent uh you know time
frame for drying um in terms of judging
when it's done
the kind of loose the loose guide uh
that shaie actually recommended was
doing a weight calculation and looking
for about 25% of the original wet weight
um you can of course follow it up with
the the stem uh you know the stem kind
of snapping test or like what degree of
snappiness it's at and those are
generally what I use to determine like
uh when it should move on um it's
interesting uh measuring by weight so
basically every little how it works is
that you break the plant up you put them
into like paper bags and you put those
paper bags in the fridge essentially
that's that's that's all it is but
what's quite convenient is that I will
Mark the original weight and the target
weight before everything goes in the
fridge and at that point I just take
them out and put them on the scale and I
can tell when the bags are ready
individually I also try to keep it so
that the I try to group the flowers by
Mass
as well so that uh you don't get I think
it's kind of getting towards kush's
question as well like you don't get
different sized or quality buds in one
bag because you don't really know
whether they're all drying out at the
same rate whereas they're roughly the
same mass you can you know sort of like
uh you know ballpark estimate that okay
it's it's probably mostly done um I
don't know like uh was there anything
you all wanted to know about the fridge
stuff uh uh yeah your your um your
bagging method are you double bagging or
is it just brown paper bags into the
fridge or the brown paper bags going
into another bag like a turkey bag as a
secondary good question so I think what
most people are doing is just a single
uh brown paper bag but I have seen
variations and myself I actually put
them all into a cardboard box because I
have to use our like actual fridge and
the cardboard box just kind of ensures
that it has a little like microclimate
that doesn't get like destabilized as
soon as someone opens the door of the
fridge so it's a little bit of a buffer
um that's the only difference uh I have
seen people use like pizza boxes I've
seen people use like more than one bag I
think it really does it's just one of
those things where I think you kind of
have to tailor it to your particular
fridge and like your your environmental
humidity and everything because that all
of that is going to have an impact as
well
how does how my only question would be
how does the the actual temperature
impact
curing because like I mean just thinking
about the the basics with what Peach was
talking about with the um with you know
like freezer keeping it in the freezer
will keep the turps and everything way
longer than in the fridge there's a slow
degradation in the fridge but it's very
very slow so I'm wondering if there is
what kind of gash exchange goes on that
temperature for
curing I wish I knew more about the
science and I should also qualify that
this is strictly for the drying part um
I don't know if I would consider this
like part of quote unquote curing um
this is just to get the moisture out but
the idea is that at a certain threshold
of temperature you are losing Less in
terms of like the volatiles and stuff I
again I don't that makes sense none of
this has been proven to me um and like I
said earlier I've never actually done a
side by side I would love for someone to
to do it at some point um but it's just
yeah given the constraints it's kind of
one of the only ways I can keep things
going pretty quickly um
yeah yeah what's the uh what's the
relative humidity in the
fridge I did check this I don't know if
I could tell you off the top of my head
right now think it's 4 or something like
that yeah it'll be like 20 to 30
probably in the fridge oh wow okay so
it's low definitely good to have it in a
bag in that case yeah that probably it's
probably different in that bag it's
probably a little higher in that bag
right probably higher and also I guess
the interplay with the temperature is
definitely something I don't understand
like you know obviously the low temp
keeps it going for much longer but the
low humidity also is like you know a
counter point to that so it's I mean
it's the the humidity is relative to the
temperature to the water holding
capacity of of the air so it's
definitely even though it's low it's
still it's really cold so it's really
slowing it down because the air can't
hold that much water anyways yeah that's
right so yeah so it's not the same as
having it hot and dry where it would dry
out in a
Flash yeah much different
yeah yeah so I mean if anyone out there
kind of has more science or more
knowledge about how that works or you
know any theories about whether it's
good or bad I would love to know
um leave a comment below please well I
was just I'll have to look up the study
but I was just looking up a study about
chlorophyll leeching in cold
temperatures and that the chlorophyll
and it it was studied off of water so
storms uh in the summer the water would
have a higher chlorophyll count whereas
that same water in the winter storm when
it was cold would have a much lower
chlorophyll count and so there were
there was talking about leeching and how
chlorophyll has a harder time um
plasticizing or or uh having
biosynthesis um being created um under
colder temperatures so there could be
benefits to the cold temperatures not
allowing the chlorophyll to operate um
in a negative way or and staying inside
of the the plant
material yeah I think that's definitely
one of the that low temperature
affecting you know various um metabolic
processes and all that is definitely one
of the contentious points like whether
you know what's good and what's bad
about that
um compared to a conventional or more
conventional dry you know all that stuff
is like a bit of a
mystery yeah I'd love to do side by side
comparisons that'd be a lot of
fun I mean the rate of the rate of
vacination is slower as well you know
when it's
cold right little Hill try it yes I
will I got I got fresh I still have one
Greenhouse to take
down might happen what do you still have
to take down this
year uh I got a greenhouse that has
light supplemental lights and uh it's
mostly rs11 and
Skittles yeah man rs1
boy hype all hype 13 minute High
bro I I did a a thing where like I was
doing a review and like as I'm I have
the camera on me and as I'm talking I
smoke it and within 13 minutes I am dead
sober after smoking rs11 it killed me
man first time I've seen it I I've only
smoked indoor and and I wasn't impressed
and I already had the Clone so like you
know I was still going to go with it and
it looks okay it smells okay it's just
oh my God like I'm so not stoked on it
and this is usually the best run of the
year is this fall this fall run that
runs into November yeah um just because
you can get the colors and just
something about like low light levels
but also supplemental light and like
cold nights like you can you can really
do some cool things in that greenhouse
and
like I got it full of like a strain I
don't give a about but the Skittles
would be good Skittles the Skittles will
taste great um I'm I'm a super fan of uh
of of that strain and just as far as
like head stash or something to smoke
that's tasty that's that's what I'm into
anyway so you get old sweet pink
grapefruit by any
chance yes um what do you think about
boy would I like to have that that
strain back in something working on it I
only I only grew it once it had an
amazing Funk it was a very like
horizontal grower lateral
brancher um just lime green nugs but but
like just like things don't smell like
that anymore yeah that's the closest I
can get to Skittles like trying to
compare it to or explain to someone who
used to grow stuff like that is like
grapefruity citrus extreme maybe closest
to something I remember from SPG like
the beston I've grapefruit grapefruit
peel is the something I get from it for
sure yeah
yeah SPG God I wish I still had that is
it
still the Clone is still live it's in
Canada we'll work on it we'll see we'll
see oh man that would be great to CU
that man like things don't smell like
that anymore no no I think it would blow
people's minds nowaday just kind of like
how Che doely would other like that
it it won't test 30 but you know still
amazing weed yeah yeah you could just
lie about it just send it to a lab that
lies about their test and just put that
out you know that's how they all do
anyway I mean that's that's every lab
yeah it's a standard that's how it's all
done so maybe it will maybe it's a 25
yeah right well we're gonna I think
we're going to do the that Z episode
next so that could be cool um as
well um chush did you want to PR us with
those questions yeah yeah so um one of
them was just kind of a a personal
observation that I that like I
personally like to do in my garden and
it goes back to triming and the
different morphology of different plants
um I so if I get a golf ball uniformity
nug plant and all of the buds are
conical triang or golf ball decent
uniformity um I like to let those dry
out a little bit more and so when I'm
trimming these and it it requires a a
dense Bud because you're going to be a
little rough with it but I'll hand trim
I won't use a pair of scissors I use I
I'll put on a pair of black uh nit trial
powderless gloves yeah and the the
bigger rounder golf ball nugs I'll pick
the I'll pick the water Leaf off I'll
pick just handpick everything down and
even sometimes if it's bristly enough or
if it's uh if it's Decay if it's if it's
dry enough you can just brush your
finger across some of the the the Sugar
Leaf and it falls right off now I I'll
do I'll let I'll let those dry easier
and it's easier to work with my hands I
have really big hands all these scissors
are tiny they they my hands cramp up if
I use the scissors too much but when it
comes to uh a little bit larier strain
or a sativa leaner or something that is
just covered in Lea and is a a pain in
the ass to trim I won't let that strain
get as dry I'll have it just a little
bit wetter so that when I'm working with
it with the scissors H the buds a I can
be a little I can squish the bud down a
little bit I can morph it around a
little bit and I can work my scissors
around the the content a lot easier so
there there's Nuance to be had like you
you you you can't just subjective or
objectively say that this is the best
time to trim this all of this weed
because there are certain types of Bud
that is easier to handle that some you
can trim just by your hand and peeling
stuff off and some that you need a pair
of scissors for um the other oh and the
other thing is the just the powderless
gloves and working with that like if you
guys like your scissor hash um use the
powderless gloves and do your Charis
like finger hash you know your hands
will get coated with enough hash that
you can take time oh dude the CH it's
it's some of the best flavors in my
opinion is making that scissor hash or
that finger hash when your hands are
coated that's my favorite hash bro and
it's so easy to do with the powderless
gloves whether you use latex night trial
as long as it's powderless but the the
finger pressing it literally comes off
so easily you only need like five or six
thumb presses before it starts
collecting the material to itself and
it's just the it's just super easy so if
you guys aren't doing that if you aren't
trimming your stuff with those with
gloves like that and capturing some
really nice some some good resin I
suggest doing that um and then one thing
I want to take just quickly though
what's chars without your um skin oils
Is that
real yeah well think
yeah was going to say it's traditionally
like yeah you're getting you're getting
all the all the flavors if you think
about it really yeah um and then just
one other thing I wanted to pull back
and talk about and like I I think all of
us have had a friend or know somebody or
have had this experience you go over to
a buddy's Garden he's growing a really
good weed amazing weed maybe even better
weed than you are and you're like dude
good job keep it up make sure
everything's good and then two weeks
after harvest and after cure and he's
like man I I don't know what happened
all this shit's dried out too fast like
there I think we've all seen it where
somebody grew really amazing weed took
the diligence to grow the plant all year
long and then just slacked off when it
came to harvest curing and hang I think
we all anecdotally have stories of
friends or people we know that killed it
during the grow and then slacked off at
the end and like I just
want I just want to reiterate like take
it seriously like do do the due
diligence make sure your growing room is
set up make sure you know you have the
space and the time planned out for it
make sure you have the time to trim it
when it's ready to be bucked off the
lines I have personally seen so many
good Gardens literally just fall apart
because the gardener at the very end
just just either hit a complacency wall
or just didn't take the the curing
Harvest and hanging process seriously
it's um it's as important and meticulous
as the grow session all year Al and it
it happens in a much smaller crunch of
time but it's ju it's just as important
in my
opinion
so um just to add to the the shus part
what I learned from um our homie at
zomia that goes over there and like does
that is that a lot of those dudes that
actually do the shus their their hands
don't really have a lot of skin cells
come off anymore because their hands are
so callous from dealing with the
costic turs of and the the cannaboids or
cannaboids whatever of um of that stuff
their hands are just so freaking callous
that not a lot don't have there's no
natural oils coming out of their hands
their crazy yeah that's crazy sounds
brutal but like I thought about it and I
was like yeah that makes sense like if
you think about just like getting
getting you know rubbing against plants
like oh bare arms sometimes you can get
really itchy you know like when you're
having a heavy trim sesh and your balls
are itchy and you know the the sensitive
parts of your that Shick could suck
bro yeah
sorry were there prompts in there for
the others um um no no just like just
the Nuance I've noticed between trimming
different morphology like suggestion for
the hash and if you want to capture
capture your scissor hash and your trim
hash uh using the gloves and then just
reiterating the you know take a step
back and make sure you're the the latter
portion your last 20% is as important as
the 80% that you grew all year or the
that you took to grow it indoors
whatever your frame is you know take
care of the end don't slack off on it
take it seriously I've I've seen a lot
of failures just because people were
like H you know I'll get around to it or
it doesn't have to be perfect I grew
this fire looking weed you know look at
this this is going to be awesome and
then it it doesn't turn out like they
thought it was because they didn't take
the last portion of it seriously I've
seen a lot of Growers who are um who
think they're shitty Growers because
they're not very good at drying and
curing and vice versa I've seen a lot of
people think they're great Growers that
that are shitty Growers and and kind of
do okay at the drying and curing part I
want to say that like as a relative
newb um it still scares me not knowing
whether or not if if I get some flower
that's not so good like I it's still not
very clear to me whether or not I messed
up in the post Harvest at this point um
and I'm not talking about clones that
I'm re running they already know of
course I just mean like you know new new
plants that I'm trying I'm like is that
because I miss upop at the end I don't
know I'm going to have to rerun it and
see if it's the same or you know I'm
going to have to try and Vary something
in my dry cure to see if it makes any
difference um I I guess what I'm trying
to say is that like I don't feel like I
have that much certainty when it comes
to the end product quality and knowing
like exactly where things may have gone
good or bad yet I'm hoping to like
obviously develop that over time um but
it's so complex that I'm like this could
have gone wrong at like any of these
points I don't know it could just be
like a shitty expression from the
genetics and that's just how it's it
could be the genetics as well yes yeah
exactly so I'm still yeah still getting
there still working my way there
yeah um I thought otherwise we could
just open the floor like anything you
know anything that comes to mind for you
guys around any of these topics uh any
of your any Reflections on like your
most recent Harvest anything like that
um gonna going to throw the indoor guys
under the bus a bit and say one of yours
to respond in some way um I was kind of
gonna ask
actually um do any of you guys look at
like the pistol development at all uh in
terms of like looking when to harvest
and all of that
or I don't know it's kind of just
something like I've
never really used it but I don't know I
kind of just see that it like
correlate heavily I I mean like if if I
still see white pistols or or stigma at
the end of harvest I'm like I'm I'm
thinking that I probably screwed up
somewhere if I know that this should be
done and I'm seeing a bunch of you know
my hair sticking out but at the same
time like there are some plants that
will never stop throwing that like Kim
91 stuff like that when it's grown right
so it's it's up in the air just where
you like to high it's funny you mention
that the Kim 91 S1 that I got going out
right now it's it has like one or two
white pistols still sticking out the top
of it endless and she actually she
retained a couple of her pink pistols
too I was really this laid into it yeah
I was really surprised to see pink like
on the top of every cola two or three
Pink Pistols usually I'm used to seeing
those Fade Away pretty yeah pretty early
into
flower yeah so there's there's a lot of
strains that do that and like you just
kind of have to know which or which like
I was talking about the Bundy sis S1 cut
earlier that thing will do it it's just
like endless ugly ass white hairs it
looks like it got shocked you know like
one of the traits of it yeah I mean I
guess it just depends on the genetics
and stuff and what the way some some
strings just do I mean most of them tend
to the hairs die off and you know it's
you know maybe not time to harvest but
you know it's at least been pollinated
or hand fumbled or whatever you know
there's it means all sorts of different
things when the hair's Brown
up yeah LEDs too hot yeah something I
look at is like once most of the hairs
are
turned like like a majority of them
especially on the
tops um I I know that like Harvest is
probably about two weeks
away um at least this is this is
outdoors this is greenhouse
um like once they all kind of turned
then you're going to start really to see
you're really going to start seeing
swelling in in the nugs and uh you know
you're still about two weeks
away I have a question for you do you
see a lot of pollen contamination out
where you're growing outdoor like from
other Farms blown in not where I am at
all um
never um unless I'm contaminating myself
yeah right yeah can
happen but uh in town like down in
Garberville or Redway if you're grown in
your backyard
like you'll get seeds and everything
every year that's funny dude I'd be soad
some years some years worse cuz like
people are like some people are
flowering males out in their backyard to
bring up to their their Garden up up
somewhere else and yeah I mean it's town
and and there's weed in everybody's
backyard and you don't know what kind of
garbage they're growing or Hermes or
what I know man but so that's fairly
common in town but out here just
especially where I am no way um just
because I'm there's there's nobody
really growing weed very close to me and
it's very windy so I mean no I've never
had an issue with it I did have a
neighbor with a mail plant I saw one
time and I just kind of barked at him to
cut it down out of here or
or I would do it for
him this is r a random that was too
early I had I had a her me plant this
year um
in my Skittles Skittles sherbet cross
yeah um one of them straight up hered
more male flowers than than
female and uh I caught it I caught it
early enough um I haven't I haven't
really trimmed up that weed yet so I
don't know if it's seated but I kind of
doubt it just yeah just from looking at
all the male flowers and and the weed
around it the the the the females around
it like I'm I don't I don't think it
Herm um I mean I don't think get uh
seated yeah yeah was but other than that
like yeah pretty good way to get
on your neighbor's bad side if if you
got a bunch of stray pollen running
around your
property I was going to say like is have
yall witnessed or heard of any like
spiteful individuals who've gone and
like pollinated someone's Garden because
they no but not pollinated but but if a
neighbor had pollinated your garden
accidentally and theirs most likely
that's that's definitely happened and
yeah that that can cause some problems
I've heard of lots of lawsuits you know
I've heard some stories in Trinity Pines
where guys were using drones and they
were pollinating other people's Farms
with drones that's epic wow that's
that's pretty up yeah that's like
epic hate bro Trinity Pines is pretty
crazy though it gets pretty wild up
there that's funny man
bunch of
dicks yeah there's been a lot of L seats
especially during the hemp stuff um
whether it was you know hot hemp or you
know like it's supposed to be fem seed
and all of a sudden it's all pollinated
their people like Chad suing like the
the people they had do it or whoever
because they didn't understand what
feminized meant or any of it like that
was pretty common yeah also they were
they were putting out like really un un
untested seed for the most part that's
that that happened big time in Applegate
Applegate Valley in in southern Oregon
um bunch of hemp farmers in the valley
seated up everybody's selia crop
and uh I think that I think that cause
cause some problems I I could only
imagine yeah if somebody seated my crop
what would happen like I don't think I
would sue them but like you can't
with somebody's livelihood like that and
honestly like there is you are liable in
the in the era of legalization you're
super liable yeah for ruining somebody's
agricultural crop yeah especially if the
person's legal you know what I mean like
yeah you definitely love oh yeah so I
don't know still L catch your ass
whooping um I had a question also for
you outdoor Growers so like once you
guys see like betrus and whatnot um on
an outdoor crop is that like signs to
harvest that right now or kind of just
cut it and let it go and and harvest it
or like how do you guys deal with that I
think it depends on where you are like
how close to harvest are you it it your
petritis could have been caused by
caterpillars in which case cut it out
and let it
ride um but like if you see betri
like you might go another week before
you see betrus again on on the same
plant or on the same strain so in that
case you just got to start monitoring
and looking closer once you see it until
it it gets to the point where like okay
I saw three new spots today tomorrow I'm
going to see 10 new spots cut it you
know so it like it kind of progressively
gets worse and you got to know when to
cut your
losses yeah think that's the Harvest
Time thing like okay like okay where I
think we're g to you know we got 10
spots of mold today let's let's Harvest
tomorrow because it's just going to get
worse and so that's that's your Harvest
timing right there it's molding you know
right I think it also depends on
infection location um you know if it's
in the base of a main Cola as opposed to
a lower tier Branch or a little snug or
if it's on the main stem near the near
the base of the the plant there's the
I've noticed in my garden usually it
only propagates where there's dead cell
material if there's dead plant material
for it to grow off of or in the instance
of caterpillars it's uh it's their
I've noticed that the the the the
proliferation of it starts where their
is just resting on a flower so it
kind of depends on the infection site
depends on if I take that Branch or if I
take just the tip of the cola off or if
I take the whole thing or if I take the
whole plant yeah there's just just the
tip
I I had a question about bet tritis I
think this one's for locco because I
think locco and I had a little talk
about this I don't know how long ago but
so far mostly when we talk about Bettis
we consider it to be like an exogenous
uh or like kind of caused by like
exogenous factors like caterpillars uh
humidity Etc but lo you were you
mentioned to me that there was also a
notion of systemic petritis I don't even
know if that's the right term for it but
was that something we were talking
about um I think we have um and like I
think it's kind of like never really
been settled if it's systemic or not
systemic I don't
know it's not really what do we mean
here when we say systemic okay okay yeah
yeah um but like systemic I guess it's
like if if one part of the plant has it
like the rest of it is or can have it
type of
deal but yeah
yeah anything else from anyone uh
er no I mean I think like what you guys
have been talking about are been great
points and just like what kush was
saying like the biggest thing that has
helped me um is to just be prepared for
what you're doing you know like know
like how many plants you're going to be
taking down make sure you have a space
ready for it um you know make sure you
have your environmental kind of like
thing like environmental controllers and
stuff like that in place before uh you
go you know because once you once you
take them down they're drying whether
you like it or not uh whether you're in
good conditions or bad you know so just
be prepared for it you know I think
that's the best way like to set yourself
up for Success yep oh one other thing I
wanted to add was uh people who are very
meticulous about scoping Tricom Amber
and cloudiness um a lot of people don't
take into account that when you chop the
plant and hang it that uh maturation
still goes so and it varies with strains
it varies with environments I've seen
some that have 20% Amber tricomes jump
up to 40 by the time hang is done and
I've seen some that only add like 5%
more so that it's another Nuance
subjective like you have to you have to
get in there and and work with the
plants to understand what it's going to
do I've wondered about this too
especially because uh it takes so much
longer for me to dry in the fridge I I
often have thought about that like
whether or not that that process you
know obviously will continue but at what
rate yeah right
yeah I mean if nothing else we can
probably call it a WP yeah I think we're
right about that
range and then possibly maybe an idea
for the next episode is uh just talking
about what we grew I mean for an outdoor
Round Table what we grew this year what
we liked what worked well we might go
for next year and get a get a get
another hour and a half two hour
discussion going on that because I I
could talk about plenty of that as well
too I'm already excited for next year's
grow and I'm not even done trimming this
year and I'm I'm chomping at the
bit I'm definitely ready for some like
offseason content because I imagine
there's there's a lot of prep that you
guys have to do anyway in the offseason
thinking planning Etc so I think that
could be cool for sure I want to see you
guys go through the jars and like
describe each one as you go through it
and what nuances you look for and how
you assess your weed and like all that
stuff because I think people be really
into that yeah that seems to be why they
like the reviews that I do is because
they're someone that has experience with
something giving them a real realistic
on theground idea of what this thing
smells and tastes like and all that so I
think people would be into it call it
call it like a jar talk have a round
table called jar talk jar jar talk I
like that I also want to kind of credit
Kush by the way for this episode um he
actually wrote up a bunch of these
questions and and and the outline and
I'm stoked because it's the first time
someone else has done it instead of me
yeah I'm like yeah that's awesome and so
you know maybe the next one you may we
we may not need both you know me and
Matt maybe one of us maybe yeah you
could take the Reigns fully Kush at some
point we'll see yeah I I I see in the
future getting more outdoor cats on and
there might be a panel big enough to
where both you guys don't even need to
be there we might have enough people
talking yeah I don't need to be in any
outdoor episode I'm a idiot Outdoors
like same that's all I got are dumbass
questions is all I got so
yeah well with that's it I wanted to
thank each and every one of you for
showing up uh is there anything you have
to say ER you want to
plug no I'm just happy to be here thanks
for having me thanks for letting me hang
out with you guys Mr Kush of the Giants
uh just plug the Breeders send it to
Discord if you guys like this content
like literally just just hang out in the
Discord get it like everything you see
here is tfold in text on the Discord it
gets deeper we get more Nuance we get
more more discussions in there just go
check out the
Discord little
Hill
um I just want to say thank you to you
guys for having me on and and and the
opportunity to talk shop um you got some
new merch I bought a bunch of merch for
uh for uh I don't know just for the Farm
um organic cotton hoodies uh racer back
tank tops and
sweatshirts um very high quality
apparel and it just supports a small
organic farmer so you want to reach out
on Instagram Instagram um they'll make
uh they'll make really nice uh Christmas
gifts I think absolutely for all your
loved ones you guys do any hats any
snapbacks or anything I have I have some
hat I have some old hats still I mean
they're new but they're old right um if
if yeah just just a trucker hats uh
which I which I like a lot they're the
old style and uh but uh yeah I mean it
just it directly supports my farm and
keeps my head above water that's why I'm
doing it so I appreciate any
support thanks guys awesome local what
you got yeah uh thanks for having us
Matt uh and like uh Kush was saying uh
the Discord I mean this this is kind of
what we talk about all day every day um
there's plenty of pictures which we
don't get to you know put up here but
you know the Discord is where all the
goes down um so if y'all can please
do
join yeah I just wanted to also say that
so that people have an idea we have
about 500 people on the Discord I think
maybe four to 500 so it's not small all
it's a good active
group yeah so thousand you got anything
else you want to say nah nothing nothing
beyond that just again also very
grateful for all of you here and yeah
very grateful for like all the new
energy that's being brought to the show
and the just the crew in general me as
well um just just speaking for myself
like the show's come a long way since I
first started it as my live stream on
Instagram um there's been times where
I've you know BR my teeth to bits and
and right now isn't one of them I'm so
stoked with the direction of this place
um being able to take you know a few
weeks off and just like deal with my
health stuff um it's it's been amazing
so thank you a thousand for for taking
the time to do all this and all of you
guys that that come on and like put your
time into to this I I can't thank you
guys enough and uh with that go check
out our breeders syate patreon that's
where you get to the Discord um you can
save money at r.com I think it's 30% off
if if you're a part of the patreon um
what else do we have go to lifted
genetics uh yeah lifted genetics lftd
genetics on Instagram um he carries a
lot of the breeder Syndicate folks too
um we have rot Eco Europe for our
European connection we have Gert by
seeds who also carries a bunch of the
European or I'm sorry the British
Syndicate people but it's for Australia
so for Australian fans you do have
access to our stuff and uh rot.com for
all your spray D BL I think that's
it and go buy some uh go buy some merch
from Little Hill and show support and
with that I think that is it did I get
everything
thousand yeah I think so thanks everyone
thank
you
[Music]
cheers want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link or description below our merch site
is officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is topnotch I've
been saving old designs for years for
this purpose so please check it out
Syndicate gear.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it
out