welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
revolution hey everyone um both thousand
and my myself are big Advocates of women
in our community and we're also big
Advocates of them telling their um
truths their their true stories their
adventures in
cannabis and uh that's not always going
to be a beautiful pretty picture um
especially when women talk about their
lives so a trigger warning here um I
don't normally do anything like that any
kind of trigger warnings or anything PC
but in this case like it is one of those
things that I know there are are some
women that that have so so much PTSD
they cannot um even stand hearing about
it because it triggers them too much and
I respect that and so does thousand so
does peach so we wanted to put a
disclaimer in here at the very beginning
that um there may be some uncomfortable
Parts it it'll only be brief but um yeah
it's your choice if you want to listen
or not to that that and with that we
hope you enjoy the
show Welcome to reader Syndicate I'm
Matthew Riot seeds here with
thousandfold my co-host and today we
will be talking to Sweet Peach kiss 13
yeah so sweet peach kiss 13 head of pure
organic medicinals and founder of GI
Mary James um welcome on the show uh so
swe so peaches as we'll we'll refer to
her in short um is one of our Discord uh
community members and um peaches
alongside her husband Buckshot Hill um
have been a great duo in the Discord and
I think recently Matt you got to meet up
with them did and hang out a little bit
which is was a blast it was a blast we
had F I felt like Matt you had a couple
of weeks of
like didn't you meet um Denali I like
yeah you had a series of like double
dates I felt like yeah spindle and his
wife yeah it was fun you know like
getting to meet people for the first
time from our group is real fun because
like you never know what you're going to
get but most of the time it's been
especially with the couples that I've
met it's been pretty amazing they're
gonna be lifelong friends for
sure yeah so peaches like I mentioned um
one of the main reasons why we have
Peaches on the show today is actually to
talk uh hash making yes um but that's
not the only thing that peaches does uh
that's just what we're going to call the
show but we'll get into some of that um
so peaches what were some of your
earliest experiences with the
plant well um to be perfectly honest
even though I come um from a third
generation I'm a third generation grower
um my grandpa grew and my dad grew I
never messed with weed as a kid my
parents were very strict um the only
time I touched weed as a kid was when I
took it from my dad and and I put it in
a baloney sandwich in a lunch bag and I
gave it to my boyfriend at
school and he got caught with it and we
got trouble and I got I got my ass beat
for that one oh I bet drawing attention
yeah I I drew attention to us in not a
very good way no so I got in trouble for
that one and then I never smoked weed
until I graduated and got out on my own
um and then unfortunately the first weed
I ever did really smoke was uh some
Mexican weed in the park and then I met
Buckshot and Buckshot had his own weed
that he was growing um it was some Bag
seed from as he's a rosta lady in a
Subaru in Humbolt is where he got it
okay and it was purple weed and he got
bag seed from it and for some reason he
named it the super green and so he was
growing that when we got together and
that was my first experience seeing a
plant um or uh getting to smoke actually
really good weed that was my real first
experience and that was what in
1996 um when we first met um because
yeah my dad never showed me his plants
my grandpa didn't show me his plants it
wasn't our family wasn't like really out
there about it um my grandpa grew weed
to give my mom because my mom was
diagnosed with breast cancer um and so
she was going to La for chemotherapy so
my grandpa grew the weed that my mom
took to LA to hustle to pay for her
hotel and to go to chemotherapy wow and
then my grandma also hustled weed to
help pay for my mom's stuff gangster so
um and then my dad grew weed you know
just for himself because my mom passed
away when I was four she she didn't make
it um you know and unfortunately I wish
so much that she had known that that
same weed she was selling that she could
have used herself yeah um to help treat
what she had for sure and and she didn't
have a clue and so uh she didn't make it
and so my dad you know my dad's been the
black sheep of the family he grew weed
we got busted and raided um I remember
that very specifically that day having
the cops come down the driveway and like
trying to figure out why are all the
cops here like what's going on and they
sat us down on the couch and they told
us to stay there and they searched our
whole house and they took all my dad's
weed and they took all his plants and my
dad was their motorcycle mechanic
because it's a small town and
uh uh so they didn't take him to jail
wow they just took
everything taed him so hold on you were
saying that you never saw a plant when
you were growing up no he nope he grew
them down in the creek all um like he's
told me stories about how he grew them
tucked under the willow trees in the
sand so they didn't have to be watered
and you know all that stuff you know he
smoked it I knew they smoked it you
could smell it come out of the bedroom
but uh you know it wasn't like how I am
with my kids you know my kids know all
about the weed they help they you know
all about it it wasn't like that for me
you know you know I noticed that a lot
of parents that were Growers and had
kids either were very permissive wanted
to involve in it like educate them or
silent about it because they had the
other mindset that their kids could
potentially tell the wrong person at
school and bring down
you know like there's not a lot of in
between between the two and uh I was
going to mention where where peaches is
from isn't typical California it's
actually very woodsy and beautiful
Sequoia area so there's going to be a
lot of creeks a lot of mountains stuff
like that yep is it it's mountainous
it's very mountainous uh our we have 40
acres that backed up to the National
Forest oh wow and there was a whole big
creek that ran right through our
property right so Gorilla growing was
like quite a I don't know natural
decision I guess given that kind of
terrain yeah yep um so wow that's
amazing so your family has had this
quite long and intense relationship with
the plant and all these different ways
okay okay we'll probably come back to
some of that but um what were some of
the first because the show is going to
be centered on extracts I didn't want to
ask what were the first extracts you
tried
well that would be um some dry sift that
we did in the in the back bedroom
probably in like in
96 um uh he showed me by taking he put
the flour in a sifter just like the
sifter I used to sift the hash out of it
comes out of the freeze dryer now and he
put flour in there and he had one of the
um glasses the glass pieces from one of
the grow lights MH and put it at an
angle and then had a a piece of paper at
the
bottom shook it over the glass and it
would go down and then the THC would
stick to the glass and everything else
would go to the paper and then we would
take a card and card that up and we
would use that on joints and bowls and
so that technically was the very first
extract yeah um definitely
yeah I've never heard of that but
that's he he did that he developed that
when he was 14 that's so cool and uh so
that was the first time he showed me how
to do that and then the first time I
actually made uh ice waterer hash was in
uh
1999 uh we bought the first set of the
one gallon bubble bags from the O BC in
Oakland was that is that bubble ban oh
no Oakland is uh oh was it bubble ban
yeah yep shout out Bubble Man yep the
very first one so they were one gallon
bags and um and actually what's crazy is
the first strand we washed and made hash
with was
bubbleberry oh that's nice did it make
good hash it did make very good
hash did the berry stick with it do you
remember honestly I I couldn't tell you
specifically if you asked Buckshot that
he could probably tell you he probably
would remember huh he would so this is
the original bubbleberry um yes from s
MAA from Tony very cool very
cool
um uh I just blanked I had another
question which was
um what was your how did you see hash
relative to smoking flow at the
time yeah I remember it used to knock me
on my ass cuz I was a hell of a
lightweight um and we had had just had
our daughter and so um I was still in
that hole I can't smoke during mom time
you know sure nowadays geeez yeah right
that's a time to do it yeah so I you
know for me the hash was like a
nighttime thing um I I really like the
taste of it
um so I I but I love flour I can't the
flow is still one of of my favorite
things to smoke I'm not going to lie as
much as I like to make cash um there's
nothing like good
flour like I will I I have to
say um so the hash for me back then was
just it was the like nighttime smoke and
yeah get the job and normally what you
would just add it to a joint is that the
yeah like you know the snake in the
grass that's what we used to call they
call them hash holes now yeah but it was
the snake in the grass or we would do
the um on top of a
bowl
yeah the classic yeah okay okay so just
to round out this little um Icebreaker
introduction would you please tell us
about first of all pure organic
medicinals and then uh GI Mary Janes
just to let the audience know like you
know what you're up to well uh we start
with GI Mar James because that came
first um back in 2018 we got involved
with uh battle buds who was associated
with the weed for Warrior Project um and
so we became a sponsor for that and it
was a great event it was men and women
combined they would come together and
you know have like a day where they did
food and hung out and they had weed and
a giveaway and stuff and then I noticed
there was women there and a lot of the
women just congregated alone together
and um that's when I thought of starting
GI Mary Janes which would be the same
concept that the battle buds was based
off of which was a veteran group but it
was going to be for just women veterans
so the women veterans could come
together and have a safe place to meet
where there wasn't men because a lot of
women veterans have um um you know been
assaulted yeah they have dealt with a
lot of [ __ ] from men and I my intuition
when I saw the group interaction was
that these women needed a safe place of
their own to do the same thing not that
they weren't having fun but I wanted to
help provide them with that same aspect
by themselves and so um I started doing
that and it was going really well until
coid happened and we lost our meeting
spot and so we haven't been able to have
meetings anymore um until I can find
somewhere that will let us come and you
know smoke and hang out and do all that
stuff can I ask as well were you just to
just to be clear were you ever in the
military yourself
or no I was not I am not a veteran um my
dad is an xmarine my grandpa was a World
War II prisoner of war my uncle was a
Navy veteran from
Vietnam um so I grew up around the
veterans and honestly the only I mean I
know a lot of people always say oh I
would have joined but um my grandpa
asked me not to join the military um I
was actually in the process of trying to
sign up for it and he came to me and
asked me to not do that to
myself and my grandpa was my world my
grandma and grandpa raised me pretty
much after my mom died and my dad fell
apart and I watched my
grandpa struggle every day with PTSD and
the stuff that happened to him as a
prisoner of
war and uh it made me have a lot of
compassion for veterans and what they
experience and so it was just something
that was dear to my heart and I saw
these people struggling and cannabis was
helping them and I had cannabis and so I
just chose to
help I'm glad you did it sounds like uh
that's super important it's very smart
to have a space like that for women
because that does happen a lot I have
friends you know that have been through
that and it's not the most comfortable
environment um military unions and stuff
like that
yeah no it's it's very
um very
loadable what you what you've been doing
super cool work um doing the good work
as people might say Okay um we I'm sure
again we'll come back to that um how
about pure organic
medicinals so they found me on
Instagram um about I don't know four
years but four years ago um honestly I I
refer to us as a band of
Misfits um because we are not corporate
cannabis in any way shape or form that's
why we haven't hit the market yet
because it has taken us like they were
it's been six years for everybody else
involved I've been involved for three
years now and what I brought to the
table was my hash experience my edible
experience and then all the equipment
that we had acquired over the last few
years is what's making their hash room
run um so there's you know two main guys
who have been in
cannabis you know their whole lives and
so we're just we're trying to come to
Market with um you know we have a
solventless license and uh it's it's
hard just to yeah for for someone like
me who's not really like close in any
way to like the American you know legal
Market or license side of things what do
you mean when you say um you have got to
market yet and so what what does it mean
that what's been happening in this whole
time um we're jumping through
hoops um you know there's all the
testing that has to be done
um we had to find a
distributor uh
it's well considering the fact that
there's only three of us and in the last
month I've had to wash by myself
probably like 150 lbs of weed 5 lbs at a
time wow um ho it takes a while um and
then that has to go for pre-testing and
then we got to package it and then it's
got to go to distribution and then it
goes through another round of testing
and then it can actually go to market
wow okay so just to I'm just trying to
signpost for everyone this is already
after after you've gotten your license
right this is already postlicensing and
you're still having to do like basic
more compliance stuff yeah cuz they they
come every year and do an inspection and
if there's anything that's not perfect
then you have to fix that and you have
to do this and change that and all that
wonderful stuff and being not corporate
is is kind of a major Boon because it
cuts you off from a lot of funding um am
I right yes that's been our biggest
holdup um in fact I know everybody
thinks I'm like woohoo you're a hash
maker um I don't usually get paid when I
come up here um I have literally I I've
gotten paid a few times when they've had
money from our few investors that we've
gotten but most of the time I come up
and I work on my own um yeah trying to
you
know I I want to build a legacy for my
kids you know my I my son you know Tiner
he he's going to be the fourth
generation I already know my daughter
she's grown she's you know she doesn't
want to do anything with the weed world
but that's fine that's her choice she's
doing great um out in Texas and uh so
for me this is really important I want
to bring I want to create a legacy for
him that is legal that he doesn't have
to worry and be scared about going to
jail and having the cops kick down our
door and all that [ __ ] that we've
worried about our whole lives and so
funding has been our our biggest hurdle
you know we've had to literally stop
what we're doing and wait for to try to
conjure up some money here or there one
of the guys went back to work full-time
to get another job just to help pay for
the mortgage and
stuff jeez so you know it's not easy
it's not all the you know Glam and Glitz
that a lot of people think it is it's
really hard work and they don't make it
easy especially if you're not a rich
millionaire like anybody who's on the
market now that is legacy you can
guarantee those people have worked their
asses off to get where they're at for
sure yeah it's I me it's a lot and you
know like there's also the added cost of
testing each time you bring in a new
strain each different way you extract it
has to be tested that cost a lot of
money like a lot of people just assume
that that's there it's cheap but it's
not it's super not yeah every COA is
$475 exactly it's so that's for every
metric ticket if I wash 10 lbs of runs
that's a metric ticket if I have
something else that's another metric
ticket and and then if I take that runs
and I put it in live rosin that has to
be tested and if I take that same runs
and I put it in a cart that cart still
has to be tested separate and then if I
take that and put it into an edible that
has to have separate testing you can't
just test what I made once and put it
into three products exactly so every
basically every point of the production
chain almost or the supply chain needs
to be tested every time it's a new
enters into a new product and form if
I'm correct yeah
yeah that in form has to have a COA yeah
yeah so I guess just another reminder or
insight into the fact that you know it's
essentially still very much pay to win
or pay to play I guess um you know you
really need to be able to either
sacrifice enough you know afford yeah
what is an immense cost to get going um
yes
okay um stepping away from some of that
uh what you called it um jumping through
hoops and going back to the the hash for
a little bit um one thing I wanted to
ask you about was how you see your
process having developed like you told
us about some of the very first you know
quotequote extract or hash that you
made what how how did this journey go
for you you know like first of all like
just developing yourself as someone
who's doing hash at home and then
transitioning into this bigger scale
it's more commercial scale um well let's
see
um in uh I was actually in you know
we've always done our own personal thing
and for friends and family um yeah maybe
we can just start there first then just
start with like what was it like making
hash for your friends and
family it was
nice it was you know a one gallon bucket
on the kitchen counter um and it was
just really simple you know you we would
do it an ounce at a time like uh I think
one of our best washers at the time was
the LA Confidential that we had um it it
always washed well um and then you know
so it was just like a you know cuz
Buckshot got hurt way early in our
relationship with his back and uh so
he's been basically the stay atome take
care of the you know things at the house
and then I've been out working and and
you know handling all that stuff and
uh in uh 2018 I was in nursing
school and uh I finished my pre Rex and
all that and I actually got my
associates degree in uh science oh wow
and uh I was supposed to go to RN
school for the rest of it and uh the pro
I went and I was going to sign up for RN
school and I went to the meeting and I
was doing my stuff and she's like okay
well um you she's like do you work I'm
like yeah I'm a full-time CNA I you know
I work 40 plus hours of work a week as
you know a CNA and she was like well you
can't do that anymore and I'm like what
do you mean she's like well to go to R
in school you need to be in school
fulltime ah you're going to have to quit
your job and go to school because
there's no way you can do both it just
doesn't work and um I couldn't I I
couldn't quit my job how are we going to
eat I can't support us I have to work
like these are realistic American
choices now it it is it was no joke like
I had gone through all my financial aid
for all the prxs I did sure um I had
nothing left and so we had
literally uh his mom had given us 10
grand and I was she cuz she was like you
know put this towards nursing school do
something and I was like
well I can't live off this long enough
for to go to nursing school cuz that was
my first thing no way yeah and so
Buckshot took it and invested in uh what
the clear
class and uh learned how to do
distillate well when he did that they
were supposed to give him a job yeah and
that was the plan he was going to get a
job doing that and then I could go to
school to be an RN and we would be okay
cuz once I was done I'd be able to
support us and we'd be fine we wouldn't
have to struggle anymore well they never
gave him a job they sold him some CBD
distillate and taught him how to do all
this stuff took his money and then never
gave him a job so we were sitting here
and you know he was already into the
rosin and learning all that and had a
the first Sasquatch uh M1 press he was
doing flower rosin
and uh when this happened I was like
[ __ ] what are we going to like what am I
going to do I can't go to school like I
know how to grow good weed I know that
like it's something I've always done
I've always made good Edibles I mean
back in the day I used to make edibles
for the velia clubs for the medical
clubs and so um we decided to put
everything into
hash and we bought a freeze dryer and we
bought um the bags and we started with
uh the fruitless trash cans yeah and I
literally washed hash in our kitchen on
scaffolding on a ladder standing on a
ladder to wash hat he actually has proof
of this there's pictures
a um and that's how we started with the
white fruitless trash cans and we got
the ice extract bags and a free dryer
and uh it we started there and then we
started to do the seshes and it honestly
just kind
of took off from there yeah what do you
mean by the seses well around here the
secret sesh where uh the black market
companies come together in some rented
secret location and we set up a table
and they let people come in and they get
to shop kind of like a farmers market
yeah
we got it it was it was fun it was a lot
of fun I'm not going to lie um it was a
blast because you got to meet
like-minded people and become a part of
the community and then we were helping
people again and it just was a lot of
fun so I did want to dip into the tech a
bit more at this point um just so up
until this point of like scaling up when
you're still dealing with like you know
the one gallon bags and whatnot in that
early era what did you learn do you
think about making
hash honestly back then I I don't I
didn't learn as much as I did once we
got the bigger equipment um okay cuz
there wasn't as much information out
there you know like and and we wen't
ones to be on the internet very
much uh that's actually a question I did
want to ask at this point so how did you
get that information to start making
cash where did you learn that I have
that came from Buckshot yeah he he is a
research Powerhouse um
okay weed has been his life forever and
so he had read I'm pretty sure some
information from Neville about hash
making and that had peaked his interest
and that's when we got the one gon bags
and and so um the biggest part I think
about that point was learning how to dry
it right cuz there was no freeze dryers
and so we would wash it through the
little bags and then they when the kit
you got these little screens they're
orange and
blue and we would put that on top of a
piece of cardboard yeah and then put the
hash on it so it would draw it out and
then if you keep it in the fridge it
helps the whole process and does all
that so that was probably the biggest
learning curve at that point was just
learning how to dry it right so that you
would get it moldy yeah I've I've heard
this I I don't know much about like I
said earlier like I'm not you know very
Advanced at all and in hash making but I
have I have heard that you know the
drying part is really really key um you
know like my hardest part when I was
learning how to like use bubble bags and
stuff I was teaching myself because I
you know like I mean the information was
out there at that point but like I just
was stubborn and figured well I just see
how people do this they just stir it
with some ice no big deal right you just
pull up yeah nothing but but I was
taking like dry leaves that would
crumble up and crush up you know just
stuffing it all in there getting a full
drill with a painter paddle on drill
speed and just go for 45 minutes and
yeah that did not make exceptional hash
it did not it's some of the worst [ __ ]
ever so a lot of it is is to do with
preparation too right like big part yes
like uh we learned about cuz uh We've
we've done we do leaf and we have done
Leaf but most of the time we like to to
wash flour because it just gives you
better results and um one of the things
we did learn back then was about making
sure you froze it first even if it was
dry yeah um cuz it just helps
the stocks break off yeah yeah it just
makes it
easier um on the point that Matt was
making um yeah the other the other kind
of variable that I see people obviously
needing to control to some degree is the
the kind of like how much agitation are
you actually introducing and there's
obviously a sweet spot right like you
need to move something around but not
too much or you're going Break Stuff
yeah you don't want to go drill
drill speed is a little much yeah cuz
you got to keep in
mind that every time a leaf breaks in
there it releases chlorophyll yeah so
when you release chlorophyll that's when
you get the green slime and so but you
also have to wash hard enough that
you're you push the water through the
bud you know like I like how a river
rushes through a canyon
yeah that's what you want the water to
do so it'll rush through there and break
the heads off and carry them out so you
can't be too gentle but you can't be you
got to not be too rough and I have found
um you know my I use a 20 gallon and so
that means I'm washing 5 lbs of uh fresh
frozen yeah uh with 20 gallons of water
and so uh what I do is I do a 10 minute
wash and then I let it settle for 10
minutes and then I do so many every wash
I do is a 10minute wash I found that's a
pretty nice sweet spot where for one
your arms will get tired yes let me tell
you and two it seems to be a good amount
of agitation to you know without
breaking it up too much and totally
disintegrating
it and that's just something right there
you know that's something people as a
wash hash you'll have to learn how hard
to do it I mean people can see my videos
I I put some good work into it but you
know you're trying to that's I don't
know how many pounds of water and weed
in there that you're trying to you
know get all the heads off so do you
normally grind the weed up before you
start or like just put in full buds no
um honestly if it's perfect the perfect
way to have it is where you take off all
the fan leaf and trash Leaf um anything
that doesn't have crystals and then you
Buck it up into little like the buds you
don't want a giant bud in there you know
you want to take it off of the stem um
and the other cuz it's hard cuz you
don't want too many Cuts cuz like I said
every cut in there releases chlorophyll
yes but if you have too big of a bud
you're not going to be be able to get to
the inside of that that makes
sense but if you grind it up too much
then you're going to have way too much
chlorophyll makes a lot more sense some
people too um what I have found is if
I've had people bring me Leaf to wash
which I hate washing Leaf because it you
have to wash it different you cannot
wash Leaf like you wash bud and I think
that's a common mistake some people make
is assuming the instructions for what
people put out there for washing fresh
frozen flour is not how you're going to
want to wash your Leaf
interesting yeah I didn't know that no
clue it's a little different you got to
it's cuz the material is different it's
really not the same and so people have
washed their Leaf just like the flower
and they end up with a muddled mess like
you said when you over agitate you get
too much Leaf material in there cuz you
break it up you know it it mashes in
there even though it's in water and
Frozen it'll still break up and if it
gets too small it just passes right
through the bags that makes sense I mean
most of my hash was always like greenish
Brown and like after it was dried it
would just snap you know it's not not
not ideal too too much plant material
yeah just a bit just a bit I learned
later you know I got a washing machine
like a like one of those like you know
Chinese made little tiny washing
machines for home and I realized like
how slowly it was agitating stuff and I
was like oh oh oh okay so 45 minutes of
drill speed probably a little bit
much yes yeah little bit Annihilation
man Annihilation dude it it made hash it
made a lot of hash but not much
resin in
this yeah um so this is really good I I
love this little trunk of the
conversation cuz we just got to hear a
bunch of tips um but did want to draw
out a bit more from you peaches like can
you tell us about what your process is
like now for like the
business uh yeah cuz I definitely had to
adjust because well I used to have help
washing hash yeah um either bucka and I
washed together or we had a couple of uh
the friends from the veteran group that
would come help so I had to adjust a lot
to coming up here and doing it by myself
um and then wanting people wanting me to
produce a certain amount in a certain
time you know
that's would you mind like taking us
through the process as though you were
like like like in a in a normal workday
for you okay yeah so if I was coming in
wash hash the first thing I have to do
is I prep my washroom I got to put all
my equipment together get the air
conditioning running bags ready you want
to wet your bags down so they're not dry
um make sure everything's clean ready to
go um I line my trays with my liner so
when I'm ready to scoop they're ready to
go
um then let's see I chill my spoons for
scooping I always put them in ice and
water so they're cold um I fill up my Ig
glue Reservoir with ice and water um and
I put ice in my sprayer and then um I
take out my fresh Frozen from the
freezer and then uh I put it into a 220
wash bag inside the bruit with ice and
water and then that soaks for 30
minutes just sits there and soaks that's
what you let it
do then uh after that I will do a
10minute wash and then I let it settle
for 10 minutes so the hash sifts down
through and collects at the bottom um
now at home I used to scoop the bags
with every wash um but that's really not
time efficient and so now what I do uh
is I have ice in my catch can too I have
ice in the bottom of my catch can and
then I have my bags in there and um I
also because we only do full spectrum
hash which is the 70u through the 149 U
I don't have the 120 bag in there I
don't have my 104 bag and I don't have
my 90 bag in there I literally do a and
I don't catch 25 cuz 25's trash some
people will say whatever but I don't
catch 25 I've got my 45 bag my 70 bag my
150 bag the 180 bag and then a 220 bag
cuz I always make sure I put a 220 catch
bag in the top of my bags even though I
wash in a 220 bag that way let's say
your bag rips
yeah something happens and you get
material through then you don't get it
into your hash you catch it in that 220
bag first yeah um so uh so I let it
settle for 10 minutes and then I drain
it and I also keep ice in my 220 bag so
that when it go so I'm trying to keep my
catch can as cold as possible because
I'm not going to pull my bags for each
wash so I drain it and then I have a
trash can reservoir filled with water
and I take a like 10 L
Glass thing and I Scoop from there and I
fill up my can real quick cuz if I wait
for the hose it takes too long cuz I
have a food uh safe drinking water hose
you know MH and um but if I use that to
fill the Can it can take up to 20
minutes to fill the can so I fill my
reservoirs and I have them chilling and
sitting there and so I Scoop from there
I filled the can probably takes a couple
minutes and then I do another 10minute
wash M 10 minute settle drain it and
then I repeat the process again and wow
at home I used to do four to five washes
um but at work I do three washes and I'm
done cuz if I
found from my prior experience of
washing and scooping between each wash
that as your washes go you get less and
less hash and pretty much by your fist
wash unless you have like some excellent
washer you're not getting anything but
stocks you've already gotten the heads
and you'll know that if you've ever
washed and kept your washes separate and
then pressed your washes separate you
can tell that you get less of a return
the the farther washes you go
out that makes sense I also use a um
scope to to scope the weed to make sure
the heads are missing um you just a a a
bud and I break it open and I scope it
and I see like did I get most of the
heads are there stocks missing or you
know then never heard of that that's
yeah it's a great tip
yeah y I mean if you don't have a scope
I would the other thing I do is the
finger sticky test and uh you just grab
a bud and break it open and feel and if
your fingers aren't really sticky then
you probably don't have much THC
left um who so my main question is how
are you lifting these heavy
bags
u i mean that's pretty heavy though like
20 gallons of wet products well it's
really you know the it's really the five
pounds or so of weed that's wet with the
ice in there about 20 lb of ice and
however much 5 lbs of wet weed weighs
it's heavy but I I don't know I I just
do it
cuz I was just thinking about when I
used to do it with like even five gallon
bags but we didn't have a drain at the
bottom so we were lifting the ice and
the water and that [ __ ] was heavy as
[ __ ] no if I had to lift the water too I
probably couldn't do it yeah yeah no
that would be very heavy that's why I
was like it is heavy plus I'm standing
on a stool so that I'm waiting for my
ass to fall off of there I'm not lying
yeah oh no get a lad
I well what I want is a Pneumatic table
one that will go to the ground so I can
wash at the ground and then pump it up
and then drain it yeah but I don't have
that so we only have a table so I have
to stand on a little stool to wash hash
oh
no which I don't mind it's it's better
than sitting on a ladder they probably
make like cheap foot pump pneumatic
Tables by now though I was going to say
like you go sweet oh it's just it's it's
one of those things where it's a it's a
couple hundred expense that we haven't
got to get to yet for sure yeah yeah it
could go to testing it could go to any
number of places that's where it's gone
as testing I bet which I have to say I'm
proud to say I've passed all testing and
my coas came in and my rosin tested at
over 80% THC wow so I've and just as a
side note when when we met up you gave
me some um different uh products and I
I've had experience with Rosen um but
not a lot of experience with like really
professionally well-made rosin and now I
get rosin I did not get rosin at all I
did not understand it why it was so why
it would be a more expensive product why
people preferred it over other types but
that was some exceptional stuff so Props
to you on that wow thank you very much
that that really means a lot to me have
worked really hard she won the hash bash
in fact uh for for our server so if that
tells you anything
yeah yeah really cool should be very
proud earlier on you also touched on how
important drawing was at home when you
were learning what is the drawing
process like at work oh it's so much
easier um so once I scoop it out I put
it on the freeze dryer trays that are
lined with parchment paper and then you
put those in the freezer to prefreeze
cuz they need to be frozen solid before
you stick them in the freeze dryer and
then um I use the freeze dryer for
drying I do uh you do adjust the
temperature down um this is somewhere
where I'm going to come in conflict with
a lot of people um I've been using the
freeze dryer for a really long time
before anybody was even using it for
hash that I'm aware of I mean there
might have B but um the freeze dryer
works through sublimation okay so what
happens is the freeze dryer heats up and
releases the moisture from the product
and the vacuum sucks it up and it sticks
to the drum mhm and that's how things
get dry and so and and so the freeze
dryer Cycles through a heat and cooling
cycle as it does this because your
product's Frozen in there mhm cuz it
always freezes at
first so when we first started um I
reached out to somebody to ask about hey
what are you drying your with your
freeze dryer at and all this cuz I had
read that hash needed to be done at a
different temperature mhm and uh they
told me to run the freeze at
35° and I'm like that's not even out of
freezing like yeah you know like that's
so I I tried that and I got wet
hash it didn't
dry and so I was like I had already
thought when they told me that I was
like that that doesn't sound right
because it has to heat up to a certain
temperature in order for sublimation to
occur that's just how science Works um
so if your product's not defrosting at
all how is it releasing the moisture in
the right amount of time or even at all
I personally set my freeze dryer at
50° because that is warm enough where it
allows sublimation to occur but not so
hot that it affects the color or the
Tarpin or anything like that and you
know and I just have found better
results I don't ever have wet hash my
hash is always dry um and so because
you'll see a lot of people who tell you
oh after you make here rosing uh you
need to tint it overnight to release the
moisture and that's because you had wet
hash that you pressed because you didn't
sublimate out the moisture during the
freeze drying process because
everybody's so concerned about color
that they're literally not even really
freeze drying their stuff is that like a
thing in hash where they want just white
hash is that a demand or it is a demand
it's very frustrating because um um a
lot of people will pull early mhm you
know like everybody oh Harvest two weeks
early and you'll have lighter color well
I honestly don't like the taste of hash
rosin that's been pulled early because
anybody who's a grower of any sorts has
pulled their weed early or lost a branch
or something along those lines and then
dried it in the oven and smoked it right
yep okay so we we've all done that if so
that taste that
weird chlorophyll like taste that comes
with that early harvested weed that's
not ripe is what you get in your hash
you don't get the Tarpin you just get
that weird flavor yeah I
iric it to me it's an injustice to the
plant yeah I mean to me it just sounds
like marketing almost like uh how how
the customers are driving the genetics
Market by demanding cookies even though
Growers know that's not an ideal strain
to grow anymore blah blah blah we've
kind of all moved on past it but because
the consumer is demanding it it's almost
like nobody can move on yeah
yeah that makes sense all you know the
whole color thing came into play with
distillate and
BHO um everybody was all up oh the you
know you can't have dark distillate and
dark vho means it's bad and all that and
then somehow it transferred over to Hash
yeah and it's kind of ridiculous because
in my opinion some of the best hash is
made from Su
grown fullterm
weed yeah it's got flavors that you just
can't get
from does it have bigger
heads you know I mean I haven't I
haven't exactly examined the difference
in between uh the heads of indoor and
outdoor up close sure um I'll have a
chance to do that this year though I'm
interested take a look and see if
there's a difference I just I think it's
the turpine profile that develops you
know the sun does something out there
that's how the plant was meant to grow
yeah
um and indor makes great hash too I just
think you need to let it go all the way
let it do what it's supposed to do let
those heads get white get a few Amber in
there let it develop the tpin I mean I
when we grew the blueberry muffin in the
very beginning it smelled like
pickles and then it turned into this
amazing Jiffy blueberry mix so in a few
weeks time the turine profile changed so
imagine if you're pulling 2 weeks early
the change in the tpin that happens
during that development like there's a
surge of all kinds of stuff in that last
finishing part of flowering and people
are missing that because they're so hung
up on I want white
rosin that makes that yeah I mean is
there ever any white can you make white
hash that is completely fully finished
or would it always include some form of
Amber no it's always going to have Amber
because just how the plant is yeah so if
you're seeing white hash can you
artificially do that is there a case
where people are artificially doing it
um well a lot of people are passing CRC
off as hash and what's
CRC the color remediated stuff and it's
not even hash it's actually BHO that's
been run through the color remediation
thing and they remove all the color and
[ __ ] from it and then they sell it as
hash I didn't even know that was a thing
remediation they this is a thing that
they
make oh yeah yeah wow it's to help
remove you know cuz they first used it
like with distillate and stuff to help
remove pesticides or you know stuff from
the dirty distillate and then people
learned how to do it with BHO and then
people started saying oh well look at
this looks like rosin so I'm going to
sell it as Ros even though it's just
treated D yeah that's wild but you know
what like it's not too far off from what
I'm seeing in the market with them
passing off outdoor as indoor in the
myar bags because you can't really see
it from the outside and I don't know
that the market can identify It Anyways
either way if they're not Growers like
even I can have a hard time sometimes
you know like with that with your boss
[ __ ] the other day it was so well grown
and so
loud and you know it the bucket said
it's like 11 months old so I figured
this has to be just really well dried
and cured indoor but no it's the density
everything was so nice on it um I would
have never guessed so yeah I mean the
stuff I'm seen though is that C off as
outdoor to indoor is nowhere near like
that it is obviously like oxidized
outdoor
completely yeah that's a big problem
with the industry yeah it is and uh you
know like that's another aspect of not
having to deal with corporatocracy
though that's pretty cool if you guys
can make it work you know because you
won't have to play in those games you
don't as a smaller Corporation you don't
have to um appeal to investors and
people that aren't cannabis people you
know pushing the rules so that's pretty
cool yep exactly
yeah um I want to flip the question a
bit um and ask you you know for those of
us at home who we don't really know what
to look for in Hesh um in terms of
you've talked quite a bit about the
process and we just are now starting to
talk about the end product so in your
opinion you know how can we know when
hash is good in your opinion what's what
makes good hash um in terms of the
actual product are you talking visually
or smoking just to break it down for her
a little further those things so
basically once hash has arrived in your
hands in some form and you don't know
anything about the process how do you
judge that it's
good
H well I would say my first thing would
be just uh I always smell it first to
see what it smells like um yeah
I don't I don't ever judge by color
because uh you
know I already explain that part yeah um
but yeah
um I would say it's upon smoking it like
um if it's live rosin then you know you
want it to uh have a good melt in your
bowl and not um crackle or anything like
that cuz if it crackles or something
that means it has more moisture in it
um
uh and then and then I go by The Taste
when I when I smoke it how it tastes um
cuz I can't stand that early harvested
taste cuz it to me it's just this weird
I don't even know how to describe it
it's just a weird coating flavor um so
uh I also look for like if the tpin coat
your mouth that's also a good sign of a
nice hash because you get get that where
you you know for a couple minutes
afterwards you can actually taste it on
your palette and you're like yeah you're
like hm what was that that's what what
are these flavors that are happening um
now if it's like the full melt you want
to put it on a you know bowl and melt
that and see if it actually Bubbles and
melts down and does all that nice
gooiness into your bowl you
know now you
mentioning you go M no I was going to
ask there's there's a few terms you use
like live rosin live can you explain
that term because I think it's very
misunderstood even by
me so live rosin means that uh they cut
the plant when they cut the plant down
uh they bucked it up and immediately
froze it within like you know 20 to 30
minutes of it being cut off the plant
it's put into a bag like the way uh we
did it was we got dry ice and we put in
the ice chest and then we put a bag in
there cuz you don't want your weed to
come in contact with dry ice ever
because dry ice is manufactured with
chemicals and so it has chemical
residues on it so dry ice can be used
for stuff but you don't ever want your
stuff to come in contact with it and so
you put the bag in there and then as
you're trimming the weed um like we
would chop the plant down and hang it
upside down and then just start de
leafing and then you take the buds and
you chop those up and as you're chopping
them up you're dropping them into the
bag and they're
freezing and um the way we do it is we
put it in the turkey bag first because
if you you don't want a vacuum sealing
because when you vacuum seal it you
smash everything and they're going to
stick together and you're smashing tric
Combs and all that so you just want it
packed Loosely in a bag if you want to
put it in a vacuum seal bag you can but
don't vacuum seal it just seal it and
then it goes straight into a freezer and
that's where it stays until it gets
washed and that's what makes it live
rosin so how does that differ from fresh
frozen that's the same fresh Frozen
whole plant fresh frozen is what makes
live rosin gotcha gotcha I've always
wondered what live meant like if they
were keeping the plant in the pot and
like lifting it over to the press and
like smashing it like that's what I
thought it meant I didn't know like I've
seen the new term like living diamonds
and I'm like living now this is taking
it a step further like not just alive in
a pot like I thought but living diamonds
does this have you ever heard this term
that that's a new one for
me I don't know like are they still
growing in there they should be growing
in my jar by the way it sounds I don't
know I mean I've made solventless
diamonds but I wouldn't say they were
anywhere close to living and I I made
them with live rosin but I wouldn't say
they were living like yeah going from
live to living is is a Le is a it is a
leap a little bit you know like
something's inferred and implied and the
other is like why you're
alive I don't know I just I I remember
um some of the first people I saw using
the term live resin was over in Colorado
I can't remember who it was it was one
of the um it's one of those guys R
Pritchard or one of those dudes but yeah
it was it was very interesting um
watching that come up and then like
people gate keep over that term and
saying oh no that's really not what it
is this is what it is you know like
people redefining it as it went so I was
always kind of interested where the
definition ended up Landing in the end
yeah yeah um I also did want to
like just summarize some of what you
said
about how you evaluate um hash and you
and kind of like what man has has said
about flowers as well like you can't
really judge it based purely on its
visuals like you were saying um too much
variability too much diversity you can't
really tell that something's good based
purely on how it looks I was just
curious about one other quality um can
you tell anything from how pliable or
not the hashes is is is there does that
mean
anything um well if it there that would
be the the stuff that's a little less
pliable is what people refer to as fresh
press um it's what comes right off the
press but then it also depends on
strains um yeah every strain is
different uh when it comes to washing
and then the texture you get at the end
of the hash uh every strain has a total
different effect there's some strains
that are very creamy texture like um and
then there's ones that are almost
shatter
like uh yeah
mhm so it's it's hard to judge off the
texture as far as if it's a good quality
or not um yeah I I yeah I I would agree
too because like I've had with what
little hash experience I have because I
I'm such a noob to Hash other than like
smoking like bubble hash and like finger
hash you know like going into the
diamonds and all that stuff I'm fairly a
noob and so I remember making shatter
back in the day in San Diego and being
you know like I know what that tastes
like and seeing all these other hashes
come out that look like they're just
gooey tricomes I assume that shatter
would be the subpar stuff now especially
because it's so cheap now but like the
other day I haven't seen shatter that's
just as tasty as anything else whereas
like mentally I'm thinking it's cheaper
it must not be as good but I don't even
know if that's the
case do you have any opinions on that
one with shatter versus any of the other
sorts you know cuz the texture doesn't
necessarily have to do with the quality
as it well it in some cases it does cuz
like I know that if um when we were
messing around back in the day when we
would press some older weed like that
was been cured and older back when we
were doing the flower rosin thing um
stuff from older weed came out more
shatter likee like it didn't want to get
creamy it didn't want to
um have any but kind of texture but just
to make a mess like literally like glass
and so uh I don't know if BHO is along
those same factors where you know maybe
something that's older has a tendency to
not have those uh maybe the fats and
lipids that bind it together so
much so you're getting something that's
you know a totally different different
texture and that glass light
texture if that makes sense it's just so
interesting to me because like if you
smell shatter like you're not getting a
ton of scent off it even some of like
the dried rosin I don't get a ton of
scent off it but when you smoke it it's
like full flavor everything's there and
like it's all new experience to me you
know I love it I love learning all this
stuff what I don't like is like
dispensary typical dispensary stuff
because you just never know what kind of
Mystery
magic you're getting especially when
it's like black market dispensaries and
stuff that's true yeah yeah for
sure
um you touched on this a little bit
Peach but I did want to know what your
favorite plants or strains were for
extracts the first one that comes in my
head is strawberry
banana she's a
dream
she washes well and uh retains the
tarpine profile very well makes a great
textured rosin um just a a really good
one um a couple other that I've washed
that were good washers were uh grapes
and
cream uh that one M produced over
5% do you know what the lineage of that
one
is no honestly I do not probably an
exotic mic one I'm
guessing with and cream you know like
cookies and cream type stuff yeah yep
and he stole strawberry cream in put
made it strawberries and cream [ __ ]
okay that so that's two any any others
that you
like um Oreos was a good washer for me
um uh let's
see the Doughboy didn't do bad at all
either I hate washing gelato okay yeah
let's flip it what are the worst ones
what are the worst ones gelato okay it's
not just me fellas no what I've found
with gelato is it has very thin
membranes THC membrane heads you know
cuz that's part of what when you wash
hash you want something that the the
membrane of the THC head is kind of
durable so can
deal with the washing without shattering
yes so gelato likes to those heads
shatter really easy and so what happens
when you wash gelato is not only are
there not very many heads but the heads
that there are shatter and so you end up
with like a sticky mess in your
bags um cuz you know when it's a Sandy
resin it collects in a bundle and it's
down there in the water and it's
swirling around but when it the head
shatter like that they just want to
stick in your bag and you can't get them
out like even with the coldest spray
water they'll still stick in your bag
screen and it's just maddening because
it's a mess and you lose THC and like
it's just not fun cuz there's hardly
anything left when you scoop um except
for some fats and lipids and a little
bit of THC um
the other one besides that I have to say
now um I don't know whose train wreck it
was but it was a train wreck that was
grown by a friend of ours that it was a
horrible washer interesting um yeah we
washed five lbs of it and got seven
gr wait five PBS and you got seven
grams absolutely horrible cuz when we
washed 5 lbs of strawberry banana we got
over two ounces of rosin back oh wow
yeah that's
horrible so that that that's a
comparison for you from over 2 oz of
rosin to 7 gram of the same amount of
flour
washed so and that would be purely
because of its heads for whatever
reason uh yeah you know or it could be
how it was grown I mean um somebody else
might grow a train wreck that you know
washes better I'm not not sure but um it
has to do a lot of factors it's you know
it can go back from to the The Strain
itself and the structure of its heads
how it releases them how much THC it has
and then you go to the grower and that
person has to you know grow it right and
treat it right cuz otherwise it's not
going to be very good just like flow
it's the same thing if you don't put
that love and time and attention into it
you're not going to get Hash Hash is
only as good good as what's put into it
yeah it's kind of like what mat and I
were talking about a little bit In The
Name Game episode
where the plant when you're when you're
like processing the plant there just so
many different points of which you could
mess it up really um or different points
at which you could change something
quite quite majorly Without Really
knowing um yeah yeah I'm I'm excited to
see how uh The Punchy washes did you
you've gotten to smell all the the
examples now
right yes I did I'm excited about that
Punchy one cuz it had some really good
flavor and I'd be interested to see if
that gets to come through the wash and
into the hash itself actually fingers
crossed yeah yeah nice shout out to the
uh Punchy bloster yeah oh um we have the
review going up tonight so you know
anybody watching this video can go back
and check out the reviews of the same
samples that she's talking about right
now yeah it'll be like a week in the
past now but yes yes people can check
that out um okay well I did want to
round out some of the tick side and I
wanted to kind of bring it back to
people who make hash at home and just
want want to kind of maybe ask you a
difficult question which is
like from all your experience you know
what would be some of your like top tips
for people making hash at home you've
sort of touched on a little bit of this
already uh so don't don't worry about
repeating yourself but you know what are
the stages and what are the techniques
to focus
on um well if you're at home you know I
have made some bomb hash in my kitchen
without a cold room you know everybody
says you have to have a cold room and um
it does help um I'm not going to lie but
if you're at home you know wait till
night time and turn on your
AC so it's cooler in there um
the other thing would be uh have
a an Igloo cooler you know like you put
water in like uh construction guys use
them all the time they're drinking water
safe so you get yourself an Eglo cool
cooler and you fill that up with ice and
water and then you have your pump
sprayer and you fill that up with ice
and when you're going to scoop your bags
and rinse you make sure you fill your
sprayer that's full of ice with the ice
water from that Igloo
because the main important thing when
collecting your hash and doing the whole
hash process is keeping things cold and
so at home you're battling not having a
cold room and so having your uh spray
water chilled and ready having your
sprayer cold is essential and then um I
have found um by putting ice in the
bottom of my catch can under the bags
like in the bottom where the water goes
and then in my 220 bag in the top I'll
put ice in there too cuz that'll help
keep your catch can cold yeah um mhm and
then I would say make sure you
um soak your or put your Scoops and ice
water so they're nice and cold
um the using the two
220s make sure you you know you wash in
your wash bag 220 and then use a catch
220 um and
then um at home you do have to I do not
recommend doing several washes in them
pulling at home you're going to want to
do your 10minute wash with and and this
would vary I mean if you've got a
small setup like a one gallon you're
going to want to wash for 5 minutes not
right you know that it IT sizes up as
you go so you don't because you don't
want to overwash and I think sometimes a
lot of people um overwash more than they
underwash and so at home you're going to
want to do your wash and your settle and
your drain and then you're going to want
to collect your bags and then um repeat
the process after that and so as and
that's how when you collect those bags
you look and see how much hash you're
getting in there
and then after each wash you evaluate
those scoops of hash
and that's how you can determine for
yourself how many washes you want to do
like I said at home sometimes I would do
four or five washes where at work I do
three and I'm done trying to get it you
know through the cycles so at home I
would recommend you know as you scoop
you know use your intuition if you look
like you're still getting a good amount
in there then go another wash but if
it's like a minuscule amount and you're
like I don't know if it's worth all that
hassle then it's time to call it quits
there those are really good tips um
anything on the drying at home or yeah
any tips for like how we know people
don't have a freeze dryer obviously so
what what's the next best thing people
can do um well the the they want to you
know use the Micron screen
and just like we did back in the day
with the um put it on the cardboard so
it pulls out the moisture and then um
keep
it covered in the refrigerator so it
doesn't oxidize too much but it still
will you know release the moisture and
uh do all that and then there's the
whole micro planing it after that and
then letting it dry some more on the
screens
um that's the best thing you can you can
do and if you don't care about color
then you don't have to worry about the
air too much um and most people who are
drying air dry anyways aren't too
worried about color cuz it's already
going to be a little darker because of
the air drying unfortunately air is the
enemy of hash so yeah um
yeah okay I had one one last one on
people for people at home which
is um in terms of the actual process of
washing or agitating you know what what
is your like ideal for someone at
home
um well I would not use a electric mixer
of any sort or a drill no drills no um
you can buy you know you can either buy
a whisk at the store some people like to
use whisk um The Kitchen Store is a
great place to go or like the restaurant
supply store uh to you don't mean like a
hand whisk right like a machine whisk no
well no they're like like bigger whisk
um well it depends on the size of your
buckets like if you're using a one
gallon and yeah you could use a little
hand whisk no problem and I would say
like I say a five a five minute
agitation on that on a on a little one
gallon bucket now if you're going to go
to a 5 gallon bucket you could probably
do a 10minute and be totally fine and I
mean you're not going to want to beat
the hell out of it but you got to try to
push the water through the buds so
you're going to want to wash it I mean
if you've ever watched a washing machine
you know like not the new ones that
don't have the thing but you know old
school ones that spun you know that's if
you've watched any hash machine on
Instagram run you can see
how it it it does push stuff through
it's not too gentle of a process but
it's also you know it's it's a learning
process you can tell people and that's
what I find is people a lot of times
somebody told me they washed for 25
minutes and I'm like why 25 minutes
straight and how many times and he was
like four times and I was like oh no no
that's totally
unnecessary you know cuz you're you know
you don't want to beat the hell out of
stuff yeah so um I can I can verify you
don't want to beat the hell out of
stuff because you have to remember the
longer it's in the water the it if your
product's Frozen it's defrosting and
what you'll see is as it defrost it will
start to release chlorophyll more and so
once that starts to happen is when you
you know you don't want to be washing
forever because you're trying to do it
in a short amount of time before that
weed gets so saturated it's a sloppy
mess
yeah thanks nice thank you
so many um gems that you've dropped
already um I'm going to have to rewatch
this a few times just yeah just to get
some of this down I know a lot of it
seems basic but I am so basic when it
comes to Hash making I I will need to
yeah because I'm I'm going to do a round
soon I think um so I'm gonna try and try
and absorb as much of this as
possible um we wanted to maybe do a
little uh tangent away from from the
hash for a moment
and ask you about your
Edibles
yeah I don't have no way to begin I mean
did Matt get to try anything I did I got
to try a bunch and um you know I'm not a
big edible person I love the FL flavor
of cannabis and stuff but I've always
found it's either like my friends have
put like you know 10 grams into a
brownie of hash and I'll just be total
for three days or I just don't get
affected too much but these were really
nice man and it wasn't just like the
effect it was the actual flavor the
things I'd never seen before and and I
don't know if you want to talk about
like some of the milk dads stuff like
that that that are very unique and and
just
amazing well um you know I've I've been
doing Edibles since we've been doing
weed um at first I did you know
caramel's cookies and all that stuff um
but when we got the freeze dryer um
bakashot came to me and he's like hey
have you seen or ever heard of
freeze-dried Skittles and I'm like of
course not like I don't know anything
about the freeze dryer yet we just got
it I'm reading the book here and it
talks about you know you can do ice
cream and I'm like I remember space you
know actually not ice cream from school
I remember that and that's obviously
what this is and he's like
dude like we should look into freeze dry
candies and I was
like okay so we started with hash and
then I threw in some Skittles and
figured out how to medicate them and it
was kind of over from there yeah I bet I
started doing all kinds of stuff I
learned you know in my opinion if a
candy like there's certain candies that
don't work mik and I don't work
chocolate doesn't freeze dry peanut
butter doesn't freeze dry um
there's certain candies that just don't
want to do things others do you know
it's just a matter like licorice just
gets hard and it's and and I I only do
candies that change into a texture
that's appealing like to me if it just
freees and gets hard that doesn't mean
it's actually worth it yeah
exactly so it was a lot of trial and
error with things
um but uh so yeah I started doing the
freeze dryed candies cuz because I
wanted to have something that nobody
else had on the market everybody has the
same Edibles everybody's got gummies
they do brownies they do all the you
know the same sh lollipops yeah yes and
so go ahead I have a I have a
provocation here um which is I'm someone
who's like why mix food and the you know
and cannabis why not just keep them
separate make good candy sure but why
why mix them like what's the
point well because consuming cannabis
has a totally different
effect and
um there are some people who don't like
to smoke and some people who can't smoke
uh people with COPD and things like that
that can't actually you know smoke
cannabis can use it and consume it and
get the benefits from it by eating
it and um and people eat it at work and
do it in front of everyone they have
nobody has any clue it's nice and sneaky
you know yeah that's that's one of
things to me yeah sorry you go paches um
I like the Edibles to be able to sleep
at night like when I travel and stuff
and I'm not going to get a good at night
sleep that's when I like to use Edibles
cuz I honestly as much as I love making
Edibles I hate the taste to we with a
passion like it'll almost make me puke I
love it I love it so much stand it
that's funny cuz you make such good
stuff with it it's unreal oh you should
see my face there's times when I've made
brownies right and I like out of habit
lick my finger and be so sorry oh my God
so sorry that I did that because I just
I can't stand the taste of it but the
thing about my Edibles I like is they
don't have that overwhelming weed flavor
that I can't get past I mean I've had
Edibles we bought back in the day that I
literally couldn't eat I was like I
can't I'm going to puke like I bet and
so part of my goal was to create Edibles
that not were only unique in style but
didn't have such a strong flavor that
maybe people want to eat them and that
was part of the feedback I've got from
people is that they do enjoy my Edibles
because they're not such an overwhelming
weed flavor that they can't actually
enjoy
it yeah I know my my chick was doing
literal dances as she ate your cucumbers
your your uh freeze-dried cucumbers and
they had like Dill on them and stuff so
they were kind of pickly yeah they were
like pickle chip they were she is so in
love with those things so you even make
healthy items too now that um are as
well yes that was one of my goals too is
um one I don't think you should have to
eat 1,000 calories to get high yeah it's
not right Point um can is supposed to be
medicine and a lot of people are using
um it for for illnesses and for cancer
and we all know sugar feeds a lot of
cancers and
so when I developed my edible line the
one there's several things I kept in
mind one was serving size none of my
bags of candy are more than a serving of
candy yeah you don't have to eat two
whole bags of Skittles to get high yeah
you get 25 Skittles in a bag which is
the serving size of one of those little
bags of Skittles that you would get and
that's what you get same thing with all
the other candies it's not a huge
serving and then I also wanted to do
healthy ones so that somebody who can't
eat candy like me yeah yes can have a
fruit and I just started doing the
vegetables recently um but I've been
doing fruit for a long time because to
me that was like you can put it in
yogurt you can put it in a smoothie um
you can eat it straight I mean it's
great and it's healthy like you you can
consume it and not feel guilty yeah and
for somebody who's a cancer patient and
they want to consume a certain amount of
cannabis a day um I think it's important
for somebody to have a healthy choice to
do
that yeah absolutely and and like you
said ingestions actually the strongest
way to take in cannabis in the first
place so if someone has like a serious
serious pain management issue like maybe
like trying to sit there and smoke
joints every 10 minutes it's going to be
a bit much on their lungs so yeah you
can eat one hash Brownie and be toasted
for a few days and be good you know
yep yeah I think you should be really
proud of those um the the healthy items
that you have too because you just I
don't really see that in dispensaries or
Collective too often where you're seeing
like like cucumber chips and stuff
that's that was really really out of the
box and super
delicious thank you I'm really glad she
lik them yeah I'm I'm even though I'm
diabetic I still got to try a Milk Dud
and those were insane I don't even like
Milk Duds but these things you put it it
was like a ball like this big and you
put it in your mouth and it just melts
it just melt it D it was so heav heav it
was so heav so good so yeah I'm I'm I'm
a fan I'm a fan for life thank you
that's part of the other cool thing
about some of the freeze-dried things is
stuff that like people who have teeth
problems um yes you know some people
can't eat salt water taffy anymore uh
any kind of Taffy and when you freeze
just you know like the caramel inside
the milk that is it puffs up and it
becomes that crunchy ball of goodness
and So like um saltwater taffy does the
same thing wow it puffs into a little
ball and so it just melts in your mouth
and so people who can't eat those things
anymore can now eat them in a and
experience that same flavor just in a
different way and experience without
losing a tooth or messing up their
dental work or any of that stuff yeah
that's for real I I got jacked up te
since I was young so like that's a
serious consider like hard candies and
stuff like that I don't even mess with
it because I don't want to knock out
teeth or anything crazy but yeah these
just melt in your mouth it was insane
insane so good I'm jealous you should be
you really should be
they maybe one day I'll make it over
maybe one day yeah you've got to you've
got your next party yes you definitely
must um well I I did actually have more
questions uh within the like extracts or
hash section but I also thought we could
move to some more General open questions
about
you know your Reflections on your time
uh in the industry and and and whatnot
and then maybe if we have time after
that we can come back to some of the um
other extract questions yeah so I did
want to come back to
the you know um how has it been you know
you you you mentioned women in the
context of like veterans and like them
needing safe spaces what's it like for
you as a woman in the in the in the in
the cannabis
um feel free to be as honest as you want
you know or not yeah yeah as diplomatic
or as not as you to be well it's
definitely a man a male dominated
industry um yeah that's for damn sure
and for me I think my version of being a
woman in the industry is probably a
little different than some others
because I don't have any big names
behind behind me I don't I'm not related
to anybody famous um yeah I've had to
fight tooth and nail to be where I am I
remember going to get a job trying to
get a job at the local grow store and
they told me they wouldn't hire me
because I was a
girl and I guarantee I could grow better
weed than anybody there I promise you
could God knocked the teeth so and for
example when I first started this job um
um there was another guy that uh he he
had actually wanted to do a article on
me uh for some about flower rosin that
he had gotten from me um and
uh anyway he he got to talking with the
people who I'm involved with pure
organic medicinals and he actually
during a period of time um I had cuz I'm
a two-time cancer Survivor I've had
breast cancer and ovarian cancer so a
couple years ago I had a scare where I
thought my breast cancer had come back
and so I wasn't able to come up to work
uh for like 2 weeks because I had to go
to my appointments and have a mammogram
and ultrasound and all this stuff and
during that time period this guy tried
to take my
job wow and I guarantee if I had been a
male he to try to do that no yeah and uh
cuz he was trying to set his girlfriend
up to be the female presser for our
company and you know and I'm like
um I am a
female I don't I don't I don't need help
like um so it it's been hard you know I
went and took uh they paid for me to
take a class a hash class this the
puranic paper for me to go take this
hash class just to see what was going on
out there and uh I found it funny cuz we
went to the class and when I first
showed up they're like oh are you here
to drop somebody
off um no I'm here to take the class oh
okay and then um I I was nice I brought
you know cuz I I'm a giving person so I
brought some edibles with me and I
handed them out and I find it funny that
after I paid for a class and took the
class and I watched that those people in
that class follow everybody who took the
class but not one of them followed me
that's wild that is so wild to me they
are so St it's sad oh man yeah it's sad
but also like unsurprising um
unfortunately to me it's also their loss
like even in our group you know like our
group it is a very good demographic of
mostly male like the Cannabis Community
is it's like a few females and 99% male
but like not at any time would I have
ever thought to not like respect
your experience and skills because
you're a woman like it wouldn't have
mattered if your name was Sweet Peach
kiss or douge Bob fresh you know like it
wouldn't have mattered and I just it
blows my mind that people are so
ignorant they'll walk away from some
someone super talented that they could
learn a lot from just to uh not have to
cater to women or some annoying [ __ ] I I
don't get it myself
but it is that I just want to say you
know shout out and respect to all the
women in the industry it can't be easy
um DN right for all those
reasons um and yeah I think you know
we're going to we we do what we can I
think within our little Community to to
make sure that you know people feel as
as safe and as comfortable and as
welcome as we can make them um but yeah
it's definitely a set of problems that
like this industry is not dealt with yet
not very well not at all not at all yeah
not to mention I could tell you a couple
of hash makers who I've had to block cuz
they you know for some reason find it
necessary to find send pictures and not
hash oh yeah and that's another thing in
our like I hear this all the time guys
keep your dick in your pants women don't
want to see that it's ugly like no I've
never heard heard of a woman in my life
being like man I'd really like to see
some someone's penis that's a very
attractive fleshy member like what do
they think like this is not how it works
it's not how much rather see a picture
of hash yeah right show me your hash
show me something that will impress me
not your little dick right yeah cuz now
I got to block you and [ __ ] all that
cuz it's totally inappropriate and
unnecessary and like really and it
creates a lot of bad feelings too
because it's not just you it's your man
too because now you know what I mean no
thought at all in it no would you do
that to any other male hash maker I'm
sorry do you do you send your dick kick
to a to a guy maybe it's actually what
we need to start doing we need to we
need to start equalizing things so yes
we do I'm going to start sending my dick
to every breeder out there in hash maker
you're welcome I'll just start sending
someone else's dick to every other guy
out there well yeah I'm not really going
to send mine I don't want to get made
fun
of to pick up yeah
anyway um yeah yeah so you know again
like mad respect it's it must be one of
those things where like they're
such the obstacles that you face must be
so subtle sometimes and so Sinister and
no one else can see them um you know a
lot of the men won't be able to see what
you guys are facing and yeah um
hopefully over time we hear more stories
like yours and you know like with
anything else we just um draw people's
attention to the fact that these things
happen um yeah still y you know I just
to add to this I watched you know I I
had had mentioned that we were going to
be putting Miss Jill seeds on the site
and and I was pretty disgusted at the
response that that the male people were
giving her a lot of it had nothing to do
with her as like being a person it was
more about her being female and I just
judging her off just being female and it
was just so bad and I ended up blocking
so many people that day it's just yeah
do better please do better can ofis
Community you know that's part of why I
don't post pictures like uh of myself
smoking and doing all that cuz I I want
to be taken seriously I don't want to be
seen as an influencer or a dab ho I've
had to work really hard to not be
considered as a dab ho you know um oh
God you have to work extra hard you have
to work extra hard and that's that's not
fair
mind yeah yeah it's actually so terrible
like yeah what do you have to wear like
fake glasses to look smarter and I don't
know like keep your hair shorter man
it's actually so
ridiculous no I actually you know I
posted a picture of myself washing hash
and I I'm sorry I have boobs I'm a
female and sometimes in the cold room
even in the middle of the summer it's
cold but when you're washing hash you'll
get warm like I do I don't know maybe
it's just hot flash or whatever anyway
so I posted a video of me watching hash
because I'm proud of the fact that I can
do this by myself like I don't have a
team I don't have any help up here it's
literally Me by myself and I do it the
whole way through and I I've take great
pride in that and um some guy po
commented on my post oh well you know
just using your boobs to sell hash blah
blah blah and I was
like
fo how is it that a guy can post himself
watching hash and nobody says [ __ ] about
him but because I have
boobs you're going to make shitty
comments to me that I'm trying to use my
boobs to sell hash really they just
threatened I mean it's just to me that's
just like threatened
easy yeah exactly I I I find out real
quick the men who have egos yeah about
it by the way people respond to me talk
to me um you know the discord's been
great people are amazing it's become
it's a way better Community um there
than I've found anywhere else so um that
makes me happy props to you for creating
that cuz you know it the guys in there
are funny as hell though I have to say
yeah you know like I have to remind
myself like to be extra but like you
don't ever get offended by my dumbass
dick jokes or anything else I'm used to
like
no are you kidding cuz growing you know
being in the Cannabis industry this
whole time pretty much it's all been
guys I've always been what I call Wendy
of the Peter Pan boys yeah yeah the lost
boys I'm usually the only girl of the
group and it's all a bunch of crazy wild
guys doing whatever and I'm over here
like can we not do that so we don't
die
yeah yeah I'm like the voice of reason
of everybody so that's kind of how
Discord
feels yeah I mean that's that's the
other funny part like I think people see
a you know identify someone as a woman
and they're like please mother me I'm
going to do some naughty stuff can you
tell me not to do it yeah um does happen
um and I don't know at the same time I
will say like we do have a few DED
people in our in our community but
overall I think it's like a pretty good
place and sometimes they hide in plain
sight
yeah but you know we we're always
keeping an eye on it we're always
looking at ways to improve it um so very
much appreciate your presence there um
yeah me too yeah okay and you guys have
both been an awesome awesome yeah
great yeah yeah well thank you yeah
Power couple I think is what people in
the server I believe that's a
term um I did want to move on to you
kind of reflecting more on GI Janes as
well um as kind of adjacent um so you
mentioned that it kind of slowed down
over Co um is it starting back up is it
still
active we're currently not active
because I'm trying to find a place to
meet um I can't really afford to rent
somewhere for us all to meet and um I
live up in the hills and I well plus I
don't let strangers come to my house I
mean I do know these ladies but like if
we have a group somebody who wants to
come that I don't know I I can't trust
people at my house um yeah so we're I
I'm I'm still currently looking for a
meeting place cuz it needs to be
somewhere where we can hang out and
smoke yes you know um not many people
allow that yeah I was just thinking
sorry this is totally an interruption
but I was just thinking um I don't know
how the women are with tick but you know
you could always set up like a little
Discord just for them as well um in the
absence of like a you know a physical
space um you could have a little Discord
server a great idea we'll help you shut
it up yeah if you need help let us know
but pretty easy honestly that's a great
idea wow because you know y'all could
even do like little virtual seses and
stuff
um yeah because I don't know I I always
think about part of it is the
camaraderie that they have to be able to
talk and hang out and um wow that's a
you just
totally yeah thank you I think Matt
knows this but I always have like an eye
towards like what it takes to build
community and sustain it um so yeah I'm
always interested in that kind of
thing yeah I love I love that idea to I
just got to say that again like the
forethought into it the that there are
women getting together to speak about
this stuff it's amazing I love it yeah
so cool well yeah you know the being you
know I've been a victim in my life um I
was raped when I was 18 um and I also
when I was in sixth grade A boy tried
to uh take me into the bushes on the way
home from school and then uh when I was
uh I used to manage the
Pines bar
um and uh I was doing it was a really
great job um it was perfect I was able
to support us I was a
bartender and one night uh I had asked
some guys to leave the bar cuz they were
being too rowdy and I did exactly what
buckshaw asked me not to ever do which
was come out from behind the bar yeah
and escort people out oh uh cuz security
was busy
out on the patio and so as I was walking
out the door telling these people to
leave uh a gentleman came running up
from behind me and took a giant flying
leap and used the back of my head as a
punching bag what the
hell I lost Consciousness hit the ground
um I had to go to the emergency room um
it took me a year of physical therapy to
recover oh my God and I actually ended
up with a permanent disability where I
lost 30% of the use of my right arm yeah
um and I wasn't able to bartend anymore
you can't bartend without your right
hand did they catch
him no no my brother-in-law had him for
5 minutes on the table beating the [ __ ]
out of him until security came and
grabbed him off of him and let the guy
run out the door oh my would oh my God
well at least he got some he did he got
he got some he he did get some but he
didn't get what he deserved because he
messed up my entire life you never hit
like I don't care who you are if it's a
man woman you never hit someone in the
back of the head because the
consequences of this part of your your
spine like it's it's so permanent and
even if you're mad at someone the damage
you can do not only to them but to your
life as far as prison goes is immense so
please anybody listening never ever
think to do that never it's horrible
last to I can't imagine yeah if I had
seen it coming I at least could have
fought back but I I had no clue and it
was so quick I just remember this
blinding pain in my head that just came
forward and then like I was on the
ground and then his girlfriend's like
can I buy you a shot of
tequila bro no no that's okay but so
that's part of why I'm also proud of
being able to wash hash like I do is
that you know I'm I'm disabled I my
right arm and shoulder has been [ __ ]
up ever since then yeah um and he
totally yanked out the rug from under my
feet I mean I had a job that supported
us I made really really really good
money like I was the manager and head
bartender like and we had I don't know
if you thousandfold had ever heard of
Ki travel I know what that is yeah you
know so we had Ki night on
Thursdays every Thursday night I did
that whole tour bus and everybody was
from Australia and New Zealand and oh
man those were the best
Nights Fun I have to
say a popular aie Aussie Aussie oi oi oi
karaoke karaoke
night yeah kour are are a really popular
thing for like um the younger people
who've like you know they go on what
they call the OE overseas experience
because the country is so isolated you
know they need to go somewhere um that's
really cool that you've you've come
across some of those people that's funny
oh yeah it was great because you know uh
we're right by the gateway to yuse so
we're part of that whole uh you know
come see everything yeah so it was how
how far do you have to travel to
work up here I drive six hours what yeah
wow I had no idea you stay there right
you don't you don't go back home you
stay there for a few days oh no I stay
in a hotel yet wow I had no idea you
drove that far up north holy crap that's
a lot of that's again commendable that's
hardworking going way out of your way to
to get this done so Props on that yeah
thank you like I said it's it's been not
been easy it's been a hard road to try
to do this
yeah yeah I mean speaking of Hard Road
you know thank you again so much for
sharing um you know some of those
stories you know
um really really really hard stuff um
and I hope everyone who's listening like
you know take something away from that
um
yeah well you know we are coming I think
close to the end um and I wanted to ask
you know what's next for you what's next
for like like the business and yeah what
are you excited about well I'm excited
about hitting
distribution um uh and things actually
hitting the market uh that's probably
com is it is near that's what I've been
doing this last few days is getting
everything grammed up and packaged um it
just takes a while because it's only me
I'm the only one that does all the
gramming uh because I'm the only one
with the quality
control
um yeah makes sense so it it takes a
while to and plus I can't be up here you
know I have my other businesses I run um
and so it's it's hard I I come up here
and I do some work but then I got to go
home and do work and so I can't be up
here plus I can't afford a hotel for
more than a couple days at a time I bet
because you're investing your own money
in this to do this correct like the gas
Hotel well yeah between gas and hotel
and all that yeah sometimes they pay me
like when they have money and then like
I said sometimes they don't so it's you
know it's a labor of love for you and
and hoping it yes it is yeah so getting
to hit distribution means I will be
getting a paycheck eventually like
that's what I'm hoping for so this
becomes my full-time job so I can fully
immerse in it and then if it all takes
off then they're supposed to put in a
kitchen so that then my Edibles can hit
the market and that's probably another
thing that I'm most excited about money
money when people taste your Edibles
that's money I'm telling you I've tried
so many Edibles it's
money you have to let me and Matt know
when things are starting up so we can
like
um you know spread the word yeah I will
definitely
absolutely yeah um on that note you know
anything else from either of you any
other reflection
questions no I I'm good um Peach is
there anything you want to plug any
anything you wanted to say specifically
get get any messages out there um well
you guys helped me plug pure organic
medicinals I mean that's the company
that I'm representing and working for
and so when you guys see it on the
shelves just know that I made that hash
by
hand right it's been hand washed so um I
think that's it you know I
mean it's pretty than you so much I me
do that I think it's been such a good uh
conversation you know what a great mix
of like you know your personal Journey
um the tech uh the industry you know
some of your experiences as a woman like
this has been such a cool episode so
thank you so much thank you thank you I
hope I didn't ramble too much not at all
no was great I learned a lot um I
learned a lot and and like I said I'm
going to have to go back and relisten to
this several times as I'm sure a lot of
people will because there's a lot of
good info here for especially for
inspiring like hash makers like this is
this is
great I'm thinking about starting my own
Discord for hash so you know people want
to ask me questions I'll ask you know I
answer questions I'm not one of the
people that's not going to tell you
things so
yeah
we could also set up like a uh an
extract Channel um I know we sort of
have the hash bash maybe we could
convert that into like an extract
Channel as well sure whatever yeah of
course you know like do go try setting
up these other communities especially
like you know I was floating that idea
GI Mary Janes I think that could be a
really cool idea um yeah just let us
know if you need any help as well
absolutely I will for sure I probably
will be picking your
brains yeah we're always around
yeah especially for you guys yeah thank
you all right thousand you got
anything no I think that's us um all
right I think at this point just a
reminder you know it would be now last
week where we launched the Codex so
don't forget to check out the Codex our
freshly launched strain database uh
where you get to see you know to our
best knowledge or to Matt's best
knowledge um a sense of genealogy
um for all our biggest
names but yeah apart from
that uh I guess that'll be it um go
check out Riot seeds.com for all your
seeds and femin spray needs um go check
out our patreon Discord that's where all
of us hang out including Miss peaches
and uh yeah codex breeders syndicate.com
go check out The Punchy review and uh
yeah we'll be seeing you next time
thanks for joining I will I will drop
link LS to everything in the description
so um you know how you can find Sweet
Peach and all that yeah I'll drop all
that in the description awesome because
I suck at doing that all right everyone
you have a wonderful week
cheers want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it
out