[Music]
welcome to breeders syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
lived it i'm matthew owner of riot seeds
i'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
it's interesting and like the hash thing
um you know the hash thing is is kind of
cool because you can we can widen it out
a little bit
in the sense of um you know and talk
about like some traditional weed
cultures yeah because there is a real
divide in weed cultures between cultures
that grew weed primarily to make hashish
sure uh and cultures that grew weed
primarily to smoke weed
you know yeah um and you know that that
aspect and those choices made
um made a lot of differences for people
and now for a long time america
one of the benefits of america is that
we're isolated from everywhere we have
like big oceans
yeah on either side and all that but
we're very far away from the hash
culture
yeah right so traditionally
uh all the best hash sort of stays local
uh and then some small amount of it
would go to europe right yeah
and what america typically got
was uh the b and c grade yeah you know
so a lot of times americans especially
canadians are a little different
canadians had some better connections
and some better smuggling that happened
up there yeah so they sometimes saw a
little bit better of a grade but
americans especially
um
you know they uh we got the shaft as far
as high grade
so a lot of people think of
um imagine if your view of kind bud was
like beasters
yeah and that's what you thought it was
because that's the only thing you've
experienced a lot of people if you
haven't been to europe and you haven't
and you haven't and you haven't been
tied into those communities right yeah
you probably haven't smoked the best of
the best
and so there's a lot of hash people in
america that think like the last 10 or
14 years of sort of like the hash
revolution that's happened over here
that they have the best hash by far that
they blow away all the traditional
cultures by far
and that they're kind of on the cutting
edge and they've changed the game
and they figured it out nobody else did
yeah
right which is pretty far from the case
yeah you know so it's like a lot of
those things where um
you know we can we can kind of riff on
that for a little bit
um so maybe you can kind of talk we can
we can start like maybe we'll we'll
we'll start from the beginning where
it's like the hash culture sort of comes
from
the
i would say the the near east and the
middle east yeah i would say indian
indian culture india
chinese maybe yeah i mean and and
probably the old probably the oldest way
to smoke cannabis
uh before they even figured out how to
smoke flour besides like burning flowers
on braziers or something yeah is the
hand rub
yeah you know um
and that india pakistan afghanistan iran
the middle east you can go into like
lebanon and israel in those areas and
you can go through north africa all the
way to morocco and that's sort of hash
culture yeah
right
um in terms of like people grew weed
just make to turn weed into hash yeah
where
you start getting into like
um southeast asia
uh and you know and especially the new
world like mexico and colombia and
panama and these type of places in
africa
they mostly smoke wheat
yeah and you know um one that that
caught me off guard was nepal
i always think of like nepalese temple
balls and that kind of hash culture but
if i remember correctly when i was
studying it most of it was a flower
culture it was most it was it was a
little bit of both yeah you know um but
you know and so
to be to perfectly honest like when i
started going to amsterdam um i i went
there in search of seats
yeah you know and then i started getting
introduced to hash and
uh you know i smoked a bunch of stuff
but in the coffee shops
uh it's a lot like you know it's a lot
like dispensaries or whatever there's a
wide variety yeah of mids and junk and
really good and pretty decent and stuff
and it wasn't until i met collectors
yeah um that started explaining to me
like how it all worked
yeah right
um and so
there's an aspect maybe we maybe i could
talk for a minute about before we talk
about the regional differences for a
second maybe i could talk about like
uh something that we chat about often
which is the vast difference between how
traditional hash is made
um and how
american hash is made yeah right so the
american hash
uh the way it's made um in most cases
is you it's it's you know a lot of times
it's called single source right
it's a single clone
right
um grown in either depths or outdoor or
indoor or whatever and that single clone
is usually you know dried or fresh
frozen and then it's you know it's
processed um and then it's usually
refrigerated or frozen right away or
stored well until use and it's used
pretty quickly
yeah right
where in traditional hash culture
you're harvesting a field of seeds
yeah right so you know in america it's
like oh i'm going to pull down this
greenhouse and it's all for lack of a
better it's all gmo yeah it's all the
same cut you know same terpene profile
same cbd cbn thc all that it's the same
thing
yeah but if you're if you're harvesting
it from any other region you're going to
get the full range of expression of that
wine
yeah because they're harvesting
thousands of sisters yeah
and then they're processing those
sisters and unlike unlike mo if you're
if you're talking about like dry sift
and stuff like that they tend to let
that hash age
yeah
on the plant for a number of months
and then when it's cold and bone dry
they start a sifting process yeah
right and then from that sifting process
um you know then they make it into
various grades
and then they press it right so that's
not done in america at all
all of your all of your terp [ __ ] all of
your whether it's fresh frozen or it's
you know bho or it's it's uh
you know uh whatever extraction you're
doing it's usually single source yeah
and it's not aged usually the plant is
taken down fresh
and as soon as they can make the hash
they make the hash yeah right and so
you know i'm not exactly the expert on
the science or whatever but definitely
aging it creates you know it it
transfers things
from one to the other right certain
amounts of cbn or cbd or this or that or
whatever is converted into other
bioactives what not and then on top of
that when
uh we've wanted to get uh
our buddy bodhi on here for a long time
to do like a hippie hashish trail kind
of episode
yeah and so we might get more in depth
with that but
when
essentially when europeans and white
people first started going to the hash
regions and looking for export
most hash there was a lot of hash that
was one two three years old
yeah you know a lot of the best hashish
uh wasn't smoked until it was over a
year or two years old
yikes
right i guess it's just different
climate though you know it was different
climate
it was stored very differently you know
and they just thought that it was it was
not like it wasn't ready yet
yeah
you know and so um and what's
interesting about this is that if you go
to amsterdam
and you have all these people that have
all the same access to all the same tech
that we do here yeah as far as
extracting modern cultivars for hashish
and all the hash heads over there
will tell you
that the best hash that they smoke is
the top import
they can use pollinators they can use
tumblers they can fresh froze and freeze
dry and microplane and do all the tricks
that people win awards with over here
yeah and they still think that hash is
inferior in quality and effect
to the best of the best import
right
and
you know but in america we all think
that our [ __ ] is the best [ __ ] ever
of course
basically as soon as we invented the
nail and we invented some modern ways of
hash smoking in 09 you know 2010 2011
yeah that that was the revolution
and hash went from shitty to amazing
yeah right now it's true that most
americans got shitty hash and it's also
true that when all these white people
and all these europeans and all these
americans and and brotherhood of eternal
love and all these [ __ ] started
coming to these regions to look for hash
and started offering crazy amounts of
money
yeah the quality went way down yeah
people started adulterating it people
started middlemen started making it
worse
people wanted volume because there was
so much demand
right so a lot of times the best stuff
never leaves
yeah even like even my friends in
amsterdam who are very tied in
them getting the best of the best is
really hard
i would imagine so and they and they
savor it
right they absolutely savor it and they
hold on to it and it never makes the you
know i almost said clubs it never it
almost never makes the the coffee shops
yeah because it's all traded amongst
each other
yeah right it's all bought and sold that
kind of grade you kind of have to know
someone yeah it's no different than like
if you if for to mention him again if
bodhi gave out some like 14 week amazing
sativa you probably wouldn't be able to
buy it from the cookie store
yeah well you'd have to have a home
you'd have to have a homie well well
maybe now maybe but but even someone
even something that takes that long yeah
yeah for sure you know what i mean like
in europe you know there's there's still
like i have a buddy over there right now
that was texting me on what to get
matt i didn't tell you this but he just
bought some cg 13. and some c5 and some
and some a5 from over there you know
um and those you know those are 15 16
weak strings
yeah that's you that's unheard of to get
in a dispensary over here yeah that's
wild
but over there it's their bread and
butter
yeah you know so you can find that stuff
so the biggest just to reiterate before
we get too off track um
the biggest difference is between
american hash and like the best
traditional
is
uh
you know the what i was told by the the
amsterdam crews is like the best stuff
is made in traditional regions
but westerners help them
to make sure that the purity and the
process is amazing
okay does that make sense so making
their technique more purifying making
making sure that the cl the cleanliness
you know and the technique and all that
is good screens and everything like that
and you know people one of the reasons
why people ask this is people asked
about temple balls right these nepalese
temple balls
and i will say that these nepalese
temple balls that i smoked from my buddy
was some of the best hash i've ever
smoked in my life
okay and it's interesting because a lot
of people over there feel that way yeah
right
and they feel that like
there's something to the fact that like
a lot of this stuff is being grown at
six or seven or eight thousand feet
yeah
right where the air is thinner
and there's more uv
and maybe that leads to a different type
of psychoactive or a different type of
thc production
sure
you know and so they would say that like
you know uh our buddy yo sammy
you know would say i don't care what
modern cultivar you have i don't care
what amazing cut you think you have or
how pure you make it
you know it shits the bed next to the
best typical
yeah like if you can get the best of the
best he's like just in flavor and effect
yeah right an effect is hard to say
because it's invisible right yeah so
we got used to making all these modern
cultivars and thinking that like
thousands of years of hash culture
we just beat
yeah because we're a little cleaner
yeah because we have a little bit better
and we have a little bit we have some
machinery and we're a little bit better
processed but like old-timers will tell
you that like they think that putting
your hash in the in the in the fridge
ruins it
yeah
and you know what what what's weird
about the nepalese stuff is i will say
that
and this isn't a plug on it or whatever
but anything i've ever smelled
that smelled like the mendo perps that i
cracked yeah had the mendo perps in it
yeah in the sense that like i've never
smelled that terpene profile from any
other plant that wasn't it
yeah
unless it was related to it in the sense
that like someone bred with it or it was
it was an ancestor of that right yeah
except these temple balls that i smoked
and they smelled when you were burning
them they smelled like you were burning
mendo perps
that's interesting now you know does
that mean that like the mendo p is
nepalese i don't know you know but or
does it mean that it just evoked that
terpene profile yeah
you know
i i can't say
um but all those guys over there what's
crazy is that um
all those hash heads over there they
grow all kinds of phenomenal weed
and they sell all that weed to buy the
best hash they can get
yeah
you know like somebody like somebody
like you know uh when you were
interviewing uh uh uh camara and and red
you know yeah
i mean he was saying that like you know
he's never even seen sam skunk man smoke
weed yeah
that you know the the top people over
there are hershey's
yeah
you know they smoke hatch they're resin
farmers
makes sense you know that's what they're
after they're after a resin yeah
and so you know we could widen that out
for a little bit
and talk about how
um
you know
this is like a totally different tangent
or whatever but um
when
americans started smoking weed
we were a flower culture
we were getting weed from mexico and
panama and jamaica and colombia and all
these things and we were getting bricked
um and we were getting you know we were
getting bricked of this stuff
and we started blending them with
afghans because of prohibition right
and it's super common and matt can speak
on this too but
most of the weed smokers back then
were very disappointed in the smoke of
the afghans
yeah
they didn't really like the high and
they didn't really like the way it
burned
yeah i mean it was so vastly different
than what they were used to
compared to compared to sativas because
those sativas have been have been bred
for smoking yeah they were bred for they
were bred to be burned as flour yeah you
know where i mean i i told this before
but there's this funny story of when sam
skunk man was in
um was in afghanistan and he was
searching for seeds
right and so he was asking these
warlords for seeds
for flour
you know and they looked at him
and they said you know smoking flowers
for women and slaves
right are you a woman or a slave yeah
and he had to convince them
that he was a man and he just wanted
them so he could grow his own
flower at home and make resin
i wonder if he pulled out his wiener
you know
uh and let me prove it you know but to
them it was like that that was that was
the thing the flower was a waste product
yeah
you know peasants and women slaves and
women smoked smoked flour real men
smoked hash
that was their culture so
obviously you don't care how flour burns
and you don't care how the flower
affects you
because you never smoke it in that
culture yeah so americans were the first
people taking all these hash plants and
and afghans
and actually wanting to smoke them yeah
it hadn't happened before because none
of those people back back home where
they were from gave a [ __ ]
yes
and you can kind of draw a line from
morocco
on the the western part of africa all
throughout north africa all the way up
through
lebanon and israel
all the way over iran and into
afghanistan and that's all hash
yeah
right
but then once you get to like cambodia
thailand
that all kind of got lost
yeah and it flipped into weed smoking
and exporting actual wheat
you know my heart huh i wonder why
i don't know why that one became so
separate
you know i don't know
you know
um you know and you know it's like i i
prefer flower too to be honest and i
don't think that we need to like base
what what what we think of on what
afghans think um
but uh you know
definitely they um you know they just
thought that because that was the
culture that they were raised men smoke
ash
yeah
you know and women smoke flower and
slaves i like that they weren't
good enough
women were puffing tough on the flower
over there
and you know and so there's this thing
where when i first went over to
amsterdam i met this guy he's still over
there steve the nose or whatever and i
got introduced to some of this hashish
culture
and they would show me the best moroccan
the best lebanese these are amazing
temple balls this is from afghanistan
this is from the pakistani highlands
and you smoke all this stuff and it's
unbelievable
yeah like he had the best hash
collection i've ever seen in my life and
these guys
they didn't even really smoke weed very
much they had it
you know but they mostly cared about
hashish
that's so funny you know and they
thought they didn't care what method you
used they didn't care what extraction
technique you had
uh didn't all all those cuts that you
could make hash off of they were
inferior
yeah
they were it was inferior hashish
interesting you know
yeah and you know and so we we
huh
when we knew you there i'm here
so you know they um
so
it's really a big it's really
interesting because americans like until
things open up
um i would say that 99 of americans have
probably never smoked the top import
grade of hash that you can get yeah
they just haven't seen it yeah it
doesn't it doesn't show up it gets it
barely gets to europe
yeah before it gets absorbed i see a lot
of people asking about the the opium
thing
and i can comment on that real quick
what they're referring to is an old
story
and it wasn't hash it wasn't a weed
thing it was necessarily it wasn't
necessarily a weird thing the story was
that tie sticks were dipped in something
called passa water which was uh the
water used when you produce heroin so
when you're when you're doing the
conversion from opium to heroin the
leftover water is called passive water
so there was theories and or people
would spread stories that you know all
thai sticks were dipped in past the
water and that's why they were so strong
when in reality it probably wasn't the
case that's not really how how the the
water works drying on the
to weed you know
but it that that is stuck forever so
that a lot of people think that thai
sticks have heroin in them and that's
yeah that's where that came from
and you know they don't mostly because
yeah i think if it happened it would
have been very rare i mean the re the
reason why is because cartels like that
um
they don't put more expensive drugs on
cheaper ones yeah for free that's not
how that's not how they operate you know
yeah i mean uh you know now with like
the whole fentanyl thing and all that
their people are cutting all kinds of
stuff with highly dangerous substances
yeah uh back in the day if anything got
cut with anything it was by something
cheaper and weaker
yeah i still am very skeptical on on
street fentanyl being cut into normal
things because it's still more expensive
i would imagine then
most of the drugs are saying that it's
cut with it doesn't really make sense
unless people are trying to buy fentanyl
and they're cutting it with [ __ ] but
cheaper i'm gonna i'm gonna reiterate it
one more time just because i think it's
really important which is that almost
all traditional hash regardless of grade
or quality is made out of thousands and
thousands and thousands of sister plants
grown from seed
and so you get a very wide range of that
that strains
profile thc
cbd cbn terpenes all that kind of stuff
it all gets blended together
right yeah and so it's
vastly different
than
growing a room or growing a greenhouse
of gmo or skittles yeah or something
along those lines and taking the exact
same genetic cut
right yep and
that exact same genetic cut and uh
and and extracting that
right
it's just very different and the way
they process it is different and how
long that it takes them before they
think it's cured into something that
they want to smoke
is also different so american hash
culture is very new
and it goes against the grain as far as
like any other kinds of
uh hashish culture that you would that
you would you would see now it is true
of course that with with demand
right they're going to mix all kind
brokers and and and people looking for
profit are going to mix all kinds of of
cut into hash yeah i'm talking about the
nicest stuff i'm talking about the pure
grade yeah right and hash in these
regions was a lot better
before all these white people showed up
demanding tons
oh i'm sure
and then once all these europeans and
all these english and all these
americans started showing up on the
hippie hashish trail in the 70s and they
wanted just enormous amounts of it they
blew through all the best
and then of course just like any other
humans you're going to get a bunch of
people that are trying to meet demand
yeah so the quality on average is going
to go way down
and you're going to get a bunch of b and
c grade
and then you're going to get
you know and then you're going to get um
you know the the top end is going to be
a lot more rare
yeah
you know
um and you know
the like i said all those old-timers
that smokehash they all swear
that the best traditional hash is still
the best
yeah now whether that's because of the
strains they use whether that's because
they dry farm it you know i mean i'm
sure there's a bunch of different
reasons
but the process itself is very different
yeah
and the effect is very different and
they they all they all swear by it and
that's what they take the best of what
they grow
um you know and that and people say that
too people say i see that all the time i
have a buddy of mine that was like oh
yeah yeah yeah they know what they're
[ __ ] talking about they [ __ ] make
hash with the same hat the hand they
[ __ ] wipe their [ __ ] on
yeah right and it's basically like
these people these humans that have
spent thousands of years refining their
hash culture don't know [ __ ]
yeah from what we've learned since oh
wait on
yeah right
right and different cultures
we've gone we've gone through everybody
dabs with a [ __ ] thousand degree
glowing cherry red hot nail or banger
yeah unpurged bho
every two or three years we're like
improving our technique and you only
have to go back five or six or seven
years to techniques and [ __ ] that people
wouldn't do again
yeah yeah already get out of style that
we learned that a bunch of these
terpenes are like carcinogenic
yeah at the heat that most of these
people were dabbing them
yeah
with right and then the other thing too
is when you watch you know you can get
on ig right and you can watch some of
these hash cultures work and how they
heat the hash and how they work the hash
you know and how they get the hash
malleable and how they get
the resin to be warm before they use it
you know
all that different types of stuff and
like and so there's a lot to learn from
those people
you know because they've been smoking
hash for a long time
yeah you know and like we you know we
stumble upon all this stuff and we think
we're doing amazing because you can see
through you know we want to put it on a
piece of parchment paper and be able to
see through it yeah we want to make it a
fresh frozen
harvested fresh frozen put into this
thing put through a freezer dryer all
this different stuff and
you know um you know frenchie people
talking about frenchie and stuff like
that and he did bring a little bit of
the
of of of of that different culture into
all this you know but there's an aspect
of
um you know the the old-timers will tell
you
that you would store the hash in like in
loose bags right
in a cold spot
and they said if you wanted to ruin your
hash you put it in the fridge
yeah
and and the fridge and the humidity and
the [ __ ] would ruin your [ __ ]
hash they were like if you wanted to
ruin it just just do that to it but if
you put it into a cold dry cellar and
you let it age for a while
boom
it would get better
yeah you know and
you know and so and they also grow with
a bunch of different cultivars that
we're not used to
yeah that's very true too
you know um and you know and they you
know they grow from seed every year
yeah right and we don't we grow from
clones
you know yeah um and so we've gotten
really especially on the west coast you
know um
we've gotten really egotistical
about our hash making yes and about our
extracts and we are you know we are
doing better i'm not i'm not saying that
like what we do isn't viable
i'm just saying that like from the
people in amsterdam that have vast
experience with both
yeah
they all prefer
the traditional [ __ ] if they can get the
grade they want oh i'm sure so that
should say something
okay people are asking the title of the
book and and someone did point out that
cherniat maybe isn't so well liked but
um this is with uh lawrence cherniak and
alan drunker's it's called
uh how she used the joy of making and
curing it's i was just putting up some
pictures to illustrate as we were
talking about how she used the different
styles looks
techniques in here
but yeah people used to sit there and i
don't know if you can see my hand or
whatever um but like you can they would
sit there and rub and rub and work and
work and work and really get the hash
warm and malleable sometimes people
would put it into a plastic bag and they
would put it in the heel of their shoe
yeah and they would walk on it to like
work and work and work and they wouldn't
just sit there and you'll see videos on
ig now because there's people that are
going around afghanistan and pakistan
and some of these hash cultures
of how before they use it they heat it
up
they work it they get it to be they get
it to be a certain way so there's a lot
of there's a lot of uh
there's a lot of old techniques that i
think are kind of being ignored
yeah that um
you know it's almost like this [ __ ]
where like in california in the 70s
people knew about red and white wine
yeah
you know that was that was the level of
knowledge that like red went with
with prime rib and meat you know and
white was for their wife
and went with fish or chicken or
something and that's about all they knew
yeah and now you fast forward 30 years
or 40 years or whatever and now it's
like they're like oh merlot and this
appalachian and the pinot gris that's
that um you know that uh
that's that's all going on
and and whatnot and you know i think the
same thing is gonna happen with hash
yeah we're a baby hash culture in
america
and we don't know [ __ ] and we're
learning stuff and every few years you
can see hash culture and you can see
people's techniques improve
yeah right
um but we could learn a lot from
you know and maybe they'll get to a
point like with the legality of things
or whatnot where you could grow a field
yeah like it would be cool for seed
makers right where you could grow a
field
of uh of seeds
yeah and then harvest the whole thing
for hatch
yeah that would be awesome and then you
get the full range of whatever you know
matt's bubble berry or or yeah you know
a skittles hybrid or a gmo hybrid or
whatever the case may be you'd get the
full range in the hash
instead of just like this one cut i'm
going to concentrate what's in this one
cut
yeah because that's never been done
before right
yeah that's not exactly how it's done
over there it's not typically how it's
done over there and so we have we have
our own thing and it's not bad or
anything like that i'm not saying that
but
it it's very different
yeah
it's very different now
we could expand it out a little bit
and talk about
um when
when they first started bringing afghans
you know we all started growing sativa
in america right yeah
because
sativa seeds came free with the [ __ ]
wheat
yeah you get kilos of you know head
stash brought in and everyone's selling
it your weed came with
free seeds yeah we used to sit there in
high school leaning back against the
chair and we'd have a we'd have a tray
and you'd break up the weed up here and
you let all the seeds and stems roll
down
and yep keep and you keep your weed up
there right but
hash didn't come with free seats
yeah yeah
so i'm just watching someone tell a joke
about bubble man
we uh so we don't have we don't we don't
we didn't get very many seeds so
you know
sativas were all everywhere everywhere
in the 70s and 80s and that was
primarily what it all was how do you
think puck washes
how do i think like man you know
if you want to if you want if there's
people out there that don't like me and
you want to think of me as a shitty
grower i should show you some pictures
of
my puck grows
because i did some i did some depths and
i did some greenhouse outdoors with it
and uh
boy was it not impressive no i wouldn't
wash it because there would be no reason
to wash off of it i got it was it was a
really ugly i mean i can't say what it
looked like in the 80s or in the 90s
when it was a little younger
um but you know when i got it it hated
sunlight and food
yeah
and you know strangely enough those were
two things that i like to give my plants
sunlight and food at the time so yeah
yeah it was uh it was really unusual
um
you know and uh
you know they uh
so there's you know bubble hash and
there's another aspect of it too where
it's like maybe we should we could talk
about this for a second is that
most people
most most americans i was gonna say
white people but most americans will say
it that way right yeah like we don't
like our time is our time is money
you know so you look at the way
traditional people sift sifting is an
amazing product
but it's the most time consuming yeah
and it gets the least yield
so
it's the rarest
so americans are constantly looking for
can i wash this
can i bho it can i see what what way can
i do it that's efficient and i can get
an extraction that yields
how can i get yield
right well most of the time you have to
put that through a solvent
it's not just knocking the flowers
yeah over a screen and getting and
getting dry sift and then putting that
dry sip through a series of screens and
cleaning it up like bubble man as shown
right even water is the salt water is
the original solvent
that's why it's so funny that people
call water solventless
water hash is solventless like look
put in is water a solvent into google
and see what comes up
yeah
it's a solvent yeah sure is the original
and what's crazy about that is if you
read now granted there's a lot of
there's a there's some thc and terpenes
and stuff like that aren't soluble in
water
yeah
but there is if you read like rob
clark's book hashish about 25 of
terpenes are water soluble
yeah
so you can so there's times when we did
stuff with water hash right where
you run something like some kind of
tangy cross
yeah
and that and that citrus that citrus
comes through super strong
right yeah but then you run something
like the 56 day headband and it comes
out smelling like axle grease
yeah it's super potent
but it's like chemical process didn't
like it's if the chain that makes up the
the the aroma and the taste
didn't make it through the hash making
process
right
so
most of the stuff we do today whether
it's bho or whether it's water hash and
then frozen or this or that a lot of
these things affect the flavor
and a lot of what becomes popular
is what keeps its flavor
with the time saving techniques that we
use to make hash extraction easier
yeah
you know i mean you watch you watch
these guys like on ig or whatever then
you see them do their traditional hash
thing no american wants to be sitting
there with a face mask on for eight
hours a day over a thing shaking
flour and knocking off the crystals and
then carefully you know like refining it
it doesn't get you enough weight for
your time
yeah
people we want to use machines
well that changes it too
yeah
right
it has to do and part of the reason why
i think like the tangi and the whole to
mention that again the tangent the whole
citrus craze happened
is because when
like you know in the mid 2000s you
couldn't give away calio
no no people would not
if you had citrus weed that was a great
way for your broker to look at you and
say no dog
yeah not a dog i don't need that
headache
i'm not taking your weed you know but
then and it was also citrus weed tends
to not be that potent yeah
so it's it's you know you could call it
i don't want to say minzy but you could
say moderately potent at best yeah where
the flavor people did blank
lacking recreational potency yeah but
then
you start extracting it with bho or this
or that or whatever and all of a sudden
that that citrus terpene came through
super solid and now the shit's 70
percent thc
yeah and it actually gets you high
yeah and so a lot of the popular strains
in america that got made into hash
um
got made into hash because after you put
them through the the processes that we
do to make life easy
yeah still tasted and worked good
you know but the but the old like the
old static tech and the old like and the
old sifting tech that was like used
forever that wasn't abandoned because it
sucked it was abandoned because it was
lower yield and took a lot more time
yeah
and amer and you know most hash guys
like to make their money quick right
yeah turn it over i want to turn it over
you know and so
you get like what you think is the
world's most amazing hash
the hash collectors in europe don't
think you're smoking the world's most
amazing hash yeah that's not that it's
not good
and everybody can have their opinion you
know yeah they just have a different
perspective on it and uh more
man it's hard to say a bit more cultured
at some points when it comes to hash
specifically
i mean it's one of those things like
like that's why you can compare it to
wine
yeah you know it's like
now in california you can have all these
wine nerds that are extremely
intelligent about the different grapes
and the different grades and the
different appellations and where certain
varieties do better than others because
of climate
yeah in the 70s it was red and white
and that's kind of where we are hashish
wise right now we're just learning and
like anybody who's listening right now
like you know who's made hash for the
last 10 or 15 years think about how much
your techniques and what you've been
doing has been changing
every year or two this whole time
it's not like you've reached the
mountaintop
you know it's like people figure out a
way to do it better and then people are
like oh [ __ ] i'm going to do it that way
yeah and a lot of the traditional ash
people tell me that most of the modern
cultivars that we grow with suck as far
as hash extraction
where you get some yeah where you get
some lebanese [ __ ] or you get some
nepalese stuff that for generations has
been grown just for that
and that [ __ ] dumps
yeah
you know because that's what they
designed it to do
and when when the hash revolution hit 10
12 years ago you know um
people started looking around for all
the elites that had been kept around and
do any of these also dump hash
yeah
they weren't bred for that
no one ever thought of it
hash was like a you know hash was like a
personal product
yeah maybe you could get some key for
the club maybe you should get some water
hash at a club
you know
people would get scissor hash
you know if you were working or people
would get finger hash when they were
bucking down stuff and all that but it
wasn't like commoditized
right
did you ever use an iso 2
oh god yeah
i want i want one of those to try out if
any of you guys out there have an iso
too i will trade you some seeds for one
uh i used to use my dad's as like a
he-man castle along with my group uh
castle grayskull and [ __ ] but i'd really
like to see how it works today you know
we could probably do a we could probably
do a whole show one time on just the
different eras of like oh that sounds
cool
yeah oh i'm gonna go on an octagon oh
i'm gonna grow areaponics oh i'm gonna
grow nft oh i'm going to grow this way
oh i'm going to extract that way oh yeah
you know coliseums yeah colosseums i
mean dude i had to call it i had two
coliseum i mean we could go through all
that of just all like whatever is the
most cutting-edge [ __ ] imaginable you
know do you remember the v tables the
they were like that yeah yeah i remember
when those popped up there's a pencil
and so it's funny right because a lot of
my friends are egotistical or whatever
you know but it's like the the main you
talk to hash people in california and
the west coast now and they think
they're the best hash people that have
ever lived sure
that they dominate
you know and i'm not dissing them
because they are figuring stuff out and
they are making nice hash
yeah right most of them are failed
growers [ __ ] them they're also turning
their back on thousands of years of
humans learning [ __ ]
yeah
you know and and it's it's like it's
like when you're shocked when old people
have something to teach you
yeah you know yeah uh you know there's
there's there's techniques and there's
things and there's aspects um you know
that uh you know i mean think about all
those classes that frenchie did
who the [ __ ] are you yeah to be
you know and he was and he all he was
doing was just
teaching some people
how
different cultures over there made some
hatch yeah
you know and people ate it up
yeah they did
you know and there's different flavor
profiles and there might be a way where
you take a cultivar and you extract it
one way and it fights potent but it
sucks
and then you do it another way and it's
amazing
so it's not like all strains react the
same like something like i said some
things go through water like a champ
right i even did [ __ ] where i would have
like a a greenhouse
full of the same strains and then i
would have outdoor
yeah and like sometimes like the sour
diesels and certain things like that if
they got rained on a bunch in october
their terpene profile wouldn't be
exactly what i was after yeah but the
sour diesel grown 30 feet away in a
greenhouse that never got rained on once
it was fed with the same food and the
same everything would be bomb
you know but like the super silver haze
or certain citrus stuff it wasn't
affected by the rain at all
yeah it just kept its profile but
sometimes the rain enough rain would
[ __ ] up the flavor on my weed
yeah
you know
um and uh well you know someone just
said it's potent but it sucks that's the
biggest oxymoron ever not really it
depends because it depends on how it
depends on how you
what the high is like
yeah right i mean you can quality of
high you can read old high times right
and not to bring up high times but
a lot of people's opinion of the old
afghani one
was that it was a uncomfortable
anxiety-inducing body high that gave you
heart palpitations and it was one of the
least enjoyable smokes out there yeah
and they way preferred sativas or normal
or nl's or there was lots of other highs
that they liked
yeah they thought it was potent
but they didn't like it
yeah you know some people like some some
people the
that sativa buzz that nl5 haze buzz or
that neville's haze buzz it's super
potent and it makes them want to crawl
out of their skin and jump off a bridge
and die and they'd never smoke it again
if you know they hate it yeah that's
like me with skunk one types they
[ __ ] hate it it's super potent it's
amazing it's the nicest sativa i've ever
smoked
but there's people that are smoking a
couple of times and they'll be like i no
that's a bad time for me
so
you know potency is just one aspect it
just means it's strong it doesn't mean
that it's going to affect you in a
pleasant way
yeah you know i personally i don't like
edibles
yeah oh no you can't control the high
you can't you're just strapped in
because and the reason why i don't like
edibles and i'll be perfectly honest is
that they [ __ ] with my equilibrium
oh really they give me this like you
know when you're drunk and you're like
if i put a foot on the ground i'll stop
the spins yeah yeah they can give me the
spins ooh that's not and i don't like
that feeling yeah and i'll have friends
that'll be like oh you just gotta eat
enough and blow past it
yeah and for me i'm like well how how
many hours of uncomfortable do i have to
feel before i start feeling good yeah
because
i don't feel good
yeah you know i like weed a whole bunch
and i don't feel good at all
you know so how many hours of my life do
i want to not feel good
yeah
you know that happens to me enough you
know so i don't do edibles because
like i got kids and [ __ ] you know so
you know one of my kids could break
their toe or whatever and yeah
it doesn't matter how much weed i've
smoked i can hop in the car i can take
them to the hospital i can do whatever i
need to do yeah but if i just ate a
couple hundred
milligrams of edibles
i might need to like call a lifeline you
know or yeah for sure
i'm not you know
and then yeah i have all kinds of people
are gonna start commenting oh you just
need to take these you just need to ate
these i'm just saying that for me
the way my body works
sometimes it gives me the spins
yeah and i don't like the spins i think
a lot of people don't understand that
though how how variable the everybody's
brain chemistry is and how each
individual
cannabinoid or what have you interacts
differently with everyone not everybody
gets the same effect from the same clone
though though you know i mean
collectives that's the way people are
taught i'll all indicates do this all
sativas do this all hybrids do right in
the middle you know it's just not yeah
it's just it's just not that way i mean
i i chem 91 is one of my all-time
favorite highs
yeah it makes me feel like i'm a
teenager
watching a mel book mel brooks movie and
i got a big thing of popcorn and i'm
happy and content and life is great
yeah and we have good friends
that are like meh
i mean i love what it i love what it
what it breeds like and i understand
that a lot of other people like it but i
wouldn't like to smoke it on a regular
basis yeah but i love it
you know so there's that aspect too
you know and that's that's one of the
main things that
um all the hash guys the experience tell
me is that they can't they just simply
can't find the same effect
yeah have you tried suppositories buddy
have you tried any of those no i can
assist you if you need help i know you
got you've got all those you got all
those extra jumbo i got that extra long
attachment on the thing to get it
released no yeah i don't i don't i don't
need any of that kind of stuff i mean
i'm sure that
for people that have a hard time and a
bunch of nausea
you know um i'm not trying to make foot
fun off it or whatever that might be the
best way for them to absorb
yeah
i got a pretty funny pretty funny story
about boofing stuff
so i had a friend named brian he's dead
now but he had heard that if you boof
oxycontin and granted that we were like
17 18. you heard that if you boof
oxycontin you get really [ __ ] up and
this is the early days of oxycontin
so he stuck the oxycontin up his ass and
waited and waited and then he realized
that there's a coating on the outside
that it really won't penetrate through
your [ __ ]
so he had to crush it up and re-insert
it and do his ass
that's my boofing story you're welcome
everyone
i i do joke with
my friends that are younger than me you
know
that their contribution to drug culture
is boofing
yeah really that is that really that's
what they that's what they're going to
be remembered for that's their
innovation
yeah you know
all that different types of stuff and
you know whatever it it uh
like i have seen
people
making suppositories for very sick
cancer patients and aids patients and
other various aspects
and i'm sure
that uh they do a great job
um but what people also should know too
is that when you eat when you eat weed
or you take it you know a suppository
style it turns into thc 11.
okay did you know that no i didn't it
converts into something when you smoke
it it's it's delta 11 thc delta 11.
that's right
and uh it's much longer lasting
you know um and so that's kind of why
you get [ __ ] like in the sense of like
if if it hits you the wrong way
yeah you're sort of stuck with that
feeling for a while
yeah and so me and delta nine are real
good friends
yeah delta nine and me we get along we
we see eye to eye on things
i can smoke whatever format even you
know i don't i'm more of a flower person
than hash but i can smoke a bunch of
hash and i can still accomplish whatever
i need to do yeah 11 hydroxy not delta
that makes sense okay yeah 11 maybe i
misspoke but um but yeah it it converts
in your gut into something different
okay and it's longer lasting and it has
a
some different effects
well yeah doesn't it um bind with your
fat cells too which makes it more potent
in your stomach now we're getting into
into areas i'm not familiar with
yeah you know it's one of those things
where i don't care about edibles that
much because i don't
um i don't uh i don't use them they're
not that important to me you know i i do
think that they're a great way for some
people to get medicine
yeah you know but i i got [ __ ] to do and
i got kids and i can't take myself out
yeah yeah it's a good way to take
yourself out and you know to be honest
like in the 90s and stuff like that you
know uh
now you can go to the you can go to the
store and you can be like oh i'm going
to get a 5 milligram or a 10 milligram
or a 50 or 100 milligram you know yeah
um and back in the day
you know and you know when i was doing
edibles more it was like is this ganja
goo ball am i gonna feel anything
yeah
all the way up to i'm in my tent and i
can't move
yeah and i'm missing the festival
because i'm horizontal
you know yeah okay
just primary just answered he said no it
crosses the blood brain barrier more
easily makes sense it converts in the
liver not the gut which totally makes
sense yeah yeah i knew i was gonna i
knew i was gonna misspeak i knew that it
affected you differently and it
converted differently yeah um i was
nervous to talk about the various
science of it because i i wasn't i
probably wasn't going to get there yeah
see i'm i'm very um adventuresome and
i'll talk about the science of it you
know exactly nothing what i'm talking
about so i'm good at that part i just
knew that it converted differently
and it and it it lasted longer and it
has a different series of effects
uh than inhale and then smoking
yeah i know someone said that um people
with diabetes can't feel edibles and i
can
absolutely disprove that
because i'm diabetic and i can feel
animals
yeah i mean i i've been on you know i've
eaten some ganja goo balls at times and
stuff and i
definitely i'm not i'm speaking from
experience when
i was like i'm in the tent and i can't
move i can't stand up i need to pee am i
going to pee myself
can i move
yeah you know that's the good [ __ ] yeah
because you know it's just like it's
just bad dosing
yeah these six kinds of goo balls are
almost worthless and you wasted your
money and this one is like catatonic
yeah you know do you really want to be
catatonic at a festival you know yeah i
know that's how you get raped happens
well no
but it's just yeah you paid money to be
there and now you're laying on rocks on
in the tent
spinning
you know
um
but it's just one of those things where
it's like uh
you know and actually too it's like it's
interesting in the sense that i don't
even know if i should bring this up but
i have a i have a daughter that's i have
a couple daughters in middle school
right
and it's one of their big issues right
now
is edibles
really
think about it taking animals to school
yeah they're easy to mask
an older brother an older sister or
someone that's willing to go and buy
them and kick them down
yeah they're sour patch kids they're
made in a bunch of attractive ways now
like when we were kids the only way you
got edibles is if some degenerate older
brother made some brownies yeah exactly
off some shake or something like that
was able to stink up their whole house
or some [ __ ] yeah now they can get like
these really attractive much more
controllable packages
right they're you're not going to get
caught with a lighter or a pipe or
stinking like weed or anything like that
you can just eat like a 10 milligram
yeah right and so they're a lot more
prevalent
makes sense nerds ropes sour patch kids
rice krispie treats all kinds of there's
an immense amount of baking
and candy and [ __ ] and much more
controllable amounts
um that uh i just don't like it
and i'm not what you're saying is kids
are good customers
no you know i just mean that kids kids
are going to get access to whatever is
cool that's available in their local
area and it's easy to smuggle in i mean
i remember back in high school they
would do like locker raids and all kinds
of [ __ ] trying to catch us dealing drugs
and uh we didn't have things like you
know gummy bears and [ __ ] like that yeah
if you if you if you took out some of
those gummy bears if you took out some
sour patch kids from a from a an edible
thing you got and you put them in a real
sour patch kids thing and took them in
your lunchbox or your thing or backpack
how would they [ __ ] know exactly yeah
invisible at that point you know
um
but you know so i just uh i just i just
don't like edibles
you know
i just don't like edibles um but
um we kind of got off we kind of got off
track there or whatever but it's like a
big thing
you know and some people are into them
but they steal they steal my they steal
my equilibrium i don't know if they
steal other people's equilibrium
but i start
not feeling the right way and then i get
hot
yeah and when you get hot and you have
the spins i mean how fun is that yeah
you end up puking that's enough it's not
fun for me
yeah you know
but
you know and i i think it'll probably
take like it would probably take like
international
freedom
where weed really becomes opened up
you know yeah for americans
over here at least to really start
trying like the finest grades
of imported hashish
i just don't see i i see the
the world opening up and it being so
super corporate and hyper illegal that
nobody's going to be [ __ ] with [ __ ]
like that
you know it's going to be in afghanistan
they'll have
those small clubs and all that [ __ ]
it'll be just
that culture infiltrating everywhere as
opposed to letting the cultures that are
there stay there being able to try each
other's cultures uh
who knows there's money to be made off
this [ __ ] you know right now you know
you can get you can get greek olive oil
you know you can get those iberian hams
that cost eighteen hundred dollars for
the leg that have been dry aged x amount
you know there's a lot of debt
you know what you can't get
thai land races anymore it's very very
hard things are disappearing not just
the not just the strains but the
cultures are disappearing with them in
some senses and granted that's not a
hash culture necessarily but it's just
like just like those strains
disappearing i mean it's you know the
techniques are going to be going with
them
over time
so you know people are saying people are
talking about people paying more for six
star or whatever else so
there's an aspect where
you know there's obviously different
grades
right
but no matter how pure you make it
you're still limited by your starting
material
yeah are you all getting it from a
single source
right is it all the same cultivar is all
the same cut are you getting it from a
field are you getting it from uh you
know you planted thousands of seeds and
you're harvesting those females
yeah you know
um and uh and all that and so
uh you know there's an aspect there
where
um
you know because you're gonna cut hash
is concentrated right
yeah where you're gonna concentrate what
was in the flower
yeah you're gonna concentrate the
qualities of that of that thc or that
blend or that cbd cbn terpene
profile all that you know what do they
call it entourage effect
yes you know so you just you're going to
get a vastly different experience
probably from moroccan from lebanese to
afghanistan to southeast asian to
sherbolotto
yeah
right
yes sure
sure
and then a lot of times too people
people still like even makers right now
it's like oh my god this is unbelievable
the terpenes off it are amazing but it
yielded two percent so [ __ ] it i'm not
gonna do it
yeah right people want hash dumpers
yeah it's gotta it's gotta be
commercially viable
first
or it won't get beyond some small little
circle there might be some there might
be a few friends that like wash it and
they're all trading grams amongst each
other and all stoked but it won't
trickle down to where the normal person
can get it because it wasn't a viable
amount
exactly and i'm not a hash guy that that
big or whatever but i do know from
working in legal cannabis and stuff like
that that there's minimum numbers of
weight return that you need to get to
make it be viable yeah to pay for your
time to pay for the equipment to pay for
the the shift work and all the stuff
that goes into making hash so if it
doesn't dump enough
regardless of how nice it affects you
yeah it's going to get it's gonna get
shifted to the side
yeah and if you've got something that
that blows your head off but it yields
three and a half percent
and its sister plant
tastes a little bit different and
doesn't work as good but yields six
percent yeah the six percent is getting
run and washed all day
yeah because that's making them money
you know
so
um you know so there's that too where
it's like the commercial side of it
people might think oh we have the best
hash in the world but
unless it's commercially viable you'll
probably never see it
unless you're growing it and washing it
and making it yourself
yeah or in your small circle of friends
and trading it amongst each other
just like you know just like before like
if you were growing a 12 or 13 or 14
week plant
you'd probably never be able to buy that
in a store
yeah i wouldn't think so gmo is probably
the first thing that came out that took
12 weeks
that people were willing to jump on
yeah that always shocked me especially
coming from the cookies well part of the
reason part of the reason why i think
people were willing to jump on it was
because even though it took two weeks
four weeks longer than they wanted or
three weeks longer than they wanted it
dumped like crazy
yeah and it tested super high
and it smelled like chem d and kmd was
not everywhere yeah so it like so you
know there so the yield made it worth it
yeah right where if the yield doesn't
make the extra time worth it i mean matt
and i joke that like i mean there's some
pretty famous breeders out there that
are like if it takes any longer than 63
days it's [ __ ]
yeah or i'm harvesting it early
yeah i've got this banger colombian and
it takes 11 weeks but i don't take it
longer than 63 days because it doesn't
fit my model
yeah
you know
and that's kind of how that rolls
yeah
and american way the american well it's
just it's it's there's a difference
between quality and commercial
yeah and that's what i mean too about
about like for instance the uh the wine
industry is now there's enough education
in the wine industry
that
a certain seven or eight year old
cabernet
from a certain winery in a certain
region
you can get that extra ducats
to make that a viable product
right now cannabis doesn't have enough
of that separation
to make the rare and the cool and the
expensive worth it
right there's all there's like this
range that everybody's working in and we
haven't gotten educated enough that you
could be like you should pay more for
this weed because it's neville's haze
and it takes 15 weeks and you know it
does this
eventually you'll have people that are
willing to throw down for that
yeah right right now you don't
right right now it's just it's it's you
don't you know
and so until you get that level of
education until you get that consumer
willing to pay for it i honestly think
like the reason why
people are going to yell at me for this
but i think the reason why freaking uh
hayes did so well in new york
right
was because there was there was
musicians and rich people and wall
street brokers to sell it to
yeah
they could they could sell them a higher
grade
yeah straight up just like that you know
i mean do you think kush would have been
so popular in in la if it wasn't 7 200 a
pound wholesale oh yeah no never it was
an aspect of it where
where it became massive because in l.a
it was like oh this is expensive and
exclusive and it's not in your bag
yeah
and then people wanted what the what
what people had it
yeah right and people were willing to
pay a [ __ ] ton for it
but we really haven't gotten there with
weed yet too much there's individual
things that break through here and there
but we really haven't gotten the
criteria as to like why
this weed or why this hash is nicer and
should be more expensive
yeah
you know um
you know i mean i even saw there was
there was some [ __ ] i can't remember
what it was i you know i see that uh you
know uh chimera is on here he was
talking earlier this week about he's got
rks that he doesn't want to release
because it's got unique traits in it
that
he wants to utilize later
yeah and he doesn't think the market's
ready for it
whatever those traits might be
you know
and that could be that could be true too
there's lots of times the market isn't
ready for anything i've always been very
good at being um
at the forefront of stuff and absolutely
making no sells being at the forefront
of stuff and watching others come and
clean up with it it's just about hitting
it at the right time when the market's
ready for something i mean we talked
about that before too like all that
super dog work that me and my and my
homie did you know yeah um that was like
years before american seed sellers could
really get a toehold
yeah we had no place for it to go
yeah
you know we had no place for it to go
you know
so um
uh you know it's it's got to be the
right it's got it there's got to be a
balance between commercially viable
and fire
yeah and it has to match
you know so i don't know right now it's
like we've been in we we went to war
with afghanistan for 20 years so it's
probably not the uh
um it's probably not the best time to go
over there as a white guy
and
start looking around for hashish and and
rare things like that you know yeah you
can get taliban or whatever
um but
you know but uh
um but they actually have a real culture
over there
yeah they have a real vibrant hashish
culture
and it's just separated from us
you know it's always a trip to me with
how how um
religiously conservative those areas are
but there still is a breeding culture or
a weed culture there you know
this is so counter to the muslim culture
i just you know it's like i think it's
one of those things where it's like uh
it predated you know predated the that
whole thing yeah it's just it's it's it
was just kind of like how
you know like you know there's any
number of different things where like
christianity just absorbs certain pagan
rituals into itself oh yeah that's true
good because they because they couldn't
get rid of it
yeah they co-opted it
right
yeah so you want to bring you want to
bring allah to
afghanistan you're going to have to
incorporate some hashish
yeah because it's ancient there and they
ain't getting rid
yeah should have done that with
christians
you know better here yeah i mean well
you know they i mean they it just it
just didn't it's probably an anomaly
yeah know like it's an accident
you know um
and you know they probably didn't
realize how much effect they were gonna
have a thousand years later or two
thousand years later i'm sure
in the in in that regard
you know yeah
so
but yeah i mean hash
you know the the hash in america is
moving along really quickly
uh and i wish i could go back to
um maybe i will sometime and go back and
um and talk in in holland and stuff like
that and see what what they have right
now is their best stuff
yeah that'd be interesting to know
and just how it affects you
yeah because that's what they all talk
about is the the flavor and the effect
is just unused can't you just can't get
it in other [ __ ]
i'll be the judge of that [ __ ]
you know yeah i don't know yeah
but and they also even back when i was
going back there a bunch it was like
they would grab you know like you know a
certain amount of kilos would hit
amsterdam and it would all get bought up
by collectors
and then they all sit on it and hope
that they didn't run out before they
found something else of that quality
yeah and so they'd have a chunk of this
and a chunk of this and a chunk of that
and you know so on and so forth and
whatnot
and that's what you know they they'd
smoke they'd smoke they they'd almost
keep flour for the americans
yeah and then show you and then they'd
show you what they really were into
yeah
in that regard
you know
um and
you know and so uh you know we're
we
uh i don't know maybe maybe there's a
there's an aspect with america where we
blend we blended a bunch of the smoking
weed with a bunch of the hashish weed
what do you mean kind of create huh what
do you mean
well you know we took stuff that was
bred for smoking like
thai
colombian and and mexican and things of
that nature
and then we blended it with all this
stuff that was
specifically designed for hashish yeah
like all the afghans that came over
originally yeah
that was all bred exclusively for
they did they weren't going for like
does this flower taste good
yeah they never tasted the flower
right
yeah they hashed it
but the hash had to taste have a taste
of its own
you know yeah but it's like everyone
it's different when you're burning aged
hash
that's versus versus like a bunch of
flower material yeah
you know and so we started figuring all
that out and we started blending it with
sativas and blending it with different
things and trying to see how they all
came out
yeah you know it's weird in the sense
that like america and holland sort of
became the two places i should say
canada too north america
sort of became where like all the
various regions of weed started blending
yeah you could probably put australia in
that category
that sounds like it sounds like i don't
have a lot of familiarity with over
there but like it sounds like australia
was another melting pot where they got a
bunch of southeast asian weed and they
got a bunch of uh
um
they got a bunch of indian and
afghanistan and pakistan and blends of
different stuff you know
yeah
and whatnot and so
you know it uh
and there was people too maybe we could
switch we could switch bases for a
second there was people that were asking
which is more matt's world than mine uh
i can let him talk for a minute about
what the what the internet what the seed
market is like outside of us
like outside of the us
outside of our like little sts reversals
like what everyone's familiar with oh
this guy's dropping caps dropping
something matt's dropping something csi
has a drop here comes these people
you know because we're used to like very
small scale um
you know like and i think probably most
people think of the last 10 years as
what's normal
yeah but that's not i would think so
yeah
but that's not really what's out there
but you know obviously like so maybe you
could talk for a minute about like what
what is it like out there
well i mean like
so like someone like chimera that's been
around before me he's gonna have a
different experience than when i entered
when i entered in you had to [ __ ] with
europeans or your seeds weren't going to
sell you know if you weren't [ __ ]
with european seed bank and were trying
to do direct you had a very very small
chance of getting any meaningful sales
because people wanted to buy from seed
banks seed banks were known there wasn't
a lot of places to do exchanges you
could always you know do it get down in
the dms on different forums and stuff
but that was that was really not cool
like it wasn't looked at as a cool thing
to do by the the forum owners because
they were they were kind of taking uh
some risk for your exchange even though
it was done in the dms it's still on
their server and transactions so it
wasn't looked upon positively by a lot
of the the
the uh forum owners for anybody to be
doing any exchanges of any sorts and
usually you'd get banned from uh places
for doing anything of the sort
um so we were we were
mostly counting on um
when i entered in it had just started
the british and uh
attitude wasn't a thing when i first
started um but yeah most of it was
outside of the us i think kevin stairway
was was that canada or that or u.s
i think uh canada
i think it was canada
is it canada where calrissian was i
believe so
yeah i mean
you had the canadian seed banks a lot of
them wouldn't pick up american folks i
remember um
med user chris
over at woodhorse seeds he was really
not friendly to most americans um hemp
depot
was around but you still had a hard time
getting them to pick up most americans
so being an american you had the choice
mostly of british or if you were lucky
like a a dutch seed bank would pick you
up but yeah it's
it was minimal a lot of it like when
when i got booted off the attitude
subcool had asked it basically gave that
given them a uh ultimatum me or him and
at the time there was just me and him
that were the americans on there
when i left the attitude and uh
unceremoniously left
um
i had to to figure out what was i gonna
do was i gonna take the risk be the one
american trying to
sell direct or was i going to just find
another seed bank and get [ __ ] so
first thing i did was try to operate a
seed bank with a few other americans and
unfortunately chose the brothel brothers
who were notorious scammers and they got
me
and eventually i just learned [ __ ] i
gotta do this myself or it's it's not
gonna work
and from there you know i mean
you could be operating great in the us
but if you weren't taking credit cards
like the europeans then you just weren't
going to be any sort of competition and
those were always going to get the the
sales
nowadays it's a lot different nowadays
there's all sorts of direct buying uh
instagram kind of changed a lot you know
instagram made everyone a lot more
accessible um seeds were a lot easier to
sell because people weren't as
interested in effect they were more
interested in learning uh by looking you
know oh that's pretty that look that
looks dank became a real catchphrase
during instagram oh that looks dank
but i mean
back in the day we kind of knew that
looks didn't mean anything when it came
to dangerous i mean yeah the weird thing
let me interject for a second because
i'm saying stuff in the comments is that
america was an enormous seed market
yes but everyone that tried to deal with
america
typically got in trouble yeah so
everyone in europe you know when they
saw what happened in neville um yeah the
super sativa seed club just shut down
and a lot of
you know seed banks became very hesitant
to ship stuff to america yeah and then
canadian seed banks sort of took over
that that role for a minute and started
being willing to ship stuff to america
um and a lot of times they sort of like
took the reins from europe because
europe would send it to canada
yeah you know and it would get and it
would get filtered through but as as uh
you know camaro was mentioning a few
minutes ago um heaven stairway went down
because there was an intercepted
shipment to the united states and that
got cannabis world and overgrowth shut
down at the same time
and well
and we we're going to do a full episode
on this me and flan but it's we're going
to go into detail on um silk road
heaven stairway
overgrow
icy mag and how they were all related in
the big bust
this is over a period of several years
almost i mean it's people are still
being prosecuted from one major [ __ ] up
yeah
and then that's one of those why i used
to go to amsterdam to buy seed in the
90s
was because that was the most reliable
way to get it uh getting it shipped over
was very difficult you know and a lot of
people wouldn't do it uh mark emery who
had you know cannabis culture magazine
uh and all that and he had his whole
seed company um he ended up doing i
don't know five-ish years or something
like that in america
in prison for seed sales
um so there was a big issue with
america's this voracious seed market
but how do you get
seeds there without getting in trouble
yeah
and so
you know there wasn't you know people on
ig now you can see all these things and
that's why i was joking about you know
oh this guy's got a drop coming
you know when 20 years ago or whatever
when i was doing a bunch of breeding
work um there was no outlet to get that
to anyone yeah there was no way to
advertise it there was no way to set up
shipping there was no way to i mean even
like somebody like dj short who um
ended up working with a bunch of
canadians
part of the reason why he worked with so
many people was that in order for his
sweet his stuff to get out there he had
to work with tony from sag martha first
yeah and then he ended up working with
the dutch passion crew i think yeah i
think a dutch passion and he ended up
not liking that and then he ended up
working with various people up in canada
but he had to work with third parties
because there was no way for him
to safely distribute advertise and
communicate with people from america to
get seeds out
yeah so it really wasn't until social
media exploded and ig exploded and
proposition 215 and medical started
spreading enough that it started calming
down
for all these seed companies
like you know think about all the
popular you know
cap or or you know swamp boys or these
people you know cookie anybody
right all these people came up and their
possibilities started
in the social media iga
yeah so what matt's talking about is how
difficult it was as an american seed
breeder to even find a home
that could that could be a middleman
that could get they could get your seeds
out to people so you know my buddy
that uh that i you know he doesn't like
to be mentioned but my buddy i call
staten island he kept talking about like
the potential for seeds
and i was totally dismissive
right
and we were both right
right at the time i was right
what he saw 10 or 15 years down the road
what was coming
yeah
you know he did he he saw it but it just
wasn't there yet
i remember making that that
shift from um
cash cropping i mean it's a very very
clear memory for me when i had to make
that choice of [ __ ]
i can cash crop
or i can make seeds i'm learning i
cannot do both you know and having to
make something that i know i know i can
make enough money to survive
growing
since mia
that's not what i love to do
you know that way that did that slowly
was not my passion anymore my passion
was making seeds and and learning what i
could create you know what could be
created in these rooms and uh having to
make that decision to only go to siege
was a tough one because at the time it
was very risky there wasn't a lot of
money in seeds i mean granted
greenhouses killing it dna was killing
it but americans just weren't killing it
at that level yet
i mean dna we can talk about dna for a
second those are two americans plumber
and the stunt cop yeah and they
you know they they went to humboldt and
mendo and all these different places and
they gathered up a bunch of seed and a
bunch of clones from various friends
but they had to go to holland to make a
seed company
yeah there was no there was no in the
early 2000s there was no way they were
going to do an american-based seed
company
how would they even get a hold of you
yeah how would you get a hold of them
how would you not get busted
yeah you know it was uh it wasn't it
wasn't very easy and so we basically
worked first through holland
and that's kind of why holland became
the epicenter
was it allowed it
yeah right neville got lucky because he
had balls
and a bunch of american breeders were
fleeing prosecution in america
and bringing him stuff
right and you know he got stuff from
from greg and he got stuff from sam
skunk man and he and he got stuff
through mel frank and jorge cervantes
and he got stuff from jim ortega
all these people
you know because that was the place that
it could go
yeah and then when canada became the
place it could go that's where it all
went
and then when california and oregon and
washington started being the place that
it could go that's where it went
yeah and it really sucks
because there's this artificial line
between america and canada
that sort of kept our two cultures it's
made it a lot more difficult
to
huh
i'm not gonna lie between 2007 and 2010
the fact that it was such a small market
it was [ __ ] killer you didn't have
all kinds of competition i mean the the
best competition i had was like swerve
and sub at the time and rascal you know
for americans and rascal was he was at
the top of the the food chain when it
came to reversals but i mean
sub and swerve you know
yeah no i i mean there's there's there's
an aspect of it but it's like that
you know um
people think that like people don't
realize how long it took
to get to get democracy where some guy
in a garage could have a 15 lighter or
two or three four lighters or whatever
yeah and make some breeding and do a
drop
yeah and advertise the drop
and let uh and let everyone know
that it was coming
you know i was just thinking about
something as far as drops go like i
remember when that was looked at very
negatively if you're gonna do a drop
meaning can hit one male to more than
five or six plants you were a shitty
pollen chucker and that was like a mark
of shame like drops were not a thing and
now that's the common accepted way this
clone or this male crossed x amount of
clones and that's the accepted way but
back in the day that was not you were
not looked at favorably i mean that's
what i did so i'm not looking down on
anyone for doing it i was one of the
people looked down on not favorable for
doing those i mean we talked about it
before but you know 12 or 14 years ago
the four or five guys uh doing reversals
were looked upon as cheating
yeah it's cheating you're ruining the
[ __ ] you are ruining genetics for
good you're ruining the gene pool you're
eliminating males you're taking
shortcuts you're doing this [ __ ] up
thing that shouldn't be done
you're trying to do shortcuts to make a
quick buck
yep um and it went from that and it was
you know i don't know
uh
emery is a douchebag i totally agree
that he i think most people agree he's a
kind that he is a he is a non-he is not
a nice person um yeah
by any means um you know i mean but
you know there's a there's a lot of
people that uh you know you get to know
him and weed and you're like oh boy
yeah he's not a good kisser but yeah but
there's an aspect where it's like like
we've talked about it what was it it was
it was matt and rascal and hybe and
uh a couple other a couple other people
doing rehearsals
yeah and it was a sea of of male female
breeding
yeah and now fast forward 12 years and
it's completely reversed
yeah it's like 98
fems
and 2 percent of people doing rag
breeding yeah it's rare to see people do
i've got a red seedline drop
you know what's really weird too for me
like i i don't do that many um
fem seed runs anymore i really don't
even though i sell the spray and i've
been doing it a long time people
associate me with that i i don't do them
often i don't do them very often at all
and i prefer regular seed breeding
because it's so much easier it's like a
[ __ ] free pass to not fail
and uh yeah it's it's it's a totally
different than people's uh ideas of what
fem breeding is and how easy it is it's
uh regular breeding is easy
in the sense of getting actual
successful pollination
with real not that you're going to
achieve your goals that's still the
breeding is a lot of there's still a lot
of dead ends and failure in my opinion
and sure you know and all that but but
you know feminized breeding even
even getting pollen and getting viable
pollen
um you know uh people
it's a crabs you people are saying i
don't think the market's telling
breeders what they want
no
i don't necessarily i don't think that's
it i think that
finding males is a bunch of
and people
started doing things where you can't get
either one of these two elite cuttings
but i'll give you a hybrid of them
yeah you can't get tk by skittles
yeah you know you can't get either cut
but you can buy a hybrid from me
and i think that's what started it and i
think honestly it's like people buy
what's available
you know um and uh
you know
reversals just you just took an elite
cut and you crossed it to another elite
you took an elite cut and you threw that
on 15 or 20 other cuts and boom you've
got a seed drop
yep and reversals actually really killed
the the line breeding
you know companies used to we were going
to talk about simon today tonight right
we're going to talk about sirius a
little bit or whatever
uh serious seeds they offered the same
six lines for like [ __ ] 15 years
yeah 20 years
you know uh scentsy seed bank you know
uh when neville was there or whatever
probably matt and i were looking at a
bunch of the catalogs
they barely offered a new line for five
or six years yeah it was the same as
[ __ ] and then in the late 90s they added
two or three more lines yeah back in the
day they expected you to work on your
line and refine it hopefully and you
have those flagship strains yeah make
those lines better over time now it's
literally like i did this reversal i got
x amount of seeds they're here until
they're gone i probably won't make them
again i gave it a name
yeah
you know but
that's it there's no lines you can't you
can't hit up you know um you could hit
up serious seeds throughout the 90s and
you could get ak-47 and you could get
white russian and you could get chronic
and you could get bubble gum and you
could get
um you know whatever
right and it was just on on it was just
available
so let me let me use this point actually
to tell a story and you'll like this
story because it it has something to do
with you so
i gave natso some seeds a while back and
i i was pretty sure i remembered what i
gave him
right um i thought i gave him an old
pack of ak-47 and i i was like man
when's he gonna pop those [ __ ]
and i would bust his balls over it like
man where's those aka 47 get him pop
he's like i don't know what you're
talking about i'm like [ __ ] not so
right so i bust his balls for at least a
year and a half two years two years
every time i lost his [ __ ] ancient
seeds i'm the old seed guy i talk up ak
like crazy all this different stuff he
sends them to me not only do i not do
anything with him but i [ __ ] him over by
like not actually cracking them or like
crack them i just [ __ ] ignored them
and then i lost them and i keep telling
them i don't have them over and over and
over again
and i'm like dude i gave you these
[ __ ] seats what the [ __ ] so anyways i
was busting his balls about him again
probably i don't know a month ago yeah
you know something like that not that
long
and someone i hadn't talked to for a
long time skunk tech hits him up and is
like hey you know i haven't talked to
matt but let him know that i f2 those
ak-47 seeds he gave me so
oh i was so happy too because i called
that up and i was like you're a dick
dude you gave them to someone else
and [ __ ] me and told me that i [ __ ]
lost them and i didn't remember and i'm
a stoner and [ __ ] yeah yeah
you know you said i sent rare [ __ ] from
the 90s and i blew it off
but in fairness he still does have super
skunk and devils haze over there
but you know there's a there's a yeah i
mean in fairness to me
uh before 2017 there wasn't like
biblical fires every year in my area
yeah yeah yeah i don't mind the fires at
all and so that that ruined a number of
seed crops for me and gave me kind of
some ptsd
and all that but yeah i mean going back
to going back to simon i mean can you
imagine if
you know whoever you know for the last
five years the swamp boys have offered
the same six lines
yeah
matt's offered the same six lines
caleb's csi's offered the same 20.
and they just remake them
and that's what people are doing
yeah and you get you're expected to work
on all those lines and improve them but
you can because you're only offering
half a dozen
now every seed drop is like [ __ ] 20
things
yeah at least usually you know and
they're all given a name and they're all
given packaging and they're all given
this and they're all sold and that's
that that's that
and you'll likely never see them again
because the person's not going to remake
them
and honestly the person the [ __ ] the
person isn't even usually growing them
out anymore
yeah
you know
so i i will say just just to finish the
story
i will give skunk tech some major props
he didn't even have to tell me that he
had those he didn't have to tell me that
he did selections and
made more and he certainly didn't have
to tell natso to make sure i get them
you know or make sure i know about them
to get them so props to him for doing
that i was i was that was pretty [ __ ]
cool and uh there are
ak-47f2 somewhere and they're uh based
on the cherry stuff so that's cool too
what's sad about it
is that in 1999
um they changed the laws in holland in
amsterdam and um i should say the
netherlands really because only two
provinces
uh are uh
are our holland but in the netherlands
they changed the seed laws where before
seed making was legal
and they changed it to being illegal and
most of the big producers in in the
netherlands got busted within a year or
two of that change yeah
and a lot of seed strains and a lot of
lines that were available throughout the
90s
then changed because parents were lost
yes being dutch
and i'm not trying to be
racist is the wrong word or whatever but
just culturally
the dutch are businessmen and they won't
admit that they lost anything ever
yeah
so if you ask ben or alan drunkers
they'll tell you they have all the same
breeding parents that they've had since
the 90s yeah but we know that's not the
case and it apparently simon admitted
that he lost a couple of breeding
parents
in in his raid and coli mist and ak-47
were not the same after
yeah
we should also it should also be said
and this is super [ __ ] annoying for
me right
but that
neville and
s super sativa seed club kind of came
first
right
so they just told you where they were
what they were doing
yeah they didn't have competition right
so neville was like oh i got this nl
from this person and i got this from
this this and i crossed them and i
called it nl by this
yeah right and and he gave you a whole
bunch of information on lineage
yeah and we can go through we've done it
before but you can go through and most
of where neville got his stuff we know
the name of the person that gave it to
him we know where he got it we know if
he got it as a seed line or if he got it
as a cutting
right yep we know all that [ __ ]
i like simon and simon was really nice
to me right but
i don't [ __ ] know it's an ak-47
yeah i don't know exactly what's in
collie mist i've been hunting for 25 30
years what the lineage on that stuff is
yeah and all the second wave of breeders
uh that came out uh sag martha syria
seeds th seeds dutch passion all you
know uh
um what's his name um luke from paradise
yes what's in scentsy star
god only knows what's in what they all
started hiding it
yeah they they hid where they got it
from who they got it from what the mix
was in
right and so it started this massive
guessing game of i love ak-47
yeah i have no idea what's in it
i would love for simon to one day be
like i'm old and i'm just down to
say it you know what i one thing i will
say that's also interesting is from that
old pack of seeds and i believe they
were sold and simon said according to
the number on it they were sold in 2000
which meant they could have been made in
98.99
what was interesting was that the cherry
pheno was supposedly popping up what do
you say one in 500 or 100 000 something
a lot it took a lot to find it
in the three seeds that popped
out of 10 from this old pack
two were cherry
so i wonder if there's some sort of like
viking in it um which was a very cherry
line floating around amsterdam at the
time that a lot of people are using um
but that's the first thing that that
makes me think that and i think that's
pretty interesting it could you're you
know let me just said that that uh
something that i didn't know that it
wasn't lost in the bus that simon's
ex-wife killed them killed a couple
plants out of spite
oh wait it was it was it's common
knowledge that he lost him and i mean i
always heard that he lost him yeah um
but
you know i assumed it was in the bust
and he admitted that he lost one parent
but he never admitted that he lost more
than that
yeah but he would just never give up the
mix
yeah
he just never
that that's another thing that also
really confused me is that
i don't understand why
they would i granted a lot of them were
trying to steal each other's clones and
steal each other's seeds or whatever but
if they were breeders they would know
that how expressions in cannabis work
you know so they probably like i would
think that they wouldn't be focused too
much on well we can't tell them the name
or the the line that this came from
because they'll get the same thing and i
mean well no one knows and you're aware
uh neville's opinion was they stole most
of it from him and didn't want to give
him [ __ ] credit
yeah i know yeah he thought everything
was his though no matter what i know i'm
not saying it is i'm not saying it's
true
yeah but for whatever reason
um you know like yeah what's in chronic
what's what's what's kali missed
what's synchronic what's what's ak-47
what are the parents
yeah where do you get the parents who
gave them the parents
yeah you know
um all that right you just don't know
yeah you know they've never come out and
said and those things came out in the
mid 90s
yeah so we're talking 25 years plus of
him being secretive yeah
you know and yeah neville had an ego and
he thought the whole [ __ ] scene was
based on his [ __ ]
yeah and some of it was but some of it
was his ego you know i still think he
renamed afghani one
i mean i know you do yeah i'm always i'm
always going to push that theory and
it's based on nothing but i'm still
going to push it just because i can i
mean one of the things that i learned
about uh
someone just asked what i believe in
collie missed
um i was told by some guys in amsterdam
that um
you know that the mother plant was this
thing called the mango
and it was made by this guy that i don't
want to name his name or whatever but it
was he was the guy that came up with it
and that was at least half of it
um and i i see people uh
uh
you know there's people want to talk
about whatever but i mean the thing is
is that when i went over there and when
i started going over there in the mid
90s there was already a bunch of dudes
that were middle-aged that all had beef
with one another
yeah and obviously neville and sam had a
bunch of beef with one another and they
sniped at each other for years
um and so there's an aspect there's an
aspect too where it's like sometimes
people just didn't want to give other
people credit
yeah they didn't want it to come from
them
yeah you know they didn't want it to be
that way they didn't want it they didn't
want to be like oh well i got that from
homie
yeah because homie was a dick to them
in their mind you know and then they had
beef and so then there was politics you
can look at the politics of 90s
amsterdam and you can fast forward 30
years and it goes on today in california
yeah
it's very common
so this is this is one of the
old pictures of afghani one that has a
lot of similar traits to what you will
see in in things like super skunk or
even chem 91 and that's one of the the
things that originally put me on to that
and seeing and the la athey cut that we
had that was a afghani number one
selection homie just said uh cali mist
was originally called western winds
western winds was one of my favorite
all-time
uh
cannabis names cambodian cambodian
that's what they said but i don't
[ __ ] know it's supposedly when they
were at cerebral together it was the
same thing
and they broke off tony called his
version western winds
and simon called his kali mist but they
were the same thing yeah they were the
or they i mean maybe they maybe they
made different breeding selections or
choices but they were the same
the same origin for the most part i will
say tony tony has been ridiculously
transparent and open with me when it
comes to asking any questions he's the
only
dutch dude who who had a seed bank from
back then that never like flinches when
i ask him something he's always been
super open even if it's not like
even if he doesn't know the answer he'll
tell you well i don't really know this
game i bought it in bulk from xyz and
that's what it is and that's all we know
he's been really [ __ ] cool about it
so i got to give props to him for that
you know i mean maybe maybe he would say
what it was but maybe if it came from
simon or he had b for some guy he didn't
like he wouldn't say it
yeah because that goes on today like
people don't want to give other people
credit if they don't like the person you
know or they feel like they got jacked
on a i mean even like somebody like sam
like
if it wasn't for mel frank i don't you
know talking about it years later you
wouldn't know that afghani won and
durbin poison came through mel frank
yeah and he gave him to sam
yeah you know sam showed up in amsterdam
with him
you know yeah
and uh you know and then you know tony
tony has you know and then once a line
splits
maybe different breeders make different
selections
yeah they lean it towards one direction
or another you know they lose adam and
the bubble gum and like the different
ways simon worked bubble gum supposedly
and all that yeah i mean i know that i
know i you know i didn't i didn't know
until tonight that that uh simon's ex or
whatever killed killed the cut but
simon's cauli mist in the 90s was much
more sativa-leaning
and then around 99 2000 it got shorter
and thicker and more
more indica more afghan
and it lost some of the ethereal
qualities that i liked a bunch about it
you know that's one that i'd really like
to reproduce and we have the old seats
to do it but i just it's one of those
ones that like i'd spend
money and time reproducing it and they
would just sit there you know and nobody
grew up because cali missed really isn't
one that people talk about at you know
the average fur still in the u.s it's
phenomenal there's phenos in western
winds and you can look
in western winds and cauli mist
especially in like some mid to late 90s
high times cannabis cups like the glossy
pictures they would have and those and
those things
um and uh
you know and um you know so
they uh they're those are really nice
you know yeah and um
you know
you know then he comes out and says it's
kind of true i don't mean that like sam
took a bunch of credit for it i just
mean that it was like in the list of
stuff that that mel that you know that
he brought to amsterdam yeah and he
didn't obviously say well i got these
two things from these guys and i got
these from these guys and here's the
three haze brothers names that i got
these seats like you know it was sketchy
back then yes you still can't get that
[ __ ] out of him
you still can't get that out of him all
i'll tell me is that i'm wrong about the
a story tell me what
one day you know one day
i mean it's uh one thing about weed is
that people are opinionated
yes and it takes a certain kind of
person to take the risks that we all we
all take and the various things that go
on and you know we get beef you know and
all that stuff and so
um but it's it's also true that a lot of
weed is a flash in the pan
so it might be around for two or three
or four years five years and then all of
a sudden it's gone or it's not there in
the same it's not there in the same in
the same category anymore yeah it
doesn't exist
um and there's some there's some really
good versions of ak that still float
around um there was an ak in colorado
that our good buddy working men and i
talk about all the time that was a huge
yielding beast of a sativa um and it
smelled exactly like sandalwood did
pure sandalwood terps uh matt worked
with an ak version that had strong
cherry liqueur
cherry and then lemon i had a lemon one
too that was awesome and then i had the
rc colafino that used to go around skunk
magazine and it smelled like flat cola
it was it was pretty uncanny so that
that's a pretty wide terp range in the
ak line and and interesting and unique
terps and a lot of them had some pretty
god some pretty good highs with them too
you know
so that was a really simon didn't have a
lot of strains
but you know the only the only strain
that i think he had there was absolute
bunk and i apologize if you hear this
simon is chronic
yeah i grew out a bunch of chronic and
it was big and midsy and ugly
and i never found anything worthwhile in
it but
his bubble gum and his ak and his white
russian and his cali mist and all that
that was all real nice weed
i think white russian is totally
underrated too from all white russian is
a super underrated strain and it was one
of his standards for a long time and it
was killer weed yeah there was some
really nice phenos of it
you know i wish i knew i wish just for
my weed nerdism or whatever i wish i
knew i you know i wish i knew what ak-47
was
yeah like what is it
i think if we're getting these cherry
liqueur phenotypes is from hexabutyrate
not a terp but do you think that i mean
because we know that during that time
there was one real strong cherry kicker
that was being used in amsterdam
um
which was the either the holland's hope
which was a version of the viking or
just using viking and they were being
used widely at that time so i i
i've never
now that i know that it's just like and
how how commonly it occurs it almost
seems like it would have to be
chimera and crybaby both telling us that
the cherry is is is uh from uh
it's not a terp you know yeah that's why
you know it's it's the theol's and all
all the various esters and all the
various things that lead to aromas
uh that's not an aldehyde that's not
that's not nice uh forte necessarily
there's a lot of learning that i could
do over there that would expand my
knowledge
um but
i would love if he told me what was in
it
yeah
it would be real it would be really neat
just to know because it's one of the
all-time great strains
yeah the super cool strain and it's neat
that there's
um it's neat that there is uh
maybe here's something that we've talked
about and that most people don't don't
think about too much but um we're
getting close to the end but i'll throw
it out there
yeah and maybe this is something that
like a chimera could chime in on or
whatever but
um what would happen let's say you have
two ak-47s
or you know or two nl5 hazes or
something like that from the 90s and
you're pretty damn sure that they are
what they are that they're the exact
same
era they're the exact same parents
they're just two different
two different plants but from the same
seed line yeah if you reverse one on to
the other
do you get a feminized
seedline because it's not an outcross
and it's not an s1
so so give me the situation again
let's say you took
uh
you know um
a a cherry ak and crossed it to the
colorado sandalwood ak okay
it's not an s1
and it's not an outcross
no
right
that's when we make up words like in
cross that's when we make them up
because cannabis is very unique and we
got to make up our own [ __ ] words
you can do it with anything you could
take any any anything that you know are
sisters
yeah and that came from the same parents
right because most people that are doing
reversals
99.99 percent of reversals are either s
ones or out crosses
yeah we would i mean i know me and caleb
refer to them as f2rs just when we talk
so we know what we're talking about but
i don't think there's any standard term
because there's a way where it's like
you know part of the reason why we do
s1s uh one of the reasons why we do it
in cannabis at least is because often
there's only one pheno there's only one
living cut of a certain line left and in
order for you to look within the
genetics of the line and see what else
might be in there you have to cross it
to itself
yeah we would make normal lines out of a
lot of these strains had we a male
yes or had we but if you have two
females
and you're sure they're the exact same
thing
right then you could breed two sisters
together
yeah and it wouldn't be inbreeding as
much because they would have two
different genetic profiles
yes right it's not you're not in you're
not inbreeding to the extent that an s1
would be no no you're not you're not
isolating traits still so you take you
take a sandalwood smelling
ak-47 and you cross it onto the cherry
ak-47 yeah
and you you know and then you have you
have a you have a feminized seed line
maybe that's what uh bitter did with the
p91 s ones took two different p91s ones
and crossed them together to create his
neck but the difference is that those
are two s ones crossed together
yeah i'm talking about like two sisters
from the same exact hybrid
you see them same thing
that's what i was though two sisters
from the same because if you have an s1
if you have two sisters from an s1
there's one parent
and that's one has one parent right
there's two identical parents so the
genetics is essentially one parent
but if you take two sisters from a
regular line
right
yeah then it's two parents
you know
and it's like if you like for instance i
got multiple daughters you look at my
daughters they're not two peas from the
same pod
yeah obviously you know they have some
they got you know they look very
different from each other
yeah you know my wife and i's genes
popped in different ways in that regard
so you're referring specifically to an
f1 hybrid and then using
two
sisters from that f1 hybrid not from a
reversal necessarily like let's say for
instance you took
um you know we can't get we can't
guarantee this but let's say you took c5
and crossed it to cuban black and you
were sure you know that you're or you
had two phenos of nl5 haze
yeah and you knew that the mom was nl5
and the dad was haze in both it was just
two phenols from the same thing
right and you cross those you reversed
one on to the other
yeah that's probably one of the most
rare things in breeding
because then you'd have a feminized line
but it wouldn't be an s1
i mean the only difference between that
and the feminized version would be that
the feminized version would have less
variation
because there wasn't an additional
uh line
at the
what we're calling the parental level
but that's what i just mean in the sense
that so let's say you take let's say you
make a cherry ak s1
yeah you're gonna only have the gene
pool that's within that specific
that specific plant
it would be going in that direction for
that specific but if you had if you had
a sister of hers
yes that was totally different even
though they're sisters she probably has
a different a slightly different genetic
makeup
so it would be a sibling cross
yeah but it's almost never done because
we almost never have to it wouldn't be
nearly as inbred
yeah it wouldn't be nearly as inbred as
a reverse crop and you'd probably you'd
probably get like a a lot wider
expression within the seats
you know what's interesting though what
you're describing is almost exactly what
dj did with blueberry
two
things that were were from the same
parentage two totally opposite different
expressions and constantly re-cross them
from a small population
each generation i mean i'm not saying
that like in a perfect world if you had
hundreds of seeds that's the direction
that you you should go in oh no no but
i'm just saying that is a method sure
there's there's an aspect where it's
like if all you have in the line is one
living living example
then you all you can do is self it
yeah but if you got two
then you could widen the gene pool just
slightly
yeah and have and have a group of seeds
that had a slightly wider gene pool
than you could get with s1
yeah but i think like if you keep like
that
he did it with moonbow 99 and mumbo 112
yeah i think if you do that and you keep
doing it in successive generations what
you get is a lot of mutants and
weirdness without necessarily the the
narrow down variation i was just
thinking in terms of like 90s weed or
various things where you might get lucky
and you might have one or you might have
two or even three phenos that might
exist
yeah
you see
yeah like where it wouldn't be that that
would probably be
i don't know
you know it's just something that's not
often done but if there's two females
from the same line you might be able to
figure it out
but it's almost never done
think of somebody that think of somebody
that has that often
it's like it's almost like that crossing
it's not don't you don't see back
you don't see back crosses to males
often done
but it's an interesting thing you know
what i mean it has its place
yeah i just in terms of i mean in terms
of most genetic preservation we're like
super lucky
if one pheno of an old line survives
oh yeah for sure
you know but in the case of in the case
of nl5 by hazy
there's probably three or four or five
that survived
yeah a lot more than that i think if we
really knew for sure i think there'd be
a lot more
you know and so there's potential where
you could you could you know you could i
don't know i mean it's just interesting
in that in that regard right yeah
projects the monster those are not
siblings
um we don't know for sure
they're not [ __ ] siblings i don't
think so
yeah but we once apparently hoped that
we hoped that that philos and some other
and some other genetic groups would be
able to prove these things
and it has not happened
yeah no phyllos got everybody's money
because they promised they would be able
to show what was a grandparent what was
a child what was a hut what was a
daughter what was a mother and not not
the case
and we're still going to do a full
episode on that eventually
um
on why
why we were able to prove that it was a
broken system
uh effectively prove it but um yeah
you're gonna give it a little bit of
time so people don't get to butt hurt
and sue and all that [ __ ]
you know but it's it's just one of those
things where uh
between no whether males or females are
responsible specific
there's no there's no you know there's a
lot of there's no way it works
because because cannabis for a long time
has been
well i just i was just gonna say that um
cannabis for a long time has been
deprived of science or the science
aspect
of uh of breeding uh most of it is
observational by people
still to this day there are some people
that um
uh there are some people that are doing
that are doing work uh that are using a
lot more uh scientific methods and
things like that but
um it's rare still
yeah most cannabis breeding is
observational
um and so it's hard to know males and
females
um you know we just don't have we just
we just we're not up until 10 15 years
ago or something like that we were
mostly denied labs yeah we were mostly
denied access
um to what you know normal breeders
would be able to use all the time
yeah so i want to do a um giveaway
before we're done since we're almost at
two hours
and i actually thought of something to
do so you didn't have to um
so like we used to do back in the back
in i don't know a year or two ago
i picked out
um
a phrase there is going to be a blank
spot in this phrase and whoever comes up
with
who we all agree
is the funniest answer
gets the bomb threat bubba hawaiian
lights hybrid
it's one of the more expensive ones so i
wanted to get it out there so people can
yeah anyways so
we have a few different ones let me see
okay here we go here it is you guys if
you want to participate you're going to
have to fill in the blank
rub a dub dub blank in the tub
who has the best answer rub-a-dub-dub
your answer in a tub who has the best
answer
oh man
i know this one should be nice and
creative
rub a dub dub
blank in a tub
rub a dub dub dank in a tub
12 vc in a tub
these nuts is always a great response
a lesbian
fiddling
tug in a tub
sub in a tub oh that's a good one
because that that did exist
it did exist
until it's gross
yeah i might have to pin this one so we
remember who did sub in the tub to see
if someone could beat him
let's see pin okay let's see what we got
those pictures of sub in the tub were
were not cool oh i remember when i made
the
no i'm not gonna say it since he's no
longer with us yeah they just weren't
they just you know you know 379 rks
seeds in the tub
sub in the tub
oh my god
yeah
hilarious
sub in his camera in a tub oh my god i
mean the thing about sub in the tub is
that it rhymes too you know yeah i know
it's pretty
it's great it's it's it's creative it
has a whole thing you know
yeah i don't want pea butt in the tub
either sub should win
a tub
i forgot to wear my peabud shirt i just
got another peabud shirt from my buddy
forgot it
yeah so yeah i think i think we're gonna
have to go
with tri grown send me a send me a dm
after this you get the the hawaii the
bomb threat bubba hawaiian lights
so yeah it's it's it's a it's
it can't eat it so we're almost we're
almost to two hours so we'll do our
normal little thing here on friday night
um yeah as always we're down to totally
talk a lot of what we talked about
tonight was suggestions from people on
our discord
asking us to chat about certain things
um that's a great way to get what you
want talked about talked about
is to reach out to us either on ig or
joining our discord which matt always
explains at the end
um but we're always down to
chat about things uh some episodes are
kind of formal in the sense that we have
a whole theme that we want to go off of
um and some of them are uh some of them
are are are a little bit more loose and
uh interactive
um but always hit us up you know hit me
up hit me up on ig hit me up on our
discord
you know
right now
okay so
you can go to paint or i'm sorry google
type in breeder cindy get patreon you
can join us on the discord i think
there's some some fights coming up the
second
um we just had some cool fights last
week that we we hang out talk [ __ ] to
each other and watch the fights which
has nothing to do with cannabis but hey
whatever it's something else to do um
you also get access to my whole uh
catalog collection in pdf form which i
highly recommend if you are a part of
the the the patreon if you don't know
about that go check them out
it's not just the old seed bank and and
scentsy catalogs there's a lot of really
random uh rare ones
um so yeah beers read using your patreon
go check out wrightco.com
hopefully soon we'll start having more
of the podcast show up um we might
split it off to a new one i don't know
how it's going to go but we'll see but
we'll have the audio form of the podcast
going back up very soon
um yeah uh go check out
speakeasy seed bank they've helped us
along the way with with the uh getting
the podcast and audio form up till this
point so go check them out support them
and uh yeah that's it once again friday
night thank you all for your time very
much it's always super appreciated we
like talking [ __ ] about weed
um and so we'll be here again next
friday night pleasure yep
want more breeder syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsteads.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
you