welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
welcome to reader Syndicate I'm Matt
here with thousand fold and today we're
going to have our buddy iron Lonesome
back for a more expansive more solo type
gig and I'm really stoked to have him
here I know thousand is as well we
wanted to do this for a while and I know
it's probably one of our most requested
episodes to go back and recover so thank
you for being with us
yeah thanks for having me
all right dude yeah
yeah so I think today we're just
following like a loose like linear
chronological
um structure so I think you know we
start at the start
um hi and Lonesome how did you what were
your first few interactions with the
plant you know how did you get into that
uh so I got into it pretty young uh as a
teenager
we would get you know Mexican brick
weeds that was all that was available
um I didn't have
family doing it anything like that
um so we did it it was always pretty
poor quality but it was loaded with
seeds
uh I come from a farming family so
you know I naturally planted seeds
pretty much initially you know probably
within
the first year of smoking I started
trying to grow it
um
it was
it was hit or miss but I think I had my
first harvest when I was
about 17 years old I grew up to Mexican
bag seed
um got a quarter pound of weed and I was
dig digging all over High School I was
the coolest dude I knew
what was that
well you know
Mexican back then it was it was weird
you would get weed that was
dried like [ __ ] wasn't cured either
cured in a tire crossing the border or
you know it was just yeah God God awful
quality in the finished product but
you'd plant the seeds and
um you know you would get you'd get
interesting stuff the problem with a lot
of the Mexican backseat is that it would
have intersex issues outside even
um
I I don't know I think it was just part
of the genetics so that
um you know the first time I grew it was
lightly seated and then the next year it
was lightly seated and
um I'd occasionally come across some
plants that didn't have any intersex
issues and
um you know back then
seeds you know you couldn't find seeds
without ordering them from Amsterdam
which seemed very sketchy at the time
yeah um so you know pretty early on I
was trying to select four plants that I
could grow and have Cincinnati
in terms of like the resources that you
had and in terms of information like how
much did you know about the plant at
that point like did you uh know
immediately to look look out for males
like that kind of thing
uh yeah you know I had a little bit of
you know kind of Stoner Knowledge from
people that had tried to grow
um I did have people in my family that
grew but I was a little young for
anybody to really share information with
me or take me under their wing you know
so I kind of had had a Baseline and
luckily I was trying outdoor
um so you know I didn't have to worry
about time uh you know time light cycles
and all of that I just kind of let it do
its thing and uh tried to finish it
outside how cool are your parents with
you doing all this
um uh not cool but
um you know when when I was a teenager
they kind of had a messy split up so it
was kind of like I could get away with a
lot of [ __ ] perfect timing yeah yeah and
it was kind of at that age for me so I I
started with Gorilla growing and
um didn't really do anything outdoor
until I moved out or didn't do anything
indoor until I moved out right when I
was able to 18 years old and you know I
wanted to get an apartment so that I
could blow it up and grow indoor that's
the reason you wanted to move out not
like to yeah that was your buddies no
that was my number one motivation that's
awesome
I knew what you wanted to do for a
career
yeah yeah pretty early on what I wanted
to do
would you tell us a little bit about
what some of those gorilla Growers would
like
yeah so uh early on it was
pretty much just
you know I I'd get some dry amendments
back then you know stuff that was
readily available chicken [ __ ]
um of course I would line that I'd get
blood meal bone meal cut meal all that
stuff anything I could get at the feed
store without having to go to the city
to the Hydra store and being sketchy
yeah I would get that I would dig
um
I would take a couple 15 gallon planters
that we had I would dig holes
normally I'd try to do at least you know
30 gallon holes and I would get all the
soil out have a tarp mix it up with dry
amendments put it back
um didn't add anything for aeration
didn't really know anything about that
um but I knew that you know I needed
very fertile soil to make anything
happen so I would you know I would use
the native soil and just add dry
amendments until I thought it was good
enough
okay so very little inputs
um I tried I always tried
because I I wasn't going to run any sort
of irrigation or anything like that all
of my girl grows over the years I've
tried to do in areas where I had easy
access to water so
um you know narrow river near a pond
near a lake something like that
um that because I always I always toted
it so it was
whatever would be the least work
while be somewhat discreet
I had never really thought much about
like the Gorilla growing aspect and and
not wanting to go to hydro stores and a
lot of Outlaw States
um but it would make sense why you would
have grown up like learning the organic
amendments and all that stuff versus
having to go risk your ass or your face
at a hydro store you know take multiple
cars on your way back yeah yeah I mean
well yeah it was just it was what was
available at the time I could either you
know I could get Miracle Grow or I could
get dry amendments and do it like I was
you know trying to grow a bad estimated
plant around me a lot of people grow
tomatoes you know my family did that
growing up and it was kind of a similar
technique that I was using
do you prefer to make like cherry
tomatoes or heirloom big beefy ones
um dude I have 75 eating those that's
for eating uh
probably like a cherry
tomato
same yeah unless I'm feeling like if I'm
doing a BLT you know I gotta have a big
steak tomato yeah yeah of course
so for me like you talk about moving out
how how quickly did you get your hands
on other kinds of genetics
and uh so I the first couple times I
tried to get seeds
um I would I dealt with seed banks that
I think I dealt with Mark Emery
um pretty early on sent money to Canada
was you know a hoof and a dream and
didn't get [ __ ]
um
and had a kind of follow-up
pretty similar uh I didn't really start
getting anything until
I went to the Dutch you know or the UK I
I did stuff that was reasonably cheap
Nirvana Casey brains that kind of stuff
a little bit of Scentsy
um but ordering it through seeds direct
or one of those you know guys in the UK
yeah so I didn't really
start with that uh until
I moved out and
that was I think
um
I was gonna say
um yeah that was about what I found
overgrow so I kind of had a little bit
more knowledge as to what I wanted as
you know what I could finish
um
all of that and I get you know I'd get
cheaper stuff like Nirvana and Casey
brains for my outdoor grows and you know
if I was going to do some stuff inside
where I could back up plants I would
Splurge a little bit and get a cheap
pack of CC's or something
Casey brings for the outdoor win
yeah that that stuff was solid I wish I
still had some
well yeah I wanted to ask you about that
too because Matt Matt does have a bunch
of questions for you about the forums
but before that I did want to ask out of
these early packs uh what were some of
the highlights that you remember
um I liked the KC 36 a lot I did really
well outdoor here
um
just good I mean you know looking back
on it it was all very Justified uh you
know all the Nirvana stuff seemed like
it was a skunk one cross
um
their their turban poison I did a lot I
really liked
um
their white rhino I grew a bit indoor
and really liked that uh for the potency
the flavor
didn't do much for me with white rhino
White Widow any of those white
um but the potency was there
um
so that kind of stuff really the first
seeds that I grew and I really was kind
of head over heels for them were um some
free seeds I got from evergrow from
there's a guy jlp that would give away
seeds
um and I grew a bunch of his lines over
the years you know you just be an active
member send them a message and he'd send
you some free seeds so he had um
he had a couple lines that grew uh Romeo
and Juliet was one he had one called
Phoenix Hayes that was like a Neville's
hay Super Silver Haze it was really good
yeah that was in the um that was in that
the the afro pits
um Senegal Haze at the Phoenix oh really
yeah oh cool yeah that was an awesome
plan
um yeah I love that
it was um you know
pretty heavy on the Neville's Haze I
think it was something like
you know Dutch grown got busted and the
seeds were collected and so they were
either Neville's Haze or Neville's
across the super silver haze and yeah he
he inbred it from there and um it was
just there were some phenomenal plants
in those they're bad
pedimore right jlp yep John Lee
pettimore yeah
um
at the forums did you already have did
you already get the name heinle so how
did you come to that name
um that name I didn't use it on overgrow
I wasn't as active on overgrow I was
kind of
pretty sketched out by it I had a
different handle
um but when I when that went down I kind
of freaked out for a little bit and you
know I thought everybody's getting
busted and all that and then when I
signed up for
I see mag I was
um really into
bluegrass music at the time and
um you know the highlands and sound that
was something that you know that's the
way people described the sound of the
Stanley Brothers which is you know a
kind of first generation bluegrass band
from Virginia
and so it's kind of a play on that
that's why I chose it and you know I
don't know in retrospect I probably
could have come up with something cooler
but that's uh that's what I got
I think that's a great name it's pretty
cool it's pretty [ __ ] cool a lot
that's a good story too I forget that
like uh Bluegrass culture a lot of it
is Eastern Area yeah there that's uh
Southwest Virginia and um yeah right
yeah Kentucky's the Bluegrass State
um that's where
that's where it kind of all started
um but yeah Kentucky intensity Southwest
Virginia North Carolina all that
very cool nice
yeah
Matt did you want to ask about yeah
all right so we have uh we've talked
about overgrowth talked about icy mag
are there any other early forums that
you can think of that um we're kind of
influential in your uh Growing
Experience or like online learning
experience that we have mentioned
uh the only other one I would say of
great significance to me would be
mechanic Cabana which
people that
um were getting frequently banned from
icdmag kind of started going over there
I had a bunch of
friends from the forums that were over
there and they kind of turned me onto it
but that was a smaller Forum but a ton
of knowledge there and people that you
know it didn't have nearly as many you
know 17 year old kids showing up trying
to find weed it was it was Growers
discussing
the real deal you know yeah so that one
was was pretty big for me
um for years uh and then you know there
were there were quite a few other
smaller ones that I was on but
um Buchanan command is definitely the
the only one other than I see mag that
uh was a major influence on me
yeah shout out to d man
um yep
so you know I don't know how much you
want to go into this part and it's up to
you I can write it down if not
um I wrote down early friends and allies
on the forums so like early friends
people you you met that were influential
to your whatever at the time you know
what I mean like uh
anybody stands out early on
uh yeah I had quite a few
um
there were a couple local guys I don't
know how active they are nowadays and I
don't know if
they would want me
saying their names yeah yeah well you
know there there were a few like um I
met a local guy who went by uh stretch
puppy on the forums he was a good friend
of mine we became pretty close and
we shared a lot of genetics and
um you know we both learned quite a bit
from each other we all have out of it he
was a bit north of me
um
he he drew some really cool stuff we
shared a ton of genetics and he uh
yeah he was just a cool guy he was
he was blowing it up back then in a area
where I probably wouldn't have
that's gangster but he's uh he's the
first guy who showed me the Fairfax
four-way
oh wow
and he was getting bags of it
um but he couldn't
um you know couldn't get to cut it was
it was held down we didn't know the
right people
and he um
he actually bought
um some packs of the Nirvana four-way
and he popped a packet and he found a
Dead Ringer of the plant it was
incredible
it um
it was it
was just a phenomenal plant it was very
um
very similar to some of that Rubber City
stuff
the way the heads work
um the way the heads develop on the
plants um it was it was a hell of a line
I wish I had 10 packs of that you know
um but no kidding yeah back then it was
like oh it's just Nirvana I'll buy the
real things and see if I really want to
find it
right and it'll always be around forever
yeah yeah now it's not available I've
reached out to them they don't have it
um yeah sucks of course of course of
course right yeah no that's interesting
you mentioned the Fairfax far away I
know since you uh mentioned it a lot of
people are going to be watching are
going to be the a boys
um do you have any uh Recollections of
it or remembrances of of how it was back
then
I really don't it's uh that was a long
time ago it was like that dude it was
just this was this was in the era where
you know most commercially available
stuff with beasters
um
so it was you know it stood out because
it was
locally grown high quality I would
imagine so
yeah it you know today
it would probably be really cool for me
I'd really get into it but it doesn't
seem like something that would be
you know in a dispensary in Denver it's
not it's not a modern thing
last I heard they were cleaning the cut
up I wonder where it's at it should be
through that status now
be cool to see yeah post post uh hplv
yeah I'd love to see it I'd love to you
know grow it just for like the trip down
memory lane yeah we need to connect you
guys anyways that dude that dude from
Virginia as well is pretty pretty cool
he's pretty uh legit
go
yeah
um but any other about oh yeah go ahead
I was going to say about that same time
um you know
how we would see some other stuff from
like the northern part of Virginia
um
Scentsy star I remember that being
devastatingly potent the first time I
smoked it and
um you know around that time started
seeing
Saturdays will show up and and that kind
of stuff
in Virginia
Sour Diesel in Virginia
yeah so you know a lot of a lot of stuff
came down it's it's not really that far
from New York you know um yeah and
certain markets um like the DC area back
then you know an ounce of salaries it
was six hundred dollars so I mean it was
it was very very marketable
um and so you know
that started showing up I smoked and was
like holy [ __ ]
um and luckily I had
made some friends through the forums
that I could source to cut through and
um and I yeah I fell in love with that
one I bet that's that's a game changer
especially for that era in time
yeah [ __ ] I still smoke it all the time
um there's something that I wanted to
ask you and and it's kind of a little
bit of a tangent but it's in the same
realm what are some of the other old uh
Virginia clones you can think of that
light you'd like to nod to in this uh
episode
foreign
it wasn't
like out west you know it was very small
Circles of people so there wasn't
there wasn't a ton of trading
um you know you'd see
the Ganny from Virginia Beach sometimes
um yeah that which there were other
candies in the state that people were
growing there was one in Southwest
Virginia that was incredible
um but you would see stuff like that it
was mostly cuts of Siege lines yeah it
wasn't
it wasn't stuff with mysterious Origins
and all of that it was afghani's
um there was a the Urban Poison cut in
my area for a while but mostly the cut
game
started happening
around the time that you know the price
gouging was going on in Northern
Virginia
um yeah Saturday's a little train wreck
that kind of stuff
was going for insane monies how people
started
um growing that stuff locally and
cashing in very much
I can't even imagine seeing train wreck
over there for the first time because
it's so vastly different than a lot of
the wheat over there
oh yeah yeah that was
that when that hit the area it had you
know it was on top for years and I bet
um
you know it was mostly import from
Northern California and yeah the joke
the joke was always what doesn't sell in
California it gets hit East
um so the the quality wasn't there but
it was unmistakably trading rack you
could tell I mean anybody that's grown
it could see it
um but man if you had if you had a jar
of like really nice well-grown indoor
train wreck and you cracked that you
would [ __ ] blow people's minds back
then oh I bet dude I bet uh
so yeah that was that was cool but it
was also you know in that that era
um
you kind of had to watch who you pulled
that [ __ ] out around
like um
you know you couldn't go to a party and
open a jar of sour these were a train
rack because then everybody would be
like oh what is this where where did you
get this you know yeah it was so yeah it
was
kind of weird cool guy to Mark real fast
yeah so
um you know it was
it was like when you're going out to the
party or hang out with some friends you
grab a bag of City weed that you bought
off somebody just to keep a low profile
it was bad yeah that sucks
yeah you can't even flash a good [ __ ] in
front of the chicks well you know you
could but yeah yeah
no yeah sure yeah for sure for sure so
um you know you had to be reserved to
make it yeah
um
to make it through the drug war
yeah and it was great power comes great
responsibility huh exactly yeah chicks
are always the first way dudes get
caught anyways now that I think about it
so yeah that makes a lot of sense
yeah yeah
um Matt you had a note here about the
infamous chem 101 thread on I see yes
all right
um yeah so can we talk about like some
of your um your first experiences with
even hearing of Cam what what started
that journey into trying to track down
the history because like a lot if people
aren't aware like some of my first
intros into reading on the forums about
like digging into a history was like the
chem 101 thread for me so it was it's
pretty important in my learning and
overall how we ended up here at this
point overall so what what put you on
that Journey
uh so at that time
um you know I had sourdes a witch there
were various theories floating around
about how that was related to uh Kim dog
yeah
um I had a you know Kim dog bag seed
cross that I was growing that was you
know pretty
pretty close to
um you know what a lot of people know is
like a KMD hybrid now yeah
um so I I was trying
even pretty much from the jump with Kim
dog online there was a ton of
misinformation a ton of people trying to
you know
get credit for it so yeah I I started
trying to compile what information was
available
talk to the people that were closest to
you know
to the whole thing the Kim Fam guys I
guess they would be called now yeah
um and try to get kind of a
straightforward
um
you know just a breakdown of the family
and and how it was all together and I
was you know I was looking at this [ __ ]
researching and talking to people every
night and I was like well [ __ ] you know
if I'm doing all this I might as well
put it down so the next guy that wants
to know what the [ __ ] going on can I
look it up and figure it out
um So after talking to various people
um
you know at the time on the Forum you
could talk to Joe brand you could talk
to
Peabody Kim dog Greg was on there
um who else
JJ was on there yeah a bunch of people
that were
um you know relevant in that world were
there to to discuss so I basically took
the information
as best I could and and put it together
you know looking back on it there are
definitely some flaws in it um but at
the time it was the information that was
available as well as I could present it
I mean it's like it really is still the
best information as anybody could
present it as given by the people who
told it
yeah sure it's accurate to that to that
extent and that's that's probably the
most important part I think
yeah yeah it was um
it was it was a cool thread I you know I
talked to inspector a bunch about it and
I remember I when I posted it you know
he came on and I think his first post on
the thread was you know if you're gonna
talk about Kim 91 you ought to have a
picture of the real one and he posted
because the picture that I had used was
from Joe brand and it wasn't it wasn't
kim91
um but at that time
at that time I had no experience with it
it was still sure a very tightly held
cut so um you know pay for effort right
well I mean and Joe brand was the source
of the seed so like him posting a
picture at chem 91 you would assume
would be a great source for the picture
you know yeah I mean yeah at that time
that was yeah that's straight from the
horse's mouth you know yeah exactly no I
I it's always fascinated me to know what
puts you on that Journey because it's
it's a lot of how we ended up like even
here at this point discussing this kind
of stuff together now so it's pretty
cool yeah and and it's still really
yeah yeah
for someone to come in like me in what
2019 2020 and to go and look at that
thread is still really remarkable
um yeah and the number of you know like
people who are now very notable figures
in the community
um that were in that participating like
that that's kind of amazing
yeah it was it was a uh it was a smaller
world back then
yeah and it's still the best place to go
look at all the pictures is like the one
through four two which is cool yeah
absolutely hard to find pictures of
anywhere uh at least the one yeah that
was um yeah that was right after uh
inspector had run them all and so he had
pictures that he let me use for the
thread and um yeah it was it was pretty
remarkable I'm still
kind of bummed I never got to try the
two and the three but uh you know yeah
what are you gonna do
the two the two has always interested me
because it's it's Bunch structure being
so uniquely different than all of them
you know little tiny budlets as opposed
to yeah everything else I don't know it
just always seemed more unique than the
rest yeah it was but um I remember
uh inspector did he crossed them all to
deep chunk and yeah chrome chrome ran
out the chem two deep jump and there was
a plant in there
that was like strikingly similar to
kim91 and wow yeah it it at least
visually and that kind of always
you know I just I've always thought
about that I know man I wish I could
have gotten those to pop
is this a good time for us to also ask
you about what you might consider your
first breeding projects like actual
breeding projects is does that happen in
a similar time to the thread
um well you know
really I've always kind of done it um
I I've messed with breeding different
Mexicans trying to get away from
hermaphroditic plants
um pretty much
the second year I was growing it was
something that I always kind of messed
with had found the mail that seems solid
I would I would save it
um I never had any intentions in into
really getting into breeding it was
always just kind of something that came
with the territory for somebody that was
obsessed with with weed
um and really the
the first thing of note I did was
um you know this stuff was praise dog
and I passed it to some friends that I
traded seeds with back then you know
Bodie and I talked a lot on the forums
or several other people 40 credit
um you know a bunch of guys that I
I would just swap some seeds with and
you know [ __ ] along and uh that was
the first
um the first thing of note that I ever
did before that it was mostly just kind
of
um you know I'm gonna cross this Mexican
to this Phoenix Haze or I'm going to
cross this Mexican to this other one and
try to get
rid of the hermaphrodite you know but
um yeah I would say that's the first
thing of note that I I really did
what all did you do with the trade-off
or I'm sorry yeah trade on
uh so at that time I had a pretty good
um stable of cuts and I was growing
um growing those seeds from JJ
um he and I had traded some stuff and I
had
some of those seeds I was growing some
of his
um
Nigerian silver that cross I was growing
a few a few different things at the time
and um I found a male in a trace talk
that I was really impressed with I was
impressed with you know the structure of
it the bigger the
um you know Kim he can be kind of floppy
but it was had a really nice rigid
structure
um and so I I kept it and
um there were a number of plants that I
really liked but they were missing
certain things so I basically just hit
you know
hit some plants with it I hit Green
Crack I hit purple Urkel I hit
um the Kim D and Kim four that I had I
hit
um
abusive as you Kush I had an Acapulco
Gold that I hit
um just kind of a mix a mixture of stuff
and I pretty much gave all the seeds
away I kept a few for myself but mostly
it was just you know
just giving them to my friends
so for clarity here what is the Tres dog
that is a Tim Dog D
um vx2 to JJ NYC made
um and I'm not sure
if it was I don't know if the Original
Seed line was released
um because this was before top dog
launched
um I'm not sure if he I know he released
an in-cross of it later but I I believe
when he
um you know started his company it was a
star dog is what kind of launched
launched the Kim lines if I'm not
mistaken
how so what mail did he use for the
president
it was a
sincere
yep yeah that was the outcross yeah yeah
so he used the Afghan one and then uh
and then res pretty much copied him and
used the Scentsy Hindu Kush
um
but JJ was the the first one to have a
kimchi type c line
you know that like going back I got to
give him props on knowing to use Afghani
one or or a type of plant like that to
that cross sorry it's using a back cross
like that like yeah looking back at how
many people have made epic fails if that
crosses like that's actually probably a
pretty good choice to use in that
yeah he um he did a great job with it I
you know I had that male plant that I
kept for a little bit and then I had a
female from it that was phenomenal as
well it was like a um
it was like a it had the kimdi potency
but it was a little bit creamier like um
it it's most reminiscent to me of like
if you grow TMD outside
um okay it's still it's still really
funky but it has this kind of sweet
creaminess to it especially as it starts
to occur pure a little bit
um and that
that came through pretty strong on the
trace dog
um but yeah it was a it was a great line
I
um I hit it to a bunch of stuff
and uh yeah sounds it got kind of
popular yeah the dog's Waltz uh notably
the poodle nuts cut now that was found
by 40 Grit
yeah 40 grit 40 ounce grown nut he had a
bunch of names
um yeah
on the forums he so he was
um a good buddy of mine that I met
through
yeah either overgrow or I see nag and he
he was like the first dude that was like
blowing up warehouses and posting
pictures of it he was growing you know a
warehouse of Urkel in the Bay Area and
just you know crushing it his
his Oracle was the best that I ever
smoked it was incredible
um he just nailed it but you know he was
always looking for for something that
grew faster because
if you're doing lights and lights of
Urkel you know your veg time is for
[ __ ] ever
um so when I was
um you know when I was making this seeds
I had an Urkel and I was like you know
what I'm gonna pollinate that one just
for just for my boy 40. and so yeah I
sent I sent him a bunch of seeds and he
popped them and uh yeah he found that
cut that he called the poodle nuts
and uh it still floats around
yeah I I remember my first encounter
with that was with uh a bunch of the
Colorado people I noticed it getting
really big in Denver when the Denver
medical scene came on
and I know um what's his name uh Tiara
Rojo Phil filthier Rojo he was blowing
it up with that thing and that's when I
was like God what is this because it was
super unique looking and like to me it's
uh and you'll probably hate that I say
this but it reminds me of like something
as unique
and different looking as cookies would
have been at the same time like looking
at them how different they both look
from normal standard butt around it
could have easily caught on the hype of
that in my opinion and you know like it
was almost going in that direction in
Denver it just never quite got the
cookie smash yeah it was unique
yeah yeah there were there were several
guys in Denver that grew it it still has
um
still has a pretty good reputation there
I actually
um I went to a dispensary here a year or
two ago and um I was meeting a friend
that ran the dispensary and he was
telling the people in the shop I mean
this is the guy that did dogs Waltz and
they were all like oh man you know that
was I was like damn man yeah
I've got two questions here so just to
be clear that the dogs Waltz is Urkel by
Tres dog is that right yes
okay and would this be would you
consider this the moment where you were
starting to get exposure for the first
time
um
no I wouldn't say that because it was
still you know
it was Forum exposure it wasn't like it
was
um
it wasn't like it was winning a cup or
anything like that it was you know the
people that I already knew and respected
saw that I made something that was cool
so it was more like it was more like
just getting getting the respect of my
peers and people that I looked up to
um yeah yeah the the moment that I kind
of I guess
became Infamous in the in the Cannabis
world was
um when 30 started using the Appalachian
stuff
is it time for us to talk about the
Appalachia I mean even the name I mean
we uh it might be one thing before that
and I you can correct me if I'm wrong
but the skunk magazine sub cool
um retraction was that part of
Appalachia
uh yeah the when he published the Kim
101 in Skunk magazine yes yeah that was
um that was kind of wild to me because
you know at the time I was just a dude
that had a couple whites in his house
and did some gorilla grows and you know
just some dude and I'd go to the
bookstore and pick up the weed magazines
every once in a while because you know I
wasn't getting that [ __ ] in the mail
yeah and that's it I've hooked it up one
day and started reading it and I was
like God damn this is word for word my
thread for my city mag that's kind of
[ __ ] up and you know
I I wasn't the biggest fan of him anyway
so yeah you know it kind of rubbed me
wrong
um so I I remember looking up the email
for them and I emailed them and linked
them to the thread
and they were of course super apologetic
and they were like we're gonna dock him
on the next article and we're gonna send
you
the amount and it was it was something
ridiculous it was like more
uh it was more for just getting it
corrected I think yeah I think they they
sent me a check for like 70 bucks or
something that I never passed
but it was more for like you know peace
of mind I guess I had to frame that [ __ ]
you know I was just thinking I don't
know whatever happened to it
um but yeah I probably should have yeah
that's funny funny um artifact to find
if you have yeah right
yeah yeah I have no idea what that would
be
and then there's another one that that I
know CSI would want me to bring up
before we move on and I think that
before Appalachia and that's the the
infamous icy mag Banning of high and
Lonesome where like
everybody kind of decided they were
going to start pulling their threads and
[ __ ] because they banned you
yeah I got fans
I can't remember
it might have been in the gym 101 thread
um but basically it was
having a bit of a back and forth with
old res dog all right I see Mac and this
you know
this wasn't even
you know this was pretty
government informant rest dog this was
just you know he's he's a giant [ __ ]
and yeah yeah
so so you know I had a couple back and
forths with him on the forums and that
was you know Jesse Nirvana's number one
Cash Cow so
basically if you talk [ __ ] to him you
got yanked and he was just an arrogant
prick and as far as I can tell he still
is but you know now he's also
they confirm rat so you know
I
I would get banned again over that [ __ ]
whatever
so the rest of the story goes that
everybody else on not everybody
obviously
a bunch of the respected guys on icy mag
including CSI who had you know hundreds
and hundreds of pages of amazing Growers
up there just started deleting them
to try to get you back you know I did it
worked eventually didn't it
uh no I had to I waited a while and then
I was like [ __ ] it I'm gonna sign back
up and I signed back up and they banned
me and then I I I eventually did it
again just to see and I think I still
currently have an account there
yeah I never never used it but
they always got me bro they always got
me but I always had riot in the name
somewhere you know
yeah yeah and you know it was it was a
marketing thing it was it was how he
sold seeds and if you [ __ ] with his
money you were gone
that tended to be most of the the the
the way with forums though like most
forums seem to have some sort of seed
bank eventually connected to it and then
you know they had their top dog and if
you messed with that then there was an
issue here almost always yeah it was
always fun and that's
and that's the reason a lot of people
like CSI and myself and
um many others kind of went to the
Canada Cabana because it was yeah it
wasn't a it wasn't a seed banks Forum
you could kind of discuss what you
wanted
um
just without a lot of the politics yeah
yeah command is cool
yeah
all right I think now we can head in if
you want
sure
um I did have one last thing on the
forums which is in 2023 are there forums
that are still relevant in like to you
um there's good information on I see mag
still it's um it's difficult because
as people got banned a couple things
would happen
um they would either have their post
left up without their name on it so it
just says yes so uh on some of those
older threads you don't really know
who's comments you're reading you don't
know whether to put a lot of weight into
them
um they
they there is a good amount of relevant
information there
um it's
it's a bit Antiquated at this point it's
a lot of you know
a lot of guys that are doing [ __ ] in
illegal States wiring up you know a
couple
250 watt HPS lights or something it's a
lot of you know as a home grower I think
it has a lot a lot of good material but
if you're um
if you're doing anything big it's pretty
antiquated
yep that sounds better um
and then I don't know I haven't I
haven't checked out a lot of the others
um
mechanic event is still around I know
like roll it up is still around I
haven't I've I went on there to
um
follow a thread uh where somebody was
growing some of my stuff and it was
pretty cool but you know I'm not active
on any of them I
I don't have a ton of extra time like I
did when I was younger
yep yep okay well I I think we can segue
it now to the Appalachia
um so
from the time that you first made the
cross like how long has it been
um
it was 2007 when I made it so it has
been
what 16 years wow yeah
yeah so it's you know for me
a lot of people are really excited about
it but for me it's like it's something
that I made and I pretty much grown it
ever since then
um it does really well and multiple
applications for me so it's something
you know
does well outside does well enough
Greenhouse does well indoors so I've
kind of always always done it
um and I usually make seeds with it most
of them just kind of hang out in my
fridge until I it's awesome or something
um but yeah it's
it's an older line but it's it's a good
one
I want to ask you about maybe what you
perceive to be the different stages that
project's been through but just before
that I want to ask about the name you
know why did you call it Appalachia I
know you already talked about how high
in Lonesome is drawn from bluegrass
um yeah Appalachia tell us about that
uh really it was because
I was hoping to find something that was
um
a little more solid for what I wanted
outdoor and that's a time I was doing my
outdoor grows in that region so I was
kind of hoping for something that was
regionally appropriate
um
a lot of the stuff that was popular on
the west coast and popular in you know
Spain or places like that didn't really
cross over we have a different climate
we have a lot more humidity
um
earlier Frost in a lot of places so a
lot of the stuff that was marketed for
out for wasn't really well suited to the
area
so I kind of just
uh called it Appalachia because Green
Crack was one that I grew a lot outside
and
that I was hoping to improve it with the
trace dog Green Crack has some issues
outside it
if you let it go to where I like it you
know it's it likes to rot it's it's a
very fast plant though so you can get
away with it by by taking it early it
triggers pretty early here
um and you can get it eight weeks
without any issues I like to take it 10
weeks and man if you leave it out out
here that long it's you know it's you're
losing half of it
can you um first for like an indoor
idiot like me can you explain what
triggers early means because I know it
took me years to figure out what that
even meant
yeah so as you know after the solstice
the days start to get shorter and
shorter
um most stuff outdoor doesn't wait until
it's
actual daylight equivalent to flip if it
did that everything would flip in
September here so um as it is as the
days get shorter and shorter
um you know some stuff will start
flowering at
14 hours of daylight some stuff will
start flowering at 13 hours of daylight
you know if you have it if you have it
where it only gets Morning Sun it might
trigger a little bit earlier
um so that's always been
especially with messing with different
cuts outside you know there's some stuff
that was
amazing indoor but you take it outdoor
and it triggers at the end of August and
you can't finish it right here
um Green Crack triggers pretty early
um consistently so it was it was a good
candidate to work with for my scene
yeah I know we liked it outdoors in San
Diego a lot too uh mostly yeah outdoor
experiences green crack and yeah Casey's
brains and green crack for the most part
yeah
okay yeah so that's awesome so those are
some of your initial considerations when
you made the cross
um would you be able to take us through
the Journey of like
where appalachia's been from you know
from the early days uh with Bodhi and to
where it is now
uh yeah so
I gave it to dirty I didn't really know
um
what all had come of it I kind of took a
break from
um the forums
the late 2000s maybe 2008 2009 I took a
couple years off from it I was just kind
of
sick of the politics sikka you know the
big Dickens
um
so I I didn't really know
what was going on with it I was I was
growing it outside every year I had a
couple cuts that I grew inside but
outdoor I would usually make a few seeds
with it
um
basically uh
kind of uneducated or not uneducated it
just wasn't ever something that
I intended
for you know a broad audience so it was
one-to-one breeding I find a male I like
see the lowers on a female I liked and
keep disease
um
around I don't know two thousand
I don't know early 2010s
um
Matt was actually on I see mag and sent
me a message
um saying that
Ken had won the Cannabis Cup with a
renamed appalachicut
um and I I logged on just to you know
answer my messages and team up with a
few people I don't want to lose contact
with and I saw that and you know I hit
up voting about it and we talked about
it and he's like oh man you know I
didn't want to drag you into the drama
filled me in on it and um you know it
the word got out that it was
um Cody's keeper female Appalachian cut
that won the Cannabis Cup as a 11.
um and around that same time
um
thought he had made you know a lot of
crosses with it and uh it was it was
starting to take off so
that's when it was um you know that's
when it was kind of a big deal
um
there was a ton of demand for it I you
know I had some seeds that I was working
with but not a ton
um
and
uh I think I originally released
the line as an F3
around 2012 through the sea Depot
um which was you know a European seed
bank that
was stand up until it wasn't yeah um
yeah I released those and um
the sour diesel Appalachian cross
so at which point with the oh sorry oh
no go ahead
this is going to ask with the F3
um how were you selecting towards that
um so at that time I was looking for
basically what I'm looking for now I
like um
green crack my favorite thing about it
is the flavor the candied mango it's
really good the high is nice if you let
it go 70 days but if you take it when it
looks done around eight weeks it's it's
not I mean it's not that good you know
if you take a 70. it's a nice Buzz it's
a good all-time day smoke
um but it doesn't you know
it doesn't pack a punch it has a pretty
low ceiling
um but the flavor is I mean you just
want to smoke it constantly yeah so
um you know my goal with that one has
always been try to get some of the mango
flavor with the potency
um which you know it's hard to get it
all together
um but that's that was the goal then
um and that's you know I don't know how
many of those tax got sold
um
I you know they shut down a few months
after I started dealing with them and
kind of screwed all the Breeders but
yeah
um
but that was that was the goal then and
um after I you know took my lickins
there I just kind of gave up on
any kind of ideas with the seed game
because it was too sketchy dealing with
people in Europe and all that jazz
yeah
um
is it worth talking about
the difference between you working on it
then and your recent releases of it
uh sure so
you know working on it then I made those
f3s I didn't use
a huge pool
um
to select from then
uh the f2s
you know it was from Maybe
15 seeds something like that
um and
once I got to F3 there were some plants
I liked but
when I made F force with it it it lost
the manga the mango was pretty much gone
um you know there was a higher
percentage of of lands highly resinous
plants
um the the resin from Green Crack came
through but it lost the flavor
the resident of it came through and then
the potency of the trace off but I
couldn't I couldn't get that flavor
um I I took it to F5
um see if I could
you know find some but it was you know
more of the same it was it remained a
very vigorous highly resonance plant
with um you know still a a good little
range to it um some good highs in there
but it it didn't have the flavor
um so
you know after years of
people asking about it and Matt kind of
getting on me to make some more I um I
went back to the f2s I popped 50 of them
and um
I found
um you know several plants that I really
liked in the f2s there were there's a
good bit of mango there were some some
with you know mango and fuel kind of
interplaying and in a unique way
um So to avoid
bottlenecking it I I used a couple males
and um you know all of my favorite
females
um
I grew the females out separately smoked
on them all and the ones that were
really impressive that had what I
thought I wanted in the line those are
the ones that um I
harvested seed from and that's what I
released
um did you make a conscious decision
about whether to do one-to-one as
opposed to like a group
uh so I
yeah I did make that decision so
initially I was doing one-to-one
braiding and I think that
works really well for certain things
um the
the thing with Appalachia at the time
you know was some people wanted it to
smoke a lot of people wanted it for
hobbyist reading projects
um and a lot of people had a kind of
different
um impression of what the line should be
based on Cody's work Cody had a male
that brought a lot of creaminess
um you know like a creamy Kim
sweetness
um
to the lines and I didn't want to
completely deviate from that because
that's what a lot of people you know
fell in love with with the line
um so I wanted it to keep I wanted to
keep it open
so that there would be
um a decent variety for people to look
through
um
there what I heard there basically is
that the world owes me a favor for
getting you to release seeds so
basically it's all me is what I heard
there yeah yeah yeah I definitely did
want to get into two guys one cups but
just before that
on either side of the Appalachia like in
this whole journey were there other
notable projects
um that you'd like to highlight
um
not really I've done a lot of kind of
like
private stuff for my own curiosity and
um
I don't know I have I've done a lot of
things that
I'm either not pleased with or they I've
never got around to testing them I have
I have a lot of crosses I've done but I
never really had the
the mindset
um
to release them commercially so there's
I have a good amount of stuff that I'm
kind of digging back through now
um but no nothing noteworthy that would
mean anything to anybody except me it's
the pickiest person I've ever met it's
crazy how much stuff he's made and or
like I've talked about in the past like
gone through several generations and
then been like nah I'll go back like
three steps and then start there again
and go back through it's like
tedious I mean it's it's amazing to
watch sure yeah it's amazing to watch
it's it's just not often done you know
because it is
yeah I mean it's um you know
like I have a TMD back cross that I made
um but that's not it's not something
that's ready
for any kind of
ready for me to let out I've you know I
recently did some more sativa kind of
stuff but it's um you know
Fury's still out on it I gotta I gotta
approve of it
I think um we can come back to some of
your you know current more recent
experiments and your b-sides uh but
maybe we can't talk about two guys one
cups
at this point
yeah
um that that was all I mean it pretty
much sent from a joke yeah when uh
me and Matt were talking about you know
winning cuffs and not getting credit for
it because the genetics were either
renamed or you know just not called out
and I was like man we need to we need to
start a company and call it uh
two guys one cups and I spelled it like
you know the
um
and really it's um
from a marketing and branding standpoint
it's a terrible move
um like probably the worst
um worse things ever but it was it was
uh it was just something we were
[ __ ] around with for fun to release
kind of collaborations
um yeah we've talked we've talked about
like rebranding and maybe doing it
seriously
um yeah but but there's some cool stuff
in there bro yeah that was such a good
name too yeah why don't people
appreciate like triple entender
yeah yeah it's super witty yeah so what
were your uh what were both of your
favorites to come out of that collab
how we only did too yeah
there's two there was the um the poodle
nuts bloop on it and then the lupus
headband Appalachia and that's it that's
what we've got that that comprises the
total of two guys one cups
yeah how does Google nuts relate to dogs
walls
it's a cut of it it's the it's the cut
did uh 40 grit found that was kind of
how it became popular
yeah
cool
um but yeah that's that's the extent of
that that work thus far
yeah and they maybe under new different
names new different messes
um I don't know where this one fits in
high in Lonesome but we you and I talked
about
um you talking about breeding for
recessives so where did that appear
in your
yeah timeline
um so I mean that's kind of that was
kind of like something I dealt with from
the jump
um in trying to
breed a Mexican plant that didn't have
um hermaphroditic traits I had um
I was I was pretty I always kind of been
a geek about all this [ __ ] so when I
used to get
um
bags of Mexican weed I would save the
seeds I would
um label them and I had a system I made
up it was pretty like over the top
really thinking back on it but I would
have some notes on it some notes on you
know the quality of the high
from the plants the physical appearance
appearance without being too harsh
because you know like I said that stuff
was all treated like [ __ ] yeah
and I would you know I would ask for
origin most of the time I couldn't get
it but you know sometimes it would be
Sinaloa or oh or whatever probably just
whatever that you thought would shut me
up
um yeah
yeah so I
but it was good because I could go back
and look at
um you know which ones were my favorite
to smoke and um those would be the seeds
that I bought
um I'd also go on things like you know
seed maturity if there were a ton of
white seeds in it I figured you know
they have problems finishing in Mexico
it's pretty [ __ ] for Virginia
but uh so I grew one of those lines and
um
it was
you know it was a pretty traditional
kind of Mexican sativa there was a lot
of plants with
in it but I had one plant
um it was like a straight mango and that
like a cantaloupe Melanie
um you know sweet spice it was a really
just incredible flavor it was the only
thing I'd really seen like that
um in Mexican weed
um but it it was a full-on intersex
plant I mean you know you'd have
clusters in the tops you'd have clusters
everywhere
um so I crossed I crossed that to
another
um another Mexican I had and uh you know
the next year I grew those out
um they
in the F1 there was a good mix I didn't
find anything that was quite like that
cantaloupe type plant so I made a few
more with my favorite plants and then in
the
um in the F3 of that plant I found quite
a few that had that cantaloupe Aroma to
them but they all permed
um so that was you know I was trying to
breed for that recessive flavor profile
but in that line that seemed to be
linked to
intersex traits
um so that was that was my first
um
first experience trying to breed for
recessives failing at it
um
and then you know I've had several other
instances with it over the years
um
one project
it's not even I mean I guess it's a
project because I've been working on it
for a few years but um
I have been growing
um
a line from Hyde is subterfuge it's his
um improved ABC line they say you know
the plants are very ABC they're
you know you can tell he's worked it
quite a bit it's pretty inbred the
plants are sluggish
um takes a while to get them going
um and I've been kind of making scenes
with it playing with it I've made a good
amount of hybrids with it
um
trying to
get a little more potency out of it and
trying to get away from the serpentaline
which is very I mean it's not it's not
like um
it's not like train wrecked or kindling
where it has some interesting notes in
it it's kind of like a flat kind of
one-dimensional flavor
um so the first time I made seats with
that line I crossed it too
um several things that I thought could
Aid in the potency and the flavor uh Kim
D Bubba Kush
um
I think TK a few others
and
I I popped some of those hybrids
um see Kim D ABC is the one that I've
kind of messed with the most so when you
uh pop the f1s of it they're all normal
there's not a mutant anything in there
yeah um
did you know you get some plants that
have the kind of ABC type
um flavor palette and Pie you know some
stuff that just isn't really hitting on
all that much
um yeah but
um
in the f1s they're completely normal
plants when you S2 them though uh when
you F2 them you'll start to see that
recessive Leaf pop out
um you get a mix of them
but to lock down that recessive trait
you know you have to have to take it to
an F3
um and it's something I've been messing
with it
um I've talked to CSI about it because
he's done much more work with it than I
have
um with the
uh ABC line not not subject huge but
same kind of thing
um but you know once you get back to
having that mutation on the leaf
um
you pretty much
you're back where you started that's in
square one yeah I mean you can get some
stuff that's a little bit prettier or
smells a little bit better or might be a
tad more potent but you're pretty much
back in the same ball game you know once
you get to that level so
it's um
and that's another thing you know it's a
it's a recessive trait that you're
trying to isolate but once you work it
to the point of getting there
um it seems to be linked with that kind
of adult or penalteen low potency thing
so yeah it's um it's taught me
a lot that that's a good line for
messing with like something like that or
something like maybe breeding
autoflowers where you can visually see
the recessives that you're looking for
um but it's been um it's taught me a lot
about reading it's just uh it's just not
easy yeah the stubborn stubborn link
traits like that are crazy like yeah I
mean do you think that's what Hyde was
doing because I know when you go back
and look at the um the genetics and
makeup of subterfuge it's it's like got
so much in it was it I wonder if he was
just going like always moving forward
like okay I'm gonna try to put Calio in
it and then uh it didn't really work
that great let's try this one
you know or yeah
I don't know how he did it um you know
I've never talked to him about that
um but I assume he probably had to do it
kind of similar to
what I did or what you know CSI has done
where you have to take it to an F3 just
to get back to that mutation
um yeah
so you would really
I feel like you would need to just
inbreed it to the point of it not being
fun to grow to get anything else out of
it yeah we we actually have an Aussie
guy who is in our Discord a new member
um and I believe he worked sort of
collaborated with Caleb or was growing a
bunch of ABC in Australia talking to
Caleb about it so maybe he'll have
interesting questions to follow up with
um
I think uh yeah really cool to hear an
account of
um
actively looking for these recessives
actually seeing like the ratios come out
in f2s
um yeah there must have been a pretty
amazing experience
ABC was its own like
wild rare cannabis hunt for a lot of us
that were like straight up dorks I think
like not everyone even knew about it
like it was this kind of like Niche
thing that like in the even in the
breeding Community it was still Niche
for anybody to even note that this thing
[ __ ] existed and nobody could get
their [ __ ] mitts on it in the US and
you know there's the emery release of
like that and slow crossed and yeah yeah
I had some of those did you
yeah but I when I got them
I didn't want to pop them until I you
know yeah I I don't know what it was I
was saving saving them hoping you know I
could do some reading with it or
something and I didn't know for the
night you you lose your virginity and
then you can pop up yeah exactly exactly
um yeah but that never happens so um
they just gotta uh yeah I've let them
age out and I couldn't pop them when I
went to them
I can't remember how many packs were
released to that but it was so limited
yeah yeah it was um but that's what
that's what uh odds line was based off
of yeah that Emery drop
that's right
but yeah someone finally I you our
friend resin lung even went to Australia
to try to go track down ABC like on his
own
and you couldn't do it and then
eventually eventually one dude like
still kind of I personally my opinion is
it's kind of sketch how he came across
them I'm still thinking that they might
just be by a hype somehow like
backdoored maybe
um but yeah somehow they were brought to
Market eventually and uh
I'm glad they did though yeah
yeah it's definitely
um something more for like the hardcore
nerds than the people that are like
trying to grow smokable flowers to sell
um because it has zero marketability I
think but um I mean it just looks like
Ivy it looks like Ivy yeah yeah they're
they're super cool plants
yeah I have a bunch of your your version
of the subterfuge going on right now
yeah yeah
I have facts of it that I still haven't
shopped
but man okay yeah
I think it's cool I wish everybody grew
up even for ornamental it's uh oh yeah
yeah I mean guys
yeah you could grow a yard full of it
nobody know what the [ __ ] it is that's
for sure
yeah
okay well I thought we could maybe wrap
up this bit on recessives and we have so
many questions for you um but I think
before we get on to some of the more
open-ended ones
um I'd love for you to kind of
um
I suppose not conclude but um we can we
can focus a bit more on your work again
and maybe you can talk through some of
the recent releases
um the Appalachia crosses
that you've made uh maybe standouts
anything interesting in in the process
of making those
uh yeah so those were all you know
it I didn't cross everything I have in
my stable to it I mean that's kind of
that's kind of the move but there was
you know it was all plants uh that I
felt could benefit from certain aspects
of it um you know
old Betsy is one of my
favorite things to smoke the flavor is
incredible
um it's just it's it's like opening a
jar of Grandma's jelly I mean it's just
you can't stop smelling it it's just
incredible
um every time I open a jar I'm like well
[ __ ] let me just smoke a little um but
it you know when you're vegging the
plant it always wants to throw pistols
if you get it root down if you get a
root found it wants to start flowering
if you feed it the wrong thing it wants
to start flowering it's a it's kind of a
visual plant
um so I wanted to
cross it to something
so that I could kind of I wanted
something similar that I could kind of
you know go back and pull that pull that
type of plant out with
um that was
that was a pretty successful one I think
I I really like the way that that came
out
um
yeah can I ask you could you use that
trigger that that
that pre-flowering trait as a beneficial
thing for outdoor
um outdoor it doesn't seem to do it the
way that I grow
so
in full sun it it's a little bit more
um
it's a little bit more vigorous in the
Sun and I normally grow in
pretty large pots so yeah uh it doesn't
have that issue where like if it hits
you know if it hits the side of the pot
it gets pissed yeah um
okay that makes a lot more sense yeah
yeah
okay continue sorry
um but I did that one
um the shoreline is
one of my favorites I smoke it daily
um it's an incredible plant it is an
absolute Beast outside for my climate of
all the cuts that I've grown outside it
uh performs the best uh yield wise it is
very rot resistant you can take it
through some [ __ ] in the fall and it's
um it comes out fine when everything
else is kind of melting away it's just
standing there rocking
um so that's that's one I did
um
maybe you can ask I can ask the First
Community question
um we're just from two groups
um and I imagine from Kristen as well in
spirit
um they want to know what the shoreline
what you've observed the shoreline tends
to pass
okay uh so the shoreline
it comes through pretty
pretty strong in crosses for the the
Terps the it has this on any Funk trash
kind of just nastiness
um it's super loud
um you know it's when it's flowering you
know you got some Shoreline in there um
it it comes through really well for that
and it it throws these fat colas you
know it's in Veg it's not super vigorous
but once you flip it it it just beasts
out and um you know of the
Appalachian crosses that's probably the
that and the the GMO cross are the best
yielding
um but it's it's uh it's just a
phenomenal plant and it passes the
things that I like
um but you know the Apple actually gives
it a little bit a little bit more Vigor
in veg
um it it's easier to get up
going
but yeah the funk the Short Line Funk is
what
what I what I wanted to pass and luckily
what it does yes
we'll be happy
yeah I'm interested
uh that's a a cool one so you know GMO
is
is pretty well known for dominating
crosses
um it dominates a lot of things
um
with Appalachia it
it still comes through really strong
um you know if you want
a close representation of GMO
you should pop them because you'll get
you'll get some that are kind of dead
ringers for it you also get some yeah
you also get some that have that same
kind of resin production and that same
um that same kind of dumping ability of
GMOs that have a little bit more
tropical flavor to them they still still
have a ton of stretch
um but they have a lot of fuel on the
back end so that that's a good cross and
if you're looking for something that's a
little more
um
you know modern kind of weed like I
don't like most modern things I try I
don't like gelatos at all I I'm not a
big fan of any cookies any kind of cakes
I've tried a ton of that stuff and you
know
I like to grow weeds it gets me high and
that stuff just doesn't do its one
um
GMO is
I think probably the most remarkable
plant that's come out of that of the
most you know recent eras of things and
um
it's a it's an incredible plant and I
just wanted
um you know I wanted something that
people could could find GMO but maybe
have a little more variability than a
lot of the you know GMA work out there
yeah very killer
um definitely the one that interests me
and uh is the Electric Boogaloo cross
yep yeah so that that was a bit of a
beast
um you know locals has a really good
kind of mix of Phoenix going right now I
have
one outdoor that is
um massive
um it's hasn't started to flower yet and
uh it's yeah like I don't know eight
feet tall it's a giant
um but there there is um you know I
tried reversing
Electric Boogaloo several times and it
just didn't it didn't produce pollen
um but I was I it has some really
interesting stuff in there there are
some plants in there that look
like Neville's haze there are some
plants in there that yeah there's some
you know
sensitive Expressions that have a ton of
the kind of candied mango that I
associate with green crack you know um
Electric Boogaloo has has mango but
more so like mid flowering like you know
if you take it if you take it to the end
that kind of dissipates and you have a
you know a spicy just I mean it's an
amazing finished flower but
um I wanted to see if you know that
cross could maybe bring out a little
more of that into the finished flower
and it does
um make sense so there's there's a
there's a pretty wide um you know
there's a there's a wide mix in that one
but a lot of a lot of fatigue
Expressions you get a few with nice
running colas and um you know
I'm a
huge fan of
sativas I mean that's I love them that
and dog [ __ ] electrical glue that's one
I smoke every single day and it's a lot
of run out like I just did
um
but yeah that's that's a great one I
wonder if it's like uh like a lot of us
that grew up on Mexican stuff just have
this long lasting love for for highs
like that I don't know I like I I have a
love for for all those type of plants
myself very much yeah it's um well it's
but it's I think a little bit more
palatable to a broader audience because
um
like you know hazes or Mexicans or
Colombians they can they can get you
like
paranoid and disoriented you can get uh
you know just so ripped that you're you
know confused disoriented it's almost
like you know tripping
um yeah
but but uh golf [ __ ] is just it's a it's
a high but it's it's gentle it's a great
flavor and you're just soaring it's just
you know it's like a memory of the first
you know one of the first times you got
really high and you're like riding your
bike around that's just a beautiful
childhood Bliss kind of high I love it
yeah that's one of the ones that I I
realized at our get-together that we had
last time there wasn't anybody in the
room that didn't like absolutely love
that like you know greens or disagreed
on different things except for dog [ __ ]
for some reason was the one that
everybody
yeah yeah I mean from the first time I
smoked it I've I've just loved that one
that's one of my
all-time favorites
by the way your KMD was fire fire fire
so one of my favorite growth of candies
ever
uh sometimes I get it right yeah I bet
yeah yeah
was there anything else you wanted to
add uh about this your recent release
because otherwise it was going to move
us on to
you maybe give us a sneak preview of
what you're doing now or what's coming
yeah the only other one I'll mention
just because I have a lot of people ask
about it a lot a lot of people ask me
what the most fully line that I have is
and um you know the the Gorilla Glue
cross
um I just harvested a couple of those
and that is
just
that rank fuel it has some sweetness
come through but it's more of like a
like pg4 to me has like a artificial
chocolatyness to it
um and this has like fuel with like a
a like powdered cocoa milk chocolatey
thing on the back end it's just
intoxicating to me
um it's really really nice and um you
know that's one
where I haven't done a lot of reading
with gg4 and I wasn't
you know I wasn't sure on it but man
that was one that really surprised me
when I wrote them out
um it's there's some phenomenal plants
in there
I think a lot of us that like have tried
to avoid using a lot of hike clones
waited a long time to use gg4 because it
was so heavily pushed like maybe even
prior to the cookies there was just so
stuffed in your face like you need to be
growing gg4 so I didn't yeah I'm
interested in it it looked like a
polyhybrid to me and I figured okay
that's going to breed so variant that
why would I
even care yeah but it breeds
yeah it's remarkably consistent it is
yeah for being like a poly hybrid bag
seat I mean it is it is
I grew you know half of the plants could
have been cuts of the same plant that I
grew it was yeah it has I think the
least
least Variety in any of my lines yeah I
I was one of the last to grow that cut
like because I it was like I said I just
didn't want anything to do with it just
because of how many other people were
using it and I I just thought I'd do
something different
but when I finally did it I was like oh
damn this is actually pretty good I like
how this braids too it's actually good
to smoke on its own too and I know CSI
had that same sentiment like he hit me
up he's like damn this
why didn't anybody tell us
yeah it's it's a good one
um yeah it does really well outside here
too so it kind of sticks around for that
um and that's kind of why I kept it
around
um but I've been uh I've been pretty
surprised with the way it reads
me I'm glad you guys mentioned it
because yeah I was going to point out
that
um I didn't see many of you working with
it until relatively recently I thought
that was interesting
um yeah Matt Elite turned me onto that
one yeah he said I had to train I'm like
really I don't know I mean I like Josie
a lot he's a cool dude and we got along
and and uh and then I started smoking
everybody's grocery I was like God damn
it's actually kind of good but will it
breed like this more importantly than
anything like it not only is it a good
girl or it breeds very well true to
tight kind of you know yep
yeah oh yeah
okay so I'm I gotta plug the fact that
uh these these seats these packs are
available on riotsseeds.com yes
available go there check it out and um
yeah so I thought maybe now to to to
more or less wrap up a bit on your work
in this like linear fashion
um would you be able to give us an idea
of like what you're looking towards now
and in and for the future
um we had a question from moonbeard
about
um Haze experiments I think that he's
heard of that you're you might be doing
um uh yeah yeah so I have that going
um
I actually have a few things before that
like I have
seeds done for a few other projects one
of them is um
I
I was selecting a
Appalachia out of the S3
um looking for a candidate to do a green
crack that cross with
um
I had some hiccups with you know the
sourcing of the cut so I had to get it
I um I had to get it from another source
uh for po political reasons
um so I
have that
um
have that cross the seats finishing up
now for the back cross
um and I have already harvested
um I wanted to remake that Appalachian
diesel that
um I did a few years ago so I seeded a
pretty large saudisa Plant and I seeded
um
the headband cut that you know goes by
L.A Kush from that's a dog
um that's that's another
very nice diesel
um
I really love that plant
um indoor outdoor it has
extreme potency it's a great plant
um so I seeded that
um a few other things I crossed it to my
favorite
um
Santa Cruz Rec plant from Top
um pack uh Santa Cruz good form
um I had a
plant that was just a beast in there it
um was very kind of train wreck dominant
plant
um but in the last few weeks of flower
it had this really nice spicy blue
Essence kind of come through just a
really really nice hybrid of uh the
Santa Cruz blue dream and train wreck
um so I seeded that plant with those I'm
actually just popped some of this to try
out
um and then I have the
Green Crack fully pollinated
um and those you know those would be
ready to test here shortly
that's awesome
yeah and then
um then I had another uh smaller run of
some
um
Kim D Appalachian stuff I was messing
with
um f2ing it back Crossing into victimsy
um just doing a few things there
um kind of filled in Block work nothing
um that's that's probably just going to
be stuff I mess with
um but right now
I'm I am doing like a haze hybrid hunt I
uh I popped
Super Silver Haze I have pops Northern
Lights five Haze
um mango Haze that came Theo
um Wally duck it's mango Haze IBL line
that he's he's been bred in Australia
um it's
um yeah and then a Neville's Haze mango
Haze uh also from Wally duck
um and of all those lines
um
I've grown them out and I have my
favorites
um the mango Haze I think is the the one
um yeah the CL the plants are
um
a little bit
a little bit more finicky it's um
you know it's not as easy a plant to
grow as super silver haze
um but it super silver haze tends to be
pretty
pretty much a sort of tunneline Dom
plant
um has a ton of that with the mango Haze
you get it you get some sweeter
spiciness
um high is
consistently
better
um I think it's a better representation
of what people want in a sativa type
High
um
not as muddled you know super silver
haze you can feel the Indica influence
um it's more of a hybrid
um but but the mango Haze
um that's my favorite I found
a male that I really like in there
um
I'm going to be
uh you know making some more of those
seeds as my personal thing you know
that's something while he's working with
so
um but I'm I'm crossing that to a lot of
cuts that I have plants that I have that
I really like
um
so that will start calling you Virginia
mango bro I know I know I was just
thinking about it I was like dude I need
to get the [ __ ] away from mango but it's
like you know blue I just kept going to
it and it's just you know yeah you find
it something you love and that just is
it
well and mango Haze is is way different
than like a candied mango crackers you
know sure it's um you know I don't know
if I was naming it if I call it mango
Haze but you know that was the name of
the mother was mango so
um but yeah I'll be I'll I'll be doing a
bunch of uh a bunch of hybrids with that
um hitting it to
um a bunch of the sativa cuts that I
have some of the
heavier hitters you know the chem dogs
and all that but um yeah there's a few
that I'm I'm really interested to check
out I'm gonna hit the the A5 Haze with
it yeah
so
yeah we'll see we'll see how that goes
I'm hoping everybody's not too scared to
release those seed mines because uh
let's say I checked no one else gives a
[ __ ] you know like
I I yeah friends sit on them and I'm
like what the [ __ ] are you doing
everybody else is releasing them like
you don't have to check yeah it's um
yeah it's um you know they're political
issues there I
I don't I was wasn't told anything about
it when I got it um it's you know
there are reasons not to release it A5
is is one of them most difficult plants
that I have it's um it's not easy to
grow it's yeah it's you know it's just
not and most people that are used to
growing
you know OG kush's salaries well as you
know that modern kind of it's just a
whole whole [ __ ] different ball game
and um yeah it's it's a fussy little
plant
so you know
and you know I think a lot of those
hybrids that's going to be more kind of
it's not a beginner Grower's plant
um so yeah we'll see how it goes I'm
looking forward to testing them out and
that's something that
um you know it I'm passionate about that
that type of smoke so it's uh I'm
looking forward to
actually getting to test them yeah
we need more of that in our community as
is like more of those type of highs
those offerings it's gonna get it's
gonna get more and more sparse as time
goes on because financially it's harder
to produce things like that so hopefully
people um
take advantage of it while it's here you
know while it's around
yeah you know the the commercial
viability of something when breeding is
never kind of been what I go for
um I'm not great at that side of it I'm
basically
make things that I want to see I like to
I like to grow the best flower that I
can that's what I want to have locked
down in seed form
um so
I'm not concerned about you know how how
well it does it's just something that I
feel compelled to do
I want to say that um at this point of
the conversation I'm so stoked like the
archivist in me is so pleased to have
gotten all of that information from you
oh yeah yeah really grateful for that
and
um at this point you know was there
anything more you want to say about
um your work your career so far
um because otherwise we can also launch
into
the Heap of questions that we've gotten
from both Matt and the community
uh no I think I'm good
Matt did you want to kick us off on some
of these more like open-ended questions
I know we even have some like
hypothetical breeding projects yeah I
don't I don't know if I'll cover some of
the hypotheticals because we're so far
in and I know we have a ton of questions
so let's um you know one of the
questions I had for you and it's kind of
a hard one because I I thought of
something that would be hard for me to
answer what's something you about the
modern seed era that you enjoy
[Music]
um
I like how
I I like how accessible it is for people
I've always
um
I've always been a tinkerer in in the
weed world you know it's um it's always
been a passion thing for me more than
monetary
um it's I like how accessible it is how
how so many different people are doing
different things uh
it's not you know a lot of the releases
you see and I'm not gonna name it it's
because I don't wanna
crash anybody on it but it's just the
same [ __ ] across to the same [ __ ]
um which drives me crazy and you know
I'm
I can say that I'm guilty of it you know
I've made a GMO cross I've
um you know I've crossed salaries all
the stuff but you know a lot of the kind
of incestuous lines across together the
cookies cookies and the yeah you know
um that's that's disheartening but I
like I like seeing the unique things
that people are doing and
um I like seeing people do it
on a level that
you know is satisfying to them
and less driven for you know having a
drop that sells out in 30 minutes yeah
um that's a good answer so
yeah you know like
CSI you know I've I've had a ton of
respect for him for a long time and
he does his passion projects and you
know they don't
pay the bills I'm sure but that's the
kind of [ __ ] when I sneak order into and
that's what I get
yeah right you know I want to see I want
to see what the you know
TK cross the
pck is or you know whatever whatever it
is
um I wanna you know I like I like
exploring
different profiles I don't want you know
something that dumps that I can
sell a bunch of horizon off of or
something you know I like the
I just like the overall abundance that's
out there you know it's very different
than the Dutch the Dutch era
and that early hype kind of era
um so yeah to me you're talking a bit
more about now you're a breeding
philosophy or kind of your philosophy
towards cannabis in general like do you
do you think it's it's evolved or
changed much since those like
uh brick weed seeds
um not really for me I'm kind of
you know my number one goal is still to
have the best
that I can have
um you know
weed early on I learned that I could
produce something better than I could
get and
um you know there's there's not a lot of
things in life that I can have the best
of but I can have the best sweet
that's still
it's still like my number one goal and
what I kind of what I'm constantly going
for
yeah
yeah love that
all right do you want to bring in some
of the uh the user questions
all right all right I got I got a good
one to start us off because it's I think
it'd be fun in the win wants to know
what was your worst year with the worst
outdoor season
oh man
so I've uh
I I had 20
years of Gorilla growing so I've had
some pretty [ __ ] bad ones I bet um
I'm trying to think
so I've had yeah I've had some [ __ ]
wiped out but the worst I had I had
um a pretty decent outdoor for the area
that I'm in
um you know enough that you know
there's some [ __ ] you thought about
before you fell asleep at night
and um it was most mostly all in three
sections kind of separated out
um
and in October the whole [ __ ] thing
got ripped
um I I lost plants
I've lost plants many times mid-season
um but this one somebody got it somebody
came and they got everything
um completely ripped me off I had a lot
riding on it I was pretty invested in
that one
um but they left I had a Neville's Haze
plant out there that was [ __ ] massive
taller than everything else
and I guess they didn't see it
um because it was you know it was mostly
kind of hybrid style plants smaller
bushier plants I had this one [ __ ]
tree of a plant so
I got ripped off I was [ __ ] defeated
feeling like [ __ ] and I saw that they
left that plant and it kind of sketched
me out for a little bit
um I bet you know I didn't want it I
didn't want to cut it down
um yeah you know I figured that was that
was left for me to get [ __ ] whatever
popped with her yeah so I I just let
that thing go and we had a pretty
pretty mild fall that year so
you know I think it was a couple days
after Thanksgiving I went back and it
was still there and it was just about
just about done and um I said I said
[ __ ] it I'm gonna get it so I you know
cut that plant down
staff did appropriately drove it to
where I was trying it
um so I pretty much
lost my whole Harvest except the only
thing I had to smoke until you know the
next indoor run I did which was probably
going to be in the spring was you know
just all this Neville's Haze yeah and it
was a phenomenal plant
but it was so goddamn strong it was like
you know
you can smoke that sometimes but you
can't just like you know I was like four
months into just smoking Devil's Haze
all day like oh my God you smoke it you
go to the grocery store or you like
start to walk in and you're like nah
okay I can't do this [ __ ] right now you
know like yeah
it's just like but it was you know it
was an electric winter
um but that bad
yeah but I've had that I've had floods
wiped out Gardens I've had
you know outdoor growing is difficult
enough outdoor Gorilla growing I mean
you have to
go into it hoping you get half of the
work you put in out of it
and like that would be so heavy to lose
like a whole crop at like knowing each
year in a row you can get ripped that
would kill me
yeah yeah it's um it sucks I'm glad I
don't have to do that anymore
yeah for sure
I mean indoor growing you you know that
that's a possibility but like Gorilla
growing it just seems like almost like a
weird inevitability it's something yeah
you know
yeah it's you know there's so many
different things that can happen you
know people hunting people you know just
everything yeah serial killers bearing
bodies the normal [ __ ] exactly yeah all
that
okay
um PBJ asks which of his lines would he
suggest growing for each level of
experience novice intermediate advanced
okay
um so
the appalache stuff overall they're it's
it makes for some very
easy plants I think
um
there there are some that are a little
bit more finicky I think you know the
dog [ __ ] Appalachia is a little a little
more intermediate but for the most part
those are pretty easy plants
um as a beginner I would say that this
the F3 Appalachia or the
um
which is the old Betsy Appalachia those
are I mean kind of set it and forget it
plants
um the intermediate ones would be stuff
like you know the lupus headband
Appalachia
um
you know
nah the GMO is pretty easy too
um but you know when we if I end up
releasing any of the hay stuff that's
gonna be more on the advanced level of
growing just because mango Haze itself
is Affinity plant and a lot of the cuts
that I really liked that I'm using
um
as mothers uh a lot of those are you
know more finicky plants you have they
go longer you have a lot stretch
it's a lot more
you have to think about it a lot more
nice
thank you for that
um we've got a big one from Blazer panda
a good mate
does high emotion like to go by
Appalachia daddy or father Abby that's a
good question
well local calls me Daddy so that's the
thing that
is true because local also asked what's
it like being my dad
[Laughter]
uh well you know that's another instance
of trying to set it and forget it right
okay
yep
more Earnest one
um
in the wind wants to know a bit more
about your grow take
um
he says like besides the soil mix what's
your what are your veg weeks outdoor
dates
I guess he wants to know yeah
um it it varies greatly
um I kind of I I do a lot of different
things
um in the last few years I've gotten
into
um doing some light depths outside so
um where I used to put plants out around
you know the first of June
now I'm I'm stepping in the spring and
my full season plants don't go out until
um you know
mid-july
um but you know I do a lot of things a
lot of different ways so
this year I did
um a depth run I have my
full season stuff going now I have a few
extra plants that are out in the gorilla
Spa you know I just
I don't have
I'm always looking for the you know best
way to
deal with all the seeds that I bought
basically
um
yeah
chicken feed
yeah and yeah soil mix I mean I did I do
almost
almost fully organic
um because I I just like a minted soil I
like the way plants can kind of take
what they want when they want it
um yeah
and I try to try to keep you know
fungus and bugs off them and kind of let
them do their thing outside
yep
nice Okay
um
I know Matt you mentioned we probably
wouldn't get into the hypothetical
breeding scenarios but I thought maroon
did have an interesting one that I think
is Broad enough that we could maybe dip
into it which is the one where you have
to move on a freeway three-way
oh wow Jesus
Jesus
my God
so his question is if you're going to
try and make a modern four-way what
plants or at least what traditional
regions do you think you might pull from
uh would this be like Reinventing the
old four-way or like a just a four-way
hybrid of different I think a four-way
hybrid of your your choosing
um I would probably do
a
a Colombian cross to a Mexican as the
father plant
and
hmm
I don't know it's hard to say in Afghani
because it's so Broad
um
it'd probably be
a Hawaiian Afghani cross to a
Mexican Colombian
is what I would do
and when I say Hawaiian I'm thinking of
like a
a hybrid type you know like Island weed
an older you know older one
like that Federation
yeah something like that you know like
um a lot of
oh Hawking
um was planted in Hawaii and they kind
of added in Afghani as they got it and
something with that influence I'm a
I'm a big fan of
Central American sativa's
um I really like
Southeast Asian ones but I don't like
the intersex traits
that are so abundant in those
um so I'd probably keep it um
Central American with just a touch of
Afghani and Hawaiian
boom
how about you Matt
how would you do this
man
I'd be like what's the goal what's the
end goal what's the end goal here I
don't know it'd probably end up with
something blueberry though I don't know
that's fine something blueberry what the
[ __ ] else would they do
you know
okay
um I think the last one that I've got on
my list from Ring of Fire is how has
your perception of the industry change
over the years and why
uh well you know I I have never been an
industry guy
um I don't I'm not a big fan of
illegal weed scene in every instance
that I've seen I've been to quite a few
States I've seen a lot of
um you know legal weed and it's it's not
anything that I would want to be stuck
smoking
um I do
I do like the
um
the easy access for home Growers I think
that's huge
um I think
you know that that's just that's going
to take cannabis further in the end than
the commercialization of it I think
um you know you hear a ton of people
talk about
Niche markets and you know how there's
going to be a this you know top shelf
Market's gonna arise but I you know I
think that's a long way off I think
um you know the the only way to create
a demand for something like that is to
have people you know become empowered to
grow something different something
unique and you know with a more
interesting eye and you know that's
that's something that home Growers are
going to do and share with their Circle
and
um I really think that's the the most
viable path forward for
the betterment of cannabis is through
um Growers and you know obvious people
that are really passionate about it not
just looking for a paycheck by growing
uh you know Warehouse of wedding cake or
something
yeah for sure shout out to the homegoers
um I think in many ways as well like the
last breeding series was
uh well for everyone but I think we are
also have one eye for sure on the
hobbyists and and people at home or
people growing in smaller spaces in
general you know
um yeah yeah I think that's a good
sentiment
yeah I don't have much advice for people
in big warehouses to be honest
okay
I mean yeah I mean that's you know it's
it's big business they're they're just
trying to
you know trying to get by trying to make
a marketable product that moves fast
it's just you know it's big business
yeah I just mean from the perspective of
I just haven't like I wouldn't even know
where to begin from that perspective
because I just don't do it you know what
I mean so yeah everything that we do is
definitely targeted towards uh
um I am out of I am done with my list of
community questions but uh hi nansem you
we did talk about one thing
um before this chat which was you
mentioned that you were actually drying
seeds at the moment did you want to like
just touch on give a little you know
quick overview of like how that process
works for you
uh yeah so
um you know when I'd shop
plants I'd pretty much treat them like
their flour to dry them I try to
keep the temperature as low as possible
which is difficult this time of year but
you know that
you know 60 60 rule I try to get close
to that and I'll drive slow
um kind of let the seeds mature in the
buds as as possible
um a paper bag um when I when I shook
seeds I will draw them further
um on screens and I like to uh once
they're good and dry I like to
refrigerate them for a while kind of you
know simulate a winter type period
and then I will
um
generally start cracking them and
testing them out
so yeah nothing nothing super fancy just
making sure I get as much of that
moisture out as possible before I get
them cold
no that's great you know I think these
are just the little ways we can extend
on you know say that seed making episode
that we did by asking you guys about
some of your actual processes
um so that's really really cool to hear
um yeah man did you have anything else
for high and lonesome
that's not it like thanks for coming on
like uh oh yeah pleasure having you
obviously
um an honor to call you my friend and uh
like I know how many people have been
asking for this again to have a full
form longer version of The Island
episode
I think it went well it went off so yes
a lot yeah thanks for having me
yeah anything anything from you high in
London before we conclude
now it's uh it's been a pleasure thanks
for having me and uh letting me talk
about weed in the geeky way that I'm
accustomed to oh dude this was this was
great I loved it thank you
good for sure
all right gentlemen with that I guess
we'll we'll call it a day and uh thanks
again and and hopefully if anybody has
any questions Brian Lonesome hit him up
in the patreon Discord he's in there
he's usually uh pretty available at
different hours and he'll get back to
you relatively shortly on any questions
you have about his seeds also available
on writes.com where you can also get the
reversal spray and all that good fun
stuff and with that thank you
thanks guys
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
top-notch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate here.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out