welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
cannabis strain history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
right welcome to breeder Syndicate I'm
here with my buddy high and Lonesome and
Santa Cruz goat farm pack and of course
not so dog we're going to talk about
some of our upcoming 420 stuff we got
going on for the for the site and we're
going to talk about some of their
history and like some of their likes
wants needs Desires in in cannabis uh
these guys have been at it a long time
and have a lot to offer and a lot to say
so I this has been a long Chase for both
of them so it's kind of cool we get to
get them both at once at the same time
and I think we're going to go over some
of the party too like what we saw at the
party what we liked didn't from what we
saw at the party
Etc
and they both have handy avatars they do
they do elusive
you know handy avatars
yep
all right so let's start off hi and
Alexa let's talk about some of your new
lines that you have coming out we have
of course have your uh Appalachia which
is pretty well known for for many
reasons can you talk about it a little
bit
yeah uh so that's a F3 I did I uh went
back and I had actually worked the line
to F5 and I wasn't really happy with
um
with what I had selected so I went back
to the f2s I popped 50 of them I um
selected two males and three females and
uh kind of let them go at it I wanted
more of the green crack side coming
through on the Turfs
you know one thing you hear a lot about
Appalachia is about like the creamy
milky stuff coming through in crosses
yeah
I kind of I'm I'm more a fan of the
tropical side of the of the Green Crack
same
um that creaminess kind of came through
the trace dog mail that I used
all of those that are popped
um they were very potent like the uh on
the females but they didn't have
the rankness that you would expect with
a Kim D yeah
how did that cross to the Appalachia
like did it none of the rankness really
crossed over in the in the outcrosses
did you see it in different Generations
any of it um that's not not a ton no it
was more of like a sweet cream
um
you know you see it in Star dogs
um in uh Kim four too it's kind of like
a bit sweeter not as nasty not as like
disgusting garbage as can be yeah
um but yeah so so that that's kind of
what I did I wanted to go back to the F3
kind of narrow it down instead of
keeping it wide open narrow it down to
what I wanted out of it what I liked and
um what did you like about the green
crack that made you want to choose that
as a mom or was it just like one of the
moms that you happen to have in the room
when you were doing the run like what
was specifically going on in your mind
well originally when I did it
um I was doing quite a bit of outdoor uh
on the East Coast uh or probably middle
2000s and uh Green Crack performed
extremely well outside it was um yeah
except it needed needed some staking
which you know when your Gorilla growing
you can't do you can't throw it you
can't you know it's it's a pain in the
ass so I wanted to put
um I wanted to put it on a little bit
more robust frame
um I'd had Kim D for a little bit at
that point and uh you know I was smoking
it a lot and that's what I wanted to
smoke yeah um but the plants were also
extremely robust so I crossed it to
Green Crack uh purple Urkel kimple or MD
the uh an Acapulco Gold cut that I had
at the time and uh abusive uh OG Kush oh
no [ __ ] yeah
gold cross dude
I never grew that when I gave them all
out to friends and I never really heard
anything back about that the uh the only
two that have any kind of lasting value
are the of course the Green Crack cross
and the purple Oracle cross yeah and you
said there was a chem 4 tray dog too
right yes yeah yep I did that as well
and you know
um what I found in it was very similar
to stardog there was some really nice
chem type plants in there and you know
some stuff that wasn't wasn't as ranked
you know some some of that creamy
sweetness coming through but still you
know extremely good quality smoking
plants
do you think you got what you wanted out
initially out of the the trace dog
um I I kind of wish I had
gone back through some f2s I made a few
f2s but I never really pursued it and
um you know at this point the seeds are
no longer viable unfortunately
but it's it's cool on there's um you
know I feel like if you F2 that you'd
open up a lot of stuff yeah
I mean Trace dog and chem 4 is kind of
like your own version of star dog
uh yeah right yeah yeah yeah I mean
isn't it isn't I mean it's it'd be a
different male or yeah it'd be a
different selection from the line
yeah yeah it was
um I just made a kind of personal amount
of them to go through it's like a I
always like to keep like a doomsday
stash of seeds you know
all my friends and all my cuts and just
like you know
I'm you know oh just a nobody floating
around out there I can have something to
go back to to look through even even
plants that I don't like out I usually
will pollinate them before I drop them
yeah because you just never know like
something down the line might trigger
that sense membrane you're like I really
wish I had that even though at the time
it doesn't even seem
viable or feasible for sure
yep and just you know it's fun to waste
all that space yeah all right and energy
and time time money man one thing I
thought about before before we get too
far away from it it's just the point I
might make which is that uh it's really
cool if you're doing a multi-stage
breeding thing to save seeds from every
stage of it
right so that way if you feel like you
screw up which is often you can go back
and be like oh I'd want to redo it so he
was just talking about I took it to F5
and I didn't really like some of the
direction that it went so I then I went
back all the way a few generations and
started taking it a different direction
you know I hear about that like people
say they do that all the time the theory
is very rarely any proof of anyone ever
doing that where like you've seen it
you've seen the seeds they were out
there's been x amount of years between
it and you know that that's possible and
I actually have the F5s of Appalachia
here from him so I know he took it to F5
and went back and I think that's that's
pretty commendable because you just
don't see it very often yeah
I also think like too like the the era
that that Hein Lonesome is talking about
it was I think it was more common for
people to like play around and work
their own little lines a bit it was way
before there was like a bunch of like
American Seed sales or anything like
that happening so now it's kind of like
you make seeds and it's a one-off and
they exist until they don't exist
anymore yeah
um but then I think it was a little bit
more common you know at least amongst
like weed nerds to like you know you
make something and then it kind of
becomes the base of what you're doing
and you cross it to this and you cross
it to that then you know it it and a lot
of it like he was saying it's all about
like I'm breeding for personal smoke
yeah
it gives you a lot more freedom than if
you're breeding for the market because
you're just breeding for things that you
like no it all you know the whole even
just growing it started by trying to
make sure I had the best quality weed
and I I think that's the best way to
breed
you're not being true to yourself if
you're not because how are you going to
enjoy the smoke and like go through tons
of different you know examples yeah and
not enjoy it and and pick a keeper that
you don't enjoy that's really hard to do
yeah you want to be stoked on what
you're doing right sure yeah you can
lose a lot of a lot of uh passion for
something real fast by by cheapening it
that way in my opinion I mean there's
some people out there that like all
their phenos and stuff that they they
get found get found by other people
because those breeders don't crack them
themselves oh yeah they make them name
them package them sell them and then
they find out through others whether or
not anything good happened
oh yeah
you know I would say that's kind of
become the standard these days a little
bit but in the era that high and
Lonesome is talking about which is you
know 15 plus years ago or whatever I
don't think that was the standard then
um you could get rid of anything back
then oh yeah
and before we straight too far I do want
to to ask because I know this is going
to be the number one question people
want to know when did you meet
be Bodhi and when did he acquire the
Appalachia from you to work
um so he and I had been you know
chatting and exchanging seeds on uh I
think it might have originally been I
see mag
um but probably 06 ish
um you know he'd send me a few things he
made I'd send him a few things I made
and I uh when I did the uh tray style
crosses I believe I sent all of them to
him
um just for him to check out and
um I didn't even know he'd popped any
until he uh hit me up asking if it was
okay if he released some seeds that he
had made with the Appalachia
um I think you know
I'm not sure it was something that he
meant to do but that's just kind of how
it worked out
um and he made some really cool stuff
and I mean people are still popping it
people are still passing out cuts from
those seeds that's um it was definitely
a very comprehensive job he did of
Crossing it to everything relevant at
that time
I know it's a very common sentiment that
a lot of people feel that some of their
favorite stuff came from that you know
like the the Appalachia crosses and one
of my favorite moments ever in life was
being able to to watch you and Buddy
meet in person for the first time and
then right away in the sunset
how sweet is that dude together
you know you meet him in person and he's
actually genuine you know it's it's a
rare thing but he's as nice as he comes
off and just a hell of a cool guy yeah
you know and you know we were all
holding hands stirring out the windows
you guys drove off
too bad it wasn't into the sunset you
know
right it was just almost a little bit
past Sunrise I think everybody has hello
going on though yeah yeah I had I had a
nice uh pregnant glow the next morning
so Pat let's talk about some of your
stuff dude like uh yeah man you kind of
popped out of the Woodworks with uh some
old Cuts you have an old Afghan cut that
you work with
um you work with a lot of train wreck
stuff uh one of your big releases your
first big drop was a train wreck
reversal and you hit a few things uh do
you want to talk about some of that
sure man you know uh
where do I begin you know I've uh
always kind of had interest in genetics
you know just growing over the years and
what have you but um
initially when I got into the game it
was all clones for me you know and my
crew and so yeah you come across the
occasional seat back or somebody you
know like we'd shoot up to uh where is
it up to PC and grab things once in a
while
um not beansters but you know whatever
seeds I had hidden in the corners up
there in Gaslamp area
um so you know as much as seeds were
available and like not so I was told
stories you know a lot of that was going
on down down south from where I was at
that point I was
where I'm thinking is when I was living
up in Humboldt uh up in the northern
part of the county
um you know scenes were prolific down
there right there's a reason that
generations of people you know breeding
and whatnot but clones are just so
accessible back in the day that there
wasn't really a need to go hunting and
yeah try to find whatever
um so it always kind of been on my radar
but it never been necessarily something
I turned towards
and then uh you know
um being in the game long enough you
come across certain cuts that you just
fall in love with even if they fall out
of style and what have you and
you know
um I caught on pretty quick in the 2000s
you know to the kind of turnover of
things you know you'd see something just
be prolific and then would disappear and
you wouldn't see it again and so it
determined that I would have to you know
hold on to some of these things and see
where that goes and so just you know
years pass and all of a sudden you
become this keeper of
whatever the hell you thought was good
from way back when and um so that's kind
of in terms of just what my
uh you know the way my path was laid out
with the whole garden scene so so you
know fast forward to now
um
you know I've always been on on the DL
for the most part with what I do and I
didn't really have a big intention of
riding the wave into the legal market
and try to go too heavy there
um I like Patricia worked there
um and uh and so I decided Well you know
hey man this is part of my life right
I'm not gonna just move on it's growing
as my therapy and so
um but I also am kind of bored here and
I don't feel like living by the
algorithm of the garden so to speak like
I had for so many years and I needed
some kind of pivot right so
um just like anything you know consider
doing that for years but played around
but then uh you know uh come the time
that I I'm starting to get real bored
not wanting to to move forward growing
weight anymore I thought you know this
is that right time to have fun right and
get into the genetic side of things
um yeah and so what do I do you know
I'll just kind of tick what I had in my
uh Armory and started messing around and
here we are how did you find the crew in
the first place
it's a good question
um this crew right here this crew I came
across I came across you guys you know
unlike some some of the other cats in
this in this field like I stayed true to
trying to stay under the radar so I
never got into the forums back in the
day and I mean not so nose boot you know
send people to go buy your supplies at
the store and not have your license
plate get uh oh yeah or whatever so I'm
just kind of always abided by that code
and never got onto the forums and then
um
IG comes around I would say maybe 2017
16 17 18 something like that and
started thinking about reversals I'm
like hey man I got this this tdub cut
and you know I want to see I want to
open her up and see what happens and uh
so start paying attention and as a
matter of fact I got in touch with Ryan
over there at Radio Ridge oh okay yeah
I'm awesome hey man what's the deal you
know who's who's the go-to here and
um if you put your game house and get a
hold of Matt and here's my number see
what's up talk to him and uh I was like
your ass Jesus
yeah he's like [ __ ] this guy I'm gonna
send him that
um
yeah this dude's a kook here we go Matt
um so so anyway yeah long story short
that's how I got in and then uh you know
he vouched for me in terms of being uh
somebody relatively solid in the field
or whatever you know what it for me what
it was which I appreciate by the way
yeah you had you said you had blue dream
right and for
ever since I've lost that cut I have had
people telling me heck up I got that cut
don't worry I got it and not once has
anyone ever been able to show me bud of
it I've seen pictures of stuff that look
just like it but when I would get it it
would smell like [ __ ] flow or
something like that you know it just was
awesome it would look just like it and
then you brought it down and I was like
holy [ __ ] not only does he have real
blue dream he has train wreck too he's a
little time capsules
[Music]
it wasn't just that it was how well they
were grown how well they were cured all
of it it was I hit all the points and I
was like God this guy cares about his
[ __ ] weed a lot you know he cares
about good weed and that's kind of where
I I realized like this this is legit I
want to see where this dude what did
what this dude's story is and without
going into detail too much detail
um obviously you come from like the surf
background right
yeah you could say that I mean Central
Coast Coastal Life yeah for sure I mean
I'm not I'm not a big I'm not a big
Surfer I was a skater snowboarder kind
of but that was a part of your culture
who you hung out the kind of yeah why
you would have had access to these
certain clones in the first place yeah
yeah it's definitely tied in it's tied
into the whole lifestyle of just you
know growing up in the in the 90s over
here on the Central Coast like
you were getting away from him you
couldn't find way you found a surfer but
yeah you know I was I was selling the
weed to the Surfers so you know
and Surfers usually had a pretty good
choice of weed back then like a lot of
them would travel around the world get
some of the best wheat on Earth so to
have it having the kind of clientele you
did without being specific it
um
I learned you know
that you had to perform better than
others to have the kind of clientele you
did at the time
which I took notice of and why why I
realized you you had gotten so good at
curing and drying and all that other
stuff because they were they were pretty
high in clientele well and they're
pretty picky man you know I mean yeah
their dads were Growers and they grew up
in the whole scene and they're around
the world yeah so exactly you can't you
can't bring schwag to those dudes and be
like yeah I want a good price for this
that's just not gonna happen no no one
thing one thing maybe I should interject
is like since high and Lonesome was
talking about Green Crack and now we're
talking with pack about blue dream and
train wreck is that there's some of
these things that like they became
famous long enough ago and then kind of
fell out of favor long enough ago that
people probably mostly only hear legends
about them to some degree and a lot of
people like Matt was saying get fakes or
you know or get it poorly grown for
whatever reason feed versions where they
use the name one of the things that
sucks about that is that often people
talk about why they got burned out on a
certain cut not wide that cut had
lasting fans to begin with yeah yeah you
know and I think with both with the
three things I just named with you know
Green Crack or with uh you know train
wreck or blue dream all three of those
you know uh there's a reason there's
there's a bunch of reasons why they got
popular and people really enjoyed them
yeah and then they
um you know they ended up getting burned
out you know because people were growing
huge amounts of it and once huge amounts
of it start growing a lot of people
start doing it poorly yeah you know and
and then all of a sudden it gets a bad
reputation and then something moves on
and people lose track of the quality and
like you were saying like maybe only a
few people end up holding on to it
and then people are surprised at how
good this thing they've heard of
but maybe in derogatory terms oh yeah
you know and I don't mean you know I
just like there was a lot for me like
when when high and Lonesome was talking
I was thinking about how you know like
basically once people in like Grass
Valley and certain other regions got
green crack and started growing seven to
ten pound outdoor plants
that kind of like mid Z Green Crack is
what blue
got turned people away from it but it
became accessible but you know Green
Crack is you know in extracts and
something like that it actually has a
bunch of really nice Terps it has a
bunch of really nice structure to it it
has a very like cool flavor done well
you know yeah indoor 70-day green crack
is tough to beat it really good like
yeah I'm looking so far too right and he
just said what out the other thing that
happens to people is they grow it too
big and then they end up taking it 10 or
12 days early because it's it's done
enough to pass oh yeah it makes all the
difference too so then the market gets
flooded with a bunch of you know I mean
it definitely happened with green crack
it definitely both happened with blue
dream and train wreck all three sort of
suffered the same fate and that they
could be enough of a production plant
that they got over produced and people
thought the production version was the
version
when in reality
I think Blue Dream took a bigger hit I
think Blue Dream took a much bigger hit
than just that
um Green Crack didn't because I I knew
who was who was releasing seeds of it
and who wasn't and there weren't a lot
of Siege released to Green Crack there
were like green crack seeds out there
you could buy up in Mass you know but
Blue Dream the second that thing kicked
off we had Emerald Triangle seeds which
was I believe made in Spain
um there was a you had Humboldt Seeds
you had all these different companies
releasing their versions of what blue
dream was which was whatever's bulk
Spanish company was pushing out as their
blueberry Haze I mean and that's what
cuts got passed around is blue dream
I'm saying Vince
yeah yeah exactly yeah I'm convinced hnl
that like in the in the dab era uh Green
Crack has been named renamed papaya
oh yeah a lot of a lot of those like
tropical Terps and stuff like that like
they would never call it a green crack
extract no right
Green Crack rosin and they'd be like oh
this is the papaya yeah
papaya this is the papaya you know this
is some tropical fruity and not to say
that natto has any knowledge that the
papaya strain out there from the
specific company is Green Crack he's
saying that's a probably what happens oh
well you know even 15 years ago when
people didn't want to buy green crack
around here it went as mango it went as
papaya fish yeah yeah it just you know
that happens
there's half a dozen names for blue
dream
oh yeah and maybe even more that got
made because people got blown out on it
and they're like oh this isn't that this
is blue dragon yes this is you know it
reminds me of your Barry White story
yeah yeah
you know I mean it's true and uh and but
you know the point that I'll I'll scroll
back on is that if you take somebody who
knows the strain like say pack or high
in Lonesome and they grow a nice two
three four six ounce plant either in a
greenhouse or in an indoor environment
people are going to be blown away by how
good it is oh yeah
blew over the party away I think people
have forgotten absolutely why those
things got so popular in the first place
and they only think they got popular
because you could get an eight pound
outdoor plant that was bigger yeah yeah
and that's not what got them popular in
the beginning at all it's just not yeah
it was a grow in somebody's closet
yep
I mean a three ounce a three ounce Green
Crack plant is delicious yeah it really
is you know I think a four ounce Blue
Dream is damn Delicious especially how
long did you take it back this last time
uh for the party I pulled it early
actually yeah I know it's weird yeah I
think I pulled it at 60 60 61 days maybe
and it was super Berry for me yeah that
was nice that was the best I've ever had
for sure
that was killer
when you grow a cut for you know 15.
better you better put out some work some
good work after you know 20 years I mean
really what one of the things I you know
I remember talking to CSI about this
probably I don't know eight years ago or
something where in his mind going back
to what pack was saying about where he
was up in Humboldt and stuff uh train
wreck was one of the first named clones
yeah yeah that really spread around the
growing Community deeply in that zone
like there was lots of seeds and there
was lots of name stuff that got like
here and there it popped up but like
train wreck really kind of had its
moment hey man that was the first strain
that you started seeing people wear
t-shirts with the name train wreck
across the front oh really I've never
seen the shirts I want to see for sure
yeah humble humble clothing company I
think it was up in up in Arcata uh 2001
something like that they they got smart
and started marketing strains on shirts
and yeah there weren't many but train
wreck was the one that was like you know
what you saw perfect and you're right
and you know what uh we never referred
to it or at least my crew being up in
Arcata it was never the Arcata train
wreck until
years later yeah as a signifier you know
in terms of where it came from it was
just tracks t-dub or train ride yeah
yeah I think that popped up on the
forums as a designator you know once
once it needed to be a few fake cuts and
you know people would talk a lot about
the you know this is the arcade of cut
or this is the e32 yeah 32 crew or
whatever
lemon rack was another one that was
floating around at that point yeah yeah
it seemed to pop up once uh people
started releasing seeds I think the
Dutch
started started messing with it and uh
wood horse
was it it was talking wood horse yeah
tuck and wood horse the big train I
remember using name dropping him again
but I remember when uh even though
they're discredited when philos first
came out or something
uh CSI called me up and he goes do you
want to know what uh what DNA's uh Lemon
Skunk test as and I was all what and
he's all Green Crack oh yeah
unfortunately yeah I mean like it kind
of makes sense like if they're both
skunk one they would kind of like maybe
show up in some range together
oh yeah
but I I just think like there's you know
and train wreck also the other thing
train wreck got known for was that it
was the like but long before anyone used
the word terpenoline
um you know uh train wreck Terps yeah
exactly yeah it got it got kind of a
moniker of like oh people didn't know
what that terp was but train wreck was
famous and well known I'm like oh this
kind of smells like train wreck to me
yeah it's got a train wreck smell
yeah
right you know but those it's so it's
kind of like it's it's almost a bad
thing I don't want to say it's almost a
bad thing but any strain that has the
potential to be blown out huge
has the potential to get a bad
reputation because people only try it
blown out huge not dried right not cured
right like Matt was saying about Pack's
ability to dry it and cure it and treat
it nicely
um and so sometimes even getting a good
example of what made something famous
can be harder yeah sure yeah and and
I'll tell you what man you know there's
there's times where I put it out and I
won't smoke those chicks I'm like no
that's not no I don't want to share that
with somebody yeah for sure it's not
oh yeah we all have this Those runs
our buddy uh our you know we had some
friends of ours at the Gathering that we
had or whatever that are quite a bit
younger than us
and it was really cool to have them try
some of the classics yeah that it faded
from popularity like long before they
came onto the scene yeah yeah that was
really neat for me actually you know
that's where I noticed like the kids
love the blue green they're like this is
Blue Dream what this is what it's like
what were people talking about just
watching HML push Trainwreck on poor
local oh my God how'd that go I didn't
see that part
it's 10 o'clock man I'm way older than
you you need to get here
you need to go take a train wreck bomb
hit so here
this is where this is right before I put
a Sharpie in his in his pocket to wake
him up
I was listening to an interview that
pack had uh did not very long ago last
week or something yeah and I remember
you talking about like train wreck was
the weed that like you pulled some bong
rips right before you had to do a bunch
of work
oh yeah like it was get after it weed
you know it gave you that buzz where you
felt like you could get some [ __ ] done
absolutely and particularly so much so
if you if you pulled a little bit early
you know like you can train wreck's got
such a range of when you can pull it and
what you want to get off of it sure does
you pulled a little bit early and it's
just so much more Speedy you know yeah
I feel like that's part of uh part of
what gave it its reputation of you know
big blown out plants pulled it you know
50 days because it it looks good enough
at 50 days at seven weeks you can yank
it yeah
that's why drink crap is Big with us
because like it's seven weeks if you
found it out yeah it's all about getting
700 of them in in a year if you're doing
indoor you know so yeah maybe that
that's the and that's another key why
people end up getting feel like
something's not that great I can't even
tell you how much Sour Diesel in
Mendocino County was pulled as soon as
it was good enough to go oh yeah like it
probably should have gone into the mid
70s and it hit 60 and they're like it's
ready hey man you're not doing it for
the love at that point though you know
what I'm saying no I get it but you know
but it's like people just don't I don't
think people see like that's the part
about love that I don't think people get
where it's like you know if you it's
hard to come across people that know how
to grow it the right way that will take
it the right amount of time that'll dry
it and cure it the right way so you get
that full effect there's a lot of it's
good enough to go yeah and it's good
enough for the the buyer won't reject it
hey man I'll tell you what I can't say
I'm not guilty of that in my past you
know especially at certain points in
time where it was more economically
feasible than you know just for the love
but I think when you stay in it long
enough at least for me it's like you
kind of mature into your grower status
right like
starting off Riding High Times I want to
grow everything I've got to get it all
whatever but then you start to kind of
not only dial in the plant but you dial
in your style
it was a different world too you know
consumers
there wasn't you know as many
connoisseurs people just they wanted a
bag of weed
um and you know they wanted it to be
pretty and taste good and you know if
you could accomplish that and then get a
buzz it was all good to be fair like if
I was doing something outside like any
of the things we just mentioned and it
was fall I could probably let it go if I
got good weather until it was perfect
right yeah but if I'm dapping it and
it's 90 to 100 degrees every day in
Mendo I'm gonna hit a point where it's
all downhill from here
and I might not get that last five to
seven days that I would prefer out of it
because it's going to go south because
it's 98 and it's hot and the flowers the
calyxes are going to start to yellow
it's going to start to get beat up I
gotta pay my rent you know yeah yeah
yeah you know here we had we had
hurricanes every fall you know or most
every fall and so you know in October
you might get you know six inches of
rain in a week
um you know it just it can be terrible
and so sometimes it was good enough to
go October one you know it's done
I try to explain that to people all the
time when it comes to like nature
farming you know where you're using
using the Sun or whatever that uh all
downhill from here is an important
decision to come to yeah it is it really
is key because you can you can be like
oh I can make it better and then you're
like I just made it worse
I mean one of the reasons one of the
reasons why I stuck to indoor growing
because you know you get to play God in
terms of how long and something's going
to go and and I mean obviously you know
there's there's
good and bad with both but um it's it's
an interesting uh distinction because as
an indoor grower mainly you know that
wasn't a consideration right what time
of the year it was unless you know I
didn't have the right kind of insulation
in that in the place that I'm growing or
whatnot sure um yeah
here we use I mean you know indoor
you know not that a lot of people
wouldn't go outside or whatever but the
problem up here was that it got so hot
and dry we always used to call it summer
bud
yeah same same here like you knew that
you knew the indoor summer Bud even just
because it was like you cannot keep your
[ __ ] under a hundred just because it's
like people are running Mini Splits back
in the day you know no
way we didn't you know it didn't that
kind of technology is all the stuff
that's common now I don't think people
realized how slowly we had some of us
adopted it remember how hot the lights
were
where I had three exposed bulbs hanging
in the middle and you had to get in
there to do whatever that was always so
brutal
dude like you know I always heard these
wives tales of that guy
River seeing my skin hanging off a bulb
and sizzling and it being just fine and
it was it was cooking the skin just fine
it didn't explode but I always heard
like yeah don't get your finger oils on
that bulb it'll blow up so I was always
water yeah I don't know people are like
finger oils like so I'd always like
screw them in all careful like oh yeah
yeah and screw it in because I didn't
want it
don't need them exploding
I don't know
maybe it was true there was a couple
times in life where like they hit the
top of my ear
that was pretty sensitive spot yeah
cause I'm a tall I'm a tall guy you know
and so yeah me too you're moving around
and you're trying to yeah you know but
yeah
but one of the things that we should
mention too is that you know and I don't
know high and Lonesome if you want to
talk about this but I would imagine that
when you were crossing uh Trace dog to
uh you know to Green Crack
um maybe you could talk for a minute
about like something that I'm always
interested in which is like what you
were hoping each parent was going to
bring to the children
um yeah well um you know basically the
only issues I had with spring crack
um were the structure of the plant and
then
um the uh the structure and the high of
the plant so I wanted to get something
with a little bit more robust trucker
and something that you know had a little
more uh not depth to the high because I
think the care the character of Green
Crack is really nice but just something
that maybe hits you a little bit harder
behind the eyes yeah it's still a skunk
one high at the end of the day yeah I
mean yeah yeah I mean green crack in my
opinion is just skunk one um it's yeah
probably my favorite yeah yeah it's
really good one it's definitely my
favorite of the skunk one type plants so
I have big margin yeah yeah
you know cheese is great I have run that
several times over the years I just
I can't smoke it but so much but
something about the like rotten mango
Green Crack is just so appealing
and another one of your your really
well-known cuts and this is probably
what I knew you best for and one of the
cuts I chased the longest was the poodle
nuts Kai can you talk a little bit about
that who selected the cut where it came
from Etc that was um it was selected by
a friend of mine from IC uh it went by
40 grit
um and then I think after that 40 ounce
uh several several names over the years
but yeah he was blowing up warehouses of
Urkel before anybody else he always had
the most dialed in Oracle his [ __ ] you
know I remember smoking his weed and it
just being it was like slingshotting
though it was dense but it wasn't you
know blown out it was like perfect
and uh his problem was he was running
warehouses of Oracle he needed something
with some hybrid Vigor then he and I
used to yeah [ __ ] a bunch so you
know that was one that when I was making
those crosses I kind of pollinated the
Urkle just to see if it was any more
vigorous so I uh you know once the seeds
were done I sent a bunch out to him and
he he ran him he found I think two cuts
that he really liked but that one was
the one that looked more Earthly and it
you know it got purple but it had
increased Vigor and increased potency so
he started you know running warehouses
with that and crushing it loved it yeah
nice and
yeah and
his I mean his cut his selection is
beautiful I've grown it
um I've crossed it to some stuff
um that line it ended up being you know
as you went through generations of it
there was just more weird stuff popping
up from the Urkel purple man yeah yeah I
took it I think to F4
and it was just you know you'd get more
mutants and it would just it didn't have
the Vigor uh
I don't know I could have [ __ ] it up
but uh you know it just it's one of
those things that I couldn't go but so
deep into
I I can understand that um the actual
poodle nuts cut is super unique looking
like I've seen it expressed this really
unique trait where it looks super knobby
it's very hard to describe and and I've
seen pictures of some of the outcrosses
that have that same trait you know what
I'm talking about yeah like bud
structure yeah yeah they're not knobby
bud structure yeah yeah yeah that's um
yeah that that kind of surprised me it's
not quite the you know round balls you
get with Urkel um but it's it's great
weed
um dude yeah it's beautiful it smells
and I've told people this a million
times like people always talk about
smelling cut smelling really Rank and
veg and that's a perfect example of one
for me where I can take cuts of that in
the living room and in the bedroom Bryn
B like did the skunk spray in here
because it really does smell like skunk
spray when you kind of like yeah veg I
think it's Veg it's insane yeah yeah and
then it finishes up so sweet and nice
you know yeah I know it's very Earthly
of it because like Urkel does something
similar it has that similar skunky smell
and veg and you take cuts and it's like
wow this is gonna be skunky AF and then
when you when you flour it it's super
grapey in the end you know it almost
gets there and for people that are
younger or don't know or weren't around
during the Urkel era
um one of the big issues with Urkel was
that it's not a very branchy mob it's
not easy to get a lot of cuts off it and
a lot of people would veg it for a long
time before they bloomed it because it's
kind of a slow grower
you know it's not Urban no spacing is
insane that's my problem
is one of those ones that you kind of
have to get it around the size you want
it to be when you bloom it yeah and then
it's going to grow like six or eight
inches and stop it's not like a diesel
or something that has a butt like it's
going to double or triple in size and
Branch out it's just not going to so
when Ian Lonesome was talking about like
his buddy wanting something with a
little bit better vigor
uh Urkel took its time
okay it kind of puttered along you know
it was that for me it was the node
spacing it just it was it was just
constant just like no space centimeters
yeah you had to thin it out and just
constantly stay on it it took forever to
veg it used to be you know you could
grow a haze in the same time you could
grow Urkel because you're gonna have to
bed
three times as long four times as long
and then when you flower it you know
it's it's gonna pretty much stay that
size like natto said six to eight inches
and that's all you're doing no jumping
no jumping most of my friends up here
that were successful growing Urkel they
would be blooming a round of Urkel and
they would be vegging almost the entire
bloom
oh yeah for their next round to get the
Urkel of his like the root ball and just
the plan to be a sufficient size that
they could then throw it into the bloom
when the when the other round was done
and get going come to think of it
another cut that got bastardized by like
being passed all around and a lot of
crappy grows at it because like you know
you always hear about how like lame and
unpotent Urkel is but like I've had my
head ripped off by good Urkel like
really legit put in my ass by good Urkel
it's just rare
it all comes down to the grower and you
know the conditions if you grow a giant
outdoor Urkel it's just not going to be
that quality no I don't like Urkel quite
a bit but I I have to admit it doesn't
hit me the way it hits some people now I
I will say Mr Hill says you do not like
purples at all and in fact you agree
it's all chickweed asking I mean it's
good it's good to have strong opinions I
suppose you know but I said Mr Mendo
perps but you know Urkel is Urkel for me
like I have this weird relationship with
with Urkel and that whole round of
purples because
at least in Cal I don't know you know
where high and Lonesome is but at least
in California it completely changed the
weed game
yeah and what I mean by that is before
like Urkel and Mendo p and granddaddy
purple and that like purple craze of
like 040506 that kind of hit
yeah any good weed you grew generally
speaking salt
yeah yep and I feel like the Urkel and
the purple wave was the very beginning
of like
Brokers being like do you have this I'll
take as much of it as you've got and if
you don't I don't give a [ __ ] I don't
want whatever it is I didn't want to
grow Oracle I liked it but I didn't want
to grow it but that's what they were
asking for yeah and there was a bunch of
people that were like hey man I'm having
a hard time moving my stuff and you're
like well if I give you this cut they'll
take every bit of it yeah and that kind
of started the movement of like Brokers
want this so I'm going to grow this
where I think I think everybody probably
on this call would agree like before
2004 if you grew Fireweed it was just
going to go yeah it was it was gonna go
it was gonna have a home and then like
the name game with really started with
purple craze and with Urkel and then it
went to diesels and it went to cushions
yeah but and a lot of those old strings
like we were just talking train wreck
Green Crack you know Blue Dream you know
all these different things started
getting lost to the Wayside
um because they weren't as easy to move
as whatever was dominant in the scene at
the moment
yep and we're playing that game yeah and
that's what ended up making them rare
you know like it's crazy that it's
awesome that pack loved train wreck and
blue dream enough to hold on to the real
ones yeah it is you know very thankful
for it
um and most of my collection is just
stuff that I personally liked so I held
on to it you know or you know in high
lonesome's case it's like that's really
what preservation needs is like
different groups being like these Cuts I
really enjoy yeah and so I'm gonna hold
on to them and I'm gonna grow them nice
regardless of what the market is telling
me because I care about them I mean that
that that's the dividing line between
Chase and a dollar and doing it for the
love of what you're doing right you when
you when you
when you hold on to a cut long enough it
becomes
a a partner of yours right like I always
say a train wrecks the longest
relationship I've ever had with a girl
oh yeah man I say the same thing about
the Maui because I popped it when I was
18. yeah you know what I mean you grow
up with these things right and they
become this intimate part of your life
regardless of if people accept it or not
if it's if it's in your
Zone and it's what you want then it
really doesn't matter if it comes or
goes right I mean it there there was
years we're trying to work with just one
plant in the corner yeah
monocropping it for you know the whole
25 years I've had it or however long
it's been but you know she's she's
always always kept that special place in
my heart and you know I've been around
long enough I'm not the oldest guy in
the world but I've been around long
enough to know that if you wait long
enough [ __ ] comes back around man um and
you and you learn by watching others
never hand your [ __ ] over to a tissue
culture guy
the other the other thing I think is
that interesting about what we're
talking about is that all these Elites
that we're talking about from back then
came about in a time when Elites only
got popular if enough people like to
smoke them
yeah like this was an ERA where there
was no modern weed marketing there was
no hype machine yet like things got
hyped because people enjoyed growing
them yeah and a lot of people had to
enjoy growing them for them to become
popular and not everyone had to like it
but enough of the community had to like
it for it to be desirable otherwise it
just kind of would fall by the way so I
you know I had my Clockwork Orange cut
in San Diego and down there it sold
really well it sold really well but I
was really stingy with it and I did not
like passing it out and those who had it
I made sure they didn't pass it out
because it didn't get a lot of exposure
you cannot
back then you couldn't convince people
that a strain was good unless they got
to smoke it it just it was very hard to
do and you couldn't force that
artificial height it was very very hard
to have artificial hype during those
days and even really good if it didn't
make it around it just didn't that's
what happened you know it just if it was
if it was listed as as a 50 eighth in
the back page of High Times over in
Missouri then it got some air time right
yeah
is that is on the internet probably in
like in the forums during like high-end
lonesomes like you know Heyday on the
forums I I think like the dog what
people call the chem 91 now was probably
more popular than it was in California
because oh yeah my friend that passed it
out to the three or four people that got
it he wouldn't let us give it out
anywhere and so for the most part
um Brokers were like well how good can
it be if I don't have it yeah yeah I
think the forums is where the hype
machine kind of got going absolutely
you'd have somebody piss you know an OG
Kush thread showing some pictures
talking about their cut
you know they're talking about what it
goes for in California and it would just
look killer and you know people would go
ape [ __ ] over it
and that's kind of where it all started
um then you know people start arguing
over strange and you know it's it's
gotten us to where we are today I mean
the lupus headband I remember that being
one like that name starting to get
attacked
yeah well you know people started
um getting their names attached to cuts
that they didn't create and they didn't
pop they just you know they were the the
one on the Forum to let it out the
people so it was now
yeah so now it's it's their cut that's
their name attached to it and that you
know that still goes on today you know
like oh yeah yeah I mean we better kick
you better kick up royalties to some of
these [ __ ] well I think I do
think there's I do think there's a
difference between like your name gets
attached to something because people are
trying to differentiate which one it is
and they're saying comes from this
person yeah there were certainly some
people early on
um like Lumpa or you know uh Ken from
Ken's GDP or something like that where
they intentionally attached their name
for control yeah sure yeah
you know and some people didn't attach
their name for control it's just like
other it's almost like other your
friends give you a nickname it's like
people on The Forum started referring to
things as a certain cut yeah and it's
sort of just organically happened where
other people were like no I'm going to
attach my name to it
yeah and therefore I need credit or I
need money or I need seeds or all the
little dynamics that developed around
possession and what's funny is is I
can't think of a single person that
intentionally attached their name to a
cut that was actually the originator of
the cut made the seeds or popped it
um let me think about that uh
what about Strawberry Cough
oh that's a tough one because I I don't
know did he pop the seed no you got to
give it to him yeah yeah you know
nothing against homie or anything like
that but like obviously like the the
camera one got skunked it got skunk the
A's name attached to it because he was
the first person talking on the forums
um the three people I remember that
intentionally attached their name was
like AJ attached his name to sour
can attached his name to GDP and Lumpa
attached his name to headband
uh all very Choice people yes you can
all hate me for it or whatever but I I
think those three at least like they
intentionally added their own name oh no
yeah yeah for sure yeah I think AJ was
just the latest of the game on that one
I never
heard of that cut
um I took a little break from being
online and you know any of any of the
Forum stuff and I got back on uh about
when I got onto IG and started hearing
about AJ's hour and it's like man I've
never heard of this one you know and it
just you know there's so many things
that are like that that you know I never
heard of that cut I never heard of this
sauerkraut I love the choco but you're
welcome for that you're welcome yeah let
me just let me just point out let me
just point out it used to not be a
popular thing to put yourself out there
in this game yeah one time no yeah I
tried you know pack I try to make that
point all the time where it's like the
skill sets that kept us safe for a long
time which is kind of being invisible
and keeping your head down uh you know a
lot of us were indoctrinated into that
lifestyle for 10 15 20 years and then
all of a sudden in like 2012 or 2015
people start putting their faces onto
things yeah yeah and that it never
really happened before and it went
against a lot of the and then people
started associating you know like you
know burner with cookie or something
like that like where it was like the
person that was the most vocal
ends up being like the the expert or the
person that's like the most in charge of
whatever the strain is it must be an
official on the subject
I mean what's what's funny about that
too is that I've had bunch of talks with
CSI
um Urkel I would say probably blue dream
and train wreck they all kind of have
very mysterious Origins yeah
there's a lot of cuts out there that
like I there's a general consensus on
most events that led to a Cuts creation
and the people involved to me
I I've never I mean I've heard people
claim it but I've never any of those
three strains they popped up and who the
hell made them and where the hell did
they come from and still a mystery to me
yeah all of them uh and let me let me
point out you know that some of that
might just be a of design
yeah sure you know there's there's a
bunch of old boys that that still grow
that I have known over my lifetime they
won't touch the internet and they could
care less about having anything to do
with anything but doing what they you
know keep on keeping on girl on the way
they have yeah yeah
yeah and scammers love that because it
doesn't give them competition to the
origin story very true like all of a
sudden you can be like Urkel came from
my farm this year I did this and there's
not going to be anyone that's going to
compete it you know a monk showed up on
my property and just happened to bless
us with this with this cut or whatever
you know yeah that was almost like the
canasta's GDP store and at some point I
got to cut in because people are going
to want to hear the Canasta story hnl
they're going to want to hear it
yeah and I'm gonna I got something I got
a couple questions myself exactly see
it's perfect time to bring it in
so and Estes story
from your point of view how did it go
down you remember
uh well I mean you're the one that
tipped me off to it so
I was the signal Ben you were I was kind
of uh I was kind of in the process of
stepping away from the forums up and all
that but I still checked in every once
in a while and you know mostly
communicated with you know some of some
of my old friends on there
um but one day you sent me a message
kind of letting me know that
um
female Appalachia cut that he kept had
been entered into what was it the major
cup it was like a major cup like the
High Times there's just barely doing
cups yeah in the US yeah I think it was
like the San Francisco whatever yeah
um
and evidently a cut had been taken from
Bodie's mom room by I guess a helper
yeah and uh somehow Ken got it and uh
liked it enough that he renamed it day
11 and entered it into the cup so he won
the cup with that cut of Appalachia and
to follow up on the success created a
seed line
not even using the cut to the best of my
knowledge yeah who knows
uh from what I think I if if I'm not
mistaken I think it was he had an Oogie
Kush seed line and he crossed that to
Green Crack and figured you know it'd be
close enough
and that was
um that was what came out as day 11 and
I remember it being a you know a big
deal people yeah this isn't what that
was you know drastically different
yeah so you know you kind of hit me off
for that story on I see mag and I
remember you know engaging in some
conversations about it uh I was shocked
that they admitted it
yeah like you know normally that I was
kind of how that goes down yeah like
normally that stuff stays wrapped up
yeah you know
but yeah
yeah so that was um
it would have been cool to you know have
won a cup with the name yeah right like
yeah
it was still when cups mattered like at
that time there was it wasn't like fully
bastardized to where there were
thousands of Cups you know hundreds of
Cups a year it was it was when cups
winning a cup could mean the difference
between a thriving business or not you
know yeah and it really pushed Ken's
business I mean most people already knew
who Ken was from GDP because he had
marketed himself with that but the cup
win boosted the sales for that bay 11
and his whole company and Seed launch
massively that was why I was like this
is [ __ ] gross and even the GDP thing
with Ken is is pretty suspect oh yeah it
is it's completely resistant I mean I I
you know I don't tell this story very
much and I'll have to be kind of like
I'll have to circumvent around certain
parts of it I suppose uh because uh the
person that I'm gonna talk about is like
a total Anarchist Outlaw like we were
just mentioning who would never want
their name to be known yeah
um but that person
um is who can out the GDP from yeah up
in my up in my neck of the woods and she
it actually came from a retiring Vietnam
vet who lived up in the hills by me in
the Laytonville area and
um my friend was uh pretty and female
which was pretty rare in cannabis uh
but
especially as pack will know especially
in the Humboldt or Mendo Hills this is
even rarer
for a person to like own their own
properties and be doing their own things
or whatever else it was pretty rare back
then so yeah she was kind of gung-ho
about it and he was kind of sweet on her
a little bit and so he ended up giving
her like I don't know 50 or 80 seeds of
um of his own hybrids that he had made
and she found GDP in the first batch
that she followed and the only reason I
figured that out really was because
um I helped her build like a a 60
lighter in the woods oh wow and so
um I knew her before she knew Ken and
she gave it to Ken because they were
Partners together on this thing right
and she wanted to stay totally Anonymous
okay yeah and people don't realize this
about but this is sort of like the era
where like the first real dispensaries
were opening up in the bay yeah um
places like yeah like the like you
probably remember pack like the third
floor
oh yeah you know um and stuff and uh
what was the other one uh The Vapor Room
The Vapor Room the third floor
um there was a few of them uh not very
many back then the power exchange I
believe was one you would always talk
about that was the one that Matt that
you were a little bit more familiar with
but be that as it may
um Ken was willing she wanted to stay up
in the hills and stay anonymous
right yeah and he was willing to go to
the bay and Market it
and so it kind of became TDP and there
was and there was no she was fine with
it because the last thing on earth she
wanted to do was attach her name or show
her face she had Outdoors yeah attention
she was under the radar she had a she
had you know you know 60 lighter was a
big deal back then it was a diesel thing
in the woods she wanted to stay
completely hidden
and that's kind of why Ken's story
changes
because he heard it second hand
yeah that story and and if people want
to hear the full story from the the
werewolf's mouth
it is uh there you can go on Google and
if you look up Ken's GDP story I forgot
what the name of the thing is but it's
some like rapper guy interviewing Ken
about it and he tells this real mumbly
story and you can still find the
transcript that I wrote online if you
look for it and I actually transcribed
it because it's a little screwy until
you transcribe and actually see what
he's saying but he says that Native
American like shamans thought he was a
really great white dude and helped them
and all right that's all right yeah yeah
right and um decided that he they were
gonna gift him this magical purple
Vietnamese skunk plant wow that's where
this came from
so what's interesting about that is that
the story goes is that the guy that gave
my friend the seeds was a Vietnam vet
and had brought back some uh seeds from
his adventures over there when he was in
the Army right and he it's basically
like as you know it basically became
hillweed
right where he took the sativa and he
started Crossing into some of the
indicas that started coming in into the
Mendo Humboldt area and trying to get a
plant that would finish
and then it sort of became that thing
where it's like it was like on that hill
and in that neighborhood or whatever it
was like they were running this thing
and people had different versions it
makes sense you know
um and it was unnamed and you know and
when she popped him or whatever there
was still a variety of like sativa to
Indica leaning ones and they always pick
for the outdoor they always picked a
little bit more of the sativa leaners
because they needed the stretch yeah and
they didn't want much of the moldy
density probably too but a little two
three foot chunky plant for uh for a you
know a
Woods indoor situation was perfect yeah
yeah especially in the early 2000s and
the way that people grew back then you
know a whole bunch of a whole carpet of
plants that were only two and a half
three feet tall and chunked out was a
great look yeah perfect
um and but yeah he you know he he he got
that exact cut from her
and nobody even knows who she is that's
crazy
I was just going to say a Vietnam vet
jump from a Vietnam vet to a Native
American trauma that's not the biggest
leap huh yeah I mean you know addition
here in addition there who's counting
well I mean what's funny pack is like
you know with you living up in Humboldt
obviously it's it's not like the the
natives up there have like a super high
opinion of like you know random white
dudes like Ken you know yeah
right man we're in Vegas
different places in Mendo like there's a
lot of resentment yeah absolutely white
people did not treat the natives that
were living in The Valleys very well
um but yeah he basically he had to make
up a story and whenever you make up a
story sometimes the details change you
know okay so yes or no not so I'll ask
you since you're from the area
Ken Estes yes or no Mark Emery Mini
no
uh only because
um
you know uh
you know I he just
he basically like there was it was more
than just kidding but like huh you're
welcome oh man
but he just you know he just took it
down to the third floor and it was like
he was one of those guys that was
willing to there was not that many
people from Mendo and Humboldt that were
willing to go into those dispensaries
and funnel weed into them yeah yep
people wanted to be anonymous and he was
willing to be not anonymous
and as a result of that he got his name
attached yeah there's also a really good
song on YouTube called leave Ken alone
oh man really oh it is so good I forgot
who the rapper is in it but it's all
about Ken getting popped and leave him
alone and it's it's so good
I highly recommend it
huh
description
in maybe in maybe Ken's defense just
just a little bit because I think this
you could apply this to almost anyone
that uh
um gets famous around weed is they get
famous and they get known for a
particular story
and then it's like it becomes more of
maintaining their image than being
honest
sure yeah I think that temptation is a
really big Temptation and we could talk
about lots of different people in the
industry where
you know there's like not very
well-known details that are true but you
know they have a narrative and they have
a public Persona and their interest is
maintaining that public persona
yeah I mean I I saw this in the UFO
World a lot too where people would be
like famous for let's say they claim to
have an abduction
or a UFO sighting and they get a lot of
Acclaim for this and maybe they did see
something they found to be anonymous
maybe these were they're being totally
true are honest at the time but after
that attention goes away and all the
Adoration and admiration from people and
the you're so cool this is you and the
recognition
they slowly get this one need to get
those endorphins or whatever it is again
the admiration flowing so they'll make
it up they'll they'll force it they'll
force that whatever it is and take that
reputation shot and I see that in weed
it transfers over so well I mean some
people catch lightning in a bottle once
and they spend the rest of their life
like trying to just chasing that Dragon
yeah force that hype and it just looks
better that's a thirsty ego is what that
is or people make entire seed companies
just based around the one or two things
that they're famous for and only do
variations around those things because
that's what they're known for
yeah sure all right it's super common I
mean you know you were talking we I
don't know if it was matter you but like
you were talking about the train wreck
name
I mean I heard you know wasn't there
rumors that like the e32 was because it
was like the 32nd generation yeah
30 second attempt to to Repro the
original yeah yeah something something
wild h m Wilson's got a crew the e32
crew
but I remember that
um you know that term coming out on the
forums and it was like no you don't have
train wreck if you have the arcade to
cut the e32 cut is the one I remember
Calio Calio is a part of the e32 it was
like an early dhk type thing
I don't know I don't know I know one
person who'd know I kind of bug him
about that and ask but yeah I was trying
to remember because I know it was that
was it Berkeley patience group that Eric
worked out of
yeah
that was his name on the forums like
a-e-r-i-c no it was the arcade uh
whatever that dispensary was it opened
up I think that's right it wasn't
Berkeley you're right yeah BPG was
different yeah yeah like 11 there was a
club like one of the first clubs that
opened up in Arcata was off of 11th
Street and uh apparently right dude or
you know yeah and so there was a Calio
story from him and then there was the um
train wreck and it does predate him yeah
but he he is the cut that goes around is
from him if I remember correctly and I'm
sure someone will correct me if I get
that wrong but uh yeah the e32 yeah the
cut that goes around that everybody has
came by him and was passed out by that
Collective
not the 100 original and nobody has it
yeah not the right I mean cry baby cry
baby it was pretty extensively he's done
his research there I think you're right
it sounds like what he was saying yeah
yeah he knows that story about these
I've never seen the e32 cut though I
mean I haven't put it up against the one
that I've held on to but um I don't know
do you do you guys I think it's that cut
I think it's the same cut I think it's
okay yeah I've never seen it I've just
you know seen the Forum hype about
yeah I'm pretty sure it was out of there
from Eric I'm pretty sure that's the one
that everybody has or that has it now or
that had it back then
that's hard I don't know that's the one
that CSI has then yes well I will tell
you that I'll tell you that my cut
didn't come from him directly I got my
cut from the boys up in the hill so
here's the story right come 2000 uh you
know we're all into clones and we're not
popping seeds and
uh my my roommate uh partner at the time
uh knew this girl in Arcata and uh she
was real uh you know a cute little kid
or whatever you know kind of ditzy and
whatnot and he asked her for some cuts
and she's like sure you know someone's
helping me she runs up into the hills I
want to say it was up in Kneeland area
and I got got a flat of tdub he brought
it down and didn't tell them that she
wasn't getting it for her own re-up yeah
she ended up giving it to us right and
that was my first introduction to the
plant I hadn't even seen it prior to
that in in the Years a couple years
before that and so we're growing this
thing and then come come to find out
she's getting hawked by these cats all
of a sudden because she wasn't supposed
to let that [ __ ] thing out and that's
exactly the same time that Arcata we
didn't call it arcade turmeric then but
started getting really prolific and
Arcadia and it was blocking everywhere
it's just you couldn't get away from it
yeah um and then not too long you know
two three years into that all of a
sudden people were bringing their Cuts
in and bringing their their work in and
it was you know rare you know you get 10
people line it up and it was rare that
you got that original uh you know Planet
cut from that point that's I think
because of like the tuxed lines the wood
horse seedlines I finally got a hold of
a wood horse we can talk to him finally
for an interview which would be cool I
think um yeah he was responsible for a
lot of the train wreck out there that
head seat remember grateful Head HML
yeah he did um Oriental Express I think
yeah yep yep
um but who
um
God who else did something with it billy
goat yeah yeah he did he didn't really I
know he at least did the Oriental
Express too you could do a public
service announcement uh don't name your
seed line after a famous cut
s
please don't please pick a different
name this is why we have never seen the
same sfv OG cut after swerve released
that line
don't name it don't name it the exact
cut name please God or Larry or Tahoe
they're all kind of just like up in the
air on if you ever see those cuts again
that they'll ever be anything like they
were originally because so many seeds
were sold under those exact names you
know yeah yeah it makes it makes it hard
you know and uh yeah yeah and I will say
that the Santa Cruz wreck is not from
Santa Cruz by the way yeah
yeah
but that that's super common too I mean
Matt and I were chatting about that like
if you got snow and Humboldt it was
humble snow
yeah it was Oregon snow if you got a new
Gene it was Eugene snow or if you got it
in Bakersfield there's Bakersfield snow
because that's oh yeah that's a
different things
and then you know people would get it
and they would change the name and they
would bring it to different places and
like names have always been very uh very
odd part of the history yeah
you know I found out about a local
strain here that I never heard of
um it's actually a city in the mountains
45 minutes from here but it's it's very
close and it's called the Tehachapi
Terror and I found it in a magazine from
the 70s and I know nothing else about it
but yeah it sounded so cool it had to be
Terror some backseat mash up yeah I mean
mashup was a Garb it doesn't attack do
you or to Matt does anybody know like
what is the blue dream origin story
since we've gone over like not knowing
what train wreck is what is
blue dreams supposed to be I've heard
I've heard a few different theories
hi and Lonesome what do you got
Adam Blue Dream wasn't in my world
um we were we had green crack and try
interact Blue Dream wasn't as big out
here that only stuff us off you know was
flown in
so so that specific cut when it was
first given to me by Bodhi
and the people who kind of were around
the Santa Cruz area that knew the the
crowd that was giving it out or where it
came from all said it was
98 blueberry from DJ that specific cut
that he would pass around crossed a
super specifically a super silver haze
from Greenhouse
and I only know of one company that ever
released that specific cross
and I don't know if it came after or
before
those things chicken before the egg and
it was the blue hen from um
Bluegrass seeds Kentucky some seeds
something like that yeah it was a blue
hand and I remember seeing pictures of
both in the candle Bible so I'm not sure
which came first on that but they were
both similar type plants that I'd
imagine you could find similar
Expressions uh if they were both using
similar lines to make them I would
imagine you know the only variation I
would add to that that I've heard is
um
this uh Haze that people refer to as the
Santa Cruz Haze
being being that cut that was uh used
with the blueberry
um I have yet to see
the Santa Cruz Haze I don't know if this
is just a myth or if it's I would I
would almost bet my left nut that it
would be a super silver haze based on
the the terp profile and everything else
I would be pretty pretty dead on
especially because how quickly it
finishes still all that yeah
yeah
the Johnny Blaze I think was uh
yeah it was Legend seeds Neville's Hayes
yeah that one took a little bit longer
and it still got kind of big like
Neville's
um I could definitely see super super
Hayes being the father pack I remember
if I remember correctly I think Super
Silver Haze
got dropped as a seed line in 97.
mm-hmm I think it won three cups in a
row
in in uh in the Cannabis cups in Holland
um and I believe it was like 97 98 99
something like that it could be wrong
maybe it was 96 but it was something
along those lines I think you're right
right around there it was right around
there that's right yeah I think about
like old song super Haze cut like if I
cross that to the DJ's cut DJ's Mama
blueberry that he sold when he was going
around giving lectures and stuff if I
cross those two I'm pretty sure I could
nail that thing pretty fast it would it
would be pretty regular occurring
yeah pretty sure so yeah I I could see
how that could be definitely
one thing one thing I'll interject is
that at the little gathering that we
just had
um one of the favorite things I smoked
was uh a hybrid pack made that was uh
Blue Dream by train wreck oh that's good
so good one of the one of the things
I'll say about it is that I think
terpenoline has a lot of depth to it but
it's so forward and strong like all it
overpowers a lot of people and that blue
dream hybrid with train wreck that blue
dream brought like a Sweetness in that
almost like took like the the edge off
that train wreck flavor oh yeah but like
but the the flavor of train wreck was
still there it just wasn't like the
predominant knock you just took a step
back right yeah took a step back there
was like a sweet it's almost like with
cooking where like you add some acidity
or you add some you know you add
something to balance out your sauce
and
um you know uh we joke a lot that like
once you get to a paneling in something
it's really [ __ ] hard to get it out
yeah um yeah and I didn't think anything
could tame uh the train wreck nose so
much
um but that hybrid it really allowed the
terpenoline to shine
because it gave it a sweetness I
actually did a review on the blue dream
train wreck in a previous episode in a
short episode so go check that out if
you're interested but yeah it I I was I
was really impressed because it was two
very two things I was very familiar with
and they combined really nicely yeah
that yeah I think that surprised a lot
of people and may have been I think
other than the blue dream I think that
was probably the one that everybody
gravitated to pretty hard yeah
yeah but he still did it it's luck with
intention
I think everybody did they're like yeah
so that that's that's kind of the
impression that that that's kind of the
impression that it made where I just had
to say that uh two old school you know
pretty famous things uh that crossed
really well together yeah yep yeah you
know the one thing that I that I I
appreciate that not so by the way but
all you guys appreciate the you know
your input with that I want to say that
the thing that I was struck most with
was
um not not just t-dub taking a back step
but then the train wreck comes through
and pushes up the potency a little bit
right oh yeah oh yeah you know both of
those in and of themselves if you don't
if you're not used to smoking them and
your body's not used to taking it in
they can both hit you pretty hard in
their own way yeah
um but it's it was it's nice to be able
to smoke both of the original parents
side by side and then go over and hit
hit that combination and see where it
kind of got and a hamster got pulled
back
so it was really it was really a cool
treat to be able to watch my buddies you
know and partake with my friends in
terms of looking at that in real time
and uh getting that feedback you know
it's really like any special thing to do
that anytime you smoke like 60 things in
two and a half days uh yeah it gets even
even just smelling things you smell five
or six things in a row and you're like
your nostrils are kind of burned out for
10 minutes but
um the quality of that that hybrid shown
in my opinion while we're talking about
this stuff let's talk about some of the
the stuff we saw at the party and some
of the different things that we uh
noticed didn't notice I mean um packet
was your first time there all right
unless it was your first time coming to
the one of the Gatherings so um yeah
maybe maybe you guys uh I don't know
which one he wants to start but talk
about some of the strains you saw what
you thought was the most unique what you
thought uh probably bummed you out the
most and yeah all that
ha hmm sure
you know
as we were just talking about it pox
stuff surprised me
um you know
and that that one in particular
um just how the train wreck came through
on some of his hybrids it took a back
seat I've grown quite a few hybrids of
training Rapids normally A variation on
the theme you know it's it's train wreck
with a tiny bit of this or a tiny bit of
that but you know his hybrid seemed
really well Blended that one in
particular I really enjoyed
um
uh bitters grow of Shoreline was oh yeah
oh that was amazing that was great um
and his um dog [ __ ] uh Electric Boogaloo
yes sir both of those were great
um
it was just a lot
um another one that really stood out to
me was the Death Star yeah several
people you know Panda brought some local
brats um
and that had such a it was a lot uh
ranker than I thought it'd be it almost
had like a Kim D rankness to it yeah
that was you know in that level as far
as potency I would say but it was like
definitely instead of being like that
nasty garbage it was like nasty
polyester
it's hard to say but it was just it was
it's very complex
very bright and
it's pretty [ __ ] hard yeah I dug it
yeah
so definitely it's a it's Unique
absolutely unique
how about you pack what'd you see it
stood out
man I mean there's there's so much
novelty going around that it's hard to
kind of determine some from the others I
was blown away by the cob just for the
fact yeah three year old cob sitting
there and uh you know Bodie brought that
through those that was pretty amazing I
wasn't sure if I was supposed to eat it
or smoke it so I just smoke Oh I thought
we were supposed to boof it yeah well
you can you can you can and let me know
how that goes Bodhi told me who made it
so I just stuck it up my my ass yeah I
think that's probably what made you sick
yeah it probably was I probably knew
what I was going to do with it and
poisoned it you know what I do with
everything I get
um you know I mean honestly
it's you know jumped in before I could
speak but um you know the the Electric
Boogaloo amazing you know what I mean
and yeah and I'll tell you what uh that
Shoreline brought me back to my days in
high school
oh yeah you know I just felt like yeah
man I felt like it was 93 all over again
it's a time capsule man that's a great
one Absolutely I'll look so forward to
Growing that too by the way so
um but uh you know one that one that
threw me off guard that I wouldn't have
gone and picked up
um on my own but happened to hit it and
it and somehow or another it cut through
everything for me at that moment I got
so high
I remember watching this kid just
laughing at me looking at me like David
you're stuck right now was that uh was
that Moon boat
oh really
that was good it was good [ __ ] yeah he
brought and you know it could have been
that I was on the you know 25th hour of
the day yeah it might have been it's
four in the morning you know whatever I
don't remember the time I don't remember
where I was but I remember hitting that
and just kind of floating off into this
like other place for a while and uh
feeling embarrassed because you know
someone was laughing at me at my
reaction I liked it enough to put a
picture up of it on Instagram and post
about it so it was it was pretty good
yeah it was really good it was exciting
I mean I've gone I've gone and Revisited
it since because you know I was lucky
enough to be able to bring some party
bags back
and you know it's really not that bad uh
it's not something that I would
necessarily have in my Armory you know
in terms of I want to grow this and and
get into it but I I'm right you know I
might do that if I had the right cut but
um that one stood out uh you know uh our
buddy Denali came through with some some
d
uh you saw our Denali which you know to
this day I'm still kind of just breaking
little pieces off because the flavor is
amazing yeah he brought some silver D2 I
like the silver D he did that silver Pro
you know yeah yeah
silver that silver fox
Silver Fox
21 right yeah the 21 percent thank you
it's scientific uh silver Pearl yeah
and yeah I made a post about that by the
way and um
purple scientific chimed in they're like
yeah that's not right that's not how it
should go and a few other people chimed
in and were like yeah my machine isn't
working for me like that you know maybe
get turned it in get it tested they're
like yeah tell your friend to you know
get a hold of us we'll replace it DM us
so I DM them and I said it's not mine
but I'll be happy to talk to the guy and
they're like what are you talking about
and I was like you told me to DM you
you're like no he didn't
weird okay okay and left it at that but
yeah no that thing was we all saw it
like everybody there sat around and
watched this thing nail 21 on just
ridiculous stuff across the board
oh I'm sorry I was gonna say I just got
one more shot out bro one more shout out
if I can uh to CB uh to everybody
crybaby
um and and some of the magic that he
weaves uh our friend panda came down
from way up North with an Arctic uh made
the trip down and I think uh another
friend of our ring our friend of our
friends that grew out the Meteora for it
yeah that was good yeah and brought that
down and then um somebody had the uh
what is the Bo the burnt offering next
to that which is I guess a grandchild of
the uh Meteora and it was nice to have
those side by side because
um you know just smoking that for an
offering a couple months back
um I was like wow this is very unique
this is not something you usually get
um often and uh having that next to the
media or forward seeing that kind of uh
relation between the two those that was
pretty interesting for me to be able to
get to do that so that definitely sticks
out in my mind meteor four was probably
my favorite like uh what would be
traditionally considered sativa leaning
type there yeah my favorite out of all
of them
in that category
what about you not so what about you
Matt what not to go ahead I'm gonna take
a different tact I think in that uh my
favorite part of the Gathering was the
people
and the the reason I say that is because
you know when when we threw these
parties earlier they were kind of based
around the emerald cup
um it was sort of like a way for heads
and and friends to gather after the sort
of like the big the big Gathering itself
uh and this time was different and then
it was intentional
um and it was friends that mostly talk
online to each other coming from in some
cases literally all over America yeah
coming from the Far East from the far
north from you know people spent a lot
of time and energy to make sure that
they could come
and you know I really there's no joke
getting it it was no joke once they hit
the airport to get to where the party
was but yeah yeah yeah and I do think
that like you know especially with covid
and stuff and people being trapped in
their houses and being able to spend a
lot of time online you can make some
really good friends but I do think it
really helps to spend a few days like
breaking bread with someone getting
baked with them eating food shooting the
[ __ ] I mean cornhole one of my I mean
one of my one of my favorites you know
I'm not so loved in you know yeah yeah
one of my favorite things about the
event is that you know our our homie
who's uh bitter uh you know he gets up
at like 4 30 in the [ __ ] morning or
something so he starts tough and
whenever I go to one of these events I
wake up and I just hear his laugh yeah
that's great you know because
shout out to Bitter and his wife for
holding it down by the way there was
this there was this memory I had where I
got up in the morning
and uh bitter was on like his like 12th
joint or something because he was a
little tent on trying all this [ __ ] and
high and Lonesome had just woke up and
bitter handed him this joint it was like
a chemd joint laced with uh Kim D Keith
yeah and high and Lonesome took two
three hits and he was like man this is
like this is not the starter mix
he went back to bed after that actually
and so just but but you know faces to
names hearing people's voices getting to
see people's sense of humor where it's
not typed out but it's in real time
um you know the internet is cool because
it brings it can bring people together
but being able to spend time
I think and just it was a it's like a
pro it was a proper to me like old
school Harvest Festival yeah where you
have a bunch of real weed people sitting
down making friends talking shop eating
food joking sharing their passion
basically you know
um and that you know there was enough of
us there that each brought some of our
old favorites uh that there was a lot of
good favorites there yeah I remember I
can't remember who it was it was like
I'm not gonna call them out because that
would be rude or anything like that but
I remember Panda telling me that one of
the guys that came brought like all this
like new school Za you know yeah and
after he smoked the shoreline and the
Electric Boogaloo and some Trenton some
this and that he like took all his weed
and he put it back in the bag because he
was like man you know I don't even care
about my weed he's like this right here
yeah and it's neat because you know
we're all older now or whatever and we
don't realize that stuff that we have a
lot of experience with most new school
smokers that have only been around for
eight or ten years missed the era of
almost everything that all four of us
have been talking about this entire time
in like 2010 2012 if you kind of got
into the scene in the last 10 or 15
years
um you probably didn't smoke real train
wreck or real blue dream or real Green
Crack or what the hell is Trace dog or
you know it's like because weed it's
like a flash in the pan right yep it's
like
it really is and uh and so for me you
know there's lots of there's lots of
favorites I have but
um I just I I enjoy spending time around
people who share my interests
I agree I agree aside from aside from
being able to get uh to me each now in
person I say that you're correct yeah
well even even on that you know like so
I'm in the kitchen and you know CSI and
Bodhi and H L are all talking
um and they're like eating like you know
we're eating like smoked fish that Panda
had brought down from Alaska and we're
smoking weed from over here and H L and
body and and CSI have known each other
since the early to mid 2000s yeah yeah
and it was probably the first time they
met in person
yep sure was yeah
you know so even that that kind of stuff
right there I just think is super cool I
mean me and H no have a company together
and that was the first time we've met
I remember I was like all all frantic
because I came in the door because I was
the last one there and like
yeah I was driving in the canyon I can't
see for [ __ ] it was super dark so it was
taking forever so I finally get there
and we brought had to bring the dog
because it was big and wild nobody else
gonna take care of him and I had to
carry in like three rooms of [ __ ] just
for the dog and so I am dead tired and I
remember walking by hugging someone I
thought was Panda because I've seen
pictures of panda but I'd never met
Panda hugging I'm thinking I hug Panda
went downstairs came back upstairs and
goes where's my [ __ ] high and
Lonesome and he's like all right you
already hugged me bro
[Laughter]
aside from that you know seed swapping
clone trading talking about your
favorite strains getting to share your
favorite stuff with your friends
you know uh I like watching local smoke
p91 that was cool watching the youngin
[ __ ] smoking old San Diego strain and
like fall in love with it
maybe I'll maybe I'll throw this out
there too
is one of the things that I liked about
uh dead tour was that you could be at a
campsite hanging out with people your
age
people in their 30s people in their 60s
you know where a lot of a lot of times
you're really only hanging out with like
your own age group
and we had people there from their
mid-20s all the way up to their mid 60s
yeah yeah it was probably a 40-year you
know I mean probably like you know uh
Denali and his late you know there was
there was some senior citizens there
there were some kids that were in our
opinion or barely out of their diapers
um you know and and I remember you know
and some that are barely in their
diapers yeah I remember Panda looking
over at me and being like dude I've
never been to anything like this in my
life
yeah to be able to soak people out like
that is one of the coolest things on
earth and you know I know I think I
think I stopped Matt once at one point
and I looked at him and said dude this
is one of those moments in time that's
quite rare uh to come across so
um don't you know just recognize I
wasn't telling them to recognize but I
reckon I'm right yeah I agree with you I
just think people taking their time and
their energy and money and flying and
driving and prepping and all the effort
that went in to just have a nice time
with friends for a weekend and talk shop
um you know I can't I felt High honestly
like for days afterwards and it wasn't
yeah
it was just I just enjoyed myself
immensely
there's a lot of positive intention for
being yeah that was pretty cool and uh
you know I think uh I think that kind of
like bonding with people in person is
important
yeah uh Brynn has never been to one of
our Gatherings before my chick and she
went this time and like when we got home
she's like I finally get it I finally
get how you bonded with these guys and
like why you guys love each other as
much as you do and why you guys are so
loyal and close she's like I love those
dudes now too I feel like they're family
yeah so yeah you know I can tell she's
not in the room because she didn't throw
a shoe at you yeah exactly
hey man I'll tell you what dude the one
thing I want to say about that is you
know the the world that I was brought
into because I didn't grow up in the
weed scene I I jumped into you know
Junior High High School kind of thing
but the the old cats that I that brought
me in under their wings that was the
energy and that was the philosophy you
know what I mean it was you know there
were people with egos of course and
there's people you know snazzles out
there and whatnot but for the for the
most part
there was this cultural like
consideration in this this bigger
picture that was going on besides the
plant the plant brings you together but
there's a certain way you know of of
kind of interacting with people that
that really kind of solidified that era
for me and to be able to fast forward 20
some odd years and get a touch of that
you know a tasted that again in a very
unique kind of situation uh you know
kind of brought back some some uh
some Hope on my behalf right because I'm
watching everything else fall out I'm
not joining the big the big I guess I'm
not riding the wave or at this point I'm
not and it's not my thing but
um to know that that was still well and
alive and all we had to do was uh
you know kind of let it all fold
naturally and get there you know yeah
yeah I mean there were a lot of a lot of
young guys like not to said you know a
huge age Gap but you know we're all weed
people we're all you know very much
similar yeah we're in it
um great to see I've tried to drive home
like in our our Discord patreon to like
the the people that hang out there and
the Breeders syndicate with us and talk
stuff and like get really into the nerdy
end of stuff is like when they hear us
talk about the can Illuminati they like
you know they they kind of first you're
like yeah is it like some underground
like you know they don't realize like it
was named as kind of like a a
tongue-in-cheek joke just because it was
like it wasn't anybody who gives a [ __ ]
it wasn't any of the the famous people
that you'd see in cannabis like as the
main faces you didn't see Snoop Dogg
there you wouldn't see sure been you
wouldn't see any of those guys there
um but what you did have was the most
passionate people in cannabis I felt
like I that's all it's ever been about
has nothing to do with how long you've
been doing it has nothing to me nothing
to do with how good you are at doing it
not even that it has to do with your
passion your drive and like how intent
you are to to make this your your
passion really I think that's how we all
found each other
yeah for sure it's pretty it's pretty
cool you could be on the same level as a
brother you had never met from halfway
across the world are you guys walk in
the door and it's as if you knew each
other your whole life you know yeah it's
crazy man nothing better I definitely
think it I definitely think it
strengthened some friendships you know
um which is pretty cool and in the fact
that it was pretty quick
either way as far as the actual weed
goes since I pontificated a bunch about
like just like human as the human
element you hit everybody it feels yeah
I've been super clear that I think that
the 90s and the early 2000s was sort of
the golden era of weed and so most of my
favorites are things from that era yeah
you know the chems the cushes the train
wrecks the blue dreams the shoreline
um for my for my age or whatever I just
find most of that older weed hits me
better
yeah it gives me a better effect and
even if it's a wide variety of effects
it's the rare weed that's been made in
the last five or six years that hits me
like some of that older stuff yeah and
so having a bunch of friends bring their
personal favorites you know uh you know
we he mentioned it but bitter brought
you know two three kind maybe four kinds
of kush along with the Electric Boogaloo
along with the shoreline and then
high and Lonesome had some chemd and
some and some headphones and then fire
cam d by the way yeah and some and some
different things and then you know a
pack had uh you know train wreck and
blue dream and classic the blue garlic
train wreck was a big hit too people do
yeah and um you know there was there was
a few different people that brought the
the you know the Death Star and and just
you know and just different things like
that I mean uh you know it eventually
you know at first I was like oh I wonder
if there's going to be enough weed and
then I was like man I wonder if there's
enough places to put all this weed
because like we kept moving table tops
and all that and uh well nothing usually
brings it all like like most of the
parties it's it's been like 90 percent
yeah yeah
I'm not gonna be bringing a bunch of
stuff so we were he was concerned yeah
yeah
it was that way because because I had
greenhouses and stuff like that even if
I'm like mono cropping say two things
for the market yeah I would have a 20 by
30 bed that was a bunch of head stash
yeah yeah sure and it was just me you
know so the first two three parties we
did I don't know Matt I probably brought
pounds it was yeah I think like yeah it
was like pounds of each individual thing
I probably brought like you know there
was probably like four or five pounds of
like you know total but it was like 35
different things you know yeah uh no I
think it was like one to two pounds of
like 35 different things yeah
in a commercial environment just
everyone sharing being super generous
giving samples to all their friends you
know CSI uh you know dumped a bunch of
uh you know various crosses he'd made on
the ground so that anyone could grab
them up people were exchanging seeds and
information I think I should shout out
to I brought you know not everybody
could do this because some people flew
and didn't drive but yeah I brought some
mementos from my past
um Matt brought a bunch of very cool
um magazines and old art and uh books
you know rare rare um you know catalogs
of different things for people to look
through and no one stole anything
[Music]
but that just I think I think ended up
in my stuff yeah you're the only other
person that brought books you know yeah
so it just ended up in my stuff but but
just just a bunch of friends you know
cooking and eating out and and smoking
things and chatting and all that it
really does make a difference yeah well
the vibe too right like it wasn't a
competition it wasn't about who's got
the biggest uh ego or the biggest issue
it was you know really kind of this this
joining right like I took this out I
think that makes a difference too like
honestly we've talked about like do we
want to make it like a cup event we've
talked about it a few times between a
few of us and it's like I I don't know
man would that change it like because
even even though it's all really close
friends as men we're competitive you
know to a degree and if you have like a
prize or something that we can all like
argue over like Flex on it even Flex on
each other over it just changes the vibe
completely so I mean the hard thing too
is when you have a party like that with
the way that weed works it's like a
snapshot in time
yeah so there was thing there was
friends of ours that couldn't come
because of conflicts
um there was weed that was almost done
that couldn't make it that was on the
line you know but not quite ready to be
in the bag so it was kind of like what
do I have ready at the time yeah and
some of it was a little fresh some of it
was a little old some of it was perfect
you know
um but really what it was is it was
mostly just like
you know it's kind of like everybody
brought stuff and it's like here's what
I do for love
and here's what I'm cropping right now
to survive yeah and here's a variety of
things that that incorporate all that
you know I mean how better can it get
man you know no it was I'm not I I mean
the only thing my only complaint with it
was that
um it needed to be like an extra two
days yeah for sure and I needed I needed
like a humidifier and throat
uh we had it in a pretty we had it in a
pretty dry mountainous part of
California and with all the talking and
smoking I was like a husk yeah you
sounded bad at the end of the day
you know I think all of us most people I
talked to or heard their voice for three
or four days afterwards were in the same
position yeah oh yeah it took a minute
it took a minute to recover yeah shout
out to cry baby he sent this and I'll
I'll give a plug to the company too so
nice this is that piece I brought it to
the party and he sent it out so we could
use it at the party and to hook us up
yeah it's a molten I think they say it's
the g-y-z-r perk which it's just a few
little holes but it's it's probably my
favorite piece you don't get like crap
all over the lip you know I don't know
one of the coolest things and this is
the tornado I think it's called the
tornado like ash catcher thingy whatever
yeah that was the other cool part was
just I mean I brought up I brought a
tube and stuff but there was a bunch of
different Vapes Joe you know not only
that but just like smoking smoking the
way people prefer to smoke yeah which
can vary widely yeah local local tried
glass for his first time he had only
ever smoked out of joints or blunts I'm
like bro you have to try that and after
that he was a changed man and then he
trained and then he tried the rip and he
was even more mind blown that that weed
could taste like that you know yes well
it was funny with that old school
[ __ ] Vape box uh yeah yeah and the
crew like that method that we figured
out with it or whatever you know
um and and then you just and then what's
interesting about that is you smoke a
joint a blue dream or you or you've Vape
blue dream or you take a bong hit of it
and you get different qualities sure
yeah yeah you know lots of it not so
explain explain what that box was again
oh man so the box it's like one of the
what's in the box not so it's awesome
it's probably like one of the older like
Vape devices that came out it's probably
been around for a good 20 years or
longer it's been a long time and it's
basically a wrapping
can you guys hear it oh I'm sorry hold
on let me stop that
we have an interesting house here likes
to make some noises hold up he's beating
off there it is
and uh so it's like a wooden box that
has like a glass uh element with a
ceramic on it and you can dial it in for
how hot it gets and then it has like a a
glass mouthpiece with a a tube for lack
of a better term that connects to
another glass piece
um and most people would end up like
filling the glass like really deep yeah
and then you get one or two nice hits
and then it kind of tastes popcorny and
everything and it kind of loses its
flavor and it's hard to deal with but we
figured out 20 years ago is if you just
grind up weed and you just you just use
the mouthpiece and you just suck up a
little bit just enough it's the motion
looks like when you do it yeah can you
do it you have to like Hoover yeah but
what do you do do you put it to your
mouth I do you have to put it I smoke by
putting things to my mouth and inhaling
I don't know how other people do it but
that's my message okay uh I inhale if I
can get you to pantomime and so I uh and
so you know know if you but if you just
coat the the screen with a little bit of
weed yeah you can get two or three
really nice hits and then you can blow
it out in a little bit of water or glass
or something like that and it just is
really user friendly yeah that
completely changed my Rip Deck too now
yeah we the vapewear box right yeah
vapewears and Vapor brothers made um
vapewear Vapor Brothers indeed and yeah
we smoked it a bunch and it kind of fell
in and out of favor and then when we
figured out how to do it that way
there was like a couple year period
where like that was the method
and you get really clean Terps that way
you know you get really like a really
good sense of like the profile of how
the weed tastes I feel like it's a
little bit of a different Buzz I think
you get way higher in my opinion I at
least it's it's it's a noticeably
different High
smoking any other way and I it's got to
be because like the volatile
[ __ ] that would normally burn away right
away you're actually experiencing what
it's like to you know and then the other
thing I'll say is that since everyone
was so generous with samples I'm still
smoking off samples I brought home
um and I got a much better sense of a
lot of the weed at home yeah sure I did
at the party because when you're at the
party once you've smoked 27 kinds of
weed in eight hours through nine
different methods you know you're just
looking for what cuts through at that
point yeah it's like what cuts through
but it's like you you know it's hard and
it's like then it's like I can wake up
and I can do some chores and I can take
a couple hits of this and go do some
stuff and I'll be like oh it does that
yeah it's got that kind of effect you
know like oh it makes me want to sit
down and do nothing or like packs it
with the train wreck oh like it makes me
want to move yeah did any of you get to
try the banana tie oh yeah that [ __ ]
makes me want to move makes my heart
pound I love it I love it a bit much for
me all right
that's the other part of it that I that
I do like is that you know pack used to
live up in Humboldt and I do think that
like Humboldt and Mendo and going to I
call Santa Cruz like the very edge of
the weird bubble you know yeah there's
this bubble that there's enough weed
people doing stuff around you that
there's somewhat of a community
you know and we we got some friends that
came out from Illinois and from Alaska
and from here and from there that
they're kind of like the only person
like them in their little Community yeah
and so it was really it was really nice
to see especially some of the younger
guys
um get to hang out with a bunch of
people like them of all age groups
I think probably for them it was like
more
memorable even for us
I'm sure yeah maybe I don't know I don't
know if memorable would be the correct
term saying how we're all so high you're
probably not going to retain a lot of
them you know influential I don't know
remember I remember a fishing hook
almost hit me in the head a few times
yeah yeah
and you know just just speaking of that
bubble not so that you brought up I was
telling it you know a while back you
know one of the reasons why I didn't get
on the farm back in the days because I
you know I was in that network from you
know or the network that I that I had
around me was you know it was kind of
compartmentalized right like there was
the cruise down in Big Sur and you had
your Monterey cats Seaside gas and the
injured people and you know Santa Cruz
and Humboldt
um but I I never had a need to go
outside of whatever the network was that
I was working within in terms of trying
to reach out or find out you know what's
going on with others or you know growing
techniques or whatnot not that it wasn't
wouldn't have been something that would
have been helpful at that point but
because of my propensity to not want to
be on the radar whatsoever and even
touch a computer and say anything on
there
um that had anything to do with whatever
I wasn't really compelled at least in my
group to have to you know feel like I
need some connection outside of what I'm
doing on my own you know I wasn't really
that kind of Lone Wolf space whereas a
lot of people I think and HDL could
probably speak to us better than me but
a lot of people who weren't so connected
or had to be even more
um discreet right and weren't going to
talk to anybody it was like that was a
great place to be able to make those
connections and and really kind of
figure out what was going on right yeah
here it was uh a whole different animal
I mean you didn't
you knew two guys maybe in the area it
was you know if you wanted if you wanted
to be amongst people like you you had to
find them online because you weren't
talking to other people around you doing
the same thing weren't talking and it's
still
uh still kind of like that here even
with you know some version of
legalization it's um it's still pretty
pretty closed lip at least you know the
people that have been doing it a long
time
I agree and I also think that because
we're sort of like a a very small subset
of a subculture right
um in a way like we love weed for weed
you know
um is that the either you know the
internet is a way for lots of people
that have sort of unusual interests to
find each other
right
um you know from all kinds of walks of
life if you know that or bathroom stalls
we only have two choices I mean and uh
you know so they uh how I got NASA's
numbers
indeed right off the bathroom stall
but yeah I mean I I I agree I you know
it's it's that you know even in people
think
I get it all the time where people think
that Mendo or Humboldt is something that
it isn't yeah because they you know they
think of it as like this weed Mecca
which it kind of is but it also has all
these elements that like you wouldn't
really get unless you lived there
um and so I but you know just you know
sharing time and energy with like-minded
individuals I think is a good thing you
know and I was I'd like pack I too I was
scared of the internet
um especially when Heaven's stairway and
uh and cannabis world and and overgrow
all got shut down yeah I wasn't very
tech savvy so I got worried that like
everything I did instead would be
permanently there that they could find
wasn't it
was a little bit it was kind of screen
Merchant
yeah
like 1990 and this was like probably I
don't know I think those busts happened
until like oh three or oh four if I
remember correctly
um but I didn't like when with high and
Lonesome being on icmag and all that
like I worked in that era uh but I just
basically like you were on someone
else's computer yeah and I was I was in
Norco Lake County Mendo you know it was
kind of a booming time for my area for
cannabis hmm
yeah not mine no not yours
hey Matt we didn't get you partner what
was was what was the standout or
standouts for you man oh [ __ ] I don't
know um of course a blue dream just
because like I it's a classic for me and
because I'm such a blueberry head like
um that's that that's what I I pulled to
um
let's see like the main standouts I know
everybody was stoked on the shoreline I
didn't get to try that one because I was
so busy trying everything else but
that's the one I remember everybody
being real stoked on and hearing about
um foreign
yeah I liked Caleb's Flight Plan he's
called Flight Risk your flight plan
I always get it wrong that was a good
one Flight Risk slight risk there you go
yeah that makes more sense in Flight
Plan
and then there was he had one called
um the the blackberry wine 69. it was
real unique and tasted and smelled like
wine like a Chardonnay that was cool
um there was the the
uh sweet 16 I want to say yeah that was
really good I like that one paints and
burp selection I think yeah it was from
the pinks and purps like because I'm a
Blackberry Widow hybrid Mendo perps type
thing real cool yeah yeah we kept going
back to that jar as a matter of fact
yeah there was so much stuff there that
it was just ridiculous to try to go
through it all there when I got home I I
didn't tried the Death Star much while I
was there when I got home I really
enjoyed it you know
um p91 I finally got to try when I got
home and and that was really good really
good grow of it
um
God and it Denali silver Pearl I never
get enough of silver Pearl that was just
so good and I've never had outdoor
silver Pearl yet and it was still pretty
good I liked it and it actually had a
pretty pretty strong high for silver
Pearl
21 21 at least
yeah that's what I dug for sure
I was wondering I have a bag of that
silver Pearl it was smoked on the other
night and it looked like something
Denali put out so tasty
yeah yeah
backyard victory garden yeah
you know and so he gets to do a bunch of
favorites and stuff like that so yeah
um yeah he had he had a I gave him uh my
Sour Diesel cut he had a pretty nice
example of that
um you know I didn't even get to try
that
no I don't know
it's a hard one outside like the flavor
varies a lot outdoor but the potency is
there yeah for sure
oh wait no I take that back he did I did
get to try that one he sent it to me
beforehand it was good did it really
good Outdoors yeah I was like wow this
actually is really good sour at first he
didn't know he's like I don't know if
this is good or not I was like no it's
actually coming through in the outdoor
it has a great smell yeah
the sour so variable outdoor it is
but you know
I feel like the high normally is there
it's just the flavor and the looks you
know and for me are very variable
definitely
it takes a long time high in Lonesome so
you really need a good season
yeah
um in order to get it to express right
because you really need that last two
weeks to be banging yeah and it likes to
go towards Halloweenish or even early
novemberish at times so you don't always
get that weather
not here now not even in Mendo sometimes
you know just depends yeah it just
depends sometimes you get real nice warm
Dry Falls and other times it's rainy and
cloudy and problematic yep
so my phone's about to die Matt yeah
well I'm gonna yeah we're almost at two
hours I'll touch on the 420 so real
quick we got a sale coming up on 420.
um we have some freebies from high and
Lonesome what what are the freebies
you're gonna be throwing in uh they are
the mule Skinner so that is GMO cross to
Appalachia
that's awesome and goat Farm's gonna be
a part of it too and what's going to be
the freebies with your stuff
yes sir what do we got uh I think we're
gonna throw in uh maybe we're gonna do
that Afghan uh arcade and then I got
something called hell melon
it was a watermelon Skittles hybrid yeah
watermelon skills hybrid crossed with uh
an F3 uh Angelico which is one of
bodhi's um cuts a buddy of mine had been
working on that for quite some time
around here the Angelica awesome
um got it to a nice spot and then yeah
it's gonna be something they're gonna
have a few things from both of those
gentlemen and uh we'll be having a big
uh percentage off and I'll be throwing
in some other freebies too we'll be
letting everybody know about it
um shout out to Molten glass again for
this awesome glass it really is my
favorite piece and shout out to cry baby
for for hooking it up and uh we wish you
would have been there this year but you
weren't buddy we'll see you next year
yeah buddy next time and I would just
like to throw in that uh you know when
Matt convinced me to start chatting in
public uh we kind of wanted to bring
like real weed talk without like so much
promotion into it
um and so uh everybody on this chat
today is my very good friend and so
anytime I get to chat with my homies
it's always a good time and so I'm super
glad that uh high-end Lonesome and pack
and all of us we got to chat for the
last couple of hours very enjoyable
about damn time yeah yeah I just wanted
to mention that that uh you know
everybody on this podcast today is my
really good friend and I appreciate them
a lot so
you got any closing thoughts
that was my closing thought
was this I just wanted to be pretty much
all right
if you know you got one no I mean the
Positive Vibes coming from not so pretty
much covers it yeah we all do this for
the love of it and um it's just great to
see
like-minded folks out there
I agree I agree um
well you know just stoked to be part of
a good group of people you know and and
sharing a similar philosophy uh that
goes beyond just chasing the dollar you
know what I mean it's it's really cool
to to know that that's well and alive
and um you know and you got some merch
coming out soon too yeah
somewhere maybe yeah yeah well you know
we're always in the lab doing something
around here yeah
um I would say I would say keep your eye
out uh you know I don't know if if
anyone does follow on Instagram or
whatnot I have a tendency to kind of
post some things that I'll be working
with maybe a couple months ahead of time
um and that's for me to get an idea as
to what I'm doing right it's Paul part
of the betting process but
um if you're wondering what might be
coming down uh the pipe here in the next
six months to a year or shorter
um you know there's some good things in
the works
um
I'll say that Shoreline is on that
Shoreline and that green crack is on the
list oh yeah and uh you know maybe maybe
some blue dream work you know who knows
yeah it's in collabs with you and uh
high on Lonesome in the future maybe I
hope I think that's it in the books I
think it's a good idea that might be
something I think
what was that I said I think it's on the
radar yeah yep oh well you know I'm just
stoked to watch my good buddies want to
grow some of the [ __ ] I've been putting
together um hnl's you know gonna be
popping some things or you know things
are starting to show up so
you know I'm just thankful to to be part
of it all and it's it's uh you know you
create you not so create something
really unique here and I appreciate it
yeah I appreciate it man yeah I I
personally
um have I grew up reading like high-end
Lonesome stuff like on the forums and um
ah dude becoming going from being like
an admirer to one of my best friends has
been a huge honor and um same with you
pack learning you learning learning who
you are and who you are behind like your
Instagram person but you the person
behind that and and how you're involved
and stuff has been pretty mind-blowing
it's pretty been really cool getting to
introduce you to everyone and so they
get to learn your story too and slowly
slowly hopefully everybody else will
over time so we'll see how it goes look
at how nice he is to you too I know yeah
and then there's that I get I get uh I
get trucks
you guys get you guys get warm warm
admiration
all that is is he's been loving you a
little bit longer that's all and yeah
yeah indeed
sexual frustration
yeah thank you for everybody for
everybody's time thank you for coming on
it was a pleasure
and my phone literally is a two percent
so if I die it's it's that and then not
so's dead so that's that so all right
we'll end it now real quick um and then
I'll I'll talk to you guys one second
one second
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate
check out our patreon and our link tree
or description below our merch site is
officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is top notch
I've been saving old designs for years
for this purpose so please check it out
syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out