welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
welcome breeder Syndicate I'm here with
my buddy thousand fold and we will be
talking about why cookies is the
beginning of the end of modern breeding
and maybe some ways that we can change
that hopefully fix that and what
composes some of these lines and why
it's it's headed the directions it's
it's gone so yeah thank you for joining
me thousand
hey Matt
um yeah so I guess what would make sense
here is if we do a little recap of what
the major components of the cookies
family might be absolutely so first off
I want to talk about what is cookies
itself and to talk about cookies we also
have to talk about another clone that
came out around the same time which was
cherry pie
also animal cookies hit the scene at the
same time but it's much less relevant it
looks like more of a a forum cookie
sister but for for all intents and
purposes we need to talk about which
cookies because there were multiple
cookies cuts from cookie fan that people
were growing around the same time
so we have the thin mint cut from cookie
fam
my first introduction to cookies was
what was called Girl Scout cookies at
the time
but later on became called The Forum cut
now the thin mint cut and the forearm
cut are two separate Cuts cookie fam has
always stated that the thin mint cut
came before The Forum cut so when we
refer to cookies in this episode we are
going to be referring to the thin mint
cut proper unless we specify Forum
cookies now the thin mint cut was said
to be an OG Kush that they had from
Florida that they refer to as the Flo
Rida OG
cross to what is called the F1 derb
which has been kind of a controversial
really rare cut that they don't really
talk about too much they don't really
talk about what's in it and when they do
it didn't make a lot of sense and
um yeah
along that same time we have the Cherry
Pie that came out which is my favorite
of most of them I might add that in and
that's supposedly a granddaddy purple
crossed to an F1 derb
Granddaddy Purple itself is an Urkel
Salmon Creek big bud hybrid most likely
made by Chris Yaki who is no longer
around to really ask about it this is
the best knowledge we have for this
moment
um the GDP is a very Urkle dominant
expression itself and a lot of people
would confuse the two and they were
passed interchangeably for a long time
uh but cherry pie does a good job of
expressing some of the F1 derb traits
and the cherry or I'm sorry and the
Urkel traits and that's what you get
with cherry pie
um cherry pie became a lot less
important as cookie fan breeding carried
on though at the time I'm mentioning it
because it is very integral and often a
lot of people confuse the genetics in
cookies with the genetics in Cherry Pie
and a lot of that I think is because
what became known as The Forum cut seems
to be showing traits from both the the
Cherry Pie and what cookie fam refers to
as the Thin Mint or cookies
um when you S1 or have you know hermed
bag seed self to bag seed of forum
cookies you can find a lot of Urkle
traits in it and that's why that tells
me that that is most likely a hybrid of
these two and that cookie fam probably
was right when they were saying that
thin mint came first in all in all logic
it kind of works out that way for me
um so those are the the main basis for
what we're going to be talking about and
again the F1 derb was kind of a rare
clone uh me and CSI have been have been
working with it um trying to figure it
out I worked out I worked with it really
early on made a few crosses and Let It
Go
um mostly because there was no interest
really in the F1 durb it wasn't really
talked about a lot by by Cookie fam so
it didn't get the hype
and someone who's a little bit you know
far away I didn't even know if Wonder
was like a real thing and I think that a
lot of people felt that as well I think
I think in America it's the same way um
people still argue on Instagram
constantly like when me or CSI post to
fiction to be like that's fake that's
not real that's not a real thing and
like yeah it is it's the real thing it's
been it's been the same cut that's been
passed as F1 derp since since the
beginning since we got it and um we we
decided that we were going to cross it
to some of these other Cuts be it the
thin mint we have that
um
the the F ones are being self so we can
see what other kind of traits are inside
the F1 dirt because it is an interesting
cut very interesting cut
um it's got swollen
bubbly
Brax a lot like cookies right like
that's one of its main traits it's very
low yielding a lot like cookies it's a
little more Airy like uh like a Durban
would be as very Anis Anis and a seed
type smells to it which would be like
root beer or black licorice has some
gingerbread and some some urine type
smells to it to be honest as after it
cures does it bring the purple black
leaves as well it does have some purple
traits to it especially on the leaves
um the stems early on in veg you can see
those beautiful purple traits but yeah
it does it does have some nice purple
traits that it brings with it as well
um
I'm not sure 100 what it is but since
these Durban Poison did have that black
licorice in it
um the gingerbread being an extension of
that some of the pissiness I'm not sure
I'm not sure
um I I would speculate but it would be
going out on a limb for sure that maybe
OG was crossed into it very early on
into the Scentsy Durban Poison skunk one
and that that's what we get with the F1
dirt but that's pure speculation and
it's only because of
how the the blood structure of all of it
um the the smells are very different
from OG Kush it's a it's a long stretch
from OG Kush so it's it's very very much
speculation but the small leaves
um around the buds the way they look are
very OG Kush
um the the resin production reminds me a
lot of like a triangle and stuff like
that
um and again I want to go back to the uh
Flo Rida OG as well since that's one of
the main components
um this has been grown side by side by
uh not so growing triangle uh triangle
Kush and flow right OG side by side
because for a long time we were
wondering since both of these Cuts or
early OG Kush cuts from Florida are they
the same cut you know were they just
passed under different names
so it took a while but we were able to
rejoin these cuts and have them grown
side by side and by not so's opinion
they are not the same cut they are not
they are definitely similar types of ogs
but because of specific traits a
triangle has and specific traits the Flo
Rida has which I'll leave that to not so
to talk about in another show
um
we were able to tell that they are
probably two different cuts and that
that makes up the basis for
what cookies is the directions it breeds
and again I would break it down to GDP
Urkel
Flo Rida OG Kush which is really just an
OG cush
the F1 derp which is probably a Durban
Poison skunk one hybrid
and
um yeah I think that's the the main
components if I didn't miss anything so
so that's the first layer of the inbred
pyramid of course yeah this is the first
layer of the inbred pyramid and like at
this layer like I don't see a whole lot
wrong I don't see a whole lot wrong with
the direction of reading when this hit
the scene at the time
um when cookies popped up I remember
looking at the pictures and thinking and
Cherry Pie as well because I saw both at
the same time
and I was like wow these are absolutely
unique beautiful plants for their resin
production their blood structure shape
um the Brax all of it it was a very
unique but I thought also thought
there's no way this will ever be
commercial because it is so low yielding
and that's why I took an interest in it
because I was like there's no this will
never be commercial it'll never catch on
so I took an interest in breeding with
it and I tried to take it some new novel
directions like instead of just making
more of itself I wanted to see more of
what it could bring to other existing
things
and yeah those are the directions I was
hoping it would go
um and that most breeders have taken
lines over the years
and cut specifically clone onlys
um
and I can talk about maybe why the the
politics of that have changed and how
the politics changing sort of enabled
this to happen right like for a long
time feminized seeds were very almost
demonized like religiously demonized
um
I was often told you know as were other
Femme breeders at the time you know in
the in the mid-2000s that we were
ruining the gene pool this isn't the way
God intended it to be
um we were destroying the chromosome so
it was permanently going to destroy
cannabis gene pool you know and and
basically it's just not not how it's
supposed to be it's trash it's a cheap
way to breed it's cheating it's quick
it's you know there are so many
different reasons of why people didn't
like it against God against God was a
real real thing and like it's still a
it's still something that people throw
at me like it's not natural and I can go
into why that's the worst argument out
of all of them
um but I mean in nature cannabis is
naturally intersex
as humans we want we've bred away from
that trait the intersex trait
we've done as best we can to remove that
trait from the gene pool however in
nature it's there and man has has
removed it by reintroducing intersex
traits we're actually taking it back to
where nature had it technically if you
really want to get technical like it's
an argument getting closer we're getting
closer to God again right back closer to
God you know that's where we want to be
right right so
um yeah during those times it wasn't as
proper you didn't want people to know
you were making Femme seeds especially
if you were whereas once we hit to about
2013 14 15
them breeding became real popular as as
growing became more popular in America
and it wasn't just the old Legacy
Growers and it was getting more popular
as States became online and new Growers
were popping in Benedict seeds weren't a
Bad Thing necessarily to these customers
because they didn't want to deal with
males in the first place and they
weren't really concerned about
chromosomes or genetics it hadn't come
into play in their brain so
the the marketing finally started to
take hold on fem seeds and because of
that we started to see a lot of people
making feminized crosses of cookies
including myself
um we would do self inbreeding of of
this cookies we'd use self-reading of
cherry pie you know and then we'd make
processes of these and sell these and
that's because it was more allowable and
people weren't getting as much pushback
there were thousands of people doing the
same thing with cookies and all the
cookies hybrids they weren't getting the
pushback that we had seen for a decade
prior and I think this allowed
this this culture to take hold of
selfing feminized seeds uh in the U.S to
take hold
and in doing so took breeding in a
completely different direction than it
had ever gone before
yeah
so
from there we have what what became
known as the sunset sherbert
we have
uh
gelato
we have things like uh Skittles pop-up
we have
uh what's the other runs we have things
like this all pop up the key lime so
this is the next the next Generation
this is the next generation of where
most of the popularity
took the cookies lens and when I say
that there are so many breeders out
there who have done unique novel things
with cookies when it first came out made
crazy crazy process I mean we even had
like chocolate Thai
um across the cookies we had like the 95
Scentsy star across the cookies
um a lot of strawberry cookies early on
just taking it different directions but
a lot of people were more interested in
what they could do in their room with a
tent and some reversal spray and just
cookies all right and what we started
seeing pop up were the cookies S1
Revolution the bagseed revolution
um cookies was so in demand you know six
thousand a pound so people were trying
to find any seeds they could find in the
bags of weed
um and cookies did a good job of trying
to remove those seeds like they really
tried to pick the seeds out and I don't
blame them because they didn't want the
competitors and that's when the
marketing of fortune cookies they call
things fortune cookies or you know
fookies or whatever they wanted to call
it to to try to denounce any of the bag
seed coming out but people were finding
their own bag seeds and giving it new
names uh they name it after themselves
cookies like they call it Riot cookies
or whatever for that was just an example
I didn't have that
um
we also had people that were kind of
tangentially friends with the cookie fam
doing some work
and in that group there was a dude named
Mario also referred to as sherbinsky and
he popularized something called Sunset
sherbet
um we also have something he did called
gelato and
some of what comprises that stuff is
something he had called the pink panties
now I grew the pink panties cut for a
while and I was trying to figure out
what exactly it was
um online there's not a lot of
consistency
about what it is some say it's a Burmese
land Race Across to no Florida OG the
Flo Rida OG
um I find that hard to believe because
of Burmese land race you know Thai
Burmese that's a 24 weaker and uh you
know 20 to 24 weaker I mean if you're
lucky maybe a work line would be 14
weeks you know something like that but
I'm not seeing that I did not see that
can I just ask how white spreads was the
pink panties not at all not at all about
like F1 derb um it never despite it
being in the parental lineage because of
the people that were buying cookies gear
and interested in it at this point I had
already kind of walked away I was not
interested much in cookies proper people
had already made a bunch of crosses with
it it was already starting to be inbred
so I lost a lot of interest in it but I
was interested in some of the the
parentage and um the F1 Durban the
panties were not widely passed and and
again people would have had to have been
into parentage to hunt these cuts and
one thing these cuts and like if you
look up the parentage for pink panties
it's not even really consistent so like
I can't imagine there being a lot of
hype about something that like sounds
like a Burmese land Race Across to an OG
like there wouldn't be a lot of interest
in that I don't think
yeah yeah so those two were kind of at
the limits of what we we know for sure
yeah for sure and and
like looking at it I would guess and
because I've read a few places that
Burmese cush was used or was in the room
that would fit a lot better with
that than a Burmese land race however
like
what this looked like was some sort of
blackberry hybrid
um it was low potency a little Airy
not a ton of resin production a little
fruity
and it's I've used it in projects but
it's not something I would continue to
use in projects I was just interested to
see how it bred was something that I
know to see what else was in there
um it would to me it's an odd choice to
use in a popular line nonetheless it's
supposedly what's in these lines in the
in the sunset shirt
um the sunset sure supposedly was made
in uh what I think the area of
where he made it was called Sunset area
which is why it's called Sunset sure but
there's also something called the green
sherb which is probably what is the mom
of Skittles and some sort of cherry pie
hybrid or bag seed as best we know
um it was often referred to as key lime
pie and pastas key lime pie really cool
cut really cool cut really super
resinous more narrow Leaf like thin mint
um but just resin and and lots of gas a
little bit of citrus but it's nice it's
a really nice cut
um but the sunset shrub was completely
different than the grain sure I'm not
sure which came first but when we refer
to Sunset sherbet we're not referring to
the green sherbet and I have a hard time
pronouncing Sherbert or sherbet because
it's spelled sherbet there's no art so
just wanted to point that part out
people make a big deal of the fact that
there's no R in that but yeah yeah it
drives me nuts no R in that why people
say sherbet
um and then we have the gelato which for
me is probably like personally in my
opinion is the end of this tale it's the
end of the tale of cookies the end of
the tale of breeding with cookies at
least self-breeding with cookies it is
the to me gelato 33 specifically that
clone is a fine example of what happens
when you inbreed cookies and you keep
trying to inbreed it further and why I
say that is because I've actually self
gelato 33 the Clone and what you get
when you sell gelato 33 the Clone it's
gelato 33. you get a very uniform inbred
line of gelato 33 and it for people to
know gelato 33 it's kind of gassy
depending on how you grow it kind of
gassy kind of grapey good yielding
okay resin production but not as good as
some of the other gelatos obviously
better than most Cuts but the high is
very to most people is what we would
consider very Bland boring the 20 minute
kind of narcotic not too unique type
high and that's what I saw when in
braiding gelato and like I said 33 the
reason I bring this up is because if you
sell like the 45 or the 41 you're still
going to end up with a lot of the
examples of what 33 looks like by doing
that because it is the most common
example of what you get from selfing
those the the hybrid of uh thin mints
and sunset sherbet and it seems like to
me gelato is the Clone that took hold
the name
um what people tended to use because you
have like the acai gelato expression you
have the the Mochi gelato expression
like these are all different numbers
that I'm not really super familiar with
you know like
they're all these little takes that were
supposedly different expressions of
gelato or even bag self to bag seed of
gelato popping up
and people have taken hold on these
specific cuts and just keep inbreding
them or crossing them to each other to
make more new named gelatos
and to me that's what this Market is and
whether they're calling it gelato where
they're calling it sherb whether they're
calling it you know uh any number of
things it doesn't really matter because
that's where we're at and that's why
almost everything you're looking at
looks the same
um wedding cake another one that people
talk about to me is just what happens
when you inbreed OG Kush you get a
shitload of wedding cake a very Bland
kind of creamy
um some say cakey but I'd say like uh
creamy
just Bland hash plant type OG Kush very
frosty looks great a little bit of
purple to it but it's just inbreeding OG
Kush over and over and over what about
um runs good and runs supposedly was a
uh gelato 33
cross to either a reverse Skittles or a
gelato 33 hermion Skittles it's never
really been clearly stated I made a
gelato 33z Cube which is this gittles
bx3
um early on and there was some okay
stuff in it but because there was an
outcross in this e-cube it was more
variant but watching what happens when
you cross gelato 33 to Skittles itself
the Clone
ends up being a lot of either Skittles
which is like citrus grapefruit
to the extreme like or you get more
gelato and inbred cookies
um but going in that Skittles Direction
you really just get a lot of that Citrus
Skittles stuff and while it's different
than a cookies proper and it's a
different direction than gelato
because it's inbred cookie still in a
way even though there were some other
outcrosses along the way because it's
inbred cookies still taking these
Skittles in further directions into
itself will just beget more Skittles
more uniform versions of Skittles and if
you love Skittles that's awesome but if
you if you don't want a bunch of
Skittles Terps and every single cross
that you make or outcross then it's like
a kind of a bad direction to go you know
like Skittles is great for one-off
crosses but inbred it makes it a lot
harder
yeah yeah so you're kind of you're kind
of getting to the summary of what I
think crybaby mentioned in the chat
yesterday which was uh quote unquote
cookies gets worse the further down you
go yeah right that's that's a paraphrase
I guess of what you were just describing
you know what actually could you talk us
some about the the Flo Rida OG and the
triangle and the differences
sure I could I mean where do you I mean
are we are we just gonna Pat are we just
gonna like patch this in at some point
yep
I mean so do you want me to do you want
me to start with the Flowrider story
yeah that'd be great actually
okay
um so let's see it's it's uh it's gonna
be about 53 minutes in I guess yep
all right so
um my uh my experience with the
Flowrider is is a little weird
um in the sense that
um
I was growing a bunch of super skunk
and super dog hybrids Maui chem dog uh
what people call the chem 91 these days
uh and things of that nature right and I
was bringing most of it down to the bay
to a friend of mine
and
you know he unbeknownst to me at this
point in the early 2000s I really had no
idea being stuck in Mendo that there was
this like like Kush craze that had
started in LA and that people were
getting ridiculous pricing for cushes in
LA
um and so around spring 04
my buddy was like I want you to
stop growing everything that you're
growing as far as for com for commercial
sale in California
um and I want you to grow this and I'll
take every bit of it and you can give it
to a couple close trusted friends but I
don't want it to get out and I want to
make sure you give me all of it yeah
right and so I went down there uh to the
bay and I got uh this Kush cut and I
asked him what it was and he just said
it was kush the real kush later on I
found out it ended up being what people
know now is the Flow Rider yeah but I
got that in you know spring like
probably April May of 04. okay right and
I started growing quite a bit of it I
didn't realize he was giving me the
exact same number that I was getting for
everything else
I didn't realize at all that he was
literally like getting it for low fours
and flipping it for like mid sixes yeah
I just killed
oh I was kind of getting jacked but I
didn't but you know I mean at the same
point it's like you know I felt like it
was fair you know I felt like the price
I was getting was fair because it was
comparable with everything else I was
getting and it was easy and whatnot and
so
you know
um and then how long did it how long did
it take you to get good at growing Flo
Rida because Kush at the time it was new
and it's kind of hard to grow
um it actually wasn't that hard for me
to get good at growing it uh that didn't
take any time at all to be honest
um what did take some time was figuring
out how to get it to yield well
yeah in your room like I got high
quality rips of it right away
um but obviously like most of the other
stuff that I was growing wasn't
necessarily like little bunch of little
golf balls everywhere exactly yeah um
and so I I had to I had to take a
different tact into growing it I kind of
we kind of realized that like it didn't
yield very much unless you unless you um
either a grew it really close together
in high numbers
or B
um
you know topped it a bunch because it
was so dense
no matter how many branches it had it
would kind of throw off golf ball golf
ball golf ball golf ball golf ball so if
you figured out a way to get a bunch of
branches that got good light you'd get a
bunch of golf balls and that added up
yeah um it also seemed like uh it really
liked having an expansive root system
um I didn't realize that it wasn't
nearly as strong of a rooted plant as
other things uh in terms of watering so
like if you grew it if you grew at Hydro
you kind of like had uh
you know you almost wanted to grow it
like on a root mat yeah of that nature
so that like the roots would all
intertwine and grow out into one big
thing yeah or if you grew it in like a
fluffy uh you know uh peat moss perlite
or cocoa perlite bed yeah
um it really liked the roots growing out
wide
you know if you put it in a big pot by
itself of any kind of heavy soil or
something like that it didn't drink that
fast yeah so you ended up running into
issues where like it was difficult to
water it as frequently as you might want
and clone
difficult to slow you know and so I and
so that was so that was basically like
that was my introduction
um and you know uh our our buddy who
lives down south bitter you know it
turns out that
um I got it bro you know I got things
relatively early compared to a lot of
people oh yeah yeah you know but I
didn't have I didn't really at that
point in my life I really wasn't leaving
Mendo much you know or going much South
uh past the bay
so I just didn't realize that there was
this like massive boom going on down in
Southern California it took me a couple
of years to sort that out
um and it just so happens that uh the
way that ties into cookie
is
um that's the cut that
um all those guys were running
yeah
you know that's so cushion huh what what
did you notice in the differences
between triangle and the Flow Rider
because I you know people always say oh
it's just it's just a triangle cut when
they talk about it
it's definitely not
um I uh people might get mad at me for
saying this or whatever but I
um
I think the triangle might be like one
of the better all-around cushes yeah but
I don't think it's the best in like any
one area
okay if that makes sense like yeah it
does a pretty good job of yielding it's
got a pretty good Buzz
um it's it's it you know it has uh you
know uh good flavor and all that type of
stuff
um but it um
but it uh you know I don't think it has
like the nicest flavor uh or the nicest
high you know or anything like that I
think it's just like an all-around
winner now of course like that's
preference so like people might be like
oh dude you just don't know how to grow
it right or yeah you don't know this or
that or whatever but really
you know to be perfectly honest like you
know the the best tasting Kush I ever
tried you know
um yielded like [__] yeah you know like
it was like a three quarters of a of a
of a pound of light yeah which I guess
when prices were crazy high made sense
for people
you know
um which cut was that
it was uh it was that master cut oh yeah
yeah yeah
you know but it don't you know it didn't
like it also it was dark it wasn't very
frosty
um you know it didn't look nearly as
nice as other ones
um you know type of thing so I didn't
really I didn't really realize like what
was going on as far as
um you know
so I don't I don't know I'm not gonna
sit here and say that I'm an expert on
like when exactly triangle Kush first
made it to California
sure but I you know
um I don't I didn't realize when
when you know like when I had FlowRider
it's kind of like the same thing that
with the sour
right was that I thought I had OG Kush
yeah
I didn't realize that there was this
mystery of like however many cuts that
came out of Florida and then a bunch of
s1s and then all these different things
like all that info that like is maybe
common to us now
I had no idea back then
yeah right so it was that was the one
that I ran for any number of years
yeah right and
you know I was told by that group that
it came
um direct from Florida to the Bay
yeah
and I didn't have any reason to to
disbelieve it at that point sure you
know and you know to be honest I mean I
now now that we know way more than we
did back then
like I you know I don't know what it is
yeah
I mean like you're pretty sure that it's
not triangle though and well the reason
the only reason why I'm pretty sure it's
not triangle is because years later I
wanted to see if it was yeah and
triangle because of Ricky has a
reasonably good like chain of of
provenance sure on it in terms of there
are people you can get it from
that can trace how they got it and
direct from Ricky bringing it to
California absolutely or even sending it
to California before he moved here yeah
right yeah
um so
you know so I grew it side by side yeah
with it and it's not the same thing is
it similar yes but I mean it's what's
funny is like when you were in that era
in Southern California when when
dispensaries would have like 25
different kinds of kush they were all
kind of like variations on the theme
yeah it's like splitting hairs it really
well I mean it's it's not you know
they're not always some of them are more
earthy some of them were a little bit
more lemony you know some I mean there
was variations amongst them I just don't
think that they were massive
I think a lot of it too was was people
growing in totally different methods and
that also becoming like oh this is a
different cut than yours let's compare
the pictures totally sure and so I think
that you know I definitely think you
know you could come up with differences
but it's kind of like you know when you
see like a batch of kids or something
that obviously came from the same
parents yes and their differences
they've got some different features it's
not like they're twins or anything like
that but they're definitely all peased
from the same pod yeah and so I've grown
a ton of kush
um both due to interest and due to the
fact that it was so popular in
California for so long
um you know but it get and eventually
for me it gets hard to like keep more
than two or three or four of them
because you sort of you sort of end up
picking the ones that you like for
whatever reason
you know if you're a breeder maybe you
pick the ones you feel pass on the
traits the right way yeah you know um if
you're a grower you probably pick the
ones that you're um that you're uh you
know your your broker or whatever is
happiest with
type of thing
you know all that and so but the main
thing with the Flowrider is that I got
it as OG
um it was supposedly direct from Florida
and the person that gave it to me is the
person that the The Thin Mint accident
happened in their room yeah and so it's
just it's just the the and you know and
that and I don't think that happened for
you know a good four plus years after I
got it yeah right like because so the
Flow Rider was like
was you know it just it just so happens
that it's it's the same cut
yeah that was in there you know now the
other thing is I don't know that I've
ever actually gotten a verified that I
could be that I could be totally you
know sure of
um I don't know that I've ever gotten
like the the first cut that came from
um Matt Bubba and Josh D that they
brought to LA
correct yeah you know so I can't compare
it to that one I do think that getting
verification on that cut would be damn
near impossible you know I mean if you
talked if you talk to Josh D or whatever
like he still has the same cut since 96.
yeah
um but because of the but because of the
the money and the rap and all that other
stuff do I believe it's alive I think
it's probably alive but like how would
you tell it from one of the three or
four sfv Cuts or how would you tell it
from this or how would you tell it from
the first goat like you know I mean
there's people that are like this 92 is
guaranteed it yeah and this ghost is
guaranteed it and this sfv is guaranteed
it
right and then you grow those three
things next to each other and they're
not the same plant yeah okay well let's
keep this more to the cookies thing do
you have an uh let's go into the
Thousand what you got
yeah so I guess not so it's a good
moment to bring you in as well so Matt
obviously has been also like doing a
little recap on the major components of
the family
um this is probably a good moment to
zoom out and talk about the problem at
large like going back to that crybaby
quote of uh it gets worse the further
down you go with cookies yeah um
boy what's your take on that because I
I've kind of given my take a little bit
but your take is going to be a different
and different perspective
what's your thoughts on that in general
um
you know what I think
what I think happened
basically is I mean if we wanted to
start at the end
you know
um some Bag seed fell out of some buds
that their people were rolling up into
making joints
and thin mint was found
right and it just so happens
that once that was found
okay uh in the bay
um out of some weed that came from Mendo
you know people's you know there's
people in that group that kind of
realized they might have had something
special
right and it was kind of like cookies
was sort of like in my opinion like the
birth of the modern weed scene yeah and
what I mean by that is that like it was
It was kind of around the time that IG
was really starting up
and so you couldn't smell you couldn't
taste you couldn't smoke but you could
see yeah and it was visually I mean
you'll remember Matt think about
remember how
stunning blueberry was when those
pictures were first posted on you know
on the forums probably 10 years before
that yeah you know um the only thing you
could see was visual
and Visually it was super appealing and
so you have a bunch of why do you think
the demarcation started with Instagram
and not at the Forum stage since both
were presenting pictures and you
couldn't smell it but it does I think
you're right like there is a clear
demarcation of when things changed
because IG came about when everybody had
started getting a smartphone in their
hand yeah it's a good point instead of
being a desktop
yeah
and probably the lack of long-form like
writing as well yeah yeah and you know
and a lot of those times there was
something you know the forums had
already sort of had their heyday
and it's kind of like you had to like
search them out and find them yeah type
of thing I mean it's it's it's it's
actually not that much different than
you know some of the cookie stuff is
like
um
it's also the first era where for
decades
um you know people hid their face and
hid their involvement
and all that and IG was sort of where
people got famous by showing their face
that's correct yeah that's very true it
didn't happen a lot in the Forum and so
there was a lot of that didn't really
happen on a lot of the forums it's not
like you saw Sam's man's face
yeah it's not like you saw DJ's face
you know or you know the or any any of
the people that got you know kind of
famous back then
it was like you saw some weed pics maybe
but you also because the way how wide
the World Wide Web was back then
you had to kind of it was a little bit
more niche Niche do you think it had
more to do also like coinciding with all
the states going online and a bunch of
new Growers sure I mean when when
overgrow was going on
um there was when it you know when it
first started there was one there was
one medical State yeah
which was California yeah by the time IG
was popping there was a there was it was
the whole West Coast yeah and and times
had changed and penalties had gone way
down yeah and stuff like that you know I
mean really what and this is this isn't
a diss on him although we were making we
were joking earlier but like
you know every you know they they got
burner because of his connections to
hip-hop and stuff like that and various
people he was hustling weed to to
promote cookie yeah and he became cookie
he did because because he was the face
associated with
you know now did he have did did he have
anything to do with any of the accidents
or any of the breeding involved before
that no no but we had this received one
through 300 or one through twenty one
through eighty well we did about I think
only like 15 strains uh 15 seeds on this
funeral hunt and the number 20 was just
popping when you plan so we do have that
quote from him about breeding so look
from the very beginning
okay like and you can give and you can
maybe give these guys great credit where
you know there's a number of things that
happen with cookie one
you got to remember that at this point
Southern California Los Angeles all that
had become very famous and
semi-synonymous with Kush absolutely
right there is just like sports or
whatever else like you know Giants
Dodgers or whatever in baseball or you
know there's Regional and especially
City rivalries
you know cookie was the first like you
know cookie was was put the bay on the
map yeah absolutely they did it was it
was Bay Area it was found in the Bay
Area the people promoting it were all
from the bay it was something that
everybody in the bay would you know uh
could which you know goes kind of from
San Jose to San Francisco to Oakland to
you know it's kind of like a
conglomerate of a bunch of little towns
in a few cities
they all could get behind it yeah
yeah right and so a factor of like IG
and it was extreme like because before
before cookie you know looks weren't
really all that important in weed as
long as it worked yeah cookie really
ushered in the looks are incredibly
important
and that person and that persists to
this day
you know and a lot of breeding post
cookie became what was visually
attractive
and what people kind of found to be
visually attractive was things that
looked like cookies which is it was dead
it was Frosty it looks like I mean
what's funny is that if you look at it
visually you know if you're like oh man
it's code and the other part of it is if
you have purplish buds or you have
darker Buds and you have a bunch of
Crystal on it
it makes those that Crystal pop yeah
right it makes it more visually you know
and like really dense buds as you and I
know often they don't have the same type
of Crystal as like sour diesel yeah
because they don't have as much surface
area for all that Crystal to exist on
with all the like you know I call it
Hills and Valleys or whatever but with
all the irregularly shaped yeah if you
get a perfectly shaped rock hard nugget
the whole thing looks like it's coated
in Crystal it looks like it should be
really dank yeah
you know and then because there wasn't
that much of it it was going for high
dollar
and then Berner gave it to Wiz Khalifa
and he gave it to other hip-hop artists
and they started rapping about it and
they did a good job of making it a
cultural thing yeah for sure and then
they had a situation where they had the
whole Bay behind them because the whole
Bay
had been desperate to like have I mean
the bay was has always been a massive
conglomerate of weed hustling
yeah because it's sort of the end point
for where almost all the weed from the
triangle flowed down into by the 101.
Humboldt Trinity Mendo Sonoma all that
you get on the 101 and you go to the Bay
right
but this was the first thing that the
bay could claim yeah
and that made a big difference
I think so I would imagine so you know
and you couldn't smell it you couldn't
smoke it you couldn't you know you
couldn't see what was up with it but you
could see it and Visually it looked
incredible yeah and I think to this day
a lot of people are still breeding for
um for looks yeah I mean so yeah earlier
Matt said not so that the first
generation so to speak of cookies work
wasn't wasn't the worst with respect to
breeding but it does get seem to get
worse quote unquote once you get to the
later generations like the gelatos and
runts what is your take on the that kind
of like more recent
part of cookies
um gosh
well I'll say this
the people that made cookie famous
were not the people that made cookie
yeah right so the problem is is that you
know the problem with cookie is that the
people that ended up getting it and
hyping it and making it work they
essentially had
a cut
yeah they didn't have the parents they
didn't have the grandparents cookie had
been like a a conglomeration in my
opinion of accidents that happened over
probably a seven to ten year period
yeah right and and you know that story
is very common because you know you
trace a lot of super famous weed back to
its Origins and its bagseed
yeah right
and so whether that's sour diesel or
whether that's kush or whether that's
cookie or whatever there's bag seed and
then there's different people at
different times that had things that led
to one thing led to another thing
the thing that about cookie that made it
more difficult is that the people
involved in my opinion did not want
anyone going out there and remaking it
better than what they had
no yeah that's for damn sure it's money
from from the very beginning they had no
their interests
were in using this line to get
themselves loot make themselves famous
and build a brand yeah
yeah they weren't trying to do like
constructive breeding per se well I I
just meant in the sense that like they
didn't want anyone else out there to
recreate it
better than they were yeah and they
didn't want to give anyone credit before
them
who might have had a part in making it
you see what I'm saying so you have a
you have a loose collection of guys
that's involved in different ways
there's no contracts there's no
organization everyone's trying to make
it
like this is their shot yeah
right so
um
so the problem with cookie like I mean
I've mentioned I can't remember maybe it
was on
I can't remember whose post it was on
but I kind of view like
um you know when animal cookies came out
animal was kind of like they took thin
mint and they threw it on Kush right
yeah and it was cookie but it was cushy
and it had some potency and all that
right
the problem that they faced is that they
kept they tried to make a whole family
based on one cut yeah and so they
started inbreeding really strongly
and I think what they did is they made
mistakes in breeding early on
because they were just learning about
what they were up to
right
and they didn't know how to recover from
those
yeah it would have take knowing how to
actually breed to recover that's that
like my main thing was that yes people
made crosses but breeding's a totally
different thing well you also have to
realize too that like
at the same point in time that this was
all going on okay because there was a
number of things with cookie that were
you know or let's just say components of
that we believe are in cookie over time
yeah that just happened that were Herm
accidents yeah and in that era before
you know pre-cookie everything was still
basically males and females
yeah and her accidents
and then when they started breeding with
cookies right that's that was sort of
the beginning of the reversal era yeah
right I talked a bit about that in the
beginning about how like during my era
reversals were really looked down on but
as we got into like the mid to late
2000s even into like 2013-14
because it was a bunch of new Growers
and spray was available to buy it wasn't
as like demonized as it was during our
era so a lot of people were able to do
that and not get the pushback that we
got at the beginning if that makes sense
you know and and so they weren't really
like really what they were doing is they
had no interest in releasing accurate
information
yeah what they had interest in is
releasing things that they were going to
make a bunch of money
off the pounds of it they were going to
control who had it they were going to
get kickbacks from who had it
you know what I'm saying and they were
going to build a brand based off of it
you know
um and and so that is very different
from like our weed nerd of like oh well
how exactly did it happen yeah exactly
they had zero interest in being like oh
well it you know it fell into our laps
that doesn't sound as good right you
know and then after it fell into our
lapse we took the thin mint and we
started doing a bunch of stuff with that
one cut and they also had so many
different menial types
phenotypes well the other part of it too
is that
you know when we talk about they
right
um different people in the very small
circle that they were in had different
bits and pieces of information sure and
they weren't exactly free to share it
with each other either
no I mean there's still competition
going on because nobody wanted to get
cut out yeah
so it's not just like they were all it's
almost like with a lot of those guys
like the truth doesn't come out because
it's more like a circular firing squad
yeah
if somebody was still like up and out
you know it doesn't matter what member
and point fingers at that member and lay
out exactly what they did and didn't do
right that would might even be all true
that person could point at them and
release parts that they're not super
enthused about other people knowing it's
kind of like uh the mutually assured
destruction that we saw when Dying Breed
became terpogs from dying breed
there was a lot of you know and and so I
mean there's even a situation you know
it's like where you know if I start
mentioning names or whatever it's like
and the hard part about discussing
cookie to be frank is that
um
cooking now is uh is is a big clothing
company and uh and a you know a
multi-state an MSO a multi-state
operator yes that is very intent on when
we'd get goes fully federally legal
getting bought out by somebody huge yeah
and there's an enormous amount of money
involved in cookie
indeed you know and there's there's
people in cookie you know that are that
that are a pretty big part of like the
formation of it but maybe aren't
represented nearly as well in terms of
like stock position or whatever or you
know within the company you know for
sure like
burner had nothing to do with any of it
what but
you know but they picked him
to do what he's very good at it must
have been his looks which is promote
yeah yeah
you can you can you can't I mean he's
good at promoting things he is very good
at promoting good at hyping things up he
was good at getting the babe to be
behind him because being behind him is
being loyal to the Bay yes that's very
true you know and then as a result of
that there was other members in cookie
that got angry whenever I mean I I used
to have this running joke that people
when they went to buy cookie you know
they bought their eighth you know in the
bay at like the dispensaries or whatever
they thought that like it had been hand
watered by burner yeah hand selected and
watered and manicure they and you know
and they actually even they actually
gave him the clothing company because
they didn't want him to have the weed
makes sense but then they got angry
because a clothing company has way less
issues as far as taxes or federal
problems or anything like that and also
really well with a bunch of money
selling 150 sweatshirts yep and these
other people are stuck running you know
semi-gray area 215 era warehouses yeah
yeah and they're making cash but it's
not like you know it's it's not banked
money
like a clothing brand and then when the
money came in you know when the
investment Capital came in they wanted a
front man to promote it yeah
you know like everybody you know like
every everybody sees burner all over
cookie
and that's intentional because you don't
want to see the people behind cooking
yeah because they're you they're just
your normal old style I wouldn't even
say normal or old I remember two of them
were very young and and kind of good
looking people but they just happened to
work with the feds so they were put in
the back
yeah or or you know they were younger
people that were related to
those older people
exactly you know and so as a result of
that they had access to investment
capital
you know and so now it's all about like
the problem with cookies when you talk
about cooking there's there's multiple
distinct things there's the cookie
strain
and sherb and all that which like is
right in our wheelhouse of like weed
history and all that other type of stuff
but yeah cookie today has very little to
do with genetics
that's the main point it's a clothing
brand and it's a series of dispensaries
yeah and as you well know this isn't any
secret now but almost all of their
breeding is outsourced I still think
that most people that watch this that
are new do not know that part that
cookies proper doesn't make seeds they
have other places that make seeds White
Label seeds that they release under
cookies I mean let's put it this way
because it makes their MSO situation a
lot simpler yeah they don't even grow
weed yeah that's a good point yeah
that's the wild part they don't they
they have contracts with third parties
yeah where they provide the strains
and in some cases and they have the
right of first refusal
they don't grow weed cookies doesn't
have big indoors
or greenhouses or outsides or whatever
they contract with farmers
right what they control is the clothing
line
the store
and the mylars this is my Lark that's
right
that's how you you know like you know if
it that's how I mean that's kind of how
the runs people did it where it's like
it's not official unless it's in their
mylar
yeah they control yep right and so
touching weed makes your life a lot more
complicated
it does because that's the federally
illegal part that's the sketchy part
that's this having a clothing company
and a dispensary where you're just
you're not you know so
you're brookering you're brokering
basically yeah
yeah um can I just interject here and
say that I think this is a really good
account of the social historical uh
technological commercial conditions for
the emergence of cookies but I kind of
like to bring it back to the breeding
side of things again and say
uh another prompt from Crybaby was the
importance of uniqueness in cannabis and
I think Matt you wanted to
um raise no five Haze as a good counter
example yeah so this is a perfect time
for for NASA to delve into this a little
bit more but um
a counter example maybe of of a way of
of a strain or a project that was a
cross of a few things like cookies but
when a completely different direction
and why it went a different direction
I'd say one of the best things the best
examples for people to learn would be in
all five Haze because it was a true F1
hybrid
um despite Haze being a couple of lines
of different sativa types generally
speaking what an F1 hybrid is is taking
two distinctly different genotypes and
Crossing them and in this case Haze and
nl5 one being an Afghan one being a
typically like uh equatorial sativa type
Crossing those two brings a lot of of
diversity and not only that we found
that in a real F1 hybrids some of the
most amazing gold is found you could
talk about some of the the nl5 haze
different cuts and and how they brought
uniqueness versus what cookies is
um
Okay so
I've said this before I think but I
think that nl5 Haze is probably
by far uh the most successful and
impactful
commercially available seed line that
was ever created
why didn't why did it not end up like
cookies
um well a number of reasons
uh first
you know Neville made the hybrid sure
and so there's one person
that made the hybrid
and he had the parents for years
it was cookie like like I said earlier
cookie cookie was found in a bag seat
yeah the people that popularized cookie
didn't have the parents yeah
right exactly and it was it was
accidentally made rather than
intentionally made yeah now the other
thing about it now the other thing it's
also entirely possible I think it's
likely although it can't be proven
um I think thin mint itself was an S1
okay okay where as you were mentioning
before
um nl5 Haze was an F1 yes of two vastly
different genetics coming together
okay and so this could this could also
tie into something else which you know
we we've talked about before but Bears
repeating
um nl5 Hayes was sort of a
um because it was so wild
yeah because it was it was two totally
different things crossed together
it had a really low floor and a really
high ceiling yeah which meant that you
could find absolute junk
all the way to I mean there's still
probably eight or twelve cuts of nl5
haze that are hoarded yeah that are 30
plus years old yeah I don't think
there's another line out there where
there's as many living cuts
that are that old that are still kept
because of their value
and a major a major part of that too in
in why it differs from cookies because
you know like we're talking about
cookies you know uh gelato exists you
know sherb exists all these little
different nuances or takes on it even if
they're hybrids but with the variation
and the high floor low ceiling the nl5
haze had
you were seeing variation in breeding
again like you could take that nl5 Haze
Direction one of those directions S1 it
and still have tons of variants well
maybe maybe we should maybe we should
talk about this for a second so
cookie came about by one bag seed and
then a tiny group of people trying to
control its rise yeah and not give
people access to either the information
or even the cut to do with what they
wanted yeah that's for sure nl58 was
totally different there was people in
America that found an amazing nl5 Haze
yeah okay like say in New York or South
Florida or something and they wouldn't
share it
and so some of those people that they
that they couldn't get it from those
dudes
they just went over to Amsterdam and
they bought the exact same seed line
from Neville yeah yeah there was a seven
year period
right imagine if cookie came out
and for six or seven years after that
you could go to the breeder where they'd
found it in and bought the exact same
seed line and Hunt yourself
yeah we're not exactly sure when nl5
died
um or the the formula for nl5 haze
um ended but it seems like it ended in
somewhere in the the mid to late 90s
yeah but that literally means that there
was a seven or an eight year period
where even if you couldn't get a hold of
the cut itself because it was held on
too tight you could go buy 100 or 200 to
300 seeds
of the exact same genetics and start
hunting it yourself yeah which is how
all these phenos started happening
because they weren't all bag seeds and
f1s off one cut like happened with
cookie
right yeah they could go find full
sisters
and so there wasn't one small group that
had control over it and was like lying
about what the genetics were yeah you
could literally go by the exact same
genetics from the dude
so I think that's a major difference in
itself yeah right
and then obviously if um
if nl5 Haze is a full F1
with wide diversity in the line made by
a male and a female
like there's a lot more there's a lot as
you were saying before there's a lot
more directions you can take it
yeah then a potential S1 bag seed
yes it's a it's now not every bag seed
that that created cookies was an S1 some
of them were hybrids sure you know but
it was just a vastly different it's
almost like with cookie it's like you
know there was an intentional breeding
in the beginning and then a few years
later something hermed onto something
else and then that thing got grown for a
few years and then that thing harmed
onto something else and then that thing
got grown for a few years and then that
thing harmed and then they found thin
men out of it
yeah you know and so it's just it's just
different and so as a result of that
um
you know uh cookie uh and then you know
beyond that
I mean even after like nl5 Hayes stopped
being a thing for a second in the sense
that you couldn't get the exact seed
line
within a few years of that happening
mango Haze and Neville's Haze and Super
Silver Haze all came out and that
dominated the scene again and still to
this day like super silver haze Jack via
Amnesia Haze dominate that scene to this
day almost like cookies did over here
and they have like literally kind of
bred Amnesia in the same directions like
certainly Amnesia is amnesia no matter
what you cross to it so you know you
start looking at you start looking at
sherb or you start looking at gelato or
you start looking at
and all this different stuff and at some
point in all of that they re-cross it
directly back to the same cut yes most
cookie breeding involves one cut yes
doesn't mean they might not have
outcrossed it but once they outcross it
into something they typically hit it
back again or the outcross is usually
already a component of what they were
crossing it sells so what happened with
with you know with cookie or like let's
let's put it this way Neville because he
had the both parents and was able to
make a massive amount of seeds
he was able to take the line in all
kinds of different directions
cross it to different things and make
completely new lines out of it
right that had their own thing where
cookie all all started from basically
like one bag seat
yeah and so their their method was
crossing things back to that same thing
because it was popular and they wanted
to reiterate it over well they also they
also came into it in different way like
they never had the parents
they didn't have the parents
it might be a good point for me to ask
and it's kind of like uh
it's kind of a slightly different take
but I'd like to hear from both of you
were there any positives to come out of
cookies like from any part of it like
what what do we get
in terms of like lessons or
Expressions that are still you know
useful and could be worked with uh well
I mean I might have a different take on
this than me go ahead yeah you give or
take
um cookies made
in the weed world at least
burner [__] sherbinsky
uh Powers up
um you know
um you know everybody basically but the
guy who the accident happened in his
room yeah
um they all got extremely famous within
weed world I'm wealthy most of the time
if you mention those people to anybody
with a decent knowledge of of modern
weed history they know who you're
talking about yeah um cookies cookies
started and it's probably it you know
turn it that one cut led to one of the
largest current brands
in the Cannabis space in the United
States what are you going to say a
thousand
oh this is going to say so yeah it's
obviously benefited the individuals
involved yes but uh all the individuals
involved
cookies has a brand
um you know I won't say his real name
but um
sherbinsky has an entire brand yeah um
it's basically made their careers yeah
right and since that came out
they've made an enormous amount of money
marketing clothing
marketing you know basic hybrids and
then on top of that because cookie
got so famous and the look became so
popular Matt can speak to this a bit
an enormous amount of new breeders
decided I'm gonna try to make my own
variation on this thing yeah and so for
the next decade
at least for I would say from 2010 to
2020 easily and maybe even a little bit
more the most common hybrid in cannabis
is
cookie some kind of cookie crossed to
some kind of kush
yeah so is it charitable take framing of
what you just said that cookies
encouraged a whole bunch of people to
get into making seeds
no I don't think that's true
um well because you know so what I think
what I think happened there and this
might be a little bit of a tangent but
um you know it used to be very very
difficult to be an American Seed breeder
and have a market yeah most people
um like say take DNA or somebody like
that Americans who wanted to start a
seed company they literally up they got
a bunch of stuff from America and they
moved to Amsterdam yeah Matt to throw
people off his Trail
uh wasn't your first website dot NL yeah
I wanted people to think I was a Dutch
company just in case so
IG not only did IG explode you know uh
cookie in the sense that like because it
was so visually appealing it also gave a
lot of small breeders a way to access
customers
a way to promote their seeds away for a
bunch of small hobbyists with garages to
create a seed company and then Market
those seeds and then because in the in
the in the 2010s and on 215
and all these medical places had
happened so much
there was this huge cup era
okay of High Time starting to throw lots
of cups in California monthly cups
monthly cups in California in Colorado
and all these different places so then
all of a sudden you had a situation
where a lot of these small breeders not
only could promote themselves on IG
but they could buy a booth at one of
these cups and it would almost be like a
flea market gray area swap meet where
they could get in front of customers and
start selling their package seeds to
people
I mean Matt and I joke that probably
like 95 of today's breeders came up in
that environment sure and so what are
you doing I wouldn't say 95 I would say
five percent 95 came up in the
environment of IG that's what I mean
yeah like 95
of new breeders you know like were you
know maybe five percent was old
schoolers deciding they finally could
like do it a little bit more publicly
and not just give it to friends yeah and
95 of them were people that were like
man I can I can get on IG I have 5 000
followers I have 10 000 followers I can
announce a drop yeah I have a way to
communicate with them I have a way to
stay a little bit Anonymous I can also
get booths and go sell them directly and
so
part of Cookie's popularity was because
since cookie was the most popular thing
when this was all going on
the easiest thing for these new breeders
to do was to use cookie in their hybrids
yeah to gain popularity so it almost
went hand in hand
yeah I can see that you know like if it
had happened 10 years before it would
have been Kush and Diesel
yeah it's really interesting um
intersection I mean what about you man
like what do you see as possible
positives coming out of
cookies
so
I think like one of the biggest lessons
we have with cookies like the positive I
would take from it is learning that
there is a way where
at first it was learning a whole new
method of advertising for for people who
sold seeds we had to learn to adapt in a
whole new environment in the first place
so that in itself is a good thing
because you know in a long in a business
that lasts a long time you always have
to recreate yourself in some way shape
or form to keep people interested and to
keep your own interest right
um cookies taught me a lot about how the
market works and how the market works
when a lot of money is thrown into an
industry where there was not a ton of
money especially coming from the
American side in the Sea World there
wasn't a lot of money put into marketing
so we learned how that works and we also
learned how it works when you take a
specific line that is fairly new and run
it into the ground 90 Ways to Sunday and
where that kind of takes the whole
market and that people can be convinced
that something is new and different even
though it looks exactly the same as the
last thing that was shown now I don't
know if that's necessarily for the
better or worse but any new data points
in my mind are good even if they are
null data points or bad like negative
data points where it's like it impacts
the scene negatively
I could make a point to that too where I
could say that um
I would say in the previous era to
cookie
mostly
what drove popularity to a large degree
was
potency taste and scent
you know
um you know especially like the sour era
sour could look kind of funky and ugly
and sticky you know it could have a lot
of stick you know a lot of stent could
be stemi uh all that and people would
crack open the bag and get a whiff of
that nose and look up and say this will
work yep right
um
you know Kush became popular because it
was very potent yeah it had a
distinctive gassy type nose
that you could sort of roll around in
your mouth after you hit it right
a lot of people when they first
experience Kush
and they'd smoke it a little and then
they'd be they'd realize that the
aftertaste they could sort of like roll
around on their tongue yeah and it was
very potent and it was it got you it got
you more stoned than a lot of the stuff
that was around it at the time it was
very cerebral High you know narcotic and
so what cookies did
um is cookies which in my opinion still
holds today
um today it's it's about uh testing and
looks yeah
those are the top two primary
considerations for breeding you know
if you compare it to the Barbie era for
women during a certain era women kind of
changed the way that beauty looked from
the era in the 60s when Barbie or 50s
when Barbie popped up women were
expected to kind of have this kind of
figure in form and people got used to
seeing this as what beauty is right and
I think this kind of impacted what weed
became in that cookies had a very
specific look and this became what was
beautiful in cannabis which didn't
necessarily represent the high or any of
those other things but image is what was
important just like with the Barbie era
and what we ended up was this is what
most people's concept of beauty is in
weed and what they expect it to look
like purple
extremely resonance like lots of resin
glands and stocks
and you know dense dense purple nuggetry
you know like yeah
and that's what yes well and bracks and
that's what people expect out of beauty
of cannabis it's it's defined it in a
way that it's very hard to change the
Market's idea of what real beauty is in
cannabis in the high
I mean the other part of it too is that
you know it also sort of like brought
along
a little bit of the Primacy of indoor
because most of the cookie stuff was
being grown in indoor grows in
warehouses in the bay yeah and people
would try to take it and like put it
outside or put it in depth or put it in
full sun and it grew like crap yeah
you know but for someone that was
growing a bunch of two foot tall plants
on rockwool yeah you know it worked and
so I think what happened is is that
because those people were interested in
in branding and marketing and all that
they were perfectly fine with the look
like outpacing the effect oh yeah and
once they lost the effect they didn't
really have the skill set because that's
not who they were to find it again like
there's there was a potential if things
had gone a slightly different way where
they probably they might have been able
to like marry that look with a good
effect
but they just lost it early on they lost
the effect of OG Kush which was the best
you know and they so they lost that
effect
the look was easy to find but once you
know as anybody knows if you start
picking your winners based on testing
and looks
you'll quickly get to like a very kind
of bland Bud yeah
so this is this is a good moment I think
to to say um in the last in the first
cookies episode that YouTube did
um you had a little thought experiment
that was what can you do with cookies as
a hypothetical breeding project right
and I think what would be cool for now
um for today's episode is how would you
what a possible reconstructions of it
um
they all have very different opinions
than Matt so Matt can go first
okay so if I was going to be be
reworking something very purple
with lots of
stocks that had oil filled heads which
to me is super important and a lot of
people don't realize that in the cookie
stuff like it's a lot of of stocks but
not a lot of oil in the in the heads
which is why you don't get super terpy
cookie stuff in my opinion like you just
don't so I would choose something that
would be purple
and I mean as a man that loves purple
myself I lean towards a potent blueberry
if I were going to go this direction I
would want to terpy a good Afghani blue
type to to take that over and maybe
maybe uh even in the direction of let's
say a Bubba blueberry would even be a
better direction for me and something
that I could take it 100 different
directions keep breeding it and
outcrossing it and not have the inbred
nature even though blueberry does have
some inbred nature to it I would use
blue bonnet because I already know that
doesn't and kind of cheat that way and
go up and make a uh a very dense potent
purple plant with tons of turfs that's
how I'd redo it I mean I knew you were
going to say that and so I'm gonna ask
you what if you had to do it without the
blue oh Jesus so
I would probably go
oh I would go deep chunk I would take it
to the Deep chunk route look at myself I
know because deep chunk deep chunk is
not terpy and it's notoriously dominant
in what you cross it to
but I've also crossed into things that
it is dominated by and only passes its
resin production with with those glands
so I would go deep chunk cross to Tom
Hill says
because I've actually seen it done and
it looks like cookies and it's kind of
another cheat nice that entire last
minute might have just been to just to
make Tom mad at him so we'll see what
happens
yeah what Tom's work needs is is to turn
it permanently purple that's what he
wants that's what he said that's what he
that's what he's after is this beautiful
his whole career if he could just take
his life work and make it purple for him
he would just negative fall over and die
yep I I would say I mean I'll have a
two-part thing to it one
is that because I come from a very
different world than that
uh in the in the 90s
we would have we would have loved cookie
okay because when you're growing gorilla
and you're growing shade grown weed
that doesn't get full sun and you're
hiding it in manzanita's and stuff like
that a strain that gets dense
a strain that doesn't need very much
light to get dense
um cookies is kind of famous for like
not liking sun and not liking food yeah
right so
it would it would like a cookie type
line would be amazing if we ever had to
go back to the manzanitas because it
would yield really well
it likes being shade grown yeah I mean
there was people that got cookies early
on that used to like grow tables of
something else and then on the outskirts
of that table where there was only
partial light they would load it down
with cookies yeah because it would still
yield really well
and they started getting amazing yields
per light because cookies could kind of
grow in half shade yeah so make sense a
strain that would do really well like
that and stay short and and dense up and
look really pretty that you could grow
like in not ideal conditions
we would have loved back then
as far as like where what you could do
with it now
how would you recreate it no recreate
what would be the not not so cookies
what would be the not so cookies yeah
how would you make a purple dense well I
mean that could be maybe giving up some
of the
some of the secret sauce or whatever of
what was in it
um but I think if you were going to
remake it
you know
um the the idea would be to try to keep
it somewhat wide
right so you know I mean
you know you add cushion
right so you'd add some type of kush
I would try to go with one of the ones
that we think of as like an original
Kush like the Flow Rider or the TK or
you know if you could figure out which
one was the actual one that Josh D
brought out just because it wouldn't be
necessarily an S1 it would be a hybrid
sure right so for instance to expand on
that for a second a lot of people when
they s one'd a lot of kush cuts
the Kush cuts that ended up being nice
in those s1s kind of looked exactly like
the mother cut yeah because those cuts
were already bag seats and then
when you
reverse like one of the hybrids say like
the T like What CSI did with the TK
right
um all of a sudden you get a y a much
wider variety of phenotypes that pop out
of it yeah right it's not just it the
good ones look exactly like the mom yeah
right and so I guess what I'm saying in
a long-winded way is I would try to
create create it without bottlenecking
it
because I think that's what ended up
happening to it is it got bottlenecked
way too early
that's cheating yeah what would you
recreate it with with without using the
same components but it's hard because I
mean you said you said it's hard you you
know you mentioned that you might cross
it like you know I I can see why you use
deep chunk take an adventure because
you're trying to figure something short
and dense that isn't Kush and isn't bad
I almost went purple number one and
really [__] it up so
you know I mean and then you know you
have a situation where like you know I
mean it it kind of has
it has some you know how do you remake
it without using Kush without using any
of like the purple strains that were
famous you don't even have to make it
smell the same but something that would
actually it doesn't even necessarily
have to smell taste or at the same
height because that's not what people
even judge cookies on anyways an imagery
how would you make something appear the
same what what route would you take
without using the same components
without using the same component I could
hit you upside the head with an obvious
purple right now you could use it's a
purple afghan
I mean
the thing about it is is that
is you know if you wanted to look the
way that it looks
you know I mean
[Applause]
everything I think of I'm like oh it's
kind of related to it in some way well
no not not just
not necessarily because like assume that
it is made with what they say it's made
with just Urkel and GDP and all that
you know
um
you know we there's actually
I think I'm
I think I had something to say and then
it got like
huh we broke the robot we broke it we
broke the robot I mean so I was thinking
you'd go Mendo perps cross to the Maui
or something like that well
that
but the problem is is that uh at least
when it comes to certain certain
branches of the family I think that
that's in there already
yeah but we haven't talked about that at
all we weren't going to talk about it so
I think you know because the problem is
see the the biggest issue with cookie is
that because everybody tries to muddy
the waters on what's in it
it's very difficult to get a straight
answer out of any of them even if you've
known some of them a really long time
sure right and what they're going to do
is if you if you start talking
definitively about what you think is in
there they're going to jump on the parts
that they that might be a little bit off
that they disagree with obviously that
they disagree with and then use that to
discredit the whole thing you know and
part of the reason why Matt's tried to
get me to talk about cookie a lot and I
have been hesitant to
um simply because
um you know like I said there's a branch
of cookie that wants to be a
multi-billion dollar corporation that
gets gobbled up by somebody huge and all
these people get payouts
so it's really difficult to discuss
cookie
right because there's that element to it
sure it's not just you're not just gonna
like anger
a few people
no and I mean I think this whole episode
is going to be that and as Matt and is
Matt well knows you know even even on
small people or like you know when I say
small I mean like not smaller compared
to like the cookie monolith or whatever
if Matt Matt's you know a lot of the
reason why Matt gets black in public is
because he outs somebody's truth and
then they feel like that
well it might be true it's also
affecting their pocketbook sure so the
the way that it doesn't affect their
pocketbook is by making everybody know
that Matt Ryan is a total scumbag and
you shouldn't believe anything that
comes out of his mouth
we have to discredit the messenger
right at all costs yeah and this is like
80 of your online battles yeah and it's
probably gonna be this episode is going
to definitely ignite it is you
saying something that is generally well
known
amongst the small group of in the know
type people in the Cannabis Community
but you know maybe isn't well known to
the larger Community yeah right and like
even though it might be well known
within a few thousand people they don't
want the larger Canada Community to hear
that correct yeah so then they attack
you like crazy
yeah you know you've seen this recently
yourself like oh yeah it's not it makes
it difficult and you know and and some
of these people have deeper pockets and
more political power
or I just have all the time in the world
to be demons I mean I I will say
that what's funny about it and I
mentioned it before but like literally
the person who the thin mint accident
happened in their room is probably the
least famous cookie person
yeah yeah I'd say so
you know it's probably the least yeah
I can yeah and I can see why you know
the stories always come back to this
because
cookies
embodies a lot of what the industry is
going through as a whole it is typifies
some of the current inclinations right
of the industry for better or worse
yeah big time and and the Mystery of
strains uh it definitely helps with that
because mystery drives sales and there
is some mystery to cookies like there is
disagreements between what it is and
what people say it is I mean there's a
thing I posted on my Ig a while back
it's like a New Yorker uh cartoon
and they were talking about history
um you know and I'm paraphrasing here
but there's a guy that's like oh I
remember it differently in a way that
paints me in a positive light and gives
me the credit yeah
right and so that's the thing that Matt
and I run into all the time with talking
wheat history is the vast majority of
people
in weed
are interested in history that makes
them look good and buttresses their
pocketbook yeah
or
you know even with Old-Timers whose
history is decades ago
their interest in the history is how can
it benefit me today right now and in the
future yeah there's a lot of that and
you start you get that you get these
conversations that go on and the first
conversation is pretty open and forward
and then the next couple once they
realize that there's some money or some
rep to be made
all of a sudden the story starts
changing and people start getting huffy
and angry about stuff
and how dare how dare you bring up that
I contradicted myself a month before on
the episode that we talked about it yeah
this this is what I'm currently
promoting yeah
so it's like I could you know do I know
the entire story inside and out with all
details no no but I'm not even sure the
core people know the entire story inside
and out because they all hit hid parts
of it from one another intentionally
yeah
right and so everybody has pieces like
for instance you know the the guy that
you know the accident happened in he's
been trying to recreate it using pieces
that the other people didn't have or
didn't know about yeah
because different people got brought in
at different times
you know and it is I start talking about
the truth
and there's like big brands
that are all going to be all pissed off
at me oh yeah yeah and like and and
they're investors what do their
investors want return on their
investment
Roi baby you know what do the people
want you know I mean they want to be
rich and famous and have money yeah I
mean Matt and I joke you know but this
is very much this is very much a cookie
phenomenon where you know most real
breeders
are somewhat anti-social
maybe you have a touch of the Chisholm
yeah don't like to be that public
and um you know
and the cookie era brought in uh weed
celebrity yeah where all of a sudden it
became very important where some of
these guys are they're at an art gallery
in LA
they're flying out to New York they're
small they're smoking joints dressed to
the nines
yeah right they're hiring photographers
to literally make them look good and
sexy and cool while they're checking out
their plants I don't even know how you
afford that but yeah they do that a lot
they turn they turn going to the Garden
into a photo op
yeah
yeah they go to their friends Gardens
that they don't even own
and they could look like a photo op that
they're checking on their plants this is
true and Matt's laughing about it but
like one of the things that
if you start getting photographed in LA
and then San Diego and in New York and
flying around and at all these
conferences and doing all this stuff all
the time
it's very obvious
you're not actually growing to Growers
it's very obvious you're the Growers
it's very obvious because in order to do
a good job you are married you I I don't
know any of us who are able to take a
vacation for more than two days without
freaking out like it just it's what it
is it's the Life
part of it and so it's like it's not
yeah it's not like you can't leave ever
or like have some friends you know it's
not like you can't time it
to where like you you can get a free
week or a free 10 days or something like
that here or there yeah but what
happened is is that
a lot of these guys are the front man
they are the promotion wing of this
conglomerate
right and they hire
out the work yeah so that gives them the
freedom
to be wearing a cool hat and to catch
the smoke going around their face just
so as they're standing outside the club
you know and they're touring you know a
lot of times they'll hook up with
friends to go tour facilities
and never mention it's not their
facility
yeah and so it gives people the sense
that these guys have big things going on
all over the place well yeah girls let
let them put e-cigarettes in their in
their bum hole and and make ads out of
them I mean it just it's what it what it
is is that weed really wasn't ready for
modern marketing techniques no it was
so we were extremely susceptible
to very basic modern marketing
techniques and since there wasn't any
celebrities
we were very susceptible to all of these
sort of new school celebrities and the
way that you become a celebrity in weed
is by being associated or an OG that
just so happened to be near some strain
that became famous in my opinion yeah
that's the classic way to become famous
and oftentimes the person that speaks up
publicly about it
becomes the most well-known
even if they just got the cut relatively
early it had nothing to do with it oh
yeah
you know I mean going back think about
think about like how how much I mean
this might get people this might get him
mad at me or whatever but I don't care
like think about how intent Sam gunkman
was of being on all of the early forums
and battling so that his view on what
happened was the view oh yeah for sure
and it wasn't like there was four or
five other dudes that were all there
that were competing with him no So
eventually when you repeat something
like that over and over and over and
over again
it gets pushed into the fabric of the
tail yes it's very hard to dislodge
yeah it's like a turn to punch bowl just
keeps popping back up you know and and
so you know what you know but it it's
one of those things where now back then
he didn't show his face
and he would have different monikers on
different on on different forums
yeah but everybody knew you know you
know not everybody we knew yeah you know
right not every I mean I mean that's
what we were talking about it earlier
but like there's a lot of stuff that's
fairly common knowledge
within a very a relatively small group
of wheat insiders yeah that the public
is totally ignorant of and that's that's
kind of why I wanted to do this episode
today because like a lot of the people
coming in don't understand why we have
the take on cookies being just inbred
garbage and why like when new seed
makers and I definitely specify the
difference between breeders and Seed
makers because there's a major
difference when new seed makers like
come to me and they're like hey check
out this [__] Forum crossed OG I'm
doing this is breaking this is gonna
break new ground and I I just don't have
a good response for them and sometimes
I'm just like man maybe you should try
something different because that's been
done A Hundred Ways to Sunday and they
don't get it I I mean I don't you know I
get hesitant to mention names on here
because inevitably like it'll be a 15
second clip that gets cut out in the
personal oh yeah PM's all angry but you
know being that cookies and Kush has
been Blended by
lots and lots and lots of different
people
it is very unlikely that by blending
these things you're going to come up
with something truly new and unique
exactly we have this running joke on the
Discord where like you know we'll post
pictures of that new new yes and it
looks like the same ultra dense frosted
purplish cookie type weed that we've
been seeing for the better part of the
last 14 years I mean to me it doesn't
matter if you call it jealousy if you
call it cookies if you call it whatever
cheetah piss whatever name they have for
it today it's always some form of inbred
in crossed cookies maybe with a single
outcross somewhere in there to try to
give it that fact of it it just doesn't
I mean I'll throw something else out
there for a second you know
um and maybe this is controversial or
whatnot but I actually respect
okay
burner and cookie
um going to going and trying to work
with our buddy Bodhi
and I'll tell you why okay
the reason is
that that I is because
that stuff is long overdue
yeah
for someone to take it
and to take it in a totally different
direction
yeah they've already done the seed
junkie they've already done the the the
the the Chris compound they've already
done as many variations on the theme as
you can yeah you can have other breeders
out there being like I'm gonna cross
cherry pie to Kush but not this kush
yeah exactly yeah you know and so you
know like I mean they didn't really do
it but like really what what you know
what cookies needs is like they can be
like hey Bodhi cross it to this weird
Cambodian you have yeah
way different you know what we want out
of this cookie we want the cookie to
like bring down the flowering time and
add some density to this larfy ass
[__] you know what I'm saying and
take it from 18 weeks to 12.
like that's what we're looking for
cookie needs to go in a totally
different direction
even if
that direction is risky yeah right
because you think that the corporation
itself has actually recognized this
properly
well the problem that they faced is that
is is that body and cookie are such
different
pieces of the of the canopy that both
fan bases were sort of insulted that the
other one worked with the other one yeah
like it didn't go over well you know as
soon as they announced the as soon as
they announced the [__] like our homie
got mad Flack yeah burner had to turn
off comments you know it was basically
like you know Luke Skywalker being like
I'm in a bond with the Empire but I'm
not going to try to change them
at all I'm not gonna try to like save my
dad or anything like that I just really
like like they've won
so I might as well hitch my horse to
that guinea and go with it right and so
it didn't go over very well but
you know it's like if you want something
that's not same same
right because it's almost like if I
wanted to take it like in a musical
Direction
what cookie needs is Cookie needs to go
in a totally different genre Direction
yeah right like think about like every
music thing something comes out with
music that's new and unique
fast forward 10 or 15 years and there's
a million bands making slight variations
on the same theme yeah but it's not new
it's the same well-traveled [__] they're
just trying to extract more money and
then eventually the kids are like this
isn't cool and they move on to something
else and then they make dubstep and ruin
it all
well I mean if if you want to look at it
and I don't know if you I've used this
example a bunch privately but I think
one of the most important bands in
America and like in my lifetime in
America was Nirvana oh Jesus no no check
it out dude because I'm a little bit
older than you all right and a lot older
before Nirvana came out everything in
pop everything in rock and everything on
the radio and everything on MTV was
poison
Def Leppard warrant Winger enough's
enough hair bands out the wazoo
right that was all it was Cinderella
you know Bon Jovi
right like great white shark
yeah striper yeah Winger warrant
you know and they're all variations on
the same theme and then Nirvana comes
out and every single one of those
[__] lost their job except for
Bon Jovi
and maybe one other slash they literally
like guns and roses and Bon Jovi
survived yeah everybody else died
yeah they were like this isn't cool
anymore Motley Crew can't forget Motley
Crue they did survive something modeling
crew survived okay but what I'm saying
is it went from literally dozens upon
dozens of bands that were basically
variations on the same theme
to two or three surviving and the entire
90s post Nirvana was different musically
yeah I get yeah so you can not like them
but it was like after Nirvana
every music executive went to Seattle
and signed every single band they could
find and everything after sounded like
Eddie Vedder
but they did right like because they
realized that like the the mood had
shifted yeah
you weren't going to be able to get a
big hair band in acid wash jeans and an
entire bottle of Aquanet playing a huge
heart-shaped guitar yeah and you would
have a rocking tune and then a power
ballad
you know like that formula was done yeah
they needed a new formula
speaking of new formulas I wanted to get
into this before we like totally forget
it let me see how I bring it back but
but hold just one second let me let me
just finish that thought so what cookies
needs okay is cookies absolutely needs
to step out of its comfort zone
and be like what are the qualities in
this weed that we could add on to
totally different weed
that would then be the sum of its parts
because or better than the sum of its
parts because for the last 14 years
they've been inbreeding and trying to
create various variations on the same
theme
and now it's all cookies it's all gelato
it's all runs which is cookies in July
it's all just it's all the same
incestuous family yeah and a million
different names attached to it right and
that's going to fade
right so what people need to do is they
need to take the useful parts of cookie
and be like genetically what can we add
like because cookies is so dense maybe
we can add it to like some really larfy
stuff and like solidify it a little bit
maybe we can add it to this maybe we can
do this with it like they need to step
out of their box they're not going to be
able to keep just rebranding the same
weed for the next 20 years
I don't know exactly when people are
going to move on from cookie but they
will
because they've moved on from every
other fad or phase that we've ever had
you know what I'm saying yeah yeah for
sure I mean imagine if imagine if like
we were still listening to warrant
yeah some people do it's horrible right
but it's like but most people that
listen to it it's like that's what they
were listening to when they were in
their teens in their 20s and it just
reminds them of their youth that's true
right it's like that's kind of how music
goes it becomes like you know like it
becomes for old people yeah what are the
new kids into
right
so taking that
uncsi have been working on some things
and some of them some of them I've been
working on with like the F1 derp stuff
we've been trying to go in and figure
out some things with the F1 dirt because
it was so
lauded by some and then some just
basically said it didn't exist we wanted
to see what happens when you cross this
to your Flo Rida OG cut so he took that
and you guys crossed it and we're gonna
see what comes from that we also have
the 56 day headband cut across two the
F1 derb to see how that direction goes
with some kind of headband derb but
mainly with uncsi you had given him your
your La Kush Headband cut and we've
talked about it you know I think there's
a whole episode maybe even on it
um but if you want to talk about some of
these crosses and how it'll cross to say
the Bubba Kush the different Thames the
bubble gum can you take a second to go
over a few of these
sure
um I mean just so just so people know
um I've been sharing some of my
um you know CSI is so prolific that I've
been sharing some of my cuts with him
um and then we've been doing some
um you know some intentional breeding
and then just like with every other
breeding you throw in some other stuff
in there that you think will work well
sure right but so it's it's a mix of
like you know making some cool seeds but
it's also a mix of of like well I wonder
can we recreate certain things right so
as people as people know or don't know
um the 56 uh which a lot of people don't
call it that a lot of people just call
it straight headband or the murder cat
but it's basic story is that when Kush
was really tightly controlled and worth
a lot of money in SoCal there was this
cut
and there was because it was worth so
much money and because La is La there
was some violence around this cut and it
ended up going to the Bay
and they wanted to like work with it in
the bay but
they didn't want to bring a bunch of
heat that was occurring in Southern
California up to them yeah so they
decided to rename it headband
to throw people off the trail
some people called it the 56 because it
was done in roughly eight weeks so it's
it's kind of one of those cuts that a
lot of people know as headband
um but it you know it was it was one of
you know now you ask different people
you know what it is and they'll be like
oh well it was the Kush
and that's why people get so upset at it
I will say that while it doesn't have my
favorite Kush flavor
it is by far the most potent Kush cut I
know of yeah it's very good very good
you know I got it in 06.
um there's other people that have it
that got it from basically the same crew
but it's floated around
um different people call it different
things one of Matt's buddies has it
there's a few other people that have had
it and worked with it a little bit
um but
it is uh it is a really good extremely
potent some people find it too potent to
smoke yeah which I know sounds like a
lie but it does it has this thing which
is strange for an Indica but uh Matt
experiences this sometimes it gives
people extreme anxiety oh yeah it's
called The Fear the [__] you know it
gets people high enough that they get
nervous yeah
um so you know the uh so we have that um
that was across the F1 derb we have the
flow right OG cross to the F1 derb in
the list so those are basically what
that is is that
um you know since the Flow Rider I know
for sure it's the it's the cushion
cookie yeah because of when and who I
got it from and what happened after that
right so the the Flow Rider across the
F1 derb is sort of like an attempt to
like mix some of the
um
some of the earlier generations of
strains that led to cookie yeah maybe
it's not the exact claimed generation
that claimed lineage to see if it really
pans out yeah you know or it's in you
know and it's it's a little bit more
it's an attempt to do some intentional
work
where you get a where you get a chunk of
seeds that isn't just like one bag seed
yeah and it's it's a way to look at
I know nfcsi argues me on this all the
time but really it is a way to check out
the parentage whether he likes David or
not you can see the expressions and and
traits of parents in those lines so
technically you can see what the the
sisters and brothers would look like
yeah I mean so I I will say that you
know I mean I could I could explain some
of it the F1 derb
is is the way that it was named and what
it is and how it all works is it's been
created intentionally mysterious yeah
it's it was kind of the secret sauce
that they didn't really want to let out
what was part of it yeah right and so
um you know that could be a way to get
some cookie-like stuff
and and see what's going on you know now
what's cool about the F1 derb is that it
has color and it has Terps right and it
has some unusual stuff like that going
on hopefully by Crossing it to the um to
the float to the Flow Rider into the 56
you'd get some potency
you know and some of that like dink dink
dink dink dink classic look to it so
we'll you know so we'll see we'll we'll
see what happens with that the 56 is at
the very least very early or the or one
of the earliest Kush cuts to come out of
La yeah and the Flow Rider is you know
it's it's it's another one of my
favorites and it's another early one and
it and it uh it's it's definitely the
one in cookie
uh all right uh how about your your La
Kush Bubba Kush the headband publication
uh you know the LA like I've I've talked
about it intensely
um it's one of my favorite diesel cuts
so
um what the bubble would probably add is
it would probably shorten up the
flowering time uh a lot of times some of
these hybrids that people are running of
the LA they they can run 10 11 12 13
weeks sometimes yep
um and so by Crossing it to Bubba you're
Crossing it to something that's potent
um and it would hopefully uh maybe add a
little density maybe shorten the
um the flowering time
um and both cuts are pretty potent in
different ways on their own
um we have we have one that we've seen
uh quite a bit of which is the Indiana
bubble gum reversed onto your La Kush
yeah I mean uh the Indiana bubble gum
it's kind of a weird one in the sense
that it smells strongly of bubble gum
but the I would say it's pretty fair to
say that the taste doesn't translate
yeah and the hybrids tend to to not be
as pink bubble gummy depending on what
you cross it no but the the main thing
about the bubble gum that's really nice
is it seems to be
um it's a really good indoor and outdoor
plant it's extremely resistant to mold
yeah and just the way that it Stacks
nugs on itself and the way that it its
structure it's it's you know both in
branching and buds
um as far as a production plant goes
it's a it's a big winner it's a killer
production and so hopefully uh what it
would do is it would make the the LA a
little bit more into a production plant
but you would get some of those Terps
and some of that weird Zippy high that
comes along with the um the LA yeah
um so then we get into let's let's just
put these all in one kind of category
even though it's three different cuts
that may not even be sisters chem D cam
number one and the dog m91
well
um
I'll start with d
because uh it's been grown out a lot
that's been out it was so nice I loved
it and you guys right
um that makes me happy that a lot of a
lot of people have tagged me and stuff
or sent me or you know sent me uh Tales
or pictures of their experiences with it
yeah um they're two of my favorite cuts
um and it seems like
it produces a whole bunch of gassy
highly potent plants that have a decent
amount of variety within them yeah
um I would say you know I would say
Terps you know gas gassy type
um you know somewhat a little bit skunky
Terps tend to come out quite a bit and
potency seems to be very common to find
which isn't surprising because they're
two of my favorite smokes
um and uh so that one we've seen
actually quite a bit of and I'm pretty
stoked on it yeah how about the chem one
the chem one I'm curious about that I
think people would find interesting
because it's it's by far
the least circulated surviving count
yeah it never went very far
um it is a 12 to 13 week very sativa
looking
um
you know uh very sativa looking long
Spears big Spears chunky takes a long
time 12 13 weeks that type of thing and
so by Crossing it to the LA which also
takes you know anywhere from 10 to 11
weeks easily you're probably going to
get a big stretchy long flowering plant
with a good amount of potency yeah you
know and it's it's most people don't get
to try the chem one very much so it's
kind of uncirculated in uh to a large
degree
you know so
um
that's kind of that one I think okay and
the the dog 91 Kim
you know
um the dog is pretty famous for making
things look like itself
um
I would make some I would expect some
phenos that look dog-like to some degree
um but it also is one of the most
consistent things that passes potency
and the LA is is probably in my top five
as far as potent effects
so that's what I can't I can't easily
imagine this one yeah so and and but
they have very different potent effects
uh La kind of has like this zippy
somewhat uncomfortable like sometimes
confusing or slightly nervous Buzz yeah
where the 91 has like a very warm
relaxing energetic Buzz so we'll see how
that one combines
Mendo perps crossed to your headband now
this is a very not so cross that is very
I mean both of those things I've had for
uh a couple of decades
um so they're two crosses of two of my
oldest uh oldest longest held things
um I would expect that one would be
extremely variable yeah the Mendo perps
itself has a very wide variation even
within the s1s yeah um so I would expect
a wide variety of colors
um what Mendo perps has in Spades is
terpenes of a wide variety of types and
and a wide variety of different colors
and the LA has potency and
um is very diesel like so I would also
add that there's a good chance if you
grow out enough of these seeds that you
can find what we people would classify
as skunk skunk because inside the Mendo
purpose s1's at about a 10 range that
expression is in there they're skunk and
about a 10 range they're skunk and
cushiness yeah and Mendo P
um out of anything we've mentioned so
far I think that one might have the
widest
phenotypes you know but within it you
could probably find some real gems
Obama kush a famous cut up in Oregon and
Humboldt area
Obama kush is Bubba Kush by Mendo P yeah
so it probably won't be as crazy wide as
the thing we just talked about
um but it'll probably do a you know it's
it's you could probably take my comments
about La by
um by Bubba and la by purple and sort of
combine them yeah really and it in
itself is a hybrid I would expect
um you know the Bubba kind of breeds
like Bubba
you know
um you know but boy a lot of purple
Bubba diesel really yeah purple Bubba
purple Bubba diesel would be a good way
to look at it and the crazy thing about
Meadow perps I will say is that it's not
just perps when you throw up the s1s you
see everything from black to purple to
Lavender to burgundy to Green
um it has a lot of different you know
like when I say burgundy there's some
ones that are straight red yeah like
very red so
um who knows what kind of looks could
get mixed into there
and the last but not least certainly not
least is the the headband triangle which
has also been grown out of time and I
smoked a lot of them
yeah that one
um I people have sent me stuff of that I
you know not not like I don't think I've
gotten any actual samples but pictures
and various things it's a super Sour OG
it's you know uh it's that's basically
going to be a like a you know yeah a
Sour Kush yeah
in a way you know but it's probably a
Sour Kush that's made out of
um you know the triangle has kind of a
wider genetic base than a lot of cushes
do
um and the LA is probably a different
sour than most people are used to
smoking so it's probably a different
take on those flavors yeah and and I was
like sour ogs I I put those up there
with blueberry as as probably my top
favorite smokes of something I can smoke
all the time I tend granted sour and OG
combined in many different ways but I
tend to like most sour ogis that I've
come across as far as the hive yeah I
mean it's two of the you know the it's
the two lines that were the most famous
in terms of like fads prior to cookie
probably yeah um the sour and the and
the OG era sort of overlapped
if you were
um you know who knows how many different
hybrids we would have gotten of all that
stuff if it would have been during the
prime of the reversal era yeah for sure
you know because it's Prime was a little
bit before that didn't mean it still
didn't happen on occasion yeah um you
know but
but uh but you know huh go ahead on this
note I was just curious um you know
y'all talked about the 56th day is that
one hard to reverse and would it be
interesting to see the LA and the 56
yeah all ogs are hard to reverse and all
diesels are hard to reverse it just is
what it is like pure OG's OG types that
are very lanky
I mean that's why that's why
thousand-fold you don't see on the
market
um a bunch of of diesel type s1s
yeah because often it fails or people
don't get what they consider to be a
sellable amount of seed a commercially
viable yeah yeah you know it's like
they're like oh I went through this
whole I have to do it and I got 200
seeds
and I actually don't want to sell any of
them because I just went through all
that effort and I want to see what's in
them or if you wanted to sell them to
make your money back you'd have to sell
them at 500 a pack and people just slip
when you do that like it's yeah it
doesn't work and you know a lot of times
I'll interject this too what also drove
a lot of the early
um reversal seed sales uh when the thing
boomed like I was talking about maybe an
hour ago on the show is
people couldn't get a hold of uh
certain cookie Cuts or the Skittles Cuts
or this cut or that cut you know so
people were able to reverse them and
sell s1s and sell hybrids
and sell them for a lot per pack because
it was the only way you could get access
to the genetics
yeah
yeah I mean think about like when think
about Matt when Dying Breed first was
selling at EC and nobody could get a
hold of Skittles
right no they were selling literally
everything that they could cross the
Skittles for three to five hundred three
six hundred a pack
yeah but they wouldn't have been able to
do that if people would have been able
to get the cut itself exactly exactly
you know so it's like so it doesn't he
talked enough just serious I was gonna
say I only brought it up because I think
you were in the chat yesterday as well
not so when someone was like oh why have
why isn't it like an LA sour I'm like uh
think historically those two have not
been able to be reversed for you know
yeah I mean even uh like take CSI
um all the s all the seeds of TK that he
sold were his third try yeah he
completely failed the first two times
and even the third try was a failure by
his standards he got about 10 percent
maybe 15 of the amount of seeds that he
would normally want to get from a
project like that and now one thing I
keep pointing out and I want to want to
stress on this was that these projects
that you guys worked on
they weren't individ they weren't done
all at once they were each of those
reversals was done individually at
different spots so this is a project
done over years and lots of space and
lots of time it's not just like a hit
him one and done
project it's it's there's a lot of time
and energy put into this stuff so mad
props on that and I'm still profoundly
available able to make it available and
uh we're going to start the drop on
Friday at 4 P.M for patreon uh Pacific
and uh on June 23rd and for everyone
else 8 P.M if there's anything left
because they are limited
and I wanted to get that in I'll say one
more thing too is uh
when it comes to breeding projects that
I'm involved in
um I I don't know I would say that I
lean much more towards
things that interest me or things that I
think people might be able to take into
an interesting Direction yeah rather
than like what's very popular in the
moment and I think might just sell out
really fast yeah you know and so as a
result of that you know like I'm always
looking for stuff that people could take
in a new and different direction and
especially mostly the primary thing is
like hopefully stuff that people will
like to smoke yeah effect
the effect very much so
I don't think you have any problems with
this drop with that yeah no definitely
not
is there anything else we wanted to get
in that we had written down thousand or
is this a route no I think we're more or
less there all right is there anything
else you wanted to get in not so it's
been a few weeks since we've had you
glad to see you again
so second but we're gonna put him back
in until we reach 10K so if you want to
see him and keep seeing them subscribe
I'll be back I mean it is I will say
that
um you know it is one of the things
about doing content that Matt and I have
learned is that when you start doing
weekly content
like anything else It's a Grind always
and you're trying you know you know it's
like you've got x amount of subjects you
find interesting
and then you get into this mode of like
well what do people want to talk about
what do people want to hear about what's
new right
um and you know talking how we talk
about Canon history and trying to bring
out truth
um sometimes it causes ripples in the
force absolutely you know and um I Matt
has
you know
um I generally speaking avoid most of
the ripples Matt is the one that gets
crashed by the waves so to speak yeah
but we did some stuff recently where I
bore the full brunt of said ripples yeah
and you know it it's not as easy
um or painless even
to talk about all these different
subjects there's a a wider amount of
people out there who just want to hear
truth
you know or they want to hear versions
of stories or this or that or whatever
else
and I think we do Matt and I think it's
really important to get that kind of
stuff out there
but you're always dancing this line
about like
you know what's public what's private
what's yeah you know what's what's
appropriate to be said
you know
um you know what history is pertinent
and what's more salacious yeah you know
yeah and then you get people that want
to just drive the narrative in a way
that is what we cut what we consider to
be inaccurate but benefits them
yeah and so we fight against pushback
yeah
well we both you know we appreciate you
both very much and I think over time it
becomes more and more obvious to people
um just how complex
um and scary uh some of these politics
can get what I will say in addition to
that
is that for all the bull for all the
bull
it does make me think that some of what
we say matters
it does and that we are having an impact
on people
and that people are nervous about our
impact
you know
um because if it was if we were totally
irrelevant it wouldn't matter
yeah there would just be words in the
Wind
no and we're growing and growing big
time well I mean it's just you know it's
it's uh it's it's a lot of
like what's funny about it is that I'm a
naturally diplomatic person
and so it's like people get mad
sometimes people get real mad at me
about certain things and I'm like man
what if I just want to just just vented
it all out
you know I learned a long time ago a lot
of people think I'm just completely
unfiltered and just say everything no
like they discuss like you sit on so
much is this pertinent to the story is
it fair is it okay to let that out you
know like does this person deserve to be
air hold even though they're probably
good people and you know maybe lied
about a few things like all these things
go into account we don't just air hole
everyone it's not how it works no and so
it's it's it's like really
you know and it also is it's also a
difficult time in weed yeah and for
people like Matt and myself
um who have dedicated basically their
entire adult life to this this this
subculture
um there's been a lot of rapid changes
happening
and there's a lot of good people in
Canada right now who are looking around
trying to figure out how do I fit where
do I fit how do I navigate this weird
new place
yeah and I think you guys are holding up
you know a beacon and it's
sure all right I think this is a wrap I
mean um not so thank you for for coming
and joining us on quick notice and with
that I just have one one quote from
cookie fam that I think
and with that it's a wrap thank you
everyone for joining us be sure to check
out the drop visit our patreon Discord
if you want to get in early on the drop
um because there might not be nothing
left after that and that was double
negatives but I I mean it and um yeah
thank you thousand for for helping us
scoot this along and keep it on track
because we are so ADHD tangent prone and
and this has a ton of help
yeah you're very welcome it's an online
thank you everyone and uh Matt treated
me with kid gloves today because he
didn't mention any weird truck stop
anything like that oh my God he didn't
no he did it weird I'm gonna you know
he's like you know not so has been gone
for a few weeks I'm Gonna Be Kind
you know back in I'm sure they've been
building up inside of him you know like
and he had probably had to bite his
tongue multiple times during this I'm
just letting you feel safe bro I'm
letting you yeah and then next week feel
safe before before the Trap snaps so I
appreciate that all right very happy
with you guys all right thank you guys
peace second one second
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out