welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
[Music]
revolution
hello everyone welcome to the breed of
Syndicate I am thousandfold and tonight
I will be hosting in place of Matt Riot
uh unfortunately we're still without
Matt uh last recording he wasn't well he
has recovered but he's now got to clear
like a huge backlog of like orders and
various admin um and also edit the last
episode so yeah unfortunately we will be
without Matt once again um so we have
the you here again we have local Farm
Dan Big Ear uh local and Big Ear
obviously from the last uh indoor
Growers episode um and farad Dan you I'm
sure you would have seen by now he's
also been uh helping us a lot I think
he's had to record like three times in
the last week because we've been backed
up as well yeah so it's been been quite
the time but it's also been really good
um we are unfortunately without spindle
tonight as well who is also unwell um so
I hope he feels better
soon but yeah today we will be talking
about flowering so we're going to match
the outdoor Growers uh who had their
flowering episode last time um and to
kick us off uh I think it was a good
idea by Dan for everyone to just talk a
little bit about the setup they're
working with um in however much detail
that you guys want to um just so that
like we can set the scene a bit for the
flowering conversation
yeah I'll kick us off um right now for
my home setup like I do a few plants
outside every year but um for my indoor
I kind of just have a a little 4x4 tent
I have a little 1x4 veg which I should
have gotten bigger because I like to
keep a lot of plants um I have just like
a little AC unit like a window ducted
one that I uh cut a hole in the side of
it and just kind of mounted it there and
sealed it up and uh I rock a
spider 2p um LED and then in the veg
side just a few bar LEDs so really basic
kind of just enough to get it done and
hold on to
plants yeah and then well first off I'm
going to mention it's Halloween and so
if you guys hear my box going crazy I
apologize uh they do not like the
trick-or-treaters um I do want to say I
I will say that I had I forgot that it
would be Halloween for you guys so thank
you for showing up on H sorry continue
yeah absolutely I'm dressed as Batman
right now so just picture that
everybody so um but yeah so I have like
a more kind of like Perpetual kind of
setup um I have like a few you know
different like bar LEDs like I I I'm not
here to I wouldn't like necessarily plug
an LED super hard or anything um but in
my main flowering tent uh I I have like
a um Grover's Choice light in there and
I use some of the like UV bars with it
and I use like the AC Infinity stuff um
you know just to automate the
environmental
control yeah I forgot to mention that
too yeah I got the same AC Infinity
controller just because it's like so
modular like they have like plugs that
you can plug your AC unit into and like
your deums and kind of have a lot more
control than you normally would with a
homerow setup
yeah um
so I currently have a 5x5 flower space
with a
um it's think it's an 800 watt LED um I
don't know what it it like draws out the
wall but that that's what it's
advertised at um and
I typically grow like one gallon pots
for flour um just a kind of see a number
of
things and like the homie said some AC
Infinity like uh 8 inch fans and stuff
like that
to remove air and then um I have some
veg closets throughout the house um but
yeah that's pretty
much my
girl do all of you perpetually flower
more or less yeah that's
kind of working on that now
yeah
cool yeah yeah so I try to um I you know
like I I like to run through things one
time and keep them backed up and then
you know rerun from there that kind of
thing so that's kind of my goal um in my
like kind of Perpetual thing is just
being able to look through stuff because
I am still very new um and just kind of
you know trying to figure out what I
like and that kind of stuff um
I'll also mention
um that um I do have like racks or a
rack in my veg space and that helps
utilize space but yeah same mine's
double here I just wanted to add that
just to kind of give a better picture I
guess I feel like it's mandatory if you
uh if you like really want to pop seeds
and keep backups and stuff like a 2x4
tent like fills up real quick right that
second tier really helps yeah there was
a company that used to sell a three-
tiered one that came with its own rack
that perfectly fit in the tent so you
didn't have to like line it up um and uh
I really missed the one that I got rid
of I'm like should have kept that
thing but yeah I don't really like
Perpetual very well because of my like
limited space if I had even just like
one more tent you know yeah my house is
a little on the smaller side and so I'm
l that I get to keep what I do and so um
I'm I kind of like don't plan it out
well as well as I should and I end up
like having to veg in the main space for
a decent amount of
time you reminded me that we talked
about these like POS possible idea to
have these little
isolated what would you call them like
Po pollination boxes was something yeah
like a grow cabinet type of thing like I
wanted to like have like a different
flowering chamber it doesn't have to be
very big so I'm only ever reversing like
one thing at a time and so that could be
like two small little one gallon pots or
something like that but I wanted to like
build a desk that had um like one side
for reversals and then like another side
where I could like then immediately take
the pollen and dust stuff in that I
wanted to work with without sacrificing
you know a 4x4 tent and making you know
you could make a pound of seed or more
in a 4x4 tent so it's a yeah a little
overkill for most of the stuff I'm
trying to do I don't you know sell my
seeds
so no that's cool that's really cool
okay well thanks for thanks all of you
for letting us kind of have a bit more
context for your your setup um maybe the
next thing that I wanted to prompt just
before we dive like right in is what are
the first thoughts that come to mind
when I say like prepare to flip or like
flipping or transition to flower I guess
two things that I really consider is
like the health of your plants and then
um the size cuz like you don't want to
flower things that are like too big cuz
I've done that I don't know how many
times but it just ends up becoming more
of a mess than anything um but also like
flowering a healthy plant is like your
best bet
because it's not going to like start
starving off the bat so I don't know
that's just my opinion though
yeah I um I I tend to kind of do the
same stuff like when I'm like getting
ready to like preparing like you know
whatever cross it is that I'm gonna like
I'm gonna flower all of them in one go
or if I'm gonna kind of like break it up
into multiple runs that kind of stuff um
when you start getting some numbers it
can be a little bit overwhelming as far
as like just looking through individual
plants um and I I kind of want to know
like each plant individually so that's
like a a thing that I you know I always
think about is like how many of these
plants can I really do and like be able
to focus my attention on them um
something else too um is uh like I like
to make sure that those plants are
backed up before I flip them
um sometimes you know it's I'm not
always lucky um but that's just a that's
a plus um when I first started growing I
remember one time I put a bunch of those
um 5 by5 veg pots and um I gritted them
out with blue dream in my tent and like
it was great like that PL will put on
like an epic single Cola and um you'll
just have like you know a sea of 48
tops it was great but a lot of stuff
won't do that I think I was I talking to
I think I was definitely talking to ER I
can't remember who else was in the
conversation like just yesterday I think
we were talking about there being this
threshold in terms of the number of
plants like that each individual can
manage Beyond which like they stop
becoming they stop really seeming like
individual plants um and they're just
more like a mess if if that makes sense
yeah yeah for sure and I think it's
different for everyone as well where
that threshold is because obviously that
depends on like your time energy you
know resources all that yeah yeah and it
all depends on like yeah like what what
you're allowed to do and like what works
for you and so uh um you know it's uh
it's always about just like getting to
know your plants and so um anyway um
yeah I like to look at just like the
size if I know the variety like you can
kind of start making some assumptions
based on like how it's going to feed and
like uh your media that you're going to
put it in and like what it prefers but
um I feel like a good base is always
just like a a cocoa or a soil run and
yeah two or three gallon pot and uh you
don't have to do like the one giant 20
gallon pot and there I've seen other
people do that too and I've never quite
understood it but um I did have a a
quick question for you Dan uh yeah when
you did the the single Cola blue dream
uh like sea of green did you find that
that like yielded as much as like you
know a couple fully grown three gallon
pots or like what was the yield like it
was like just slightly lower I think but
it was all tops and so it was like nicer
know and at that time like a lot of
people did like a lot of like scrog and
sea of green style plantings with like
hydro and stuff and so um it was like
more common I feel like at that point
than it is now yeah I would try to do
that again but it's just so hard when
you don't have like a single variety to
run at the same time like yeah this was
one clone on a flood tray so it was like
pretty pretty automated and it was in
like twofer
I've uh done a 4 by8 with uh I don't
know like 13 different varieties at one
time and it was just like it wasn't like
hard but it
was just good enough to get like I want
to say like an okay representation of
what things can be I don't know um it
wasn't my strongest grow but it was nice
to see a lot of
stuff yeah yeah exactly and that's what
I kind of do with my home stuff is just
like looking through different
populations and trying to find cool
plants and so um I'm always kind of
trying to like minmax what I can fit for
like the effort and to get the quality
and so um it's a challenge sometimes
though I set myself up for failure last
time and I put like I don't know it was
like 16 three gallons and they were just
like edge to edge and it was just like a
Mess by the end of it yeah I wasn't I
didn't actually like any of it either so
um so this is my first time actually
growing out of like three gallon cocoa
and I'm like [ __ ] mind blown at how
massive the [ __ ] buds get because I
like flowered strictly in ones and like
in ones I could get pretty sizable
buds um man the the threes I'm just like
holy [ __ ]
like man should I switch over like I
don't know but I kind of just like to
pop a bunch of seeds and it it the ones
kind of just suit my model the
most yeah for like the veg space I have
too keeping any like moms even in three
gallons it cuts me down like super super
limited and so uh um you know it's just
yeah it could just be a challenge on
those bigger pots but it's so much more
work when you're having to water twice a
day in a one gallon yeah so you know
it's uh it's I need to set up an
irrigation system also like that would
make my life so much easier if I just
had a five gallon bucket or something
like that outside the tent just plumbed
in like super basic on a sump or
something like that and um it prob it
wouldn't be very accurate as far as like
water distribution each pot but um it
would make my life a whole lot easier it
helps keep him alive right so you can
focus on other things um even I guess I
could just have it on a backup and just
have it at like 24 hours or whatever and
just have it do you know like a a really
quick water just so nothing dies if I
miss something but you know yeah totally
I'm like it just kind of sucks always
being tied down to the house right yeah
yeah exactly yeah you can't go
anywhere yeah oh man it's amazing to me
like how stress how stressful it is to
even plan like a few days away now yeah
man yeah sometimes I feel I really feel
bad for the [ __ ] plant sitter cuz
like I have a bunch of solos like one
gallon pots and flower and stuff and I'm
like oh my God like their their life is
about to be hell for an entire week um
but
yeah yeah and you you always notice when
you come back they're not they're not
very happy dude oh my God I was dude I
was really stoked to see this uh band
made Haze because it it was looking
really nice and then I come back and
like there's just like deficiencies and
I'm just like oh man like it doesn't
look terrible but
but it it could have been better it
could have gone better but here nor
there I guess yeah well the only reason
I brought like all this up was because I
feel like it kind of like leads into the
next topic thousand oh it definitely
does yeah and well you know like like
with any of these topics we'll end up
looping back inevitably right so um yeah
so I guess in terms of like drilling
into various aspects of the grow that
you might be thinking of when you are
preparing flip um obviously you already
mentioned some of these things but
um you could talk about you know any
training that you do before before flip
any like what kind of feed changes
you're preparing to do you know lights
IPM any of that really
um anyone yeah so like I've done a lot
of different things you know like I feel
like trellis in the end is the way to go
even on like a 4x4 it just limits access
and movement so much that I like avoid
doing it even though it's so [ __ ]
helpful um because it just makes
everything fixed at that point and then
you're kind of crawling on your hands
and knees trying to get little scoops of
water to the right plants and stuff and
so like I've I've been do you worry
about getting older and having to like
crawl around and stuff I'm starting to
do I'm starting to worry now yeah I mean
to a certain degree I mean I've already
got my own like you know Orthopedic
injuries and stuff like that and so you
know like I have a bad shoulder and a
bad knee already and so uh it definitely
makes it more complicated so that's why
I kind of still stick with like steaks
even though like I've almost lost an eye
a few times to like bamboo and plastic
steaks um but uh it just like lets me be
able to move plants out and uh you know
like pull a plant out to do de leafing
and stuff instead of trying to like work
in that cramped space in the tent even
though at the end of the day like I
would just love to have a trellis and so
um yeah that's that's kind of what I was
thinking about
that yeah I so like I kind of have a
little bit of a process down at this
point where I will like uh try to get
like a good aicle cutting off of my seed
mom that I can root up and then uh then
I have this plant that's like
essentially topped and like ready to
kind of be like trained out and
flowered um so that's kind of what I've
been doing uh so I'll you know I have
this plant that's topped it's got two
main tops and then I'll use just like
some clips in on the side of the pot and
a little bit of wire and just like kind
of spread the plants out just a little
bit at the start um and then later on
I'll I'll end up using like bamboo
steaks just for the reasons that Dan is
mentioning like I trellis is really nice
as far as like getting like a super even
canopy goes I think it's probably like
the probably the best way you know I
mean it's like a grit at the same
level um but it's just so tough for me
like if I'm in a 5x5 um I have mine like
sitting in the corner of my basement so
the back right corner of my is like
really hard to get to so
um yeah so I take my plants out and hand
water them and do all that stuff so I
can look at them and you know de leaf
and all that stuff so as much as I like
things about trellis it just makes it so
hard to do everything else that I want
to do um so yeah that's kind of like
what I'm I'm kind of just thinking about
like what local saying I want my plant
to be super healthy um I want the roots
to look really good and I you know I
just want to feel confident about
flipping that we're going into like
ahead of the game you
know
nice did you get a bunch of
trick-or-treaters right
then did I'm sorry my dog is going to
these people it adds some festive you
know Vibes to the
episode very
festive yeah um so I pretty much just
like to my plants a little bit before
flower and then flip them but I mean
nothing really out of the
ordinary how about like
um how about in terms of like other
things I imagine by this point you know
your IPM if you were doing any you know
needed to have
been I what am I saying basically like
by the time you get to flower you
shouldn't be doing any more IPM right
like all that stuff should have happened
like up until this point um what about
what about like feeding during flip okay
maybe we move into into the actual like
first few weeks of flowering now
then I mean well I kind of don't spray
anything during flower I
mean um I don't release beneficials
either even though I should um like
nematodes um and other beneficial mides
um but that gets expensive
and yeah I don't know um what do you do
for your prep and veg just to keep
everything clean before you get there um
so like honestly I'm a huge user of
[ __ ] uh suffoil X dude I don't know
like it's it's just like it gets
everything um it just sucks like you
can't drench it obviously but like I
mean other than that like it gets all
soft-bodied insects which is like 99% of
the problems that people run into I've
never really had a PM
issue um but people say you can use it
for that I I don't know
um but um yeah I've used like uh Grand
Deo in the past um regalia I've had like
Panic 5.0 but that [ __ ] is [ __ ]
ridiculously expensive all of that [ __ ]
you just listed is dude yeah it's it's
hard and the reason why I like get S oil
is because it's like $80 for like two
and a half gallons and like that'll last
you
forever yeah I've just had like issues
finding like a good dilution but like I
didn't stick with the SE oil very long
just cuz I well I already knew all these
other things that like I had tried and
worked for me um so like I I try to do
like enzyme sprays early on like a Nukem
or a Dr zymes and then like a few weeks
before
flour um if we're looking at like I
don't know like a six week time frame
from sprouting a seed to flipping it
maybe a little longer I'll save like
those last like two or three weeks and
two sprays and I'll get some sulfur on
the plant Micron nice sulur nice um so
I've tried to use like um [ __ ] Nukem
or doctor zes but every time it's just
like led to phytotoxicity like even at
their lowest dosage and I'm just like
you know what like I don't know like
it's just you can't let any light on it
at all yeah it's it's it's a tough one
so I kind of just like use the oil and
my plants look way happy after it too so
yeah yeah that's the
thing I had some spiderm issues in my
Nursery earlier this year and I spoke to
local about it um and mineral oil spray
did actually work out pretty well for me
just using regularly um which I was
grateful for because I know I know
spidermites can get really out of hand
really quick yeah yeah you might be
using a shot back to clean them off your
buds at the end at that point you know
when they get real bad
um yeah yeah so I I actually you guys
are kind of convincing me I kind of want
to go back and try it now but I always
like tried to do a few different things
just to like mix mode of action and like
the oils same thing as the enzymes kind
of limit you on like what else you can
use but that's an interesting point yeah
that's kind of why I got like some of
the venerate stuff because I was like
you know like I mean well I guess the
way I think of it is like the sulfur is
like or not sfur the S oil X or
horiculture oil I guess um in any
instance um like no bug can really gain
adaptability cuz like you're literally
like suffocating it by like clogging its
pores with oils so it's like you're not
going to gain a resistance but like I
still do want like a mode of action to
get things that maybe didn't get hit the
first time or whatever you know what I
mean like it's it's just good practice
but I don't know diversity of tactics is
always good for this kind of totally and
I think like the limiting like factor
for a lot of people is like money is uh
IPM is [ __ ] expensive man
like I guess like yeah it's it's it is
expensive but it's worth it like yeah
people oh go ahead I was just gonna say
like the reality of it is it's like if
you're taking cuts in or anything like
that it's like you're going to have to
like have an
IPM yeah and so like if people listening
like kind of don't know what we're
talking about it's more just that like a
different sprays will have a different
Mo of action of how they're killing
insects and so like with the mineral oil
example of the horticultural oil um bugs
breathe through small pores on their
abdomen and not out of their mouths and
head and so if you cover that in oil
they can't breathe and they suffocate
and die hence like the suffix oil
whereas like there are other sprays that
have like an active compon component
that's a a neurotoxin or something like
that of that nature or like the enzyme
sprays do really well at literally like
dissolving their exoskeleton and so um
yeah there's a bunch of different ways
to attack the same bug and you know some
are more effective than others what is
the strategy for light lighting uh when
you're when you're flipping for you guys
I mean I kind of run my light um at 80%
and then kind of maybe alod to 90 but
100% it's like way too intense in my
opinion mhm but that 80 to 90 range is
like kind of where I'd like to be
um but yeah I don't know I don't really
[ __ ] around with lighting too much like
that
um but yeah yeah I use my um I I use
that app on uh iPhone phone like just
kind of get like a general idea of where
my lighting is
um you know uh I'm not going to speak to
its accuracy as far as like compared to
a um actual like you know par meter um
because I don't have a par meter I'm
cheap and and I'm not going to spend
$500 uh to get like kind of pretty much
you want to buy Bruce bug's light
meter no not particularly um oh man
they're G to go after you in the
comments again bro
listen sorry I sorry I'll just say real
quick
$500 yeah dude they're money I'll
apologize to Bruce bugby right now and
just say sorry that's yeah unnecessary
stray yeah so I use the um the photon
there's a guy that I used to watch on
YouTube that does some like Light
reviews and stuff um that has done uh
side side by side comparisons of the app
with the the uh par meter and it was
like it was close enough that I felt
comfortable to use it so um so I use
that and just kind of get myself into
like a decent range um I kind of like to
um I don't want to be coming in cooking
on the lights at the beginning of flower
because I want to have some like room to
go as the plants start to you know
stretch and that kind of thing um so I I
do kind of like to be on like the lower
end of where I want to be to start just
so I have you know some room to increase
through flower um I'll also mention just
because Ern was uh saying that he'll
like gradually increase the ligh um but
um I'll raise my light to like the
absolute like highest it can be like
like
height-wise um and then I'll increase
the intensity to like 80 to 90% so it's
not like they're it's right up on them
or
anything yeah I can give like a little
context into like the commercial side of
it where it's a lot of commercial Grow
rooms kind of hang out around 650 to 750
microm malls of light at canopy height
and um a lot of these lights will push
2,000 if you have it dropped right on
top of your canopy and so like one of
the things I was thinking about is like
a newer grower who just got a light for
the first time and doesn't really have
any experience with it um you're kind of
stuck with trial and error to see like
what the plants you're working with will
like that's coming out of that light but
I didn't actually know about this app
that ER was talking about and so I'm
going to have to check that out as well
um because I think that could be really
useful um I'll also mention too like um
I'm a pretty recent LED grower I used to
grow a lot under
CMH um and I've noticed that led kind of
has its own like set of nutritional
problems that doesn't particularly come
with CMH like I found CMH plants to kind
of just always look healthy like there's
no weird like discoloration in the leaf
or any of that but that's just been my
observation um but what did you find was
like lacking I don't know like it just
it kind of always like seemed to be
either like magnesium or pot iium or
something like that yeah that's kind of
what I've seen too is like some
potassium sulfate helps a lot with that
led stress like the red stems and the
the kind of yellowing of the leaves yeah
and that's like something that I don't
have at the moment is like anything to
manipulate potassium independently and I
like that would [ __ ] help a lot yeah
I think we were actually like just
talking about that I was actually gonna
say I actually I actually just started
using that um
just like a f potassium supplement from
um nectar for the Gods uh I can't
remember the name of it it doesn't
matter who it came from but it's a
pottassium and um yeah I think it seems
to like I I did a Fier spray in early
flower on these um banana Haze plants
that I'm growing because one of them
stretched like pretty hard and just had
some I mean it didn't look like it just
looked like on the edge of underfed kind
of you know what I mean it's not it's
like you look at it and you're like this
plant doesn't look like incredible but
it doesn't look bad either uh so I don't
know so I tried that and it does seem to
be helping um and now I've just been
using it like as like a just mixing it
in with my feed like once a once a week
or whatever and it seems to have knocked
that issue
out um but
yeah I think I think like I started with
LED
so I never had that that learning curve
coming you know uh like
from so I just think like I think that
like I don't know I I feel like I
haven't ran into some of these problems
and it's not necessarily because I'm
like good or anything like that or
better than anyone it's just because
like I that's where I started and like I
got rid of those issues quickly or
whatever I don't know cool I mean yeah
anything else about feeding then since
we're also touching on that a bit yeah
yeah um I guess with feeding like
especially if you're early on like going
and getting like a basic like three or
four part program is um not a bad thing
at all I think you're going to be so
much happier with the results than if
you try and like reinvent the wheel
because you can piece it together a
little cheaper and make stock Solutions
and do all that but for the effort like
you're probably going to have a steeper
learning curve learning how to like
formulate a recipe more than just even
learning to grow weed and so uh I know a
lot of the guys on here like to rock
Cana I've used Cana in the past and I
really like it um I kind of like
something a little simpler and so like
I've been rocking Cutting Edge again
because that's what I started out with
earlier on and used to grow really nice
weed with it and so I've just kind of
added a few organic supplements along
the way to like a the TP tea from Roots
organic is a nice like dry Amendment
powder just to give a nice little boost
here and there and uh kind of diversify
what you're offering the plant so it can
do its thing yeah um so I've grown a few
different with a few different nutrients
with the cocoa stuff um like I've done
the the Lucas like the two part like
with h add added Epsom salts so my water
is pretty high in calcium so like CAG
was never really like a solution to any
of my [ __ ] problems ever yeah um but
it was like a quote on quote Lucas
modified you know type of thing um I've
done like the Maxi Bloom um Lucas style
thing like with seven and a half grams
of like Maxi Bloom to one gallon of
water that works the same as Lucas I
think it's really nice uh the only
downfall is it's a [ __ ] to [ __ ]
dissolve dude like even with hot water
you're
struggling um I've done the ja
321 um I'll say like you'll get really
nice sizable plants but like the issue
with it is it doesn't work for all
strains like it won't work for something
like a blueberry I don't know like it it
I've seen like [ __ ] like Kush mins
and all that kind of stuff like Crush
under that kind of Ja 321 like 3.0 EC
kind of thing um yeah
uh Kaa um I've liked it but I'll be 100%
honest man like the Lucas formula kind
of just like gives the nicest average
for the amount of like money that you
put
in um of everything I've tried so far
with Coco like I've done General Hydra
three part I've done like you know
several different like nutrient lines I
did you know I I don't know I I think
like if you get like a decent new
nutrient
program you're it's going to be
okay for the most part you know I mean
um I do try to think about like I I
noticed like with Cana um like my my
water comes out like very very soft like
10 PPM um so I I do use some cow mag you
know um but if I mix like if I mix like
full shrink flow notes with can with you
know
some cow mag and that kind of stuff you
know quickly you're getting up into this
like two and a half three C range where
I I don't really want to be feeding like
super hot like that you know um so I've
been trying to just kind of break my
feedings up a little bit and like kind
of like do do like you know like Cano
one day and then on the next watering do
um you know some cow mag and like the
potassium and you know that kind of
thing just kind of trying to break it up
a little bit just I you know I'm still
very much just trying to find like uh
where I like to
be yeah like one of these things that
the dudes at the grow shop I used to
work at always used to say when I was
like first learning about things is like
it all works Dan like it's uh it's about
what's cheapest you know and so like
I've actually grown pretty good weed
with just like 20 2020 and then 0 5050
and I would fully spray sea green which
is like a fish hydrate like compost tea
extract and um as long as you have like
good soil it's makes life a whole lot
more forgiving that's like something I'm
relearning with like promix and like
more inert Hydro style peep Medias and
with Coco is that um uh having like a
really well Blended like a um Royal gold
makes really good soil it's kind of like
what I'm thinking of and forest floor
Organics up in Eugene organ or they're
just south of Eugene but they make
really great soil with the byproduct
from the logging industry up here and uh
they it's all composted really nicely in
their yard and um I've noticed that not
using that I grow way dumpier weed kind
of regardless of the uh the nutrients
and so having a really nice soil blend
can help make your life a lot easier
especially earlier on before you've got
your whole system dialed and before uh
you know you really get to know what
you're doing I want to come back to
feeding
tactics at like distinct points of
flower but I think uh if we can like
maybe just wrap up this little bit on
like General thoughts on like uh the
transition and all that um so other
questions I had were like how do you all
deal with like managing humidity airf
flow how much cleaning up is happening
uh around the stretch like are you
pruning defoliating much lollipopping
all that yeah I I've done it a bunch of
different ways like I used to do the
lollipop style because even with like a
room kind of stacked with gavitas like
it just doesn't you don't really get
amazing light
penetration and uh I feel like I was
leaving a lot of weight on the table by
stripping really heavily up to the first
trellis and um the kind of the style I'm
more going for now is a little bit more
defoliating but consistently to maintain
that light penetration all the way down
and so I don't really go hard on Def I
kind of just like every time I'm
checking in I take a few leaves here or
there for kind of just open up certain
flowering
spots yeah I kind of tend to do the same
thing as far as defoliation goes like
when I'm I I take like I said like um
I'm in three gallon cocoa so and I water
like hand water take them out set them
on my bench and like you know that kind
of thing so um I'll take them out like
during flow I'm watering sometimes daily
maybe every other day you know so I'll
take these plants out and like just kind
of go through and just look and like if
there's stuff that like is blocking or
like looks like it's not getting that
much light I'll you know I'll remove it
I'm not like lollipopping but I do
remove some of the like lower Buds and
stuff just that I know are going to end
up being just like you know kind of
boofy and stuff that like I don't really
want to mess with anyways so I'll get
rid of that stuff and then otherwise I
kind of just try to leave them
alone I like leaving like a very uh kind
of certain like uh ratio I guess of like
ly or popcorn stuff at the bottom just
because like that's the stuff that I'll
just quick try and like get use as
samples early on but yeah loal yeah um
I'll like so I wouldn't say like I
lollipop my plants particularly cuz like
you know I don't get them like that like
[ __ ] wide or whatever um because like
I crowd my tent with like one gallon
pots um so I kind of just strip all the
lower stuff and like let them like shoot
up instead of like out wide
um but yeah other than that like there's
no specific like shape that I go for
other than the like making sure they're
not bumping into each other and stuff
like that um
the one thing I've noticed with LEDs is
like the light penetration with them so
it is nice to get some of that ly stuff
but I'm kind of Onie with that
1,000 um I don't like like pick it out
particularly because I do like to smoke
it early on and I am a little lazy I'll
admit well and like what some people do
especially like outdoor Growers and
Greenhouse guys like if you have the
ability to and the space and no
restrictions about it is um a lot of
people will take tops and like kind of
take the top half of the plant and then
leave the lowers for another like week
to 10 days to let them firm up a little
bit too yeah yeah and so like um
especially outdoor on like larger plants
that's like really key because that
interior canopy is never quite as done
as those top
extremities um yeah so um thousand I
know you were asking about like
feeding um so once thing like I've
noticed with a lot of plants is like you
can kind of continue that like same veg
diet all the way through um and then
there's some that'll take like a full
strain veg um and then you like try to
apply that into flower and I've noticed
some of them will like show like some
nitrogen toxicity like a little bit of
clawing on like the new growth and stuff
and so I'll just kind of subtract it
from like the part that contains a
little more
nitrogen um but other than that like
it's kind of like it's it's hard to know
when you like pop seeds and you're
throwing them into flower the first time
but like exactly the second go yeah the
second go around like that's when you
can kind of make your tweaks and kind of
adjust each um individuals like um
formula and [ __ ] like that
but it makes sense because it's like you
can't really play ketchup in flow
exactly yeah uh just quickly I think you
all mentioned this already when you were
talking about your setups but uh
humidity control AC's
dehumidifiers um so I'll I'll have my AC
running like all the time um I like to
get like cooler nighttime temps
um but like in terms of like humidity
and stuff since I have like the AC
running it does get a little cool and
dry but I also have like fan like the
small like um not like uh desktop fans
but they're like I don't know 12in fans
something like that 14 inch like on the
front floor and then the back
floor um and then they'll move air on
the floor and then I have some strap to
the top of the tent like right at the
entrance um but that's really it for air
movement yeah I have just like a small
deum um inside the tent that I use um
luckily nowadays there's actually small
Deus that actually work um they didn't
used to be that way so like when I first
started growing even even if you had a
4x4 tent like you kind of had to figure
out how to work in this you know like
two foot tall by like a foot wide by
like eight to 10 inches like this just
Big Unit almost the size of a small AC
that like you had to just like cram in
the tent with it you know or else you
just had like no real control over that
I have a question here about this like
in my mind I thought it would be
somehow I don't know if more effective
is the right term but I thought that
like it was the lung room that should be
dehumid
not the like inside Space because that
space is you know having air kind of
going like passing through it yeah um
but I don't know I'm curious what yeah
so so mine's kind of set up on a timed
exhaust and so like I'm not always
exhausting but it's set up on a timer to
where it does it like once an hour um
for like 15 minutes uh and then I have
my AC kind of like blowing like pulling
from my lung room which just my office
you know um and that's kind of influx in
cool or you know refreshen air a little
more often because if you think about it
with your AC um unless your whole room
is AC it kind of just depends on where
you live because when I used to live on
the coast we didn't need AC we just
pulled in that 65 degree air from
outside and at night it goes down to
like 45 um but that air was always
really humid you know so that just meant
more deems that you need but you don't
have AC luckily AC's act as the human
Ires all on their own and so um a lot of
people especially in like California
where it's drier for a lot of the year
you can get by without a de at
all yeah so I was going to say I use um
like as far as like the lung Grom kind
of situation is it's my basement you
know so uh I just want my basement to be
generally
dry being like a good house owner kind
of thing you know but um so uh I do have
like a some of those like portable um
AC's I have two of them um but really I
only use one of them most of the time um
I have a hose hooked up to it and I'll
run it in dry mode and just let it um
dehumidify constantly um because like
this year uh like until today actually
it's cold now but um it's been like 85%
humidity here like all summer it seems
like so it's I mean it's been a even to
just get me get me down to like 60% uh
humidity is about as far as I've been
able to get just with it this year um
but now that it's getting cold and stuff
I won't need to run
dehumidifier I'll just run an air
conditioner in my basement you know just
for it to be like comfortable um and
then I have two of those um like
hurricane like oscillating fans I have
those like mounted just like moving air
around in my basement I wanted us to
move into kind of looking more at the
progression of the different stages of
flower but I had a thought which is just
before we do that I wanted to ask Dan if
there was like any notable differences
when he thinks about this for work or
you know at the facility versus thinking
about it at home even on like a broad
level like what are the major things
that are different that kind of jump out
to you
Dan um I mean the major thing at scale
is just cost you know like I can't for
to buy anything liquid you know so like
that just means like stock tanks and
direct injection for like fertigation
systems and stuff like an Argus or a
Privia or even just some
dosatrons um and so it's just kind of a
completely different realm as far as
that goes because like most people are
just running like either a custom Blend
or a purchase blend of salt
fertilizers um but like at home um I
used to have like a whole thing when I
was like doing more Organics where I'm
like all right I'm going to like feed
seaweed until this date and then I'm
going to top dress with um you know like
worm castings like once a week for those
two first two weeks of flour and like
get a bloom powder in there and then uh
I had this whole progression and like it
grew nice weed but like now looking back
I feel like it's pretty excessive and so
um I think the one thing that might be
like a tidbit that goes against like
common bro knowledge
is that the phosphorus intake that your
plant wants is they need it immediately
starting in flour you know which means
that you probably needed to water it in
like a week before you flip and get
those levels up within the plant and uh
traditional knowledge is more like push
phosphorus and potassium at the end of
flow for like the last four weeks and
I've never really understood the thought
behind that because like if you think
about a plant that's flowering it's
doing this massive amount of cell
division at each node and then those
cells all just like expand with water
and so I'm not really exactly sure what
like a huge phosphorus or potassium dose
at the end really does besides just like
make your flowers super dense which is
kind of the original point but I think
to facilitate it it's much better to do
it like right around the transition time
and keep that going for the first week
or two and then you can kind of go on a
more base feed from that point cool yeah
I've not heard that before so that's
definitely a new thing for me to think
about
um well you kind of you kind of got it
started there right so in your mind what
are like the
distinct you know not distinct but you
know what are the loose stages of
flowering you know obviously in the
stretch that's quite an obvious one how
do you all see like the flowering the
entire process kind of being divided
Loosely yeah for me it's just cell
division and
expansion and so that's like yeah weeks
one through three while the plants
elongating the you see those flowers
forming and after that it's kind of just
like I like to just get out the way you
know and and kind of let it do its thing
and so I don't really have any secret
sauce for flower you know what I mean
besides like setting the plant up to be
able to Sprint when the time
comes okay well in terms of what about
the rest of you like in terms of feeding
at these different Junctions like what's
changing or like any any of those other
parameters feeding uh lights you know
what's changing in the course of like
flowering um so I'll just mention that
like my diet doesn't really like the
plants I guess the way I feed my plants
like their diet isn't particularly like
changing a lot like I'm still keeping
the same formula the same ratios and
stuff that like Cana
provides um it's just like sometimes I
notice like a little bit of nitrogen
toxicity so I'll back off on one part um
but like other than that like I'll keep
the feed the same all the way through
but like the one thing I've noticed is
like they don't like have a a potassium
supplement that's separate and it's like
since I already add potass or um uh
calcium
phosphate um it's like I don't need to
add the PK like I need to add some K you
know what I mean I don't know but yeah
other than that like there's no specific
like Diet it's like I I'm not like
really ramping up P or k at any specific
time like I just want to add enough to
kind
of compensate for the addition of like
phosphorus in my medium so so with Kaa
I'm not like as familiar I don't really
remember do they have you like a week to
week recipe chart where they're kind of
like changing and shifting ratios or do
they just have like a bloom like rate to
use things so it's kind of like you
maintain your onetoone usage of A and B
right yeah and then you'll notice like
as the flowering progresses you'll kind
of up you know up until like I don't
know like maybe week six to seven and
then you yeah so like the there the can
of formula is based off of like eight to
nine week plants um so it uh looking at
it it it's like around like week four or
five they is when you're hitting like
the highest amount of feed um and you're
kind of coming in I use like I'm using
the PK booster like they recommend just
to see because I haven't used it before
so I just kind of want to see if it was
going to make a difference
um but it it kind of ramps up to
somewhere around like 1.8 EC and then
that's like around like week five and
then it kind of just starts it kind of
comes down a little bit and then to
about like 1.2 EC and then it stays
there
until um you know until you finish or
whatever have you guys ever played
around with like any different um like
Bloom booster quote unques and I don't
mean just like a straight PK but there's
like products like Advanced Nutrients
overdrive or House and Garden shooting
powder um that I've noticed after using
them a few times in like commercial
capacities that they kind of do have
something in them I have no idea what it
is um that you can kind of reestablish
an earlier flower set and it lets it
basically you see the plant shoot a
bunch of white hairs again when it was
already kind of starting to die back in
siness a little bit and they used to
recommend it in like week seven but I
think they've changed that to like five
or six now um and that's kind of how
people used to use it and recommend to
use it um before they changed it because
like I I worked for the company that was
had the licens to distribute House and
Garden in the in the US back then and so
um
it's just funny how things change like
that but have you guys ever used
anything like
that um I used uh the one that General
Hydro makes it has like a sunflower on
the front of it um it's like
a I I'll look at the name really quick
but it you know it has it's like a right
liquido yeah yeah I used to [ __ ] with
that stuff a lot yeah yeah that's that's
good man um yeah it's it's tough like
there's a point where you can be using
all these different inputs and It's just
tough to tell like what's doing what for
me sometimes um
so yes I did use it but like when I was
using it I was also using a plethora of
other stuff so I can't say that I like
noticed something like um specifically
from it but I kind of like am I still
have a lot of that kind of stuff you
know like that I just didn't use
so I'm still kind of like interested in
revisiting it and like kind of isolating
it a bit more and seeing like what it
does so that's that's kind of something
that I do uh just like messing around
you know what I mean locco mentioned
that like one of the things he watches
out for is like end talks I was
wondering if any of you in your current
or previous setups had like how how
would I put it kind of like a almost
like a a sense of like what would be
risks during flower or things that
[Music]
were how' I put it were the things you
were watching out for that you were
worried
about um so I'll comment with the uh Jax
321 um it's designed in like three to be
applied in like you know like not
applied in three parts but like it has a
three separate parts that you mix
together right
and and and it has um calcium nitrate
which is like
1500 and then they have like their base
b or whatever which is like the you know
pottassium and phosphorus and then they
have like a magnesium sulfate um but
like I mean off the bat like you kind of
know that some things aren't going to
respond well because like you have such
a high nitrogen
content um and it sucks because like in
that specific formula your nitrogen is
tied with your calcium so it's not like
you can cut back
nitrogen and expect to keep the same
like calcium content if that makes sense
um but really that's kind of like the
only formula that I've I've seen that
issue
specifically yeah I always try and look
at like the potassium rates towards the
end of flow um and just like the
potassium rates in general for some
lines are like absolutely insane and
that's where you'll start seeing that
that um yellow tipping on the The Leaf
tips you know what I mean and that
dieback I almost always see that with
like an overuse of like a potassium
heavy Bloom product and it can actually
get bad enough on some of these like 30
e recipes that um the Brack tips
themselves on the flow start to get that
same dback and um I see it more and more
on Commercial flow these days and it's
it just shows me that people are reading
bottles and not like actually being good
grow
you
know maybe now it's making me curious
like have any of you experienced like
major fuckups in this period before or
has it largely been smooth
sailing yeah I [ __ ] up a
lot um JX gave me my Mo not like I'm not
[ __ ] on the product whatsoever like
it was totally like on my end um but
like dude it gave me the most like
inconsistent Health um relatively
speaking um you know just because some
things were so sensitive to the nitrogen
that it's like once the damage is done
like it that you it's not like you can
fix it you know what I mean like it's
still gonna have an overabundance of
nitrogen
um but yeah I don't know yeah I mean is
that something oh you
going U I was just going to say like the
thing I think to keep in mind too is
like when you're running a bunch of new
plants like you don't know what they're
going to do the first time you know so
there's just like this element where
like sometimes I was growing some
pineapple or not pineapple some um pine
tar Kush from Caleb from CSI and
um I just noticed that like they were
drinking really slow and then I started
getting into this weird thing where I
had nitrogen claw you know and it it's
kind of like there's a certain point
where you just got to leave it alone
because the more it seems like the more
you do the worse it's getting you know
it's like sometimes you just got to be
okay with like not knocking it out of
the park and just you know maybe if you
get an idea of it you get an idea of it
if not try it again you know yeah and
like a slight deficiency is way easier
to deal with than like an overuse of
something it's like you know what I mean
like you can always add a little more to
make it taste better but it's next to
impossible to remove it cuz then like I
did this one time I was using a um you
guys know mad farmer I think they did
make like the Moab powder and stuff um
they had a trial like veg and Bloom
powder line too and I was growing using
like their you know exact um dilution
rates and stuff and uh every time I
mixed it it was like three 0 you know
and I kept watering it in and I just saw
the plants get worse and worse until I
was like okay this is too much and then
like being newer to Growing I was like
oh well I saw this product at the grow
shop and it's like a salt remover you
know and it's supposed to help like
rinse all these excess salts out and
it's like at this point like yeah like
er saying like you're you're kind of
just like too far gone you know um it's
not going to get better and adding more
stuff to try and remove certain things
is just like the exact opposite of what
um you want and so the old adage that
everyone used to say is like um use half
as much as they say because like a
growth chart for like uh different
fertilizer usage like if I've got
nitrogen on the Y AIS and then like
plant growth on the X you're G to see
this ma or I'm sorry opposite of that um
plant growth on the Y you're G to see
this massive increase in growth for um a
certain point you know it's just this
nice exponential growth curve and then
at a certain point it plateaus for quite
a long time and then it starts dropping
um and getting into you know like aect
negatively affecting the yield for how
much you're using and nutrient companies
want to push you as far over to the
right on that Plateau as they can where
you're using abundantly more for the
same exact effect and so like what
people always used to recommend is just
like start off with half and kind of go
from there yeah I was kind of G to add
kind of like the one thing I've noticed
is there's no like benefit to feeding
like over like two and a half Max I
don't unless like your your system is
like truly [ __ ] dialed in
environmentally and you have like
[ __ ] CO2 and an entirely sealed
system and all that [ __ ] like yeah I
don't know like it it's kind of
irrelevant you know under some
circumstances yeah and I feel like some
of those stress responses from being far
over on that like Plateau where you're
just adding more and not getting
response is where you kind of end up in
like hermaphroditic territory and like
just weird expressions in general yeah
because I mean it is fair to say too
that like you know it is stress on the
plant I mean it is creating salt stress
on the root res and stuff you
know you also have to consider too like
you know these dudes are like sh
focusing on the [ __ ] like uh EC going
in but like also the inmedia like the EC
in the medium is like almost three times
as much you know like I'm just like this
cannot be [ __ ] healthy for the plant
at all I don't know like the plant will
like look you know big and and nice
and whatnot like at a commercial scale
but like there's just like I don't know
it lacks character at the end of
it well it's just like um you've you've
heard heard like I mean I know I've
heard like Matt and these guys talk
about like quote unquote computer grown
weed you
know
and I mean like when you have these like
sensors and you're reading like dryback
and like net monitoring I you know it's
like there are these setups where that's
happening and they're not necessarily
producing
like uh they're not always producing
like the best weed or whatever you know
so there's something else to it I think
I mean yeah to me that's just about
actually kind of a point that was made
earlier like actually watching the plant
and observing the plant and
not not immediately assuming that like
formalizing and automating and you know
determining the process is immediately a
good thing but it's just such a common
impulse you know
um one thing I did want to point out is
that I like what farad Dan had to say
about you know airing on the side of
like a lighter feed than a heavier one
because I think when you're analyzing
risk one of the good parameters to look
at is
reversibility and like it reminds me of
like watering as well you know for
newbies it's like or on the side of
watering less because it's easier to
bounce back from that than watering too
much you know and I like I kind of like
some of those strategic principles
because it's helpful for newer
people yeah you learn their importance
real quick after screwing up you know 12
weeks of
work you know then you're like oh I'm
never going to forget that I'm going to
water you know half as much or you know
whatever it is water more or like less
more frequently something like that you
know I wanted to add no you go you go
well I was just gonna say I know like
there's so many products on the market
to you know as for as far as nutrients
and stuff like that goes and like you
know I'm the kind of person that's like
you know like I want to try the newest
stuff and that kind of thing like I've
always been you know like I have I want
to get a nice computer or I want to get
you know that kind of stuff and so um
it's very easy to kind of go down that
road but like it's it it was really eye
opening to me uh when I went from using
all these different inputs to using like
literally a just straight up three-part
General Hydro
and some you know promix and all of
these plants are coming out looking
really nice and it's like what is
happening right here it just is so it
feels almost
counterintuitive but I just wanted to
say that because I do know that like as
a new grower it's so easy to just want
to just add more more more you
know yeah you think you're just like one
additive away from hitting that three
pounds of
light yeah yeah or what whatever it is
like you know you get obsessed on these
things where people are like oh you got
to use this you know Basalt lava Ash or
whatever it is it's like I'm sure there
are some really cool benefits from it
but like you know are you are you like
dialed in enough that you're gonna
notice it even you know um so like one
thing I've kind of noticed um is there's
like this rule of thumb to pick like a
nice kind of two two to three-part
nutrient line and get to know that yeah
um I don't know it because like you know
trying so many different things yeah
it's nice but like you don't really know
how the product works until you like
actually see it across the board and
stuff like that but I don't know I've
I've done maybe uh this is my third or
fourth grow with Cana I think my third
but I don't know like um
yeah that that te part kind of rule is
it's a nice one to follow yeah I like um
for newer people I always recommend like
like big ear was saying like the
three-part or two even a two-part GH
because they have like the Flora NOA
which is kind of like the Sanic approach
um and they have you know like some soy
protein hydrolysate and probably like a
little um seaweed extract in there and
you can grow really great weed with
florova grow bloom and like the GH Roots
like you can make perfectly good weed
with that and so it's a great place to
start as far as just like it's super
easy to learn and um you can start
slowly adding one thing at a time to
that and see if it actually does make a
difference once you have that
Baseline yeah um it's kind of funny
because I feel like that that Lucas
formula was like the best expression I
was able to pull out of like the sweet
pee yeah um I haven't really seen it
like that under Cana but I don't know um
you kind of just notice that like some
plants have their preferences in a way
but I don't know that's that's not
today's topic I
guess um I wanted to spice things up a
bit and do a little tangent on myths why
don't we start with everyone's favorite
Flushing who wants to pick up the knife
first um so I mean I guess the way I see
flushing is to like encourage lik in
essence you know like I don't think it
makes like the smoke any better but I
just kind of want to make sure that the
plants using what it already has um like
I don't know in soil or something like
soil for example that has like a higher
Caton exchange capacity I've always
thought you'd want to flush it a little
longer like if wait wait wait before you
go further like do you want to Define
what you you call flushing first or like
what you are
describing um I mean I'm kind of just
like using it to encourage
syence like to kind of no sorry what's
the actual process when you say flushing
do you mean like you're holding off
feeding oh I'm just like I'm just like
watering it like with water
yeah yeah um but yeah that's it nothing
too special but like Coco I'll do like
you know two three
days but it's because like it doesn't
hold on to nutrients as much as
something like soil so it's easier to
kind of strip those sites off and kind
of encourage the essence a lot quicker
yeah so I got um kind of obsessed with
flushing at one point I think I've
talked about this before and like kind
of what led me to doing some like dwc
type
stuff um
but uh I've done flushing in the way
that local saying is the way that I
would generally do it um but I have also
taken like a five gallon pot and poured
like 20 gallons of water through it in
one
shot you know what I mean those roots
what I wanted to do yeah so I have done
that uh and I've measured like the PPM
and stuff of the runoff you know like
all that stuff that you that you do that
people do or maybe they don't I did it
was it the cleanest smoke you ever
had I mean white ash baby very white ash
yes almost clear that's the thing that's
weird about it is like you know I've had
plants where like where how local
approaches it just started like I I'll
generally just stop watering for like
the last like few days or not stop
watering but stop feeding um and
it's interesting because some plants
will like change drastically and then
some plants will like I had this mule
Skinner uh from hin LOM that I ended up
flushing with just plain water for like
two weeks because I was just like what I
just want to see what it's going to do
um it just like never changed really um
so I just haven't noticed like a huge
difference in the quality of the smoke
so um it's not something that I'm really
obsessed about but I still do flush
because um like I've also fed nutrients
up until the very end and it did it also
didn't like it didn't make it any better
so I figure um if I can save on
nutrients and get the same end product
then I'll just do
that yeah I do want to ask though like
are we talking about a diff like are we
talking about like two different things
like is there flushing in the sense of
like your running water through your
root Zone to achieve some outcome versus
you're holding off feeding what do you
guys how do you guys see this
distinction or this like ambiguity I
kind of view it as like literally yeah I
think it is like people in their mind
mixing up like a few different things
like I agree with ER that it's like the
reason that I don't feed for that last
week or two is because I'm cheap and
like if the plants like not if it
doesn't make it better then like why am
I pay for fertilizer to go into the pot
you know what I mean and I also want my
soil to be a little bit more leeched and
not heavy and nutrients especially Bloom
NES like right once I throw because I
reuse my soil I don't throw it away and
so um I don't want it to be like super
salt filled when I come back to it but
it's like when I think about flushing
it's like some people think that it's
like increasing like it's like causing
some physiological change in the plant
that makes it better some people think
that like fertilizer crystals within the
plant make the smoke
harsher um the way I kind of view it is
like I'm cheap and
um I feel like the Cure is honestly much
more important than the flush as far as
all the like evaluation goes on it you
know and so like I've had stuff that was
fed like from a seed production run that
was fed full strength veg NES all the
way through flour till the last day and
it's a little bit harsher but it's not
that bad you know what I mean it was
perfectly smokable weed and it actually
had kind of like some nice Aroma changes
with that too with like high nitrogen
feed all the way through and so like all
these things that are like kind of
General roles of thumb in the industry
and like within the community are like
not hard fast rules for everything you
know like there is going to be some
plants that are like perfectly fine with
high Nitro or like salt all the way
through the end and there's going to be
some that don't and so it's kind of just
about like dialing it in but I don't
think flushing makes your Ash whiter I
really don't I think it's just like
stupid to even like consider it um I
guess I'll I'll mention too like back in
the day like when I was like an amateur
at growing I would like flush my medium
to like clear out any [ __ ] excess
nutrients that I may have applied like
that was a form of flushing that I've
done yeah um but like it's not like I
flush my medium entirely and then go
back to feeding you know regularly um
because like I kind of do it in a way
where I don't let my medium dry out
entirely too much where like salts
builded up um so like in theory I don't
have to like flush to like get rid of
salt it's just like achieve some runoff
and you'll kind of maintain an
equilibrium this is a bit of a tangent
but it's come up as a term um I think
when I've listened to you uh local and
Dan talk um what is the it's kind of
related to what you just said right like
what is the risk around like quotequote
dryback or like benefits or like how do
you see
dryback I mean like I don't know in
flower like I've kind of always been in
practice to encourage a little more
dryback than you would in veg kind of
just to like encourage that like
Winter's coming or whatever or like
water's a little more restricted yeah
exactly yeah yeah um but like with that
like you kind of risk salt buildup
because like as you like dry back your
concentration or like your the amount of
water to like salt is going to be thrown
off and like you're going to have a
concentration of salts in your medium um
and really like the only way to like get
that lower is by running water through
it strip to strip the salts from The
Medium but like I don't know it's it's
never like been bad enough to where it
like physically damages the plants to
what I can see um but yeah yeah I think
this kind of just goes back to like what
an was saying as far
as kind of staying on like the lighter
side of things um because I can just
tell you from personal experience like
when you're there pouring like 20
gallons of water through a pot it
doesn't feel good and you you're like
you're like man this cannot good for
this plan you know uh it's a lot and um
it
also in doing like taking like I I would
do it I'd like do like a gallon and then
do like a slurry test and see where I
was and then go again you know what I
mean and um it doesn't change it very
much man it takes a lot of water to
actually flush it you know um so I just
think like yeah just maybe like try to
not get into a position where where you
feel like you need to flush
anyways um that's nice that you bring up
the slurry test too Ern because like I
find that a lot of people or a lot of
newer Growers are like stuck on
measuring the EC and pH of the runoff
and like that runoff pH in theory like
it's not going to be the same as the
water going in or whatever or the uh the
pH of the actual medium because like
you're the plant's going to be feeding
as that water is like coming out so like
some ey on are going to be like missing
making it either like more basic or
acidic at least to my understanding um I
don't know if if um anyone else is able
to contribute to that but yeah they're
they're not very accurate tests when
you're testing runoff like it is not
like an exact representation of what's
going on in your pot and I think the
easiest example like in Hydro like the
more inert your media goes I feel like
it is more applicable but especially in
like a nice well Blended potting soil
like I was talking about earlier with
like compost and you know a lot more
organic portions to it that are that are
like did do come pre fertilized like you
can pour a cup of water through some
fresh bags of soil like that and it'll
come out at like 4 EC but like not all
of that is like readily plant available
and like you know what I mean um it's
not an incredibly accurate test on its
own
um go ahead oh you can finish dud sorry
about that oh yeah I'm just yeah just
saying like your media really dictates
like how accurate that is and I think
cocoa and promix kind of style it um
it's probably a little bit more accurate
than like real soil um but in Hydro is
kind of the only time that I really even
use it as a tool besides kind of just
like oh this is the general b ballpark
that the pH is in like plus or minus
like you know a few points and same with
the EC like PR plus or minus a few
hundred
PPM I was just going to add an anecdote
here which is that one of my most
traumatic experiences as a new grower
was like going down this bizarre Rabbit
Hole probably wholly
unnecessarily um of like freaking out
freaking out about my um medium's
pH um and just getting completely lost
because I didn't know what I was doing
um and actually I think I told ER about
this and I actually ended up speaking to
like a Cana person on the phone which is
quite bizarre like I've never spoken to
like anyone in this industry on the
phone like as a you know like a customer
before yeah yeah um and he actually had
really good advice he was just like look
if your medium there's something
actually wrong with his pH or buffering
capabilities you are not going to be
able to fix it like at home like you
won't even have the tools to like
diagnose it properly um and I thought
that was actually quite good
advice yeah that's what something like
when I was still doing the quote unquote
like you know living soil or organic
kind of stuff um I I was using uh my
soil like multiple runs you know and um
we have like an agricultural University
near us so I took it and was getting
some like soil tested and stuff like
that just to see and like through that
whole process I just I just like really
realized that
like a lot of the things that you're
like really stressing about you really
just it's so hard to control them that
uh you're better off to just like get
products that are going to put you on
the right path from the very
beginning yeah like I had a in my foray
and like Organics U I feel like Organics
is where you actually do have to
slightly pay more attention to this
because some of the organic inputs do
have their own wild pH swings like and
the main one I'm thinking of is uh a
little bit farther back like in the 201s
up until legalization people were all
about seabird guano and bat guano and
the seabird guano specifically like
they're harvesting it off of these like
little ocean rocks you know what I mean
those little rocky outcroppings that are
just covered in crap and like what's
also in it is tons of um like shell from
eggs like all kinds of different little
products byproducts and so what I
noticed with that stuff is that it's
super super basic and when I was top
dressing with like the
teaspoon um for like a three gallon pot
or whatever after a few weeks my runoff
was like a pH of 10 and it was like way
out of whack because that seabird guano
was just like very very um basic in its
own natural component you know based on
it it's a composition and so um with
normal like liquid bottled nutrients
like you're usually watering in between
like 5'8 and 65 by like design because
it's like usually naturally buffered by
the way they've designed it and so if
you're not inputting anything that has a
crazy pH swing then like you shouldn't
have an issue going forward at
all yeah that's more or less what he
said he was just like if you have the
right product it's going to be
adequately buffered and like you
shouldn't really have to worry about it
like on this scale you know on this
level um
yeah well I don't know if you have
anything else to say around this
flashing topic I wanted to move it along
towards like any other weird myths that
yall have heard about flowering like I
know that some people are like I'll just
say that like one one pet one for me is
people who think that like basically
like abusing the [ __ ] out of your plant
like driving a steak through like the
stem or like super Crossing or any of
those things are beneficial and not I'm
not going to say that they're not like I
just don't know but I'm curious about
you you know everyone's thoughts on
stuff like
this I think like the most that I've
really kind of like messed around with
is like cold
stress you know um like early on just
kind of like I I don't know like I it'll
get really cold outside and I'll like
sometimes like just vent cold air into
my tents um I still do that sometimes
you know
um and I think that it kind of tends
to I I don't know I it may be like a Bro
Science thing but it kind of tends to
make them look a little bit like
frostier and that kind of thing like I
just feel like around like when you can
get like cold Su like really cold dry
air the plants just like kind of react
to it a bit but I've you know in the
cold stress thing too I've also seen
like people taking like ice and putting
it in their you know putting it on top
of their soil and like watering over it
and stuff like
that yeah trying to force that purple
man yeah yeah it when I was when I was
like starting out um I I just didn't
really understand a lot of this stuff so
like you know purple weed was pretty and
that's cool or whatever you know now
it's just not something that I'm I'm
really concerned with my favorite one is
when uh if you ever go to a hydro shop
they they're not common anymore but
especially the shops that have been
around a lot they just have this [ __ ]
left over from years ago but um there's
all these white bottles with like
different pictures of fruit on them and
they're all like artificially
flavored um like sugar supplements you
know what I mean and like they were
everywhere for a long time and like
they'll just have a picture of a grape
on it and it smells like artificial
grape cuz that's obviously how you make
grape Aromas and weed is by like pouring
artificial grape flavoring and sugar
into your into your med and these are
from like professional companies like
Botanicare and [ __ ] you know and it was
just like a thing for a long time and
I'm sure that they knew it was [ __ ]
when they were Mass producing this but
it's a it's one of those like old
vestages that I just always laugh about
in this
industry yeah I I had a person tell me
sorry just about the fruit thing I that
you could put put your buds like when
you were drying them like have them on a
rack and then have like fruit underneath
of it and like a flame a fan like
blowing across the fruit onto the buds
someone told me that's how I should be
drying it I'm not kidding ethene
baby it's it's pretty nuts how many
[ __ ] like old W tales that there are
in this this community Community yeah
like hang your plants upside down while
you're drying because it it concentrates
the THC in the buds that one was a good
one that's an amazing one that shoulding
the Hall of Fame of myths it's so good
yeah or was one Matt said one time like
shock the plants with like a car
battery bro I me you got a shotg to turn
them purple I think for me it's more of
like a psychological or I don't know
cultural interest that I have in this
kind of General strategy of like if
you're violent towards your plant and if
you traumatize it it's good yeah and I'm
like why though this makes me think I
was I was reading some kids uh um
Master's thesis out of San lispo and in
it's about like reversal Tech and like
triing out a bunch of sprays and um in
it he like has this full paragraph about
like s's rization technique like it's
like this like you know industry
accepted method you know what I mean and
I just love that that appears in a
master's thesis and I remember like
screencapping that and sending it to
Matt and I'm just like look at this
[ __ ] dude wait you have to you have
to elaborate what that is calization is
just like torturing your plant through
like drought stress and heat and like
keeping a giant plant in a Solo Cup and
like just stressing it in every way
imaginable to like get it to Herm and it
like I guess it works on some things but
it's just like if you think about like
the EP potential epigenetic costs of
that like I don't know it's not like a
proven thing but um I just can't imagine
that like stressed plants produce the
best possible Offspring I hope these
people on
parents yeah right yeah just snack my
around a little bit makes them
strong yeah it's like go you know go
play on the train tracks it'll help
build character kind of thing um yeah
that's last Generations game like yeah
yeah
any other like weird myths that you all
can think of um apart from like so we
mentioned additives various kinds of
like
stress oh yeah um some people do like uh
I've heard people talk about um like
doing like a dark period before
flowering to like help trigger flowering
yeah that was a good one yeah yeah it's
like 24 hours dark on flip I remember
that one from when I first started
growing yeah I remember dude I mean you
can get on Reddit and there are just
threads dedicated to this oh yeah you
know I go there and I just destroy them
yeah cuz it's you know I mean yeah all
sorts of things like that also the 28 or
I've heard people doing 48 hours with
two days no lights before flower it's
weird I don't know I've actually noticed
that that technique can help to some
degree with um different reversal sprays
too and the amount of phytotoxicity
experience and then also just like its
efficacy is that um I think that there's
some interplay with
um light intensity and like the plant
breaking down the silver ions that
you're spraying on it and like I don't
have like proof it's all kind of
anecdotal um it could also just be like
hormone play and like the newest portion
of the plant is um like has a different
set of hormones doesn't have that
concentration of silver on it from the
last sprays and so it rever HS back to
female first but it's just something
I've noticed is that the lowers on
Plants tend to stay um a little more
reversed than the tops do and so I have
a little experiment in mind of like
under lighting and not top lighting and
and seeing if that has like any effect
on that but just a little side tangent
yeah I mean that makes sense too I mean
because you know I mean a lot of those
things um break you know have some kind
of like decay in light so it very well
could be that
well maybe we can step away from the old
wives tales and myths and kind of come
back to you know the earnest side of
flowering and anything else that we may
have missed out
um what about if we think
towards like late flower does anything
change or is it like even more hands-off
than the rest of it because for me
generally it is right I'm sure for most
people it's like you're just watching
waiting
yeah I mean I'm still just kind of um
I'm paying attention probably like the
most I am to the humidity uh around that
time you know around the like end of
flower and stuff and I'm also I will
also tend to like lower my lights just a
little bit um like at the start of
flower I'll I'll be somewhere around
like 80 to
85% and I'll get up to about like 90
95% and then I'll work my way back down
to around like 80% for the last like
week you know just kind of give them a
break let them chill out do their thing
whatever yeah I do the same thing with
oh sorry loal but I do the same thing
and I just kind of scale back the
nutrients slowly from like week six to
nine yeah and I'm talk like 300 parts
per million increments and I do the same
thing with the lighting where I kind of
slowly ramp it back down from that
Peak yeah I was just going to add those
last two weeks um I'll like I won't feed
every watering but I'll like supplement
just like a little bit of plain water
kind of just to you know cuz they're
they they don't really need to eat that
much but it's kind of just to feed them
a little bit kind of get rid of some of
that food you
know um but yeah nothing too crazy um
and then I guess I did want to comment
earlier on like the old wives tail um is
there like there's no like kind of uh
one kind of kir all product like Cal Mag
for example I know a lot of people like
recommend that for everything and it's
just
like I don't know just take information
with the grain of salt I
guess yeah C mag for president baby
2024 I think I made that Meme years
ago how often have you all encountered
like btis um a lot flower I've I've had
it you know a few times in my in my time
and I remember the very first time it
was like I was so devastated that first
time it was like you know Christmas was
ruined but then over time I'm like I've
become a little bit more like
desensitized to it I'm like okay cool I
I've lost like a couple of tops like
whatever but yeah for my personal
growing I've never had like too much an
issue with it with like some of my like
very first Blue Dream crops like the
more I would knock it out of the park
the worse the betrus would be cuz like
we just didn't have the humidity control
for end oflow out on the coast it was
always at like you know
80% um but I've lost when I was up in
Oregon I lost like a field to Bettis oh
and it's it's devastating you know what
I mean it's kind of funny that you bring
up the Blue Dream because um I actually
had one Santa Cruz wreck it was the
number three um that I had never uh
finished flowering it out cuz it it
showed signs of betrus early and I was
it was a crowded tent and I was like you
know what like it's just best to kind of
cut this thing down and not let it get
to the rest but yeah I mean that's kind
of I mean if it's one plant um in an
entire tent and you don't want to
sacrifice it like yeah I mean yeah
especially if like you're you're
Outdoors like that's when it's like
you're at the mercy of the weather you
you know what I mean and so like that
year I lost that field it started
raining September 1st and it didn't stop
for about six weeks and then the end of
October was like gorgeous you know just
to like rub it in a little bit you know
and so uh you can once it starts it's
not going to get better there's not a
single product that you can spray to
stop betrus once it's actually going and
a lot of betrus itself is actually like
a hodgepodge of a few different fungi
and so um and they're all like not
treatable and so it's usually time to
cut it down the other thing I've noticed
too with petritis is a lot of times like
the bud can look fine on the outside but
like the inside is where it's [ __ ] up
bro yeah and that's why like um your IPM
going into flower like we were talking
earlier is super important because even
if you do have something that you don't
mind spraying partway through flow
that's like a little more inert like an
enzyme spray or something it's not going
to get into those internal crevices of a
flower and that's where those mold
spores because like betrus is like a
metropolitan fungi is what they call it
it is in the Airstream like all over the
world and so like it's all about just
like not creating conditions for it and
so your IPM early on is going to dictate
whether it's going to be a big problem
for you later because um a few early
sulfur sprays to kill those um mold
spores off and kind of inhibit them
early on can go pretty far later on
which is saving you a whole world of
hurt yeah I was going to say to locco
like you know you build up you build up
that like fear of seeing those like
Twisted little leaves and stuff you know
yeah yeah I just never really I I I've
had it on my like the outdoor plants
here but I've not had it inside um I say
pretty on top of it or I try to like
between runs I you know I take
everything out and you know clean it
with like hot bleach water and stuff
like that like you know I really do just
I just try to like focus on keeping my
grow environment just like fairly clean
generally speaking and that seems like
it helps for me yeah that is huge like
some zerotol sprays or like peroxy
acetic acid with bleach um or even just
bleach bleach is great um I got to the
point um when I was at like a slightly
smaller commercial scale where I would
literally atomize the entire room with
zerol and bleach waterer and like I'm
hitting the lights I'm hitting the
tables I'm hitting the walls and ceiling
like a good reset and keeping clean all
the way through is a really big for the
fungi
problems yeah yeah I mean I when you
guys were talking about IPM like I it's
I it's not the best thing to say but I
don't do a ton of IPM because I just
really stay on top of that stuff and
like I just haven't seen those issues
you know if I do see something obviously
I'll address it but like since my very
first like the very first video I had I
got spider mes uh from a
friend and then otherwise that was such
a terrible experience that I was just
like I'm gonna stay on top of this you
know what I mean I was I was just like
really upset to like lose I didn't
really lose but I just felt like I could
have done so much better and all these
things I was like I just need to stay on
top yeah like keep your system closed
loop the more you intake um the more you
intake stuff from outside like just the
higher chances you're going to get bugs
and so like if you don't clone trade and
you just pop seeds and stuff the chances
of you having anything but like a little
bit of Attis on your biggest buds is
like pretty low and so uh you can keep
on top of it a lot easier and so I
advise against clone trading for the
most part and also too like if you have
some even if you just have like one or
two plants outside like when you come
inside wash your hands you know stuff
like that like it's just just like
things that are uh pretty common sense
but um they can definitely go a long way
yeah and I guess to like a lot of the
new Growers like it's never too late to
start like an IPM like you're better off
starting off
earlier um but yeah yeah yeah before
there's a
problem um so just just little note Dan
do you have to go Dan I'm trick or treat
duties yeah yeah I gotta go take my boy
out it's his first like real Halloween
that he can kind of understand what's
happening you know we don't want to mess
with that yeah should we B you a for now
and then uh three of us can wrap up um
yeah yeah no that's awesome like thank
you guys for having me on again and um
had a great chat I always love
bullshitting with the boys and so um
thanks for saving the last three
recordings
buddy yeah no worries man my wife is a
little uh she's like are you done yet
and I'm like uh we got one more coming
up so yeah but I will I will see you all
again for this uh this Z sherb episode
that we keep alluding to I'll try to
give you a week off next week and then
we'll come back to it yeah yeah yeah for
sure well thank you
guys I'll see you later later have a
good time well I guess for us it's just
like rounding this out now I mean is
they is there like anything else that
youall want to say about flowering or
like um maybe uh is it worth talking
about your last whether you last
flowered anything interesting to
highlight um I guess uh the one thing to
highlight is like a lot of these um uh
bottled formulas or powdered formulas
whatever it maybe
um a lot of those are like not design
but like they're adver Iz for like nine
nine wheat crops right so like when
you're um growing like longer flowering
like this is a good one plants like I
don't know you kind of just want to
prolong those periods by like an extra
week or two if that makes sense like
just to compensate for any of the extra
weeks like that's kind of what I've I've
done um and it's helped
me um but yeah I don't know that's just
kind of one thing that's that's probably
where it's good to have some basic
understanding of like the distinct
stages right so at least you can
translate like the time frames
um yeah yeah and like I've said like my
issues mainly been like a potassium
deficiency like towards like the end of
flower and I mean now I know next time
it it's just to kind of supplement a
little extra potassium just to kind of
keep the plant covered up until
then
but yeah that's really it like I by no
means am I an expert on like feeding
plants at all like none of my plants
look 100% happy by any means but yeah
yeah absolutely I mean it's it's
definitely I think that's the biggest
thing that I would try to impress on
people is that it's there's you know
like you're you're gonna get to a place
where you're growing stuff that you're
happy with but you're probably always
going to feel like you can make your
plants look
better you know I mean yep and
so they're just you just have to find
that place that's like a comfortable
medium for you I think yeah and I you
know I I said this the last time but I
didn't qualify it for this recording but
like one of the reasons why I've chosen
the three of you is because there's a
really nice spread of like experience
you know we have ER who's a bit newer
growing for a couple of years local
Maybe maybe like what a decade local or
more slightly more no no no no no not
not a decade just yet no um seven years
at Max I want to say seven years okay
okay and then Dan you know with like I
think about 15 if I that would have had
me growing at the age of
15 well Dan sat when he was 17 when did
you start uh it started when I was
18 that's early man that's still really
early but I think my point was also that
like one we have a spread of experiences
just to like you know showcase that
because I think that's good information
and of itself but also like Ern said
like no matter where you are there's
always something that like you could
improve still like I don't think anyone
you at any point is like yeah it's
perfect all the
time yeah and I just like also want to
say each plant's like a new adventure
like every seed you pop like you're
never gonna know until you like flower
it
so exactly exactly I don't know like
some things like to take care of
themselves and that's like always a
[ __ ] bonus but then there are those
instances where there's just you know
some parents just aren't the happiest
parents you know what I mean like so
some of the off Offspring might like
express some of those like sensitive
traits or you know stuff like that but
yeah I don't know yeah you're right you
may as well kind of treat it like every
time you grow something new it's like a
new game almost um you have some of the
of course your Baseline like protocols
but apart from that it's like you're
just going to have to react slash like
rerun yeah and it was pretty cool too
I'll say like popping like the eveve
appy and like all the Santa Cruz wck too
like each like individual has its
different needs and like that's just an
entire different game on its own like
you know and they're they're from the
same like parents you know and like
you'll have some that like take care of
themselves some that need a little more
babying than others you know this and
that but yeah I know ER wanted to say
something but sorry about that oh no
you're good dude no I uh I think you
kind of covered it mostly I think I
think something that I would say is like
maybe I don't hear a lot of people talk
about that they sometimes have plants
that just don't look good for them you
know um and it's okay if you if you run
something and you just don't like it you
know I think like we really like talk
about keeping stuff around a lot and
learning stuff and stuff like that but
like there can come a time
where uh you know sometimes like you
just don't have to force it you know
just like have a good time just like
remember why you started growing that
kind of stuff I I'm very much about that
you know like I want there to be good
vibes and that kind of
stuff absolutely I think that's a nice
sentiment for
sure if I mean anything else guys if not
we can probably start wrapping up I can
start on like the
outro um I know you're probably gonna
plug the Discord but like if anybody has
like questions or any of that [ __ ] like
you know we're always on the Discord
so yeah
yeah yes
definitely yep yep we're just dudes that
growing weed like like everyone else so
you know like we like talking about that
too so please
come well you two already there but any
shout outs from either of you for
anything from the Discord yeah I mean
shout out to Matt for always uh like
having us on you know letting us shoot
the [ __ ] with each other but yeah also I
just wanted to say too Denali sent me
some really cool Disc Off SW this week
and it was like I know that it was very
meaningful and I just want to say shout
out to I love you you're the best yeah
D's the [ __ ] best
dude yeah Denali is great he's uh trying
to Blackmail me says he won't come on
the show unless I like visit you guys
we'll see
um but yeah I mean shout out to you guys
thank you so much um for coming on the
show local especially like what like
yeah it's going to have like two or
three recordings in a row so I
appreciate that a lot um yeah shout out
to Dan and NN of course for making the
time as well and yeah lastly shout out
to Matt just for like doing all of this
and letting us like also run the show um
I think it's also for him like a nice
thing I think he's he has wanted to get
to the point where he could trust other
people to like handle the show if if
he's busy um so I think he's also really
stoked about you know where this is all
heading Ed um but I'm sure we will
welcome him back very
soon um apart from that I just want to
say that like Dan mentioned we are
lining up a skills episode as we've said
um just takes a little bit more prep
because we want Dan has a few questions
that he wants
to um get sent to CSI so Matt's going to
facilitate some questions to Caleb that
will be part of the show Lo will join us
as well um and we'll talk about uh some
of the uh hunting that he's doing
through some sure best ones apart from
that we've also probably got a harvest
and post Harvest episode uh coming up
initially I thought this was just for
the outdoor group but now that we've
done this one here and maybe that we
just combine forces and just do like
Harvest and post Harvest like as a you
know just like a combined group because
you know I don't think it yeah obviously
that like goes across like indoor and
outdoor grind so we'll see I'll see how
how people are like positioned for that
um other than that Riot seeds.com uh
rioto Europe for those of you in Europe
we have G by seeds run by our um homie
MADD Boo for those of you in
Australia uh of course check out the
patreon which is how you can get onto
our Discord we we always talk about the
Discord we was R about it I I'm almost
at the point where I'm like maybe we
should like
not push it so high because sounds culty
but it is a great place so we do
recommend it um and lastly we've got the
Codex um do check that out if you
haven't already put some more pressure
on Matt to add more entries or update
them um we also hope to get Bodie on to
help us with that once he's settled
in
um yeah thank you everyone again for
showing up on this Friday night um
thanks again you guys for setting aside
your Halloween night to do this and we
will catch you all next week bye
everyone later y
[Music]
later want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it
out