welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
[Music]
revolution
welcome Breer Syndicate I'm Matthew and
I'm here with my co-host thousandfold
and today we're going to be talking to
Big earns spindle and local all from our
can can Illuminati group so welcome
fellas thousand take it
away yeah welcome everyone so sort of
like the outdoor growing episode we're
hoping to start a little like recurring
indoor growing series and today we're
bringing on as Matt mentioned some of
our homies and we're going to talk
through some for this episode some
pretty basic basic uh indoor growing
topics and then uh at the end we'll
we'll kind of conclude with like a more
open kind of philosophical question
about you know what people think makes
for a good growth um but to kick things
off and to warm everyone up I thought we
would just go around and talk about how
long have you been growing and what have
you been growing recently or now uh
maybe we start with spindle Michael
so I grew my very first plant in
1995 I think it
was um and I just had started some seeds
I worked at a golf course at the time
and there was an area off of the 13th
hole that kind of had some trees and
brush that they didn't clean up and I
just put some five gallon buckets out
there with some seeds and grew my first
plants that
way um and it actually came out pretty
decent um I think probably by 96 I
started my first
indoor that I could really call growing
you know otherwise it was just a couple
plants I'd water a few times during the
summer well I'm going to ask you each
I'm going to ask each of you more about
like the actual Journey um but for now
Michael what what have you been growing
recently recently uh I've been growing
some super
boof some Sour from
NATO some some of Matt's Riot Berry
which was excellent some uppercut from
Caleb uh some big sir from Caleb and uh
just getting into some new stuff from
pack some of the blue dreams and stuff
like that oh yeah yep that's quite the
lineup and then I always I always have a
few quines in every run H quinby yep
yeah that's a recurring feature of of
your Runs huh that's great
absolutely yeah all right we'll
definitely come back to some of those
PLS later um how about
Ern yeah so I probably have been uh
growing the the shortest period of time
out of all these people I've been I
started growing um in
um and just you know kind of got like a
clone from a
friend that also didn't know what they
were
doing and uh gave me spider mes on my
very first grow you know that kind of
stuff um and then uh just like really
quck I've always been like the kind of
person that like hops into Hobbies like
head first and that's what I am for this
is just like super hobbyist and you know
just getting to kind of like live like
my 18-year-old like dream of like being
able to grow this [ __ ] that I saw on
High Times you know what I mean and yeah
so it's been a cool it's cool and as far
as like what I've been running lately is
you know stuff from the dudes in the
group um I've got several appalache
things going uh from high and
lome we're both East Coast you know and
uh I like really have this like thing
about like wanting to support people
that are like local and like get stuff
that's like being bred in my area and
stuff like that so I've been trying to
support that um and obviously he's just
like a sick [ __ ] dude so like it's
cool yeah you just happen to be uh
supporting like one of the best breeders
in America yeah of course it's easy to
support when it's like dank you know
what I mean but it's like so yeah I have
like some of his um uh like a Bubba
times dy I have a Santa Cruz wck times
appy I have some appy f3s going just ran
his mule skinners so I'm like really
trying to look through his stuff you
know when are you two going on the
fishing trip I don't know but soon
hopefully anytime whenever that'd be
cool dude that'd be real cool that's so
cute I'm Jelly jealous yeah um all right
local how long have you been growing and
what are you growing now um yeah so I
started uh actually like flowering
plants in
2016 um so what is that like six seven
years
um and right now currently I'm running
uh some uh ashter uh Death Star um
Band-Aid hay 7 and then Santa Cruz wck
number
six um from pack there's no reason to be
putting asteris on that goddamn death
that drives me nuts dude that's Death
Star it's funny give us some tell us
about the asterisk one of you um I don't
know I don't get it so I don't know I
don't know if
it's act I don't know what it is it's
just dank you know like it was it I I
mean it's just very it's just a cut
that's very hard to trace provenance on
like from the dire it came but like for
the people who have experienced death
star before and had it from like death
star crew it's Death Star it's
definitely definitely Death Star if not
it's it's like the most perfect Death
Star reproduction ever you know either
way I'll say as well that that asterisk
tells you so much about how much these
guys care about what they know or don't
know and it's yeah I think it's really
sweet I guess I can also add that within
like the last year it seems like
everyone and their [ __ ] mom's popping
out with the Death Star so I don't know
it's just like what what the hell
Grandma's Death Star it made it out of
it made it out of circles right like it
used to be a cut that was only in
certain circles you could only get it
feed certain circles but it's one of the
few that like the real cut made it out
of those circles into places where
people were selling clones on the Clone
market and because of that it's
accessible and it's one of the few that
like I think is a really dank line that
made it into the Clone market like the
actual cut and in this case it's a good
thing or probably would be
gone yeah yeah um in in hearing from you
all I did actually want to draw on one
thing I think the earn was getting into
um so we'll do another I want to do
another round here in this warmup which
is what did it feel like that very first
time you actually flowered something
that very first time CU recently right I
got this feel and it's totally unrelated
like loc has been setting up um new like
fish tanks for
himself and it kind of gave me that
sense of like it reminded me of that Joy
when I first set up like my first like
growing
space um and I kind of wanted to yeah I
kind of wanted to hear from each of you
like what that moment was like when you
were first like actually growing you
know whenever you think that was um can
start with Michael
again uh uh to be honest thousand it was
uh about 100%
fear just being super scared of getting
caught yeah um having to go in the
middle of the night to uh cut the plant
down and just hoping I don't get pulled
over on the way home with
it that's for real yeah like I'd like to
be like oh it was so awesome it was
awesome once it was dried and I was back
at home you know with with uh the plants
but the actual uh the process doing the
pro the process was super scary yeah I
bet you taking it home would have been
freaky that time as well but yeah it it
was nerve-wracking but you know once it
was in the closet and I could actually
look at it in light because I was always
going at night to water and stuff and
seeing like the nice pinks and purples
on it like I was I was pretty pretty
[ __ ] stoked you know and I was proud
of myself you
know it's nice being able to do
something for yourself especially when
you're young you know I think that's
gonna make this this whole conversation
pretty interesting right is like there's
several different generations of Growers
here from from Modern Times uh that have
only grown indoor to like my generation
and then all the way back to Michaels
because he was growing well before me
you know all the way back he's not that
old man like he's so much older bro he
was growing in the old days bro well
what what's a real kick in the balls is
these guys like local and Panda that
have been growing for like such a short
amount of time and they just hit home
run after home run yeah like see their
pictures and it's just like oh what the
[ __ ] you know what it reminds me of is
like in skateboarding like back in the
day when when I would be skateboarding
and doing tricks like we'd be busting
like 360 flips thinking we were just so
good you played like the Tony Hawk game
and see all this crazy [ __ ] you could do
in the game and now I go on Instagram
and watch kids doing the Tony Hawk moves
real in real life and I couldn't even
comprehend the gravity physics of any of
it it reminds me a lot of that with
these guys like I didn't have a quick
start I had a brown thumb I had a lot of
failing to do but like er even just
since he's been in our group I've
watched him progress just like and like
jump me like a lot and how and how his
product turns out routinely and that's
that's something else man it's something
else to watch yep yeah awesome yeah yeah
for the record I should say that for
myself I've been growing only for about
four years as well so I'm in between ER
and local in terms of Growing Experience
or at least time I could
say um er yeah what was that initial
moment like for you whenever you think
that was yeah I mean I can remember it
like full on like you know um ordering I
you know I started indoors so like I
ordered like some shitty like mors Hydro
kit and like got like a 4x4 tint with
like a light and everything I'm like
setting all this [ __ ] up in my basement
just stoked you know what I mean like
super excited about it um I had like a
whole 4x4 ENT for one clone to start
because I just like had no other seeds
or anything and I was just so like and I
would just like sit down there with a
chair and with my tent open and just
like smoke a joint and just like watch
this [ __ ] plant you know what I mean
like what I don't know what I was doing
but I was just so into it you know what
I mean I was just like man like I've
wanted to do this for so long and like
just like for whatever reasons I haven't
been able to and now I'm able to and I'm
just like it's just so cool to me um I
still definitely have that feeling like
when I like like I have the like you
know whatever some some plant that I'm
super stoked about and I'm getting ready
to flip it I'm just like dude I'm so
[ __ ] stoked to just see what's going
to come out you know what I mean um so
it's still really fun to
me hell yeah
local um so my first time like actually
getting set up growing I mean I was like
maybe 18 or something like that um and
was obviously kind of broke so like I
bought piece by piece um throughout like
the the first growth cycle um but like
it was still fun to watch it because
like it was you know it was growing but
I had like a shitty uh vipar Spectra or
something like that um and a 2x4 t0 and
kind of just uh went with it nothing
great but uh started learning each round
after that
so I guess that says something
thing was it like a a particularly scary
or you know exciting moment for you um
that was in a really like uh weird you
know uh place in my life where I just
didn't care about stuff so not
really um yeah but yeah that's really
that's an interesting
contrast yeah it is I mean yeah it's the
different Generations though you
know yeah yeah I mean you don't have to
tell us but I mean it's a context for
this because you weren't necessarily
like I don't know like it it wasn't a
passion when you started is that
accurate or like why why were why were
you so kind of like I don't know uh
epoe um I guess it was more so that I
was interested in growing things like
just plants in general um
and when you're broke you don't want to
[ __ ] buy weed bro like that's the
last thing you want to spend money on
especially when eights are 45 bucks a
piece it's like [ __ ] that dude yeah all
right that makes sense that makes
sense um I wonder if Matt actually wants
to tell us about his first kind of
moments um you know like I've talked
about it before but my first uh moment
after after I was on my own and decided
I was going to grow by myself um I
thought I was going to be smart and
avoid paying all this high dollar for
lights right because I figured I would
outsmart everyone so I went to um
Walmart and got uh some hallogen grow
lights that they called them hallogen
grow lights and they were just basically
hogen heat lamps and I tried growing a
Seedling from Bad Seed with this
hallogen seed lamp and it was the most
painful thing
when I when I showed my friend who was
another grower at the time that that was
way more advanced than me and I showed
him and I was all proud of this and I
was like is it supposed to be like this
and it was like a Seedling like you know
a foot tall with like just little cot
leens on it he's like dude put that out
of its misery now and I remember feel so
heartbroken what you can save it it's
alive I'm not killing it he's like bro
kill that please and yeah so mine was
not a good experience mine was a very
disheartening experience it was one of
those times where I had to realize just
cuz you think you're like smart at [ __ ]
like you can't just run head first into
something that you know nothing about
like going from my dad's [ __ ] when I was
a kid to that was just night and day I
had no place that you I could outsmart
anyone so that was a big learning curve
you know yeah I spent a good month
wasting time on that bean pull of the
seedling
yeah yeah cuz I mean it's really nice to
hear from you all about about yeah how
you started because I think as we've
already seen like it's very different
for different people um in different
contexts
um how we also kind of came
to how' I put it how we got to This
indoor growing episode actually was I
was actually trying to figure out a
hydro episode with spindle here and
unfortunately we couldn't get we
couldn't we didn't manage to convince B
to come on and so we kind of adapted
this to a more General like indel
growing episode um and in that time I
was starting to think more and more
about less about the tech you know less
just like isolated conversations about
tech and and and and gear and stuff and
more about oh I actually wonder what
people's Journeys you know individually
were like um Michael I think you you
started to get to this in your intro um
I'd like to know
like how did you get to the system or
setup that you're using now you know how
long did that take how you know uh from
a very broad you know perspective um
yeah I'd like to hear from each of you
about this like how how long did it take
for you to develop your system to where
it is and what were some of the major
lessons along the
way I think in in the beginning it was
really hard because I would buy like
High Times or uh cannabis Canada
Cannabis culture magazines and I'd see
the Articles and I'd see the like the
metal HED lights and stuff like that but
uh there was nowhere in Eugene that I
could find that stuff for sale so me and
my buddies would have to drive all the
way to Portland just to find a store
that actually sold the lighting
itself you know like uh I wish I wish
those tents would have came out I don't
know when people
started uh buying the grow tents or they
started being made but uh man I wish
those would have been around you you
know when I was younger CU those things
are just super
convenient um as far as the system my
first closet grow was in just uh
soil you know um I kept doing you know
after that first successful one I kept
doing research and I'd see articles and
uh one of my buddies approached me with
uh setting up his garage to do like a
nutrient fil
technique and we just bought a bunch of
gutters from Home Depot and we'd let the
water pass through and the plants sat in
the gutters uh raised up on like hydron
uh little
baskets you know and we had a good run
in the winter and then the summer the
run just completely turned to [ __ ]
because at the time I didn't understand
but it was the heat of the water like
once the the garage started heating up
the water temperature started heating up
up we started getting bacteria
everywhere that's the dep of it dude
yeah and we didn't have anyone to ask
yeah no there was there was no YouTube
to look up videos on how to do it um so
really it took me a good five or six
years to even figure out why that run
didn't work yeah you know so I had tried
the nutrient film technique uh I tried
eban Flo once I moved to California that
one seemed real simple a lot of a lot of
work um and then I
saw somebody on the old forums uh you
know what I think it was Ivan I don't
remember what he went by it was uh
something Jack Mayer Jack mayhoffer
yeah yeah I saw him do like a a post
with he was using cocoa I think but it
was drained to waste yeah yeah and uh
when I saw the drained to waste it just
all clicked to me because I was like oh
my God that is so so much
easier so much more precise and I can
just use uh you know a little condens
scent pump to get rid of all the runoff
you know and there's not going to be any
mess and uh so once I saw those posts
and I wanted to try it myself it I knew
I before doing it I knew it was going to
be the easiest way for me you know and
now that I'm older i' you know I'd love
to be an organic Gardener but I simply
don't have the
time you know with working as much as I
do and the amount of work it takes and I
don't want to have any failed runs I'm
getting older I want to make sure every
run that I do I get to see the potential
of the plants maybe it's not the you
know 100% greatest organic knock it out
of the park but it's always good with
the system that I run yeah you know it's
easy to dial
in I agree yeah yep yeah so you've kept
this current system for how long would
you say at least like you know
Loosely uh drained waste I've been doing
for 10 years
wow could you okay I'm pretty I'm a
little bit ignorant about nutrient film
like could you give us a like a very
like you know High L okay so imagine um
have you ever seen an arrow cloner yeah
okay so the plant basically is suspended
above where the water passes
through and The Roots just hang down and
we use you can use uh PVC pipes or
gutters or whatever and a constant flow
of water with nutrients in it is always
bathing the roots but it never stands
still so the water's always moving all
the time it's a little different than um
like let's say uh what is it oh God the
one where the water deep water culture
yeah recirculate deep water culture it's
different than that where in in that
system the water sits pretty uh stable
in one spot and then you air rate that
water yeah this one the water's always
moving it's always passing through yeah
which is also why when it gets heated
and a little bit warmer all the water
stays warm and it gets really super
aerobic yep crazy yep it's definitely
it's it's super difficult you'd have to
you'd have to spend the money and really
be on your game to have like a large
scale nutrient film technique down yeah
some dudes had it down but it yeah
exactly it took chillers and all kinds
of stuff right a lot of expenses
and one problem overnight your plants
would be dead like if a pump went out or
something or your Chiller went out you
could be pretty much finished in 24
hours yeah I like I grow in rock Hool
now for the drained waste because I can
get away with a lot if something breaks
and I don't see it for 12 or 14 hours
the plants are still fine yeah you know
I've I've gone more than 24 hours
without watering in wol before and still
been able to pick up and just go oh yeah
you know so it's it's very flexible
I did have a general question for you
about you know the very broad field of
hydro would you say that over the last
few
years one technique has kind of emerged
as the most popular or favorite and is
it this one is what biger would call The
Meta oh uh drained
waste absolutely yeah like if you're
doing anything on
scale um which I'm not but if you were
like like uh one of the big facilities
I'm pretty sure 90 95% of them are
running drained to
waste yeah you know yeah yeah yeah
that's interesting so over time people
have converged like towards this this
approach yeah that's cool yeah I'd say
for uh the deep water culture that seems
like mainly a a small homow yeah
situation where someone wants to grow
two or three huge plants I rarely see
anybody stick with dwc for like a whole
career of growing it's usually like a uh
a path someone takes for a while you
know but there are people who have it's
just so rare to see someone be like a
hardcore rdwc dude you know see it seems
like a lot of extra work it's a lot man
that's what I was gonna say that's
that's I I did that for a little bit is
it's a lot it's a lot of work you go in
you tell us about yeah tell us about
what you learned yeah so yeah I mean I
started with soil just like like Happy
Frog or whatever you know like from the
hydro shop and got some like the general
Hydro One Part nutrient to start it's
like a flora Nova and like a wait sorry
can I just ask you here were you
watching Mr [ __ ] Mr kanuck oh absolutely
I watch Mr kanuck his [ __ ] editing is
next level I mean like as far as like
cool looking weed Mr kanuck he so he's
just his like he has really good editing
nice
cameras Shout Out Mr Kut
[Laughter]
bro so I'm not I'm not gonna trash this
dude anyways but yeah yeah yeah so um I
yes I was watching stuff like that and
was
um I went to the hydroponic store talk
to this guy he sells me a bunch of [ __ ]
that I don't need basically and I go
home and just you know grow some shitty
plants for a little bit you know yeah um
and then I got really at some point I
don't know why but I got really obsessed
with
like the fact with like soil that like I
couldn't control like like if there was
some kind of nutrient excess or you know
or whatever it was I just couldn't
control it quickly enough you know what
I mean so would like I got obsessed with
this feeling of like needing to be able
to like really monitor each of those
parameters with like pH and stuff which
is what led me into dwc yeah so I went
to dwc and um you know I'm not growing
at scale either but I am doing like a
Perpetual kind of deal and um I had this
one run where like a lot I'm going to
Echo a lot of the same stuff spindle
said um I had this one I had this one
run where I was growing autos at this
point in uh dwc which like woo dude
crush me you know what I'm saying right
and um they uh they were looking great
one day I mean like great D like the
best plants I've ever grown and then the
next day they're like drooping in brown
and I was like what is going on you know
and I'm like trying to save these plants
and I couldn't you know like they died
like like three plants died and uh that
was like my first real failure where I
was like I couldn't didn't get anything
from the grow you know what I mean um
and was like midflower you know and I
put a lot of time into it so I was like
man that's sucks so I started reading
into it and stuff checking my water
temperature really frequently I ran into
the same thing water temperature starts
getting up to like 72 something like
that you need to be like 65 so I'm like
I'm looking at like water chillers and
I'm like man I'm going to have I'm
running like a 4x4 and a 2x4 and I'm
going to buy a water chiller for each
tent like are you kidding me that's $700
in water and I was like no I'm not doing
that so so that was the end of my deep
water culture career I did like a couple
runs in it and it really taught me a ton
about just like managing pH and managing
PPM and stuff like that but it was just
too expensive for what I was going and I
also wanted to be able to hunt like you
know a good population size and that was
tough for me to do in deep deep
articulture as
well and you know you ALS there's a lot
of things you also if it's recirculating
then you you know there's you have like
all the plants are Fe feeding from the
same Reservoir so then like you aren't
it's I mean that's not accurate you know
you're not controlling like what each is
getting and stuff so it's just a lot of
things um so then I ended up um coming
back into oil and tried to do the
organic kind of deal for a little bit
which realistically was me using organic
nutrients and doing drain to
waste um you know and so I wouldn't
necessarily even say like I'm not going
to sit here and tell you I'm an organic
you know I you know what I mean that I
have any real good uh base for that um
but that led me up into where just one
drained to waste cocoa with can of
nutrients and I went down to just
Baseline Cana a&amp; grew plants for a few
runs with that and then now I'm adding
stuff in to just like see how it affects
stuff um because I was adding like
silica and all this all these different
like additives and just not really
having like an understanding of like why
I was doing it you know so oh yeah let's
come back to silica lighter because I
think it's one of those ones um so your
current approach earn how long have you
been
doing that um you say it's pretty stable
now yeah I mean basically I've been
doing the same stuff uh for I don't know
I've ran through I'm on my second bottle
of Cana now so I don't know how long
that think you know I mean not that long
I mean I've only been growing for two
years so you know who
knows but I I just feel like I've I've
done I did a bunch of approaches like
really quickly because I just wanted to
see it all you know what I mean um yeah
and now have settled on the drained ways
kind of thing and yeah yeah remind me to
come back to like uh additives later uh
I think we'll we'll have a nutrients
kind of recap later but yeah okay um
local tell us about your you know
current system how you got there yeah so
right now I'm running um Coco trained to
was
um using uh Cana
amb um I've been rocking I'll just say
one thing before we get any fur because
I know three of us use Cana we are not
sponsored Affiliated we're not marketing
for Cana just Happ and step you know we
like it sorry local um you're all good
dude um so I've been rocking that for
about um well not Cana for two years
three well three years now [ __ ] uh um
but I've been doing uh cocoa drain to
waste for three years
um and I kind of got into that because I
was you know doing organic uh air quote
organic grows indor and wanted a little
more control more um you know uh space
to pop seeds um so Coco is my best
option
yep y any like in terms of like what you
experienced like did you go have to go
through any like I don't know big
failures or anything like that um my
first one um which was overfeeding some
plants not all plants responded
negatively uh because I was um my first
run of Coco was using Jack
321 um and it it was a little high Inn
for some
varieties um
um so you know some things weren't the
best other things were pretty good but
then I switched over to something that
was um you know a little less
uh highend nitrogen um or at least had
you know calcium heavily associated with
nitrogen I don't know I I don't think
it's a
good source for every variety per se for
calcium but yeah when when you use Jacks
do they still have like have a is it a
bright blue color still um I remember
one solution being blue I don't remember
which one but it was like blue and then
kind of like a brownish one yeah because
I always when back in the day the first
time I ever tried Jag I remember being
like the super bright blue and I was
like why do they add dye to their
nutrients like that's so weird like a
can't want die you know yeah I'm not
sure maybe it's just like the raw for I
don't know the form that it comes in I
don't know like it's weird yeah but I
don't know no
clue um while yall were talking I did
kind of have some thoughts around some
of the trade-offs between like the
various Styles and for me one of the
things that seems to be
common between you know quotequote
organic and quotequote
hydro is there's some degree of
finessing and troubleshooting before you
arrive at like a stable
approach would you all agree with that
like it feels to me like for both of
them once you've kind of dialed it in
enough you can kind of take it for
granted at that point and kind of run
with it and the interesting thing for me
as someone who you is still like you
know peep based po
is that um you know one of the
trade-offs there is that I don't have to
do as much kind of fine tuning I'm kind
of buffered and like kept safe you know
in certain ways from things but I may
not at the same time achieve like say
quite the same degree of like stability
as like a hydr grow or you know
something like that yeah what are your
thoughts on some of these things I
imagine I imagine some of you have
facted these things in like what the
risks are you know setup
costs uh stability you know those kinds
of
trade-offs kind of open to the floor
just kind of riffing a bit you know um
oh go for it no go ahead loo please um
yeah so I was just gonna say um you know
one of the big uh drivers for me
switching to Coco is um I wanted to have
you know the growth of a hydrop plant
but not have to invest in an entire you
know Hydro type setup so Coco you know I
can handw waterer it and get really
really good results and you know really
fast growth in a tiny container so I
thought it was a really cheap approach
to having a semi-productive
system yeah totally you know sometimes I
think uh one of the things with like you
can grow organic in Pete right like
that's more of a soil
mix thousand yeah yeah I think um what's
nice about growing that way is you have
uh like a higher
floor you know you yes you it's it's
easy it's not a lot of work to come out
with um a really like a good product
yeah you know like you'd have to really
[ __ ] something up to grow garbage that
way you know whereas like if you take a
hydro system um a couple mistakes or a
couple misunderstandings about certain
things you can grow some really shitty
weed you know fragile yeah yeah I think
that's one of the benefits of doing it
the way that you do it um I also think
it's a lot harder to hit this like a
really high ceiling with Organic I think
you need to really really be good and be
on your game have an understanding of
what you're feeding and when and when
those nutrients are
available that I think is a lot easier
to hit um in Hydro you know I like that
you know and I consider what local does
hydro as well even if it's not a system
you know because he's controlling what
the plants are feeding and what's
available to them all the time you know
um going back to like the Ean flow and
the deep water culture what I didn't
like about those systems is that number
one you have to completely empty um the
reservoir like dump it all out and then
change it every week because the plant
as it's getting watered especially if
the water is recirculating all the time
it's going to pull what it wants out
right away so early in the week it's
getting everything it want wants whereas
as the week
progresses those nutrients are going to
be less and less available to the plant
because it's already drank them and what
that also does is that alters the pH of
what's available to the plants so you're
having to stay on top of it whereas the
way uh I think all three of us are doing
it now we always know the plants pH is
the same wherever we want it and it's
always getting a constant supply of the
nutrients
um that it wants and has available to it
you know um so you're not having to
worry about certain things getting low
when we don't have the big systems that
are monitoring what's you know coming
out of the plant after
water yeah yeah I mean that's kind of
like when I had that kind of experience
in dwc where You' get into late flower
and the plants would just not really be
eating and they' just be drinking more
than they're eating and then all of
sudden you check your Reservoir and your
pH is like went from 6.2 to like 5.5
overnight you know what I mean it's like
your EC just shot shot up yeah right and
now you're like trying to like do this
math in your head like how the [ __ ] do I
how much water do I add back in to cut
this like you know it's just a lot of
variables and there's been a lot of
these times where I'd be in my basement
just [ __ ] dumping water everywhere
you know what I mean just [ __ ]
getting rid of those reservoirs and it's
just it's a lot of work man if you're
just in your basement like dumping
buckets of water it's a lot yeah if
you're lucky enough to have a drain in
your basement yeah I have a I have a I
have a soap pump down there thank God
you know yeah dude that it's a nightmare
I keep just thinking about that in
California where there aren't many
basements yeah yeah I mean and you're
talking like sometimes you know if you
have say you have four plants with a
reservoir that's like damn near 20
gallons of water yeah you know what I
mean that's a lot of water a lot of
nutrients a lot of
everything yeah yeah yeah and I think
it's it's really interesting there all
these different ways of evaluating these
different grow approaches like I really
like what spindle said about basically I
think he was unpacking what consistency
means in a way like having a higher
floor but maybe like a lowest ceiling is
is like more consistency and that's a
tradeoff right but then you have
different kind of tradeoffs like like I
was saying with um Hydro or soiless if
you have a system for it the trade-off
is that the labor is not necessarily
during the run when you have fine-tuned
everything but it is the process of
actually fine-tuning it all to begin
with and getting it stable to begin with
that's where the labor goes for organic
it's it's similar in the sense that like
your ability to prepare your soil
troubleshoot it test it all of that is
upfront labor that once you've yeah sure
once you've kind of gone through that um
then your growths are like you know
easier but you have to do all that labor
up front um and then if you're in like a
you know you're hand watering and you're
you know potting mix or whatever like me
the labor is constant right it's about
hand watering and keeping an eye on
things and tailoring stuff to that yeah
and the last sorry sorry you go you go
in no that's I was just gonna add that
that's kind of the thing that I like
about drained a waste is that it just
allows me to not think about the
nutrients anymore you know what I mean
to a certain degree I get to a point
where I can just mix my stuff I know
what my water is coming out whatever you
know I mix it I feed it and then I'm
able to just focus on a lot of other
things like just good watering practices
and like making sure your environment's
like in a good place and like making
sure that your plants are looking good
you know just things like that and I
think that that's just like much more
important than focusing on any certain
nutrient line in itself you know to a
degree and I definitely want to make
that point too because like yeah I've
grown good I what I think is good weed
with General Hydro with Roots organic
with like other you know tons of Brands
and like it's just more about like uh
paying attention to the plant and like I
think like good watering practices and
stuff
personally yeah yeah we definitely come
back to that about you go Michael sorry
thousand want to reiterate that I'm not
saying that organic has a low ceiling
because I'm saying like a really good
organic Gardener has organic really high
feeling
um more about
like yeah it's it's it's a lot um easier
to get to uh somewhat high ceiling in
Hydroponics than it is in organic it
takes I in my opinion it takes some real
skill to hit that high ceiling but
organic Gardener said do their products
absolutely
amazing yeah yeah yeah I should yeah
definitely not trying to imply that like
yeah I when I say like uh higher floor
lower ceiling I do mean that very
broadly and like that's still me me too
I don't want to offend anybody because
people get super [ __ ] pissed off and
I've SE amazing
organic there's a reason why we have
five people here so they we get if if we
get in trouble they have five targets
and we spit it out so we didn't gang up
take them out right five times one or
that too that
too um well I think the last the last
thing I think for me that emerged from
our conversation as well is like the
different forms of like Risk mitigation
so for example like again like Michael
was saying if something goes wrong for
me in like a Peete based potting mix um
there's usually time for me
to resolve that where is something going
wrong I imagine in like uh dwc setup
like Ern was saying it happens very very
fast um and your recovery window your
time your window in which to recover is
like much smaller
right yeah I mean this is cool I think
this is the reason again this is the
real reason I think why I wanted a bunch
of us on is because we could actually
talk through some of these like
nuances whereas you know you get those
like click baity videos that are like oh
Hydro versus Pete or like organic versus
synthetic outside of like any context
and like bad information I think yeah
yeah yeah yeah I think like any style if
you just take the time to learn it and
you know you're going to grow good weed
you know you just have to be willing to
learn how to grow plants that's
ultimately the end goal there you know
it doesn't matter about the nutrient
line you need to learn about like how to
grow
plants or like you just have to mentally
prepare yourself for someone in the
comments to be like so what's the best
approach right well there's no best
approach though that's the problem you
know what I mean the best approach is
what works for you you know yeah and
that's why I'm also like a big thing
about like getting seeds you know like
all everybody like when I came into
growing I saw all these websites selling
clones you know what I mean and I had no
idea what that was I mean you know I'm
just some random dude that like wanted
to try to grow weed and then I get
online and I see there's I can buy a cut
of literally you name it you can buy it
and it's like they're a thousand dollars
you know I don't know and um yes so I
just really think that people should get
seeds and find plants that grow good in
their environment and with their setup
and that's the way that you will find
good
week yeah yeah I think um we we
definitely approaching that that broad
topic of like you know what makes for a
good grow but before then I did want to
kind
of I think who who was I talking to
about this must been ear local we were
talking about uncertainty around popular
tives I thought that'd be an interesting
little uh segue into that so we were
talking about silica yeah right as one
of the additives that is very popular
and and commonly prescribed but also
like not not really
knowing with any certainty like whether
those things actually make a difference
kind of curious for like y'all to go
around and think about like I don't know
have there been additives that you've
used that you're like I don't know if
this is just Superstition or like I
don't know if this is just like Dogma or
you know whatever I mean silica is the
bat one for me that's a big one for me
um I think the conversation we were
having was about how I'm I'm always
trying to just figure out better ways to
like when to water my plants and like
when to like how like I don't know like
I don't really necessarily want to mix
every nutrient that I'm going to use
into a resz and just like feed it all in
one go sometimes I'll just break it up a
little bit you know um and I had mixed
some silica in with my Cana just to see
like what it would do and it
precipitated like pretty bad
um because silica like drives the P ph
up like insane and like all this stuff
and then it's like I don't know it just
that's one for me that like um I have
done it with and without side by side on
the same exact plant and I can't tell a
difference
personally oh I remember we were talking
to farad Dan as well and he was saying
that he did think there was a difference
in um I think he said it was like stem
thickness or something that he could
tell or
yeah youres I'm GNA kick all your asses
in the silica conversation right about
now which which kind of silic are you
using that's important um so I yeah so
I've used like a couple different kinds
but I mean like the dry potassium
silicate okay so that's that's one thing
that I think like you guys know me I am
dumb as [ __ ] when it comes to Organics
and nutrients like it just never been an
interest to mine but one thing I have
learned is that ium silicate is
something great in gardens if you're
like reusing your soil especially
because in cannabis it takes so long for
it be consumed so there's unless you're
reusing your soil and reusing your
medium throwing silica in in potassium
silic form isn't going to do much but
there is you know stuff like power SI
and again not sponsored here by anyone
but um Power SI which is a I've and I
was going to say I've used that one as
well when I was doing the deep water I
was using there and that's my favorite
thing but I don't use it the way
everybody else does because the way I
found it works best for me was adjusting
nitrogen deficiencies and like calcium
magnesium deficiencies on the fly
whenever I used it I would use it in
concert with other nutrients to make it
it would almost be like mainlining it to
the plant like watching watching it
change before my eyes like in within a
few hours I would see major changes in
how quickly it would uptake other
nutrients as far as what the the uh
monosilicic acid which is what power SII
is was doing itself I mean of course
it's going to increase the stem strength
and structure that's what silica does
and it's a more effective readily
available silica but how it helps carry
other nutrients is super super
interesting to watch and that's been my
favorite thing for it for when I screw
up my plants it helps me adjust it on
the Fly and get it back to peel like
instantly and and you always notice it
too because your P your plants will
immediately just go prey straight up
it's h quite good for it that's a that's
what I use as a ph up oh interesting
really the power SI no monocytic
acid power power SI I only use as a f
your feed oh interesting yeah because my
reservoir is sterile yeah yeah
interesting
yeah I certainly won't I can't say that
there's no benefit for silica obviously
I just think that like for me personally
like I've focused more on um like upping
calcium and just good watering practices
honestly like just knowing like just
like literally that on like I say that
all the time but no [ __ ] just like
waiting for the pot to be light and then
watering it then and like learning what
your pots feel like when they're light
and stuff like that has probably been
like the biggest thing that has made my
plants like look healthy I mean that is
I mean it's so e like if you get on
Reddit right now and you look at all the
beginner posts about like my plants look
like [ __ ] I bet 90% of them are just
overwatered oh I'm sure I'm sure
absolutely or not realizing about pH
fluctuations and thinking it's like the
wrong kind of nutrients am I using the
wrong kind of nutrients a lot of times
it's just not even phing their plants
and just not uptaking the nutrients at
all I mean we can do a little segue and
talk about like troubleshooting cuz I
think that as a as a kind of process as
well cuz I think that sort of to me it's
kind of interesting as someone who's
still pretty new like if you see
something going wrong you know where
does your brain first go and what are
the kind of like successive stages like
like Ern said for me initially I always
did assume it was watering because for
whatever reason for the first couple of
years it was that was a hard thing to
figure out or I don't know why like the
dry wet cycle thing was just like I
don't know why it was still confusing to
me but I'm kind of curious to know
whether y'all have like any kind
ofh I don't know any kind of sequence um
of of parameters to look through when
you're troubleshooting a
problem maybe start with local Local's
been real quiet has he passed out yeah I
don't I don't even know what additives
Local's using and I want to know that
too um yeah so um I guess in terms of
additives the way I kind of see
additives is um if all your Essentials
are in check then like additives are
really cool but it's like
sometimes it it might be best to adjust
your main feed and then consider
additives after the fact and I think ER
was kind of mentioning that in his uh
working with
Cana um you know but I think that's kind
of the way I see additives is using them
um have you seen any uh any real
benefits from any particular additive
local um I guess it depends what you're
trying like to achieve like if it's an
actual like deficiency maybe like or
maybe you want to add a little more
extra
like I don't know calcium like I don't
know uh pcal is pretty nice I like that
that's helped me a lot I don't use it
every watering maybe like once every
other week or
something um but can you tell us a b
more about that one yeah
um uh calcium phosphate I think is like
the is the the chemical um nomenclature
if you will um but it's uh has a good
amount of calcium and a good amount of
uh
phosphorus um it's it's it's a nice
additive for like flour um yeah I really
like it as well I don't like lack
calcium by any means but like it doesn't
hurt to add a little extra um I also
find that under LEDs your plants will
definitely benefit from calcium you know
or other additives just CU yeah they're
metabolizing you know maybe a little
faster or whatever um
but yeah that's kind of my take on
additives have you played with anything
else that's been interesting you know um
no not really
um I really all I use is a Cana AB maybe
some like some of their PK
but I really don't ever use it I kind of
just add like a little bit of pecal
every you know two weeks and then um
sometimes I'll do one of the nectar of
the Gods bottles but like that's just
like um sugars really for the bacteria
that I inoculate my Coco with I know it
sounds kind of intuitive but like it
still it still does something I assume
right you know you're establishing a
beneficial relationship um my EC isn't
too extreme you know it's it's nothing
exaggerated you know I mean I still use
m all through my growth I use M when I'm
transplanting and all that stuff I put
it directly on you
know do you guys notice a difference
from not using it to when you do use it
I do yeah I do kind of like I like to
use it like uh especially like at
transplant with my clones I'll inoculate
The Roots then and
um I don't know man like it could just
be like it's like evaluating The Roots
is like hard sometimes right if they're
like all looking pretty healthy so like
but it it does seem like they form just
like more thicker Roots you know um I
don't know I think it just helped like
my kind of thing that I'm thinking about
is like if there's waste material in the
soil and stuff like that and the
bacteria are just like kind of like have
like they're able to help with that I
don't know I'm growing in small pots as
well like local so
um yeah anything I can get to help is
good I I do want to say for the record
that there are a number of things I use
that I've never systematically verified
as like being beneficial but I still use
every every run so yeah use like 17
bottles of advanced nutrients yeah yeah
and you didn't necessarily know what
what they were all doing right yeah no
[ __ ] clue and the two-part formulas
are 10 times better yeah yeah I mean
that was the thing that I I think like
additives that have like I've really
noticed Alpha this so what I did was
when I switched to Cana um I switched
over to Coco and all I grew with was
Cana A and B there were no no other
additives nothing for the entire from
start to finish um and then I um added
back in the calcium phosphate that
Local's talking about um and I noticed
like the transition like from like when
they start to stretch when they like
start to slow down on stretching into
flower I was um I don't know they just
look a lot healthier around that time
period for me um and like the whole
stretching period using the calcium
phosph uh the calcium phosphate um seems
the plants just look healthier
comparatively local is there a
particular brand of calcium phosphate
that you
use
um [ __ ]
not
really um just I guess any that you can
find at your like Garden Center um I'm
not a I'm not a build-a soil guy but
build-a soil sells calcium phosphate
really cheap you can get a 25 pound bag
for like 20 bucks and it's like a
teaspoon per gallon so it lasts forever
and like the thing is is like it has to
be watered in solution if that makes
sense so like the particulate has to
be in the solution yeah so you have to
use like um saponin or some kind of
other surf like something to hold the
calcium in
solution like the actual rock
particles because it's rock phosphate it
like it's derived from rocks it it
doesn't dissolve uh no it doesn't sadly
interes so I use I use the sap the sa
like sapin in from I get it from Crybaby
um and just mix it with it and it it's
like a it holds it in suspension pretty
well nice I also alternatively have top
dressed with it before and just watered
it in so I've used it before like at
transplant like I put it in my root Zone
as well just like throw a little
teaspoon you know sprinkle some um that
helps them adjust as
well interesting
okay all right well anything else on any
other like notable or interesting
additives I think they're completely
unnecessary but that's just power SI and
maybe a fure of calcium or kelp
like maybe but other than that I think
the nutrient companies are so on point
at this point that additives are really
uh they're
unnecessary you know a lot of them are
yeah I I love power SI because it helps
with the stretch so if I
fure feed uh Power SI every three days
during the first 20 days of flower my
plants won't elongate too much and I can
keep the canopy a little more
even
nice okay that's about all I have for
you there was a moment when Matt left
and I thought he would you know Matt's
actually kind of confessed to me in
private that like growing conversations
bore him so I thought he was going to do
that like I'm gonna go to the corner
store for some
milk then just not not return but he's
no I'm still here no what actually
happened is you know I've been using
this proxy today and it ran out of steam
already just by starting this episode
it's already dead of batteries from a
whole battery so I was pissed I had to
go get the other thing that I used live
review yeah live review I mean like
really it's already dead I don't smoke
that much I don't think come on
now I do but come on that
sucks okay well I did want to move on
to again I think quite a philosophical
topic which was troubleshooting I think
ER kind of uh gestured towards it before
I'm just curious like do you all have
any general thoughts on like your
troubleshooting process um or advice for
for noobs who are like you know trying
to figure out what's going on with the
plant
plants I'd say generally the answer if
you're if you're just learning the
answer is generally not going to be more
fertilizer it's most likely GNA be less
water Y and less intense
lighting you know um you can't trust
everything you hear I know the LED
companies they're constantly pushing you
know uh these lights at 12 in give you
1,400 ppfd or whatever that is um you're
really asking for trouble with that [ __ ]
you can get away with six 700 uh par and
just Watering your plants less and
making sure the environment itself is
good you know humidity and temperature
uh they're going to do a lot more for a
beginner
grower than um trying to really blast
your plants you don't have to grow like
the jungle boys you know like that's you
don't you know those guys they have
perfect facilities you can get away with
just taking it slow and easy and having
beautiful
plants yeah yeah yeah if I would have if
I could like tell myself like you know
starting out again like what to do I
would go straight to like a two-part
drained away system and I would learn it
like the back of my hand in and I would
dial my environment in and I would you
know it's so it really like like what
spindle was saying earlier how he was
like well maybe it's not like maybe it's
not the best as like some you know rings
out in mindo with like the best soil in
the world growing the best weed and you
know all this stuff but it's like maybe
the ceiling isn't that high but it's
pretty good I mean it's better than
anything I can get around here um and
that's
I mean for me that's you know that's the
goal
here yeah yeah we're actually getting
pretty close to like yeah what makes for
a good grow and I'm still like really
excited for that part of the combo but
local thoughts on like troubleshooting
SL you know what advice would you give
to people
um I mean how frequently are you
Watering your plants is the
question um I'll be honest like a
handful of my problems maybe within the
last three years if there even
problems um I guess they are it's just I
acknowledge that me not you know
watering them one
night um you know gets my plant a little
pissed off
um
but God damn it I did that thing where I
forget what we were just talking about
talking about troubleshooting and like
general advice with people yeah um I
don't know just you know keep on
schedule with your watering um like
spindle said don't overfeed
um what
else just make sure your environment
isn't too extreme like you don't want it
to extreme in humidity or you don't want
it to extreme in heat I mean you just
got to learn how to adjust your
parameters to get your plant to grow
ideally I'm not really too I mean I'll
do it like for the sake of getting my
plants happy but I'm not going to
monitor and you know have like graphs
and [ __ ] display my VPD you know um but
yeah just that kind of
stuff yeah and I think what you and
spindle both have implied as well is
sometimes it's not just one parameter in
isolation that's wrong it's actually
like an interaction between multiple
parameters so if you're blasting the
plant with light and you're not Fe
enough you know there are two approaches
to that you can up the feed or you can
lower the lights or you can do both um
and they they do all interact right so
this is a complex system and one of the
difficulties with troubleshooting is
that you may see symptoms and assume
that the symptoms tell you one thing but
actually these are Downstream
consequences of like something else
happening further Upstream so to speak
Absolut the other thing I would mention
in this is also if you're making changes
to not make more than I would say one
change at a time if ideally if you can
afford if you can afford not to
gamble um because if you start changing
multiple variables or parameters at once
you're not really going to know what's
doing what and for me when I was
starting out getting to these like manic
flurries uh trying to fix fix things you
know I tried to change like two or three
things at a time and then not know what
was actually working um or not
working yeah
yeah I think like something that I do
now like in my own practice like for uh
to Tripes shoot the first thing I will
do is like if I see a plant that just
looks bad I'll just water it with just
nice clean just you know phed water just
like nothing in it and just see how the
plant responds in that way um I've also
you know before I've like just literally
watered plants until they will fade I
just like have taken the nutrients away
and veg to just see what it does and and
how long it takes for it to happen um
and it it doesn't it's not like you're
if you don't feed your plants one time
they're not going to die you know what I
mean like they can make it one time
without it and so um I I just think that
like the propensity for of new Growers
to like overfeed is so it's so easy I
mean even me like I got the nectar for
the gods stuff um to just kind of mess
around with and just going off of like
what they recommend and had my plants
like super curled up like on nitrogen
and stuff you know like it just takes
time you got to learn where your
nutrients are and stuff you know I mean
there's not going to be a substitute uh
there's not a cure all answer you know
you got to just kind of go through it
and learn
them yeah totally and I think there is
definitely a culture of more is better
and we're going to we're definitely
going to unpack that um maybe a s just
to take a break maybe from some of the
like strategy and tick and philosophy
stuff I didn't want to ask yall what
your favorite things to run ever have
been just so that we can like yeah have
a little little shift of tone um maybe
we start with local this time local like
can you tell us what your favorite
things ever have been to run um my
favorite thing ever uh that's a pretty
obvious one I would say as of now uh
it's a sweet PE two two or three yeah
sweet PE y yeah totally um that one I've
had for like three years now I popped it
from seed I mean it's really tell a bit
more about it like it's lineage and
stuff yes
please um so yeah uh Bittersweet uh SD
um one of our homies made that using um
two p91 S1 selections from um packs that
he got from Matt um and as a result of
those two parents
Crossing he made the sweet pee um and
yeah it's a really fun cross I saw some
really cool
things um really potent nice smells nice
taste nice bag appe peal I mean like it
kind of checks all the boxes like I know
everybody says that but like man this
this stuff
is like
I kind of wish the p91 got a little more
hype than it has now um you know just
simply based off of the stuff that I've
seen from the crosses it's it's put
out
cool uh
Michael you know instead of instead of
me saying uh particular plan um can I go
off like my favorite run that I've ever
had yeah hell yeah okay so uh when I
first got the Bubba cush in
2001 I set up a room uh to do EB and
flow and I'd never tried it before but I
thought you know I've I've read enough
about this I've got a bathroom right
next to this bedroom and I'm gonna go
for it um I had very little
understanding about you know how many
times to water and things like that well
uh I was growing
in
hydron and I
misunderstood the watering schedule for
EB and flows so what I was doing was I
was just flooding the table one time
every 12
hours and uh the strange thing about
this is that by underwatering that Bubba
cush I was able to get that thing so big
that it grew next to the ogs the same
height
and I think that extra stress just
really brought something out of the
Bubba cush um on top of that I I at some
point I started getting fungus snats in
one of the tables and I had bought in
this stuff called naturol and uh midf
flour I think I was using probably twice
as much as I was supposed to be so the
reservoir when it would pump in would
almost look like a melted chocolate
milkshake and just smelled God awful but
for some reason that batch of Bubba Kush
came out with just beautiful huge nugs
it actually out yielded and outsized the
OG Kush that was in the other table and
it had the most beautiful lime flavor to
it beautiful neon green color and uh I
would say it was one of my most
uneducated and probably it potentially
could have been my worst run ever but
the Stars aligned and it just turned out
to be like my most fantastic favorite
run of
kush so were there like lasting lessons
from that for
you you know not really this is just
like a weird oneoff yeah because the OG
came out pretty shitty on the next side
of the room so I knew it couldn't handle
that kind of dryback but I learned with
the Bubba if I really wanted that thing
to move and move fast and not take three
months to veg I needed to really put
some some some dry stress into that plan
and it just made it into something
magical yeah it definitely is a
fascinating topic like the different
individual plants and the different uh
Tendencies and needs right 100% anything
that I put in the table with uh like the
super short Afghans um like Bubba or
let's say U Matt's berries like the riot
Berry um it's really hard not to
overwater them next to my other uh more
OG leaning
hybrids you know so you really have to
pick out what's going to be running on
that Reservoir if they're all getting
the same feed at the same
times so definitely yeah that was
definitely a huge lesson yeah it's a big
learning curve yep going to full Afghans
yep that's cool man thank you uh Erin
favorite plants or
runs yeah I mean um kind of like the two
plants that I've kept the longest now at
this point have been the LA Times
bubblegum uh and then I have a Bard
again from Crybaby that I've kept um
it's born again is the first time that I
ever had
terpinolene so born again a jel cross
what born again is um it's the white
Lodge cut of Clockwork Orange to the
cheese sour lemon
thae um yeah and it's like a it's kind
of I think it's like a little bit of a
like in talking to cry BBE it was like
supposed to be like a little bit of a
joke because it's like a little Haz like
uh like the way it grows and stuff you
know um and anyways it does it's a super
vigorous plant the first time I ran it
it was uh well I flew to New York for
the weekend and came back and it was
like touching my light and like some of
it was like above my light you know just
like very very very vigorous plant um
but yeah first terpinolene for me which
was like I mean dude like I love
terpinolene now you know so like that's
like a really cool I really like that
smell and stuff you know and then the LA
syate what's up
terpinolene Syndicate oh yeah yeah
terpinolene is great it see so far it
seems like it makes everything better uh
I don't know but then I the LA Times
bubble gum that I have is um pretty racy
and just like a short finishing plant
and it was like the first plant from
like a legit breeder that I grew like
CSI you know what I mean CSI is like
yeah he would like there was like runs
where I just ran seeds of stuff that I
didn't care about because I was scared
I'd kill
them so that was the first run that I
popped that was like I'm not going to
kill these plants for
sure oh dear yeah yeah I mean has anyone
here actually ever come close to oh
sorry you may have already mentioned
some of this like what's the worst state
your plants have ever been
in yeah I've killed a crop yeah
[Music]
yeah I mean
how bad you want to get bro like I
remember when I had first learned about
micronized sulfur and spraying wable
sulfur um someone else is giving me like
totally different ideas on how to treat
pm at the time they're like no no no no
no no you need to use Nukem not so need
to use Nukem and I was like everybody
else is saying to use this I was like
screw it I'll just mix them and use it
and when you mix oils and sulfur what
happens is it just melts your God damn
plants just absolutely totaled my whole
flower run just the second I did it and
I was like oh man but after that I
learned that like I should have already
known that and I was an idiot for doing
it but I never burned sulfur I never had
to deal with any of it or deal with PM
like that before so it was a new
experience and uh I learned to stick
with micronite sufur because it's
effective enough especially in veg um
not in flower obviously yeah that's
definitely one time of the many I've
watched my plants go down like within
hours I've never
used it's a great for PM dude it was a
game changer going from having to use
like harsh harsh chemicals the few times
that that I had had it like in San Diego
and everybody would just you know they'd
blast to the hard chems and um that
stuff like you even being around it and
smelling it you know that that's not
going to do you any good I'm not even
going to say the brand name any of that
want to get sued they like yeah that
shit's probably cancerous and crazy so
um knowing that there are other options
that are safe and I mean when people
think of sulfur if you've only burned
sulfur and this was a big reason I
didn't want to use it in the first place
is because you think oh my God it's G to
smell like rotten eggs indoor I don't
like this is an indoor indoor where I
live like maybe I don't want it to smell
like that but it smells like wet beach
sand when you spray it so it's a really
pleasant smell to me and the plants
actually like it a lot um quite a b bit
does the does the PM usually come in off
of The Cutting that you you bring into
your room um it can come off cuting
depending on where you live PM can be
like if you have a whole bunch of plants
around you and it's just thriving in
your area come in on your clothes it's
why I like to be naked um in everyone's
grow room that I go into I just I don't
care whose it is I just like to be naked
and they better understand because I'm
just trying not to pollute Gardens is
what I'm
doing
but no it's yeah it's like typically
people when they bring in clones or
trade clones you're going to run it to
PM because it's in a lot of people's
rooms if you're in a room that's never
had it like you don't have your IPM
running for it you're GNA run into it if
you're trading clones for sure but a lot
of times yeah it can come in on clothes
it can come in on your deck anywhere I
think is a good
Vector so sometimes nudity doesn't work
we try it's a short Vector a very short
bth
um what we even talking I can't remember
what I even asked I don't know it always
goes back to the like
how how talking about favorite plants
and stuff right yeah talking about
favorite plants and I think I got
distracted by talking about like how
messed up have your PL like how
devastated you know have have
um I can't even talk right now yeah I
mean I've I've wasted a bunch of plants
I will say I mean like like I wanted to
learn about like I wanted to try making
rosin you know like hash and stuff which
I have done successfully but when I
first tried it I did not you know wasted
tons of plants you know just not tons
but I wasted plants you know trying to
do that stuff you know just it's all a
learning process it's just like you you
unfortunately with Canabis like you read
about stuff and there is a ton of good
information but it's also mixed in with
like tons of Bro Science from the last
30 years that you have to sip through
and decide if it's legit or not you
know
yeah I mean that might be a good segue
into the kind of what I think is like
the tail end of this combo but I think
quite a also quite a big Topic in of
itself which
is you know what do you all think a good
grow you know means like what what is
good you know what are the because like
like some of you have mentioned already
like there are some myths that float
around you know it's about yield it's
about this or that um you know it's
about pumping them with nutrients it's
about pumping them with light you know
those things what are your thoughts on
some of these myths you know any pet
peeves like for me for example I got
really hung up on the idea that plant
should be given 1,000 ppfd for example
for flowering like it was a rule and I
insisted on it for a couple of runs and
it was actually just [ __ ] me up um
and I had to take a step back and be
like why are you doing this like why are
you just sticking to this weird number
that you know someone pulled out of a
hat seemingly
yeah I mean you could pick any any myth
in cannabis you know like to start with
here um how people germinate seeds you
know is wild um yeah I always found it
to be best to stay as CLE as possible
but other people have different opinions
on that you know that's probably one of
my biggest pet peeves though is like I
like people to be as cly as possible and
not introduce War bacteria to whe may be
popping seeds and um yeah yeah that's
probably my only major one I'm not too
picky anyone else like you know what
what has anyone kind of like absorbed
something and then kind of regretted
that you
know
I mean I did the same kind of stuff like
with lighting as well you know I mean
there was like
growing
um you know it just takes time to like
like all of it is just like you get this
light that's like the first time you
ever get an LED grow light it's insane
you know what I mean it's like you have
the sun in your
basement like like it is so [ __ ]
bright you know and it's like um I know
like the first when I first started
growing um like I had this clone in
there and like I didn't I had my light
turned down all the way uh but I didn't
realize it I thought I had it turned up
to a good level and so for like like a
month this clone just basically sat in
like stasis like didn't do anything
really you know and then I'm like what
is [ __ ] going on right now and then I
just like look at my stuff and it's like
oh you're an idiot you know but like
it's really easy to just Overlook one
little thing like that and like then you
kind of beat yourself up about it but
like you that's the only way you're
going to learn those things for me you
know like it's to [ __ ] up I've still
never even seen LED I mean like not in
my own room LED lights over PL I don't
even know what that looks like to be
honest
yeah you know I think one of one of the
general myths that I've seen that's like
been going on for the last couple years
is kind of the whole um and it's kind of
a joke now too but the whole Athena
jungle boy feed3 3.5 EC deal um which I
think what a lot of people don't
understand is that if you're not running
LED super hot rooms like between 85 to
90 degrees pushing CO2 and uh super high
humidity so the plants you know not
drinking a lot of water then in in those
perfect condition i s they get away with
those super heavy
feedings um but for a homeg grower when
when the room's a little bit cool cooler
like let's say you run 80 and your
humidity maybe is closer to
60 um if your plant starts drinking
super fast that way because having the
humidity lower and the temperature
higher makes the plant drink more um
you'll burn your
plant you know
so I I think that's that's like one of
those myths that a lot of people you
know and myself included I didn't
understand why I was doing it originally
and now that I understand how the plant
uptakes nutrients and things like that I
realize okay I can push my plant another
way and feed it much less a lower amount
per
feeding and still get the results I want
yeah well and I also think that just in
general like what just to add on what
spindle was saying is that
like it like there it being able to feed
3 and a half
VC isn't the goal that you're working
for you know what I mean like even if
you do have those perfect conditions and
you're able to feed at 3 AC that doesn't
mean that you have good weed I mean
we've everyone now has smoked jungle
boys and cookies packs and like knows
what it is I mean it's right like it's
not like people aren't like going crazy
over that weed right I mean like I I
don't I don't have any rooms that run
that way I don't have any tents that can
have those opt optimal conditions so I
don't know what their plants necessarily
need you know like maybe in those
conditions that's what some of their
strains actually require I just don't
have that situation so it's just such an
interesting impulse to me though
underlying all of it it's like
basically the idea is
that maximalism is good and it doesn't
there's no real justification for it um
I don't I I don't think any of us really
need to be getting four pounds a light
you know that's not that's not our goal
but I think they they have very
different goals than we do you know so
they're able to do things we can't do
and you know I mean it must work it's to
some level for some of them I mean they
can't all be producing terrible weed but
nobe and maybe what we're getting to is
that uh like with breeding right like
there's there's always going to be a
context for your grow and what are you
growing for right and I think that's
what we're approaching you know um you
were kind of asking like what the goals
are of what a good grow would be to each
of us is that was that the question yeah
I think that's I think that's another
way of asking it and maybe we can yeah
have a go with that you know for each of
you what do you aim for you know what
what what makes like a happy grow or
happy
run um yeah local you need to chill out
with the Oreos and [ __ ] we can hear it
but lo you go you you're up what what
makes a happy PL or run for
you I that's I mean that's really hard
to quantify but as long as my plants
aren't
like you know looking extremely
deficient in one thing and resin content
looks you know what I would expect it to
turn out to be then in a way that is you
know a marker for a successful run
but there's always things that can
improve you know but that's that's kind
of like the minimum I see as like a you
know I'm going to smoke this I I don't
mind it at
all um um but
yeah yeah I mean I'll qualify that like
success here is definitely in quote
marks and the whole idea is that we all
have different senses of that I'm kind
of just curious about unpacking it um
er thoughts
on what makes for a successful or happy
plant to
run yeah I mean like
um I I mean I'm kind of the same as
local you know it's not like I'm a I
just want my to look generally healthy
um and like I kind of gauge that off of
like I take Cuts pretty often off of my
mom's and stuff and like you know I want
them to route you know around the same
speed stuff like that you know I'm
always just like watching stuff to make
sure that everything seems to be going
the way that I expect it to go um and
that's kind of what it like that's kind
like my goal right now is to just look
through different stuff and find we that
I like you know I mean these guys have
access to stuff that like I've never
smoked like named wheat you know what I
mean like from anyone uh like I just
don't have access to that kind of stuff
so it's been like me just kind of
finding like a place of like stuff that
I like and then kind of trying to go
from there um so for me like a
successful run is to pop a pack and you
know make it through and like feel like
I saw a good expression of that line and
like be able to make a decision if I
want to continue growing that direction
or not you
know I really like that and I think for
me one of my kind of
idealist thoughts on this on the subject
was a good grow means that like you said
ER the plant can express itself as fully
as possible or like kind of fulfill its
potential to like the maximum degree and
that well and I say idealist because you
know you don't really know that like the
only way you can actually know whether
it's fulfilling its potential is if
you've run it multiple times and
possibly under different conditions but
I still think it's like obviously a
noble goal to be like to see each plant
as having uh a certain degree of
potential and in your grow just trying
to see whether you can meet that you
know in some form um I think that's one
of the ways I think about it now um
yeah Michael thoughts on this I think uh
at this
point i' I've have have enough Harvest
under my belt and like
it's the amount that we Harvest it you
know it used to be like how many pounds
per light and how much you could get
would be the general winner of what was
a good grow or not um I think at this
point with you know we not being that
valuable except on a mon AR level um
really I see success as popping a pack
of seeds that I'm actually interested in
and then having you
know being happy with the end result of
50% of those
seeds so if I pop a pack and I get seven
females if four of them come out and I'm
excited to smoke them or I'm excited to
share them and show them that's a
successful grow
yep y that's another good that's another
really good angle I think um and that
has like you said more to do with like
the probabilities around you know
running out a pack and what the
individuals end up being like yeah yep
you know it's important where you get
your seeds from you know like you you
know you're spending money doing this
you don't need to waste time you only
have so many harvests in a life make
sure you're getting something that is
reputable and that you're happy with and
if you buy a pack of seeds from someone
that you know is new to you and their
junk you don't find anything you'd keep
don't keep throwing money at those same
people you know like go with the ones
that are you know giving you something
to live for something to be happy about
something to be excited to show your
friends I was thinking about this you
know in terms of like a difference in
philosophy uh
between like different people in the
community there there there obviously a
large number of people who who will say
I just want to be happy with what I
bought I don't care who I bought it from
but I bought it and I just want to feel
okay with it and you shouldn't tell me
that like I should care you know where I
got it from and then there are the
people who I think are more like us who
are in a way like perhaps like never
really satisfied and always looking for
bit and B and so you do have to look at
every little parameter that you can
control i. you what the genetics are who
you bought it from um I think it is
interesting because it it's a very
divisive thing it feels like in the
growing Community the people who think
it doesn't matter where you get stuff
from you can always find good stuff and
the people who are like I want to keep
looking harder
um I think it's interesting you know
that it reminds me of something that we
used to say a lot um you know like
people used to be real passionate about
uh cars and I'm gonna buy American you
know you'd hear those people like I'd
only buy a Chevy or a Ford you know I'd
never buy a Japanese car you know
because they want to reinvest in their
country and their people and then you
have the other you know whatever part of
the population that's like I don't care
I just want you know a good car that's
cheap and it'll
run you know so I think each individual
has to decide what's important to them
I'm not giving my money to someone that
I think's a white supremacist or a child
or anything like that you know those
things are
important you know I'm sure a lot of
people don't give a [ __ ] and oh yeah
this guy ripped off Caleb and his whole
line is uh basically just CSI
repos but they're a little bit cheaper
you know well hey I'll just get it from
Caleb because the dude's legit you know
I don't care I'd rather spend a few
extra bucks and get it from the guy that
deserves the recognition than the dude
that just copies everything Caleb does
you know it's just a different mindset
dude like um it is it's not important it
isn't like where I spend my money to me
matters because I know like that's a
vote for this person existing that's a
vote for his family and if he's a good
family man I care about his family but
I'm not I'm not like I'm in this for
making lifetime friends on top like I
don't just have customer relationships
with any M like people know that that
know me like we become friends over time
because I I give a [ __ ] about the people
I'm interacting with but you know it's
just it just depends on what you're into
some people are just like I don't care
who it's from if it's dank it's dank but
a lot of those people also don't like
clearly have not even gotten to the
point where they even understand what
dank means to them like they haven't
even made it that far in their Journey
if they're still that mindset in my
opinion you know that's that's where I
see it yeah I I love seeing the people
that I care about succeed that [ __ ]
excites me you'll also find the people
that want to take advantage of their
friends that succeed more than anything
else yeah there's just there's different
types of people in this world you know
yeah yeah I think that's like oh sorry
oh you going you going no I was just
gonna say coming into the weed scene
like as like a newer guy you know and
just like meeting people on Discord and
stuff
like I didn't have like a clear
understanding of like what um like how
you know like how small the scene is so
like it's like these dudes know each
other and stuff you know and like you
like you're definitely voting like
whether you like it or not you're like
making a decision with your money when
you spend on in in such a small scene
like that kind of money like like really
goes a you know that really goes a long
way like if like Matt loses one or two
people it's not like seed sellers are
like you know have millions of customers
you know what I mean like it's very
small and when you yeah I mean you
should like the by obviously like I want
to smoke good weed but if the choice is
smoke good weed and support shitty
people I just will not smoke weed yeah
you know there this also goes two ways
with some of us too like um there's a
lot of us as as seed makers and this
really screws people up like when they
email email me and they're like yeah I'm
going to drop three grand and they
proceed to like you know like downt me
and be rude I'll just be like dude I
don't need your money you sound like an
[ __ ] like I'm not even into it like
it's not it's it doesn't matter if it it
would keep the business running longer
in many cases it just doesn't matter to
me because bad people don't need to
touch plants it's just what it is the
fact of the matter I think it passes
down I think bad juju flies with this
[ __ ] and you see it time and time again
where people support bad people making
seeds and time and time again bad things
happen to these people throughout their
lives like this stuff travels and
Carries On I'm not a very spiritual
person but some things in life are just
evident to me yeah plants are living I
mean plants are living beings you know I
do think about that and I like I think
about like um when I have gotten plants
from I've like you know gotten packs
from people and started growing them out
and like been mid I mean I've been
midflower and found stuff out about the
people that made them and I just I
there's nothing in me that wants to
smoke those plants anymore I've just
I've thrown them I've thrown whole
plants out just truthfully I just am
very much like I got like a a big part
of this is really cool as the community
and like now that I'm a part of it I
don't I yeah I just can't support like
shitty people yeah not not only that but
if people don't you know if not enough
of us vote with their dollar and in the
end of this we're left with you know uh
compound and Seed junkie uh we're allay
the price like that's gonna be a shitty
World they'll be living in you know yeah
and I also think that even if even if
one were uh ethically or morally uh
indifferent to that situation there are
enough good options on the market that
you can consider things like ethics and
Community when you make these decisions
because there like we don't have enough
sources at the moment I mean you can buy
a pack from pack or H lome or Matt or
any of these people that are in the
server that are legit people doing it
the right way and not you know not
[ __ ] people over and you can find a I
mean I would say a keeper in every pack
almost I mean at this point with a lot
of that stuff I mean I've grown through
a lot of their like not not a lot but
like at this point I've grown through
enough of it that like I've found plants
that are really good you know and it's
not like these guys are trying to lie to
you or anything you know no some in some
of those cases they people that I had to
force to sell their seeds like high and
Lonesome and even pack like these are
guys that like existed and were making
stuff that I thought was cool and I was
like guys like I think other people need
to see this it's really really good you
know and hen lonon took years and years
he did not want anything he was around
before me so he knew like what goes
along with selling seeds he knew what he
knew all the headaches that come with it
so none of that was interesting to him
he just likes plants you know so yeah
some of these guys you have to drag in
Kicking and Screaming but sometimes it's
worth it and I think that he was
definitely one that was worth it so it's
pack I I've popped 72 seeds from CSI and
I've had two plants I was disappointed
in out
of that's insane you know where I was
like ah this is kind of boofy yeah you
know and it's also
one of the most difficult line lines to
breed with so yeah I'm not surprised you
know yeah everything else was
unbelievable and that's EXA what it
should be yeah and and the special thing
about that too is that like he's pretty
open about it and says like you could
expect x amount of Booth from this line
blah blah blah and being able to to tell
people with transparency what to expect
again is a loss art in seats and a lot
of people don't get that like just but
just for cas in point any of these hype
strains with any of these like food
names are any of those like what they're
implying in that case what are you doing
what what are we what are we even naming
this [ __ ] for yeah why not just call it
xyz123 I don't know right that shit's so
annoying that's what you know like when
you put blueberry on something it's
blueberry yeah when Dynasty says
something is gonna be strawberry or
pineapple it's pineapple exactly you
know if it's cherry vanilla it's cherry
van Jerry vanilla right yeah you know
like that's that shit's important you
know Blue Sushi I don't like what the
[ __ ] is that even supposed to be I don't
get it you
know yeah I've never had a marijuana
that tastes like a hamburger either no
no thank God thank
God yeah it's not an appealing one
no um yeah I mean I think that was a
good good exchange about like how we
make our you know buying decisions um in
this space I think it's always going to
be a really interesting topic um isn't
it weird that it's like all passion or
no passion with it on those answers what
divides people it doesn't seem like
there's a lot of Middle Ground on that
people either tend to be very passionate
or very
Blas yeah yeah yeah I mean it's that's
what it seems like to me as well yeah
remember Sean pointed that out it's like
uh team sports almost yeah definitely
you
know it's hard to not have communities
without that to to not that's true
because communities are all built on
like passionate ideals at least the best
communities that stay that stay together
and stand firm are built on passionate
ideals and passionate ideals definitely
they become strong ideals and that
definitely leads that team Sports type
thing I've been trying to think of how
to to keep our group from experiencing
that as best we can because it's hard
because I'm everybody sees me and I'm I
have my own very very opinionated way of
dealing with things but at the same time
like I'm trying to Tender that with the
idea of it my own personal opinion is
affecting the way other people think
maybe that isn't so smart and trying to
figure out how to maneuver that it's
it's interesting but yeah it's always
evolving well and I to I think too like
I've always appreciated like when I just
coming
here um and having an honest
conversation about like what
expectations are from what you're
growing and stuff like that I mean you
just don't I mean like when I started
growing that's what I wanted was that
Community to be able to like talk to the
dudes that are like like growing these
plants and working with them and like
get like an idea of like what are they
looking for out of this and like what
you know what I mean just stuff like
that like it's just like it's so much
work like when you pop a seed like you
don't realize that you're going to be
with that plant for like you know you
might be with that plant for a year or
more you know I mean like it's a big
commitment and like I want to like know
about like what I'm doing and like what
I don't know there's just so much to it
and there's people that do take it
seriously enough that can tell you that
that I just don't understand why you
would support people that don't take it
seriously um
I wanted to kind of like tie this
together with some of what I was saying
about what makes for a good grow and I
like sorry tie this conversation about
buying seeds uh together with that
because for me one of the cool things
that you get out of buying stuff that is
reliable and has descriptions that you
can actually like somewhat
trust um is that you get to
see you're going to get to see what
people actually say you're going to get
to see so so last night for example I
was actually asking Matt hey I'm growing
this like T1000 times Underdog Ole I'm
seeing like some OG leaning things I
think do you think that this is like an
O leaning thing and get getting to see
that for me is also part of what makes a
good yeah that's awesome like you have
questions about lineage you have
questions about expressions and you get
those questions answered in the grow
that's a good grow to me yeah
yeah I mean so we're coming up to where
are we we're like almost at the 2 hour
mark 15 minutes away or so does anyone
else have any other kind of like broad
Reflections
on uh grow philosophy grow Tech uh kind
of like what I was saying at the very
beginning this episode is a bit broader
it's meant to be about yeah Broad tech
and Broad like philosophy I think for
subsequent episodes we can probably pick
like topics like uh mid to late
flowering or IPM or stuff like that but
for this one does anyone else have like
any other Reflections or like talking
points um I have one and usually I go
last but this one I want to hear what
these guys have to say um one of the
main things with indoor growing and and
it was a long journey like trying to
chase OG Kush Cuts over um you know that
was a real popular thing when I was
coming up as OG Kush which cut which
Kush cut do you have is it one of the
original legit ones and I remember
coming across this grow um or not this
broke this weed in a collective in San
Diego called Point Loma Collective back
Point Loma patience Collective and it
was called Tokyo OG right and it was the
danst danst OG Kush cut I thought I
could ever I was chasing this thing and
I remember they told me it was a lady
would come in and drop it off and the
lady was the grower and the breeder of
this cut and so I remember being in
there and hanging out and waiting for
her to come do her drop and trying to
catch her like just to talk to her hey
dude you know it's talk and I missed her
the one time she came in when I was
there and I was so bummed and later on
we became friends in life and that's
when I realized it wasn't that it was
just a special special OG it was special
it was a great OG Kush cut it was how
well she familiarized herself with that
single cut and truly truly what I felt
mastered it to bring out its best peaked
expressions and it was so good she
outgrew every [ __ ] OG griller in San
Diego and everybody faked having her cut
but it was always obvious when it was
her grow and she never passed her cut
out um it was always obvious when it was
her grow because it was so expertly done
and you always knew when it was big so
yeah shout out to her and it was also uh
a big Learning lesson for me yeah so
what's the sorry Matt what's the prompt
for people like what are you asking us
to think about here well like the fact
that you know like there's a lot of
Clone chasing we do all this clone
chasing people trying to find this clone
and a lot of times it's not about that
it's how well you can grow a single
clone yeah and that was kind of what I I
learned and experienced through that
whole whole section you know and I don't
know if clone chasing is as popular as
it is now or was then as it is now with
this generation but that was a huge
learning experience for me and I don't
know if anybody else has had similar
experiences you know I think that's
really a lost art at this point because
if you think about it Matt you know 20
plus years ago you'd be lucky to be able
to get one Elite like let's say you got
an elite clone yeah that's probably all
you're going to be growing for the next
10 to 15 years yeah it's true you know
what I mean you're gonna learn that
plant inside and out you know like if
you got an OG you're gonna you're gonna
learn how to grow OG exactly you know
whereas now there's so much available to
all of us like um good point there's
very few plants that I want to grow more
than two years you know if I do it's for
Nostalgia more than than anything else
because I'm worried no one else will
keep it and it'll be gone forever yeah
yeah you know point and uh there was a
time when I first started going to
dispensaries here in the valley and uh
you'd go in and there'd be you know 20
different jars of OG right oh yeah like
every name you could think of and to me
you know I didn't realize at that point
that uh Ken had been selling
s1s so I would through all those jars
and I'd be like they're all OG yeah you
can just tell some Growers know what
they're doing a little better than
others you know like this guy whereas
now when I think back now I'm thinking
huh I wonder if maybe there were
different that many different OG Cuts or
if there were just a few handful of cuts
maybe five or six and then these people
grew really well or really poorly
exactly it's hard to know like I still
I'm I'm not a 100 perc sure like when I
hear sfv the examples I've seen they
look identical to the original OG that I
saw when I moved here yeah you know and
there was no sfv OG back then no so you
know I'm still confused about that too
but I think your Point's very well taken
like when someone knows how to grow
something it's going and they make that
their love or their passion it's going
to be unbelievable I bet if I was able
to smoke uh high and lonesome's
Appalachia it' probably you know the
farthest thing from skunk number one oh
yeah it's next level dude you know so
yeah I I definitely see where you are
with
that I think it reminds me Matt we
should one of the other one of the kind
of topics that we could cover in a
future episode is like preservation
propagation you know like all that stuff
I remember like Chimera also had some
stuff to say about that maybe it would
be funny if we could maybe include him
in one of the
um absolutely but yeah uh anyone else
local any any last
thoughts um no I didn't sorry I had to
press the unmute button you got electric
boogalo yeah right um so I don't know I
think running a clone like if you're set
on a cut I think every time you rerun it
you're going to learn something about
how it does Express and I I think like
obviously in that you're going to learn
what you can tweak to make the ride a
little smoother the next time um and I
do think that that is like you
know um something really important
especially when you're kind of learning
a cut you know to learn what you can do
to maximize its
potential um and it's like ogs and stuff
like godamn I wouldn't even know where
to start like any OG High hybrid I've
had has just looked like ass under my
conditions um but that's cuz I grow in
pure cocoa and that's like not the way
to grow OG Kush at all no system yeah
exactly so it's just like there I did
want to I did want to highlight here you
know you talk about rerunning a plant
and and getting to learn it better which
is obviously true but in rerunning a
plant you actually learn more about your
situp as well that yeah it's like used
to say Don't just grow your plant grow
with your plants so it's not just you
you learning the plant it's also your
plant learning your environment and
adapting as well yeah
yeah yeah very good point LEL ER any
lost yeah and that just to what Matt was
saying with the learning its environment
and that kind of stuff like I mean
that's the biggest point that I would
make would be honestly I mean don't
worry about getting clones you know what
I mean don't don't be so
stressed about getting cuts from people
because I think that like these dudes do
have work that you can find stuff that
is on that
level absolutely out of a c pack and I
think that you're more than likely to
find something that grows better in your
environment that way as well you know um
like you get to do the selection from
the very beginning and I just would say
like I just for me clones don't seem
like something that I'm super it's not
something that I'm want really just to
make it clear I guess we're talking
about like clones in two different ways
there's like clones with uppercase c i
Elite clones that people look like
that's what I'm keeping clones of your
own stuff that you're just rerunning
right and I see yeah and I definitely
like I think that it's very valuable to
like run your stuff multiple times and
learn it because like all these guys
will tell you that like that they like
the Clones settle in and like do
different things and stuff you know what
I mean so like it is worth spending that
time I'm just saying maybe just spend
time with something that you find cool
you know exactly exactly what someone
else finds quote unquote Elite like when
you really find out who the guys were
choosing these old Elite clones the way
they were running their plants and you
see their pictures on the forums you
will appreciate the word elite a lot
differently I think and and people
realize man I'm way better grow in that
dude I'm going way better [ __ ] than them
I'm in a way better situation uh maybe
what I'm choosing is more Elite to me
and that's that's a legit thing to say I
mean that that can happen a lot it's
it's every everything is subjective when
it comes to what is quote unquote Elite
in cannabis and that's that's a big big
Learning lesson I want to say as well
that oh sorry Michael I'll just quickly
say like there are lots of hierarchies
in this in this community and people
wanting to preserve those hierarchies
whether they're hierarchies of clones
hierarchies of breeders people are
fighting to preserve these weird ladders
and often they are just mythical like
they're just made
up smoking
mirrors sorry Michael what were you
gonna say I you know I I think there's
there's benefits to both because uh you
should definitely look through seeds and
find what you like but at the same time
if people talk about something that you
missed out on for long
enough you know it'd be nice to try them
you know like uh when I hear about day
recer and stuff like that I wasn't
around for that that never made it into
I'd never heard of it before so that's
something I'd want to try you know I'm
not saying it'd be like the elite cut
that I'm going to grow the rest of my
life I don't think there is such a thing
but getting to experience those things I
think it means a lot to you know people
that missed it you know I I've heard
about chmd and chm91 for 20 some years
now I want to see him like the real to
know the real thing is in front of me
you know not just uh something made up
you know and that's why I try to tell
these kids so often not kids people that
are that are coming into the scene now
that like the way that you get those
clones you it's so hard to buy them and
get legitimate copies by buying them it
really I don't even think they're for
sale they're not and that's the problem
like if they do it's usually through a
back door and like you're not going to
get good provenance on it you're not
going to be able to ask someone hey did
you get it legit from this dude you know
like that's never going to happen so
you're never going to be able to really
reassure yourself taking the buying
route um so just be a good person and
make friends in the community learn [ __ ]
and that's how we all fell into it and
like everybody in our group knows like
[ __ ] I I put all my clones out there and
said [ __ ] it take what you want crew
don't give a [ __ ] like that's how it
works but it takes a lot of trust in
building time sharing time with people
it's not about buying [ __ ] and and those
things are there those things are there
to get and to be had and to try and just
knowing the right people and just being
decent human really you
know sorry go ahead Michael sorry it's a
it's a latency thing blame blame me
being by the South Pole yeah um I'll
just say that um
oh now totally
blanked that's good you
go I just I wanted to say too like um I
had bought two packs of Chile Verde yeah
and uh I didn't want to pop them so I
went and I got uh from purple City
genetics I got a clone of the Chile
Verde yeah right and I grew it out and
uh I sent uh is it HBK yes yeah I sent
him pictures you know I was like this is
really nice stuff and he was like oh you
know that's not actually my cut of Chile
Verde that's just one they picked out
yeah and I was I was kind of
disappointed I was like huh okay then I
popped a pack of Chile ver I found
something so much better than that Elite
that they were selling all over
California in that first pack where I
was like oh my God this is why he calls
it what he calls it did you find it
Chile ver if you know oh it was
beautiful his original cut dude when he
so good it it smelled like like carneada
the jili ver it it smelled exactly like
it and I was mind blown and every every
chili ver day that I smelled since is
someone else's selection and it's
nowhere near as good as his was the
purple City one was really sweet yeah
yeah yeah really not at all you know and
then the one I found in the seed pack
was just like so unique I was like holy
[ __ ] yeah they unique [ __ ] in
there okay I remember so the point I was
trying to make I think uh with respect
to what Matt was saying about how
you become connected and actually uh
create relationships with people I think
there's a confusion in the in the
industry or Community where people don't
know if they're meant to be acting like
customers or like community members and
it's not even their fault because no
lots of discords or communities they are
like treated like customers and they
they become used to that and so they
they they have entitlements as a
customer would feel like they might have
um whereas once they come into a real
you know quote unquote real Community
like
ours it's totally different you can't
act like that you can't just assume that
these are all transactional exchanges
and that you can just expect certain
things no yeah and that's why I kind of
say the thing about the clones and is
just because like coming from where I'm
at like being an unconnected new grower
the best way that I could get access to
good wheat was to find good seeds you
know I mean yeah buying I I'm so
thankful that I didn't get into buying
stuff and like because you just hear
nightmares of people ruining their
entire grows from getting some weird
pest or something you know I mean and
that can happen you know I mean
Lots wait till you get a pest and you
torn down your room three times and you
keep getting it back at yeah right the
gift that keeps on giving bro yeah
that's a demon right there yeah
yeah that's for real like the Santa Cruz
super M
yeah [ __ ] seen that thing a few times
bro it's like a bed bug can live in the
sheets for years yeah
right yeah me and CSI joked about the
the spider mics that like would drink
floramite and like laugh at you as they
like chug it yeah we've seen it all dude
like to the point of where like it was
completely obsolete to even use any of
those harsh TS anymore because they were
just so like they didn't work anymore
you had to find legit means of using
like real predators and stuff to kill
these things yeah yeah maybe we need to
have an IPM episode as well yeah sure um
but yeah you know we're coming up to the
two-hour Mark I think um we've covered a
lot of ground today uh I hope to see the
these guys back again and we might even
have different people coming in maybe as
well uh for future indoor growing
episodes we might end up having a proper
Hydro episode um as well so hopefully
we'll see some of you back um is there
anything else from anyone or
Matt happy
birthday thank you happy birthday happy
birth yeah when people are watching this
it'll be later so don't wish him I mean
you could wish him a happy birthday when
this hairs but yes this
isce new new uh a pretty a new drop
coming pretty soon from goat farm and uh
Miss Jill already up on the site right
yep and I'm about to put a Brian Berry
C Michael can be a host I know right you
can help me I so I don't have to say
cringy
stuff I'll take it I work
I don't any yeah any last shout outs
from
anyone local shout out to
Mila
en
aita Chun glass anything hey Chun
[Laughter]
[Music]
glass yeah I anybody else got any shout
outs you want to do
er no I'm good thanks for just having me
on here guys this is cool to talk
Michael yeah thanks guys this is fun
what you got Michael any shout outs no
all right then I'll shout out glassby
2.com go check it out like my favorite
glass on Earth it's the only thing I'll
use I'll second that yeah right like
it's no [ __ ] yeah no [ __ ] we all
use it now and it's not because he's
sponsored it's because it's legit watch
the episode watch the glass episode it's
really good really good one people are
sleeping
yes and um yeah thousand you got
anything birthday
boy no just happy to be here happy to be
invited yeah just happy to be along for
the ride right okay well with that go
check out Riot seeds.com for all your
seeds and spray needs like uh we said
adding Miss Jill's Ryan Berry cough
tonight um goat Farm's gonna have a new
blue dream uh Santa Cruz Blue Dream Drop
we're doing stuff on our uh Discord with
that and the patreon 50 care so check
that out too and and yeah go to the
Discord hang out I think with that we'll
call it a wrap guys thanks so much
everyone and happy
[Music]
birthday, want to sit at the table with
The Syndicate check out our patreon and
our link tree or description below our
merch site is officially live we have
all sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies
to sort you out and shipping is super
fast and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out