welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate this is a bit of a tangent
although Dan I think touched on it
somewhat um Matt what are your opinions
on like mother care I know it's kind of
like its own Topic in many ways but just
spend a few minutes on it what do you
mean like what what specifically um how
different is your approach to
treating like your mothers versus like
your plants that you know you're about
to maybe flower I mean one of the main
differences is you're not you're you're
completely training them differently you
know you're training them for clones for
the most part as opposed to for uh
something that you're going to flower
out so you're you're feeding it much
differently you're not feeding it the
heavy PK it's never going to bloom um
you give it a nice round regimen um a
lot of times what I'll use the moms to
do like seed seed plant moms is to make
seeds more seeds and clones and that's
about it um yeah I mean it's just it's
such a different mindset I mean
realistically like it's it's a lot
easier to run a a vroom of moms for
clones than it is to ever flower
anything because you know most of the
fuckups come in flower right everybody
can grow in veg pretty well for the most
part I'm curious as well this is more
the Practical side of things like do
people give them like less light and
stuff as well just because they don't
you know don't need as much or you know
are other things you can kind of like
skimp on yeah I mean you could throw
them under t5s and have them grow even
slower but still stay healthy there's
all there's a lot of different things
you can do to to maybe re quote [ __ ]
growth without without affecting it or
hurting it too much um when I was
running the 600 watt uh double-ended
cfhs um I would always run them at 300
like just to have strength because it
never needed to be more than that they
could stay healthy didn't they didn't
eat too aggressively that meant I didn't
have to do as much training as much
cleaning as much maintenance because
that's a that is the other side of it
like it's constant maintenance and
cleaning when you have a bunch of moms
in
room yeah yeah I guess if we wanted at
some point we could do a little episode
on like mother care sure yeah if you
guys want to see us do an episode on
mother care leave a comment below and
maybe maybe we'll do it even though I
[ __ ] hate grow
shows I'm still stuck on the fact that
you're a house and garden
boy yeah yeah I am I like I like house
and I like that the I met the owner of
House and Garden us and Eve dude he what
you know was it Steve Geer I'm pretty
sure was a dude in San Diego um who
owns hydroponic stores down there um he
owns uh uh uh what was it's like the
main hydro stores down there I'm totally
blanking right now but he also was like
the house and garden Duty always hook me
up so like I don't know man I'm very
very um I'm a little biased when it
comes to House and Garden because they
did treat me very well no matter
what but that's important to me I like
to be treated well by a company that I
support and you know I was nobody when
they were treating me well you know I
still am nobody and they treat me well
so it's kind of cool I used to buy cases
of shooting pwder H you know that's the
one product I've never used I've never
used shooting powder never have yeah
that's cool it works what is that it's a
bloom booster it'll like make your
flower it's it's definitely got some
pgrs of some sort in it because it makes
your flowers reset Bloom and so you'll
be in like week six and you'll get a
full flush of white
hairs whoa so what do you what do you
meant to use it for it's to shoot
instead of root like it's supposed to
convert the plant over from shooting to
rooting or rooting to
shooting that's the idea yeah got it's
just like enhance flowering and so you
can like up your yields like 10 15% like
adding a packet of powder to like a 50
gallon resz once or twice in week
six it works right just yeah I see I
see anything else
on uh veg in general any any any weird
stuff that comes to mind that people do
that you're like why um I I'll toss in
one weird thing like a lot of people
like I'll see it in forums um on
Instagram
when people see red stems they
automatically assume it's a deficiency
but there are a lot of genetics that one
of the traits is red stems so don't
assume just because you're seeing red
stems that it's a deficiency because
there are a lot of genetics that are red
stemmed um that's about it that's all I
care to have yeah I do get on every
single plant regardless so I assume it
may not be genetic but that's something
to eliminate too right yeah
yeah uh anything else from anyone local
any any last thoughts on this before we
move on to
cloning Lo fell
asleep uh maybe his mic's not working
again uh it's all right
um anyone else if
not hand it over to n because so kind of
similar to the germination one um I
think yeah like I said earlier ER just
does a really good job of like
accounting for the things he's scene as
he was learning and also also ER has
actually filmed a little cloning
tutorial for us and might be the first
of more maybe um this one that that we
will probably uh release next week or
something I don't know I haven't talked
to mant about it yeah is specific to
what uh he calls call or what we call
Callis Tech has a few other names but
anyway sorry that's just a way to
introduce uh Ern yeah for sure I mean
like I've So like um I've talked about
this in a bunch of different episodes
but or like bunch of different a few
different episodes but I have um tried I
tried dwc and stuff and you know I've
done those kind of things
so I've also tried cloning that way you
know uh
so cloners and stuff like
that um and like they they work
obviously they work you know what I'm
saying um but for me in my setup I just
found that um like the most consistent
way for me to clone and like cheapest
and easiest and just all around like
lowest maintenance like and it works
every time for me has been this callist
Tech um and you know the way that I
found out about it uh was through um
that slow
nickel on Instagram and and
basically when you cut your clone it
goes the end of your clone goes down and
sticks out the bottom of your Cube
that's it um and you just have this
clean dry area where the end of your cut
like the cut end can form a callus and
heal it and like you know close itself
up and it like keeps bacteria and
pathogens stuff like that from getting
up inside there and it just made sense
to me like I was like duh like if I get
a cut on my finger I'm gonna leave it
open to Air and I'm GNA let it like form
a scab and then it's going to heal you
know so
that was just made so much sense to me
so that's what I started doing um I I
tried I went through a bunch of
different um I've used a ton of
different like rooting hormone Solutions
you know I've used clonex I've used dip
and grow I've used the stuff they sell
at lows I've s you know whatever I've
tried it and um so now I've kind of
settled on using dip and grow just
because it's cheap it's I mean it's
super cheap it lasts forever and it's
and it works so I use it um and then I
use rock wool cubes because they're
cheap and easy for me to get and um that
I like the way that they dry back um I
think having dry backs is important for
uh like it's important for clones too if
you have your cubes soaking wet all the
time you know it's not going to be good
for the tissue so um yeah that's I don't
know how this you want to go I guess we
can Loosely say that dryb backs are
useful when you're trying to pressure
roots to grow right like that seems to
be a general principle um maybe this is
a good point to pass it to Dan just
because um Dan in your mind what are the
kind of other parameters that you should
consider when you are cloning um so er
obviously like just described a specific
piece of tick but what are you thinking
about when it comes to like you know
environment um yeah
yeah so um I've had two different types
of setups like most people that are
homeg growing are going to need to use
like a variety of different humidity
domes there's like the Mandi domes I
think are the most common ones that
everyone gets because they're cheap um
I've actually found some cool ones on
Amazon that you can get like stacking um
height extensions for which I want to
try out and just start taking like Mega
clones and stuff and they're like super
heavy duty plastic so you don't like
ever uh like I break those M does all
the time like the edges start fraying
and they can cut your hands up and um
same thing with like the 1020 trays that
um people clone in that's 10 by 20
inches um they uh um they break and they
rip they have rough machined plastic
edges and you can cut your fingers open
all day long if you work in a clone
house or a
nursery um but I've got a lot of
opinions on this [ __ ] because it was
like my first longest gig was like
working in um black market nurseries and
stuff and so I've tried literally all of
it you know like at scale and So like um
I personally like clonex I but I do
appreciate dip and grow as well it is
way cheaper and more cost effective and
it's alcohol based and so you're
actually kind of cleaning up that cut
Edge too um to a certain degree and
keeping that a little more um you know
like fungal and bacterial free um I
actually really like the AOC cloners um
especially when you're just doing like
big batches of single cuts um it's the
fastest way I've or I mean I've gotten
root Roots about the same speed in Pete
plus as well um but um the aroc cloners
are just cool man like I just think it's
a cool piece of tech they're like a
massive amount of work to keep clean
because you have to just like gut it and
bleach all the internals and um it's
just kind of a pain to run um but I had
really great success just rocking um
protect and kln from Dino and then um
there was a while back I can't remember
what the dude's name was but he was on
IG and he's the one that taught everyone
to use pool shock bleach in there it's
like the the bleach they use for um
swimming pools and stuff and um it
actually works really well if you have
the dilution right to just keep
everything really clean and um oh you
don't have to change out your water and
but you you sometimes you have to run
chillers with those too because the pump
makes heat and so you have to like burp
the excess heat out of them like they're
kind of a pain in the ass but they're
cool um but like as far as like rooting
media you have like the three main
options of like grodan Oasis cubes or uh
Pete plugs and so like Oasis I think is
like a plastic type material um but uh
you only see dudes from the triangle
using those like that's the only time if
I ever get clones from dudes in humbold
or mesino they come in a [ __ ] Oasis
Cube he use those in San Diego too I
like them yeah I like them too man
they're they definitely drain like free
drain the most fre like you know what I
mean you just tilt it on its side and
that water pours right out versus like a
groan a lot of times you have to like
stack a few of them and like drain the
water out and then flip it and even it
out um they're used a lot in like
traditional agriculture like I used it
when I worked at the flower shop and
stuff and that's how I was first aware
of them that they were even a product
you know yeah yeah and like they have
their own like compositional differences
I actually like Pete plugs the most if
you have like a what are they called the
riot are they are they the root riots
yeah yeah root riots mother root riots
they they have the most airspace and
like uh that I've seen in them and so
they sporing me by now for real for
real um but I like those the most I tend
to get Roots faster and just healthier
more vigorous Cuts with that media for
some reason um but I've also noticed a
massive difference in quality depending
on who you get them
from that's what I was gonna say yeah
it's they're
so yeah cuz like sometimes you open up
the case and they've got like
aspergillis like blue green molds and
[ __ ] growing all over them and you're
like huh I don't know if this was added
or if it's just growing because it's
like humid and sealed you know yeah yeah
that's what took me to rock wo was my
local uh hydroponic store has got those
root Riot cubes and I would get them all
the time and um they started just like
the shape of them it was like there was
not enough Peete in the cube like in the
mold you know what I mean like it was
like they didn't have enough stuff there
and then I got one batch and I opened
them up and they smelled weird I know
that's like super but I like they
smelled sour and I was like okay that's
not right so I just got rid of them and
then switched to rock wol just because
like I just never had that issue with
them and you know but yeah I don't have
a strong opinion on those two you know
yeah rock is really nice because I feel
like if you get the cube saturation
perfect um you don't have to water until
Roots
emerge yeah I don't I don't at all yeah
yeah and then at that point you're kind
of just vegging in the tray you
know but uh so that's how I kind of feel
Oasis cubes you definitely have to do
one to two small water editions like um
with those ones I would rock like um
grodan you can just put right into a a
1020 tray and you can drain off the
water put like a slotted tray um the
cube in the slotted tray and then the
that one inside the you know no holes
tray and drain off water that way but I
like to have perite underneath the Oasis
cubes um and that kind of keeps them out
of that water so when you're doing your
water additions they're not just like
completely submerged it Wicks up from
like a a nice you need a fine pearlite
though not the Big And Chunky stuff you
need like a number four number five and
um so you depending on the media water
the water scenario may be like
drastically drastically different so if
you're switching those up constantly and
like not adjusting other parameters
that's probably why like someone may be
having trouble like in their early
cloning issues also like the cleanliness
of the cuting that you're taking like
when you're indoor and you don't have
bug issues and you're on point with your
IPM it's not really a big deal um but if
you're taking cuts off of like outside
plants like that actually almost [ __ ]
me recently because I had bugs that just
came came from the environment and
almost like ruined my whole grow that I
was just starting and so it set me back
like three or four weeks of like having
to douse everything in Sulfur and like
let it grow back to healthy again and um
geez yeah it's so much easier to like
you can apply some like tissue culture
Tech that we'll get into next about like
how you initiate cuting and so like that
involves like soaking it in a mild
bleach solution and then rinsing that
off and putting it in I've done that
when I was trying to save um other
people's genetic collections where they
had like rud AIDS and spidermite
infestations and all that and there was
just no way to do it other than like
literally soaking the cuts and bleach
before you plug them and um yeah yeah
it's it's
bad um yeah before we we move on to the
tissue culture section I want to see if
local local has any thoughts slash if
his mic is working now
cloning yeah my Wi-Fi kept disconnecting
sorry guys God damn it okay yeah umine
but anyways cloning um I gotta say uh
environment and plant Health you know is
really important um I'm sure these guys
touched a bit on that but um you know
right now for example um it's a new
house first winter not like a new house
but you know what I mean like a new spot
um new winner um and it's like I'm
getting used to the like temps of the
place um and it's just like ambient
temps are just way too cold um so I kind
of just
gotta figure out how to keep warm you
know um the space heater makes the room
too hot so even on the low settings I'm
might have to get a smaller one um so
we'll see but yeah just environment are
you keeping
warm yeah I got my two
cats yeah something I was going to throw
in there too that local mentioned but I
we didn't I don't know if we fully
touched on but yeah just like Mom Health
you know obviously that's important you
know the plant that you're taking the
cut from should be healthy um wellfed
you know like you don't want to be
taking cuts from like a you know we
plant you know I mean obviously you can
and you can try but you know if you
start with like the most healthy plant
to take cuting from that's going to set
you up for success as
well um yeah Matt anything to add to
that no man Mother Health everything for
cloning um and of course like with with
h the Hops and thyroid you know there's
a whole bunch of other techniques um for
cloning that a lot of people have kind
of started doing and I guess that all
changes on if you or hinges on if you
trade clones or bring in clones from
nurseries or whatnot but that's a whole
another episode and I think we covered
that previously in another season so
definitely check out that episode the
tissue culture one that we did
do or hlv episode that's what it was
yeah yeah yeah hlv
yeah yeah that's it okay awesome
um okay well Dan we can talk speak to
well we can invite you to speak to uh
one of um you know one of those topics
tissue culture as we have gestured
towards uh how did you want to start
this one what do you think might be
interesting for our
listeners um I think just kind of like
an overview of the process and then like
some of the different texts and like
phyto hormones involved in the different
steps that may be useful because you can
do this stuff at home you know I mean
there's all kinds of like home tissue
culture guys and home micology guys that
are working out of like invert like you
know they're literally totes clear totes
on their side you know and they spray
them down with alcohol and like you
don't always need a hood you just have
to be you know like mindful of what
you're doing and like maybe Dan one
thing here is like
uh are you able to kind of like indicate
like precisely which things can be done
at home versus things that like are
definitely not doable yeah I think I
think like we'll break it down into um
three sections is how I have it kind of
like broken down in my head is like
there's micropropagation there's more
Advanced Techniques like marem culturing
and like embryo rescue and a few other
like more theoretical ones that like
people don't use very often and then
like how people develop Sops and so I
think the only thing that might be more
Troublesome at home is like the more
advaned techniques because um you're
just dealing with cleanliness and
multiple transfers like every time you
transfer something at home is like or
even in a lab that's like when you're
going to contaminate it and so um it's
all possible to do at home though like I
know people that have done this [ __ ] in
just like garages and Tents in their
house and so um I hope you're dude like
hope you're I'm no expert in this either
like I did a senior year in a tissue
culture lab in college and been like on
the outside looking in and like talking
with people that are doing the research
and um uh I just kind of keep up on the
current topics and like the players
involved um just so I'm like you know
current with the times but like I don't
do tissue culture for a
living and so um I have a really close
colleague that would like he would could
speak to this like Leaps and Bounds but
um I don't think he wants to like out
himself or be very public um but uh the
main thing that like most people are
doing is just like multiplying cuts and
storing genetics and so that's just
micropropagation and so there's three to
four main stages of that and so like
your first one is just your mother plant
like your X vro in your grow room plant
and you have to take a cutting off of it
right and so to try and surface
sterilize that to the best of your
ability you soak it in a 10% bleach
bleach solution and you rinse that off
with um sterilized water which is like
something that you've put through like
at home it would be a pressure cooker
but if you have a lab and like work with
a group it'll be your
autoclave which is just a fancy pressure
cooker with more controls um and uh so
you have to rinse that off with
everything has to be sterile first off
so you're like you're working in a nice
clean environment with no draft ideally
with a laminer Flo hood and you can get
those I've seen them people are 3D
printing them nowadays and so you can
buy those on Etsy now for like 200 bucks
um and I've actually get a 3D
printer I have a friend that does 3D
printing that I work with and he's an
absolute G and so like I kind of want to
buy one and then like reverse engineer
it you know and make a better cooler one
or just a bigger one for myself you know
with the same
premises um but so I'll keep you guys
posted on how that goes but um so yeah
there's initiation you soak it and
bleach and you try and just get that um
into culture and it onto a gelled medium
it can be gelled with like a product
called gel xan or a seaweed product
called augur um and normally you don't
really need too many hormones to
initiate it because you don't really
want to root that plant right off the
bat you know what I mean you're just
trying to get it into culture and have
it be sterile and so um even if you
surface sterilize
properly there are a lot of like
parasitic
endophytes that just live in the plant
and a lot of them are bacteria and
you'll see these like milky white
contaminants that it like erupt out of
the cut Edge that's sitting in the gel
and um you can't really always stop it
and so like what a lot of people do is
they use antimicrobials in the media to
kind of make it look like they're doing
better than they actually
are um because we've seen it routinely
with the work that I've been like
watching one of my colleagues do is that
like they it happens all the time and
you can have it in vitro for um eight
months before it even expresses and so
um there's uh actually you can find them
on uh Google Scholar if you look up
cannabis tissue culture contaminants and
things like that there are some public
papers that have been published that um
have like categorization like visual
charts to like point you in the
direction of like what type of
contaminants you
have and then uh if you actually get
past that initiation stage then you go
on to stage two which is multiplication
and so at that point you're going to be
replating your initiated plant on a
variety of different cyto Canin
depending on like what your goal is for
that so if you're taking those and like
doing phyto hormone research and things
like that where you're just trying to
see what the plant's going to do um with
different additives and chemicals add to
it then you may not want to elongate it
that much it all just really depends on
what your goals are but a lot of people
are just looking to multiply plants and
so right now um there's this cool dude
called Connor Stevens who's a friend of
a colleague of mine he's out of uh
Cornell University he recently started a
company called polymorphisms here in
California um which is a tissue culture
lab and like genetic preservation lab um
for the commercial industry here um and
he identified 2ip publicly as the um the
most most productive cyto kind into use
for shoot elongation and multiplication
and so you can actually go and look up
his re research it was actually just
published
recently and uh from that stage you can
either send it off to more
multiplication on the same Media or you
can then take it and you can try and do
marem cultures on it some people like to
initiate on meristem some people like to
do it once it's already in vro um I you
know I don't really have a comment on
like which one's better but um uh if at
that point if you are rooting that's
when you would take it to the next stage
and change the hormones to something
like an IBA or an NAA which are the
active ingredients in products like
clonex and dip and grow and uh you can
root your plant and then wash that gel
off and take it XV and grow it um uh but
yeah there's I've been seeing some
really cool stuffff like using packo rol
um in cultures it has potent I I the
research isn't done so I don't want to
speak to it too much but it's cool you
can try all kinds of different phyto
hormones they're all available through
Sigma ald and all kind suppliers and um
that research is pretty still largely
unexplored like people are doing it
privately but um you're not going to be
able to read about it and so I'm very
interested in just doing very basic
research like that where it's like hey I
put this many plants under this varing
concentration of NAA versus IBA and
let's see what they do differently you
know it's super super basic research um
but that's how you like develop your own
Sops because nobody's really sharing
them and what I found is the publicly um
researched ones they're um published
that you can read they don't all work
the same and in all environments with
all plants a lot of them are done with
hemp which is not a onetoone correlation
with anything cannabis related for um
THC production and those types of uh
chemo bars or whatever you'd like to
call them type ones um and so uh I've
noticed that're they don't really
readily work all the time um but um the
way that you really develop these Sops
and like the model to think about it is
is you have to do
everything
um it's like basic research like plot
design and so like you'll have like say
I have like 12 plants and they're in or
let's say 16 they're in a 4x4 grid
they're all in their little petri dish
um I can have it a gradient of like IBA
on one side so like the bottom left is
uh you know like zero micro moles of uh
IBA so that's the control and then an
increasing quantity one micro five micro
moles 10 Micro moles and then on the
other access you have it um with like
NAA or a different phyto hormone that's
cool so you're actually using like
you're using kind of like the spatial
order to help you index like the
different yeah and then you can
everything in between on that axis is
the combinations of and so you can test
multiple chemicals and their effects and
the combination of their effects all in
one little experiment that takes square
foot that's that's really clever you can
even stack it vertically and go in a
third dimension too and add a third
phyto hormone you know like or a third
treatment yeah exactly yeah you you can
I don't know if you can take it to 4D
but I guess you could yeah you could
have this big huge grid and having it go
all the way up stacked um but yeah um
it's really fun I I really enjoy that
type of research just because people do
it and people don't share but I'm very
open with the information that isn't you
know like contracted away from you guys
that I can't share and so can I can I
pause you here just to invite questions
from anyone else at this stage um yeah
yeah like Matt local have you had any
any uh any interactions with any of
these kind of chemicals or experience
sure napoline acetic acid um indol atic
acid indc acid they're all basic rooting
different different types of rooting
hormones um but not in like Ager medium
stuff like that I've tried it at home
and been very very a big a big failure
at it because I wasn't like didn't have
a fully clean environment I was trying
to do it in the house with dogs and [ __ ]
so yeah um I don't have a lot of success
with tissue culture but I do have a lot
of failure uh dealing with tissue
culture people
sure I if anybody else has anything they
want to add loal anything on this yeah
not not much like direct experience I've
worked like um in collaboration with
Labs that that have done like TC and
[ __ ] so like I've seen it be formed I'm
familiar with the process and stuff like
that but I've never like done it myself
um but I'm definitely
interested um it's just it's a lot to
get into at once
um
yeah yeah what I've noticed is it it
kind of has to be a focus like a the
main course for someone and that's why I
haven't like deep dived it is like I
just I don't really have the time to
hang out in my lab and my base B for six
hours a day right now like maybe in
another year or two I can like start
going down that path but um yeah you do
need like a project right to frame and
constrain what you're
doing yeah yeah otherwise you're kind of
just holding and making a ton of plans
um but I I really am curious and what I
want to get into when I do build my
little setup is um uh getting into
embryo rescue because I feel like that's
going to be like one of the the key
things that's like if you have these old
seeds like what is the best way that you
could posibly do it like we were talking
about earlier and like the best way is
in the hands of a really experienced um
tissue culturist that has like done that
research and I don't personally know
that person and so um well I just sent
some off someone I just sent someone
some off to someone he's one of the most
experienced tissue culture people I know
of yeah um so he even he said like I I'm
not sure how far along this is but I'm
going to give it my best shot which when
he says that to me it tells me there
isn't anyone like renowned out there for
that specifics but I know if there was
there were so many breeders that would
pay good money to have certain old seeds
at least attempted to be popped you know
for sure well what I see is like people
always want to you have to like sell
plants and be the nursery right like
that's like the the profit motive to
like start a tissue culture lab and how
you get people to give you money to do
that project because it cost
insane amount of money to want to do
this sort of thing but at the same time
that directly gets in the way of people
wanting to give you their oldest stuff
that actually has provenance because
they think that you're going to turn
around and use it and profit from it and
sell it to other people maybe against
their wishes and so like I think there
does need to be room in this space for
someone that genuinely is just a
preservationist their little setup is
exclusively for genetic holding for
specific clients that doesn't ever sell
clones yep I agree that that'll be who's
trusted enough for for serious people to
trust them you know it would take
something like that yeah and that's kind
of going to be more the angle of like
what I want to do with my work is like I
don't need to make thousands and
thousands and thousands of plans I just
want an easier way to hold more good
stuff that it's like I don't have to
water it every day I can maintenance it
once a month you know
absolutely yeah I'm excited to see where
embryonic rescue goes I I there was a
lot of Promise about it just a few years
ago people making claims that they could
take any old seed and do it with it but
you know it's it's a lot more
complicated than just having an old seed
you have to have living cells in there
it can't be totally you know dry stuff
like that so before we get all the
questions um yeah you can't do it with
any old seed not every old seed will do
it takes living cells in
it man are you allow to
discl what's that man are you allowed to
disclose what you sent off or no nope
yeah nope nothing nothing about it not
to who
nothing not yet not yet yeah I don't
have anything old enough but I think it
is something that's like needed in the
community and needs to be Focus D I did
have another a kind of different angle
on this which is in your experience like
with tissue culture what have you
witnessed as like successes what have
you
seen uh like just as far as like
techniques and like what's common or
like I just I guess I just want to hear
about like some like some stories some
anecdotes um tell tell my story you know
that one don't you yeah yeah there's a
lot I'll I'll start like this there
there's a lot of scammers in TC and
cannabis and there's a lot of people
that have like the most Bas level
understanding and like accomplishments
in it that like want to sell courses and
sell you that they're this guy that can
hold your whole library and like they've
all popped up more recently they're all
pretty young cats and like I don't trust
any of them yeah like um I know people
that like do
this at like a a doctorate level and
they don't claim the things that these
other people claim and they've been
doing it with cannabis for years like
that research takes a lot of time and a
lot of effort and um I don't think that
it's like hidden knowledge to any extent
like marem culture is just marem culture
um if you've worked in any TC you've
probably done it on other plants um so
um it's definitely totally all possible
it's just like whether those people have
actually put the leg work in to um teach
you how to do it and how to optimize for
what you're going to interact with in
the real world versus their like like
there's always one plant that does what
you want it to do right like I may be
like rooting a dozen plants on the same
media and one will always like do really
like pretty well unless it's like some
weirdo [ __ ] media but if it's just
like a run-of-the-mill like Ms media is
like the most common one um then like
there's going to be something that that
responds well to it but the rest won't
you know and so that's what I think is
happening is that these people find um
one uh uh recipes and methods that work
for one plant in particular their little
like model research plant so to speak
for their grow and then they teach that
to other people and they're like yep
it'll work every time you know how do
you pronounce the MS word oh merage and
SK scoo I can't I don't know I like mer
mer and SC yeah yeah how do you spell
that it's like a Japanese name and then
like like a Scandinavian name like
Mig something weird yeah oh yeah yeah
yeah I see I always wanted to hear
someone pronounce it who actually knows
how to pronounce it but I don't know
anybody who knows how to pronounce it
yeah I have to like look it up and if I
read it I think I can say it but yeah
look it up Mur it's like Mur and or
scooch yeah yeah yeah there you go there
you go that sounds better than my migi
and scoo
yeah I add there that's not
there but that's like all science words
honestly like depending on where you go
to school people like like there's no
accents in English right it's just like
there's a common way to like say
something and so um people will throw
like the accent so to speak in the
weirdest parts of like long like multi-
syllable scientific words and I think
it's so funny because like um uh like
heterogenous heterogenous yeah you know
what I mean like people that I've heard
that said like four or five different
ways you know what I mean from like
professional teachers and stuff like
that you I don't know if it's cannaboid
or cannaboid I don't know which more per
I think it's cannaboid but I I don't
know yeah cannabis no when it when it
comes to ination like that that that is
very much like a local thing I think a
regional thing yeah the British and the
Americans if you look at like three
syllable words the British and the
Americans just just like don't do it the
same yeah yeah like
aluminium
aluminium Alum it's not even spelled
that way
[ __ ] yeah just like for us is it do
you guys spell it different to yeah we
do yeah
yeah up or or am I am I am I trolling
you Matt you
might what was that thing that I tried
to it was you got Birds it was about
whether the birds are mammals I think
yeah it was yeah yeah I Wasing to tell
you that birds are
M it's not hard to F me on that stuff
dude I didn't I had to take specific
courses to know that [ __ ] in college and
I still don't know it man like I took a
whole mology course that I got like a
[ __ ] D and I was just like sitting
there in my senior year and you like had
to take an upper division zoology course
and I was like [ __ ] this [ __ ] I'm a bnst
bro like why do I need to be like
memorizing animal skulls and like all
this stupid [ __ ] just to graduate all
you need to know is the monkey and the
baboon song and if you don't Google it
all you need to know about monkeys and
baboons I learned it from my grandpa
when I was a little kid as a side not
one of my grandpas taught me the monkey
the my stepgrandpa taught me the monkey
and the baboon song If you ever look it
up it it's more funny uh when you see
the lyrics for
it
leave it that all
right we have gone off the
[Music]
rails I think we're kind of done guys
like does anyone else have anything to
add about any of these topics Bing in
general any broad advice for newbies I
think we this is pretty
comprehensive yeah I'd say so for for at
least this far I think we covered it
pretty
well yeah like we said can can probably
break out into like specific things like
we talked about mother care and you know
there probably a couple of other things
um actually this is probably a good time
like if if there are things that you
want us to cover um please leave
questions in the comments uh because we
read them all I read them
all I find it so hard to come up with
new ideas sometimes so yeah we need help
yeah and some stuff like it you know
like I've covered it in past episodes
but only so much and like sometimes I'll
feel like okay that's covered no need to
do it again but maybe we didn't cover it
that well maybe there's stuff that you
would like us to talk about so
definitely leave that in the comments
too because I just assume it's covered
[ __ ] it we're done well the other thing
is that people don't a lot of people
don't go back like if if we've got new
viewers or new subscribers a lot of the
time people may not actually go into the
archive and just kind of pick it up but
there's a lot of good stuff in there a
lot there's some there's there's some
okay stuff some of it sucks there was
one guy in the the last comments from
the the Q&amp;A and he's like We Know Dan we
know and I was like what the [ __ ] he
talking about and so I listened back and
I counted like [ __ ] like it's like 47
you knows that I said I was like you
know you know oh man you got the curse
the curse hit
you you know what's strange do you know
what's strange like different episodes
will have different like will have
different Tendencies as a group like if
one of us starts saying like a lot it
actually spreads I think that's me
that's me for
sure I say a lot too and local says a
lot too and I know I think there was a
common comment that was like how many
likes does it take to get the center of
a
podcast a weird thing that people
multiple people said it I'm like are
these guys Bots like it's so strange you
just said it twice in that sentence no
we just talk like girls from La yeah I
mean I'm a literal Valley boy like I
have every excuse to talk like this I am
from California Valley Southern
California Valley I get to say like [ __ ]
them
all and by proxy you guys all get to do
it too I actually knew someone who would
like end his sentences with like I could
see that yeah I know people who do that
I had a
friend I had a friend who would end
every sentence with a question like are
you oh yeah are you are you sure like
he'd say something and it would just
every everything came off is totally not
confident because everything sounded
like a question it's really you want to
go to the store a lot yeah New Zealand
does do this a lot the infliction goes
up at the end it's to kind of like not
not seem too assertive or too aggressive
I think H yeah I can see that with the
personality of this person yeah for
sure I had to stop myself when I was
like there was like a period of time of
such a NorCal bro that I Ed so many
sentence with like you would be like
yeah but [ __ ] and I this Seattle girl
this Seattle girl was like why do you
always say butt
[ __ ] that's a good one it's a good
one yeah I don't know it's it's really
obvious like all our Tendencies when I
try to do transcripts of shows and
that's just that's a hot mess that's a
hot mess I end up hating myself
personally it's all my [ __ ] so
yeah no it's been good it's been good
and like we're humans we have glitches
and like repeat ourselves in weird ways
yeah and if if you don't like it leave a
comment and then comment who you hate
the
most stru you hate the most Jo us next
week on the Linguistics podcast that's
right that's right everyone will just
say they hate the Brit yeah that [ __ ]
Brit Dude that [ __ ] Aussie guy digy
do yeah
it's not my fault I'm Scandinavian yeah
I know I mean you were born in
Antarctica it's not your fault it's
where Scandinavia
is
Scandinavia lives in
a all right all right I'm gonna I'm
gonna try to rescue this and say yeah
try to
attempt indor and earn might actually
cover some of these like uh grow topics
and and maybe like more practic detail
in this series so keep an eye out for
that um they've just started so if you
haven't seen it it has been
unfortunately 18 plus so go and look for
that I'll put it in the description it's
a really cool one for for newer Growers
especially but you know for anyone um
they've got their own Vibe and it's it's
sweet um probably the other thing I'll
point to is that by this point when
you're listening to the show will have
had both uh both parts of the shahad
707c Bank episodes up so definitely go
check those out um good RS in part two
good reveals in part two uh I believe so
um things not well known that weren't
covered in other shows and stuff uh sha
so yeah uh big big reveals in some cases
uh other than that you know there's um
lifted genetics lifted seeds L lftd on
Instagram Gert by seeds in Australia um
we have uh rioto Europe our good buddy
gold over there for all of our European
seed needs we have Riot seeds.com for
all your spray seeds uh all the can
Illuminati gear all the breeder
Syndicate gear we have our Discord with
our patreon which is really awesome and
yeah do you guys got anything you want
to plug I did the mar plug first booze
booze so I'll say something to booze
because uh so booze are good by
seeds uh distribute seeds for us for
Australia but recently I spoke to booze
and he mentioned that um he is open to
trying to get stuff to New Zealand as
well so oh awesome awesome if you're in
New Zealand you might want to hit him up
yeah okay that's all I got Dan local Ern
you guys got anything you want to uh say
get off your
chest um just want to shout out my new
uh reversal sprig directly competing
with yours yeah that's right that's
right listed on your site yeah be listed
on my site farmer D's reversal spray
right to Riot's ex Ral spray yeah no
realistically realistically what what
I'd like to do if because Dan's doing
really good work with reversal stuff and
he's actually doing really good
experiments and if his does turn out to
be more effective than mine in a like in
a more General sense as far as applying
to more plants then we will definitely
carry farmer Dan and we'll be doing
something with it because it's just the
most most important thing to me isn't my
spray it's that people get the the most
effective spray for the best dollar
because that's really what's about in
the end you know and I think Dan's about
that
too yeah I'm kind of stoked on that I'm
GNA be trying to just like specialize my
stuff in the future too like that's kind
of the goal is like it's like hey this
is the OG spray you know like this is
the Z spray this is the you know like
whatever but it's like we haven't quite
gotten there I've got like a nice
General spray but no no actual
commercial intentions just yet you need
you definitely need a spray you need a
spray for like lady TP um lady potency
type uh strains like Skittles and and
Tangi they they need their own special
spray because they don't get people high
so they need special can't say lady
potency
dog is that is that not allowed anymore
for the little girls out there yes for
the little ladies that's what I meant
yes the little ladies not of course not
the big ladies not saying that all
ladies are I've heard a new term for
this which is actually dad weed right
who is it yeah that's what I say Dad
weed
pack pack taught me a dad turps for
terpinolene those are dad turps bro yeah
I [ __ ] love it because anytime I show
a bag of like tarpening Dom stuff to
people like oh that's some old
[Laughter]
school yeah it makes sense Dad Dad smoke
um thank you guys
for like helping us again uh ER local
Dan yeah thanks for letting us say out
yeah I you guys I don't know if you guys
all said this already but um go to Riot
seeds to get your blueberry stuff that's
where the Dank gear is it's where
everybody's getting the good seeds and
everything so do that if you're looking
for them in the United States yeah I
guess I don't plug blueberry enough on
this show right
no I don't think you do yeah I do love
it I do love the blueberry shout out DJ
Short even though he probably doesn't
like me too much shout him out for
that and with that I guess are we done
local you got anything no no I I don't
have any shout outs this time shout out
to my no shout outs
yeah none no one deserves it shout out
my two cats it's been that kind of weak
for local yeah
yeah all right thanks everyone yeah with
that that ends this week and we'll see
you next week uh same time same play
same channel
cheers want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it
out