welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to breeder Syndicate
I'm Matthew here with my co-host
thousandth who's been absent for a few
episodes while he takes care of stuff
thousand where have you been what's been
going on yo yeah I everyone it's nice to
be back it's been a while um I don't
know it's not been that long but it
feels really long in in the context of
our show
just because we're weekly if you're gone
for like a few weeks people are like oh
my God he's been gone for months is he
gone now but I think it's been maybe a
month maybe it's been a month yeah um
but yeah life was just getting pretty
crazy I have kind of two pretty major
projects outside of you know outside of
cannabis that um were just yeah totally
consuming me one most people don't know
you're a leading actor
um behind the
scenes I was on a huge
feature yeah yeah Swedish soap
opera can see it
now but thankfully one of those projects
is like winding up um so you know I
could just feel like the mental space
kind of coming back but yeah for a few
weeks there I just couldn't even think
about anything so definitely
appreciate um you know Matt taking over
for a bit I I saw that Dan obviously
came on for a stream as well which is
awesome oh
yeah how was that show do you remember
that that was was that that
was that was not last week's but the
week yeah two weeks ago yeah from when
we're recording this currently it was
two weeks ago yeah no it was great
anytime Dan comes on it's always really
easy he's a quick thinker and he's witty
so it's just very easy to fire back and
forth you know he is quick he is quick
um I think I got to see a bit of it and
um his kid's really funny as well like I
like it the kind of like the random
insights into Dan's like home home life
yeah I know that's great yeah the chaos
of home
life yeah and I think
otherwise what was the other thing I
wanted to mention oh yeah I did have
another within within my growing I did
have kind of a big fail um I was meant I
was wanting to do a little pollen truck
and yeah tell us about just for yeah
yeah just just for my own personal
project not not a commercial thing at
all it was BL it was going to be a blind
selection everything but um as Matt
knows I wanted to do uh blueberry in
Cross
um and an appy cross well yeah blueberry
and cross and appy um and I just I think
partly because life was so crazy already
then I was struggling just to like there
were multiple points in which I think
[ __ ] up so as Matt knows I had some
germination difficulties with the
blueberry Andross totally my fault I I
think I just like didn't really think
about the fact that they were like you
know obviously it's quite an inbred line
and so I didn't really take the care
that you know that should have
warranted um yeah I bust balls about
germinations and how it should be done I
just had another message uh with
something similar where you know I like
I always say wait until you get your
first true leaves like barely starting
before you take them out of the sterile
environment before you put them in a
medium like to me that's super important
because they can get water through the
top as opposed to just trying to get all
through the tap rout when bacteria is
invading the tap rout and stuff and
someone just had like six seeds like all
start and stop and you know I mean like
it's just a a common thing to
hear I think it's one of those things
where if you are just used to Growing uh
really new you know relatively hybrid
stock then it's easy to become
complacent because you're like oh well
it's worked for me like just about every
time I'll just keep doing it the same
way even though I kind of knew of course
especially because I'm on the show with
you yeah that like my Approach which was
you know just like soak and then sew
yeah um is obviously not the most uh how
do I put it if you're playing a
probability game that's not what you
would do um exactly if you're trying to
maximize your like success that's not
the approach this is just like the most
convenient approach for a lot especially
as it relates to money too like people
buying seeds you know they're they're
they can be quite expensive so like when
you lose one out of a population of 10
that's a tenth of the money you've
invested gone now and then two and then
three and it you know yeah yeah so it
was my first big lesson I think for that
and um it was kind of fun still at the
same time like it's not it wasn't all
just bad like I remember messaging you
about it and then even getting to try I
think there was one that like it was
quite strange it like popped
it like had it had cottis but like its
tap wasn't developing and that was quite
interesting to look at um for a while um
and I guess I just like you know learned
about different things I talked to Dan
about it and he was like oh yeah you
could try like I think both of you were
like yeah you could try some rooting
hormone on the little yeah route to see
if it does anything and yeah so I
learned I learned quite a bit and it was
it was definitely like an interesting
like you were so hard on yourself bro
you were so hard on yourself dude I hate
it man like it I I know it's a part of
it but like yeah I don't like failing
like that yeah know I I I understand
like I I don't like failing at all and I
do it quite often I think it was also
just that added context of the like I
should have known a bit bit than that as
well I think that hurt more than just
the failure was like yeah yeah I think
we had just done the germination episode
right before that too that was the best
part yeah so that was stage one failure
and and in the end I still got like I
got one special girl out of that so I
was at least like thinking okay I
salvaged it just I have something
something um but that wasn't the end of
my fuckups
[Music]
um I so I had like five or six appies up
uh in addition to the BB incross yeah
and then what happened was that I found
a few males what I thought were males I
had one that was like definitely a male
and then I was like oh I've got this
other one that I think's a male and it
seems to like you know again quite
fairly arbitrary selection during V was
like oh yeah it seems to smell better it
seems to be like has nice branching
structure I'll just go for this one and
I threw the rest away and of course of
course when it flowered it was not at
all a
male no so no so I had no backups either
right so not a huge lesson like uh don't
just assume that your you know your your
pre- flower identification is always
right like at keep it back up yeah CU at
that point I remember looking in looking
in the grow space and being like oh my
[ __ ] god like this whole project is
[ __ ] now because of
me yeah like um prejudging like by
branching and stuff can be real tricky
especially with some lines that stretch
real heavy they can look real male and
yeah it's not it no I mean I was looking
at the pre-fl flowers obviously as well
it would just I thought I was I was kind
of like judging across the different
males that I had I guess or something
basically in my mind I had like three
males and I was trying to make a call
but they were obviously not all male
yeah so yeah you know obviously many
obvious lessons there like taken more
time to have committed to one could have
kept backups of the others like but with
small space it's hard to do so yeah yeah
yeah I think definitely the context
being quite stressed about it as well I
was kind of like hurrying to make a call
so that I could free up space and free
up my own time being like okay cool I
can get rid of all these plants now
great yeah um but yeah you know overall
still really funny and like of course I
still get to grow a bunch of great
plants still get to you know flower out
the appies get to flow out the
bbx um and the bbx I've kept as well
I've got cuttings so we'll get to go
again um and uh I didn't keep the appies
unfortunately but I'm going to be I'm
running already vegging the
uh good old Mountain viw which is yeah
you should have plenty of stock over
there now
huh yeah yeah than thanks to M high and
Lonesome uh blew up my mailbox got yeah
got got
plenty did I get the blue EX in there
for that round or not were they made yet
not this round not this round that's
okay though like I got plenty of other
blue stuff that I want to look through
like the blue resin you know Blue Sour
the the the blue Bubba stuff as well you
gave me a couple of different versions
of that there's some really nice berries
coming out of the blue Bubbas both of
them the PE Berry and the blush um yeah
yeah yeah it's a great selection that
may be my next that might be what I do
next yeah um but yeah otherwise this
current or this upcoming um truck is
hopefully going to be that BB and cross
girl and uh an eie appy mail and that
will be fun are you sure you don't want
to just jump into reversals before you
even do
that oh man no I a little more no no no
no no no I don't to add any more comp
any more complexity to this I just want
to make some
sceds um and just like yeah like I said
to you I think privately like just
really want to see what the process is
actually like and go through it
um and yeah I think it's just one of
those things I think that you naturally
want to learn as a grower after a while
right like it just makes sense yeah I
mean there's nothing more um I don't
know satisfying to me than like having
fully formed seeds and buds as you pull
them out looking at the maturity seeing
they're all mature and yeah I I love
that whole part of it watching New Birth
happen it's weird it's weird how
maternal instincts kick in when it comes
to seed braing over time so even
especially on your first time too though
like that's yeah yeah it's it's it's a
good feeling
yeah and I mean maybe this kind of ties
into what we'll talk about a bit later
on kind of reflecting on some of these
uh conversations that you and I have had
with the especially the older Forum guys
like I think one thing it reminds me of
you know when I hear them talk
is it's nice to remember that kind of
feeling that magical feeling when you
first started um when you new and and
how amazing it all was and it's not that
like we lose that completely but it's
easy to like forget maybe sure yeah
and I think you know obviously pushing
yourself to doing new new things is one
way to kind of um get that feeling back
like you know for me like trying to make
seeds is is is going to be somewhat
equivalent to me growing my first plants
it's a new completely new experience
cannabis burnouts a real thing like
especially over you know decades time it
can be very very serious and you can get
burned out pretty hard so it is always
good to keep it changing and keep you
know experiencing new things in it
yeah definitely definitely I I won't you
know I wanton name names but you know
the I like there's a there's a there's a
friend mutual friend that we have who
like yeah just just had a hard time and
it's like you can see like how much work
it is obviously obviously like to
maintain you know that many mothers or
you know to try and do all these
different projects
and yeah yeah so hats off to all of you
who've been doing this for you know you
said decades that's not me obviously
some of you have and that is
that is the next level to me yeah that's
hard especially keeping moms and [ __ ]
too once you get into that it's like now
you're in it for the long haul you know
yeah yeah yeah no no vacations no
breaks that was the other thing I was
goingon to mention there was a couple of
months ago like it was actually possible
that we were thinking of doing a small
overseas trip this year yeah um for
unrelated reasons that's not happening
but like even trying to think in my mind
like how to prepare for that um you know
like if I you know what I would try to
save and how I would try to save it like
would I have to pass them to someone
else to take care of would someone have
to come to the house and you know yeah
obviously these are known problems that
we all have I remember one time I tried
to do it using something called blue
mats um yeah yeah that's so for people
that don't know they little ceramic like
things that have a hole on top with a
plug connected to a u a piece of I don't
know tubing and you you set it in the
like a bucket of nutrient solution you
set the the dripper end into the plant
and over time it's supposed to Wick it
up in there but the problem is like
unless they're weighted heavily they'll
just sit at the top and barely get any
water into it and I found that out the
hard way one time you know like it's
it's so complex I was like oh yeah I'll
just run blue mats no big deal I've seen
other people do that [ __ ] so yeah no
it's it can be hard compx
I've looked at that too obviously as
many of us have and I think the thing
that freaks me out is how long it would
take kind of what you're saying really
just yeah how long it would take to test
and calibrate um you need weight
on yeah and you need to actually like
figure it out over quite a long period
of time and then and then know that it
will work otherwise don't rush into it
last second and just wing it in hope I'm
telling you yeah that sucks yeah you at
next we I don't know why they're not
like sold weighted because they just Bob
on top and barely get any water in it
but you need it like almost completely
immersed to get water in it so if it's
not weighted heavily enough then it
won't go into the water it it just
doesn't make any their design doesn't
make any sense to me so you mean this is
the like Reservoir side is that right
yeah yeah yeah it doesn't make any sense
to me at all I'm sure some experienced
blat people can can comment yeah chime
in leave a comment below and tell me how
I screwed up yeah yeah tell tell those
of us who are like maybe vaguely
interested as a contingency if we you
know how how you would approach using
something like
that yeah
um anything else well you know speaking
of burnout it was good you know part of
the break was actually being able to get
out of the city just for a few days so I
left the plants here and they were fine
for a few days um thank God for Pete for
me just that's why I don't do Coco um
and it was nice just to be aware for a
few days and just like have a change of
scenery I think in fact when when you
and Dan were doing the live I was on the
road and Dan was messaging me being like
where's Matt he's late like should I oh
yeah that's right that's right I think I
woke up like last minute or
something yeah I think you guys started
no it wasn't too bad I think you guys
started maybe like 10 15 minutes off the
mark but it was fine yeah yeah that's
funny as well yeah nice to be on the
road
the last time you were on the road Matt
uh last time I was on the road was just
for that last trip rose all
sick
oh yeah oh I I mean technically the like
a few weeks ago when I went out and djed
and uh out in the mountains ah yeah yeah
yeah got it yeah yeah I was so [ __ ]
hung over I was wild I don't drink
anymore ever like ever not a beer here
there so yeah yeah someone busted out
peanut butter whiskey though and
me that ended me there's like pictures
out there of me like snoring in my car
like that sounds like it would be nice
for like a couple of shots of when you
get kind of sick of that or does it like
is it okay to keep drinking I mean it
was delicious to me it was so it was
sweet and delicious I never had it
before this dude uh Steve he had like a
a parka and like it was a scooter rally
out in the mountains for like Vespas and
Lamas and old mod culture and um so he's
wearing his parka and he opened it up
and he had like all these little like
airport whiskey bottles of all these
different types he's like B so he's like
here try this peanut butter whiskey I
took a sip I was like that's delicious
clunk clun clunk clun clunk and I had
already drank some beer earlier so that
was just end the end of me pretty much
but I was the last one standing trying
to get everyone to still drink with
me yeah there's no way I could like I I
I haven't I haven't really had a drink
in a long time and I think if I were to
have like a night I would be [ __ ] for
ages like yeah it took me I think I
slept for like two days after that I was
just so hung over so hung
over not a
fan hey at least it was a change of
scenery I guess and sure it was nice to
see those people as well for you yeah
and I had a DJ Gig the next week um
going underground records here opened up
their new location and one of my best
friends that I used to be in a band with
owns it so we did a DJ Gig there the
next following week but that was in town
it was fun though it was nice seeing
everybody like all the old homies show
up while we're just playing
music yeah that sounds
nice yeah I mean I I don't really like
DJing too much um especially don't like
being called the DJ because it has all
that connotation with it I just like
playing music forcing people to listen
to the music that I like is is my
pleasure you
know yeah yeah and it's a great service
for those people yeah yeah I bet yeah or
some punk rock down the
throat yeah I mean I think for me that
was I think that that that's like the
summary of my time away ultimately and
um I think I think today's episode will
be a bit more of a rambly one we we're
going to take it easy we've got a few
different like mini topics to to discuss
um and so I think yeah we're going to
talk about uh well Matt mostly is going
to talk about the the uh upcoming
rescheduling of cannabis uh and then
we'll maybe reflect a bit on like the
Forum episodes the some of the
releases uh whether you know Matt and I
have are excited about any any shows
coming up um and then we also have a bit
of a like Community question that we can
dig into for to to kind of wrap it up um
but yeah just a chill one
today all right yeah Matt do you want to
tell us about the whole resiling thing
yeah I mean like first off it it took me
a while to look into because my
immediate reaction when I hear about a
law being passed that isn't voted on I'm
like okay who lobbied for it what money
went into it and if we're not voting on
it they don't do anything to give us
more
like rights on their own just for the
good of their just out of the goodness
of their heart that doesn't happen with
our government or or in politics ever
like I know you didn't vote on it you
know but let's uh let's I was he
schedule this you know like there's
always a reason behind it they always
have agendas it's politics it's how it
works for me so I didn't really look
into it much um but I did you know
enough people were asking about I was
like well I guess I should kind of look
into this you know instead of just being
skeptical um so it looks like it's going
to pass I don't remember how long it's
going to take to pass but it's not
necessarily passed yet um there there's
like a 30 to 60 day window for people to
like write in and like the DEA to
comment on it and all kinds of other
weird [ __ ] that goes on
um let's see you know you have different
Republican Senators chiming in on it
Democrats and the one thing I I saw
about an hour ago they they uh tweeted
out that the DEA didn't sign off on it
which was interesting and they don't
know quite the implications of the DEA
not signing off on
it so that's kind of an unknown right
now was there something about the
director cheing being there or something
I saw a headline maybe yeah I don't in
the thing it said they don't know if it
was like
a a stance of them not showing up to not
sign off on it as like a [ __ ] you um or
if it was just like a matter of someone
not being there but it wasn't signed off
on by the DEA which leaves room for a
lot of push back from the DEA if they
want to and they can always be an issue
always as they've always been because
that's what keeps them alive is drug
drug war money you
know um yeah I mean okay if it were to
if it were to go through um so assuming
it does go through like what do you see
it's impact being maybe safe for like
maybe we start with like um people like
you man like how how might it impact
Someone Like You who's like you know it
wouldn't selling seed stuff it wouldn't
like from my level of seed sales it
wouldn't affect at all like it's not
changing plant counts it's not changing
um uh the ability to accept credit cards
it's not changing anything like that um
there is some kind of banking build
that's slightly altered by it but like
this all goes back to licenses licensing
the banking thing yeah yeah the the
banking thing is a huge part of why the
Cannabis industry is having issues um
there there is some IRS statute it
changes a little bit and I think it only
changes it to the point of where you can
like report like lights as taxable stuff
you know like if you buy lights you can
report that as a write off um and I
guess that wasn't a thing before I
didn't know that but I mean I don't ever
you know write weed stuff off because it
just seems like playing fire you know
what I mean um but it's been interesting
to hear like the different political
Avenues since you know we're a a a
Democrat and Republican only country
um there was a quote from a Republican
senator here that said marijuana is a
gateway drug and Democrats move to
legalize reflects pro-criminal
anti-American policies that will
stimulate more crime on American streets
he also argued that cannabis banking
legislation facilitates an entire
infrastructure and an ecosystem for more
drug usage In America which um very very
1970s
1960s type rhetoric I'd say yeah um but
that's to be expected I don't I don't
quite understand um the Republican
Democrat divide on this because they're
both so money hungry for taxes whe even
though Republicans say they're not like
they're as money hungry as the
Democratic side is for taxes could be
thing for their voter base you to like
play to what they perceive their voting
base you know their values to be in like
I don't know trying to make a bit more
of a show of it but ultimately maybe
still being like no it's going to be
great for for the taxes or like our I
don't know yeah and the one thing I also
read was that they wouldn't be able to
it would take like light speed
unprecedented um quickness for them to
pass this before the next presidential
election which depending on who's
President next if it's completely
different
Administration that could come backfire
and refold everything and make this a
totally nonissue you know what I mean um
but at the same time like I don't want
to sound like I'm saying you know
Democrats are doing something
Progressive for the Cannabis industry I
don't believe that for one second like I
think that they're doing it for
themselves like for their own
Investments for their you know their
sons and daughters who have these
cannabis companies that they're
investing in like that's what I think
this is all about big money that's
investing it's not to benefit um any
smalltime grower it's not to benefit the
people who have been pushing for
decriminalization or rescheduling all
these years there's nothing that's going
to benefit us like that that's not how
this works um maybe asking an obvious
question but would it benefit like Big
Industry players yes yeah I think so in
the end but they it wouldn't be like um
like a collective owner it wouldn't
benefit someone like that it would be
Big Industry like uh like one of the top
six marijuana companies on Earth you
know something like that that control a
large share of the the money coming in
um I'm sure those companies I'm sure the
stock prices of just sky Rock since
those announ very possible very possible
um here's a good quote too um let me see
I'm trying to see who is by sander zag
zagzebski co-chair of Clark Hills
cannabis practice whatever that is
schedule three doesn't legalize weed in
fact it just means it has a medical
benefit and you can buy it with a
prescription uh said whoever sandersi of
cherry of Clark Hill's cannabis practice
but none of the providers of cannabis
are licensed pharmaceutical companies
they're not FD regulated and of course
none of the recreational folks are
getting a prescription of any type so
cannabis is not going to be complying
with that regime um yeah the immediate
impact of uh rescheduling will be that
the IRS code section 280e will no longer
apply to plant touching state legal
cannabis companies and they will be able
to take normal business tax deductions
afforded to other Industries so that's
like the main thing is
that it's write-offs tax write-offs and
that's what tells me it only affects
like the major corporations that are
interested in that and that's probably
who lobbied for this what about like uh
individual consumers in terms of like
uh I don't know criminality and and what
people could be charged with how does
that so so far they're not even like
looking into as far as I'm aware like I
was researching this like making it
reverse charges of people already in
jail it's not really affecting that and
that's disgusting to me um it's and
again someone this is another quote this
is simply ending the federal prohibition
on cannabis for all purposes it will
still be up to states to decide what
legal what's legal within their
boundaries so it's still up to states to
decide and if your States like a more
anti-cannabis State it's not really
gonna like mess with that all that yeah
okay wait so can we come back to the
banking thing can you tell me a bit more
about the banking thing cuz that's like
a separate but related that's it own act
right that yes act and so how does it
how would it be affected by this
rescheduling or how how are they like
it's not it's not it's supposed to be
like Optics and say like oh this is a
good look for future like that they
might change that future you know what I
mean but because of this it might leave
them to change that okay even with that
like you have to have the correct
licenses and everything to even have
that apply to you like you know you have
to be one of the bigger companies that
pays these big big bucks to be able to
play with banking systems when this does
happen in the future um yeah it just
sounds like a bunch of Chad [ __ ] from
what I'm from what I'm hearing from you
it seems like for most of us and most of
the people who watch this show it's
probably not going to change our lives
or you know sorry the the Americans who
watch the show it's not going to change
their lives too much no and to me it
does similar stuff to like prop 64 was
telling everyone that it made cannabis
legal in California and people just like
oh cannabis is legal in California look
at the US it's so Advanced with its
marijuana laws and like while everybody
else is like going out of business
because we can't compete with big
corporate cannabis like it seems to me
to be one of those things where it's
like they go we rescheduled you know
we're so Progressive blah blah blah and
it's just nothing it means nothing yeah
it's cynical yeah yeah and and I'm
always like very very biased on those
takes but just even looking at what like
non-biased takes are on it they all are
saying the same thing I'm getting from
it you know like it's not going to
change anything U unless you're a major
player and and it's not even going to
necessarily go in before the next
presidential election which could mean
that it's a non it might be a non-issue
that it'll get flipped off the second
you know another Administration goes in
if they do which I don't even know what
to say about any of that but yeah I
think it was interesting to me because
it um the announcements came around the
same time that uh Germany legalized yes
um and obviously that they're not the
same at all or like you know there's a
huge contrast between the two I think
Germany's one is
like yeah it's not full
decriminalization either it's like
legalization in the sense that like uh
you know as an adult you can carry up to
x amount right and you have X amount of
plants like two or three or something
weird yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah and it's
it's wild to see people's reactions to
stuff like that in Europe like um you
know like I I mess around in the UFO
World a little bit so I was I was in a
chat room over there uh for a YouTube
show and just a random guy in there was
talking yeah congratulations to us you
know cannabis just legalized in Germany
we can grow one plant or whatever it was
and I was just like oh man you don't
even realize though like you don't even
know how bad this is you're you're it's
just it's I don't know it's such a
Negative take on all of it but just I
just see the Fallout 10 years from now
that they're going to be like actual
cannabis producers not just consumers
because consumers don't seem to ever
recognize the part that like how it
affects the Growers and will affect what
they get to smoke on the back end of
it no well to be fair to most consumers
it's just like a black box right they
don't really know much about what's
actually as long as they can go byy and
smoke they're happy that like I said
yeah they the producer aspect of it they
don't get they're gonna end up with
Walmart weed
so try to explain that it's like just
okay I'm looking at the I'm looking at
the law it's if I'm not mistaken and
someone obviously free to correct me
anyone in the comments but uh for an
adult they can carry up to 25 grams
which is about an ounce um and you can
grow up to three plants three yeah
that's what it was yeah yeah so think
about how much great breeding you can
get done with three plants it's very
hard yeah very hard so how how are these
like all the best breeding that's been
done in our in the Cannabis scene in
America has been done clandestine it's
not been done by these Big Industry
people selecting out of a thousand
something plants it's been homeg Growers
you know um but three plants makes it
rough makes it really rough to hybridize
do any of that stuff
so man I it it is really complicated and
like I sometimes think if I being really
optimistic uh you could say that
superficially it's going in the right
direction and hopefully eventually that
will lead to something better than what
we
have um I think that's they rarely give
back rights yeah like to me it's just
like they they don't give back rights
just to do it ever that's not something
yeah yeah yeah politics yeah yeah yeah
and when you that's like why when I see
oh we're rescheduling even though you
didn't vote on it it wasn't like you
know a movement by the people that's
when I'm
like who lobbied who lobbied Lobby
[ __ ] I don't I'm I'm so anti lobbyist
it's the most disgusting part of our
political system well one of them other
than the fact there's only
two like two sides that can get into uh
any kind of office
really yeah yeah I mean this all just
reminds me as well that down here you
know in the uh Democratic uh nation of
Antarctica um
we had it's similar like in terms of its
classification it's a similar problem
like it's I think here it's called class
a um and it you know alongside like the
hardest stuff um so you know more or
less the same class you guys call it one
to three right yeah one to three so you
probably have a to c yeah a Toc same
thing we had a it was slightly different
in that we actually had a n a national
referendum uh a vote on whether to
legalize and it wasn't I don't think
there was ever the option to
decriminalize I think it was only like
legalization so similar to Germany like
you'd have limits um the vote failed on
like a knif edge knif sge it was like a
like maybe less than 1% yeah um that it
failed so you know people voted no and
it was just really infuriating because
the government at the
time still could have just passed it
like they or they could have done
something but they just you know they
just kind of used that to cover their
asses and they were just like yeah see
it's no so we're not we tried yeah yeah
we tried there you go and now it seems
likely that that kind of opportunity
won't come up again for another like
decade you know because there's nothing
in it for the
government yeah but at the same time I
just think like knowing that that's a
place I'd like to move because that's
where opportunity is found in the Bold
you know I see what you mean I see what
you
mean yeah I don't know it is complicated
because at the same time it's like I
also it's hard
to someone who's just a consumer and
feel them feeling safer is hard to you
know that's kind of irreducible that's
you know you can't say that's a bad
thing for people who just no I'm just
kidding just kidding people but it is it
is complex for us who are like yeah on
the other side of it yeah I just it to
me it's my my passion's breeding so it
stifles breeding it to me it totally
stifles it like if it's left up to
corporate a cannabis who know really not
[ __ ] about cannabis to then take the
genome further that like it just
completely stifles all like like I said
everything all the best genetics out
there have been made in Black Market OBS
um over the years and there's not been
since since the legal times there hasn't
been a lot of advancement in breeding in
fact that's when we got the cookies era
so it's just like this is what we get
you know so it's to me it's it's proof
and evidence of it stifling
breeding yeah yeah it Narrows things it
um yeah yeah yeah yeah I mean because at
the end you you're just subject to the
forces of capitalism right which are
ultimately like
exploitative and um just want to exploit
the you know whatever type um of product
that like seems to be the most
successful and that's all you're ever
going to get right
what I've been talking about like my
friends up there tell me is that the the
people who do the buying of seeds for
the government that are allowed to be
sold aren't even cannabis people so you
have people choosing what genetics go
forward forward that probably don't even
smoke or have any interest in why these
are the genetics are choosing to go
forward I don't even know how they
determine that like it's a crapshoot or
a monkey throwing [ __ ] you know like
yeah it just blows my mind how that
works
yeah
um yeah anything else on this I'll never
rely on politicians for my job or career
or my passion like I I've tried to make
this such a non-issue for how I exist
and live that I could give less of a
[ __ ] what's going on in the political
world it doesn't affect me and it never
will I don't
think pardon my
French n it makes sense I get it I get
it it's it's pretty
it's it's very
um it's very discouraging to witness
like the more you learn about um how
those games work and the lobbying and
everything it is extremely Bleak um even
for those of us who live outside of the
US like obviously everyone we know we
have to kind of like watch what's going
on for you guys because it it does have
like consequences for the rest of us
especially those countries yeah um so I
mean Germany as well right so those two
you know the US and Germany
making moves is something that we have
to pay attention to yeah
definitely but yeah yeah still still
pretty disappointing yeah um if you guys
have any other opinions please weigh in
in the comments it's obviously like
quite a you know quite a thorny issue so
and I like if I'm being a little bit
even more skeptical I'd wonder if they
brought up the scheduling [ __ ] during
this particular time in the world with
the chaos going on on like be like a
highlight to a distraction yeah because
like people were wondering why Democrats
and Republicans are aligning so hard on
a specific issue together when they
don't on anything and all of a sudden
it's like okay let's bring up AR reason
to fight again you
know yeah yeah don't think about the
wars think of any of that yeah
exactly
geez well okay well mat is there
anything else you want to say on this no
I just
just people do your research um even
though I didn't even do research much
until recently for this but um use
common sense if they're giving you
something you didn't ask for and it's
the people who take money from you and
taxes ask questions don't just assume
it's for the benefit of the people
because it's usually
not that's my best
advice maybe I don't know I feel like as
you know citizens under such governments
you just hope that the interest happen
to align with yours that's that's
literally it
yeah vote at politics locally and hope
to affect stuff in your state you know
like there's that old quote all politics
is local um that's a real thing you know
but even then it's just who wants to get
involved in [ __ ] politics anymore God
I hate
politicians oh man it's a freaky looking
game from the
outside cannabis is bad enough bro and
political enough I don't want to get
that yeah and which is
worse I'm not sure euphology might be
worse than all of
them okay shall we move on to just our
like a mid-season recap yeah let's do it
so man and I talked a bit about this
we're not like going to get into like
very very specific uh Reflections or
anything but I kind of I was my prompt
for Matt was like we had a bit of a
theme this season which was talking to
people who were involved in the forums
from quite early on um whether that's
canak Cabana Crews there're two of them
right de man's crew and then Kirby's
crew and then well maybe not Cruz like
those two generations generation and
then we had subro on as well and so I
think I think my PRT for Matt was like
you know do you have any like very very
broad uh like feelings Reflections after
hearing some of that like didn't it make
you think about your own time in that
time on the forums uh you know whether
it's like what they were growing what
the culture was like for them versus for
you um I don't know yeah STW I think
yeah um so like uh start with the can
cavana episodes um like uh Dem man
skiddy hoe their generation was the
generation before mine on the forums
like before I started getting really
involved so it was it was things like
that for me are always a treat to hear
when people that came before me were
integrally involved in stuff that I was
involved in later and hearing like
different because not everything's
literal or not everything's passed down
correctly so you get to hear all these
stories about how other things happened
and I don't know like that those are
some of my favorite shows to do is
interviewing the people who came before
me and were just as passionate about
like seeds and genetics as I am that's
the kind of stuff that really really
really interests me
um I think it also when I hear them and
their stories it obviously makes me
imagine what it would have been like to
have been them where it was like an
absolutely New Frontier of like
communicating about this stuff and just
like you know um Uncharted Territory
right yeah and like the idea to pass
Cuts around and hold them and get them
out to people on forums and stuff like
that wasn't being done before these guys
so I mean there were small Pockets like
the 77 crew and stuff like that but
generally speaking that generation of
guys um it really wasn't being done like
that before so it really really built
the whole industry as it was to carry on
um yeah I will say one more thing is
that like for me like one of the feeling
I did feel some jealousy right in the
sense that uh obviously not saying that
there were no politics but the politics
back then were very different and it it
didn't it definitely seemed like not
every action was so weighted was so you
know I don't know how you would put it
but um they definitely it felt like they
were much Freer to do whatever right
pass things around to whoever share um
hold on people weren't as precious as
they are or might be
now um so yeah into the Kirby episodes
um those those were my era like I was
active during that time and and this
goes on to the sub Rob era he was a
little bit before me but then our times
kind of Co onesided even down to me
being in the San Diego's finest you know
threads with him um the the one thing I
noticed the most probably in the in the
My Generation
episodes my my experience from other
people's experiences in the Forum is
always so vastly different like I came
in trying to be the figurative pipe bomb
for the industry in my mind like seeing
everything I don't like and seeing all
the corruption and just wanting to like
caused chaos and and started over you
know like this needs to be broken and
rebuilt there's so much corruption just
inherently in here like a revolution of
sorts like I'm an idiot so like I really
thought I could do this [ __ ] you know um
in doing that I was banned from every
Forum that existed at some point other
than my own you know like maybe yeah I
don't think there was any that I didn't
have some sort of temporary ban from so
well while these guys were you know like
had a lot of camaraderie and stuff on
the forums I had some of that
but not a ton like not a ton I was very
much a rogue
element so yeah it's it's interesting to
hear other people that have had those
experiences and like I had friends that
were like really well-liked on the
forums and stuff but it was always a
joke because I was the most hated guy so
like trying to
um associate with that was always really
hard you know there of course there's G
to be some jealousy there like I would
have lik to have had that camaraderie I
just didn't necessarily feel that with
everyone and if you and at that time if
you spoke up against anyone that was a
big name and and even asked hard
questions uh even respectfully hard
questions you were just met with
derision and once you're banned from a
place everybody's like why' you get
banned must be a piece of [ __ ] and that
just carries on each time you get banned
more and more if everybody's banned this
real bad you know what I mean so I guess
that's one downside of that time which
is that people were very like it was a
lot more for like of bit a term like
feudal like
hierarchical yeah you know there these
little like on not enclaves but little
like tribes and um if you were out you
were out right of those yeah and I've
talked about it before on the forums
during my era that like okay versus uh
like the Dem man era there was one main
Heaven Stairway seed bank where you got
to go do this stuff and you know
overgrow was attached to that that Forum
but during my era every single form had
a seed bank attached to it and and in in
doing that if you spoke up against any
of those breeders on there you're exnay
and blacklisted from that forum and all
you know like all the dick writers that
go along with that on each level so yeah
it's uh that that is a main difference I
think between those two eras how hard it
would be to assimilate it would have
been much easier to assimilate during um
the man's era say versus um what Kirby
was talking about for sure or sub even
okay well I mean on that note like did
you have any thoughts about maybe more
on the side of like genetics provenance
like were there did you have thoughts on
like you know how different was you know
the stuff that each of these groups were
growing um to what you were maybe or
even just uh between themselves um were
there any like new was there any new
information that came to light in any of
those conversations I'm sure there was
new information um I'd have to go back
and relist
yeah but like like d man's crew era um
lots of Brothers Grim we hear that
non-stop from that era um the Dutch
Flowers we talked about Dutch Flowers
that's some new info that I that I could
put out there um Dutch Flowers they
weren't a Dutch they weren't a Dutch
seed company but they were called Dutch
Flowers and they were ran they were sold
on Heaven Stairway and they were making
like you know like they put them on
auction on seedbay for like cbay for
like you know a th000 which was
ridiculous for back then like ridiculous
but it would be you know bit up bit up
bit up and um I've always had this
theory that and and it was I think it
started through reeferman which is like
the worst Source on Earth for
information but when I first spoke to
him I asked him who ran Dutch Flowers
because that's always fascinated me this
this company that had like the first
hype seeds and um he's like oh yeah that
was Cal reian I was like are you sure
he's like yeah well you know I worked
with him a lot you know like I I know
what he was doing
and then my old buddy JoJo would make
seeds and send him into Heaven Stairway
and looking back I would see that they
would come out and be released under
Dutch Flowers that was also kind of
interesting but I didn't know if like he
was just sending in reproductions for
free at that time or how it was working
um but when I was talking to dman he
came to the same conclusion separately
on his own about Cal reian and that's
not his real last name by the way so so
you guys know um I'm not doxing him um
it's or RC Richard calan
um it always seemed to be like really
really nice um copyrighting like the
best for its time like this strain will
be blah blah blah it came got its name
because of blah blah blah it was always
really well spelled out always sounded
really good like the metal Haze because
we grew with uh or could had this
metallic taste you know like all these
different facets chocolate trip so chocy
with the chocolate thae and the Indigo
diamond and you know um yeah it was
always so appealing even even during my
era go going back and reading that they
always had the best copywriting and
that's kind of what calan was known for
um that's right I remember you
mentioning specifically how good the
marketing the writing was right it is
phenomenal like legendary um I mean I
probably use as try to incorporate
aspects of that in my own just like in
in trying to describe as best I can
when I'm selling something my experience
with it based on reading those and being
like oh because they're saying this this
and this I feel like I can get this this
and this from it and that appeals to me
but like I've tried to be more accurate
about it because their [ __ ] was not
accurate at all like go looking back
after being able to grow a bunch of
Dutch flower stuff like chocolate trip
wasn't chocolatey it was more like c99
you know like [ __ ] like that like
yeah I don't know that's that's one of
those parts of um history I'd like to
really really pull the threat on is RC
and his his business because Heaven
Stairway was so legendary and um he's
still out there you know like the guy's
still out there I and I know where he
works and it would be nice to interview
him but like because he went through so
such a big process with the courts and
[ __ ] I don't know if that dude has PTSD
from it all or he even wants to speak on
anything it would be great if he did um
if anybody knows him you know can always
show them the show and tell them to
reach out um yeah that's one of those
white whes like figuring out the RC
Story versus Dutch Flowers and overall
the Heaven Stairway story I actually
remember you talking about RC like quite
a long time ago on this show before I
started and stuff potentially like he's
someone or maybe that was R oh R he's
the other good really good writer yeah
he's the other amazing amazing writer
yeah from High Times back in the day
again that dude so far is still alive
he's really old but like I would killed
to interview him and have gotten no
response no interest no nothing like
I've I've written him letters uh emails
I've tweeted at him I see him respond to
other people so he's looking at his
tweet his Twitter but like yeah I can't
get anything like that those two are
some of the bigger white whales and of
course the other R the other RC Rob
Clark the other RC yes yes we um yeah we
will say say less about that for now but
yeah for sure um the three white whales
though you know sorry this is a t
complete tangent I think we'll come back
to the Forum stuff but just thinking
about copyright um are we [ __ ] now
with chat GPT like like all the white
label companies just going to start
using AI to write all their like you
know really generic descriptions of
stuff I also think like pictures for
plants are soon to be [ __ ] like you
can just have a a a picture you can't
back research and see that someone's
this picture from someone and you can
have it completely made up by Ai and now
you have this new strain even though the
the the seeds may not look like that at
all when you grow them out but like as a
presentation to put a picture up there
like yeah I think that's going we're
[ __ ] with that too like it's going to
be hard to tell who's lying who's not
unless you're a good grower grow them
out can you know have have data points
to show oh this isn't even like that
that guy's a [ __ ] dummy you know
there GNA be a lot of that coming up o
okay that this might be like a topic for
another episode sure yeah what AI means
for marketing in
Canabis you know like I'd rather not
have a picture than use a fake picture
like that like that's just promises
promises yeah um yeah I don't know
that's actually misleading as opposed to
like I don't know yeah
exactly okay okay anyway sorry back to
back to the Forum stuff for a bit um
what about when what about talking to
sub Rob because obviously that one you
know that San Diego that's local to you
how did you feel about those those talks
I like subro and me have been friends
for a long time I love that dude like me
and him have talks about life and just
everything in general we get along so
well on every level politically
everything like we just see the world in
very similar ways um during the San
Diego's finest area he was the only
person that was nice to me in that
[ __ ] thing um like no one liked me
there not one like they just did not
like me and I you know I'm kind of
grading so I get that but um yeah so I I
would have liked to have been more
involved in that and I remember at the
time feeling like like I should have
been more involved in it but I felt like
I wasn't allowed to be more involved in
it if that makes sense one thing I did
learn that I wasn't aware like because I
was kind of friends with ape like during
those years uh G as we referred to him
ape and
um buying tons of clones off him a lot
of the Clones me and Rob were running
during those years were the same exact
clones and I didn't know that and I
didn't know uh that that he was a major
influence like one of the main
influences on Sand die was finest
popping up to showcase the Clones so
that was fascinating shout out ape again
he's the guy who who made sure I had
cookies really early on and Cherry Pie
and stuff um always been super super
good to me like yeah I mean even in my
like brief paray through that through
those threads like you could tell he was
like a hub right like yeah write that
down by the way hit up ape might well
have him on see if we can get him on
yeah yeah yeah he's a great speaker too
he really intelligent so yeah it'd be
good good call um what about the plants
that sub Rob talked about like most of
them were they mostly familiar to you
because they local
or all of them all of them were familiar
like that that's what was really cool
about that was like when you have these
strains from your local area that you're
very familiar with or that are like
legendary and you grow up thinking about
those or you know what I mean like
they're big in your life that builds
camaraderie as well you know um the bull
riter the one that like by the time I
got down there it was gone it was just
[ __ ] gone so it was like just this
mystery you know like anything about it
was a mystery but Afghani bull writer
was down there you know um and and of
course me and Rob like kind of had
differing opinions on the uh the release
of The Afghani bull riter but you know I
had a lot more info on that uh the Back
info on uh the particular person we were
referring to so yeah that's always going
to happen you know like especially in
Cruz like he's going to like someone
that I don't or be be L at least like
not know as much about someone as I do
or have as much to say about someone as
I do different experiences that happens
a lot um yeah yeah that that tends to
happen when I talk to people that were
around during a certain era I'm like
[ __ ] that guy you know like what do you
mean he's okay [ __ ] that guy that
happens a lot so
yeah one thing I didn't get the chance
to ask him in that first episode
was like what's happened to those that
group of people now or whether he's
still in touch with them or still does
stuff with them or um like one of the
main guys was a guy named gry skull I
mean I'm still in touch with gry skull
too but he's moved on I think from
cannabis now finally
um I don't
know I'll keep it vague on that but yeah
he's a great dude though everybody all
those guys still talk to each other I
think they're all still really close
grotch sub Rob um spol Shan cron um all
those guys are still really tight and
there's more there's more sorry guys if
I didn't name you but yeah there's a lot
more um Josie Wales of course no longer
with us um he's part of the gorilla glue
for four crew
um Ross same so yeah I wonder if um in
those in those shows it was it was clear
enough to some people who are newer like
that some of these guys were actually
directly involved in some of the
biggest you know things that we have now
like for example I know one thing we
wanted to cover that we didn't get to
was talking about um hplv and the fact
that like on San Diego's finest that was
one of the first times it popped up like
people talking about it was gry skull
talking about the sour no the Gorilla
Glue Flo I think or sour dub one of the
two um being quote unquote dted that was
one of the first times it was ever
brought up that was on there and later
talking to Tumi and a few other places
it sounds like sour dub was actually
patient zero according to everything
they've back traced that that might be
where this
weird however it was introduced from
hops was onto the sour dub plant and
then distributed maybe not at the
beginning of sour dub but later on you
know I wonder if it's possible as well
that there were multiple patient zeros
in different places at a or there
literally was just one single point of
origin I yeah don't know enough about
these things um I don't know yeah I mean
it it just seems s like such a random
thing to bring a uh something over from
pop cannabis I got to say as I was
reading through those threads it was
really interesting to kind of like see
them talk about it without of course
like you know without the context that
we have now yeah yeah and it's almost
like [ __ ] I don't know like
uh I it's like a flashback in a movie or
something where like you seeing the like
origin of some villain or something you
know and people like the first thoughts
that or what people were saying about
yeah this like evil presence that was
just like starting to grow um need to go
back to the future dude and send him the
[ __ ]
info yeah oh yeah man reply to that
thread man they'll get it back in the
exactly never know build a wormhole you
know I that's that's a part we didn't
get to that I thought that would be
interesting to talk about yeah Rob Rob
didn't want to talk about that yeah
again um the other thing that popped up
in those threads that we didn't get to
talk to I mean speak to although it's
not like the most exciting topic but I
did notice it was the Forum cut
appearing in those threads as well and
when that happened yeah like I said um
that was around the time ape got it to
me you know and and uh lump lumpy had
his big uh um thread lumpy flowers lump
status on um icy mag showcasing the
Cherry Pie and and cookies that was one
of the first threads like just huge
grows of forum and Cherry Pie that
people got to see in animal cookies too
um so yeah and that was that was one of
the first times I saw it and really got
to see like this weird un same did he
post those in the same thread or is like
his own I don't remember if he started
in San Diego's finest but I know up in
there but he did have his own thread
called lump status flowers I think right
or lumpy GSC cherry pie or something
like that yeah but he was a part of the
the SD's finest crew too um yeah because
you know one thing about going through
the San Diego's finest threads is that
there are a lot of pictures of old
plants in those and I doubt that like
you could like you if you searched on
Google that you would find those
pictures I think like you'd have to
actually go and dig through them um but
there's a lot still there I was quite
surprised I was surprised that Rob
pulled up the super hog it was an old
line that me and James hog had worked on
like the the um Hogs breath OG SoCal
Master hybrid and like he text me's like
do you see this and it was me posting in
like I don't know 2009 is I think I have
the super hot yeah it's [ __ ] like I
haven't seen that in a long time totally
forgot about that strain
yeah wild to see
that um I think I it was maybe the I
don't know if I'd seen pictures of the
p91 before that thre yeah they're up in
there yeah so I I linked to those
threads in the sub Rob part two episode
um definitely encourage people who are
interested in that to go and like have a
browse I mean it's like four three or
four three threads for the cuts one for
seeds I think
the the finest Cuts threads are like
like two to 300 pages each yeah they're
so long they're so long I was trying to
get through all I was trying to like um
quickly just literally flip through all
the pages but it was so yeah much it'd
be hard to intake all that info you know
in a city I think what I was I was
starting to just ignore all the text and
just look at only the pictures but even
that was a lot yeah that would that
would still be
intense yeah it's a lot there like going
back and trying to restudy and reread
that I was going through the same thing
and some of the stuff I was remembering
I was just like oh [ __ ] this guy it was
a lot of that oh [ __ ] that guy I'm sure
you would have had like a yeah yeah yeah
yeah an interesting time going through
that yeah um okay well is there anything
else on the Forum comos that you no I
just I'm excited to do more um I don't
know how much and leave a comment below
uh respond to this like I don't know how
interesting interested people are in it
like of course it's interesting to me
because I was a part of some of that and
and participated in it and uh had wild
experiences in it met some of my best
friends on Earth you know there um but I
don't know how interested the audience
is in it so leave a comment below and
let us know if you want more of stuff
like that like genetic nerds coming on
people that are nerdy as [ __ ] like I am
about it or do you want more grow topics
or what you want comment below yeah it's
been interesting I'm gonna guess that
our audience is now like I want to say
divided but they're obviously going to
be different um groups within within the
audience and I think we got a whole
bunch of new people in through the
growing episodes and yeah obviously a
strong following already from the
beginning with the breeding um and like
Forum uh content so yeah I'm I'm also
curious I wish we had a way to like
break it down so we knew like What
proportion of people like not that it
necessar the only way we can is to get
people to comment that's the only way
we'll know really yeah comment yeah yeah
no one's ever going to fill out a
[ __ ] survey or anything no [ __ ] surve
I don't fill them out trying to get
stoners to fill out Sur yeah
no who get trolled sure yeah I'm
sure okay okay well maybe the other
stuff I was thinking that we could just
touch on even briefly is like um both
the some of the I know you've been
talking about these anyway but you know
some of the drops that have already
happened and maybe upcoming upcoming
drops so obviously it would be hard for
us to like um go over everything but are
there any like highlights for you I
think from yeah so the past like few
months we've had my blueberry incross
drop that I'm super stoked about it's
it's where I feel like I'm happiest with
the the blue work at from Blue Bonnet
and uh essentially DJ shorts blue blue
bonnet that's what I'm happiest with
like being able to release that um we
had high and Lonesome stuff come out a
bunch of his mango hay drop uh his mango
hay work uh is I'm stoked on it like
that's one of my favorite Haze lines uh
that in Neville's Haze probably um and
he made amazing crosses with it like so
yeah I'm stoked on that um pack has
another blue dream cross to drop still
of reversals that haven't been announced
and he just recently had one I knew
about that yeah and he had one with the
green crack blue dream and and a few
others um the p91 um S1 cross the Blue
Dream bitters cut yeah stuff like that
phenomenal stuff we got to see some nice
grows of all that in the patreon so yeah
definitely join the patreon if you want
to see like uh a lot of these tester
picks and uh what else we have the oh
Matt Elite drop like I've been trying to
get Matt to drop for five years at least
at least um
you know I grew his seeds very early on
and I I was just blown away not not just
by the seeds but by the human behind
them um how good of a grower he was so I
knew how in order to do selections you
have to be able to grow a plant to its
ultimate potential to see what it's
capable of and because he's such a good
grower his selections are phenomenal and
um I got to see that by growing his work
and for the last five years I've really
wanted to get to get his stuff out there
and he's just a very very much like uh
bod in a sense like just very
kind and doesn't like drama totally left
the weed world because of drama just
doesn't want to deal with it like too
many people throw out negative energy is
just not into it so he knew that
releasing this might open himself up to
some of that and he just wasn't into it
at all but I'm very glad and thankful
that he did because there's going to be
a lot of really really stoked people um
OG's been missing from our community not
not missing it was in abundance for a
long time and then trying to find like
really good OG Kush in regular seed form
became damn near impossible like I had
it in in hybrid seed form with blues and
stuff but I didn't really keep a lot of
the OG OG stuff because it was around so
much back in the day but nowadays people
are really trying to find that gassy
gassy cushy you know that pinea gassy
Fuel and that's all this is in Spades
and it's in regular seed forms so you
can make crosses with it and uh yeah and
it's like 26 seeds a pack you know like
he he hooked it up so I'm I'm I I'm over
the moon about are some of them up
already or are they like about to go up
or no they're all up cool yeah yeah
they're all up and available people
stopped pestering you about when they're
going up and yes people have stopped
that and now it's more like when is he
going to restock this one sold in 5
minutes once he got to raise talk
there's still some left but yeah it's
they they went very fast especially the
resurrection which is the uh line I've
talked about the most the Kem 91 chmd
I95
because like the reason it was called
Resurrection is because like he felt
like and I didn't understand this until
after I smoked it I was like that's why
you called it Resurrection it was like
Kem 91 but just with the turps turned up
to I don't know just a ridiculous amount
so you can smell all those the back
smells that you'd smell on the clone of
chm91 you'd be like man that would be
really nice if it was you know a lot
louder of that and it was just like all
those scents turned up and um it was
like resurrecting that old clone to be
what those guys probably smelled when
they first grew it um that Line's
perfect it's absolutely perfect so that
sold out like I think even less than
five minutes like minute you know it was
gone wild yeah I don't know I was stoked
on it I was stoked to get
there yeah yeah it's nice to see that um
you know you got the message out and
people are definitely very very eager
yeah for it I love that guy too so it
makes me happy that he can because the
other thing was he's like yeah nobody
wants this [ __ ] nobody cares and I'm
like for years I've been telling them
dude you don't know you don't know I
promise you you'll be surprised and of
course like when things sold out he's
like godd damn you know that's shocking
but yeah shout out to man
yeah and I hope uh H&amp;L doesn't mind me
saying this but I feel like hnl also has
been like quite really like
self-deprecating about his work and I'm
like why you like this why you so jaded
I mean at the same time I'm like I also
know why you're so jaded but he's just
very humble farmer guy you know that's
just him yeah him and Matt Elite are
very very similar in in a lot of ways um
and you know to be fair like I know what
it's like to have been working in a
space for a really long time it is it is
easy to get like you know disillusioned
or like feel a bit like me about the
whole thing but his attitude is more
like just seeds you know like that's
just it just
seats but yeah I think the mango hay
stuff will get a great reception um I'm
glad that most of the people buying it
aren't people buying off of hype too
because mango Haze isn't like something
super hyped it's people that want to
have a haze experience that understand
what a haze experience would be and what
it would entail to grow that it'll be
long lanky you need to grow plenty of it
to find a keeper people understand that
that are buying it so that's I think
that's super important too like lines
can be received well and or ill-received
based on who buys them like if you're
not educated on Haze and you're buying
it you probably won't be stoked
um you know yeah yeah buy
commercial yeah I think and I hope I'm
not mistaken I have to go check again
because you know you guys sent me so
much stuff but I think sent
me dog [ __ ] you know e mango Haze he
might
have yeah hope I haven't gotten that
wrong but that that seems kind of fun
yeah makes
sense he also had um freebies I think it
was
uh what was it can't remember what the
female was but it was cross to C Vietnam
Black so like an nl5 Haze oh yeah I
vaguely remember but can't remember what
theis Emil side was God damn it but yeah
yeah know like I remember looking going
[ __ ] these are the freebies that's fire
fire fire fire so yeah guys goow some
and send Matt some yes send me some
smoke or except Matt can't smoking oh
yeah yeah send me some in eight months
whenever it's
done [ __ ] oh man I impressed that you've
I mean at the same time I I gathered
like this like how bad it was how bad it
was that this is what you're resorting
to um so I also appreciate that I it was
a miserable experience um going through
canono hyperemesis
syndrome but this is a miserable
experience because like I I have such
bad anxiety all day and I really was
using cannabis to cope with that and
dabbing um and it really I don't know if
it at the time I felt like it wasn't
helping that much but like looking back
like being sober all the time it
definitely made a difference and it does
it's major life change and I remember
thinking like during the time when I was
going through all the throwing up [ __ ]
like thinking like you know slowly
coming to the conclusion that maybe this
is CHS and that I would have to stop for
at least like a month to figure it out
like thinking that it it would have to
be the last resort in my life to ever
come to that point where I would quit
smoking for a month full to even find
out just to find out and I was able to
do it from the jump and never went back
like I never re you know I I don't know
but it sucks it sucks ass I cannot wait
till time's up and I can start flooding
my receptors
again right maybe few were dabs when you
come back yeah yeah I'm not going to dab
anymore that's one thing I'm not going
to do is dab um I really
learned like I I I have a a hard time as
a like a former addict and like I'm I'm
an addict of a lot of different things
in my life whether it's food or you know
how I spend my time or interest how how
OCD I get about stuff yeah yeah yeah I I
don't realize when I'm being compulsive
about stuff so like dabbing could be a
real issue so I'm just not going to do
it when it uh I'm able to smoke again
flour I think I'll be fine with just
flour and won't have any more issues if
I go through this whole process and
really do um clean my receptors out yeah
yeah okay
well um is there anything else you
wanted to highlight otherwise we can
move on to squirrel's this moved on to
squirrel's question was a good question
I mean what do you so you have a read of
it I think you've got the the document
on your screen um what do you I'm not
I'm not 100% of on how to approach this
I'll leave this to you I think like how
do you interpret this question um he he
was asking me to break down how scammers
inflate generic terms over promising
traits so I think I've talked about this
briefly in different aspects and
different respects to different lines we
touching in many different ways MH but
um like he said for an example like ABC
sour Haze
nl5
um three different lines that are
notoriously hard for line breeding
so trying to breede
certain okay let me let me rewind it
back let's say you have a line and you
grow out
plants and only one of those plants has
that expression and you grab that plant
to breed with it right if you then cross
it to something
else you you wouldn't expect to see 50%
of the population to be that because in
its own population it was recessive it
was very rare on the line if it was
recessive it was just very rare
occurring you know
um I think that's what he's referring to
in stuff like this like Haze it's self
has tons of different Expressions so
promising like a haze IBL is hard it's
very hard to do uh it would take many
years of breeding a haze in a certain
direction because it's a a like one of
the first poly hybrids um things like
ABC uh a trait that isn't locked in
until you're in the F4 generation
roughly F3 F4 you're starting to see
true beating traits of that uh ABC type
like having a a one-off ABC hybrid would
be more hard to find that you know um
what else do we got here sour now sour I
think can dominate in looks more often
than it does in turps sour has a
particular look so when people see that
they think because it's very distinctive
look I've got it yeah they think we've
got it they think we got it for sure but
that's just one trait out of everything
that comprises sour um that burnt rubber
nastiness in sour isn't necessar going
to show up with that trait the look
trait every time so I I think that's
kind of what he means by this like we've
seen a lot of sour different iterations
of the generations and whatnot but like
in um for example Karma saau like there
was a lot of just mostly OG in that it
looked like sour but it was a lot of OG
turbs um and people really thought they
had it you know just because it had the
look so I think that's what he's
referring to in this um I don't even
know if it's more of a a scammer thing
as opposed to just like people that are
behind the scenes making the seeds don't
know what the [ __ ] they're talking about
um they're not growing out enough plans
to see that they haven't achieved what
they're
claiming nor do they understand how
genetics work and that having a rare
expression pop up in a line doesn't mean
that they can cross it once and then
that line is like half that yeah I think
that's I think that's the key I think
that's a key framing I think that's a
good summary statement of this and I
mean I had a
different maybe this is another way to
ask you this question which is
like if you were you know uh you're
trying to be responsible as a breeder or
seed seller um knowing that like these
things tend to be
probabilistic um what's the best way to
frame this kind of information because
obviously you need to give people some
information but you you kind also
pretend that like you know absolutely
what they're going to get so I guess you
know one of my initial impulses to say
well you can you know one thing that I
do see people do is like present like a
range right a range of expressions and
say okay when when I grew this out when
my testers grew this out we saw like you
know some collection of possible traits
and I guess that's maybe one of the ways
you can approach it right like yeah the
other way is to use a true breeding line
as a parent that will help a lot you
know like if one of those parents is
very close to true breeding for several
traits I mean that's why again why move
on from Bonnet forever because it it's a
tributing line like it regularly and
reliably kicks blueberry turps and it
has a very specific look has specific
resin pattern type that it breeds true
for in the sense that it in almost
everything it's crossed to it'll occur
more regularly than its partner in that
sense um that makes it so you can say
okay you can expect to see bury this
this that you know like three different
main Expressions that helps because it
it brings some accuracy um but the other
way yeah is to just explain the
different ranges the the different be be
realistic about the flowering times too
because a lot of people are not
realistic about flowering times
whatsoever in the
descriptions yeah it reminds me didn't
we did we not do a show where like we
actually look through like some seed
websites just to see what the marketing
was like did we actually record that I
don't I think we did I don't think we
did
I was goingon to say that like another
time we could like we could pull up a
website in the background and actually
show people who we're talking about just
to like you know not rough too many
fills and like maybe like just comment
on like the way that the information is
Being Framed stuff like that uh we can
do that another time I think that'd be
fun I it' be a nice experience it would
be funny it' be very funny I think make
lots of
friends I'm so sure we did it I I feel
like I memory of you and I looking at
say like Barney's Farm website I think
we did you know what I think we did that
for just like a few minutes of something
but not a full episode of it it would be
interesting to go through like open up
the attitude let's go through the list
that actually was that would be a great
episode comment below if you want us to
do that because I'll take the Heat and
do it you know like I don't I think for
the major seed banks it's not too you
know it's not too scary because you know
they're this like like you said it's
like Walmart it's like who cares like
Walmart the attitude anyway they're a
bunch of [ __ ] that's what I say um
they were [ __ ] to me [ __ ] them so but
it's not even about them it's about the
the Breeders they carrying though like
we'd be going over the Breeders are
carrying those are individuals um and uh
yeah but I'm down to do it because like
everybody should be held accountable
including myself you know people hold me
accountable all the time and ask me
every question they can so why not
everybody else you know I've talked
about these ideas before like in a
broader sense like uh I think that we we
probably could do a different kind of
reviews of like differents of cannabis
content but I just haven't really
thought about how to frame it all like I
think it would be very funny to do like
a Strain Hunters one for example oh my
God yeah um but again I don't know how
you know practically I'm not sure but we
can think about it I me yeah comment
down below if you want us to review um I
don't know mainstream I guess you'd call
it mainstream Cana content I think it'd
be fun to do like on the on the patreon
Discord to load it up like a video and
just have me talk over it but then again
I'm probably oh yeah on the stage yeah
yeah it would work on the stage it would
be hilarious yeah I could do
that okay um what were we talking about
again oh yeah yeah that question yeah I
think also it just reminds me that yeah
like you said we have approached this
question in like many different ways I
think in the past like we had that whole
episode on like white labeling we talked
about it again with pico white labeling
that side of the marketing we've talked
about breeding in general and like how
you look at in terms of probability and
like um you know what a true breeding um
plant would do in a breeding project as
opposed to something that you you know
have no clue about or like you know
whatever
um in some ways this is just the
question isn't it like this is the
question we just come back to again and
again which is how do you given the
information that you have as a consumer
or buyer of seeds or whatever like make
decisions about what you're buying and
it's I need to make B marter episode
which would be like going through the
attitude or something how do I how would
someone experience go through and pick
seeds you know if they're something
specific something like that yeah yeah
yeah we could do it we could do it
because I think what we've done in the
past has looked at it from a breeding
point of view yeah but not necessarily
from the buyer's point of view no no
it's yeah and I you know like a lot of
what I was doing early on was because I
was also a seed buyer not just a seed
maker and I felt like people need to be
protected like this their hard-earned
money you know like people are getting
swindled left and right not just people
some of my friends were still getting
swindled at this point you know still
are and uh it' be nice to have something
for them to understand like this is
something I take into account when I'm
looking at seeds and Seed buying from
someone this far in that's from the
opposite side of the spectrum go in look
at other things and but I'm sure people
would say I'm just a hater or you know
just hating on certain companies because
I'm jealous or something but I
realistically be it'd be nice to do from
a seed buying perspective to help people
I mean I have you know my current take
on it is that like I just won't there's
no way I would even consider buying
anything if I just if I don't know the
person and when I say don't know them I
don't even mean like I recognize their
brand I mean like if I haven't talked to
them and I don't know what they're about
I'm not even going to consider it you
should be able to ask questions and yeah
yeah be able to be relatable to these
people because at the end of the day
rock stars I'll put it differently as
well like there's so much good work that
can be trusted or like good work from
good people who can already be trusted
so why would you even like bother with
like yeah anyway been that from the
rooftops forever like why even waste
your money like that when there's
already good people yeah yeah yeah
you're not going to be rewarded for like
taking risks in that regard I don't
think no no no there's not a lot good to
find that way
yeah okay well I think that's good that
kind of signals that yeah maybe we do we
should do a show on on that specifically
like the buyers Journey yeah and and
feel free to leave comments below if you
have other show ideas we'd like to take
them from our patreon Discord too u a
lot of people in there you can hang out
with but uh feel free to leave show
comments below too um yeah
yeah man I think that's us for today I
think we like can keep it pretty cute um
M wrap it up in a package yeah yeah
little
bow pink bow that's
right all right so uh I guess you have
anything else you want to
say not really this is nice to be back
uh feels very to have you back you know
feels very familiar it wasn't hard at
all to slot back in so nice to be back
all right with that um go check out
reds.com for all your seeds and spray
needs um we have stuff to make feminized
seeds there's a bottle behind something
over there
that's hidden um uh we carry seeds from
all sorts of breeders in our crew like I
said high and Lon just do his Mega Hast
drop pack has his blue dream stuff up
and his trade wreck stuff up uh Matt
Elite seeds there's still some left to
get we have my blueberry and cross drop
uh M Jill has her seeds up there sub Rob
has his seeds up there the skank dog and
the
sssdh um no I'm missing some but yeah
anyways go check them out they're great
people they're up there and all these
people are accessible whether it's on IG
or the patreon Discord all these people
you can talk to and interact with and
they'll talk to you about their lines um
then we have uh of course like I said
our patreon Discord go check it out
patreon.com Syndicate it's uh $5 a month
uh for the cost of a coffee you can have
a lot of benefits uh 30% off me and
paeds um or high and low I'm sorry Farm
info people info people it's a great
it's a great [ __ ] community and when
like in other communities there's always
trolls and [ __ ] this one handles itself
I mean it's pretty self- policing if
someone doesn't fit in and they're just
being rude and and hurtful they don't
last long so um I really appreciate it I
never thought I'd see it grow to what it
has um I a lot of that a thousand
because like it it really really turned
up um yeah I'm proud of everyone there
and uh yeah I think isn't that it did I
cover it oh oh go check out um lifted
lifted seeds.com lftd seeds.com um Riot
Seed Co Europe for all your Riot seeds
in Europe needs ger by seeds for all of
your what would you call that part of
the world
Southeast you I think you'd say like
Oceania but people don't know that term
just say austr New Zealand yeah yeah
Australian austr New Zealand needs uh
Gert by seeds on Instagram and uh with
that yeah that's it
cheers everyone
everyone want to sit at the table with
The Syndicate check out our patreon and
our link tree or description below our
merch site is officially live we have
all sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies
to sort you out and shipping is super
fast and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history history together daily
it's an amazing community of learning
away from IG and it's an amazing
resource for old cataloges and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out