welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey in defining my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
[Music]
hey what's up everyone Welcome to our
first edition of is it worth the hype
the idea behind this series will be to
have my review of some of the modern
hike flower that is out there and let
people know from an older Breeder's
perspective what I'm experiencing these
are never paid or sponsored they're all
on our own dime and the help of good
friends too we have ensured that there
will be no case of being beholden to
anyone for a good review so that's part
of it I wanted to put this out there at
the beginning like you know because
people kind of get that less transparent
about why they're giving good reviews or
bad reviews and just from the jump we
want to say we ain't be holding to
anyone
reviews or reviews
I have to edit button anyway so it
wouldn't matter even if we were I'd just
be screwed so yes with that said welcome
to the first official installment of is
it worth the hype and today I thought I
would start with
permanent marker so this name
immediately brings to to mind like being
in high school or just doing art and
smelling a Sharpie marker you know what
a Sharpie marker smells like right
um
yeah so or like a marks a lot you know
very acrid ammonia it like almost uh
hard set to place but everybody knows it
it's in your sense memory so that's what
I was expecting when
um I got this
um and today the flower that we have was
grown by alien labs and um I'll throw up
some pictures here
and as you can see I'm going to start by
going over just the looks not sure who
gets the credit but that's the permanent
marker I'm not sure what's in it it
doesn't really
cookie something that's all I mean
because realistically you're not going
to get a straightforward answer from
that those persons
um
let's see
picture up uh just for looks alone
um The Strain checks all the boxes for
the most you know most flower buyers
most flower buyers are going to be very
happy when they see a good grown version
of this
um it's a deep purple
super Frosty white resin visually very
similar to things like Oreos ogkb very
dense which isn't my preference because
traditionally I used to break up flour
by hand however with the flour mill
grinder and again not sponsored I paid
my own money for this overpriced [ __ ]
um but now I use this because it
actually is a great grinder despite
being overpriced I it's great it makes
like this dense flower be very aerated
fluffy and doesn't destroy all the resin
glands somehow I don't get how that
works but it's pretty phenomenal I just
think it could be done in a crate a much
better price point considering that's
all the magic that and that are all the
magic
you know
um so yeah visually it's beautiful
um can't complain like it's it's very
well grown uh it's not handled roughly
it's pretty decent um
I don't recall ever getting something
from Alien Labs before but
based on all the other stuff that I have
gotten recently from
that brand
um
Loud Pack uh all AKA whoever they're
selling through that day
that that stuff doesn't even compare the
quality of this so
shout out and props to alien labs for
for good quality on this [ __ ] for real
and um shout out to my homie who who
sent this my way this impressions are
sin so what I like to do scent I like to
uh grind it up now prior to grinding I
like to smell the bud on its own and see
what I smell there and see if anything
more comes out after the grind so I'll
explain what I smelled beforehand I
wrote it down
um I said doughy Sherby cookies
so that isn't super helpful at all for
folks who didn't have a lot of
experience with any decent sourced
version of any of those cuts or S ones
so I'm going to try to elaborate a
little more
um the first scent and this is gonna
confuse some people because immediately
they're going to go to burnt rubber
that's not what I'm talking about
the first scent I get here is a car tire
shop
like the actual shop where they sell
tires
um
it's not burnt rubber but it is the
smell of a tire shop and it's just one
of the many smells in it
um the next scent is the most people
typically refer to as doughy and if you
think of it like um in the sense of like
making a cake vanilla cake batter at
home
um that's more of the line of what I'm
thinking as opposed to a baked cake that
you can smell the sweetness from you can
almost taste it from the smell with with
cake batter
it's more doughy there's eggs there's
you know milk there's all kinds of other
stuff in it that when you mix it up it
combines into this very specific smell
that is the smell underlying a lot of
cookies and a lot of triangle a lot of
OG Kush Expressions because of the
triangle
um
yeah let's see what else we got but I um
I'm only getting a fraction of some of
the smell I typically associate with
sherb types which is
and it's like all of that with some
peppery spice to me now not everybody
smells that some I mean there's gas in
it too there's fuel there's candy but
like the overall the unique smells about
sure that peppery stands out a lot to me
and I don't smell
that here
um there's some oh that's what that
herbaceous smell is not quite black
licorice but actual enemies that's or
anise I don't know how you pronounce I
say iniestas anise anus I don't know
yeah that's there that's the smell of it
um I was going to refer to as Herby
um and I said I also say this particular
Grove this cut is very nice old school
kind bud smell in in it that's
attractive that one is harder to pin
down other than herbaceous and fresh
which I just figured out
um that was from the grinding
um
see
um but it's not something I often smell
on cookies types this actually did pique
my interest in the strain so when I open
up the bag and I started smelling this
stuff I was like yeah that's that's an
old school good smell
through the grinder it all smells
exactly the same except that I was able
to pin down the Anis so by crushing it
up that flavor or that scent came
forward a lot more for me so it's much
more identifiable than just Herbie fresh
it's it's
anus anyway uh look manicure overall
thoughts on appearance um for being from
California facility it does look well
grown and like someone put time in care
into it uh into the dragon cure the
scent is strong and the dry is perfect
not too dry not overly moist and
unsmokable the resin glands appear
intact not overly handled and no
oxidation or signs from being a
greenhouse grow or past is indoor which
I'm learning is like
the
classic thing to do now is to stick
greeny [ __ ] in mylars and know that all
the people buying mylars probably aren't
going to pick up on it so yeah so what
I'm going to go ahead and do is uh start
with our first sesh and that's going to
be combustion
so I'm gonna grind some up and put it in
the C2 Bowl which I managed to drop
straight on tile today
and not have break which is a first for
bowls you want to check it out it's very
very thick and makes the grade as a nice
built-in filter in it even the um
this side is really thick too this is
what usually explodes like had I dropped
this bowl
on tile we wouldn't be talking we
wouldn't see be seeing a picture of this
bowl they just don't make it but these
things are uh
special they're made for idiots like me
that drop Scruff and so is this this
stuff's
solid
anyway
let's give it a rip here and see what
what
wow
okay
so the flavor
the flavor tastes like sherb to me
that I didn't expect it's got a lot of
flavor
it's actually got a good flavor to it
too I mean it's like a good version of
the sherb flavor which I'm not a big fan
of the sure flavor I don't hate it but
this is tasty this actually has really
good flavor which shows that it was dry
and cured well grown well
manic geared well
yeah the sherb
I wish I could describe the sherb flavor
it was so hard for me I can always do
scent but flavor's much harder
not gassy
you know what
the rip
the rip will help with this the rip will
help with the flavor and be pinning down
some stuff so this is why I don't just
do just combustion in these reviews
because I've learned after after coming
across this beautiful technology of
vapor wands
um especially really dialed in ones that
are very precise you can really
experience flavors and and scents and
highs that would have been burned off
the second that lighter hit and not
giving you the same effect
um
all those volatile compounds are still
there and you get to enjoy them and
experience them
that I'm being destroyed so that's why I
love the rip and there's so many flavors
that
yeah it's wild it's wild so
using my uh C2 double procure
double ratchet perk
for the rip
with the microphone this gets a little
complicated but let me see if I can get
this figured out here
okay
got the rip on and the way it works is I
have a Sharpie a permanent marker
setting right there that I always know
to turn it to and uh yeah and the way
these work is you set it on the bowl for
a few seconds let it heat up and then
you start inhaling slowly slowly and
then the vapor starts forming and
realistically the first hits are almost
all terpenes for me and and flavonoids
and all that kind of stuff and you
really get the best flavor at the very
first hit
that's weird
it doesn't have a lot of flavor
as the sherb flavor but it has
has less flavor of vaping than it does
combustion
that's a first
I couldn't possibly tell you that is uh
that's weird to have no flavor with the
bread and it's not a knock on the grill
I think it's actually the
the only flavor coming through is the
sherb flavor
that I've experienced with sherb and
usually it's very heavy
but there's all the other flavors have
dropped
in The Vape session so
all that's there is a very light sure
flavor very interesting
because the person who sent it to me did
refer to this strain as very Sherby and
just by looking at it and like breaking
it up and smelling it and stuff
I really wasn't totally convinced that
it was that shirby in fact I was more
convinced it was along like a gelato bat
region you know um
I always write the flavor once you smoke
it I is very sherblike
um
flavor definitely is is all sure
dominant
um I really apologize that I can't break
anything down further when it comes to
the flavor of sherb other than
uh it's the flavor of that
spicy peppery cookie dough
sweet candy it's hard to explain
um but the flavor of it is just this
light
not even pepper though yeah it's it's
very hard to explain
um it's one you'll have to experience
yourself on that end I can get you there
scent wise flavor's a little tough and I
really thought the rip was gonna help me
like figure it out real fast because it
usually does but that is the first time
I've ever had something go from a lot of
flavor combusted then
Vaped so that's a new experience and see
now you're learning with me I didn't
even know that was possible but yeah I
know it has a decent High
um
I'm not sure how long the legs are but
at least I can feel the start of it you
know and it's not surging like Urkel
it's not making me paranoid it's kind of
bright Peppy Peppy
uh
chatty I guess so I should probably end
this because I'll just be rambling like
a dumbass anyway but yeah so overall
um I think the the writing system that
someone on YouTube offered was skunks so
I'm gonna find a little image of skunks
I'm going to pop it up right
here and uh yeah
I don't even know how to do that but I'm
gonna figure it out and I guess we'll
figure it out together
but I'm gonna give this uh
I'm gonna give this
because I'm gonna try to use a tough
rating system here like I'm Gonna Save
the fives for just like crazy
exceptional
you know so fours should be
pretty legendary
so I'm going to give this a three skunk
rating as in
something I would not be embarrassed to
hand to a friend that is a hype strain
and have them smoke it like this is good
enough that I think everybody would
probably enjoy it even some of us old
like curmudgeons that don't even smoke
hype stuff
uh so if that helps any I hope it helps
someone I've been wondering what this
thing was did it actually smell like a
Sharpie marker to me no not even close
um but it did smell very good it did
smell very good and it smoked pretty
well
um uh and if we're going for a high
factor I've got to say it definitely has
a pretty good height it's got a decent
I'll leave it there I'm gonna start
rambling anyway thank you for coming by
check it out go check out riotsseeds.com
grab your femini spray there
um go check out our Discord that's where
we all hang out daily and uh check out
our show tomorrow
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out