and do some you know find the recessive
trades you know markers on what every
leaf is and you select data points you
collect as much as you can on terp
profiles and noses and stuff like that
but you can be a pollen Checker and
still do that stuff too yeah but uh you
know it's like you're actually so
breeders actually are Fina Hunters I
think that's the biggest part too your
Fino and genotype uh you know hunting
goes on and you basically have to go
through and get your nose on stuff you
have to get dirty and then you use those
things for future products and when you
say you know you mean like and you know
right here you're growing it in Arizona
you're growing it everywhere no that's
more like geoclimatized variety
basically genotype would be like the
structure or the way the leaf sets are
things that aren't going to change so
with phenotypical expression
phenotypical expression can be uh
affected by nutrition and environment
okay so I can take the same cut as you
right yeah and we could grow it at my
house and we could grow it at your house
it's going to express two different ways
you're going to get different
phenotypical expressions for sure
whereas the genotype could be exactly
the same so the the basically the way it
was like a freak Show uh Freakshow
that's the specific genotype of that
plant yeah
it's easy to spot that genome yeah but
it could smell different and that would
be the phenotype for sure for sure
that's that I was kind of behind it you
know