welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
cannabis strain history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
we joined this conversation already in
progress and it kind of ends abruptly
too so uh yeah
let's get to it
tend to be on like meth head hours which
sucks because like you don't want to
have that in common with them but at the
same time it's like realistically light
hours are cheaper if you're an indoor
grower at night so like a lot of us live
on vampire hours and that's just how it
goes and if you're keeping moms yeah
neighbors traveling after 10 p.m yeah
after 10 pm neighbors don't stop by
randomly
yeah exactly it's safe to go get in your
grow room and smell like weed and yeah
exactly dude yeah yeah uh you mean it's
it's funny because you know I would
imagine from the outside and I've always
kind of looked at it like I wonder what
my neighbors think because like they see
this this young man who like barely ever
leaves the house never leaves on trips
never you know and is up at all these
odd hours like they must think of a
tweaker and that's just the only
conclusion you know well now nowadays
you can say you work online and that's
normal but back in the day 20 years ago
it's uh that you know we couldn't use
that excuse but yeah yeah that's hell
assessed 20 years ago right
yeah for sure
so I'm here with Jay from Next
Generation seeds formerly of federation
seeds and and who is with you
uh my friend Casey um he's been growing
uh other than growing his own uh death
Bubba for years he's been working with
different LPS uh big companies in Canada
doing a lot of the paperwork and doing
the extractions uh for quite a few
different LPS up here
oh nice I I love me some good bubble
gotta go over some bubble Tech because
that's one thing we have not covered at
all on this show is is yeah hash bubble
hashtag yeah and that's that's the [ __ ]
yeah I've been uh that's one thing with
growing uh seeds you always have lots of
uh samples of different hashes I've uh
yeah it's insane the number the
different grades and actually I have a
box right here
random uh
toad just just every different strain
you could think of uh different sounds
let's go through them let's go let's go
through and hear what kind of strains
that that are you you have over there in
hash form because it gives us a good
idea of what's going on over in your
territory as far as the strains
currently that you're into yeah well uh
different types of hash
um some are really good for uh for
pressing Verizon and some just like dump
the resin or just sticky right away and
then some no matter how good it is
um it just it won't press it'll still
always look kind of uh golden but it
won't actually get slippery
um so yeah it'll get like classy all
every all the way through yeah but uh
I'm really happy with one of the strains
I've done uh lately my red truffles okay
what's in this so it's uh it's uh the
Truffle strain crossed with the
Colombian red oh yeah and uh when you
put that in your hand and just it just
goes like a slick plastic with it within
seconds
it's an amazing amazing strain and I've
actually got a lot more of it going on
on the next round here so
yeah we're gonna do some fresh Frozen as
well but when we can
um yeah but 90 of my crop is usually
done for seeds so it's usually dry and
awful dry soup but even the dry soup
just you know some strains are pretty
powdery um the Greek god even though
it's one of the sweetest ones it just it
doesn't get slick and slippery
is that one more Sandy
yeah it is yeah
yeah it uh it's not like uh actually the
old Sweet Tooth was the same thing no
matter how great Sweet Tooth was and
being white and pure and it just
wouldn't stick together
um whereas the BC Kush would just melt
in your hands um
but the Sweet Tooth was a lot nicer
tasting but uh
it is wild how differently certain
strains will wash versus impress versus
others like you know um for example
there's the cookies and cream and stuff
like that has that same Sandy type resin
when I think of purples like purple
punch
um they have that same Sandy type resin
you know so when you said Grape God I
was thinking you know that that that
super purpley type resin I work with
that similar to the purple punch which
is super Sandy one okay yeah
yeah and a larger resin heads I I
recently got a new camera for doing
macro shots oh nice it was neat to see
uh all the different strains in the the
size of the different heads and and just
you know before we had these good
cameras uh we just never never got to
see that um no and it's kind of cool to
be able to understand
the head ratio and what you're
harvesting it makes a huge difference
right
so I was talking with one of my buddies
and this is kind of a random tangent but
it just it just sort of hit me and he
was over in
um where was it he was in it's either
Thailand or India and they were talking
about the land races out there how they
don't have as much it says they the the
farmers were saying that they look more
resinous but they don't have as much
heads per square centimeter square meter
square millimeter whatever it is and for
that reason the quality has gone down
that was that was their explanation for
why the quality's gone down so far in it
was in Milana so
um I was wondering is there any does
that even make sense I I don't know as a
non-hash guy or non-hashmaker is that
something yeah I'm not a big hash guy
too but I can tell you what I see from
my own strains um like yeah some of them
have uh much larger heads
um and uh smaller stocks but there's
some strange that they're almost all
stocks uh on the on the trichomes and
just tiny little heads
Casey's the professional on that um
that's it you're looking for those big
heads and like fire in fire out you know
like yeah the better the quality you're
putting in when you're harvesting that
low quality plant matter you're gonna
get other that automatically comes along
with that and if you only have a little
bit of this and a little bit of this
you're what you get at the end is isn't
the quality rate
and clean a little bit over this right
it's funny because like people people
are sad about breeding like you know uh
are Femme seeds better than red seeds
all right do you find that they're more
potent uh is this hash better and it's
just like literally you can break it
down to [ __ ] and [ __ ] out you put in
[ __ ] you get [ __ ] you put in good
quality and that is it whether it's
Femme seeds whether it's anything when
it comes to cannabis good quality gets
you good quality and that's it yeah I
I've never noticed a difference between
quality between the regulars and femmes
you know obviously I do vibrating with
the regulars um yeah Femmes are just to
grow out for people to grow but uh you
know but there is some breeders out
there who I don't know if they just
don't know any better or or they don't
care there is actually that actually
breed with feminized seeds
um and
I'm I'm still I maybe it's Bro Science
or I don't know but uh I just don't
breed with uh feminized seeds uh
everything's got to be selected all my
moms are selected from regulars most of
the um the Clone only is in today's
California Market or not even
California's the the U.S market all the
Clone only is in fact were found by a
feminized or bag seeds or you know like
accidents whether it's Sour OG any of
the cookie stuff anything modern at all
all came from it so it's just one of
those things that over time I think that
was definitely a way that people thought
at the beginning was like yeah use rags
to breed because at least you know you
get that extra chromosome and you know
you're not breeding out the female
chromosome whatever but over time we
realized oh it's just it's just that
chromosome is there and it's it's a
different it's autosomes taking course
over
um sexual chromosomes and that's just
kind of why it's fit so it's it yeah
there's not really any
it's the same kind of thing [ __ ] in [ __ ]
out so if it's a plant that naturally
harms a lot and will constantly kick
Herms of itself it's probably going to
breed a lot of Herms into it and
intersects into its future right but if
it's something that happens just very
rarely an errant one you know then it's
a lot easier to breathe with that
okay yeah well I tend to anything that
uh shows any herbs I tend to just toss
right away yeah
um
um but there is a few strains here and
there that maybe spit out a little
banana at the end
um but that you keep but I I really
don't have any except for I have one
different Fino of a purple Pine Berry
that I I don't really sell but uh
but yeah it got the last week or so it
puts a little banana but they're always
sterile but the bugs are so beautiful
and big uh it's hard for me to toss that
mom
um see is it is it seed maker it's hard
right because like we see all these
other qualities that are in Plants
um that have nothing to do with their
sex traits sexual traits like they could
have the most amazing resin production
we want to we want to carry that trade
on right like we want to use that but we
know that if people buy those seeds and
they find that intersex trait they may
not have that same like compassion for
intersex traits that we have so we just
can't work with it we just cannot have
it in our rooms yeah and uh as a seed
company you can't be selling people
things that uh go Herman
yeah because there's a lot there's a lot
of newbies out there and uh and they
usually [ __ ] up on a few different
things here and there um so uh that's
what something I really haven't had much
of a problem with uh yeah as far as
hermaphrodites or mutants um uh even
with I make my feminized with STS
and uh yeah and I had no problems like
people say like with the uh with the
other methods of making seeds sometimes
there's a few Hermes or they're not 100
female yeah with my formula on of the
STS I've had I've had no basically no
issues for about 10 years now
um you're starting with a lot of really
really stable stock as far as like
uniformity because they're lines you've
worked when I noticed a lot of the
intersex issues pop up is when it's
newer lines that are unworked like you
know doing a a hybrid between two brand
new crazy poly hybrids like animal mints
for us to I don't know Cherry truffle
butthole you know like you could you
cross those two then there's like all
this parentage below so all these
possibilities of plasticity come out and
intersex traits are abound you know like
that's the way I look at it and if
you're if you if you've booked lines
already worked out those intersex traits
and you're feminizing yourself then
they're going to be pretty freaking
stable but then they're going to have a
lot less Vinos popping up it's going to
be more true to what people want from
that product you know yeah what they
expect yeah when they go to your site
well a lot of my strains are uh I've
been working with for 25 years and I
haven't read them out to anything else
but obviously here and there I bring in
new like like the red truffles I brought
in because it was just so impressive
sure um
um but yeah I bring in new stuff here
and there but it has to pass uh a few
tests to get into the uh yeah into my my
mother room so look at it what kind of
tests are there like talk about some of
your um qualifications for bringing well
um
basically it's got a well as I we said
last time on the show um uh flavors and
the number one thing for me um the
Caribbean levels It's gotta taste really
really good from start to finish on that
joint
um that's number one for me before plant
structure before anything it's the
terpenes and the flavor
um
yeah that's right now actually one of
the ones uh I've been really pleased
with is our blue Dynamite
um yeah and I brought I brought that
back way back in 2007 it was all over
High Times and uh I wanted a few Awards
with it
um but uh I just recently brought it
back and uh we grew out a big batch of
it and uh
I selected five different females that
that I I wanted to uh rejuvenate yeah
and match the cones are out but after I
grow out the seedlings
um I picked my favorites rejuvenate them
and then try them as a clone before I
make my final selection and or try the
samples of each one set them in for some
tests um
back in the day we weren't able to send
them in for tests they no just didn't
exist but now nowadays uh nowadays we
get to do that
but before the numbers comes to flavor
um
I you know sometimes I don't care if
it's only 20 and not 24. yeah if it
tastes better
um
yeah you usually don't always agree with
you
um and uh
yeah if the terpenes are high you don't
notice those lower numbers as much
that's true
and
yeah well people uh people drink wine
and and not uh Everclear for a reason
it's not always about how what the
number is um it's about how you enjoy it
um exactly and for me like when it comes
to smoking taking the edge off is like
99 of the time that's all I want to do
is take the edge off not yeah yeah
inhibit I don't want to be uh cross-eyed
and confused and walk exactly
yeah I have to be able to function
sometimes
yeah there are times when that's very
appropriate you know yeah and other
times most of the time I have to run a
company and stuff and it's like yeah
yeah
actually I have some of that dude
um
tell on the camera but man this the
latest batch the cross I have now it's a
really good outdoor strain but purple I
don't know if you can tell that oh yeah
no you can't quite see it yeah okay you
know we just had um we had a big
breeders meet up about I think two
months ago now and one of the strains
that came in was blue Dynamite someone
actually threw a big like really nice
outdoor batch of blue Dynamite it was
really good I was it was very grapefruit
dominant super sweet pink grapefruit
super yeah um yeah exactly
original grapefruit so yeah that makes
sense and I was like well you know it's
great for maybe I won't get too baked
but I mean I was baked it did a damn
good job even I mean like I I don't
smoke a lot of outdoor because I've
always been an indoor grower and there's
not a big outdoor scene where we're at
in Bakersfield because it's so hot
nobody grows outdoor that much
um so I don't get to try outdoor often
and I wasn't I wasn't expecting to be
floored but it was really good there's
decent stuff that's good yeah yeah a lot
of our strange people uh people tend to
really like our strains for outdoors um
because uh because a lot of the
hardiness we have from uh the mold
resistance on the west coast
um Vancouver Island it's raining all the
time so in the first 10 12 years of my
my breeding career was all on the island
where it's everything's just the
humidity is through the roof so uh yeah
mold resistance is something I always
you know sometimes by accident but it's
something you select for yeah the Mendo
Growers love it and I know a lot of East
Coast Growers lately that hit me up the
one thing I've been telling them is just
like dude you like everybody everybody
that I know in Mendo that is in like
more humid situations they all grow they
grow next-gen seeds like they all do so
I've been I've been recommending that
for East Coast cars they're like man my
Situation's so humid I guess well you
know this is a great solution people
that have bred in this kind of climate
uh great strains good quality strains
for this climate this is what people
need to be thinking about not I wish
people would think more about that as
opposed to what's hype what will work
good for me in my area I think that
would solve a lot for a lot of people
and their issues
yeah well I've noticed that too we've
got a lot of feedback in the last few
years here um uh for outdoor Growers uh
even with our Auto flowers but also with
our some of our other outdoor varieties
like the Avalon blue Dynamite Time Warp
um streets are we're right on the on the
west coast uh
uh tend to be way way better for mold
resistance uh yeah you can finish them
in those Hills yeah yeah a colleague of
mine uh Ron Harrington with uh Golden
Hat seeds he's originally from Oregon
State and it's very rainy and humid
there just like it is in Canada on the
west coast uh and he uh he breeds a few
autoflowers as well
um and last year on his farm he did a
bunch of uh his own varieties obviously
uh and my grapefruit Haze and my
Dynamite yeah um alongside ethos seeds a
few autoflowers from them and a few
other American companies that aren't
from a human climate and yeah all of the
all the American strains molded yeah
right yeah and mine mine were my
grapefruit Haze was sitting in the
middle of a bunch of moldy Buds and all
of mine not a drop of but try this um
that's awesome so it's yeah and it was a
pretty wet year last uh last year so
but yeah that's what one thing that
people don't realize if you're on the
if you're going Outdoors on East Coast a
lot especially uh they'd really like the
uh the more molders because they get
more rain than you guys do down in
California oh yeah
yeah
so what's next Generation working on
currently like where where you guys at
what what other than the the red
truffles what what are some of your
directions you're wanting to take the
company yeah well I've got my Avalon
strain which is the tough hearty outdoor
strain um we've got some CBD in it now
we've crossed it out to a Spanish uh CBD
strain that I crossed it with and I did
a few back crosses now so we have a good
Avalon CBDs about 20 THC and about four
percent CBD
is Avalon um one of the more
grapefruiting ones
I can't remember which one it's
originally it was the very first strain
I ever bred back in uh was it
1996 I believe
um and uh it's a it's an Afghani hash
plant crossed with a blueberry
blueberry that's right yeah so but years
and years of selective uh breeding
outdoors I did all my selections
Outdoors on the west coast
um so it became really really Hardy uh
finishes about the end of September
um and you can put up with a lot of wind
and a lot of rain and yeah just down
like some straight uh we got a big news
terminals playing over but the Avalon's
standing up straight you can put up with
that so I bet it's that hearty breathing
dude
yeah yeah so
um and the other one uh while we're
actually working on uh our first Contact
strain we've got a doing a big pheno
hunt on that um it's a one the mother is
a one-to-one uh CBD THC strain
um but I've outcrossed that now to uh my
Romulan oh wow so we're testing that out
right now
um
yeah yeah but
what's that one called
uh first Contact first Contact okay yeah
yeah I kind of recommend that to
beginner smokers because it's lower a
little bit lower THC but this and the
CBD is really high but the terpene
levels on that strain are are through
the roof
um that's awesome really really stinky
and branchy it branches out like crazy
it's always a give and take a little bit
when it comes to to Quality and in
terpenes right like it's it's almost a
little bit of give and take it's very
rare that you see something in the high
high testing range with high high high
terpene percent it's very rare it can
happen actually yeah it's a yeah you're
right about that
um I noticed that with my grapefruit
diesel uh strain which is the highest
terpene levels I've ever recorded
um yeah just over five percent
um
that's extremely high
um yeah but the THC level is only like
16 or 17. yeah on but it's it's still my
favorite to smoke one of my favorites
yeah and everybody smokes it just loves
it because you know you're tasting that
flavor right down to the roach yeah and
so and everything I cross it with tends
to have about two and a half three
percent uh tripping level
that's nice
quite a bit yeah what kind of Terps is
it coming out with mostly
um
you know what I can't honestly I can't
really say honestly um yeah I don't I
don't remember in a while it's a new new
selection for a new mother so I haven't
sent that one in for testing yet yeah
I I rarely get to do testing just
because I'm so cheap that I just don't
but but I get customers that aren't as
cheap as me and every once in a while
you get those those cool customers yeah
we get a lot of feedback yeah we get a
lot of feedback too because uh over the
the last few years we've been selling a
lot of uh seeds to some of the big LPS
here um and they need they do do their
tests on it and they give us the
feedback so that's awesome that's that's
amazing to be able to get that much
feedback back you know and yeah it's
always it's always neat I listen to all
the customers getting back to us after
they grow in a crop and you know the
good reports the bad reports you know
it's we got to hear it all
um yeah but you know generally they're
pretty good
I I I hear a lot about LPS in Canada
um we've had a few guests on in the past
like our last guest Pete has talked
about LPS
can you kind of explain for us Americans
what an LP even is is it just a company
a cannabis company or yeah well in
Canada we have several different types
of licenses uh that are highly
controlled by the government there's the
lp it's a licensed producer so that's
right and then there's the micro Growers
for the people who are smaller like they
have a small medium-sized Warehouse yeah
and then there's a nursery license where
you're only allowed to sell seeds or
clones gotcha
but they're all highly highly regulated
by the government uh he in case you can
tell you more about that but uh the LPS
are allowed it basically covers the
whole gamut of being able to package it
you know a micro grower or a nursery has
to go to go to another company to
package it for you um they're just
fixing all that now like when I when it
first started you had as a micro you had
to go
to an LP or you had to get a processing
license and now you can get a sales
license so you have your own path to
sales but originally you'd have to go
through an LP which would have all the
licenses to be able to get you to Market
the one thing that blew my mind that I
found out about Canadian
um maybe this is just territorial I'm
not sure but was that the people who
were in charge of buying for the
government are like just randoms like
they're not weed people at all like and
every every Province or state as you
guys call it uh is different and
different regulations in every Province
um so yeah if I was that's one reason I
we still haven't gone for our full
license here in Canada is uh if we went
for our full Nursery license to sell
seeds and clones on the legal Market we
would be prevented from uh selling on
our website yeah we wouldn't be we
wouldn't be allowed to sell overseas
which is the majority of our Market is
overseas
um so for us the so right now I'm going
for a medical uh a few patients um so
that allows me to do my selecting and
breeding and then provide the medicine
for the patients but uh but the full
legal
market for us isn't really it's not not
the way to go so we're looking for
perhaps eventually here getting uh
moving out of Canada
yeah so uh yeah I've already got a a
location down in South America
yeah I started reading at
um but we've even considered uh working
in the states
um
so but you guys have the same thing too
every state is different yeah yeah
California's a nightmare man like they
the way the way that I think that it's
gonna wrap up is to where there's not
going to be any path for anyone to breed
because there's not going to be any kind
of plant count that allows you to breed
you know not nothing realistic like 12
you may get 12. but for a seed company
it's what we piss on 12. you know like
then we need 12 for one mom to stay
alive we need 12. you know like that's
not realistic
yeah exactly yeah we have uh two
licenses here for it's uh 317 plants two
licensed so we're just about well 635
plants we can do so that's nice that's
just that's just enough for me to work
with I wish I had more yeah I know never
enough right never enough
we're looking at a license in Argentina
where they when you get a license uh
they just allow you a flat uh two acres
uh do whatever you want on two acres
whether it's indoor outdoor Greenhouse
it doesn't matter
um it's simplified but uh but there's
other there's other steps they have
there too that are that are quite
difficult do they do they have like a
good power grid to where no matter where
you're at no matter where you live in
Argentina you can just hook up like a
[ __ ] big old indoor and blow it up
um yeah it's pretty good actually so
that's the uh well set up uh the
electricity cost is about the same as
Canada
probably a little more expensive than
the US
um
but uh you know there's no snow there
um yeah so uh as Canadians we like uh we
like not having snow oh you guys sick of
snow up in Canada no it smells good ice
fishing uh he's uh he's ice fisherman so
it lives in the woods but uh for for me
I absolutely hate the snow so yeah here
it gets up to like 120 degrees
Fahrenheit here so like I hate the sun I
hate the sun I I could deal with the
snow because I can put on clothes but I
can't get more naked so I hate it yeah
100 yeah yeah [ __ ] that
well I'd rather be in uh shorts and
shirtless yeah yeah
cooking cooking I'm not a good Canadian
I guess I look at a Canadian or you
you've got a lot of snow and hockey come
on
so
let's talk a little bit about the lp
structures and stuff because I I that is
something we've never really covered
um
let's say you want to run a big Seed
Company up there what kind of license
would you need just hypothetically
though you know what I mean well I need
a nursery license like like the
warehouse that we're in I'm in right now
and working in uh we're about 90 percent
of the way having it built for a nursery
license and we we put a stop to that a
few months ago when we realized that uh
the market isn't here in Canada
um for us
um it just didn't doesn't make sense so
we're probably gonna that something
changes in the next few months we're
probably gonna wind down uh operations
here in Canada and uh move overseas uh
just the regulations are just way way
too tough
um yeah and uh like if the government
uh employee who selects the products to
sell in the stores
says uh nobody buys seeds so we don't
want your seeds yeah I can't sell them I
can't so that's no point to me that's
insane to me like oh this person do who
has no tap on the market at all says
today we don't want XYZ and that's your
main strain you're like what what what's
your input what's your context for this
they have yeah
in the province we're in here now in
Alberta I believe it's uh
a few years ago they took a bunch of
seeds in from some micro Growers and LPS
and they didn't sell very well in the
strain because basically everybody had
like one or two Strays it was all white
widow or a big butt or something like
that oh no and then they the government
said well these aren't selling very well
so we're not going to buy seeds anymore
is saturated too so so do you think um
so just from my perspective as an
American I noticed right at the
beginning of covid
um was when
the the drop happened as far as the
market in the U.S like that's when the
weed Market just bottomed out and it may
not have been it might be like it might
have just been a correlation causation
type thing where it happened at the same
time but whatever happened happened here
at that time like that was a very good
Mark to know when the weed Market
completely bottomed out yeah and it
affected
it affected the seed Market maybe six
months after that did it hit around the
same time there yeah yeah pretty similar
for the weed Market we are really legal
Recreation kept doing kind of its thing
I think it might have picked up a little
bit but I would say like on the flower
side
on the gray it would be down sales for
sure I don't know about seeds yeah well
and on the black market here uh prices
on the street dropped from about twelve
fourteen hundred dollars a pound down to
about
um and for five or six hundred dollars
that barely pays your electricity bill
exactly um it's not solid but a lot of
the a lot of the uh there was a lot of
stuff going on with the back doors of
the LPS sure
and the micros like how it always is but
uh
but now these days the customer the
customers in Canada have slowly just
moved they're lazy they go to the store
there's a store on every corner yeah um
and only the the good Growers and the
guys that are really weed Geeks they're
the ones still buying seeds but yeah
there's not as many of uh guys that are
just kind of doing it for fun
to make a little extra money on the side
um
I got two pallets of Lights here that I
can't even give away
no way 1000 watt HPS is I got about 45
oh I bet I can't even give them away
so
so yeah it's crazy right how quickly
it's lit how it was just like on its
head and then flipped all of a sudden
and yeah seeds the seed Market bottomed
out as far as I can tell yeah the seed
Market too yeah the seed Market for us
is it's mostly been maybe in the last
six months to a year is where we really
noticed a big change because we have our
whole we sell a lot of wholesale seeds
so what people want to buy whether it's
100 seeds or a thousand or ten thousand
uh our wholesale prices have just
dropped
um they're yeah it's crazy how much is
dropped um
so
anyone who hasn't dropped their price
per packs during this is is silly
because they're they're probably cutting
themselves off because it's it's the way
I looked at it was like
um seeds are a
they're not a
then you don't not everybody needs seeds
that are Growers it's a it's something
that they do extra when they have extra
space to select you know I want to find
something new but they can go get clones
down at the grow store for you know can
a pop so why would they need seeds it's
not something they necessarily need to
select new stuff every time they can go
get what's hot what's hip from clones
and that seems to be what happened when
everybody's money kind of vanished you
know in the US with covid and everything
else going on and the weed Market body
going out but seeds weren't so necessary
anymore
yeah well you guys down in California I
believe you can uh sell and buy and sell
uh cones in stores yeah yeah we we can't
do that in Canada
you know I I take that back because for
a while yeah yeah they're starting we
were able to I don't know when 64 hit I
don't know it kind of screwed everything
up and the last I I saw here locally
they were not allowed to sell clones
anymore but a lot of places do so I
don't know yeah it's one of those things
yeah they're starting to now like I've
seen there's some stores that have
setups to actually house clones
um to be able to move them and then I
think through the medical Market as well
companies can sell clones to medical
patients
but there's the logistics side of it
right depending on where you are it's
top break like to send clones through
the mail and exactly depending on
what you're getting right
yep and and who you're getting it from
because you just don't even know if it's
going to be what you expect and like I
mean if government regulations all up in
the middle of it that really [ __ ] it up
like super yeah because they really
don't know what the [ __ ] they're doing
they have no place in it like really
yeah I'm random what the [ __ ] does that
have to do with anything yeah the people
that made the regulations were not they
were not pot smokers or Growers
um just a bunch of bureaucrats it seems
uh yeah they're trying to figure out the
commodity yeah like they wanted to treat
it like Oscar Meyer ham and or what you
know anything else like that that's just
not how it works yeah yeah they didn't
really understand uh lead customers like
we customers
it's not like uh somebody who who drinks
beer every day and they go Budweiser
Budweiser Budweiser exactly and they get
a brand
weed smokers want to try something new
um all the time you know sometimes they
have their their reliable go-to strains
but uh yeah they want to try new flavors
it's not uh yeah it's not like that I
like the alcohol business and that's how
it was really viewed up here for a lot
of The Regulators they just seen it as
like like alcohol
yeah that's the way they viewed it and
that's not how it is
and that's how they try to treat it here
too and I think that's that's one of the
the big issues that they've run into
with like you know even driving trying
to you know figure out how to screw
people over and give them bwis for
smoking like they're having problems
with that how do you figure that out you
know yeah I've got some buddies like him
that I wouldn't trust them if they
weren't smoking and driving yeah right
yeah
it makes me a lot cooler like I don't
get all worked up about you know other
drivers a little less road rage eh yeah
I don't I don't I learned to chill out I
used to like as a young man what I
didn't used to smoke and drive a bunch
like I I get all Rowdy about like how
fast I was getting places and like ah
get out of my way and now it's just like
just chill you know with other people
that have them when I get there yeah
it's like what are you so worked up
about
yeah it helps
right on yeah [ __ ] yeah I don't I don't
smoke as much as I used to when I was
young but uh yeah a long road trip
always needs a few few puffs
so um
what's something that you smoked
recently that like not not necessarily
out of your own stuff but that you've
tried recently that really was like wow
that's different like that's a unique
strain has there been anything
um I I live in a bit of a closet here uh
a big closet with lots of plants but
so here in Canada I'm smoking most of my
own strains always
um yeah but in South America I tried
some really interesting streams down
there
um but what kind of strange did you try
down there
um yeah actually I quite I met a really
good grower in Chile uh what kind of
worker he's growing out a bunch of my
stuff right now but he had a lot of
different Jamaican strains oh wow and I
really really like a few different Blue
Mountain uh sativas and also he had a it
was interesting because he also has a
Colombian red down there uh oh
interesting and and I and I grow
Colombian right up here I've been in the
past and I'm breeding with her now but
it was it was nice to see that his was
very very similar to to mine oh that's
rad yeah it's on the other side of the
planet but uh it was yeah a bit of a
confirmation that I'm getting a bit of
the real deal here
um how long flowering is that Colombian
red
that's got to be about 12-ish
yeah that's the one uh well we have a
cross with it now it's the Colombian red
crashed with that Mexican sativa that
I'm calling uh Latina sativa
um and that went about 13 14 weeks yeah
and it probably could have went more of
it yeah it could have kept going if it
wasn't like done done like the rest of
the room the rest of the room because I
I when I was down in Argentina my Casey
here was watching the crowd for me
taking care of yeah some of the strains
he's like Jay I can't keep these alive
what's going wrong I said well it's 13
14 weeks old and yeah that's why you
attack you can't keep me because when I
grow seeds
I grow that plant so long until until it
almost dies on the stick yeah get the
best quality seeds and I fertilize to
the end and he thought he was doing
something wrong here for a while like
yeah no no look at the date I put those
in the room oh okay then figure it out
that's funny yeah some of those
Colombians go
26 weeks every bit of it like there's
there's some jungly Colombians out there
yeah I I I'm a big fan of the sativas
you know some some guys like the kushes
and the indicators but I'm a sativa guy
um
I yeah I Can't Get Enough dude
um yeah yeah I like the sativas myself I
like ties and and very clear-headed type
Highs but you know it's just a different
different smoke for different occasion
though for sure um one of my buddies
told me to tell you if you do want the
celestial Temple sativa the old old
release he has them for you he he uh I
don't know if it's him or somebody else
um it's on my list to talk about here
but uh we had somebody contact us about
two weeks ago saying he has he uh he
watched the podcast and he has the
celestial Temple yeah yeah he sent he's
uh it's in the mail he said that's
awesome that's so cool we're gonna send
him we told him anything you want man
pick whatever you want from the catalog
oh that's right of you guys so uh yeah I
can't wait to try out that was such a
nice very unique strain man I haven't
seen anything like it with those long
long fingers yeah yeah it was just it
was actually uh uh a buddy a mutual
friend a breeder Steve and uh red uh
burnt down people back in Vancouver who
will know who burnt down is
um okay he he had it sitting in the
corner of his living room for like two
or three years as a house plant yeah and
he always like oh no he kind of ignored
it
um and it was just it stayed in veg just
sitting in the corner of the living room
and we took some cuts of it brought it
back and he had never even grown it out
I think reader Steve uh had had given
him this cut and it's kind of just sat
there for a few years
and uh and it the story is it's from
Ecuador
um yeah but whatever you did with it it
was hard to get it to flip into flower
it would sit there and Edge forever and
I believe that took about 12 13 weeks to
flower as well but the high from that I
remember the high from that it's kind of
like a really a soapy spicy perfumey
strain not not fruity or Piney at all
yeah yeah and uh and it made it was kind
of like some of my Jamaican strains I
grew up it left me out I was kind of
confused feeling
yeah it's one of those trains that you
don't dare do math yeah right yeah
um yeah some of that stuff you have to
like put your light hours down to eight
or nine hours to get it to trigger into
flower and initiate and just leave it at
eight or nine hours so if you're growing
anything else that like wants you know
normal light hours it's just screwed
because it's got a god flour with
whatever that that one wants but though
some of those have the most quality wild
special highs and that's what makes them
worth it that little weird chance you
know yeah
people don't grow enough sativas up here
I agree
there should be a lot more of them going
around but
that's not cool in the yard too and you
get the great big sativas there's giant
a few friends that grow them and they're
but up here in Canada Outdoors we can't
really finish them properly other than a
few of the uh early sativas and a few of
the strains from uh
um a great white North and yeah Canadian
bread seeds uh they did the uh yeah they
did some early sativo it's basically a
Durban Yeah Yeah from Manitoba and stuff
like that um
yeah there's a lot of good breed
actually this brings me to the point uh
when you had uh a peek there on the
other day yeah yeah let's talk about
something he was bringing up a few
things about how uh about BC bud and how
all the big players in BC back in the
day or maybe even now but back in the
day anyway they weren't from BC yeah um
we all migrated from out east uh we
always heard about okay you can grow
weed in BC and not go to jail for too
long
so we all kind of migrate and the
weather was better so we all kind of
migrated when I was 20 years old the
first thing I did me and my wife
moved to the coast
um
but but most of Canada a lot of the
biggest breeders and players in the game
were not from BC
um yeah
legal uh climate and uh
they're all a bunch of Alberta boys
um Mark Emery is from Ontario a whole
bunch of really top top grade breeders
from Ontario from Manitoba which nobody
talks about there because you could go
to jail for 20 years for growing plants
so there's a bunch of the big breeders
from that rural Manitoba
um man either at Bubble Man uh Richard
uh what's his name uh Mark uh markerson
yeah yes yeah Mark yeah yeah he's from
Manitoba as well and uh yeah we're in
the is the kootenase really big too
yes yeah so yeah a lot of the Kootenays
where they'll have a generational
Growers that have been
yeah their parents grew and their
granddad grew um like our humble yeah
yeah
kind of and Vancouver Island is is
similar to that yeah yeah where I like
the mighty might boys there they're like
their parents their grandparents they're
all grew uh they were uh I think Vietnam
War
wow
draft Dodgers yeah they leave uh the
states when they got drafted so they all
came up to Canada and so it's generation
after generation of Growers um but yeah
that's mostly the island and uh the
Kootenays
um yeah
so yeah um yeah a lot of a lot of good
strains but uh like when I moved out
there I to BC uh
I uh I did I didn't realize that a lot
of my friends were lazy hippies and uh
they didn't keep they didn't keep other
plants around because they could just go
to talk to somebody else and buy a tray
of cones for the next Grill and and for
me being from the the prairies where it
was all rare I was just a rabid
collector and I just got everything I
could get my hands on my bedrooms were
bigger than my flower rooms half the
time oh same same always yeah
they grew up with it was always there so
they kind of didn't take it seriously so
that's why I think a lot of uh us
easterners
um kind of came in and took over the
market
um yeah and even even when the Prairie
boys or the East Coast guys uh had weed
to sell to the states
they just called it BC bud or beasters
yeah um because you would never tell
anybody that you're actually growing it
it's like oh yeah I bought it from a guy
in BC it's like that makes sense you
would even tell your best friend that
you were growing in your basement
um yeah yeah that's how secretive it was
back in the 90s so yeah yeah it's still
that way here where I'm at like you just
I'm all even all my friends know like oh
we don't know where Matt lives that's
what it is it's just you know they just
know that's part of the drill you know
yeah it's it's an old school mentality
and I don't think it's probably not even
necessary as much anymore but like that
idea back then it was that you didn't
want to end up on any one short list
when someone's girl got robbed you
didn't want to do that so it was like
you didn't even want to ask someone
where they lived if you knew they were a
grower and if you're a grower you didn't
want to talk about it because you didn't
want to get ripped or robbed or yeah
need to know only only need to know
yeah and anybody who is going uh a buddy
who is going through a divorce or split
up with a girlfriend
you was like okay bud no offense but I'm
not going to talk to you for a year uh
yeah because one of the most dangerous
things was uh was when somebody split up
um yeah and vindictive uh ex-girlfriend
would just [ __ ] rack you out um my
chick my chick has been mind blown like
she went to that party
um in the in the mountains with a bunch
of us that all met up around the country
and she was the one story she heard in
common was that we all have exes that
have blackmailed us over weeds like that
is just a part of our life we all have
been blackmailed over growing dude yeah
you got two guys that can uh confirm
that here right like it's just it's I
don't how do we how do they even know to
do that like is there a rule book
somewhere that says hey find a grower
and blackmail them you know lived
happily on it for years and so yeah like
I was away [ __ ] you yeah you got kids
even worse even worse yeah yeah we've
both been there man
actually I liked about uh when I moved
over to Spain um
it was so waiting for me to uh be able
to uh oh how do you
welcome aboard living
in Spain I was able to uh live openly
and free I didn't have like Vancouver
Island we had one couple friends that
actually knew where we lived and nobody
else really knew where I lived even
though even though they were close
friends
um sure but
in Spain nobody gave a [ __ ] like
everybody was growing you'd never have
to hide it I mean like I said the first
tray of clones I sold in Spain was to
the local police officer
um that is so crazy it was it was it was
a non-issue what year was to your crop
yeah hey what year were you in pain
I believe I went there in 2008 okay the
week that Mark Emery got busted he went
there during the Glory Days for Spain
yes exactly that's why I know a bunch of
the big players in Spain yeah
FM Royal Queen and all those guys yeah
yep uh so yeah I was there 2008 until
2016 I believe oh [ __ ] 16 or 17. so yeah
nine nine years living there so let's
let's break into something I've I know
I've mentioned it on the show before but
it's something that is very often not
talked about it's one of those golden
rules to see things that like the guys
involved don't want people talking about
it but it's a reality
can you talk about some of the big
players in Spain who are making the
majority of the seeds for the seed
industry is that something you're open
to talk about
um yeah it's uh it's an Open Secret um
anybody that's yeah close to it was um
there's probably only a couple dozen big
farmers that provide seeds for all the
big companies because most of the
Spanish companies well originally
the Dutch were the big companies yeah
and then they started farming out seed
making to Spanish Growers because
everything was cheaper in Spain and it
became more illegal in Amsterdam they
cracked down on it oh yeah and yeah the
Dutch guys we're getting older too
they've been doing it for 20 years and
they want to retire it yeah getting
older so they bring their clones down to
a Spanish farmer and give you the Clone
say hey can you make these seeds I'll
give you 50 cents a seed and uh I was I
was a proposition by a few different
Growers too from Paradise and then
serious to make seeds for them um
I never did it maybe I should have but
uh but yeah I know after the first one
after the first five or six years or ten
years of uh the Spanish guys uh farming
the seeds they're like well
forget these Dutch guys and the Spanish
slowly took over the market uh and they
stepped up to so but a lot of the
companies down there there's a few that
are
that are breeding their own things and
yeah aren't just retailers uh but the
majority of the Spanish companies they
buy it off a farmer and you know three
or four different seed companies will
have the exact same bag of seeds but
I'll have a name that's similar yeah and
what I noticed
what I noticed was a lot of it started
with like okay the the Dutch would bring
like the drunkers would bring their
clones down there they'd sell you know
the seed lines would be true to what
they were selling at the time but then
like over time I noticed like Greenhouse
like you'd never consistently get the
same seeds in the same pack because they
were just like give us something like
Jack Herer like and well you know is
there lemony a little bit Lemon Haze all
right it's
and they started to get a lot more like
that and and I think it's probably one
of the most open Secrets behind the
scenes but on the front side most people
don't know that they're buying from like
12 breeders in Spain when they're buying
these large large companies like the
major yeah I don't even need to name
them but yeah the large company yeah we
don't need to name them because it's
obvious if you look at the catalogs
everybody's got a critical Cross or a
silver haze or uh
Amnesia something yeah yeah they're all
they all come from the same bag half the
time yeah
but yeah yeah and a lot of the
autoflowers too they uh the Spanish are
really big on the Autos um they did some
great breeding on Autos there really
good breeding like they they made the
Autos uh a good thing because yeah when
autoflowers first came onto the scene
they were [ __ ] yes they were tiny little
runts um it was kind of a novelty uh at
the beginning yeah um and that actually
that a lot of the first breeders of the
autoflowers actually were from Canada as
well out in Toronto uh region I don't
know know them myself personally
um
but I think a lot of the first Auto
flowers that were marketed
um like the low rider yeah yeah yeah
doctors that was uh that was in Ontario
uh guy
um man I'd love to talk to that dude
yeah yeah I have no idea what happened
to him but uh I don't either
yeah the Spanish guys brought it up a
level and they they got better and
better with their Auto flowers and uh
and I started doing Autos probably about
eight or nine years ago because the
market demanded it um yeah yeah
and all my all my friends I know a few
of the big farmers that made seeds for
like Royal Queen Dino fam sweet seeds
pyramid seeds all the Spanish so I I
ended up my first uh big run of the
Autos was uh
a big button uh Northern Lights yeah
yeah and that's what I used as my first
breeding material to to breed into my uh
my strains was that Buddha seeds
the Northern Lights
no it's my buddy Louie's neighbor
um
so he sells to like three or four
different companies that's awesome
yeah yeah he yeah a lot of the farmers
there will sell it to three or four
different seed companies and
and uh yeah that's the way it works a
couple guys will get really good at
growing a few of the strains that they
like and they dial it in like I'm not
I'm not gonna [ __ ] talk the Spanish guys
they don't know I think they do great I
think they gotta do good work um but
but a lot of the deceived companies are
different than the seed breeders and
Growers um absolutely companies I would
say 80 90 of them are just they're
resellers and yes you're good at
marketing but they're they don't
actually make their own yeah I call them
I call them seed sellers versus breeders
like they're seed makers who don't
really breed there's breeders who breed
and make seeds and then there's seed
sellers who are just resellers don't
really have much of an interest in the
breeding aspect they're they're uh
they're
yeah it's a business they run the
website
I often find it amazing how into seed
making people get and how little they
actually understand what's going on just
behind the curtain you know uh in that
regard like I mean it seems like when
you talk like if I remember correctly I
think it was 99 or 2000 the Dutch closed
their law that made seed making legal
yeah they had a loophole and then there
was a bunch of busts and that seemed
like it it shifted a bunch of people's
work to either Switzerland or Spain
but it's kind of been like a little bit
that way the whole time like the whole
reason most of that work even went out
to Amsterdam in the first place was it
was more permissive than the 80s and the
Reagan drug war and all that and so it's
almost like the the movement like looks
for where it's liberal and they can get
away with it
get away with it just enough just enough
just enough and then you know like you
were just saying like you know various
companies we won't name it it happens in
America right now too where it's like
people have a brand and they have
packaging and they have a following
right and so all they need to do is put
seeds into that packaging and into that
brand and into that following and people
think that they did it from beginning to
end yes when in reality they farmed it
out you know and they're just buying
from a menu because they have all that
packaging and that brand and they're
going to do a drop and they're going to
do a collab and people don't understand
people think that all these individually
weed famous people most of them are
making their own stuff and keeping their
own mothers and like in-house working it
yeah and it's like it's such an Open
Secret but it's also like so like poorly
understood by like 90 of the rest of the
group out there and I I don't want to
act like I'm [ __ ] on any and I know
you guys aren't either like I don't want
to make it sound like I'm [ __ ] on
any of the um steps in this process
because like each those steps of those
process do their own thing and like
they're making their own success like
obviously some of these major companies
that have people that don't make any
scenes that have never touched a seed
other than to resell them are the most
successful companies so like yeah you're
pretty funny because yeah a lot of the
companies that sell a lot of the seeds
they've probably never grown hardly 10
plants exactly and even myself like we
sell a lot of wholesale seeds uh for
other companies they want to buy a bulk
batch of seeds and they they package it
themselves they're better at marketing
than I am yeah sure there's a lot of
people like that like reading so
and most breeders are like that like
just we're into the plant side like I
I've had to force myself to get into
like the podcasting side and the
marketing aspect like none of the stuff
I'm comfortable with at all I mean to
some degree dude for a long time
regardless of what country you're in or
whatever
um people that were deep weed people the
best thing they could do was stay
invisible and keep their head down
yeah and so it's a very different skill
set to be like oh get out there promote
yourself promote your brand promote your
company be the face of it so in a lot of
ways like you know
um it's it's just not it's just all
different uh yeah if you want to survive
in this business you got to change and
uh I've been realizing that as well I
have to be more proactive uh with social
media or people don't know who who you
are
um yeah yeah I had yeah a few uh weeks
ago I got on a stupid uh argument like
you shouldn't do on Facebook and some
some guy was uh telling me like oh I I'm
the biggest player around here I move
packs and I supply stores and I've been
into this from the old days I've been
around for like eight or nine years and
I've never heard of you who are you I'm
like you've been around since eight or
nine years old yeah so
you kind of engage with those people
it's you gotta just ignore it and it's
very hard though sometimes it's so hard
and you just wanna because our culture
we were raised different like it was a
lot of us were raised with like an
apprentice type culture where like you
[ __ ] get your [ __ ] smack stop
don't embarrass the people around you
don't embarrass your culture well it was
it was hard to get I mean I don't I I
try to explain to people a lot and I
don't I don't think it sinks in very
much because we live in such an
information dominated Society
but when most of us started how
difficult it was even to figure out the
basics
yeah
yeah you know
yeah you know there wasn't forums there
wasn't the internet there wasn't the
exchange of ideas yet or anything like
that and because it was so risky getting
into a trusted Circle was hard and
almost by accident more than intention
we kept our Circle small because it was
just too risky to uh have a big circle
yeah
yeah but uh yeah but I you know I I I'm
not and I just want to make everybody
clear like I'm not dissing anybody in
Spain it it's mostly you know like
because probably some of those Spanish
breeders and some of those Spanish
farmers are really good at what they do
yeah I know if you're really Kick-Ass
Growers and breeders in Spain um you
know so it's not to disparage them it's
just more like like you know you've got
these these Brands we don't need to
mention them but you got some big brands
that like kind of ruled the 90s from
Holland yeah and then they start getting
busted and they're getting older like
you said and they like they kind of lost
their Verve for it but they have this
brand and they can sell a lot of seed
and so you know you talk to a lot of the
Dutch and they'll never claim that they
lost a single thing sure yeah
okay yeah the original parents
everything I mean why admit that you
lost anything 40 years in running I mean
what's funny is you know I mean I guess
I'll discense you for a second or
whatever but like no they still if you
go on their web page today they still
use the same pictures that Neville had
in his seed bank catalog in 89 and 90.
yeah yeah they haven't updated their
Super Skunk picture in 35 years
some of the bigger ones I know
Greenhouse my my uh my business partner
is uh he's a friend with uh Ari and he
ran time seat back for the day and he
used to move a lot of their the seeds
for Ferrari and and he's been in their
mother room he said there is these trees
and Aryans uh main mother room that are
they're trees they've been going for
years and years and there's a few
companies that have the original cuts um
but most probably don't and I know we
all we all know we all lost strains that
we uh that we produce but let's be
realistic like Greenhouse are the ones
that
are probably the most notorious for
doing the white labeling of seeds I have
never understood why Ariane would heat
moms of anything for that long when he
doesn't even sell seeds of the [ __ ] that
he's keeping these moms because he
probably does it all dude
I mean yeah maybe he does but it doesn't
make sense in my head like I see them
doing the The Strain Hunters and I don't
I don't want to diss the dude because
he's done a lot I guess you know but um
I see Strain Hunters I see them
collecting all these land race strains
but I've never seen like these big
massive reproductions of all these
streams I've seen them vaulted is what
I've said that that dude is I couldn't
say for sure but he probably is the most
as far as the public people go he's
probably the most successful business
person in cannabis sure
Franco had a heart for weed he uh he
really he was a weed geek I never met
him jars and samples in front of him and
he was just passionate about it and he
could smell everything and he would go
on about it Aryan barely maybe spoke the
odd joint in the evening
um he's the businessman you know the the
great face behind it but but uh Franco
he was the real deal I saw it yeah but
uh like just like nowadays I actually
talked to Aryan when I was down in South
America at the trade show it was down
there and him he a lot of the seeds now
are made in Colombia
when I told him I had oh I got a couple
hundred thousand autoflowers you're
ready to move blah blah blah and he
looked at me and laughed he goes I got a
barrel full yeah he's like okay well
okay
yeah
a farmer you can you can look at that
and it's like that's always I actually
look at Holland and Amsterdam I look at
all the eras as like teaching moments in
a way because it doesn't really change
that much and even like living in
California and having like legalizations
sort of start to sweep through America
all the same stuff that was happening in
the 90s and Holland is happening here
now yeah you've got your like
underground weed nerds that just want to
like have a good living and work with
plants and they have to bond with like
sort of straight business people that
don't care nearly as much but have that
aspect or have sides of like they have
access to Capital or money or the things
that you don't and from you know yeah
that's one reason why like about five
six years ago I moved back to Canada uh
a few of the big uh companies here the
big LPS were kind of courting me and
trying to get me to come grow for them
uh but I would have had to sell out all
my genetics
um and give them my my strains and I
would have just started making a wage
maybe a percentage of a big company I'd
maybe make five percent shares from the
company or something sure and uh and I
kind of uh
after a few of them came to me I that's
why my partner now uh Taylor uh
I chose him as a partner because he ran
kind seed really really well yeah he's
old school he knows how he knows how to
he's anybody who talks to him on the
phone when they call our website
uh Taylor's the most friendly guy Taylor
yeah yeah when you talk to him man on
the phone
your best friend after 10 minutes on the
phone and he's a bit of a big soft teddy
bear here and he'll he'll always give
you free stuff
um yeah which is fine and but he's
somebody who I know will uh can deal
with her customers so I teamed up with
him even though he didn't have
the funds and it was a bit of a slower
rise to get back into the game over here
in Canada but when he has when he's on
the phone with a customer it's one of
our rules
um like when I teamed up with him years
ago he's like there's no [ __ ] um
like the cus customer asks something
about a strain if you don't know just
tell them you don't know
um and he even said that to me yesterday
I told him we were going on the podcast
he goes Jay just don't say anything
that's not true if you don't know
something don't worry and it's the
advice I gave him and he gave that yeah
like it's just something beautiful isn't
it to be in this business for this long
people see that [ __ ]
um they do and there's no shame in
admitting you don't know what where that
strain came from or what crosses what
exactly you tell people what you know
and and that's it so one thing that
that's held true on our podcast since
day one is that our it's been at least
the people who are serious weed nerds
and that appreciate our show is that
they always sense when someone's being
transparent and just being like yeah I
don't know you know like I just tell it
the way it was and you can always see it
in the comments everybody always is like
yep yep this guy's not a bullshiter
appreciate it you know all the time yeah
that's what I think that's right yeah
last night when I was watching uh uh
Pete there on there yeah yeah it was 20
minutes 20 minutes into the podcast like
oh this guy's not a bullshiter nope he's
a real deal
um yeah no [ __ ] defeat
yeah yeah yeah I I actually like that
it'd be interesting to have a little
podcast with me and him chatting because
he knows a lot about the Ontario scene I
know that BC scene better and uh we
could probably
say that together we have all the mutual
friends
um but yeah it'd be pretty interesting
to actually to chat with him sometime
yeah that'd be great I'm sure he'd enjoy
it too he loves it
yeah he's an old dork like yeah I only
watched uh one podcast of his but I
think you guys have about two or three
yeah I think we did Total yeah
yeah with him it's just he's got so much
information in there it's just about
keeping him on point you know because
he's like he'll start talking about
something and then he'll get a thought
in his head and all of a sudden you're
like 45 degree angle you're off on a
tangent about something totally else
yeah
don't we yeah you know and he yeah I
like that he gives unvarnished opinions
of what he thinks about people you know
yes that's my favorite you know because
it's like a lot of times one of the
hardest things about like doing a show
like this is like you're trying to get
information across right and people come
on for different reasons or whatever you
know but it's like it's very difficult
to be like just real and and what I mean
by that is to not just like make it's
really tempting to make yourself look
better than you are yeah you know
there's no need for that there's no need
for that it hurts you in the long run as
any of us know it's like a lot of
breeding is accidents a lot of breeding
is failure you know a lot of breeding is
like you wish you had the things you had
back then now because you do a better
job with them now than you would have
done 15 years ago when you were still
just figuring it out
and you know it it uh I actually think
it's amazing how much cool stuff has
come out of cannabis
um despite like most of it coming out of
garages or little warehouses or little
Greenies
yeah I mean when I was first going when
I was first going to Holland I just had
no idea that like every five or six
years weed would reinvent itself
and
I mean and this and what I mean by that
is that like if you don't get seeds when
they're available
you have no idea if those seeds with
those parents will ever be around again
well I mean that changed over time
though it accelerated the the process of
how quick strains turned over
accelerated I mean OG Kush lasted 20
freaking years like white widow lasted
you know 20 freaking years but now it's
like cookies and then runs then you know
this and that it's going way faster the
fads are going faster I think yeah I
think that's modern marketing yeah yeah
it's just marketing for newbies um yeah
yeah but but yeah like uh actually to go
back to uh what Pete said about uh
I'm gonna add the tangent here as well
but uh what Pete said about Mark Emery
and back in the day
um you made some really good points and
uh like to clarify like last the last
podcast we were chatting and uh I was a
little bit vague about some of our my
history back in the day uh working with
Emery but uh I don't have to be that big
but uh yeah for about a year or so like
the Federation when I split from
Federation
um it was a big uh argument I had with
with Mark and with Mike from Federation
um because uh we I was out of the city
uh for for about a month or so and I
came back and my partner at Federation
had a bunch of strains on Mark Emery's
catalog that I know did not exist oh
that sucks dude you just renamed him and
I uh yeah and that was the last straw
and I went in I I went in I told Mark
hey Mark I'm done with Federation me and
Mike are split I'm starting my own seed
company and by the way all those crosses
that you have there in the catalog they
don't actually exist
um they're just renamed seeds because
Mike wanted to make some money and Mark
did not care he goes oh well no of
course
yeah and uh and I was like and then and
that's where I start I stopped selling
uh seats to mark that was that that same
day I was done uh so I went over to kind
seed I started selling the kind seeds uh
Amsterdam Seed company or Amsterdam Cafe
and a few a few companies online in
Ontario but I I stopped selling to Mark
Emery that that very same day and that's
awesome it was only about probably about
five or six years later when I don't
know if you guys know uh Michelle Rainey
no she came up she anyway she came to uh
uh Vancouver and she took over the
business end of Markham recedes in uh
okay probably the mid-2000s
and now okay and she she ran it straight
and because Mark was too busy doing his
political [ __ ] oh yeah yeah I was
getting into trouble and blowing money
um so when Michelle took over she ran it
straight and she was honest about it so
that's that's why I went back into the
Emory catalog but before that from about
Joe 2005 I never sold to mark because I
I knew what was up you know what I got
to ask don't you yeah
what what strains were on the list what
strains are on the list
oh dude I can't you know what
it was about four or five of them that
he had I I can't really remember
um had to though had to try I'd have to
[ __ ] I I actually I do have some of my
the old Emory catalogs here I could
probably figure it out by looking at the
old catalogs but uh off the top of my
head
yeah of course like they weren't they
weren't your Creations so why the [ __ ]
would you care to me that's always been
the risk of like when you're buying
especially from different countries and
stuff and like an order comes in for you
know eight packs of this and they don't
have it but they have other seeds and so
they're like well I'll just take the
money and I'll fill this order with this
is close enough and off it goes and
and you know that's a slippery slope
indeed
I always tell people unless it's a
really big established company if if a
company online always has a strain in
stock
chances are they're bullshitting
um like as a breeder myself too like
sometimes you run out of seeds and I I
don't have room in my group you make
that strain for another six months so
yeah
you can't always have every strain in
stock unless you have an insanely well
organized large operation
um that's the one thing I tell people
when they ask me
yep when when people ask me what's one
thing I can look for to know if a seed
company has uh is reputable and I'd say
well look how long they've been around
and has any other stuff ever gone out of
stock
that'll that'll give you your answer
yeah
I mean I mean it's not always true
because there are amazing people who can
keep their stuff in stock and much
better than I ever could obviously but
yeah for the most part if they're doing
it legit they're gonna run out of stock
and stuff every now and then
and you know sometimes you're doing
regular if if you're doing regular
breeding sometimes you get like a
prolific amount of seeds as he was just
talking about and you you might have a
55 gallon drum
like he was saying like full of whatever
um and then you're not gonna run out you
know so yeah it's just unpopular yeah
you know right but you but you can't
really sell them after three years or so
the germination rate goes down if you're
not starting them right sure yeah every
here's when you start seeing the dip in
the germination rate um
that's what I found I mean
yeah yeah
yeah if they're not fridge stored people
don't understand like how quickly like
because they can go from being real nice
to just but all of a sudden a month
later nothing's popping I saw it happen
with a lot of my old strawberry stuff
for whatever reason all at the same time
it just
take a [ __ ] and that was that can't sell
anymore
one of the things I think is interesting
about three things too it's about
stability
yeah
I just I was just saying that like one
of the big shifts at least that's
happened in America is like a lot of the
old school people have what I call you
know they have lines right and like you
were saying you have lines and You
remake those lines at different times
for new seed a lot of the smaller
breeders these days everything is a
one-off yeah everything is made once and
it exists until it's gone and the
likelihood they ever make it again is
very small yeah you know because they're
not really naked
yeah and when they do remake it it's a
different phenotype
yeah exactly so it's become very flash
in the pan in that way where people
advertise a drop and if you want that
hybrid you better get it then because
you know it's not like the old Seed
Company days in America at least for a
lot of people where it's like I have
these age drinks
here are the lines I offer yeah yeah you
know and I've been working on these
lines for quite a while
um and so you know but but strangely
people want worked lines but they also
want new stuff every single drop yeah
yes that's what I ran into and that's
why I said with the with the blue bonnet
[ __ ] I was like I'm done I'm done I'm
not changing anymore I'm just staying
because either way I'm not winning so
I'm just gonna stay here see how it
holds yeah stick him a gun and I wish I
had some of the same Cuts I had back in
the 90s and I would have stayed there
with a few of those strands because you
can't get any better you only knew it
yeah if you only knew right right like
some of those older lines from Neville
I mean Matt and I were talking to
someone that was uh you know very close
to Neville the last you know decade or
so of his life
and even he bitched about he wished he
had a lot of the stuff he had in the 80s
and early 90s now yeah because you got
you know 30 years of reading in and man
what could I do with them in my 60s yeah
I was in it you know I mean I think part
of life is
I wish I had now what I had back when I
was an idiot kid yeah and I think that
keeps happening the older you get you're
like man I wish you know because you
just you gain experience if you're if
you're good at what you do and you care
you know is that a man thing like does
anybody know any women that have that
same drive or something like that
I don't know any women that are like
that about their like oh I wish I had
that old strain from back in 62 like I
never would say that ever I and I I
don't know maybe it's like a man's drive
to I don't know there's a few but not
very many
yeah I would I don't think there's very
many yeah
I just think there's some Industries
that are that are male dominated yeah
that's true
um and I think cannabis or some
combination of it
yeah actually yeah we're here in Canada
there's quite a few women that are big
players in the game yeah especially in
the legal Recreation because well women
are facing like they're better at doing
and going through the legal system than
we are and creative too like I know some
really creative women in the
recreational Market that are doing
really well with their branding and
stuff like that just because of it you
know what I mean there's a huge gap up
here between the old school guys that
have been doing it forever and
and businessmen and trust and throw the
government into it's just miserable
right yeah a few times some of my best
Partners were that ran my websites
um and they are we Geeks and can out
smoking
um so in South America I encountered
that as well
Argentina women are running the show
down there um they're running they're I
bet they're doing the seals they're
running the shops
uh it's it's more so than Canada in that
way um
I didn't really expect that because it's
more of a machismo uh male dominated
culture but uh yeah down there uh
yeah the women are they're hardcore
that's awesome
that's awesome you know a lot of the
women Growers that I know that actually
interact with the plant
tend to be much better Growers than men
too for whatever reason they have that
connection plan yeah you don't want to
admit it but yeah that's true at the end
of the day you're taking care of a
living thing right
yeah
Vancouver uh all the Asian Growers
um it was all the women running running
rooms
um oh wow and you know all the like the
Vietnamese and Chinese uh groups in the
Vancouver yeah the women would be in
there taking care of the plants and the
guys would be out there selling and
dealing with the gangsters gambling yeah
[Music]
do you know much about that culture like
that's not a culture that that's ever
really been talked about like the the
Asian culture uh the Asian black market
culture in cannabis or in in Vancouver
uh we have uh very very large Asian uh
uh population there um yeah so uh like
one city I lived in right next to
Vancouver called Richmond it's probably
80 uh our Asian descent
um wow and they they were they'd rent
these big giant mansions and they would
pump out the pounds that's awesome no
pots no nothing dirt on the yeah bird on
the floor yeah white lights yeah you'd
walk into these places there'd be mold
halfway up the walls like wherever the
poly started up was fine and down was
black mold
and they just run these giant hot houses
burn them and turn them and on to the
next place like it was a while yeah when
they when they got big in the the late
90s
it's their fault that uh that the rental
uh societies uh told the police told
landlords that you have to inspect your
your rental house every two months
and that's all because of the uh big
Asian gangsters who would go in and
destroy a house
three four crops and then they move on
to the next house it kind of wrecked the
uh rental uh uh scene uh in British
Columbia
wow I didn't even know that was a law
that would yeah British Columbia only in
British Columbia because one out of
three rental homes were a grow up
commercial drop not not a small one it
was a
it's actually not I mean I think that's
just the story to some degree like of
how like a lot of times like like
immigrant populations work
you know in the sense
well yeah they not only that but they
have like tighter family units the
people are willing to live on less
um you know they're willing to bond
together to raise themselves up it
whatever they're doing is far better
than where they came from to begin with
they stick together uh you know ratting
on the group is Unthinkable because it's
your entire family and everyone you know
and all of your connections and all that
and so it's actually a pretty effective
method
and it goes on in America too
um in all kinds of different ways I used
to I didn't know very much about it but
I used to have some friends
um in the Canadian scene you know 20
something plus years ago and they were
independent and they said the hardest
thing to be independent was like you
basically had to be invisible to the
Asians and the bikers
because those were the two those were
the two big groups they kind of wanted
to dominate everything and so he you
know he was always like I always have to
Bob and weave and not irritate either of
either of those groups
you know yeah
um yeah and yeah
and Vancouver and British Columbia back
in the day was exactly the same yeah
um Edmonton too everywhere across Canada
it was the same uh you know if you got
up to a certain size you kind of
to not get taxed um you kind of had to
know someone or yeah but I was lucky I
was in the seed business
um so they kind of seen us as a novelty
they didn't take us too seriously we
weren't competition to them so and I
would some of the boys I would give
clones to and uh they were off often buy
their personal bag off of me and they
wouldn't even smoke their own stuff
because they fertilize it right up to
the end and they they sell it to the
states and call it beasters and but they
wouldn't even smoke with their own stuff
so the boys would come to me and buy
their personal stash so I I was always
kind of left alone to do whatever I
wanted but uh but yeah it is once you
get to a certain size you kind of have
to have the the blessing
I wonder if they were trying to tax
Emery at all
no I mean it was pretty big and Flash I
don't think so
yeah he was too flashy I think they
didn't want to be Associated and get
busted that they kind of took the heat
away from them he took the heat away and
he was he was out there advertising BC
Bud to the world he's a BC Vibe it's so
great so he brought everybody to the
market he brought people to British
Columbia to buy their weed so they let
Mark be he was a useful [ __ ] idiot is
what he was a useless in the
neighborhood you'd come because that's
where his store was and then you'd find
the 10 other stores that were hidden
around the market right yeah honestly if
you're even in America too if you're in
the Flop the flower market and the seed
Market don't really intersect very much
that's right that's true they just don't
like and they don't affect each other
all that much if you're pumping out
specific clones for production
you know like somebody with 30 different
strains trying to make money in that way
he's not affecting your clientele or
what you're doing or your life at all
it's just not even the same world yeah
it's really not the same world yeah
since I moved back to Canada about five
six years ago
um I I I make seeds um if I had a couple
pounds of weed I wouldn't even know
where to sell it
same
it's bizarre um same like yeah when
you're in the seats for that long like I
tell people this a lot too that that are
interested in getting into the seed game
I always tell them if you're ever get
gonna get serious about it you're gonna
have to make that choice one day to
permanently turn to seeds and when you
do flour it's only going to be your
testers but you're not going to be in
flower production anymore you're going
to lose those contacts eventually
because you're just not going to need
them you're going to devote your life to
seed so you know yeah you're eventually
going to have realizing one or the other
yeah
yeah exactly and I've always uh my
buddies back in Vancouver back in the
day they they look at me like I'm an
idiot sometimes because I'd be growing
these big rooms of uh Congolese and
Mexican sativas that take 16 weeks to
flower I like yeah like Jay you could
have flipped two crops by now and made
all this money and and you know maybe
they were right but uh my
I'm a weed geek though so I um so yeah
it was all about selecting for me I was
looking at the long game because I know
even if I exit the industry I can come
back as long as I have my genetics and
stay true to my what they are and don't
[ __ ] I can always re-enter the
industry
um
but it's just going bud and just
flipping pounds
um
you're you're a nobody and there is no
brand you're just a guy with a bag of
wheat
yeah so
I think there's multiple ways to do that
I mean where I live there's a bunch of
people that sold flower to support their
lifestyle
and then did a bunch of breeding for
themselves and their friends because
that's what interested them
you know so it's almost like they had a
commercial side of it but then that
funded their interests
yeah you grow up one commercial room to
pay the mortgage and pay the bills and
then you play in the other room tough
not to be interested that's for sure
yeah
yeah because for my experience has been
and I don't know about you guys but like
the older you get in the weed scene in
order to stay
excited and like you know pumped to get
into your room
um I'm in my mid-40s or whatever most of
my friends if you tell them I want you
to Mono crop this
they could Pro they could do a good job
but they'd probably want to like just
shoot themselves after a while because
they'd be so bored you know like
literally like like you know my buddy
you know you lose your passion yeah yeah
you're like okay I grow these two
strains I've dialed it in I figured out
all the when to raise and lower the EC I
figured out exactly how it likes to be
grown and now I'm just making minor
adjustments and steering the ship and I
feel like I'm a factory worker yeah
we're like seeds and all this other
stuff
it brings Joy yeah exactly but we need
those people uh to produce uh weed for
the for the public but uh that's not me
um yeah definitely I have to grow I'm
growing out seedlings it's like
Christmas time when you when you start a
new batch of seeds to see what's going
to come up uh I'm like a little kid at
Christmas wondering what's under the
tree
um yeah for sure you can dial it in yeah
like yeah he's more of a pick a few
strains and dial it in so we all need
each other in the industry but uh
but that's not my game
I mean what what I find hard about like
being a breeder or seed popping or
anything like that is that it's pretty
small about a size seed pop you can do
where you can honestly judge like what
just happened because if you do a big
seed pop and you want to save it and you
want to have backups and then you want
to get all your friends that you trust
to help you smoke and test it like you
can do a big seed run but eventually how
are you going to judge those hundreds of
plants
yes right and you can and the problem is
for me is that all the stuff that you
can visually see like you can be like oh
that one has the structure I like that
one has the the leaf ratio this one has
the resin but the part that really will
make a strain lasting or not to me is
invisible
like you don't know how it's going to
affect you or taste until you try it
yeah you can't look at the you can't
look at it behind you and be like oh
that's going to be the one
yeah in fact also like what I like to do
as well is uh after I've did my
selections out of a female hunt
um you have to grow the clone of the
variety too not just the seedling after
you oh yeah you see the structures and
different characteristics and you gotta
yeah put it through some scratch you
only get it to see that one way one time
I and I talked about that a whole bunch
where I got to a point where I never
flowered like when I was testing seeds
inside I never floured the seed plant
yeah clones and root all the clones and
flower the Clone because I would see the
seed plant once and it would never be
that way again and I was always
interested well what is the Clone gonna
do yeah
you know you don't have that you don't
have that Tap Root you don't have that
seed plant Vigor you don't have the same
stretchiness it's just different
well even now even though I'm switching
most of my rooms over to LEDs uh when I
do my seed selection because I've been
growing under uh HBS for for decades
when I do my selecting in my tester room
I do it under the HPS and I yeah trim
nothing off the bottom I leave all those
Shaggy bits at the bottom to see how and
I don't pinch it just to see how it
grows naturally sure and that's what
I've been doing for for 25 years uh so I
want to see what it does all on its own
without any manipulation and then I make
my selections
the way I've been doing it for that's
that's my way of doing it because
and then after that with the Clone then
I start playing see if it ties down good
how it reacts when you're pinch it I
mean because sometimes unless you see
what it does
you won't know what kind of manipulation
to apply to get what you want out of it
you know if something if you don't pinch
it and something makes some incredible
two and a half foot long Cola
you might not want to pinch it and go
for all those side buds yeah yeah you
might wanna you might want to leave it
that way you know sometimes you might
grow something and all those bottom nugs
end up nice and solid
you know sometimes they end up all leafy
in a mess and so if it's leafy in a mess
you're like oh I have to strip all that
off to concentrate it up top
but sometimes it'll make nice nug all
the way down to the base without any
effort
and you know sometimes you have to watch
exactly yeah
I remember we have it the first big I've
seen that I was impressed with was
actually breeder Steve's uh shishka
Berry
yeah oh my God like it was like three
feet tall just one big giant Cola and
just stuff you hardly seen any uh red
hairs on it it was just big green and
crystally uh with almost no red hairs
and what did it smell like
um I always wondered with shis could
Berry because I've never had like just
cuts up there
a little bit on the fruity side I would
say
it was there was almost too much resin
that it cut out all the terpenes there
wasn't no it wasn't okay
you [ __ ] up and it was huge and my
lime green huge lime green buds I gotta
I gotta have Steve that one man he he
nailed that one that's why and it was a
yeah it was a it was a quality name
yeah yeah I mean people we can talk
about
some you know sometimes what's funny
about it is like a cool name goes a long
way
for sure and even even shishka Berry
like it's got a cool nickname you can
just call it the Shish you know like
things that like that matters
you know yeah there's so many strains
that I know that are just just kick ass
but they have a shitty name and nobody
buys them yeah
it's sad but you know what what's that
if you could think of one strain uh each
one of you one strain that you think
should get more recognition than it
currently does what what what's this
first strain that comes to your minds
so from Vancouver Island Seed Company
Jiffy pot huh
okay
um and from my own stuff probably my
first Contact
um the first Contact
yeah because it it's high CBD and super
chirpy but I I don't really sell I got a
big bag of it but I don't really sell
many seeds and it's and people don't
know what they're missing on that one um
yeah it's just super super chirpy you
can just rub your hand up against the
leaves and you know you're sticking to
it um and it's a nice Buzz um
really nice Buzz it's not super Stony
but it's one of those
quality when my son's when my son
started smoking weed I that's the strain
I gave him because I wanted to hire CBD
and lower THC because yeah yeah I'm
still 18 years old you got to get your
head together a little bit and get to
work
um so I told hey if you want to smoke
weed do my first Contact so uh but no
it's one of my one of my best strains
that I people don't buy a lot of and and
they should because it's it's one of my
best ones
um but yeah other than that strain of
mine and Jiffy pot from uh
from Vancouver Island Seed Company
those are they had a two up right off
the top of my head those are the two I
can think of what do you got Casey
I'm all about the death Baba I think uh
we up here we got it's the pre-98 death
bubba cut it's called and it's just like
the obnoxious Kush gas candy like it's
just amazing in the the like the medical
benefits that come along with I don't
know if it's the mixture of terpenes or
what but uh it's phenomenal like even
for myself for nausea like it's just
been like it's one of those strains that
I could never if I had to pick one for
the rest of my life that would be it
you know what's in it
uh uh if you give me a couple minutes
I'll figure it out because I've got test
results here I just gotta dig them up I
want to um I want to say a long time ago
somebody gave me seeds of it it was like
a black domino Bubba maybe but I I think
that there's been a few over the years
that have had that name so I always
wonder like when people talk about the
death we just call it the pre-98 cut
it's been a cut that's been around for
years and years and years similar spell
to the OG kush yeah it's like super
super gassy soup I wonder if it's just
Kush what if it's just our Bubba down
here the p98 Bubba
or if it's a hybrid of the 398 Bubba
yeah I have no idea I uh I have the OG
Kush and I'm not a big fish guy but uh
everybody has it I stick with my own
strains but uh
I like the high Emoji Kush I like the
the high of older Jeep coaches to me is
what always it like it no matter what
any cup I've ever gone to where it's
like a real legit cup if someone brings
a really good cut of OG Kush it's very
hard for anybody to not pick that one as
the winner like it just seems to always
be the winner in the room uh for the
high
but there's a few similarities as well
with the cheese I know people have
noticed that the cheese is a little more
uh rank smelling but uh there is some
similarities uh when it's over dried you
can really see the uh uh similarities
with the cheese
um so in this death Bubba it's dominant
as beta caraphylene and then fenchal
uh Alpha Himalayan
isobarom meal
uh lemonade
beta nursing pinene Alpha and beta
pinene
complex I think that just I think that
just means it gets you [ __ ] up yeah
yeah it's very complex is what it is
yeah
yeah like I've uh oh salmon fishing on
the ocean
seasick like puking two Puffs straight
me right out same thing I had knee
surgery yeah knee surgery come out of
the hospital they knock you out for it
yeah and uh woke up dry heaving puking
tried the gravel no no good
out of the hospital to Puffs straight me
right out like
pain management and stuff like that like
on the medical side of things like I
think it should it should be everywhere
there's a company finally I think
bringing it out in Canada here pistol in
Paris
um they're going to be launching it into
the legal recreational market and like I
think it should be in the medical side
of things for sure like if they should
do studies on it right yeah I'm going to
be Crossing it with my Romulan here on
the next round as well so uh give it a
try he keeps raving about it for a few
years and I've smoked it it kicks my ass
yeah
I'm gonna I'm gonna have to try it like
for nausea stuff that sounds awesome
that sounds killer yeah oh yeah if you
can find it it's uh it's something else
yeah
not so what about you
yeah I'll take them
what's a strain that you think has a
like has a crappy name maybe or whatever
and doesn't sell as or get the shine
that it should
uh I mean there's a bunch of them but uh
I'll get like the uh dog [ __ ]
yeah yeah you know there's there's this
strain it used to be called in
Minneapolis it had a way cooler name it
was called Electric Boogaloo and it's a
little mysterious what it is but I think
it it might be like silver Pearl by
Hayes or it might it's it's some kind of
hazy hybrid from the early 90s yeah and
it's one of those ones where like you
know Matt and I you know we have some
get-togethers with a bunch of friends
you know and people gather from all over
and breeders come and stuff and it
always ends up being one of those ones
that like everybody isn't it's in their
top two or three that they tried and
they always can't figure out why it's
not more popular yeah it's definitely
one of those ones that I I you know I
was talking about it the other night
with someone I was like I think when it
comes to Elites they're like everybody
seems to love Bubba everybody seems to
universally for the most part like OG
Kush
and Everyone likes Electric Boogaloo and
I can't think of anything else that like
some people like blueberry some people
don't some people you know that like
those three I could think of I I mean I
I tend to think too that we're in such a
commercial industry in a way that people
only want to grow what's currently
popular
yeah and so when you get old like we are
now or older there's been all these
great strains that have gone through
your hands that deserve their moment in
the Sun but they just don't get enough
play because they're not currently
popular they're not being cropped for
production people aren't getting to try
them that much and so as a result of
that it has nothing to do with the
quality of the plant itself it basically
has to do with this weird hype and
people's access or not to it
right now and that's and that and then
it ends up just getting saved by heads
and passed around and grown for personal
and passed around to friends and stuff
like that and everybody can't believe
um what uh you know and names are a huge
thing I'll tell a story
um there was this strain in Mendo that
was made by a friend and it was called
it was made by everybody shot it was
called Big Wreck it was Big Bud by train
wreck okay
and it was Frosty and it was beautiful
and it finished at the end of September
it was really pretty but nobody wanted
big wreck nobody was interested in Big
Bud train wreck right yeah and so one of
my friends changed the name to Barry
White
and as soon as the name changed to Barry
White not only could they move endless
packs of it but they got a premium
you know they got a couple hundred bucks
more than they should for other things
and it was all about the name change
nobody wanted big wreck but Barry White
I want some of that that happened with
that that happened with us as well a few
years ago when I started working with
the OG Kush
um uh we just had it named as a cross
and never sold and then we our OG Kush
crossed with the Romulan of wearing
renamed it Ogopogo uh and he started
flying off the shelves
I don't know if you know what Olga Pogo
is yeah yeah it's out like our uh senior
Loch Ness Monster
yeah yeah exactly and but great stranger
names
make a big difference you know I I tend
to think jesel is is one that I've
noticed that like it's it's one of the
original canvas but for some reason it's
no one's ever hunted it and everybody
that had it dropped it for whatever
reason because the name just never
caught on it was a dumb name
I mean it's it's and that's what I was
saying before too about how like a lot
of weed access is kind of flash in the
pan where it's like if you weren't there
for those few years you might had on how
to have access to it at all and so most
of the currently popular strains aren't
nearly as good as the collection of old
school classics that some people have
access to there's just not a proper way
to Market them and get them out there
and people often want to do what's easy
yeah you know and they want to do with
the Brokers and the buyers and the
market is asking for and so whatever
that shift is they'll just go with that
flow
and you know you can end up having
people hundreds of people hundreds of
Growers having some popular cut and then
the market shifts and 10 years later
four Dudes held onto it
yeah yeah and that's like the most
common thing
well thanks I'm thankful for those four
Dudes yeah is that right I've gotten a
lot of strains back uh from uh some old
friends uh that I thought stories that I
thought were gone years ago and
people come out of the closet and say
hey I still got a cut yeah what what's
really important actually is is people
in like I don't know about Canada
specifically but like in America people
that like you know live in areas that
like don't change all that much right so
they can they can grow their two or
three little strains and they can sell
them to their friends and their friends
are just stoked on getting really high
quality weed and the fads don't affect
them
yeah that's a lot of times who you find
Oh I thought this thing was lost and
they're like no I have it you know I
never was forced to change
and we still love it
that's how I got my uh Hawaiian sativa
back
yeah a good old boy from rural Manitoba
said hey I still have it I bought it in
1999 and he has beautiful cut and uh
thank God for him
yeah that's a great line
classic classic coins TV line one of our
buddies is I I just gave all my seeds of
it to uh my buddy brains and he just did
a big pop of it so he could be running a
bunch of those and reproducing those too
just to see if we can find in them but
that's my favorite I mean I never had a
traditional Hawaiian line because it's
before my era but out of all the lines
I've ever had called Hawaiian that was
the one I thought was the nicest it was
a nice like sativa sweet just had a
really nice quality High though really
nice
yeah anything that I usually see now
that's called Hawaiian is not like it
was back in the day oh yeah a lot of the
Hawaiian from the 90s I remember a real
what they call a menthol
Menthol flavor uh sativas uh and that's
how I remember the Hawaiian interesting
but nowadays no not you don't get that
Menthol flavor very much anymore it was
intense intensely uh menthol
and that was during the 90s from Hawaii
up there in in Canada
yeah yeah I got with Federation Seed
Company we got those those uh genetics
from uh from Vancouver Island Seed
Company from from G-Man there
um
yeah he had a few different versions of
it a few different crosses it was
amazing it's uh but he got it straight
from Hawaii
I know we've touched on him briefly
before but
it seems like he had like a major major
influence on your career at least and a
few others around you and the strains in
in Canada in general not just in
Vancouver Island
yeah he was a big influence for me uh
and a few other breeders on the island
and a lot of the source genetics came
from him he was he was growing since the
mid 70s and uh you know I I was a
Youngster on the scene coming in mid 90s
so
yeah
I'd love to talk to him about when he
saw the first indicas and stuff like
that since he was around during that
time and what his experience was with
them has he ever told you about anything
like that
um oh yeah yeah we we were we grew side
by side for years uh back in the day but
uh he's kind of dropped off the planet
here and I actually mentioned or I
messaged him about two or three months
ago and yeah he hasn't gotten back to me
so yeah hopefully he'll turn up because
he sounds like an interesting guy to
interview me yeah but you probably won't
ever see his face
oh that's funny old old school old old
school yeah
yeah
all right it's hard it's hard for some
people to turn off that Decades of
programming
that's true I don't want you to see my
face I don't want you to see my name I
don't want you to have any association I
mean we even have friends of ours
that'll come on the show and you know
they want to wear a mask or they want to
be in a dark room or you know they live
in a state that's not that permissive
yet and they worry about it getting out
you know or even friends or family or
you know in some cases
you know something like that knowing
yeah so everyone has a different
perspective on like what their own
safety is or perception of it
a different era yeah for me even like
for been selling since mid 90s and like
didn't tell anybody anything like if you
didn't buy off me you didn't know
and uh now to see all the brands that
are popping up just because they didn't
care or they would advertise or whatever
now they've got established Brands years
later words myself like I didn't say
[ __ ] with a mouthful to anybody and we
started starting from scratch right a
whole lot more knowledge but on the
ground sure that's right
I mean when I when I was young in
Chicago
like there was only two or three people
that knew I grew
and sometimes I would be at a party and
Alpha one of those people I would buy a
full price eighth or quarter
yeah so that way when friends saw me
with the weed they knew where I got it
yeah they wouldn't they wouldn't think
that I I why you know he can't be the
grower I saw him buy it off a homie for
a hundred bucks a quarter yes yes
you know it's it's one of those things
where it was like I mean we used to I
used to I had a good friend of mine I
would pay him to drive me to the Growth
Store
because he was straight as can be and if
they ran his license plate and they
raided them he literally had nothing
that was going to get him in trouble
yeah that doesn't get him on anything
you know and so we wouldn't even go we
wouldn't even go to the Growth Store
with a car that was tied to any of the
sites yeah you know yeah you parked 23
blocks away yeah I didn't understand
computers and so when overgrow and
cannabis world and some of those first
forums came out I was terrified to post
yeah because I didn't know if a
government agent could just like call me
up and figure out like exactly where I
was posting from and where the computer
was and I had so many good jokes I could
pull right now and I'm just not going to
even my medical licenses even medical
license is Canada like I thought that
was a joke like they were just like
people were signing up to get raided
right yeah yeah for sure when they could
have went out and got a license and been
legal I just shut up and kept doing what
I was doing
I did not want to be on that I I thought
everybody was just eventually going to
get pulled I thought it was the biggest
yeah
you guys are ridiculous like you don't
see what's going on here yeah
but you know it
that's interesting too because when I
first ended up in Mendo I actually ended
up on a legal medical program because my
ex had cancer right and it was through
the Sheriff's department and it was
through the the Health Service of uh of
our County and all that
and literally like the sheriff was so
cool back then he burnt like the feds
threatened to come in and take all of
his records because they wanted to know
who was who
and he burned them all yeah that's
pretty cool he literally he shut the
program down and he burned all the files
because he was like you're not going to
come in and rate a bunch of sick people
nope I don't know who it is you don't
know who it is oops Yeah right yeah and
so sometimes there were cool people yeah
a cool cop that's never heard of that
before that's crazy
I mean for a Time
they exist in theory yeah they do exist
I mean they're humans like anybody else
they might be a preponderance to one
side or another
but I mean weren't you mentioning
earlier on the show that like you know
you were in Spain you were selling
clones to Cops
the cops yeah I never feared the cops
when I lived in Spain um in Canada it's
a whole different story when you run
into a cop you kind of
look all straight and proper and pretend
nothing's going on but still see until
proven innocence and in Spain yeah no
fear of the cops you could be you can
walk up to smoke and enjoy and uh report
you know something legit I just didn't
fear cops there
um that would be nice it's a whole
different in their ears yeah that's a
different culture that's that's the
thing yeah as an American I often forget
like and not even just an American like
where I'm from specifically is very
top-heavy and and conservative so if he
lives in the worst place in California
the worst like the worst we have TV
shows about our police force being
jackasses you know yeah it's not good so
like my perspective is a little skewed
on police that I I never really have any
positive outlook but I forget like yeah
other places they are your peers like
it's not that same adversarial thing
yeah when I was growing up on on the
Prairies here in Canada my uh parents
they worked uh for the police they like
janitors and they did some guarding at
the prison and my dad told me after
years of working with him he said one
out of five he's a good guy he's there
for the right reason
the other four
they're just people who want revenge on
society the one out of five is a good
person there for the right reason so
just hope you get one of those one of
those one out of five
yeah I mean if you if you get off having
an unreasonable amount of power off off
of people in most situations that's not
a bad career for you yeah
it draws people with that bent you know
yeah exactly
it does I mean Spain has always been
interesting to me because it's almost
like the only place in in like Western
Europe that has a climate that's like
that's close to where I live to some
degree you know uh when you look at the
map of how much sun Europe gets versus
how much sun America gets it's
unbelievable
uh how much sunnier large parts of
America are compared to Canada or you
know or compared to Europe
you know
um and so you know did you get to grow
any any city did you get to was was
Spain did you get to do some outdoor
there did you get to do something yeah
did you get to try yeah
all the strings that I couldn't grow
outdoors here in Canada I was able to
grow in Spain and oh wow up here we're
around the 50th parallel here and when I
lived in Spain we're around the 35th
pretty much the same latitude as uh
Northern California like San Francisco
yeah where I lived in Spain and I was
able to grow all my shaquillas the first
that's the first thing I did on my
Island sweet skunk my grapefruit hazes
my Hawaiians first thing I did was
planted those sativas and I a few big
properties there where I grow a bunch
and then a few few patches in the
mountains and then like I have some
questions on that because that's one of
the that's the reason I brought it up
was that I've done a bunch inside and I
you know I obviously live in an area
where I get to do a bunch of sun grown
too
um you were I would imagine you were
primarily indoor in Canada for a long
time right so then you go over to Spain
well you were just talking about let's
let's just focus on the stuff that you
couldn't grow outside in Canada yeah but
you grew it inside in where in in Canada
because that's where that's where it
could finish
where there are strains of yours that
did things you didn't expect were there
things that when you've got to grow them
in the sunlight you found some
differences or you found some things
that really surprised you
you know
because
not too much actually
um
maybe a little bit but I had already
been growing for about 12 13 years
before I moved to Spain so I kind of had
a good feel for
how my varieties performed in different
situations sure sometimes they wouldn't
uh grow outdoors on the island but I
would always had greenhouses so I had a
good idea so of what what kind of what's
going to express itself in the in this
election but uh
yeah and you see anything like notably
different over there like is that what
we're trying to get at like the
expressions like from yeah like even
I'll give you a couple examples so like
the chem family that I run and some
different stuff like that if you grow it
inside it grows a certain way
if you grow It Outdoors you'll get hot
pink to magenta hairs on it quite a bit
that I'll never ever see inside but then
sometimes if you grow out in the full
sun you'll get a leafy Afghan mess where
if I grow it like say under like woven
poly that takes out some of the UV and I
grow it smaller like in a greenhouse
I'll get like a more indoor expression
uh outdoors in Spain um
a lot of the red hairs would come out on
the wrong one that I never seen indoors
or even in the greenhouse in Canada
um sure that the red hairs in Spain just
were popping out it was it was beautiful
beautiful looking plant uh
yeah
other than that not not a big difference
uh in most strains
interesting because I feel like indoor
you can have you have control over
everything
but the light the you know there's not a
better light that I've experienced than
the sun I've tried all kinds of
different combinations and mixed light
inside and you can kind of approximate
it but like it's weird like I would
bring a lot of my strains
um and like some old euros and stuff
like that like Neville and Shanti and
some old guys actually told me this
where they were like if you want to keep
old moms healthy try to give them three
or four months a year of sunlight
yeah that makes sense yeah and I would
take my plants in February or March and
I would put them into a greenhouse and I
would think they looked pretty healthy
and then after about a month of being
outside I'd be like man these things are
banging
these things are really happy these
plants are really growing well and so
there's something about like just that
full spectrum
where it has all the spectrums in spades
I will say indoor
I indoor I can kind of do the same kind
of trick though with the revenge like a
Sim not maybe not as as vigorous because
it's not the sunlight and obviously
plants prefer the sunlight because of
the spectrum but you can get like that
little bit of a a vigorous re-jump on
plants with the Revenge uh
at least I found like especially for
breeding and stuff Old Stock
um old mom stop arrive Edge does wonders
yeah uh yeah there's nothing nothing
better than this on so
outdoor guys
I mean it's just it's one of those
things where you know the only reason
why I asked is because if you're stuck
up there not stuck but if you're in
Northern like you know there's certain
sativas there's certain things that like
even for my area like it doesn't stay
nice into December
I can't I can't in my environment you
know like I can't grow certain
equatorial stuff and get away with it it
just doesn't finish and so then there's
these there's these things where it's
like the only thing I've ever
experienced with them is growing them
inside yeah because I can't take a 16 20
weaker and see what it does in a
greenhouse yeah unless I've got added
light and mad heat and all these
different things that we typically don't
around
you know so I was just curious if you
like when he went there did he get to
see different things from strains that
like especially when you were talking
about some of these like 16 week
Mexicans and different things that
you're Crossing if you got to play
around with those more because the
weather was just nicer
well I I uh I really like playing with
my grapefruit Haze and my Island sweets
Come Those are the two strains that I
can never finish properly in Canada and
down there I was growing monster monster
plants uh like four or five pounds of
plant and just that that
lemony hazy flavor
that was just and just branches and
branches of wake
um it just can't and they did actually
grow a lot a bit of a different
structure than indoors they're a lot
branchier uh both of those terrains
um indoors maybe it's because I have a
growing technique indoors okay keep the
plants close
so much different when you're outside
for the most part too right you're not
just growing in feet yeah well actually
I didn't do most of my plants were
growing in containers so uh yeah so yeah
the soil was pretty similar um
but yeah other than that yeah
what was the island Street skunk again
real quick
what's that the island sweets Gunk what
was that one again
um that was selected from uh breeder
Steve's uh sweet skunk
do we remember or did we not know um
nobody really knows I think
um you have to ask uh red or Steve about
that red would probably be the best uh
source of info I may have I don't
remember he thought it was in Northern
Lights 1005 Hayes
grape rude what I think it was
it was
I'm pretty sure that's what it is
man another one I'm not remembering it
wrong but if I remember correctly that's
what red thought it was some NLP rays
and it maybe at some point was added
into Rick got grapefruit or something
like that added to it
um and then and then he was saying that
there was a difference
talking about Mark Emery again there was
a difference between the original sweet
skunk
and then people gave seeds to mark
and he was and he he added the island
and he and he sold some different Weird
Hybrids of it and stuff like that yeah
when Mike and I started Federation
um we had a clone of the island sweet
scum or the sweet skunk that was going
around the city
we got a cut we made our own cross with
it and it is Island sweet skunk instead
of sweets
yeah
but you kind of had to because Steve did
not want you using his [ __ ] name
right like Steve was like oh no no he
didn't like that very much yeah but but
I I was trying to give him give him
credit for it he didn't like that sure
yeah back in the day I I get it in the
beginning I was that way too and people
would knock off my string and just
rename it
kind of bugged me a bit in the first
years but nowadays
like yeah everybody this far in
um
you're going with good genetics somebody
exactly copying you it's a it's a
compliment it's not a ripple yes
so I always felt like a compliment with
somebody would take your strain and grow
it themselves I almost thought a bigger
compliment with somebody would take your
strain grow it themselves rename it as
something else so they would get the
credit for it if it was good enough
you know because every single person
that's if you never want anyone to grow
your strains then you can't have a seed
company you can't let them out you can't
have friends do it because that's the
most classic thing in weed is people are
going to take it and they're going to do
what they want with it always
they're gonna buy somebody else's work
before me yeah yeah it's just the most I
mean you know I uh you know Neville you
know Neville got hella bitter because he
thought 90 of the Amsterdam scene was
people just buying and biting his seed
work yeah he did
and then you know and then you don't get
loot for it yeah but that's the that and
that I think honestly that's also what
led to a bunch of seed companies like
never wanting to reveal what was in
their actual mix
because they got tired of competing seed
companies using the exact same verbiage
on their advertisements and the exact
same lineage
you know so people started getting all
secretive about their about their mix
and what was in it and what the sauce
was and what they used
because they didn't want people to know
yes that's the way she goes that's the
way it works did you have anything else
on your list that you wanted to get in
because we were about two hours in I
mean if there's anything else you had
written down that you wanted to get on
this episode a heck of a lot
um just to uh
let the people know it's a good outdoor
strains whether they're Autoflower or
feminized uh
springtime's coming up so uh
get your seeds now absolutely and what's
your website where's the best retailer
to get them
Next Generation seedcompany.com
awesome we have very few uh other
resellers right now
because we do a lot of bulk sales to
other companies and LPS and big farmers
in the states so people are looking for
bulk seeds
we have that or we just have packs as
well so
and you mentioned you have a phone
number too that people could call that's
not super common um what's the number
yeah
um it's I believe I sent you a text uh I
can look it up in one second it's a
Canadian number
is it the one that you texted me from
I uh excuse me one second here
um
yeah it's Taylor when you call the phone
number on our website it's uh my partner
Taylor
um and he'll uh he he's great talking to
people he'll probably throw you
something free if you give him a call
but it's uh yeah
1780-782
-7804
okay there you go anybody you want to
get your Canadian seeds and maybe maybe
you're not even in Canada maybe maybe
you're in the US and you're in a climate
that needs that that mold resistance
it's awesome stuff
um you know there's all the hype out
there and then there's the solid stuff
that's been around forever so don't uh
don't buy the hype
anyways uh not so you want to get
anything else
I just always like talking weed with
people so I'm I'm always appreciative in
people's time
yeah man we loved having you and uh with
you guys yeah and we need to do a hash
episode so you know you're welcome back
on bro like we need to get a full way
for sure well I appreciate your guys's
time so much and uh yeah I need to get
to editing so we can get this thing out
tomorrow
yeah have a good one awesome good to
meet you guys have a good one yeah
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out Syndicate here.com we also have
an underground Syndicate Discord where
we get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out