oh
all right uh welcome everybody I hope if
I yell at my dogs you don't edit it out
no no my dog's barking
okay I'm gonna try the intro welcome to
breeder Syndicate I'm here with Jay from
Next Generation seeds formerly of
federation seed bank thank you for
coming on the show brother
oh thanks for having me
um you're you're someone we've wanted to
talk to for a long time we don't we have
not covered BC in super depth and you're
one of the people that was super
integral in that scene uh responsible
for most of at least maybe you're
responsible for bringing it to seed most
of what is still being used today from
the BC area I should say and I'd love to
talk with you about some of that maybe
start with the early Federation time and
maybe a little bit before that and talk
about what got you into weed what what
Canada was like when you got into weed
all that
um yeah
yeah well well Canada as you know is a
big country like the us and we have
vastly different cultures depending on
where you live in Canada and I I grew up
on the Canadian prairies in a very
conservative community and
um our weed was hard to get it was very
expensive
and you have to deal with Shady people
so our Dream as a Young Stoner growing
up in Manitoba is to go to the West
Coast uh where all the good stuff came
from so when I moved uh out to Vancouver
um I just immersed myself into it
immediately
um
just try try to learn how to grow and I
was fortunate enough to get a job at
Mark Emery's uh hemp BC it was called oh
wow yeah and um I was just hired as the
kid in the back as the carpenter
building things wiring up the girl kits
building
um hydroponic systems yeah and um and
that was my kind of my first year just
getting to know uh Growers all
throughout British Columbia and the West
Coast
um
that was
oh that would have been 95 I believe
awesome yeah
and I spent about a half six months to a
year doing that and of course as soon as
I could I started my own grow up and uh
together with Mike from uh Federation
uh me and did that together and I would
just collected as many clones as we
could get our hands on yeah I noticed a
lot of the people in DC were so spoiled
that they could they could they would
drop take a really good clone and then
not keep mothers of it because they
could just buy another drink for the
next crop because everybody had
phrase and me is somebody where it's
extremely rare uh I just gathered
everything I get my hands on and within
a year I probably had over 60 different
mother strains going right and then
testing them and dropping the ones that
were shipped and keeping the good ones
as you do
um and then yeah then Mike and I started
Federation not only lasted with me about
maybe a year and a half yeah and we went
our separate ways after that
um
but and then next
next generation was started shortly
thereafter
that's all right from Federation
um I started Next Generation right away
yeah and uh moved to Vancouver Island
away from the city got myself a place in
the country and nice Farm to work on and
yeah I got into a really hardcore ever
since uh
I was just I was uh kind of uh just a
collector of strains I was obsessed of
uh
some awesome collecting
and
cardio there
I can't hear Matt oh yeah there we go
sorry about it there we go yeah there's
got it muted
um
a lot of us when we get into breeding
like especially with me I know I dove in
head first I wanted I wanted to see
everything you know like collected moms
kept like hundreds of moms of everything
and it took a long time to start sorting
through this stuff but you have that
excitement and vigor at the beginning of
just I want everything I need to see it
all so yeah what were some of the ones
like the very first clones you started
getting
um well we had a few um like the sweet
paint grapefruit uh that Romulan they
were from Romulan Joe I was robbing the
Joe for a while
um and some Hawaiian sativas that came
through uh Mr G Mountain there from
violent Seed Company uh he had a lot of
good crosses uh that are phenomenal in
in my opinion he's one of the most
underrated breeders uh from back in the
day uh can we talk about him for a quick
sec just to give him a little bit of
shine because that's someone like even I
this far in I didn't know how integral
Mr G was into
all of it the the whole Vancouver not
just Vancouver Island specifically but
the BC scene how much of his genetics
played a role in creating the larger uh
Supply
yeah and uh a lot of people see well
these are an old-timer he's very very
quiet very private sure he's
connected with all kinds of people and
he's he just kept his head down and uh
and did good work and a lot of his
clones and cuts got passed around and he
would make uh sometimes make a lot of
crosses that he never himself never had
a time to grow should we give it to
other Growers here test these out test
these out
um and we received some good seeds the
original Hawaiian sativa came from him
wow um uh Burmese he had a beautiful
Burmese and I know a few other Growers
have copied his Burmese is he a source
he was the Burmese that went around BC
yeah I can't say 100 sure but he was the
first one
um that I know that had it okay and he
he had it before uh I believe before
reefer man um
had it um yeah I know and if he he was
the source of the grandparents of the
original God bud and a lot of those
varieties uh and that's what I've read I
have my Grape God crossed but I didn't
read it with the Grape God clone I read
it with the parents of the Grape God so
that's really so confusing with that um
my mind's slightly different than the uh
from the the God Bud
um yeah a little more a little more
fruity
um a little more stink to it
what were the um grandparents of the the
god butt um
well there's lots of rumors and there's
a lot of confusion
um but it was a strain that he called
Jiffy puck
okay which uh I always told them it was
not a very good name you could come up
with better names
even though they're of course
yeah but then for everything
yeah a few other Growers um had the
Clone and they did a few crosses and
then it got renamed different sex groups
and Growers named it different things
yeah after that some Growers called the
A-frame some were just calling it purple
skunk
um and then uh the the grandchildren of
it the granddaughter I guess is what
became known as the god mud oh okay and
that was via
the only one I've ever heard of those
was the people from Canada have talked
to me about the purple skunk
you know yeah I think that there's
different Generations or groups of goers
I think there's two different section uh
different uh groups of genetics that
were both called purple skunk it makes
sense because it's a very common name
yes purple and skunk yeah yeah kind of
like purple kush up there yeah was it
was there an early just single Purple
Kush clone that was brought up there or
um
not that was brought up here I believe
um reefer men I would probably know a
lot more about that than me uh he had
one of the first purple gunks in the
island pink I believe it was and I think
I was bred out of something that he
calls uh King The King mud or King I had
that written down here to ask you about
yeah the king yeah but I'm just not
really uh too sure we were in we were in
different Circles of uh communities but
we didn't run into each other quite
often and we actually chat now more than
we did back then so yeah
so we we have you going on in and uh to
to Federation you have a little bit of
interaction with another person and how
early on did you start interacting with
like Romulan Joe and Romulan the Clones
first Romulan actually that was very uh
that was even before we that was the
start of federation Seed Company we
hadn't had a seed company and uh Romulan
Joe I was just like I say I was a young
kid building Hydro equipment and uh
Romeo and Joe uh I would just buy my
personal smoke off of them every week
when it came to town and uh you said one
weekend he needed help harvesting and
moving his his crop from Vancouver
Island over to the city
so I went and helped him for the weekend
and me and my buddy Mike were talking
about starting a seed company and the
Romulan was one of the Rave
um yeah at the time and so Romulan Joe
uh sold us the Clone for seven thousand
dollars uh we got we got a couple cuts
he just gave us a few cuts and he was
seven thousand bucks and that was our
Flagship strain
um that we started with it kind of built
our company around
yeah yeah and it it made a big
difference in the in the in the world of
seeds I I know that was one of the ones
I chased really early on and I don't
know that we ever saw the real Romulan
pure clone in the U.S I doubt it yeah I
I doubt it too I haven't seen the real
thing down there I mean there was so
many rumors about that clone and where
it came from
um and it was very hard back in like the
Forum days and stuff and even earlier to
determine what was true you know there
was rumors that like the guy Romulan Joe
was actually called Mendocino Joe and
came from Neo yeah and came from rings
and eyes County and fled to Canada when
a bunch of busts went down and then
there was Canadians that said that was
Bull that was definitely not true and
not true you know from the 70s nope it's
from the 90s it's from the 40s remember
that was from there was just it was just
one of those ones that there was a lot
of rumor and there was very little fact
come coming out or someone who like knew
for sure would come out and just say
what needed to be said so it allowed all
these stories to percolate
legendary
and Romney and Joe was very secretive
and he just kind of got a kick out of
all the stories that go around uh about
sure he just kind of talked with now and
I've actually seen him a few months ago
and uh I stopped by his place for a
smoke and uh I told him about some of
the rumors because I had somebody from
the states that breeds Romulan telling
the story and and I told Joe about this
and he just shook his head and laughed
and he goes no no no no no no it's not
how it works yeah I think that person's
claiming they bred it or like that it's
from their family
yeah yeah
Mendocino Joe's They're family members
one of the crazy one of the things in
cannabis is since we all come out of the
Shadows it's very hard to have facts so
people come out with a big story and
they want to chat about things and you
know sometimes there's opposing stories
to it and sometimes the people like you
said are just secretive and older and
don't care
yeah you know yeah it's um like I can
tell you a story what how about Romulan
Joe told me um okay he's uh he uh
he was a new grower from Eastern Canada
moved to Vancouver Island it's outside
of Victoria and
um he was taken under the the wing of
some of the old-timers back then um in
the would have been in the late 80s late
mid 80s but uh when he first encountered
the Romulan it was a couple older
fellows
um now I think one of them's passed
um and they started off growing they
were pre uh Korean war vets they moved
back to Canada uh into the Cannabis and
all they had was Mexican and Colombian
and they started trying to breed with
that
um and they had very very little luck
small buds but they got faster and
faster breeding but it was still
basically sativa like the Colombian red
and uh
and then in the early 80s I believe it
was 82 or 83 uh when the first afghanis
started coming over
and they crossed out their variety that
they've been working on with uh an
Afghani and then they get a massive grow
out I believe in 84. okay and um
it shortened it made it workable that
they could grow in greenhouses they
never really had lights going back then
it was all in greenhouses on the South
Island
and there there was a runt of the batch
that they kept the cutting of it was the
smallest plant in the room they said
kind of the most finicky as well as far
as pH goes uh but it was so extremely
strong
um and they kept that cut from 94. or
I'm sorry pardon me 84 1984 yeah
and um and
they never even actually the first few
years he said they never even gave it a
name never had a name and that makes
sense Romulan Romney and Joe said you
know it's the late 80s when he was
sitting around helping them trim one day
and they're watching TV trimming and
they were watching Star Trek and they
started joking about how
this stuff will knock a put a dent in
your head just like a Romulan
and that was when the first first got
coin dies or Romulan and it just kind of
stuck from there
I love how these names that's the story
uh Joe's told me so that's awesome
that's great I can I can confirm even
now I'm doing some grow outs uh with
some Colombian genetics and I noticed a
lot with um the structure has absolutely
nothing to like the old school sativas
but the the high that you get from that
Romulan it was like a lot of the
different uh the couple Colombian Reds
that I've grown and the punto Rojo it's
a very very similar smell and high but
obviously nothing close to the same
growth structure but the flavor really
reminds me of the Colombian red that I'm
growing right now
um with the Romulan like a squat little
thing
very squat so it was one of the more
Afghani type structure selections yes
yes and and low yield as well but uh
after we after we did about five or six
back crosses into it
um
we noticed every time we used our uh
mostly Romulan mail on a female of
another variety that that smell and
potency would come across uh wow and the
structure would follow the female and
but he did it the other way around and
used the original Romulan as the female
it it was not it was a lot more unstable
it was it was uh
some patterns
that's super important we've actually
talked for a long time amongst our crew
like as a running joke kind of how when
you're breeding you're looking at things
and there's all these big impressive
plants that throw the kind of structure
and Bud you want all over the place and
then there's this like little runt
mutant thing that you think about
killing a number of times and that thing
ends up being the clear winner over
everything yeah and so it's like it's
it's an Ode to runs and it's an Ode to
like mutants and stuff like that because
often from a production standpoint all
the qualities you're looking for
you don't find the quality of smoke and
effect very often in those you find them
much more often in the weird ones
yeah
I am shocked to have the foresight to
like know to keep the runt because like
even back then a lot of the old wives
tales were yeah killed the the unsturdy
ones killed it you know as fast as you
can get those ones out of there you know
as a Seedling then people would be
killing the runs so I I think that's
awesome they had the foresight to know
that
what you see isn't necessarily what
you're gonna get in the end it may have
other traits that are really amazing
especially with indoors I've learned
that as well with indoors you don't get
away rid of the runs right away uh with
Outdoors you're looking for more outdoor
Vigor so you'll kind of call them pretty
quickly but for indoors now you gotta
wait and see what they can do yeah we
wouldn't have things like OG KB or Urkel
any of the weird stuff you know if we if
we didn't keep the runs around the
weirdos
yeah so I mean you know effect is
invisible
yeah and that's kind of one of the weird
things about cannabis is is until you
can actually dry it and cure it and
smoke it you really don't know what you
have
you don't know if the if the way it
smells translates into the way it tastes
you know you definitely don't know how
what effect it's going to give you so
you can learn some things by watching
but it kind of takes dried flour or hash
to kind of get you to where you want to
be with it
so yeah to give you the proper feedback
definitely
rings did you want to try that on
Romulan oh I was just thinking about
when I made seeds I have a doll was
the mic is messed up again yeah
okay
you see the time it's in the 8 17
something does it work no
no you gotta I mean we can hear you it
just comes with it with a nice car and I
can't remove the Crackle
I can't remove that in editing at all
no no
um
testing testing one two three yeah I
have no idea it's a messed
hmm
all right all right Rings you're getting
a boot to get a mic yeah that's fine I
appreciate you stopping by to help dude
I really do
later on
we wanted to have rings because he had
my he he lives actually down the street
from me and he has a ton of experience
growing your work
um he's a big Next Generation fan
massive over the he's always been a
outdoor from seed kind of guy not that
he doesn't do indoor
um but he never really got huge into the
Clone thing although he does keep clones
he always likes growing from seed and
breeding every year
so out of the three of us he probably
had the most experience in actually
growing out stuff you've made and seeing
what he thought of it yeah I was I was
mainly a federation guy back in the day
I grew a lot of federation like the and
that's what I want to go over with you
some of these because the number one
thing that people were asking oh you're
gonna get you're going to get someone
who knows about Federation we want to
know about these specific strains so if
you want if I can run through these with
you real quick just say kind of first
first few sentences that come to your
head on each and if you want to go into
more detail on any feel free uh Mikado
um that was basically our version of the
uh sweet Pig grapefruit oh okay very
cool yeah it was basically our uh semi
it was F4 when we released it F4 back
cross
um but that yeah it's basically the
grapefruit
that's awesome uh Dynamite
is that next Generation that's the next
Dynamite is next Generation but when I
left Federation I renamed it uh Dynamite
uh instead of calling it Mikado or
grapefruit because
people were upset about if you're using
somebody else's name oh God you can't
call it grapefruit or I'm going to send
somebody to visit you type of thing yeah
change the name but I wrote it in my
description this is our version of the
original grapefruit yeah so I mean
what's about the best you can do at that
point I mean yeah well at first when I
released it instead of calling I called
it grapefruit and yeah I said this is
the grapefruit first made famous by
breeder Steve of uh spice of life uh I
just I was giving him credit and letting
people know where and I was kind of
naive I guess yeah and then he got upset
saying oh wow if you're using that name
you owe me money I'm like well
yeah yeah yeah
all right I'll change the names so as
you learn your way through toe stepping
in in the seed world there's no written
rules it's like each person has their
own rules and you better know it ahead
of time or else it's interesting because
so many name changes happened either
from just that very thing where you
change seed companies and somebody has a
trademark or there's they get upset
about the same name or in some cases
like a little on a little shadier note
uh seed breeders don't want people to
know the origin stock of what they're
releasing because they don't want to
give credit and they don't want to give
a percentage or they don't want to deal
with any Bulls so they just like make up
their own name and then there you go
again I I was like yeah oh go ahead yeah
I always like to give credit to where
I've how what I created it from because
everything we have was built on somebody
else's work that came before us
um and it's just just a matter of
letting people know and being honest
about it it was I was my philosophy
behind it but yeah there is a lot of
people a lot of strains nowadays you
know that there's something in there
that they're not telling you yeah
probably a lot in the states without
yeah oh God it's been that way for
forever I mean we've even talked about
it how like in uh you know Neville would
just say what things were in Europe and
everybody that came after him in Holland
kind of obscured things
and one of the things I want to like
Matt and I did like a kind of a two-part
thing on the history of uh of seed banks
and when we got to Canada we realized we
didn't know enough about the internal
Dynamics to like talk intelligently
about it but I definitely come from that
era where like say looking at like Mark
Emery's magazine you know you would open
those up and you would see those
catalogs and you would see all the
traditional Amsterdam stuff that they
brought over and were reselling but then
you know there would be
um you know there would be all these
five or six different new Canadian
companies
I like
yeah a lot of the stuff that came over
from this from Holland then after I I
know some of the guys that were doing
all the moving of the seeds over Yeah
Yeah by Mark and you can guarantee that
a lot of those genetics are not what it
says on the package uh when it comes to
the Dutch when it comes to all this
imported Dutch stuff back in those days
um but as far as the Canadian uh
homegrown companies um they're that was
pretty much straight up and pretty
honest
um yeah and because people were doing
their own thing there was guys in the
Kootenays there's the mighty might boys
uh Vancouver Island Seed Company and a
few of the others that they were giving
you what it says on the package um but
not so much with the Dutch stuff the
Dutch would even joke sometimes when
they're selling to Canadians in bulk
that they just go to the back room and
they have their Indica bucket and their
sativa bucket and they come out I've
told people this for years yeah people
don't believe me when I say this they
really did like they're like What's
closer to Jack Herer uh there's Stone
case yeah there's a [ __ ] close enough
they won't know yeah yeah that's enough
they won't know yeah
that's it is it really is how it went or
just you know like somebody like we've
heard people talk about how like Mark
Emery would get quarters for seeds and
have run out of the particular thing
that they had requested but he still
wanted to make the money so he's like oh
this is close enough
yeah he'll buy it off one of the local
guys and then uh and then repackage it
yeah yeah
yeah that's pretty typical I was never
back in those days Mark Emery never had
anything in original packaging because
everything was smuggled and none of us
seed breeders were organized enough to
to make packaging and you're right yeah
it's a risky thing to do back then it
was yeah you got the new shop that would
you know
packaging in your house for proof you
know that's bad you get caught a lot of
people my age would get those magazines
and would literally pour over every
single blurb about each of the seeds and
create lists of dreams that you wanted
because it it was kind of like
pre-internet or very early internet as
far as forums go and so information was
limited and so when the Canadian seed
breeders kind of came on the scene at
least as far as access for Americans all
of a sudden there was this plethora of
new stuff
you know that like you were like oh what
about this or what about that or on some
of this
and uh you know yeah
purple stuff coming from Canada too
because I was a purple fiend and I
remember Federation Next Generation
Um there was one great white Seed Co
maybe a great North that had a lethal
purple or something yeah that's all
kinds
yeah white Grizzly they did a few of the
cootie breeders yeah yeah there's one
guy from um the Kootenays that used to
work with Steve uh he goes by kootene Og
on Instagram I want to give him a shout
out he was great man he's a great dude
yeah I mean you know Matt there's even
rumors I don't know if I believe them or
not but there's a story in in Mendocino
in my area that some of the early
purples that came over and became famous
in my neck of the woods had some
Canadian Origins to them yeah I've never
been able to verify if that was true
um but some of that purple skunk some of
those purples especially some of the
stuff that was growing up there in BC
indoor scene stuff like that there are
there are some old rumors of Origins
um and that's one of the reasons why the
stories have never come out about like
which person in Humboldt or Mendo or
whatever actually made it because it
kind of came down from Canada
um you know before Osama Bin Laden
ruined flying
yeah because there was a big difference
one of the things I was thinking about
when uh Jay was talking was that just I
mean obviously we're all we're North
Americans right so you've got the
Canadian side and the and the American
side and there's these two big weed
cultures but they have differences but
there's this Border in between
and sometimes the Canadians aren't very
friendly with letting in certain
Americans depending on their past you
know and vice versa and uh and you know
and then but it was more porous in the
90s and then after the terrorist attacks
happened they really tightened up the
Border
yeah and they really made it more
difficult for interaction you know
especially that yeah five or two years
after it happened
see you know even mailing seed or
getting over the Border or exchange of
plant matter or what have you uh became
a lot dicier than it was before
you know uh before we had a lot of a lot
of problems yeah
yeah I mean before they were kind of
worried about Mexico
but they weren't really worried about
Canada
so Canada the Border was kind of like ah
you know it's Americans and Canadians
are just crossing and then they took it
a little bit more serious because they
got worried about people using that like
porous nature to get in and it made weed
it made the weed game a little different
I think well I remember
I remember uh when uh back in John
Walters was the drug czar right before 9
11 or right around then uh but actually
it was before that it was still in the
late 90s um and Mark Emery had been
getting busted over and over again and
he loved being in the media he was on
CNN news and our hot springs all the
time and and we get raided all the time
and I remember one year after a second
or third bust
um
they came in and the drug czar said
we're taking down these Canadian
seed cartels they call them seed cartels
and all the seed cartels in Canada are
the equivalent to Narco terrorists every
seed they sell is a thousand dollars
worth of marijuana on the American
Street
and I remember Mark Emery he held a huge
party when uh he when we got called
Narco narco-terrorists oh my God and he
Mark Emery took that as a great
compliment and he threw one of the
biggest parties we ever had oh my God
you know I probably would do the same I
probably would do the same but it would
I would regret it but I probably would
have done the same like in that area
just I mean there's a reason there's a
reason why a lot of the old-timers who
are free
um you know chose silence and secrecy
yeah because you know being invisible is
a real superpower
you know uh once they Shine the Light on
you it's pretty bright
yeah and a lot of the old Growers like
uh G-Man they're from Vancouver Island
Seed cup a lot of these guys too they
started back in the 80s where you could
do serious time uh oh yeah and we have
yeah and they unlock more other things
to lose as well businesses and family so
they were just used to not
even still just they still don't talk
about it yeah
that's how you're conditioned so
do you have more on your list Matt that
we kind of got sidetracked or whatever
but maybe we could tangent back to it
and you could ask Celestial Temple
sativa
ah yes that was that was very nice it
was very um supposedly the rumor was it
was seeds from Ecuador
um very nice we crossed that when we
first released that it was a a
grapefruit F4 male
in Federation we use that as the male
that pollinated this Equity
extremely nice strain um
it was lost it ended up in one of my
collections that uh ended up being lost
in a in a divorce
yeah I lost half my seat collection uh
in the divorce and that was one of the
strains I lost
um but yeah very very nice straight if
anybody still has genetics of that
kicking around that would be very uh
we'll put our ears out
yeah
we have a Long Reach with the show like
you like we were just talking about
early Pearl the other day and someone's
like yeah I got f2s F6 yeah you know but
and they're legit ones so that's it's
kind of neat how that works
um
BC Kush
yeah um I'm not exactly sure where that
came from it came from um uh the Asian
community in Vancouver when I got the
the cut and there's rumors that it was a
big bud but it was just so extremely uh
I know the best way to
that's why it's like creamy a creamy
creamy smooth flavor it would get you
nice and high but not a confusing eye I
considered it for myself daytime smoke
sure like I could still function I can
still do math I can still drive it
sounds like it sounds like a girl type
High
yeah yeah and in a way actually but um
yeah but it was nice and round and
bulbous was it super dense too like Mega
dense yes yes very dense
very dense but not not the stinkiest
drain drawing that's why a lot of the
Asian production Growers liked it
because it would get very huge and not
stink out the whole neighborhood like a
lot of the other varieties not be a big
red flag
yeah this is back today have a really
hard time accepting that a lot that a
lot of old famous things uh to use a
term that's very common today weren't
very terpy
that low smell low odor was actually a
big benefit
um because you definitely didn't want to
pull up to your spot and get out of your
car and smell it before you went into
the building so people used to think of
low odor and and you know low terpenes
or whatever as sometimes a benefit
you know a lot of the production growers
in the city yes that's exactly right for
the if you're a production grower in the
city uh growing something for export but
most of the good old boys living in the
country
we wanted the Turks we wanted the flavor
um yeah yeah and another part of it too
is that you know if you got a big
yielding resinous thick dense thing that
smelled like nothing you could safely
cross that to something much terpier and
hope that those terpenes crossed over
and would show up because they it
wouldn't have any Terps to interfere so
you were looking for like the resin and
the density and the production and
hoping that the effect and the flavor
came over from the other side of the
thing
that's exactly what we did with our
Romulan we used when we made the Romulan
BC cushcross used the male from their
Romulan and a lot of Lent a lot of the
potency uh and a lot of the smell but it
kept with that BC Kush size
um
yeah very very nice way to that was a
nice cross I still I still produce it
but I don't have the original BC Kush
cut anymore but that's yeah I still
produce a version of it so
that's cool that you've you've found a
way to keep your lines going even when
stuff gets lost you know your lines well
enough to be able to work them to get
them back to where you feel comfortable
saying this represents that line well
enough to be that line that's that's
right yeah there's still a few few
varieties I'd like to to get back but
haven't been able to
um
but uh what which ones yeah which ones
uh my Bonkers definitely my Bonkers
strain what was that one it was my it
was
it was one of the first trains I read on
a large scale Outdoors on Vancouver
Island and it was across uh the first
mail I used was a Burmese grapefruit
okay and that was the video and the
female was from uh
some growers in uh the Prairies of
Manitoba it was a purple [ __ ] it
was called crossed with uh uh early
sativa which is basically a very fast
version of the Durban that was is that
what early sativa was
one
maybe it was an actual Burger but that's
what it actually was and it was very
very lethal leafy just like yes
[ __ ] and the purple [ __ ]
um it was always grown from seed because
you couldn't keep it cut
the resonance on that between the
Burmese and the Resonance of the purple
[ __ ] uh it was just astounding
the the leaves even the fan leaves had
Crystal right out to the airs so when I
first made the first four-way cross and
I grew a massive crop on Vancouver
Island outdoors in one of the wettest
parts of the island and the buds only
they came out the size of footballs that
top Buds and even the smaller buds at
the bottom was the size of a pop cat
and uh
but just the production was just massive
but the first few years it was kind of
Airy yeah from the [ __ ] and the
early sativa and I grew in a wet part of
the island so I that first year I lost
about half of my crop to mold it was all
seated so I I selected uh my best seeds
and after about the third or fourth
generation of breeding that
into itself outdoors I was in the
wettest and wettest of years I was still
90 of plants had not a drop of botritis
or mold on them oh wow just from going
through the first few years of just
calling out those traits
um yeah
and it became really well known around
Canada anyway for the amount of resin
and the terpene level was through the
roof uh so a lot of people would use it
to make hash uh things like that and I
that's one strain I did lose as well
that I've had I've had customers come to
me and send me seeds say oh yeah I still
make your Bonkers so so they send me
some I try it out it's not like not not
like not like it was and I yeah the only
people that I know that actually have
scenes have been put away is uh Ari in a
greenhouse oh and yeah good luck on that
getting them back well my my business
partner is actually pretty decent
friends with them but he already is like
well I don't have I have so many seeds I
don't have time to go digging through
that or send an employee it's Lorien has
such a large catalog I can't even
imagine and when I first moved to
Holland and I get a seed trade with them
uh actually with Milo from uh who made
the cheese so I traded yeah yeah
with for the cheese and then Milo didn't
have uh time he ended up just giving
them to Ari and putting them in his
vault oh wow so that's the only place
that I know for sure that there's a good
uh
a good generation of it there stayed
away stored away so
man I'd love to know what's actually in
his vault and what it actually is you
know like some of that early early
silver Pearl stuff and early Pearl and
early girl get my hands on it yeah
basically every old original person I
would love to know what they still have
and what what their little seed Vault
contains yeah um because everyone claims
they have ever not everyone many people
claim they have everything unchanged
from the beginning and obviously as we
all know the truth is a bit different
than that
um but pockets of stuff exist and some
people are very generous and some people
are like I have it and you don't and
it's sitting there until I decide to do
something with it
well the one Dutch company that I have a
lot respect a lot of respect for
yourself The Flying Dutchman
um I'm not sure uh Eddie
I'm not I forget his name but I've tried
a lot of his genetic back in the day and
uh in Holland itself and in Europe he's
got an extremely good reputation he's a
few coffee shops where you can go and
get the real strategy but yes this is
the the real Master Kush from you know
1983 or whenever it was and it's got the
original Proper Cuts
um
is now just
okay
pot of gold and The Real McCoy from from
them you know uh we found multiple
really nice versions in those things
um so yeah there was a time when uh I
liked the Flying Dutchman quite a bit
yeah I like vegetative
yeah they were uh the original skunk
cage crosses
yeah and that's what my haze that I use
in my grapefruit Haze cross my Romulan
Haze is from that over 20 years ago yeah
oh wow the Flying Dutchman scum case
um your grapefruit Haze made it down to
Southern California down to San Diego
and um mid-2000s it was it got pretty
big down there here guys great three
days yeah yeah right closer to the
2010 probably actually when I started
seeing it at collectors but it got big
down there it was pretty cool
um cotton candy
cotton candy every you know that's a
special um well cotton candy Federation
that was basically it's an F2 uh sweet
tooth
okay sweet tooth blueberry
sweet Juice blueberry
yep and then back
yeah into the Sweet Tooth again so and
you said it was sweet tooth number two
specifically I if I remember correctly
yes okay
yeah we have for 25 years ago but
yeah right Hawaiian sativa I think we
went over that a little bit right yeah
that was from um that was from Vancouver
Island Seed Company yeah yeah it
actually had I believe
I believe that was an F3 back cross when
we when we released it so probably 80
something percent Hawaiian sativa yeah
an old Afghan I mean
um and that's another I do have a
Hawaiian sativa now it's not quite like
the original back then
um I wish I had something a little
closer but uh
yeah reproduce those buddy just
reproduced those I'm sure he'd be happy
to send you some of the reproduction up
and see if it's anything like the
original
yeah yeah actually for man was saying
the same thing because brieferman's down
in Jamaica right now and he's he's
trying to bring back uh the old Lamb's
breath and he's testing out all these
other sativa varieties in Jamaica and
when I was chatting with him the other
day he mentioned uh that he had some of
these old client sativas as well
are we talking about old reefer man or
new reefer man
um
I didn't know there was yes CS
oh yes yep that's okay okay
yeah yeah that someone else owns a
company now so he okay I think it's
maybe a family member up in Canada yeah
yeah
I'm not sure yeah
um uh Island sweet skunk
um that's still one of my best sellers
um yeah I bet that's a good one it's uh
you know I've had that one from day one
that was the sweet skunk number four
from spice of life
that first year when Steve made the uh
sweet skunk there was about three or
four different cuts that he selected
that went around for a few years and
this was the most sativa phenotype out
of all of them okay Captain started
working with uh
yeah it's still one of my favorites
still one of my best yielding strains as
well
but uh
would you consider it hazy
yes in flavor yes yeah
definitely a real lemony
hazy like similarities to some of the
super silver hazes even yeah yeah or the
Jacksonville mirrors yeah
that makes sense and we've heard that
we've heard that it's like uh it's based
on nl5 Haze but I mean we hear different
things from different Canadians that's
one of the rumors
um and you'd have to ask uh Steve or uh
uh uh red uh yeah yeah
you would probably know a little bit
more than me about the exact background
of it
received one of the Clones uh in 96 so
sure exactly wake up but yeah I heard
also heard that the rumor that's NL
Hayes
so there's lots of good stuff that came
from nl5 Haze and it just made me
mention that too because when you said
it was like one of the haze when it's
one of the most sativa ones and it
tasted a lot very similar to those
things you know it doesn't mean it's
true but it like it definitely lends
some some points to it maybe
yeah and one thing I kind of wanted to
mention just real quick because I think
it's interesting is
you know we I was talking about the line
between Canada and America obviously but
as America starts to legalize in all
these different states especially like
on the east coast and the and the you
know New England and New York and some
of these areas that are a lot wetter
they keep trying to import California
bread strains which got developed in a
very arid climate and I've always
thought that people north of the Border
will probably have genetics like when
you were talking about like oh I was
growing on the rainiest ass part of this
island and we were breeding for it and
by three or four years in we got some
stuff that was resistant
um you know in the west coast we don't
have very much of that because it never
rains in summer
Oregon State or Washington State yeah
yeah but in California I mean but in you
know places like New York and on the
East Coast where summer is very humid
they're probably going to end up wanting
to breed in Canadian work
into their stuff
because a lot of that stuff will have
resistances
definitely uh my uh a colleague of mine
here that runs that Golden Hat Seed
Company
um he's originally from Oregon Mr Ron
Harrington and he uh this last summer
did a massive grow out with a bunch of
uh American Auto flowers
okay right next to some of mine and some
of his and he said most of the American
red ones that were from California or
Colorado or a few of these other places
he said they just were inundated with
moles and botritis yeah Meanwhile my
varieties of autoflowers were you said
not a drop of mold on them
um and that goes back to yeah it picks
up those traits after years of selecting
um
because if you have to
nobody wants to lose 50 to 75 percent of
their crop to rot so you start breeding
with the ones that survived it and like
I said my third fourth generation you
get to a point where you don't have a
speck of it
yeah exactly it's hard in California to
breed for those traits because it
doesn't rain in summer
so you don't have humidity
yeah
I noticed that too I lived for uh for
nine years I lived in Spain and it's a
similar latitude as Northern California
around San Francisco except in Spain the
difference is they have really high
humidity
um so a lot of my varieties did really
well there uh yeah it was really neat to
grow uh my strains down at a completely
different climate but all everywhere
I've grown long term has been very humid
uh because the coast of Valencia there
where I lived it's it's regularly 70 80
humidity uh and 35 degrees outside
Celsius right so uh
yeah right now where I'm living in uh
Alberta Canada it's very dry so this is
probably the driest climate I've grown
in yeah in my whole 25 years of growing
um and I I miss I miss growing in a
human climate sometimes it's hard for me
to get my rooms up past over past uh 40
humidity in my indoor grow rooms and it
it's really hard to dry and you cure
your butt here in this climate as well
yeah I I have good friends in Colorado
who have similar dryness issues and and
keeping their dry rooms moist enough for
long enough so you get that slow dry you
know um and your weed doesn't turn into
dust
um dryness is a huge a huge positive in
my opinion once you get late into flower
but when you're early in veg I think
more humidity is actually helpful to get
small plants to vigorously grow because
they don't dry out and crisp
definitely that my if my uh bedroom goes
up in humidity I I don't worry about it
at all
um yeah but in the flower room the dryer
I can get it the better
yeah
all right UBC chemo back to the list oh
yeah like UBC chemo I don't know
anything about chemo
I I grew it for a few years I ended up
dropping it uh I just was never
impressed with it it
some people loved it uh I thought it was
a way overrated
yeah a lot of brown hair no resin
just not I'm not particularly fond of
that earthy flavor of strain it's not
something I like myself I like the spicy
or the fruity strains
it was just very dull tasting to me so
after I started Next Generation
Um I didn't that was one of the Clones I
dropped yeah so there's other people
that would know more than me about that
one
um how about uh time warp
um very very underrated uh very
impressive strain okay very underrated I
think I have a jar left here actually I
was smoking something nice
um what's it taste like and smell like
what's the the Turkey um
slightly Piney a little like a floral uh
perfumey in some ways okay yeah
um and I think one of the reasons that
it stuck around for so long on in in
British Columbia was uh it's one of
those strains that
uh you can store for long periods and
it'll keep its flavor it doesn't leave
the uh lose the terpenes so it's when
everybody's harvesting in September and
October the prices obviously go down for
when you're selling your weed so Time
Warp is one of those you can dry it pop
it in the freezer and six months later
or next summer when it's dry you can
pull it out and it'll sell smells just
as fresh as the day you put it in wow
and that's a good good trait that is
very good yeah and it was just really
nice to smoke right I know it wasn't the
strongest
straight but I would guesstimate because
we never did test back then I would
guess around eight
17 to 20 somewhere in there okay what
percentage uh hitting 20 might be a
little hard but yeah in that in that
zone
um yeah and I actually I'm bringing that
one back because I lost that's not I
lost that original cut as well
um supposedly it's still out there but I
had lots of F5 and F6 uh crosses that I
had so like in the last few years I've
been doing selecting
to get it back to uh close to the
original and so now I have two different
versions of it I have uh the one that's
very similar to the original
and I have one that is similar to the
original but a lot larger and what's
what are they called
uh well just Time Warp and Time Warp XL
okay basically and uh the XL should be
on our website in a few weeks oh awesome
uh the original will be ready just in
time for spring
uh hopefully by by April we'll have the
the original time mark back
that's pretty cool
I've always wanted to try it but I
noticed like whenever whenever I was
young and I was buying um like outdoor
strains trying to grow them indoor it
was it was actually harder to bring
outdoor strains indoor for me you know
like I would always hurt them unless
unless I started like keeping a clone of
one and running it several Generations
as it acclimates it stops that you know
but like it took a while to learn that
stuff you know yeah and the time we're
cutting is one of those strains that uh
would never do get indoors very very
stringy the uh the branches could not
hold up The Vibes
um
and it's meant for it was bred Outdoors
it's meant indoors it just did not yeah
it was not impressive at all indoors
yeah some plants just don't translate
it's it's really weird I know not so has
a lot of experience with that too you
know indoor to outdoor strains yeah I
mean I definitely have seen a lot of
very stable stuff outside that panics
and Herms when you bring it inside yeah
um I've done a bunch of experimenting
and side by sides because I've grown a
lot of the same strains for a long time
uh I think that plants use different
spectrums of light for different
processes and when you put them outside
in the sun they just get like the whole
Cornucopia of anything they could want
from light is right there for them to
pull and if you look at the spectral
charts of any kind of lamp you might use
indoors they're very very narrow
compared to the Sun
and so I tend to believe that there are
certain things that like the sun
you know
um you know and and you just don't get
unless you blend a bunch of different
types of Lights in the same indoor
um you just don't you just it's really
hard to approximate that and some plants
are super sensitive to light
uh and you know and UV and and all that
different types of stuff and so I can't
say it for certain
um but you know I would agree with that
I would definitely agree with that
you know I mean I I have plants that are
very old now and I think sometimes
they're very finicky inside and I can
struggle with them a little bit but if I
put them in a greenhouse they're a champ
every time without fail they just rock
that's how the time work was yeah
and I just distribute that to like you
know the sun is about is the best light
so definitely
it's interesting in that regard what
about Pine berries
primary um
very nice strain um
I'd much um it was it was about very
popular straight outdoors in Canada uh
back in the day and I bet a lot of that
got sold down south as beasters
um I'm sure but it was the beautiful
little like golf golf ball sized buds uh
and just prolific easy to trim very very
branchy uh it would usually finish I
always harvest the planting stages when
we get fields of It Outdoors you'd go uh
probably the first or probably the
second week of September you'd go cut
all the tops the top foot top colas and
then you'd wait another two weeks and
then the bottoms were just Affiliated to
get big and you can do that almost three
harvests off the same plant and just
work your way down as as it thickened up
that's awesome it was another one that
was very mold resistant you could put in
in the rain and it can take it
and uh I know a lot of guys sold it as
indoors it looks so nice in a bag people
would pass it off as indoors when oh
yeah and you knew you go oh that's
obviously outdoor or Greenhouse but you
know a lot of the part of the public
didn't know that so it was nice enough
to fly under the radar yeah that's very
common I mean especially the first
second and third Cut Thing uh for even
my area outdoor Growers and stuff that
had limited dry space something that you
could cut in waves and you could fill
your drawing room and then by the time
you were empty it you could take another
round and then by the time you emptied
it you could take the third round that
was very beneficial
um because space was a premium and you
could you could much easier grow more
than you could process most most
definitely for us to uh you know the
whole month of September and halfway
into October was basically a month and a
half of harvest every two days you'd go
out to the bush
you harvest what you can you watch for
any problems and if it's still sunny out
you leave what you can and then it was
every second day you do the truck drive
and yeah it was uh a lot of that too you
hang up the pine Berry and then get it
down for a week it's dry enough you got
to fill up the room and then we just
pack it away in a room to trim later
because you rarely had enough time to uh
to trim it as it came in
so I'm sure
I I missed those old days
yeah I do too to be honest with you my
old days are different than your old
days obviously I'm like the generation
under but even then still like the the
for Californians like the Heyday prop
215 was was like
you know we had a pretty good I think
better than we had it for a long time
for a lot of people you know the reason
why indoor is King is you are able to
grow indoor in more places than you were
able to grow outdoor both from like a a
place where outdoor was you know would
do well and you could get away with it
and and not get in big trouble you know
indoor you could have a garage or a
bedroom or a warehouse and it was safe
from prying eyes outdoor yeah you kind
of had to be somewhere semi-permissible
or at least where the cat and mouse game
could get played yeah
um yeah so very rural very rural uh
places you have to be you have to be an
Outdoorsman
up here in Canada to do it so
what do you know about the Ortega clone
that went around Canada anything
um actually I've never worked with that
one I can't really tell you much to info
on that one yeah I wasn't sure that
that's just one of those ones that I
hear about
um there's an Iranian that went around
in Canada I think
Auto yeah I believe that's that's more
in Eastern Canada
Quebec just like the M39 those trades
more of a Quebec thing gotcha uh Pink
Kush
did you purchase
I've never worked with that one
um reefer man would be the professional
on that one yeah you did a lot of work
with it so I've never I never really
worked with it myself
okay my next list goes on into the Next
Generation era the most important era
for your would you say it's the most
important arrow for your your work and
the stuff you're most proud of
oh yes um Federation was just my first
year and a half in the business
almost 26 years now doing next
generation
so yeah that's even to this day I I have
a lot of the old strains I picked up I
still stayed with a lot of my old
strains I keep trying to perfect them
start bringing on everything new yes
that you know the popular strain of the
year I admire that a lot and that's it
really impresses me I'm not really
interested in other breeders work
yeah
and keep working on my own stuff making
it better so I mean in the American
market today uh people that do that are
probably like two percent yeah like 98
is probably one-off hybrids that they
make and then they sell and then they
move on and each drop that they do is a
unique you know breeding or reversals or
whatever the first time working with any
of these moms yeah and it's very rare to
have people that just like these are my
favorites this is what I like these are
the traits I'm looking for and I'm gonna
keep working these lines towards what I
enjoy
yeah that's that's exactly how I do a
lot of my varieties it's just once I
know what I'm looking for I'm just
trying to stabilize certain traits
with a lot of the varieties so yeah and
I a lot of people keep offering me and I
do obviously do do uh some one-off
coupons and cutting some other varieties
so right now I have a really nice Larry
OG I've got sure my death Bubba and a
few other strains and I just I bring
into it and do make some one-off crosses
but they're not the they're not the
strains like I treat like my children
um the other there's part of my catalog
that you know been a part of my life for
25 years so I can I can tell you exactly
how they do in different climates and
what to feed them what not to feed them
and uh
so but yeah
I'm sorry good
um I was going to ask you have you seen
the pink Death Star up there by any
chance
pink death star Pink Death Star
no I can't say I have yeah it's one it's
one that keeps going around up there and
I've wanted someone that has interaction
with it to describe it to me I've almost
had people get it over here but never
makes it yeah it's just one that I can
talk about well I know more stuff about
the genetics and what happened on back
in the old days in the late 90s to 2000s
because I left Canada in 2008. okay and
I moved back only in
2017. oh wow almost a 10-year Gap where
I don't really like kind of out of touch
with what happened during that 10 years
sure when I came back here five years
ago
um
I kind of just get set up my warehouse
and I started doing my own uh my own
varieties again and I mixed less with
what's going on in the in the local
community than I than I used to
where did you go during those years and
were you still breeding and selling
seeds
oh yes I was reading in Spanish oh yeah
I was making a lot of seeds in Spain
Amsterdam for six months that was too
expensive to live there so I moved down
to Spain and yeah had a few different uh
breeding operations down there and I
produced a lot of seeds for uh a lot of
Moroccan farmers and I actually forgot
Farmers as well there's a lot of the
Dutch guys uh
they would Farm out their seed making to
a Spanish first so yeah yeah
the influencia profits and the loan
where I lived I know a bunch of the big
seed producers uh they're all personal
friends of mine that produce for sweet
seeds pyramid seeds uh for green every
other street over there it comes from
the same farmers and the Dutch Dutch
Growers too it was too expensive to grow
up so they would just come meet a
Spanish guy or somebody like me living
in Spain and uh needs for them they
bring us yeah they bring us the cones
and say okay here you go we'll buy them
off you for a bucket seat
uh just make them for us so a lot of the
Dutch companies don't even make their
own stuff anymore oh yeah that's been
going on for a long time too since 2000
really yeah I mean I believe in 99 or
2000 they change the law in Amsterdam
there was a loophole or in in the
Netherlands I should say where you could
grow legally cannabis seeds and they
couldn't mess with you
um and I think they closed that loophole
and then a bunch of the famous seed
companies got raided or busted or
whatever and I think that was one of the
big reasons that the exit has happened
um and it also secretly seems to be when
they started farming out the actual seed
production to third parties and not
doing it in-house anymore but just not
mentioning that it was all third parties
producing their seat
yeah and a lot of the Dutch guys you
know you're living in Holland uh
wouldn't you rather live in Spain where
it's nice and sunny
uh all year round so a lot of them are
hired to to Spain so a lot of them did
bring the genetics down there and they
have their network of friends and
Growers
and you know a couple buddies it seems
like Spain and Switzerland
first you know reader reader Steve went
to Switzerland shauncey went to
Switzerland some other people went Swiss
for a bit was there Scott was there yep
yep all that and then some people went
to Spain and vice versa and that kind of
became like the new places in Europe
um one thing this is totally random but
I don't want to lose it before before we
do is that
um maybe you could talk for a second
when you were in Spain about like how
much Moroccan do you think is still
actual land race Moroccan and how much
is imported Spanish work grown in
Morocco so yeah actually I know quite a
bit about that because I went to Morocco
several times quite quite a few times
with a lot of big uh I had some Spanish
friends that were big house Smugglers
and some of them with it had Grow shops
and they were seed breeders in Spain I
would go Supply Spain or Supply Morocco
with seeds but uh when the first time I
went there to meet some of the farmers
in the mountains and in ketama uh I went
there looking for that old school
Moroccan sure uh the real Brown the
stuff they made
yeah they made the key for it but by the
time I went there it would have been
around 2009 2010 they had our at that
period they had already switched over to
mostly Pakistani genetics
interesting there were very few Farmers
that were still doing the old school
Moroccan uh strains that had that nice
Dusty flavor more like the kind of more
resembled a lot of the Lebanese stuff
actually yeah think about it and uh but
a lot redder hash like the pakistanis
would yield double or triple
and so
but they uh at that point they still
weren't cutting the males they were just
starting to learn to go out oh wow
and and if you did if you were a grower
who did it cut all your mails well your
neighbor's mail Paul is still going to
fold in yeah but but even with a bit of
that floating in you're gonna it's gonna
be substantially less yeah
yeah when we went started going down
there
to Morocco a lot of the big guys that
were the big sellers in the region for
the local hush farmers were starting to
clue in that if we started
bringing buying the Spanish femini seeds
um they would up their heels they
wouldn't have all these males and they
would get a lot more hash so they
started a reporting a lot of from Spain
a lot of the super silver haze and
critical uh plus so
so many of the farmers there started
switching to buying feminized seeds and
a lot of the US farmers in Spain when we
had extra seeds we knew that every year
the Moroccan buyers would be up in Spain
and they would buy seeds by the million
yeah and then they would distribute it
to their farmers and stop the quality
and yields uh so yeah they switched I
would say with the last five years it's
mostly Spanish
varieties well which is based on Dutch
stuff we wanted the critical and soap
case and uh and I've actually been
running quite a bit of contact lately in
the last two years with a big rock and
uh guy down there and they're really
looking to develop strains now that are
more drought resistant
there's a lot of interesting a lot of
the varieties from Spain were not draw
resistant they used so much more water
yeah and uh so a lot of the farmers
there now are putting in drip lines even
back when I was there the farm that we
went to they already had to drip lines
my Spanish friend who uh was the buyer
of all their hash he brought down it two
Vans full of drip lines uh to this farm
for these guys and they were doing a
really good job
of it yeah
but yeah they're really the guy that I'm
talking to now uh he's on the other side
of the mountain he's not up in the
mountains in katama he's down in he's
got a research place about 10 acres and
they're trying to develop the drought
resistant varieties oh wow I've been
talking to him about it and he's asking
me which varieties of mine are the most
drought resistant so they're going to be
working with some of my varieties doing
some selective reading down in this area
it makes sense they go from very drought
resistant varieties that probably were
low lower yielding because they're
because they could survive in an arid
climate and they weren't really getting
as much inputs as they needed but they
would live to these bigger yielding uh
Dutch things that drought resistance
isn't a problem when you're in Holland
indoor and you're just getting fed with
Rockwell all the time so they weren't
breeding for that and so they get these
bigger yielding plants but they're
thirsty
and then they realize they don't have
enough water
you know that's an interesting education
area
I never did find find any of the
original Moroccan uh I had the
the guys that I knew there I'd ask them
about is there any Farmers still growing
this original variety and I had them
looking for me because I wanted to get
my hands on the seed sure um and I had
any luck what's a shame about that is
you would think that the critical plus
you were talking about and the super
silver haze and some of that those
obviously like some of that original
Moroccan would be prime breeding
candidates to try to mix into those
lines and to find ones that are drought
resistant and acclimated but yield more
yeah that's that's definitely right
that'd be the way to do it
yeah too bad you know I didn't mention
it but like when you were talking about
uh reeferment being down in Jamaica
Jamaica has a similar thing in that most
of the original Jamaican lines are
basically it seems like almost
completely gone and they've been
replaced by Dutch genetics
um that were shorter and faster and
bigger yielding and easier and maybe
better names for them
um and so it's it's you know it's the
way nature works or whatever but you
know a lot of these land races have been
displaced
well that's one thing that I know reefer
man is doing right now in Jamaica with
the plot of land that he's working on
he's trying to bring back a lot of those
old varieties because he has pretty
extensive collection and I know he's
been working on bringing back the old
Jamaican lands breath with uh his uh
Rastafarian Collective there I believe
he's working with
trying to bring back the old one so if
anyone can do it he can do it
I've I've often thought too that like
some of the places like in Afghanistan
and Pakistan that have so many of their
original varieties it's probably because
it's been at War for 25 years and it's
been pretty dangerous for westerners
especially you know white Christians or
something like that to go into those
Hills
um and so as a result of that they
really haven't gotten Super Silver Haze
or critical mass or this or that or
Dutch hybrids because it's not easy to
go there
you know yeah that's not it's bad you
know definitely a little more secluded
those genetics haven't been polluted yet
so
interesting maybe someday I'll have to
grow a grow a beard and go there oh all
right
yeah I know we can go I'll grow a beer
and go they're all incognito
um so let's talk about let's see Diablo
that's that's a real popular next
generation one that I remember yeah it
was very uh popular
um that's another one I've lost but that
was basically my Avalon uh across with
that early sativa as well
yeah very cool
yeah I know there's a lot of growers in
the Midwest in Minnesota Michigan uh you
know across Nebraska Kentucky back in
those days I just loved and raved that
bucket Diablo because it was one of the
strains uh when it was in veg it grew
like a sativa and extremely fast but the
second it tripped into flower
um it would flower fast uh whether it
was indoors or Outdoors indoors it was
about a six flowering period but it
didn't give the Quality quality buds
indoors Outdoors it was just amazing so
in a shorter climate you could you could
veg you can get a large size plant and
when it flipped it flipped hard and fast
that was one of uh yeah it was very nice
trade our buddy rings that was his
favorite
he has a bunch of pictures of it just
Mass just like 14 foot plants out in
Mendo wow yeah
um your Afghani Kush
which hash plant did you use in that
uh The Afghani Kush it was an Afghani
hash plant uh in BC back in the day that
was one of the first ones that I used to
read my Avalon strain with but it was
Danny hashback crossed with the BC Kush
actually
okay my uh first uh thing that I strain
that I referred to as the Afghani kush
yeah so that's those are that's the
parentage there
okay uh grapefruit Haze we talked about
this earlier it was going around San
Diego for a while
yeah
um that's like you said the original
grapefruit uh Pink Grapefruit Mercado
Dynamite whatever you want to call it
yeah uh with like you're saying the
Flying Dutchman uh skunk one by Haze
very nice
I've been working with that ever ever
since
um it's now basically is that inbred
line but it was the very it was the
first first variety that I turned into a
into an Autoflower
oh wow doing that as an Autoflower very
very long time now since I've been in
Spain about 10 years and it's the one
that has uh great mold resistance
everybody that grows it here in Canada
has
when it's side by side with another
Autoflower it may not be
as a larger plant uh but it is stinky
and it's no mold
very very cold resistant so
what did you use to um to to make your
plants Autoflower what was your
Autoflower input
it was uh the very first
Rooter Alice Cross I used was of uh
ruderalis big bud
okay that was going around from a grower
friend in Spain who worked a few other
seed companies
uh and that's what I did my first uh
back cross with it was already
uh it was already a semi-stabilized uh
looter Alice big bud it was already
being sold as an Autoflower so that's
what I used as my first back cross
and then yeah once I had four back
crosses into it it was it was stable
it was more more stable
yeah on a few Generations into it now
like I did a lot of a lot more selecting
since I've been back in Canada as well
so
that's cool yeah I've done very little
Autoflower work but I did some with uh
Ernesto from Buddha seeds Spain
um his his uh white dwarf they were they
were dwarf autos auto dwarfs I think he
called them okay
I had a good friend in Spain that made a
bunch of the red dwarfs white drawers
yeah yes
a few of those they couldn't even be my
buddy's Dro that's what they came from
yeah
Ernesto right
uh I think he owned uh yeah yeah
it's like most people over there they
buy their seats yeah yeah exactly yeah
you know this is a little off topic but
maybe not when uh since you decided to
go and move to Europe for 10 years was
it personal reasons was it weather was
it like you felt like it was a business
opportunity over there for seed making
was it a combo
there's a combo of reasons um I I've
always wanted to travel Europe and and
do what back in the day if you wanted to
reach the big leagues in the seed
business you had to move to Europe yeah
so and that mixed with uh the week that
I moved there was also the week Mark
Emery got sentenced to five years in
prison for selling seeds oh that's a
good time and I was I was uh to say they
were looking at me pretty heavy I bet I
just felt it was time to go and leave
for a while yeah before I end up in the
can as well
before you end up yeah
I was more in the background but I was
one of the largest seed producers that
that he had yeah so I figured wow it's
the perfect time to leave uh better get
out while you're ahead
yeah so that that's what I did and uh
anyway did you enjoy laying there
I
almost consider spraying my home uh
living there for nine years when I
travel to Spain it feels like I'm going
home
yeah did you did you speak Spanish
before you moved there did you learn
while you were there
I learned a fair amount of Spanish when
I was there yeah yeah
it's pretty fluent now so is it fairly
affordable compared to like California
that you know very affordable very uh
blind space in Spain if you're living in
the north of Europe it's very expensive
yeah
um
in Canadian or American dollars I
probably paid about 2 500 for a small
apartment with a little Garage in the
back in in Amsterdam
so uh when I got offered the opportunity
to move to Spain
um my rent went down to about 400 and uh
and I had a three-story 14 room hotel
that was that I lived in for 450
so and the cost of living is next to
nothing in Spain oh my God in comparison
to uh yeah yeah
the food is cheap and great uh
nice and polite there yeah the culture's
pretty polite yeah very very different
from what I'm used to I mean the the the
culture one of the things I think is
cool about the culture especially for
people that do a lot of indoor gardening
like we all do is uh they stay up late
um you know it gets it gets hot there
and so it's very common you know you'll
have you'll have playgrounds full of
kids at 10 o'clock at night because
that's when it cools down that's normal
that's totally normal you know eating it
eating at 9 45 at night because that's
when it's cooled down and you start
cooking you know late does it get that
hot there
it gets very hot
like no yeah I love that I I was always
being in Canada when I lived in the
cities I do my watering usually at night
I go out and start working in the grow
room at 10 pm because you knew the
neighbors weren't going to come over
things like that so you go out to the
girl room at 10 p.m you work till two or
three in the morning
um and that was kind of my cycle so when
I moved to Spain it fitted perfectly
yeah that's what I was just thinking I
was like man it really is well suited
for indoor gardeners because it's got
that late night lifestyle like Matt you
trip out you can literally be at a
playground at 11 o'clock at night and it
is full of screaming eight-year-olds and
running around parents hanging out the
swings are full people are like it's so
weird like
yeah they just they right
yeah a lot of the LGBT people don't go
out during the day because it's too hot
that's not too far it makes sense at 10
p.m you'll see all the old ladies on the
street with their canes walking up and
down the street till two in the morning
that's awesome during the summer months
oh it's great it was very I enjoyed
living there and uh I'm still
considering retiring there once I'm
on a personal note my dad wanted to move
the family to Spain in like the 90s
um because he had a bunch of work in
Europe and it was so much closer my mom
wouldn't do it because she didn't want
to learn another language but he was
basically like if we would have moved
there then with the exchange rate what
it was and how cheap real estate was
he's like I probably would have retired
15 years before I did just because of
the way it all worked out
um you know it was so affordable I think
it's changed a little bit but it used to
be incredibly cheap
you know it still is compared to Canada
uh in the U.S uh it's still very cheap
very very cheap so
yeah I can never afford to buy a nice
house here in Canada again but down
there no problem
yeah same in California it's crazy now
it is crazy like where I live in
California Bakersfield it used to be
like one of the last little bastions of
affordable living in California you know
where you could get a house for 250 000
you can't get a tiny house now like a
1200 square foot house or less than half
a million it's it's over you know like
in Spain yeah for 250 000 in Spain you
have a beautiful house with a swimming
pool and a nice view
yeah crazy yeah I mean Matt doesn't even
live in a nut I mean he technically
lives in California but like
it's not technically yeah no I just met
the reason why I said technically is
because when people think of California
they think Coastal and woods or
mountains I live in hell he just lives
in in boiling hot desert dry nasty and
it's still affordable it is still an
affordable now yeah it's crazy
so what what are some of the ones you
want to cover the most from Next
Generation that that our current stock
that you want people to know about the
most well well we brought our Romulan uh
back femini yes awesome yeah it's uh
yeah it's as close as I can get to the
original except that it produces better
than the original
uh produces much better than the
original that's a big good trait for it
yeah yeah I can't say it's not quite as
Piney as yeah as the old one was but
it's it's pretty damn close
so
yeah is that the dominant terpene
profile for um Romulan was Pine yeah
very Pine okay
gotcha just get really the dominant one
definitely
so
so yeah um and I don't know if you've
seen my catalog or a peruse the uh the
website a little bit but I've got a few
new varieties
um I'm bringing back uh old Colombian
red Mexican variety
uh
around the 12
weeks
around 12 weeks though so awesome and a
lot of people that scares off but not me
no even if it was longer I'd rather have
a a nice pure trustworthy Colombian red
light or something didn't worry about
how long it flowers I've also got a
tester room I last year I made a bunch
of uh I crossed my Romulan with a few uh
uh Malawi gold uh land race oh nice and
also with the Rojo Colombian and also
with the Acapulco Gold
so I've got a a nice room right now with
about five weeks into flower right now
I'm doing a big uh grow out and testing
them out but the Malawi's the first
round they were so wild and so sativa
and I didn't find I wasn't quite uh
very impressed with it but I did a few
crosses anyway with a few of the nicest
cats and the romulent crops that I've
done with it are just coming along
phenomenally right now
and it struck me so much and made it
Global indoors because they were just
they were so lanky uh in the first round
that I did so yeah if I do release that
that's that's probably still going to be
a year or two away before I release that
that's what I'm working on right in my
private stuff right now
that's really cool stuff though yeah
Malawi can be really resinous uh I
always have a story like I learned
that some like sativas will not flower
under like normal 12 hours of light with
Malawi that was the plant that I learned
that with after three months of keeping
it under 1212 and zero
sex straight showing up I'm like what is
going on
with the Congolese sativa one time I
grew that out I was at week 16 or 17.
yeah and the bugs were no no bigger than
my little finger yeah and all my friends
were like Jay you're you're an idiot why
you could have pulled off two or three
cops already and meanwhile they're just
pulling down weights and I've got the
six light room that I just I just cut it
and threw in the garbage but yeah but if
you if you don't experiment with those
you don't find the good ones either so
that's very true yeah I have never seen
it like that before
like yeah I noticed that with the
Congolese it was it wouldn't flower it
would take so long to even kick off but
was it from seed
oh yes yes because one of the things
that I learned
um you know with some of the guys that
had run like a bunch of the Neville's
Haze and some of like the that kind of
work in Holland was they told me like if
you take an old clone and you flower it
it's ready to flower because it's been
alive for long enough that it knows it's
it should be blooming but it hasn't
and they said if you get some of these
equatorial sativas going they're very
used to like from seed knowing that they
need to veg for six or seven months
before they even want to think about
flour so they said it can be very
difficult to get an extreme sativa like
that to trigger early
because genetically it just doesn't want
to you know like you can force that you
can force the matter with light cycle
but it's harder because it wants to it's
almost like a pre-puberty you know human
or something like until it hits that
phase it's just not ready
so
yeah yeah
like and it makes sense right like you
have a situation in which it's always 11
13 or 12 12 or something like that near
the equator like a Malawi or a Colombian
or a Panamanian or maybe something like
that and they're just used to Growing
for you know maybe even six seven months
eight months before they bloom and then
they bloom for five
some of them take longer than a year
from seed to finish because there is no
winter
they're terrified of dying under they
don't it doesn't get cold enough to die
that's true yeah if you want to grow
those indoors it's best to keep them
root Bound in a small container in the
corner of the room for six months before
yeah and then pull it back out again
yeah no I brought home some Neville's
Haze and I think it was 98 or 99 right
around then the first year or two it was
released and I was planning on making
all this seed and I set up this room and
I couldn't even get the males to drop
pollen
you know for my like I had a whole room
that was just ended up being head
stashed because it was like you know 20
different plants that I was thinking was
going to make seed and there was no
pollen to make seed and I had to restart
them and put more plants in there with
the same males and wait some more
and I did but I that was in the I didn't
know the tricks of the light cycle to me
when you bloomed everything was 12 12.
that was what the book said that was
what you did I never heard of 11 13 or
10 14 or any weird times like that it
was like you know at the time the level
of knowledge I had it was like 12 12 is
what you do
yeah
so you know learning
yeah what were some of the products that
you what were some of the books that got
you into growing like when you first
started learning to grow were there
books involved or just people
um I was fortunate enough to uh
get clocked down in Vancouver where uh I
learned from other Growers more than
books yeah
um and when when Jorge Cervantes was
making his first books or maybe after
the first books that I knew of anyway
yeah yeah he was he was up in Canada uh
taking photos in my Grow rooms that's so
funny some of the first books that I've
seen were books that I was in yeah so so
yeah I I it was Hands-On Hands-On
learning for me and that's awesome
yeah that's that's really really
interesting not many people can uh say
that they're first place that they were
seeing had their grow room in it
so you have your your blueberry punch
which is which a Romulan blueberry is
that what it is correct very Romulan
male which which Blue Line are you using
um it was uh one that I
the one I'm using now
um my for when I first I was a DJ Short
uh blueberry from the late 90s
and I crushed that with the grapefruit
mail that I was using
um and then back across that it was an
F4 basically F4 blueberry that cross
that I'm using
um with my Romulan mail and that's
basically the one I'm using I'm actually
doing a final hunt of that generation
right now I've got about 40 females
going right now oh nice I'm looking for
a new a fresh blueberry to use yeah
so if I have my main grow room where I
make my seeds and then I have my five
light go room where I've just constantly
just testing and just drawing out things
yeah
yeah yeah I have a blueberry fiend
myself so I understand the hunt for the
perfect blue that's one of my uh
favorite things in life yeah I was a lot
a lot different than what you see as
blueberry on the market these days but
we used to have different
and way different than the Dutch Passion
blueberry is nothing like the blueberry
from back in the day yeah
you know when that passion one is a lot
easier to grow
yeah it looks a lot better nicer in a
bag easier to trim uh but it just have
has no smell it's not that old fruity
smell like the old blueberry had the
Dutch don't seem to care that I noticed
that a lot about some Dutch strains
because they all mixed their weed with
tobacco so for them the flavor
isn't as important they the Dutch breed
bred for a Healthy Growth structure and
buds
they weren't as concerned about the
smell
that makes a lot of sense with the fact
that they were mixing it with tobacco
that they wouldn't have paid as much
attention to that I used to battle with
them about it yeah I bet me too I still
do like that well I mean you know I
would go over there and they would think
I was nuts for smoking pure flour and
not mixing it with a bunch of tobacco
you know or like the most common thing
they would they would do is they would
make a a hashish snake that they would a
thin a thin you know roll of hash and
then they would roll tobacco around that
and make a big spliff and start chiefing
that and so I remember yeah the first
couple cannabis cups in Amsterdam that I
went to I went with a few other
Canadians in Vancouver feedback my
friends there and a few other breeders
and they would make fun of us Canadians
um because we would smoke pure joints
and they're like oh these are the
hardcore drug addicts they're smoking
I don't actually smoke tobacco so I
found it very difficult like especially
in winter when Amsterdam is very cold
and and kind of grimy to be in a coffee
shop with like eight or nine spliffs
going yeah the amount of and the amount
of smoke and the amount of tobacco smoke
and just me just wishing like like these
places need a huge carbon filter right
because yeah it was actually kind of
intense like it's more tobacco than weed
you prissy American I mean they thought
they thought it was they thought we were
nuts for sure as far as the smoking pure
cannabis you know but
um but yeah it uh it's changing over
there
right I have I Matt and I argue about
this but I almost think that like DJ
shorts blue work is so inbred
um that it works best in out crosses no
I agree you know that like it's really
hard I've grown a lot of his work trying
to find like amazing examples of each
line and it's really hard to do for me
to find like the Grail that like looks
good and tastes good and has like
potency to it and isn't a leafy monster
um but it seems to shine when you throw
it on things that aren't it well I I
think and I'm gonna stick by it until
the day I die now and it wasn't from
anything that I did it was it was it was
growing someone else's blueberry work
like
um you know I I at the time when when
this guy uh Lonestar from Texas resin
company when he released his blueberry
work I had released my first blueberry
work so I had no interest in growing his
because I already had the best you know
I was like I got the best mine already
smells like blueberries how much better
could it be well mine was lacking resin
production and it was it was beautiful
it was very purple it looked more like
Oregon purple tie type more loose buds
not dense
um low resin production and just no
recreational potency it had a lot of
medical potency where where nerve pain
and stuff it would dull it it was great
for that but recreational people would
just be like what is this garbage this
isn't getting me high you know but I
thought I had the best one and then I
lost it
um and I had to go through a bunch of
blueberries and the first place I
started looking was Canadian blueberries
because in my experience Canadians that
was that era where people were starting
to capture that super blueberry actual
blueberry smell actual blueberry taste
was in the Canadian blue line so that's
where I started and I ended up going to
this guy lone star's work who I'm not
sure which blueberry line he used but it
seems like at some point near the end he
outcrossed to some sort of Afghani let
the blue breed true the blue Terps and
the blue uh flavors all that breed true
but it doesn't breed like an inbred
plant because of that because of that
one single bat cross I can cross it to
like his line to a blue velvet and not
have too much inbreeding then all you
get is the mutations and the you know
foxtail look with no resin so yeah I'm
pretty staunch on the blueberry needing
an outcross at some point
yeah I've uh yeah I've pretty much
noticed the same thing uh the ones I've
seen and it's yeah and the blueberry
from back in the late 90s early 2000s in
Vancouver there in British Columbia
there was a lot of them and they were
very similar in some ways to uh the
grapefruit
yeah great food there were some
similarities
but if you draw on a batch of the
blueberry seeds
some of DJ shorts crosses with the
blueberries were always better than the
straight blueberry
yeah makes sense what's interesting too
is that I think when he started selling
his seeds first he started at sag Martha
with Tony and then he ended up at Dutch
Passion but he didn't really control
that too much I think it was more like
he sent him a bunch of seed and they
made their own selections and then when
he's when it started getting sold in
Canada it's almost I think he kind of
took control of it again and was sending
seed up there I had no idea what was
going on did DJ go to work it was
available it was available in Canada
before Dutch Passion or anyone in Europe
had it oh really I didn't know that oh
yeah so he was selling first through
Canada
no there was there was clones I've been
going around when I started oh wow yeah
I mean Oregon his where he's from isn't
very far from from you know
Vancouver and stuff yeah
yeah he'd make regular trips into Canada
and I believe he did some work with uh
spice of life
yeah yeah Steve back then yeah Stephen
Ray
had some of uh DJ shorts blueberry that
came straight from him
that makes sense yeah that's wild they
yeah I never really realized that that
the Clones are going up before they were
even released in Europe like the seed
lines are released in Europe the Clones
were going up you gotta remember at the
time that the that sag Martha and those
groups were selling it this is kind of
pre the Canadian seed selling at least
to the public that was easy and well
known
um you know it really was only Holland
am I right like that like Canadian seed
selling happened a little bit later
yeah it actually pretty much would Mark
first started and then Kyle with kind
seed that would have been around
94.
yeah I believe
right right in there at that ball yeah
yeah
I mean I was sharing with Matt before we
did this I have like some we I have some
like uh old cannabis cultures and some
different stuff and we were like looking
over like the Federation list in Mark's
catalog and different stuff you know and
and you know DJ was in there he had his
four things I think it was like blue
velvet Blue Heaven blueberry and flow
maybe something like that yeah yeah
you know and and so he was in there
yeah in the early years of uh of of
those things being advertised you know
there was definitely people selling his
stuff
high dollar high dollar for that for the
era a super high dollar
insane high prices back then
I wish I could still get those prices
wouldn't that be nice too yeah wouldn't
that be nice I remember those prices
just a few years ago I didn't around no
more no that ain't happening
so is there anything else you want to
talk about other than uh what you have
coming up but so anything else you're
really stoked about that you you have
good stock of you want to get out there
um but we have a
nice uh Banner a banner uh grapefruit
crosses okay coming out right now
um one of the other more popular strains
I have I know that's more popular in the
south is uh truffles
I have a black truffles I've crossed at
that Columbian red
oh wow so uh and that will be on the
website probably in a few weeks the the
plants are get due to get cut in about a
week so
so yeah I'm very I'm looking forward to
that I've already did some testers of it
and now I did the batch of seeds of the
Colombian with the truffles the the
Mexican sativa the Colombian Reds coming
up soon as well
that's awesome and and the Romulan is
still one of my yeah I'm so happy with
the one we have right now
um yeah finally released it again so
yeah I've got so many strains right now
it's hard to wrap my head around anyone
in particular yeah I'm stoked to see
ring Romulan back too you know like I
said there's there's been many cases of
many different companies none in
particular that I'm referring to but
many companies coming out claiming that
they have pure Romulan you know or this
Romulan hybrid and you know they're
newer people and probably don't you know
and it's good to see a a reputable
person that you know has good provenance
with this stuff that's worked it for
years that knows it bringing it back
bringing back with the real name and
everything
there's uh the Romulan here in Canada
there's just one going around on the
recreational Market uh in all the stores
that they sell as Romulan and that
actually was Romulan Joe that first
showed me a bag when I went to see him a
few months ago and uh we looked at it we
tried some together and we were like no
this is a Romulan grapefruit cross oh
man I was guaranteed it's a older I'm in
the grapefruit of mine yeah that's going
down it's definitely not the original
and there's also pyramid seeds now in
Spain they've released a Romulan but
it's also but it's a Romulan cross that
I had in Spain that my friend of mine is
making for them so they were selling is
not the Romulan as well but it's it's
got some Romulan genetics in it but yeah
I know other than other Growers that
might have the uh something as close as
me would be Vic High
yeah
yeah yeah he did pass away now but he
had a really good version of it as well
oh yeah a little bit more of a fruitier
version but it was nice it was very nice
yeah
so well that's awesome
um yeah I'm doing gonna be doing a lot
more uh work in the future here in South
America
yeah that's what I heard I'm excited
yeah actually next week I'm going to uh
Chile and to Argentina
again so I'm setting up working with a
few breeders down there with with my
genetics to try it down in their climate
and that's one thing in South America
too especially in Chile they get a lot
of rain
so there's a lot of interest in our mold
resistant Strays down there that's
awesome teaming up with a few breeders
down there and uh
and so we'll see how it goes
well I'm Gonna Keep well keep the
facility in Canada and operation
but uh in Canada with legalization
there's not much money to be made here
anymore yeah it's really really
difficult to make a living
and that the people are just bombarded
with store read there's a store on every
corner
and unless you're a real
grower is really passionate about it
people here don't buy uh buy seeds
anymore and there's so many other Gators
that just flooded the market
yep
I just don't see much of a future myself
for myself in Canada anymore so
I'm gonna probably start making the
transition
yeah over the next for the next few
months or the next year so
it's only a matter of time in my opinion
for the US is is just right behind you
guys and the way that you're seeing it I
think is is really a very realistic and
smart Direction I really really believe
that are you going to be doing any land
race hunting while you're down there
um knock off I'm going to be bringing
some of them my my Colombian and a few
of those trains for people down there to
grow out and test out yeah
but at first when I'm first going to get
established down there with my Flagship
strains like the the Romulan the Island
Suites account the dynamite the time
warp my most popular strain is going to
get established first before I get too
experimental down there yeah yeah right
so
that's one of the things I'll say about
about the Romulan is is as we are as
we're all getting older you know
um
a lot of things for especially for new
smokers and stuff like that they hear
things like nl5 or Romulan or this or
that or whatever and they're famous
names that they know almost nothing else
about
and so Romulan is definitely one that
whether or not you have any access to
the real Romulan or you just have a
hybrid or whatever the name is going to
get used because it's a catchy name it's
stuck it's part of cannabis history now
and it was prevalent enough and popular
enough that young people they want to
try the best things of yesteryear and
there's people out there that want to
give them what they want whether they
have it or not
you know yeah
that's for sure
yeah with my Romulan when I moved back
to Canada
um my partner was like hey just work on
that Romulan everybody asked for it and
I've been working for five years now
before I get to release it because now
I'm confident in what it it is I'm happy
to put my behind it but uh we for years
we got asked to bring the Romulan back
and I guess I'm working on it but I'm
not going to release it until
until I'm you know I'm proud to put my
name behind it so yeah we're finally at
that point now so
you know it's funny I was talking to
your partner and he's like yeah you know
I know a little bit but I was mostly on
the back side you need to talk to Jane
he's like I used to run a seed bank
you've probably never heard of it it was
called kind and I was like oh this one
here's your catalog because I had like a
big collection of old catalogs read out
of his old catalog to him he was stoked
yeah he's a cool guy I like him yeah he
ran uh uh kind seed uh all the shipping
into the business from uh the UK for 17
years he lived there and he became close
personal friends with all the big Dutch
breeders him and Ari and are good
friends and he just knows about shipping
seeds anywhere in the world and he's a
super friendly guy on the phone so nice
25 years so every any customer that
talks to him on the phone he makes them
happy oh I bet yeah he knows how to get
the seeds to uh
yeah that's what it is so that's a skill
yeah yeah yeah
no so yeah I have to interview him
sometime as well because just the uh his
side of the business is to me is just as
important as you know even the breeding
side of the business that there's a lot
of history he knows so much history and
backstories about what went on behind
the scenes who got what when you know
who who got what batch of seeds wed and
know what behind what strain probably
you know he probably has a lot of info
like that yeah as far as the Dutch team
goes uh he knows that very very well
um yeah better than the British Columbia
scene because he was over there during
those days time seed was one of the
biggest seed sellers yeah to America in
those days
um it's kind of like seeds men or
Attitude seeds are now
back then so he had a good personal
relationship with all the Breeders
um yeah he's one of the few people that
I know has been in uh aryan's breeding
rooms where his mother plants are crazy
yeah
that's cool that's really cool well man
I we have so much more I could go over
like I have a list of massive lists of
strains and everything we can go over
um I'd love to pick your brain some more
work
hitting right around two hours now so I
was gonna wrap it up because we've taken
a lot of your time but I just wanted to
thank you for coming on and speaking
with us about all these strains
um I I appreciate you also for keeping
track of your work like from a greater
perspective I respect that a lot like
you you're able to speak your lines you
know your lines you remember the males
you you know all that that's that's not
a common thing and I highly respond
that's something that's something you
can't fake it's it's stuck in my head I
I I remember I could think back 25 when
I smell a plant I'm like oh that smells
like something I grew 22 years ago and
it was in this town under this flight
and it was May and I just ate a hot dog
you know it's you know yeah oh yeah yeah
memories I feel that I mean Matt and I
we talk a lot about there's certain
people that you talk to and they're
extremely vague about some of the stuff
that they do and for me being like a you
know a weed nerd or something like that
since it's like so much of my life like
someone wants to talk about it like you
said I can be like oh yeah it was like I
did this and it would smell like that
and this happened and I remember I was
and you were wearing that because it's
just so part of it you know you can talk
confidently about stuff that because you
spend every day with it people won't
realize that growing and breeding is day
in day out you have to have success yeah
and you have to stack those days
together for a long period of time to
get to where you want to go
yeah and there's no days off
take your whole life
yeah yeah you don't travel you move
all right
well that's good to know yeah I don't
have anybody here I trust and watch
anything
[Laughter]
thank you for having me on yeah thanks
for having me on we can chat again
sometime if you want to get through the
rest of your list it would be an
absolute pleasure man anytime anytime
So yeah thank you so much I hope you
have a wonderful evening and uh we'll
talk to you soon
you too man all right take care you too