welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
welcome breeder Syndicate I'm here with
my buddy Kendo he is an old school Forum
member old school breeder old school
grower
and anything else I'm forgetting
nah just uh you just you've named it off
bro martial artists
he's an old school truth teller is is
the best way that I could um I could I
could explain this old school critical
thinker from the forums in an old school
truth teller and it's it's an honor to
have him here I've been wanting to get
him for a long time and I think you guys
will enjoy this so uh we'll start it off
now so you know just um talking about
the the pre-forum days
you know when I was like uh 15 years old
I did my first grows up in the hills
above San Jose okay and it was good I
mean you know at that point I had
learned how to grow pot but I had no
idea you know what I was growing and any
of that type of stuff so I went up to uh
to Berkeley there was this uh this
underground record store right what
years were we talking roughly 1975. geez
all right let's go 75 75 way back then
but me and a buddy went up to this
underground record store in Berkeley and
they had this little uh or a a group of
these little Cliff Notes hippie Gorilla
Grow guides yeah right so it was just
like this like uh five inches by four
inches maybe 20 pages
uh the the hip yeah put together that
you know described essentially how to
set up a gorilla Grill you know what I
mean was it the old cultivators
book with a little girl watering can on
the front
no okay no no all right this was this
was just like with uh you know like some
some art paper and it was it was just it
was it was crude but it was really
helpful man it really awesome yeah and
so you know I found a spot man I got
some seeds uh I found a good spot that
was in a dry wash so you know the soil
was good but uh it had a Springs fed
little little runoff above right so I
had water that I could bring down and
everything turned out good it was a it
was really beneficial that it was a a
long hot summer because you know again
you know I didn't I didn't know much
about strains at that point blah blah
and so I had grown some uh some Maui and
some Colombian yeah well we're talking
long long term genetics yeah I love
flowering man yeah so they weren't they
weren't ready until almost the end of
November well we only saw two reins
during that entire time yeah that's nice
yeah right you know I didn't even know
how lucky I was until much later
obviously yeah yeah of course but uh
turned out beautiful really really good
um you know I got it I got it all down
got it all transported because it was
way back in the mountains way back in
the Hills right so it was all you know
packing it myself packing in the dirt
myself doing all that
and uh
you know at that point man you know
pretty much all we saw was was uh you
know brickweed yeah I mean
there's some good Colombian s
Guerrero some some different stuff like
that right but uh yeah for the most part
it was all just vehicle seeds and shake
and yada yada so you know I made a
splash in my neighborhood right with my
I bet and there was a couple of guys my
brothers my brother was older like eight
years older so we had some friends who
were growing and uh you know it was uh
it was really uh you know
good for me to take my weed to them
smoking with them you know and they were
they were talking about how good it was
but I had the Kendo name for a long time
because of my martial arts right yeah
yeah that's right
so uh
uh the one guy they called him the
doctor right he was like man this is
some green lizard [ __ ] right so the name
just stuck right yeah and then from then
on you know I was known as Kendo the
green wizard right but that's awesome
you know that that girl turned out
really good man and then uh you know
over the years after that I would you
know going back in the mountains back my
dirt in uh you know grow my plants do my
thing and uh it was good and you know
back then I didn't tell anybody I was
growing weed yeah yeah so what do you
want somebody wanted some weed and I'd
be like yeah I can get you something
yeah I go to the guy yeah give me your
money I'll be back all right yeah and
then bring back my stuff right yeah and
uh it worked out well it worked out
really really well
a good good little little story from
those days was uh I was back in this um
in this park right it was like a state
park or County Park and they had miles
and miles of trails so I went way back
down this Trail got off of the county
land into some other land and uh there
was some some brush and some trees and
so you know I would do like six plants
in each area yeah so I got a spot man I
had six plants growing
and I always had an alternative way to
walk I would never walk directly to my
grill right sure so I walked and it was
up above the site right it was you know
maybe maybe 100 feet up above the site
and I'm sitting up there in this little
spot man I'm having my lunch looking
down and I see some movement right and
I'm like oh [ __ ] what the hell is that
man I don't think maybe it's you know a
deer or something right no man somebody
some dude gets up from what he was
hiding goes and obviously goes and takes
a leak and then comes back yeah and then
I see somebody else right trying to be
all stealthy in the bushes too well you
know cops obviously cops man because
they're hiding
yeah so I was like well [ __ ] this I'm
out of here so I stashed what I had you
know what I mean I had my backpack I
snatched everything that I had that was
grow related I had some duct tape some
scissors you know some other stuff and I
stashed all that and then walked back
around my little Trail got on the actual
Trail and started going back to where I
was going kind of walking fast right I
didn't want to run
so you know I keep looking back keep
looking back and I see them coming from
behind me and I was like well [ __ ] I'm
[ __ ] what am I gonna do man yeah so
I'm all nervous dude because you know
it's yeah just back in the day when you
know you're going to [ __ ] prison man
for that [ __ ] yeah for sure so I'm all
nervous man and uh bro I had to take a
[ __ ]
literally I get those I get the nervous
shits man dude
rumbling bumbling yeah I was like nope
if I keep going I'm gonna [ __ ] myself so
I just stepped off the path a little bit
man in the bushes dropped my my hikers
my hiker [ __ ] Target right I don't know
if you know about those yeah
[ __ ] right okay so I drop it down drop
my pants I start taking a [ __ ] so you
know maybe two minutes later maybe less
right these guys go by and they they
pass me up and then stop and come back
yeah put your hands up put your hands up
I'm like hey man I'm sitting here bro
what are you what are you doing I'm
gonna put your hands up put your hands
up I'm like if I put my hands up I'm
gonna fall down man in my [ __ ] trying to
take a [ __ ] you're like dude look she
sees that I'm actually taking a [ __ ]
yeah and he's like well well finish up
then oh yeah move slowly I'm like all
right man no problems sorry wipe you
know what yeah pull the target together
right because you got the little strings
yeah make a little little container out
of it a little [ __ ]
little poop container and so the guys
the guy's like come over this way slowly
right is that your backpack I'm gonna
ask my backpack no come on so then he he
tells me let me see your hands yeah
right I'm like I didn't get any poop in
my hands man
right because back then we all use the
blue stuff right oh yeah yeah yeah like
the 10 52-10 yeah when you're mixing up
if you're [ __ ] with it right that
[ __ ] would stain the [ __ ] out of your
hands right oh [ __ ] so he's looking at
my hands right I got no no blue in my
hands I got no poop on my hands he's
like what are you doing I'm like bro I'm
hiking he's like we didn't see you we
were back over so and so such and such I
go well I only went so far and I saw
that that was the end of the trail yeah
I turned around and started walking back
he's like well you know this is this is
a dangerous place I'm like a danger I
mean I mean I know there's mountain
lions and such out here but you know
danger I mean what do you guys after
well we're we're looking for some
illegal marijuana growers and you got to
be careful because those illegal
marijuana growers man they're dangerous
they could set up some booby traps and
some other stuff I guess yeah I hate
those [ __ ] marijuana growers man yeah
look at those guys
all right just go on go on down the
trail just be careful don't come back
this way again know that we're about
there hiding and I'm like all right all
right I'm sorry I'm sorry to mess up
your your investigation yeah right I'm
walking away I'm laughing bro I'm
[ __ ] just laughing my ass off right
well obviously I lost those plants right
yeah and I have three I had three more
spots so it didn't matter yeah but that
was that was some funny [ __ ] man what
was the old um the old thing like plant
one for you plant one for thieves plant
one for cops type you know yeah yep yep
and it was also plant plant another one
for the Wildlife oh that's true yeah you
got rabbits and deers and rabbits and
kangaroo rats and you name it bro they
were taking it right but I did it right
I would take uh chicken wire
yeah and I would make a basket you know
what I mean and then the basket would be
two feet above the soil line you know
what I mean so now you got a basket
that's like two and a half feet down
into your hole that you dug and then you
got a two feet up above and I would take
it and you know you always I would
always take off the bottom branches
because you know that's just drill 101
and uh you know then fold it in a little
bit so that it was maybe
you know eight to ten inches around
around the the uh the main stem yeah
yeah you mean so that stops rabbits it
stops kangaroo rats that stops Gophers
you know it's not gonna stop the deer
but yeah those [ __ ] girdle like they
they strip the bottom base of your
plants for people that don't know like
rats will just strip it and they do it
once and it'll kill the whole plant
instantly well they do that on purpose
because they want to knock the plant
over
they can only reach so many of the
leaves down low
I didn't realize that I was like why did
they always just Target That Base sucks
yeah they want they want to knock it
down that makes sense that's how it does
yeah and then you don't have the leaves
off of it man [ __ ] rabbits man
that's right but yeah I mean you know it
was a
it was it was an adventure man you know
I don't know if you've ever seen brown
dirt Warrior no right so it's a guy from
Canada and he did a bunch of uh he did a
bunch of videos where he would um he
would go out and show people how he was
Gorilla growing you know he'd have like
two big bags of uh of sunshine mix oh
yeah on each shoulder and you know hike
his way five ten miles into the bush and
blah blah blah and that's I mean that's
really what it's like yeah that's
literally what it's like you know and I
got something dude I would let my I
would let my My Sunshine mix Drive the
[ __ ] out
let it lighten up it's like five pounds
now of course you gotta you gotta
moisten the [ __ ] out of it afterwards
right yeah but I would just cut my bag
in half and then just fill it fill each
half with water
yeah let it soak it up do that a couple
times man and now you're you're Pete and
all your Forest product is all you know
nice and hydrated again no no that's
actually really good advice too
yeah you know it worked out I mean not
many people are Gorilla growing anymore
they do I mean you have some a lot of
people who watch this show do
really
yeah so this is good advice man this is
a good advice because you know once you
get out once you get back there man it's
you know it's it's easy to hydrate it
and it's just impossible to get it back
there right it's crazy right and you
know I did a lot of I did a lot of crazy
different gorilla girls man I did some
that were you know all the way up on the
top of a ridge where the water source it
was down at the bottom and what I did
was I just took old water beds and took
them to the top of the Ridge and then I
would get down below and I had a uh an
OG
um foot pump that I hooked up to a
bicycle uh pedals you know what I mean
yeah yeah and then I would just sit down
and just you know
and pedaling and fill everything up man
fill it all up and it worked out well
good the water beds because there was a
uh I don't know if you know mad Jag he
used to be on the forums I see mag and
he was an old uh grower back into a
gorilla grower in the late 70s did the
first big skunk one grows that he gave
me this old this old catalog Vlog and it
was for gorilla Growers and it was from
the late 70s early 80s and it had these
big inflatable like thing like basically
waterbed innards that you would fill up
with water for a gorilla growing but a
waterbed is perfect it's the same [ __ ]
just pump it down this is perfect and
then I would just cover them with leaves
you know what I mean cover the water
beds with leaves and then I would grow I
would grow down the backside the south
facing side of these ridges right
um because uh you know it was uh I was
grown in an area that had a decent
amount of hunters but if you know if the
incline is as such you don't have to
worry about hunters going down there
yeah they don't want them anymore around
there yeah and it was I mean the incline
on this this particular spot that I was
doing that at
um I would I would actually tie off a
rope to a tree at the top and then just
work my way across
you know what I mean because yeah it
worked out well this is long before we
had camp or any of that didn't have to
worry about helicopters or anybody
coming swooping in on your [ __ ] blah
blah blah when Camp came in
I was actually I would get on a south
facing Hillside and then tuck my plants
up underneath the oak trees yeah right
so that you know you still get that
south facing you know good sunlight on
your plants but they're kind of stealthy
up underneath the oak trees yeah so you
really couldn't you really couldn't see
them
and I never you know I lost a I lost a
few plants here and there you know to uh
to people because you know as I go in if
I saw any recent tracks or areas that
were apparent that people were moving
around in that area
it's not worth it man it was just not
worth the prison time bro yeah some
people get that greed and and think
about all the work and just like I can't
walk but that's what keeps people safe
you know you got to be smart you got to
be smarter I wasn't I wasn't prepared to
go to prison man that's you know using
my own use my instincts and my intuition
bro I kept myself out of out of jail you
know real quick you mentioned you
mentioned your name Kendo coming you
know from a karate background real quick
real quick can you tell us a little bit
about some of that karate background
because I know people are going to want
to want me to ask that so when I first
started man it was uh I got in a lot of
fights as a kid right yeah wearing
glasses you know I wouldn't take any
[ __ ] I grew up in Oakland and so when I
moved to this little town called
Milpitas a lot of farm boys who thought
they were tough right and they really
weren't tough
um and so I got in a lot of fights right
like Bakersfield
pardon it's like Bakersfield all the
farm guys and yeah that's how I grew up
yeah oh yeah bro and so you know my
parents put me into karate uh in hopes
that it would teach me discipline and
restraint keep me from fighting right
yes
it worked to a degree right yeah it
worked to a degree but it also didn't
work to another degree right I didn't
get into trouble anymore right because
people were afraid to talk [ __ ] and turn
me in right but I started off doing uh I
started off doing Taekwondo right and
that's where the Kendo came in right
because we would work with the with
Kindle sticks yeah you know what I mean
and I loved it bro I was good at it and
I loved I love whipping that [ __ ] and
hearing that well crap crap yeah it was
great but then I got into uh what's
known as kajukembo with a school called
crazy dragons Okay and essentially
essentially crazy dragons was Cobra Kai
oh okay yeah we're Cobra Kai yeah they
eat bad guys
and uh it's uh it was featured on um on
Fight Quest
yeah yeah I have I have yeah so it's a
it's a Fight Quest feature called uh
country combo uh you know we would learn
how to fight 101 then it was two on one
then three on one four on one five on
one yeah all street fighting
um no mercy no mercy karate no mercy
Campbell has five different Arts
combined together
so it was the the first mixed martial
art and it was the first American
martial art it came out of Hawaii yeah
so it was great dude it was it was
really good I enjoyed the hell out of
that [ __ ] man see I'm so far into
martial arts and and the history that
like this fascinates me this part of it
fascinates me you know I started off as
a Shotokan kid at way of Japan here with
a Ballard of a Sensei yeah but I was a
kid like I got put in the same
same reasons parents saw me fighting a
bunch and thought wanted me to have some
restraint but what it taught me was you
don't just unload on everyone you unload
on those that are [ __ ] and and
bigger than you you never fight someone
smaller than you you know [ __ ] like that
that's what that's what the discipline I
learned but I eventually got kicked out
for street fighting yeah I ended up
becoming the bully of the bullies yeah
yeah that's what I did yeah
the guys were bullies man I I take it to
them you know what I mean
I do because I see that you took that to
the forums too and as we Adventure into
there this is why like
I I really for people that don't know
like
I have spent a lot of time on the forums
myself but Kendo was on the forums
before my time and there are throughout
the history there hasn't been a lot of
people that have given pushback to
scammers the Liars to con artists Kendo
was the pre-premet right long before I
existed Kendo was holding it down hard
so I really want to go into some of that
too because it it's special moments
important moments and there wasn't a lot
of dudes who had the balls to do it
because it's not fun being that person
but it's necessary
well you know man um being at it for
such a long time I mean I was a I was a
web guy in the 80s before the internet
was even created right it was back in
the BBS days right
bulletin board services and discussion
boards right yeah there was no GUI there
was nothing like that right yeah and uh
I learned how to troll from guys at that
time right
just with words yeah you know what I
mean just with words just to get people
going and get people you know on edge
right get them exposed to themselves get
them doing that kind of stuff right but
before we get into that let me just do a
little bit more of the yeah right so uh
when I was like somewhere around 18 man
I met uh I met one of the Hayes Brothers
up in Santa Cruz
no [ __ ] oh yeah bro way back in the day
way way back in the day okay into the
liking to me right I was a I was a kid I
was growing some good lead not great
weed right is this RL
pardon is this RL no okay no no and he
wasn't I mean there there was a there
was a whole group of guys who were part
of that crew right you see the thing
behind me the the Hayes Brothers poster
yeah right up behind me yeah I like that
part of the quest part of the quest man
yeah and and so you know I I met him I
was I was actually uh uh kind of kind of
sort of dating uh this guy's niece you
know what I mean okay so I went up to a
picnic and you know blah blah blah it
was all the family there and you know I
busted out some of my weed and they
liked it and then they busted out some
of their weed and I [ __ ] loved it I
was like wow this is you know this is
this is like three steps above my [ __ ]
bro this is incredible so the guy took a
liking to me
and uh I went up and I helped him I
helped him trim I helped him do some
stuff and back in the day it wasn't the
same it wasn't a California Dream right
you guys take a take the big leaves off
and you know leave the smaller sugar
leaves right but uh he took me with him
as he went up to Mendo and humble and uh
and uh Trinity right and so I went back
I didn't go all the way through to
spyrock right but we went back in that
that area yeah and uh you know a lot of
other places and and it was it was
really interesting right he didn't
trimmed for money you trimmed for weed
yeah that's right you want to come back
with a you know a big you know
contractor bag full of buds you know
what I mean after trimming which was
cool because dude it was 70 [ __ ] 70
bucks for a quarter right back then
right and yeah so that's a lot of money
man and I was happy but yeah so I I met
that guy and I went through a lot of
other stuff man and uh
you know then uh you know I did my did
my um did my gorilla drawing for a while
and then Cali medical hit
and when when Cali medical hit uh you
know we got licenses for 2003 uh 95. 95
God damn yeah that was way back yeah
yeah it was 95. and I had been I had
been doing you know the uh the uh 215
getting signatures for the 215 and doing
a bunch of stuff working with uh a lot
of the guys Dale garlinger
um some of the other guys who were you
know the the leaders of that that
movement and uh it was great man I was I
was really happy to do that but I
started growing in my backyard right and
it was fantastic man I just got like
four I got four you know four licenses
from other people and you know I'm
growing in my backyard I got no worries
I'm not I'm not scared of nothing man
doing great plants right there it was
fantastic man and then uh
I hooked up with some of my brother's
old friends
and uh they were growing out in this
area back behind Livermore California
okay and you know California you know
but a lot of people don't know
California is made mainly Badlands dude
it's it's a lot of nothing rattlesnakes
cougars you know a lot of deserts dude
dude a lot of desert a lot of scrub
scrub Oak tumble weeds and you know it
just it was way back there this
operation was way back there and uh I
affectionately call it crazy Krusty's
cannabis Co-op okay and uh and you know
I did I did good back there man but uh
there was some there was some clowns
growing weed back there bro I mean there
was there was one set of guys man you
know I'm not gonna name names sure but
there was one set of guys they thought
growing weed was taking a uh a post hole
digger
you dig out one full post hole spot
right maybe you know 16 inches deep and
then dropping a one gallon pot in there
oh no that was their version of growing
weed so you can imagine it was it was
horrible yeah those guys growing
lollipops right this place would be
about this big around literally yeah
as white as the pot man they can't grow
out just ridiculous man so it was funny
dude but uh I did really really good up
there on that uh on that spot and made a
bunch of money but in the interim
you know as a uh before we even got up
there is when I was introduced to
overdrow right
so now let's start with the forums man
um
overgrowth was really interesting to me
right because you know prior to that it
was you know I I had not had exposure to
you know just outright talking about
[ __ ] online yeah no no not at all and so
when I started at overgrow it was like a
one
2001. and uh
and uh I just learned
I learned for a little over a year you
know what I mean just learning doing
things don't do that you know don't want
to interact yet but like I think that's
a lot of the old school method that you
sit down you listen and you learn before
you jump in so you don't look like an
ass you know that's not how most people
operate
and so like you said well I started I
started noticing a lot of
inconsistencies you know what I mean
yeah and my gut and intuition was
telling me you know this guy's a scammer
yeah this person's scamming that's
that's [ __ ] that's not right you
know but I still hadn't started posting
right yeah so
as time went on I was like all right I'm
just going to post some stuff right and
and I started actually posting on the
political forums that's where I started
posting right because you know I'm you
know me I'm a political guy oh yeah I
can't help it man but uh
you know after I got my legs you know
from posting in the political forums you
know I felt comfortable and uh I started
going after some of these guys and
pointing out that you know I thought
they were scammers and you know I didn't
trust what they were saying and at that
point I started getting blowback from
the moderators you know what I mean
because yeah these guys well these guys
were they had they had people fooled you
know everybody thought yeah the coolest
nicest most friendly guys or they were
people that were so much in need you
know what I mean yeah my whole world
fell apart and yeah yeah yeah yeah and
as you know the Forum back then yeah
everybody wanted to help everybody right
always yeah and it was cool right and I
I helped a lot of people right it was a
small community people that cared about
each other absolutely but when your gut
you know when you're intuition and your
instinct you know sets an alarm off
right I trust that [ __ ] big time yeah I
did so I would start questioning these
guys you know tell me tell me more tell
me more if I'm gonna do something for
you you're going to explain to me how
this came about that's not making a lot
of sense to me so then people would come
back oh you're a dick you're a chump why
are you doing this what's your problem
yeah that Vibes bro
so at that exactly exactly so at that
point now I'm already raising you know
what I mean awareness to me being a dick
you know what I mean and yada yada so I
was like all right whatever whatever's
clever I don't care man yeah so then you
know I'm thinking about how I'm going to
shake things up a little bit
how am I going to shake things up over
here man so I posted up a thread called
IP on my plants the classic even even
during my time
looking down right on my plants and I'm
holding a water bottle out of sight
right with a hole in the front of it and
I'm squirting the plants down but it
looks like I'm actually peeing on my
plants right on your plants yeah the
whole the whole premise of the thread
was about how much people were using
urea products yeah you know what I mean
and it was just a joke you know what I
mean yeah yeah well yeah urea you know
what I mean and it was just a joke
and before you knew it man it just
started taking off oh you're disgusting
what the hell is your problem I can't
believe you I would never smoke your
weed no [ __ ] way what's wrong with
you and it just started taking off bro I
mean literally just started taking off
and uh by the end of that thread it had
there was only a couple of other threads
that were even close right but it had
the most activity of any thread on
overgrill that's so funny thousands and
thousands of replies and comments and
you know hates and loves and oh yeah it
was a joke dude some people got it right
and most people didn't most people
didn't and then other people just wanted
to be be Chumps about it right yeah yeah
so then you know at that point now I'm
feeling real comfortable I'm like
[ __ ] I'm gonna start commenting on
everything I don't care I'm just
commenting all over the place and I'm
gaining all kinds of people and friends
and doing this and that and uh I gained
the the site of the sharks tank
okay do you remember the Shark Tank no
no before my time
so the sharks tank was uh was like the
the spot for overgrow where they could
send the trolls
it was a place where they could have
uh uncensored
um content yeah without without having
to do that and they could you know they
would send the trolls to the sharks tank
right yeah so there was a lot of guys
over there that were
um you know
really good trolls man oh I'm sure so so
they did not they did not like me juice
and a bunch of these other guys who were
over there yeah they took sight of me
right yeah so they essentially set me up
yeah and came at me real hard and you
know on overgrow they had a hard
moderation policy and I had already you
know gained the attention of of a bunch
of the moderators so when I started
calling people names you know what I
mean yeah um I got banned yeah right I
got banned right and uh so then uh
you know I was I was pissed I was I was
real pissed oh yeah but I I you know I
was like all right whatever man whatever
so then I I started at cannabis world
and I rejoined overgrow as Sir buds a
lot
and and then uh
and then I got a message that
that overgrow from plural and Mongoose
oh
you you mean you're in a barrel a plural
dude he snitched on the whole world bro
yeah yeah he's he was Silk Road he was
the guy who taught Silk Road guy oh I
know oh I know
so I got a message from plural right
yeah
and he tells me here's what's going on
at the sharks tank right and he sends me
this whole thread of these guys talking
hella [ __ ] about how they got me booted
and all this [ __ ] what a newbie he
thinks he's a troll he ain't [ __ ] he
don't know Trump you don't know nothing
right so then I was like all right Chris
watch this man so I created a website
called play button right and on the
website I just started you know posting
my thoughts posting a bunch of different
stuff right and then I started one
called the uh the sacking of Kindle all
right and on there I started talking
about it put this stuff up the plural
input gave me started talking [ __ ] about
all the different people that uh at the
uh at the sharks tank and this one guy
he was like a main moderator his name
was Mr Mico he was the main moderator
and he was one of the one of the guys
who was you know part of the the sacking
of Kendo sure so I started talking [ __ ]
about him saying a bunch of stuff about
him and blah blah blah so then he goes
by that time I joined uh joined the
sharks tank yeah and uh and started
talking about it and started talking to
him and calling him you know calling him
out and he read this stuff on playbud
and then posted up personal information
about me oh he doxed you on the set well
that was against policy yeah that was
that was that was one of the biggest tlu
violations at the Shark Tank right that
that's the ultimate troll move to get
someone to do that so I got him banned
yeah one of the main moderators right
that's amazing now at that point now
they're calling me they're calling me
you know troll Master yada yada yeah
I created the troll Mafia
I had like I had like you know
40 different personas on the sharks tank
I created like 25 on overgrow
and I would go in and I would start a
thread and then I would post to the
thread commenting on what I said right
and then I would go in and look from
another Persona and talk [ __ ] about
myself
you know what I mean and then other
people coming back and forth right and
you just go on and on right I just would
just it was fun it was fun it was great
mental mental jockeying bro yeah dude
but uh yeah so so the sharks tank was a
really good uh good way for me to uh to
get you going I got my wife into it her
name was team [ __ ] that's awesome
you got your wife into it too she got
into it well I could I would keep
telling all the different things and
she's like you know I hate it but it
sounds like a lot of fun yeah yeah let's
do it let's do it let's do it
after that right I you know I was posted
on they so then I got overdrill to allow
me to come back yeah oh they were hot
bro I was a bad person the only person
ever
to be re introduced in over Grill yeah
the only person right because I started
a campaign let Kendo back and the hell
of people that was in their signature
line let Kendo back in let Kim that back
awesome I literally there ended up being
a couple thousand of people who did that
right let me back in and let me back in
right and uh
you know overgrowth was great man it was
great and you know the IP IP on my
plants was uh was probably the the best
one that I ever put out there man but oh
yeah and I put a couple I put a couple
other ones out there right which was uh
one of them was uh moderation
moderators and the moderated
and it was a it was a vision into what
moderation truly is you know what I mean
how you moderate people right what
you're supposed to be what it's supposed
to be right and then about who and what
moderators are supposed to do and about
what we saw at overgrow and at cannabis
world as well right
that uh they really weren't moderators
they were just ego ego people who you
know would go after people they didn't
like and uh you know let the people that
they did like get away with whatever
they wanted to because
you know how it is bro it's still the
same it doesn't it doesn't change it
hasn't changed and then it was about the
moderated those of us who are under
those policies
and uh bro that one got that one got a
lot of visualization a lot of that it
opens people's eyes a lot of people
don't even put time into thinking or
understanding the psychology behind it
all
and you see and you've seen me man and
then and you know it's funny you say
psychology you've seen me you know I can
I can run circles around oh yeah 90 of
these people right I learn them it's
like the game of chess right it really
is like a game of chess right and
they're all playing checkers yeah and
psychologically you know on uh on a
website when you're on a website people
are at their keyboard and so it's their
own little world right and so they're ID
their base comes out right they can't
help but show their base and who they
truly are and it's very easy to
manipulate people I developed a uh I
developed a means by which to deal with
that [ __ ] and post called Web Foo
I love it yeah and it was uh it was
based on schopenhower's 31 ways to win
an argument yeah and Sun sues are the
war part of War yep right and so and it
it works out all the [ __ ] time I bet
it does
make them paint themselves into a corner
and then watch them you know you can see
it right away when they figure out that
they painted themselves into a corner
right they start stumbling they start
trying to figure out how to do this and
do that right
with that moderation on the moderated
post I um I got a lot of those
moderators to paint themselves into a
corner straight up because they would
come in and it'd be like oh that's
that's [ __ ] I don't do that I don't
do that and I would just post up
examples you know what I mean and always
every time I would start with no
disrespect intended yeah
you know what I mean yeah all right and
just you know get them to to you know
keep stepping on themselves and be like
well you say this but how about this
this is what you did in this instance oh
and this is what you did in that
instance it's hard for me to be able to
see any difference between this that and
the other you know when you say you're a
modder you're actually moderating the
way that a moderator is supposed to
moderate
you're not doing it by example so
explain to me where you're doing this
and just yeah so many of them bro
literally bro I got I got these guys to
where they they hated me they they oh I
bet that can get dangerous that can get
dangerous More Than People realize
though well you know I'm not I'm not
scared of nothing no I'm just talking
about like as far as people that are
snitchy that that's the scary one yeah
oh yeah yeah yeah yeah you can you get
snitched on man nowadays you get slotted
right that's what I mean that's it's
horrible with where it's gone today as
far as like because back in the day like
sometimes you'd run into these people
and you fist fight and that's over
that's cool but this other [ __ ] is not
that's that that's not in our Playbook
we don't have those roles to run that
way so it's like they get this Dominion
they always have that upper hand that
they can do that oh yeah bro and I mean
I I can tell you I had multiple people
you know what I mean they would they
would confront me because you know I've
been to lots of different you know
parties Harvest parties oh yeah areas
you know
there I was like what yeah we can do it
and uh you know I've been confronted
there and it's like hey you know we can
we can do whatever I'm not scared and a
couple guys were pretty damn big you
know what I mean like doing when you're
not the first guy a big guy I've ever
fought man yeah so you know I mean you
can you can take it to the Limit or we
could just say whatever you know I'm not
gonna take it back I meant what I said
yeah exactly
so here we are let's let's figure this
out right yep but you know from
overgrown man it uh and Shark Tank
I met a lot of people personally you
know what I mean so you know because I
would I would go ahead and uh invite
people over which freaked my wife the
[ __ ] out I'm sure you can imagine all
right people coming over staying on the
stay on the couch but of course I did
them first you know what I mean oh yeah
and find out about them
um you know I'd go to their house we'd
meet up at concerts and you know parties
and blah blah blah
and uh there were a lot of parties from
Cannabis world that I got involved in
all right can I just talk about some of
those
pardon can you talk about some of those
any any good stories from those oh yeah
oh yeah bro so cannabis world was a
sister site for uh for uh right and
that's I think that's where they that's
actually where they launched uh uh
Heaven's stairway from I believe that's
right
yep Richard ran overgrow and cannabis
world was he all right what was it was a
oh God it was NL
was it nl420 and
full girl
who else
somebody else I think was a guy named IO
il-1 maybe they started they started
overgrow
right and then
and then once overgrowth started taking
off because it didn't it was like a year
there was sixty thousand sixty thousand
members you know I just [ __ ] took off
right and so then they were
um trying to finance it by the ads right
but there was so much so much content
right I mean you got to buy storage
space right yeah yeah you gotta pay for
search uh service storage space they
couldn't do it right so it was becoming
too prolific and too much and so a full
girl
um nl420 and this other person stepped
away and clarissian Richard jumped in so
shebang handled the handled the attack
part of it and yeah
right and then they came up with uh they
started doing the auction at first and
that was that was good right yeah that's
when subby got involved right because at
that point do you remember Rue are you
his original first name was uh Richard
no no no stop cool
oh [ __ ] I don't know what is oh it's Rue
or something like that yeah I just
always called him snobby yeah but yeah
that's when when he started doing his
thing right and you know there was it
was it was a it was just a a bunch of
the 77 crew man can you no you know I
don't know much about the 77 crew if it
like because I remember there's always
AE 77 attached to everything and I know
that it's part of Eric that was Eric
a-e-r-i-t did he the 77 crew is he ahead
of it or just part of it no no he's just
part of it
was just a group of like 77 guys who all
had you know availability or uh
possession of [ __ ] tons of land race you
know what I mean or specific area
cultivars right let's call it yeah
Miss Miller right yeah that's pretty
much everything is a cultivar yeah um
but yeah there was like 77 guys and they
all got together and and just started
exchanging genetics you know what I mean
DJ Short subby Eric Stone Pony all those
guys man those hell of a preservation
dude
is he in there yeah oh yeah oh yeah dude
all those dudes I think Texas kid oh you
do yeah it takes kid uh Lone Star yeah
lone stars there yeah a bunch of those
guys Mark I don't think Mark's Castle
was a part of it though oh [ __ ] Marx
I don't think but he's old school Mark
is cool dude he's been around forever
yeah forever bro I like that guy man I
like that guy a lot man he's been around
a long time oh yeah man but uh
you know it was um it was a lot of a lot
of stuff going on with those guys um
um at that point right when they first
started it and it was about
it was about the time that I got in
there that that it started really taking
off that they that
um Richard came into play yeah and and
uh shebang and him went in together
right
but uh yeah it was it was really good
man and then cannabis world I started
getting into canvas world because
cannabis world was
a lot less
caustic than overgrill right it was way
more friendly a lot more really good
people a lot of good stuff going on and
uh I met a bunch of people through like
elk Slayer I don't know if you know oh
yeah yeah oh yeah
oh yeah oh yeah dude and that's what I
ended up at uh crazy Krusty's cannabis
Co-op
which was very successful for me yeah it
sounds like it oh yeah until uh until we
got rated by 105 cops oh [ __ ] did you
and you made it out okay oh yeah all my
plants were accounted for
um I had four that didn't have the right
tags right so they chopped down four of
my plants out of
like 70 7 years 76. not too bad they
chopped down four of my playoffs man and
it was it was beautiful bro they were
all you know five Pounders like that oh
dude it was beautiful and it was all my
own stuff right it was a
preservation
I had uh the purple block head
oh there's all my stuff that I read man
it was it was beautiful but uh
let's get back to the parties we were
going to talk about on cannabis world
yeah yeah that's right yeah yeah so some
of these parties right uh a really good
friend of fixing right
um Let me let me tell you how I made it
so I made I got uh I got the um I got
the UK cheese
I was one of the first in in the United
States to get the UK cheese so he
brought it in that was like sourced he
sourced it somehow right no he didn't no
no no no he got it from me oh you got it
from me so I got it from uh
Optimus Prime okay
we won't do we won't do first names
right but yeah yeah I've got it from
Optimus Prime who got it from uh oh God
what was his name he was out of Canada
man these uh
he's an English dude who was up in
Canada
yep Disney creator exactly you're
friends with him so he sourced it
through Vapor Vapor got it um he was in
Nova Scotia and he carried it all the
way across Canada to Visions
um to Visions little commune yeah yeah
over over in BC yeah and uh so he sent
it Vision sent it to Optimus Prime and
then Optimus Prime sent me it sent it to
me along with the vision tie oh you got
to grow that yeah it was good it was
really good it was really good it was
really good so now I got the cheese and
everybody is holding that [ __ ] tight oh
yeah it was crazy right but you I mean
you know my reputation bro yeah I don't
care I don't care man I just started
giving it out right yeah so then uh Elks
later comes to me and tells me hey bro
you gotta you gotta get you gotta let me
get that strain man you gotta let me get
that strain and don't give it to this
other guy yeah well this other guy his
name was
Danimal oh God yeah
yeah bro so it was his name was Daniel I
could see why he would say no limited
animal don't give it to Daniel don't you
dare right man whatever I'll give it to
whoever the hell I want to yeah yeah
then I started doing some research on
the animal right yeah and uh but so I
gave gave that right because like bro
you're the best I love you man I love
you so I did research on the animal and
found out the animal was a scammer right
yeah so then
I meet Danimal up in Oakland I'm going
up to Oakland to the the third floor up
there
um on Broadway I'm gonna pick up some uh
pick up some strains from Turtle up
there and uh remember Turtle no I don't
know it but I know the name oh yeah he's
bomb man yeah um so I'm going up there
anyway and so I have the cheese
and I have east coast salary diesel to
the early source of that that sour too
oh yeah so I had two separate plants
right yeah and uh
so
Danimal starts telling me a story right
the story is not even his story bro I
have heard the story already from the
person who the story was [ __ ]
originated from and right off the bat
I'm like [ __ ] you yep you that's all you
needed to hear in the east coast Sour
Diesel said here's the cheese yep he
took that back he grew it out he traded
this East Coast Sarah diesel to a bunch
of people as Jesus calling up the cheese
right and got clowned
yet and he came back at me on on canvas
world and was like bro what is this ago
that's East Coast salad diesel before
what the [ __ ] man I go with your dick
dude you're a liar and this is what you
get that's what you get I love it you'd
be a clown and so everybody was like oh
that's that's that's classic dude
he got clowned he got clowns so hard
right
and it was hella funny that's how I made
it right yeah yeah and uh so you know
we're fast friends at that point well
actually you're getting mad that we're
using his first name no no probably not
okay I just want to make sure nobody
nobody will know nobody will know his
last name anyway okay
so getting together doing different
stuff right and I'm I'm still not in
that inner Inner Circle right the [ __ ]
yeah you know what I mean yeah yeah and
uh the main reasons because there's a
couple Rudy poops who just didn't like
me yeah they were mad at you probably
from your your
previous post about calling people out
about her whatever whatever their Rooty
poops that didn't like me right but uh
Jake went to uh Rosso who was having
these Friday night parties you know what
I mean yeah
um and you know said he wanted to he
wanted to bring me to the party right
and so Roswell was like oh hell yeah I
love candle I love that guy bring him
make sure you bring him so
Jake said he was going to bring me and
this other guy uh Ed andalarcus okay he
didn't like he didn't like me we ended
up becoming friends but he didn't like
me and he was like no no you can't bring
him and Jake was like yeah okay okay
whatever yeah anyway brought me anyway
right yeah so then I'm there at Rosso's
and now there's a Russell has a Friday
night party and there's a Saturday and
Sunday party at ncgas okay
I'm sure you know right um there's
Friday and Saturday and and Sunday party
at ncgas and it's a it's a meal right
it's uh yeah yeah it's a big get
together man yeah and uh
and so you know I paid my money to go
there as well so we're having a blast
bro it's it's great great party enjoy it
uh there's some people there right that
uh uh you know that I was happy to meet
you know and and it was it was all good
right so that was that was the first
year that I went there man and uh I met
a lot of good people man a lot of really
good people
but the second year is when things
started getting interesting
so we go to we go to Rosso's party you
know it's kind of it's like a it's a cup
but it's not really a cup you know what
I mean yeah everybody knows everybody
knows whose strains or what and bugs and
jugs
no we'll talk about nugs okay okay I
didn't know if that was the same thing
yeah yeah no that's icy mag okay that
was some Icy mag stuff right and so uh
early
yeah this is before that so then uh you
know we go I go to uh ncj's little
harvest party and that year there was um
Eddie Lepp yep and
and Jack Herer yep and who else was he
who's probably there yeah his wife
um
I think DJ Short was there that year
makes sense and uh
who's the guy who did uh the Canon Bible
oh Jason Jason King Jason King he was
there as well right
and they're all you know good nice guys
right my buddy Francis was probably
there have you met Francis not the dog
maybe maybe yeah I think he was there
that year
so uh so I had met Eddie multiple times
before that right out at his farm in uh
in Lake you know I had met any of that
multiple times before that right and so
so he knew me we weren't friends right
yeah but you know we had a we had a
talking relationship same thing with
Jack same thing with Jack Herron
so
we're all hanging out and uh that year I
had uh re-hooked up with the guy from
Hayes Brothers right oh wow and he gave
me a they're still he was still messing
with with the Purple Haze at that point
right is he still alive uh I don't know
now that was a while that was a long
time ago right yeah but uh he gave me a
derivative right a phenotype of the
Purple Haze which wasn't like it didn't
grow like the Purple Haze it had the
same flavor you know what I mean
um
similar color you know what I mean but
it just wasn't the same right yeah so he
gave me that tell me here you can use
this you can breed with it uh don't give
it away uh once you're done breathing
with it kill it I was like yeah all
right no problem so I used it
um to go across uh
to go across the grapefruit Haze that
I've gotten from Turtle a beautiful
grapefruit days man that I gotten from
Turtle right and I made a that's what I
made the gurple haze out of but uh
I brought the the stuff that I had grown
out this you know derivative phenotype
of this Purple Haze to this party and so
we're smoking it Jack walks by and he
goes what the hell are you smoking yeah
I'm like bro this is you know this is a
phenotype of the Purple Haze he's like I
knew it I knew it I knew that was the
Purple Haze I could smell it that just
that just like got my vibes going you
got me oh my goodness and he sits down
next to me you know what I mean and me
and Jack are sitting there he gets out
his his little Jack pipe you know his
yeah
and he's he takes a butt of the Purple
Haze and he stuffs it in there and he
lights it up and he's smoking on it
right and he turns to me and he Stuffs
the pipe right in my mouth right right
it was still slobbered on big time
I'm like [ __ ] I'm French kissing Jack
aired right now you are and so I took a
big hit man I'm like yeah bro I had a
nice bike yeah yeah so he gives me the
pipe right he gives me his pipe
and then I roll a big fatty joint love
the Purple Haze right so we pass it
around it goes around the table there's
a bunch of guys around the table uh
inspector was at the table as well CSI
Humboldt and we pass it around the table
and it goes around and it's a thumb so
you know it makes it around easy well
the first time I was around a second
time and this stuff when you get down
about halfway bro it was that it was
that type of weed that that that half of
the joint would just turn black right oh
I bet it was just that lung Buster man
just [ __ ] you man so it comes back
around and I tell Jack don't take a big
hit just take a little head jack because
Jack is sick right you know yeah he's
sick at that time yeah and he didn't
listen to me he took some big asses and
hit man and he starts coughing
and he keeps coughing
and then his lips turn blue
and I'm like
he's gonna [ __ ] die right here in
front of me hey man no so he had brought
this the man like from Oklahoma he had
some some cannabis church with Eddie all
right I don't I don't know what his name
was yeah yeah but he was taking care of
Jack you know what I mean so he comes
out we pick jack up we take him in the
house we sit him in a recliner he's
rubbing Jack's legs getting Jack to calm
down gets Jack to stop coughing and then
Jack passes out right falls asleep wow
so I'm like
thank God she's kidding and I walk
outside and I walk to the table and all
these guys are laughing
I just laughing I'm like bro that wasn't
[ __ ] Pony at all I'm still scared I'm
still all used to they're like bro you
were about to be known as the stoner
that killed Jack Herron look at that was
going to live be your legacy for your
life bro you know that is just not even
funny man fill them with Haze killed him
with the haze man so we're sitting
around right and we're still at the same
table
and
there's a there's a good story
at that time
the Mendo perks I brought so what ended
up happening was the Mendel purps had
gotten stolen from Jack Jack uh from
Eddie lips
it was actually Jason King's string
yeah yeah Francis gave it to him okay
okay yeah so so it had gotten it got to
uh Eddie lapse Eddie lips was supposed
to keep it under wraps not let it get
out period not give it away and somebody
that was working with him stole it yeah
and so then inspector got it right
several other people got it
um Eddie knew that it got stolen and so
inspector gave it to me and I had drawn
it out and so I had an ounce in my
pocket as well and inspector was like
don't bring that out don't get that out
that's gonna be just like that's gonna
be just like the Purple Haze and
somebody's gonna smell it and they're
gonna melt exactly how it is because you
know you know what that smells like yeah
yeah and so
so I was like bro I ain't scared man you
know me I ain't scared
I'm gonna break this out I'm Gonna Roll
It Fast
I'm right here right now yeah so I did
it I rolled it up rolled up a fatty pass
it around
and somebody who I'm not going to
mention walks by yeah all right and
smells you
looks over at the table at us like you
[ __ ]
and I'm like what what I'm like what
what yeah yeah so then they knew it was
me who busted it out because they
already knew that I was a rabble Rouser
right so
Eddie lamp is maybe 40 feet away
in the distance they walk over to Eddie
start talking to him about it he looks
over he's all mad dogging us at the
table Yeah walks over he's like who got
that out I'm like hey man that was me
that was me you know that it's out there
you know it's it's in the wind there's
nothing you're going to be able to do
about it bro let's just get over it
forget about it just just you know
release release the karma bro release
the karma and he's one of those type of
dudes you know what I mean everything's
Karma to Eddie so
he was like also where'd you get it man
I'm like bro
well well you know you know that was
really messed up I agree I agree bro but
it's out there it's out there already
done
so he stands there and talks to me for a
minute longer steps away comes back and
says you know what
I release the the Bad Karma on that
strain whoever's got it you can do
whatever they want with it blah blah
blah yeah so at that point you know
inspectors looking at me like dude
you're a dick man
you got us all in the hot water and blah
blah blah so
so then after that right
walk in the house
and Eddie's sitting on the couch and he
calls me over he's like come on over
here okay Bill come here sit down
I respect you for that man I respect
that you brought that out nobody else
wanted to they were you know they were
thinking that you know it was just going
to cause him problems I'm like hey I'm
ready for it bro I don't mind you know
what I mean it's better to be you know
out in front and take the punch than you
know just continue to duck and hide
right yeah
man that's good that's good I'm glad you
did that I actually feel better about
that now yada yada
because then we're talking
and he's inviting me back to the ranch
you know his his farm up there there's
30 000 [ __ ] pot plants right in the
vision of the highway
um
nuts dude nuts
um he invites me back over there and
he's telling me yeah you know what you
come up and we're gonna do Ayahuasca
yeah we're gonna get we're going to do
some Ayahuasca bro we're gonna we're
gonna have this just crazy ass mental
exercises and we're gonna do these
things I got this stuff by doing hi
Alaska a name after after you know the
morning we're gonna wake up in the
morning and we're gonna pee into a glass
our first pee and then we're gonna drink
our own pea
and I'm like what's up with that bro
yeah the body purifies it man and makes
it even purer and stronger so the next
day when you do it you just enter the
cosmos and just fly through the universe
and you know just it's beautiful it's
just beautiful
look Eddie that's what we're gonna do
bro we're gonna drink our own pee man no
problem and he was dead [ __ ] serious
I believe it he was dead serious man
well yeah
did you drink your pee hell no yeah
I'm not I'm not down for eyelashes I did
I did peyote before dude that was far
enough for me yeah I'm not into it
either anything I have to puke to enjoy
I'm not I'm not I'm not into it dude
exactly and people try to get me to do
DMT even this day but I'm like no no
that's enough dude I don't need to I
don't need that yeah I'll do some
mushrooms yeah I can handle those yeah
I'll do some shrooms I'm not even down
for acid anymore man I mean I I chewed a
lot of a lot of times man I'm weak on
that [ __ ] now I just I I've been I've
done stuff and like I know my brain and
it's just like dude I I see it I deal
with enough [ __ ] in my brain I don't
need extra
I agree yeah I'm not into that man yeah
yeah I mean that you know that was a
that was a good party that was a that
was a very eventful party obviously
right that's a beautiful story too
and in the next year the next year was
uh
oh no so that year as well man um
my wife is there with me right and she's
chilling
and uh she's sitting next to uh DJ yeah
and Jason right and he turns to her and
he's got his blueberry you know you know
DJ bro he's he's a nice guy but he's a
big kid he's a plot star yep and he
turns to her and he's like you know here
here check this flower out smell that
all right and it's just blueberry yeah
what's that smell like to you my wife
looks at him and my wife is a my wife is
to create now yeah she's like nobody
smells like to me he's like what
weed smells like weed
and he just he he got salary bro
he got salty right away right everybody
everybody at the table because we're at
this this like
20 foot long table you know and this is
what NCGA had the party with the 20-foot
long table and then you had jars
everywhere
you know of everybody's weed right
look at that time right and a lot of the
guys that were growing there uh they
were drawn with you know grow more grow
more 20 20. right and did I mean there's
no
come on man yeah
yeah you're smoking cardboard so I
brought this preservation Haze and I
brought the gurple haze and I had jars
of that on the table
and people you know you can just go
around open a jar you know what I mean
so you'd open my jar and that she would
just slap you in the face yeah you know
what I mean oh [ __ ] that smells [ __ ]
great people are grabbing buds you know
what I mean you have another bud put it
aside taking that home with me right yep
so now my jar is empty all right and
people are like hey your jar is empty
I'm like all right whoop take that jar
bring another jar because I brought you
know yeah I brought a box of jars of
each one yeah put that put that thing
there and people are getting butt sore
bro oh people are getting blood sore we
have the same kind of parties now and I
see the same [ __ ] like when when certain
jars go empty and the guys who think
they're the [ __ ] like just why is my jar
full
and then you know the other the other
thing about these parties too right is
joints are going around the table
and you know I look at the joint
and I'm like dude that has a that has a
one inch [ __ ] black as [ __ ] Ash on it
yeah you pass
put it out pass it on yeah and
people are looking at you you know what
I mean
people walk up to me they don't want to
confirm they want to confront me right
in front of the table you know what I
mean because they know they're going to
get the answer they don't want to hear
me later and be like hey man why'd you
pass my joint I'm like bro that thing
had a rock hard hash I could have
flicked it flicked it from two feet off
the table and it would have made a thump
yeah well you know I'm like that's
that's what do you use you grow more
right yeah well yeah I'll use you know I
use blue stuff I'm like well
use blue stuff that's what you get man
yeah you know I'm not trying to diss you
man I'm sure you make plenty of money
I'm sure you make plenty of money but
I'm not that's not what I do this is
what I grow that's how I grow it you
know it's a different methodology and so
you know I apologize if I passed on your
weed but you know I don't want to choke
myself out yeah and I'll be like
honestly you know I find the people that
will use
something like that we'll use a lot of
other things that I don't find appealing
either yeah
I got COPD and emphysema already you
know what I mean yeah I need more I can
imagine if I would have been smoking
everybody else's weed at those points
probably be dead by now right yeah but
yeah just you know looking at some of
this some of this Bud that was going
around dude it was just it was [ __ ]
horrible yeah it was horrible and
smelling smelling it was even worse
right I bet what are you smelling you're
smelling [ __ ] basement bat you know
just smells like Brit and it cracks me
up because you know you see this joint
going around right yeah that that's my
weed right there that's going around
right there yeah well how do you flush
and in my mind I'm like you don't you're
never going to get that [ __ ] out of this
plant yeah you know it really flushing
is a misnomer you don't flush your
plants right yeah you allow a plant to
use what's contained within you know
within the flower available resources
within the root zone right you can't
flush a plant right yeah it's a
misnomers but you know listen to these
guys talk about what they did it was
funny
and you know like so
that first go back to the first party
that I went to it was uh me elkslayer
and inspect the GT right and and Elks
layer actually cooked coaxed inspector
out of hiding
because inspector had never gone to any
of those that's right yeah I could see
that the fourth generation guy and he
was real real under didn't do any of
that type of stuff nothing right so
we're at the we're at the parties and he
was a he was a lurker on overgrow yeah
and cannabis world
and so when we met right he was like bro
I [ __ ] love the way you deal with
these people yeah and I love it this is
great I can't wait we're gonna have a
blast tonight I can already tell we're
gonna have so much fun and Elks later
was the same way it looks weird I just
love that [ __ ] and he was like God
[ __ ] left we go to the party
we're having a good time right and um
getting people to say the stupidest [ __ ]
on the planet bro just painting
themselves into a corner about how they
grow what they do and all this type of
[ __ ] right and so then after the party
we leave kind of early right because
we're just tired of the [ __ ] we
leave kind of early and we had a spot
near there uh Airbnb with a with a hot
tub yeah so we went we got some alcohol
we're sitting in the hot tub smoking
weed talking about the party and just
laughing our [ __ ] asses off bro oh I
bet dude right and I'm like so did you
did you hear what this one guy said
about how he does it he [ __ ] jumps up
Pops on his right leg twice hops on his
left leg pirouettes sprinkles sprinkles
[ __ ] dust over his right shoulder on
his plant and then sings Kumbaya yeah
this is funny dude we're just laughing
around stuff these guys are trying to
act like they like they reinvent the
wheel the way that they grow weed right
always no no you don't now yeah there
are some new methodologies obviously bro
sure I mean with the Advent of LED and
some of the different things that we're
doing now that people are doing now sure
there's new methodologies absolutely all
right but back then bro no yeah no no
you're just growing regular style OG
style and yeah it's not it's not
happening that way definitely not
happening that way man
but yeah it was um it was definitely a
trip being exposed to you know
personally to some of these
rock stars the pot Stars absolutely like
when I met Ed Rosenthal right I went up
to his uh went up to his place in the
Oakland Hills
I'm a big Raider fan and so I would go
to the Raider games and I'd be wearing
my you know my different plot shirts and
[ __ ] right and you know I walked by this
guy you know over and over again and
he'd be like nice shirt nice shirt nice
shirt yeah and uh and then he calls me
over he goes hey man I'm Ed rosenthal's
personal assistant I'm like what and
he's like yeah
assistant he was and nobody had a
personal assistant yes yes he had a
personal assistant
[Laughter]
so so
he's like you want to meet Ed I go I met
Ed before bro yeah yeah because now this
would be personal bro you can come up to
the house and meet ahead and and it'll
be great it'll be great you'll love it
man so I'm like all right fine man so I
put together a couple ounces of some you
know preservation A's and Purple Haze
right that grew organically
um took them up there and uh he takes me
out Ed is sitting around the table with
uh
rent from apothecary
yeah
I know Brett and I knew Brett already
from before right yeah up in uh up in
Mendo and uh
this guy Jim
who puts on
um the Seattle hem Fest this guy has
like seven foot dreads man okay yeah so
these guys are all sitting around the
table and they're actually doing a uh a
judging right they got all these little
little jars of weed right and they're
judging it
so you know this guy introduces me to Ed
introduced me to everybody else and uh
you know I sit down and it's like so I
understand you brought something really
really good my assistant says you you
know you grow some pretty good weed I'm
like yeah it was a pretty good weed bro
you know I think it's okay you know and
by this time I had not only knew how to
grill but I had learned how to
consistently and perfectly cure
is so important bro yeah well that's
what I that's what I learned from the
ogs at overgrow more than anything was
how to dry and cure properly how to not
screw up a good grow yeah dude it was
head and shoulders because I mean
literally I went to I went to one of the
first things that I did with them it
wasn't what the NCAA just partying or
anything right yeah but it was just a
little a little grow party and uh these
guys were busting out this weed that was
just
[ __ ] incredible dude yeah just
[ __ ] incredible and I had weed in my
pocket and you know the guy was like
you're waiting frankly I'm embarrassed
I'm embarrassed you know I I I yeah I
don't want to show you what I've got man
that's some of the most awesome I
[ __ ] heard in forever I'm like bro
what am I going to say I don't wanna I
don't want to break it out teach me
a lot of people do not have that ability
to self-assess their weed it's true
there were a couple of guys sitting
around these are you know oh geez old
guys right and they're like I'll teach
you what's going on man show me your
weed so I busted it out you know didn't
show them and they said oh it's grown
well I mean it looks good it's it's
growing well the main thing I could say
is you probably didn't dry it properly
you know what I mean and I'll teach you
how to dry and cure
[ __ ] yeah so I learned that [ __ ] now how
to draw and cure so I bust these ounces
out with Ed
put them on the table and you know
before Ed can even reach them Brett
snatches one of the bags right opens it
up he's like oh [ __ ] yeah oh yeah that's
my head right there puts it to the side
Jim grabs a bud and Ed's like hey man
what are you guys doing you guys he
brought it for me I'm like I brought it
for everybody yeah yeah so he's got the
other bag in his hand he's like what is
this when it was a preservation age and
I told him you need to be real careful
with that one that one is aptly named
Lobster stocks
because it is so racy it'll make you
feel like your eyes are out here
um I love it I'll tell you another story
in a minute about the lobster slots
right so so Ed is like Oh I like that I
like that man and I'm like you don't
need it you don't need to grab any buds
out of there and just give these guys
each a bud because whatever's left is
yours it's off yeah yeah I brought this
for you so he's like all right all right
so then we're conversing and talking
right and and Ed starts you know tells
me that uh you know when when I leave I
can have any book in his little his
little store room of books right yeah
I'm like I don't know man that first
that first Bible you put out Growers
Bible killed a bunch of my plants man oh
you killed him and and then uh and then
Brett was like yeah mine too mine too
and I was like yeah I brought up you
know a couple of excerpts that [ __ ] me
up he goes get the revised Edition
[ __ ] yeah okay
um
but yeah you know that was a that was a
good little good little meeting right
then I went in and you know out of
respect I took a bunch of his books
right they're still up here on my
shelves that's awesome I haven't read
them I haven't even cracked them right
but they're sitting there he had that
can't teach me nothing
um you know yeah I didn't know yeah yeah
I know a little story about that uh the
lobster stocks right yeah so it's uh
preservation Haze and it's um G13 hash
plant yep not the 88 not the 88 G13
not the one Indian guy got yeah the
Indian guy had was was derived from the
original
G13 Ash plant right and this I got from
Clips I don't know if you remember Clips
yeah breed Eclipse yeah reader Clips bro
yeah with the Pacific G13 right yeah
yeah pacifica's G13 yeah
um so
I got that uh and crossed that with this
uh this um
reservation Haze or what was the haze
I think it was the same dream for days
it was the grapefruit Haze as well
across both the present the purple the
Purple Haze with the grapefruit Haze and
then the uh the um G13 Ash plant with
the with the the nope
yeah yeah with this great free days and
um
this [ __ ] bro like I said was so [ __ ]
racy it was absolutely ridiculous bro
yeah
um
I grew up planting and it was actually
it was actually a 13 pounder yeah
it was wild it was stupid man and uh
and um
it was so [ __ ] racy that I didn't
even want to smoke it I didn't even want
to smoke it right so I was getting rid
of it to some people and one of my
buddies in Salinas he uh he bought some
pounds of it and uh he had he had a nice
little shop right a t-shirt shop and uh
one of his buddies comes in a veterano
right we're talking OG OG Mexican dude
old school uh used to be Norteno you
know what I mean socks up past his
kneecaps right yeah that's my kind of
person oh yeah and so so he uh
it brought up a nice size joint and
they're smoking it that's what my
buddy's like yeah I'm only good for a
couple hits off that [ __ ] bro I get a
lot of smoke Compares I saw this midterm
I was like what the [ __ ] eh I could
smoke anything bro I smoke black yeah I
smoke shims I just smoking anything give
me that [ __ ] bro I'm gonna finish this
joint man smoked the whole joint right
yeah you're like [ __ ] yeah I like that
[ __ ] man give me an ounce so he buys an
ounce
so he gets in his car and he drives away
he stops at a stop sign
he's waiting for that [ __ ] to
turn green
right
stop signs don't turn green bro so he
phases out
and then phases back in doesn't know
where he is doesn't know where he's
going has no idea about that [ __ ] it's
[ __ ] hard
he's freaking out and there's a sign
right up in front of him that says
hospital this way
so he drives his veteran ass to the
hospital says I don't know what they
gave me I think they they put something
in the wheels yeah oh man I don't know
what it is this [ __ ] is killing me I'm
gonna die right here
they gave milk and cookies sent them in
a bed
my buddy calls me up a little while
later and tells me yeah man
that [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] this dude up
sent him to the hospital that's
hilarious bro you have to put a warning
on that man yeah another one of my
buddies took some to a light show in
Florida
and uh another OG
I can't remember what his uh online
handle was but you wouldn't know him you
would know him and then another OG
um
no good names left okay took this stuff
and whipped it out and they're smoking
it in the hotel room
and the next thing you know this guy I
can't remember his name is freaking the
[ __ ] out
and somebody came and knocked on the
door and he tried to climb out of a
fourth story window oh no they had to
physically restrain him and hold him
down
from this week
there's been times where I felt like
doing that but I stayed in a little ball
that I was in you know
yeah I didn't I didn't like this weed
right I mean to me it was like it was
just beyond.com
no reason to go to that area because you
already know where it's at you know what
I mean you already know what's up with
that area I still have thousands of
seeds too of it man thousands of them
are they viable you think uh maybe
maybe because after after this airs dude
people are going to be wanting to the
most racy wheat on Earth and hitting you
up so think about it I know I know I
know I still have thousands of bees well
what I'm what I'm gonna do man is like I
told you we talked about it
um I'm gonna start doing some breeding
here soon I can't wait man let's start
doing some breeding you know bro I
probably have [ __ ]
one and a half million seeds man I bet
there's so much old school stuff man
things you know and we'll see you know I
got a I got a pretty good methodology
for popping them so you know if you have
if you have a good methodology for
popping old seeds I mean you never
really want everything to be hyper
sterile as sterile as possible like some
people like getting in like beneficial
bacterias and stuff all the popping
seeds I'm the opposite I want that [ __ ]
sterile so no bacteria can ruin that
getting back to the overgrow and yeah
situation right
um it was a beautiful place for people
to get together love a girl on cannabis
world man and on that fateful day in
2006 when I woke up
and clicked on the site and it didn't
come up
and then I put out some feelers and
people told me it went down I cried I
bet dude that's a family that's that's
your place people don't understand who
don't have a tribe who don't have a
[ __ ] tribe and weren't like in those
early on days online days where where
not everyone in the world was online so
it was it was a camaraderie between
people who understood that kind of
community and tribe so yeah that's
that's that was a lot for a lot of
people I was just lurking to just
beginning to lurk in 2006 you know it
took a it took a couple months for even
even a small amount of us to find each
other right and it was like
it was an icy mag right because I see
mag was just starting yep at that time
right and uh
and I think I think roll it up kicked
off right when
um overgrow went down yep yep I think
they they kicked off right then right it
was the first I think the THC farmer was
already was already gone too I think
yeah I don't know on that one
there was nobody to do it they didn't
have any they didn't have a a very big
member base yeah you know what I mean
and it was funny too because I started
off and I see mag right and then uh
uh Gypsy had heard of me right and I
came over there and he told me none of
those Shenanigans and you know you know
we don't play any of those games you're
welcome of course but you know let's
let's keep it civil and blah blah blah
and I was like okay no problem no
problem man you got it you got it and uh
I enjoyed I see mag I went to roll it up
roll it up was [ __ ] right off the
bat yeah throw it up bro the worst of
the noobs and so I went in there right
and and I told him yeah I want you to uh
I want you to delete my name I want you
to delete me from the website because
you couldn't delete yourself I'm like no
we don't do that we're gonna keep you
here I was like you know what
[ __ ] you either delete my name
or I'm gonna go with you every single
website every can of website and I'm
gonna dog your site like you I never
seen yeah because you're not gonna
you're not gonna have Kendo as a part of
your website when I can't when I can't
deal with you guys
yeah and and they you know yes they went
out and asked some people you know what
do you think and they're like
you need to delete Instagram [ __ ]
name bro get his name out of here don't
even don't even don't even play it's
just gonna be it's gonna be you're gonna
be [ __ ] because you're a little dog
he's a pit bull yeah and so they deleted
my name
uh the farmer I like the farmer dude I
still like the farmer right THC farmer
uh you know could pitch you later and
Mark's castle and I mean you know you
ain't [ __ ] unless you got a bunch of
haters bro
that's true man it means you haven't
pushed enough buttons yet dude yeah and
I love that [ __ ] man I do I think that's
I think that's incredible man like uh
talking about icy mag right yeah
nugs and jugs bro
that was a blast so I went to the Santa
Cruz nugs and jugs right yeah and uh it
was great there was a lot of guys there
uh who tossing me huh who threw it the
the original Nubs and jugs in Santa Cruz
joshimo
yo Josh Moe and uh what was her name
Outcast Outcast okay she just passed she
just yeah Joe Smo and Outcast right
wrestling people I love those guys Man I
Miss Elaine man like she was so sweet
and I wanted to do an interview with her
but she was passing like from cancer
over time and I didn't want to waste
some of the last time she had with her
family on an interview but God damn
she's a wonderful woman yeah but they
threw uh they threw that nuds and jugs
up in Santa Cruz right and brothers it
was great dude it was a blind Cup right
it was a blind cup and it was a you know
there was a lot of people there man
there was a who else was there uh the
guy who uh who found the white chrome
chrome
uh hillbilly on PCP
I can't remember his online name but
it's one of the guys we were talking
about earlier
um there was a bunch of good breeders
there good good good guys right and so
they had a blind a blind um
cup yeah so he just rolled up a bunch of
joints and just passed him around and uh
and you know I put my girl Haze in there
right and it was supposed to be an
indoor contest my group was outdoor
right yeah and so you know it uh it went
around and everybody was just like I
could tell I was just being you know
being being quiet I could tell everybody
was like wow
yeah wow wow turn it around right so it
ended up winning second place right
um it only got beat by 398 Bubba you
can't blame it you know it's just all
gas yeah yeah but it's good I mean and
especially because it was early on for
Bubba it's a good it's a great cut yeah
yeah it was just all gas but I was all
happy right and so then you know
uh
hillbilly on PCP and my other buddy the
guy the No Name
um they they knew that it was outdoor
right and so did Chrome so did Chrome
but I had showed him what I brought and
they're all like that that one that one
yeah put that one in there right so then
he'll be on PCP jumps it up and goes
that's outdoor [ __ ]
everybody everybody was mad they were
mad because it was because it was
outdoor right because people think
outdoor is not as good as indoor of
course yeah I grow something well I I
got some fine outdoor weed man yeah I
know I know how to make that [ __ ] fade
like nobody else man that [ __ ] turns
purple purple yellow orange light green
magenta have some killer plants bro you
know and you know it's it it has a lot
to do with the uh with the way that the
sun you know what I mean reduces by two
minutes a day it has a lot to do with
that right it's not yeah yeah it's not
the same way and I got a lot of my
indoor stuff too to do a fade as well
because I started reducing the time you
know what I mean I let it get you like
that that six and a half seventh week
and I start reducing the time by like
five minutes yeah I mean five more
minutes
yeah so then the plant the plant starts
to recognize that it needs to do what
it's supposed to do
you keep that 12 going the whole time
um the plant doesn't recognize it's time
to die until it's time to [ __ ] die
and then you know it it goes but you can
you can initiate that really nice fade
by reducing your time a little exactly a
single day especially with sativas that
light the [ __ ] long hours they like
shorter light hours at the end there's
an idea with my sativas too right to
keep them from herming or acting real
stupid is you take and instead of
slapping them into 1212 you reduce the
you reduce the time yeah you know over a
couple of week period right you just
keep reducing it
and then get to that 12-12 period that's
great advice I mean most achieve is even
if you get it down to a 14 and then
stick it down an hour after that you
know what I mean an hour one week and
then hour the next week I'm sure it's
gonna increase your 12 to 14 week flower
time but I mean if you're growing if
you're growing a true tie you know what
I mean
like yeah that's a lot because there's a
lot indoors how was that one how was
that one bro man it was
so what I did was I started it in a nice
big [ __ ] pot right yeah and I'm
letting it grow and that [ __ ] is just
it's [ __ ] going nuts so I flour it
and it goes even more it's stretching
even more yeah stretching even more so I
put it up against the wall and I put
this this uh you know 4x4 cattle fencing
across this entire wall and then just
weaved it
yeah [ __ ] cattle fencing you know
what I mean yeah and Let It Go and Let
it Go and Let It Go dude
16 [ __ ] weeks later bro I got a
million
buds little buds man yeah but bro
[ __ ] incredible fire little buds it
was incredible
there's a lot for people who don't know
if I remember correctly and this is the
story passed down late years on so maybe
correct me if I'm wrong it was grown by
a family in Vietnam for a period of time
and bread and then made its way here
yeah with DUI deweed a lot they read a
lot I didn't know you read a lot he was
an OG [ __ ] uh
Vietnam
ese in Vietnam
DUI
that's wild man does any of that stuff
exist still do you think
you'll find crosses
you're not gonna you're not gonna find
the original Delight that's too bad
that's right yeah do you remember the
smells or any of that from the
development oh yeah dude it was uh it
was real it was real
it wasn't Piney it was kind of
kind of sweet a little bit a little bit
sweet but it was more along the lines of
like uh yeah what what
what to repeat what I call that
because it wasn't like my name
it wasn't terpen lane or
it's kind of hard to describe to be
honest to be honest yeah that's how I've
heard it is it had a little bit it was
sweet it was a little sweet to it
um a little Savory you know what I mean
yeah not like not like meat you know I
mean I've had plenty of strands that
were like meaty but it wasn't like meat
it was a combination it was a
combination later on people said gelat
was like dead meat that was the the one
description I was like
it didn't make sense for a tie to be
dead meat smelling not Savory I could
get yeah it was it was like Savory sweet
man yeah it was an interesting it was an
interesting combination therein man but
it was really good
getting back to that nugs and jugs right
yeah
so we did the contest I came in second
it was great right
it was time
everybody's strippers
and so the strippers aren't doing their
thing man have a blast you know what I
mean dancing taking [ __ ] off everything
was great man and uh all of a sudden
the owner of the property it was like an
Airbnb before Airbnb yeah yeah the owner
of the property comes busting in no and
he's like I do not approve of this oh my
God he's going he's having a fit right
and the strippers don't even care they
start they start dancing right in front
of him like doing their thing and we're
all we're all high as [ __ ] bro yeah
laughing we're all just high as [ __ ]
cause I was smoking everybody's weed at
that party yeah yeah no there was no
grow more at that party bro
yeah it was all good weed man and uh
we're just high as [ __ ] laughing and
he's yelling and screaming I'm serious
you guys all get out of here just leave
or I'm calling the police and we're just
laughing until he finally got on the
phone oh yeah yeah he got on the phone
and was calling the police and then at
that point everybody was like
yeah
kill the nugs and jugs but we had you
know we had about an hour of stripper
you know
it was good it was good we had a blast
and you made it through the [ __ ] the
judging oh yeah made it through the
judging that was first yeah that was
first right but uh yeah it was it was it
was fun it was a good party man and then
uh you know that that that
got me in an icy mag because I wasn't
you know I wasn't that prolific and I
see mag sure
um
because uh the Cabana
right right
is he the one who created it originally
uh well it was d-man and Skitty skinny
yeah yep d-man and skinny right Beauty
Terry slider that's how I remember
Skitty yeah it's Kitty's Cherry slider
and the choco D yeah yeah so
when the Cabana started right everybody
was like you know we're gonna we're
gonna start a site right we're gonna
we're gonna get this going
and so Skitty approached me because he
was super impressed with
the moderator moderation and the
moderated right
and because I had laid out you know not
only did I point out each aspect of the
moderation situation but I also laid out
a a
um
scenario you know what I mean I laid out
a means by which I thought that a site
would be successful you know what I mean
without all the [ __ ] right
and uh you know it entailed um
you know Anonymous moderators because
you know if you're anonymous now you're
not gonna get a big head people aren't
gonna you know what I mean try to kiss
your ass and treat you a certain way
um you know there was you know no you
don't you don't ban people you simply
limit the you know their their videos
so you limit their visibility you limit
their their scope of what they can what
they can actually do
um you know and several other things so
you asked me to help put the site
together yeah so I helped them put the
side together we uh you know we we did a
bunch of stuff and and it was it was a
good site for a while right it really
was it was a good site for a while and
then uh
the um
the moderators just started acting
statelicos dude the moderator started
acting stupid and they weren't happy
because they weren't getting the
recognition that they felt they deserved
you know what I mean yeah
um they weren't happy because
um they weren't getting anything for the
moderating they were doing
so they allowed them to become part
owners and remove their anonymity
so as soon as they removed their
anonymity program just it started going
downhill right and a lot of the OG's
just started leaving because they were
getting a bunch of [ __ ] right you can't
you can't say anything
um it started becoming you know like the
world we live in now right yeah you know
a lot of people that were uh a part of
different
um
social dynamics yeah I mean they started
really pushing their agenda on the site
um pushing people uh into corners
and so a lot of people started leaving
and then you know I
started going back to being Kendo and
started calling them out started talking
hella smack right
so then I got my first band
and then uh you know it was just a short
band you know what I mean yeah yeah they
even removed the whole limiting your you
know your your visibility yeah yeah
started Banning people and then uh
they
you know there's a lot of stuff that
goes on behind the scenes you know what
I mean a lot of backdoor stuff you know
what I mean what we're talking about you
know the uh the uh the scene where you
know you the black market scene right
yeah yeah yeah
there's a lot of stuff going on there
right yeah yeah yeah through through
personal private messages you know what
I mean and everybody was doing it
everybody was doing it right there were
some people that were way more
successful than others yeah and they
were doing really really well
well
certain people who were of higher Renown
got butt sore because those certain
people were doing really really well
yeah they're doing better than that
cutting into their sales as they saw it
so they called them out right in open
forum
and open Forum yeah yeah which is to me
is kind of snitchy oh not kinda bro yeah
it is I mean it is yeah it's snitching
you're drawing snitching somebody right
it is dry snitching exactly and so so
you know me I came right out and I was
like no no no no no no no that's not
right man all you guys are doing the
same thing and you're trying to call
this person out saying that they're you
know what I mean not right for doing it
they're putting everybody at risk blah
blah blah you do the same thing don't
even try it yeah yeah so then I got I
got a six months man yep big fat man
right so at that point you know what I
mean a bunch of people left
yeah you know what I mean a bunch of
people left at that point right by the
time I got back six months later because
I didn't even post I just went in
looking at private messages yeah yeah by
the time I got back it was it was
already starting to turn into a ghost
town and uh so then uh you know and I'll
just be I'll just be honest right
I would go back every once in a while
just read private messages do my thing
hang out and then
um
recently I got into a little scuffle
with one of the original people that
created the site sure
um they like to talk [ __ ] they have
certain they have certain ideals and and
ways that they think about stuff that I
don't agree with and you know we we
talked a bunch of [ __ ] to each other
and the next thing you know they put out
a post on the Cabana
saying that I got arrested by the app
blah blah blah blah blah
so then they said for for security
concerns we're going to delete Kindle
oh
yeah dude and so you know I would tell
people at this point you know
if you're going to be on the Cabana be
real careful right because yeah to me
don't do that [ __ ] to other people
listening you know they uh also they
know that someone was doing you know
what I mean yeah but they know what
people are doing to DMS unless they're
reading them
I mean that was so silly that they came
out and said that you know what I mean
oh yeah they're doing this in private
messages because that was one of the
that was one of the points that I
brought up was how would you know if
unless you're reading people's private
messages
into a corner right yep and I was like
oh how are you gonna get out of that
corner and they tried to oh we don't
need of course so and so said that
they're doing it you've experienced a
lot of what I experienced on forums
which is don't be you know they don't
like the dude who pushes back and call
stuff out some people do some people
appreciate it you know a lot of people
don't want to be burned but
every single Forum nowadays has a seed
bank attached to it and that comes with
agendas
and that's I mean yeah I don't so so
back in the day right I wasn't into
buying seeds right in fact honestly I've
never bought a seat it seems goofy like
from your point of view if you're making
teaching how to do it you got access to
the cultivars you want what the [ __ ]
the point well and then and then I mean
in in the way that we did things in the
past right I I so I I started a a
campaign called the Great being giveaway
right
and literally broad gave away 150 000
seats
just came away you know what I mean and
and I did it anonymously nobody knew it
was me right it's uh Johnny Johnny gone
just eat with my head yeah and I would I
would put up a post and say this is my
garden right and then I would just put
up a bunch of strains you know what I
mean no pictures just strains yeah
and people would come in and be like oh
[ __ ] you don't have that many
strains going yada yada but other people
would be like wow that's interesting I
think that one and that one and that one
this sounds really good those sound like
some really good strains and it was all
stuff that was being donated from all
the the Breeders you know what I mean
all kinds of different stuff man
and so when people would say that I'd be
able to send them a private message and
be like hey bro check it out
I'm this is just uh you know this is a
ruse I'm not a girl and he's in my
garden this is a post so that you know
people can come and ask me for these
beans if you want them let me know send
me an Addie you know if you want to if
you want to donate five dollars that'd
be great because yeah you know what I
mean that'll cover your your cost of me
shipping you seeds as well as somebody
else's costs so you're you're not only
you're you're not only paying for yours
but you're paying it forward as well I
would send out those little
um you know like the three by five
um envelopes with the bubble wrap in it
you know what I mean yeah and it was
like a dollar yeah you know what I mean
yeah and so then you know they might ask
for three three strains and I would send
them ten strains you know what I mean
100 beans or more yeah and then in the
thing you know they had a note that I
typed up and it was like give give a
friend a bean you know what I mean so
please pass some of these beans forward
onto someone that you know that's
grilling you know what I mean so we get
we literally gave away 150 000 seeds man
just a game and you know I I didn't tell
anybody nobody really knew until my
buddy no good names left figured it out
that it was me right he was one of the
first people that I gave beans to
and and he was like he he came out and
and ratted me out you know what I mean
because I didn't want to yeah I didn't
want anybody to know right you know yeah
yeah you don't do things like that so
people can blow up your ego yeah it's
not it's like it it bothers me when I
see people who go out and and what do
they call that virtue signal oh I gave a
bum five dollars today so what here's
the video of me doing it yeah yeah
here's a picture here's a video of me
doing it right yeah virtue signaling to
me is [ __ ] dude I hate it I'm gonna
hate it yeah that's that's that's that's
how I was raised right by my you know my
husband raised by my grandma but my
grandma would tell me about how uh when
uh the Great Depression was around and
there were all the bombs they knew they
lived near the railroad tracks yeah and
so bombs would be on the trains and they
would you know get off the train and
they would just make a big huge pot of
beans you know what I mean my Grandma's
family would make a huge we're talking
about a huge pot of beans and just give
it out to the bunch until it was gone
yeah you know what I mean and feed them
she's like that's what you're supposed
to do but yeah I mean that you know
that's just you know giving out those
seeds is just an example of how we used
to do it right and then the same thing
you know you know I'm I was a [ __ ] dude
I would I would get strains man and I
would give them to everybody and you
know the the cheese pissed people off
another one that pissed people off that
I hoard out was the Albert Walker
yeah oh that pissed me up pissed people
off oh I bet it is well it goes back
that was that was Ducks yeah yeah and
you know it was It was a
you know I apologize to him big time
dude and I said I'm so sorry I did that
I had no right to do that
um you know I was a different guy back
then but you know they were they had the
Albert Walker and him and a couple guys
that he had given it to were talking
about it on the farm out in open Forum
right and I started a thread about you
know eating your ice cream in the
sandbox yeah you know you give your
buddy a lick you give your other buddy a
lick and then you show the ice cream to
everybody else and tell them you can't
have none and you eat Eddie Murphy yeah
yeah and that's where that's what
brought it to my mind right yeah and so
I was like you know I was like that's
[ __ ] man that's just Street [ __ ]
so then I got the Albert Walker and I
ordered out everybody dude
and you know me and Doc didn't get along
for a while right you know we saw each
other yeah at the emerald cup and we saw
each other at the emerald cup and uh you
know made up I apologize big time I said
I'm sorry bro however I can make it up
to you let me know
he was like you know what this long time
ago man it's all good you know don't
worry about it and now you know we're
you know we're over it you know I
wouldn't I wouldn't say we're friends
right I mean we don't call it on the
phone all the time but I got his number
I can call him anytime and you know it
uh you know I I I enjoy that because
there are a lot of people that I've uh
I've I've apologized to you yeah for
calling them out you know what I mean
but even then a lot of people are like
you know what I thought I deserved it
yeah I deserved it and I'm like you know
what though it wasn't I shouldn't have
done it man yeah I was just an [ __ ]
and you know I'm not such an [ __ ]
anymore you know for me I get uh I get
way more satisfaction out of uh the
minds that I can um
can alter or get into the into the line
of how to think as opposed to what to
think yeah you know what I mean because
that's more important than anything
right
how to analyze how to use their their
critical thinking skills yeah I mean how
many people do that nowadays bro
um I'm not gonna lie to you man I'm
gonna tell you the truth I mean do you
ask me questions here right and you know
someone you give me a little blowback
you know what I mean but
you know these are these are things that
uh you know other people probably could
get
um some good uh some good Knowledge from
that's the whole reason we started this
and you know we get bloke one thing that
that my co-partner didn't realize was
that by digging into cannabis history
just the genetic side just looking at
the genetic side and trying to start
putting some of these pieces together he
didn't realize how much blowback he was
going to get because from his aspect
he's just a historian you know but
you're cutting into agendas and money
streams things that people have attached
deeply to their their lives and
character that aren't true
and it's all coming out in the wash and
that upsets people one of my favorite
old sayings it's a CD business you know
the Oregon Market has been pretty tough
right so yeah had four Farms I've
already liquidated one I got two on hold
right now I got a fourth one that uh I'm
doing some things with uh it is the
devil's lettuce cannabis company so I'll
be doing I'll be doing that out here in
the Oregon Market as well
um I'll be doing some seeds right
and uh
you know I'm looking to uh I'm looking
to expand my um my Consulting business
big time yeah big time bro I'm uh I'm
doing a lot of Consulting I'm in Puerto
Rico Oklahoma
um I've done a lot of other stuff here
locally and I'm getting ready to blow up
my LinkedIn and that's going to be Kendo
Kendo the green wizard okay
um
ktgw Consulting
and I'm going to blow that up now so
people are looking if people are looking
for uh you know a a a
very good consultant someone who can
bring in the right help bring in the
right experts for your environmental for
your
um you know for your lighting
um I know the people for your
procurement of uh equipment
um help you to hire the right people to
man your grow to be lead Growers I've
been very very successful uh taking
um failing large Enterprises large
Enterprises yeah 400 lights from uh from
failing to making you know Millions a
year
so absolutely brother thank you man I
appreciate you I appreciate your show I
want to come back on man up you know
I'll write up some stuff man and and we
can we can chop it up again please do
dude this is has been amazing
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate
check out our patreon and our link tree
or description below our merch site is
officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is top notch
I've been saving old designs for years
for this purpose so please check it out
syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out