ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
how's everyone doing
well before NASA gets here don't forget
to join the patreon guys we have some
cool [ __ ] going on tomorrow there's some
fights
um
that I'll be watching
and it'd be cool
um I also have the Hawaiian lights drop
for the patreon folks all the Hybrids
are out they've been out for about a
week I'll be adding those to the um
non-patreon very soon so we got those
going on lots of good [ __ ] popping off
Farm stuff too if you checked out those
fed lines those are up right now for
everyone
there he is what's up
what's up you still a bastard how you
doing I'm all right I got allergies and
my internet connection sucks today so I
apologize ahead of time for
any [ __ ] ah it's all good I'm still
getting over the sickness that I've been
having mostly just uh in my chest and in
my sinuses still it's [ __ ] bad though
whatever whatever I got with Diane
I don't think I'm getting sick I just
think it's Mendo and Springtime and
things are blooming yeah everything's
out and about you know yeah yeah it's
about that time isn't it it is here
that's good you know things are I mean
event like what's funny is like a
million years ago when I first came to
California
um to see The Grateful Dead and Jerry
Garcia band
um I came out here in spring right yeah
and everything was Green
and coming from Illinois where I'm from
where it's flat as a pancake because of
the glacier it was I thought it was like
Ireland
yeah it was all like Rolling Hills and
and flowers and it was brutally cold
where I lived and it was a little nice
here
and I had no idea it got to like 110 and
everything died in summer
yeah
you know yeah oh I know oh I know here
it gets to be like 120 so well yeah you
you live in uh you live in the literal
frying pan yeah we live in hell yeah you
live in hell so
uh that's not my favorite part of
California what
I know I know dude I know you know I
mean I I appreciate the desert
but it's not it's not my spot we burst
Kevin McCarthy come on you you did you
know if you like flat and dry and very
very hot you know yeah warm nights and
good people good fun yeah indeed
so what what is our topic for tonight as
far as education goes as far as
education goes I thought we would chat
about a couple of things
um we would talk about maybe sort of
like the very late 90s early 2000s uh
period in the West Coast
and because there's a whole bunch of
stuff then that's pretty pertinent to
now yeah it was all kind of going on and
then I think we might talk about at some
point probably will fit in because it's
been uh a big topic amongst us this week
is a little bit of like authenticity
yeah and uh how to you know how to
address that yeah how do we address
authenticity in these uh times where
everybody's making money off something
being authentic
well yeah and people you know people
have their own their own motivations
their own wants needs and desires yeah
um you know that type of stuff and so
you know because
um
some cherry pie kush talk
cherry pie might be able to fit into
that a little late I've kind of avoided
the whole cookie thing yet yeah it's
probably a couple episodes on its own
and it's pretty complex so uh we
probably will chat about that at some
point but it needs uh that one needs
some fleshing out a bit yeah I would say
yeah yeah it's gonna be a deep one yeah
that's a deep one and there's a lot of
people making a lot of money off it and
there's a lot of rep on it so the more
money and rep you have it kind of ties
into the authenticity thing we were just
talking about yep uh you start talking
history and it interferes with anybody's
money or rep and all of a sudden they're
extremely upset yeah you know uh you
know I mean I made this I made this like
joking post I don't post much anymore on
IG but I made this joking post I saw
this cartoon and it was like I remember
it differently
in a way that fits my world view and
paints me in a positive light
that's for sure and you know relating to
weed history like you run into that a
lot
yeah
you know you you run into that a lot
you know so
um maybe we should uh I don't know what
do we we're getting up to 150-ish people
here yeah we like to [ __ ] for a
couple minutes and allow people to show
up yeah you know yeah and get to a
certain point before we start chatting
so here's one here's one just what is
the best blueberry not so dog
the best blueberry so this is another
one that when I tell you what I think
people will get upset at me yeah yeah
um because uh you know if you talk to uh
second generation genetics who is JD
who's DJ son or DJ they will say the
only legitimate place to get blueberry
is them yes
right yeah um but the you know for some
reason the blue bonnet seems to throw
these days at least uh some really
potent blueberry Terps and it's not mine
I didn't make it I don't get to get
credit for it but I did use it it's just
yeah to be transparent yes he did use it
so I mean there's actually a tie into
so I had my own blueberry line that I
created before
um during the times in Blue Bonnet was
being made and the Lone Star was kind of
competition to me at the time and I was
very egotistical about my blueberry of
course because everybody thinks they
have the best blueberry and I used it
and it did very true for blue traits and
very beautiful blue chirps and very
pretty but it didn't have much potency
for resin production to speak of and I
think Lone Star did it better than I did
I really do
so yeah what we're lucky is that it
still exists yes and you can still get
it from a number of different sources
yes
um ton so uh we're getting there I think
we're up to a decent time so we're going
to start
um and uh these talks have kind of been
we've we've been kind of moving forward
we started in the beginning in the 90s a
bit now we're starting to move forward
we actually still have like a third wave
of seed banks that Matt and I want to do
um that we never actually dealt with
that involves Canada and everything else
but it starts to get a little bit more
dispersed and difficult to get the the
accurate stuff so it's taken us kind of
a while yeah so yeah there's a lot to it
and and there's a lot to cover you don't
want to leave out a lot of stuff and you
don't want to forget a lot of stuff and
some stuff we do leave out and forget
and have to go back and tag because it
isn't that important so yeah and that's
kind of you know that's kind of one of
the things about these talks is they're
a bunch of History there's some there's
some speculation there's some
bullshitting
um they're trying to be conversational
and tell people about the memories that
people have
um they you know we'll talk about things
but they they get people bent under
shape already
um so rather than talking about like the
third wave of seed banks I thought we
could chat more about like like what was
happening on the west coast yeah which
is where Matt and I both live uh what
was happening on the west coast in that
era and how specifically California and
how that kind of like started to impact
what came after yeah
right so
just to let everybody know
um in 1996 in November they passed the
215 act uh the proposition 215 in
California and that made it was the
first state where you had Medical
yeah um now you know medical was uh uh
very restrictive at first and it was
only about four or five conditions that
it applied to and the cops had spent
their whole career just busting anyone
with weeds so they were also slow to
change yes because they saw weed and
they were like [ __ ] you it's weed and
we're asking you and so people think
that it like just became legal in 1997
uh it did not
um it started a slow process right
um and the arrow we're going to talk
about is sort of like the very beginning
of when gorilla started to end and that
process started to really take place
yeah you know there was the very
beginning of Medical in California so
things were starting to open up people
were starting to be less secretive
um and as we mentioned on shows before I
think it was 1999 that overgrowth
started and not that long after the
Cannabis world started I I don't know
the years on when they started
um so you know after a few years you had
this network of people
um that were connecting via these via
these you know these forums yeah
and chatting and stuff like that and so
one that ended up happening is uh you
know this this started a whole wave of
different things it started uh there was
you know really the forums were the
first time you could really ever trade
outside your circle that you knew in
person yeah
you know right
yeah I mean even even today I I still
see people uh you know in other states
where they say you know I can't get that
clone I live in this state and it kind
of blows my mind because back then even
like we didn't all live in like people
were getting Bubba clones from Ohio you
know that were in California you know
what I mean like if you didn't
necessarily go to the stake to get it
yeah and I mean you know one of the
things that's interesting about that is
that you know there's there's different
people uh for a lot of people
um we have a good buddy of ours that
lives back in the Midwest and you know
for him the forums and IG and Discord
and stuff like that was a way for him to
talk to other weed nerds yeah
right but for somebody like me who lives
in Mendo like everyone around me does
what I do yeah so there's no shortage of
hanging out like I'm surrounded by
people like me so there were some people
that like were you know really intent
upon getting on there and that was their
mode of communication yeah and some of
us just lived in places and stayed off
all that yeah you know so like when you
popped up or whatever it doesn't really
like correlate to like what you're up to
we all lived in the shadows yeah right
so tying into that I'm uh I'm probably
in my I don't know what it is I'm
probably in my mid-20s or so and I meet
this guy and I don't think it's weird to
say his name his name was Ron uh yeah no
right yeah yeah and uh uh Matt knows Ron
very well very well yeah and Ron was
Iran's a character and he's still around
and he did this thing where he started
throwing these Harvest parties in fall
uh in in my area and he actually threw
him he'd run like a big ass [ __ ]
house in Sonoma County uh Healdsburg
outskirts areas like that like a big
mansion essentially yeah and he had like
a catering company and so this thing
would be you pay a certain amount of
money and this thing would be catered
and then all these heads would come
right yeah yeah and so it was the first
time for me uh that I really was around
like
um that kind of scene because most of
those people that were there like they
knew each other from overgrow or
cannabis world yeah there was like
groups that came with people like me and
stuff like that that like were from that
area as well
but there was a lot of people from all
over and and people are running who Ron
is he's uh NCGA NorCal growers
association a lot of people associate
him with like the blue widow okay that
was one of his uh big jams
yeah and he used to help people get set
up he's always been pretty politically
active yeah no he's always been a lot of
the fairs and a lot of various things
that went on you know with you usually
have a booth and he politically
organized early
he got me my first uh Emerald cup
Cannabis Cup or a cannabis booth that
was the first Booth I ever shared in an
emerald uh cup was with was with yeah
yeah
so I mean I I I'll uh I went to this
thing I don't know I was 23 24 25
something like that and um I went with
my friends
I got invited by a buddy of mine and
what was neat about it is you go to this
place and you walk in they have like you
know huge dining room table or whatever
and everyone that wanted to share you
would write your name which was usually
like the handle Yeah Yeah from the
forums or whatever you would write your
name and you would put some weed in the
bag or the jar and so the whole table is
full of different kinds of weed and hash
samples
right yeah
you know and then it's
then it's where you hang out for two or
three days and smoke a ton of weed and
trade seeds with people and trade
strains with people and shoot the [ __ ]
yeah right so I go there and I'm young
and uh I'm hoping to meet like I am like
so convinced dude that uh that I'm gonna
meet these Old-Timers yeah uh meaning my
age now but that at the time uh you know
I uh oh dirty old song was there look at
that
um anyway so
I'm all convinced I'm gonna meet all
these people and they're gonna they're
I'm like it's gonna like unlock the key
to a bunch of old school strains I want
yeah right and I get there enough there
wasn't some of that there but there was
there was so much like everything that
was super popular in the very early
2000s
right it was like Apollo 11 Apollo 13.99
c99 uh you know white widow hybrids
freaking uh SSH hybrids uh yeah he said
it's the best times I ever had they were
super cool parties yeah it was it was
really cool to to see I mean there's a
bunch of people there who I won't
mention because they don't want to be
popular but I will tell you that's the
first place that I ever met CSI in
person yeah uh that's the first place
that I met uh Shaw who some people
probably know a 707 seed bank on IG
um who did the you know the chem the
chem dog bx2 and a bunch of work with
cat piss uh yeah a lot of people got
Bubba Kush from him yeah you know
um he's a he was a pretty big guy back
then yeah he was pretty involved Shaw uh
you know uh people like Jason King from
the can of Bible Kyle Cushman uh Jack
Herrera
um
you know just you know a bunch of
mountain men from Mendo and humble you
know yeah uh you know very and then
various types of people like chip uh who
now has a uh the real dirt podcast I
think yeah yeah um gold yeah but he was
actually when at those parties that was
before he started Royal gold he was
still working on like cocoa fiber then
that was so long ago cocoa fiber wasn't
even a commercial product available in
stores yet yeah he was planning on
bringing it to uh uh to America yeah he
hadn't started Royal gold but he was
planning on it right that's wild yeah
and so and so a lot of us that was that
was a lot of times where the where we
got to put faces to names yeah you know
like I didn't even know uh dirty I would
have loved to have hung out and talked
to dirty old song I didn't even know you
know if I met if I know your real name I
I don't know it so hit me up but it was
a but there was a bunch of people there
yeah and so like chip for instance who
started Royal gold
um he uh he had just come back one of
those years he had just come back from
Switzerland a tour in Switzerland right
uh because for people that don't know
Switzerland was like the first place in
Europe to really open up to cannabis
like outdoor and Greenhouse style
um and so when Amsterdam and Holland got
rough uh Shanti and and uh breeder Steve
and a number of different people shifted
over to Swiss yeah right and so Chip had
gone out and visited those guys
right and so he's got all these pictures
on his computer of like these
greenhouses full of Neville's Haze yeah
like 10 foot tall plants direct planted
in the ground
so it was just uh yeah Vic high it was
just really neat because it was a lot of
it was a lot of connected people it was
a lot of people that were active on the
forums
um it was five or six or seven years uh
before the reversal era yeah
so everything was everything was red
seeds yeah
everything there wasn't any NES I don't
even think I'd heard the term S1 outside
of a book
I don't think so I doubt so everything
yeah everything everything was hybrids
you know and people would bring their
hash bring their seeds bring their own
personal breedings and it was like a way
instead of mailing each other and giving
out addresses and DMS and all that it
was like a super swap meet right
and so it was really neat in that regard
because
for one thing uh Ron had a catering
business so part of the money that
everybody pitched in he hired his whole
team and you and he made two meals a day
for three days
that's wild that's cute oh yeah you got
to sit there and roll joints and smoke
and shoot the [ __ ] and pull tubes and
trade seeds and then you're [ __ ]
starving right and then like some like
tuna and crisps comes by the thing you
know and you're like I want some of that
and you're just so high and you just
start eating some of that and drinking
now you feel a million times better
um and so
the reason I bring that up is because
while now with a lot of these events and
a lot of these lives and a lot of a lot
of times like uh putting a face to a
name has become common yeah but back
then it was uncommon yeah very
so it was like really it was really it
was really like unusual and neat you
felt special yeah you know and I mean
there was uh you know there was times
where I mean I went I went there I think
yeah the foods were to die for old they
were really good they were fully catered
full-on meals they'd have snacks and
hors d'oeuvres that would be get brought
around finger food and stuff it was
pretty decadent yeah you know and then
just like anything else even if you're
an experienced smoker
you start smoking 8 10 15 kinds of weed
you don't normally smoke yeah and it's
the first time you're smoking all of
them
even weak or moderate weed will get you
pretty baked yeah eventually if you're
just pull in all day non-stop yeah you
get [ __ ] yeah and and so you know
there was different things where it was
like you can't hang out with everyone
yeah so you know you make friends some
friends I made there
um you know I kept up with really well
yeah others like CSI I didn't catch up
with again for a number of years after
those yes because you just you're in
different directions people you know all
that different types of stuff and um
you know uh Eddie let just it was kind
of just like a who's who
yeah and a lot of a lot of the times
those people Fletch people that weren't
very well known then yeah but now
they're all hella well known yeah you
know and they have some of the best seed
banks you know some of the best breeders
around some of the best collections of
weed around yeah
um you know when I went there I didn't
have most of the stuff that I have now
but I had I had the Maui and I had the
the chem 91 and the super skunk and I
had the super dog yeah um my uh my buddy
who doesn't like to be mentioned uh you
know uh from Staten Island he came a
couple years with us you know
um because we were still like right in
the middle of doing that super dog
project then
so yeah we had different phenos we had
the super skunk we had different things
we had hash that we had sifted from
things and all that so it was just a
really neat Gathering and time period
yeah people keep asking like what
happened but I think I think we did a
good job of recreating a little bit of
that just a few years ago
um a lot of people weren't invited you
know because it was smaller but I think
I think that there's still an ability
for our community to pull together like
that and have these big events where
people just get along chill and smoke
weed
um yeah so it was a privilege because I
wasn't around for for the wrong parties
at all but it was a privilege to be a
part of the the can Illuminati parties
those are it was [ __ ] insane to be a
fly on the wall at those events yeah I
mean they keep they do keep happening
um but I I will say that like they
probably won't happen like that quite
again no um just for the simple fact
that [ __ ] changes yeah you know uh
nobody knew who CSI was then nobody knew
who Fletcher was then
nobody who I was that you know I mean
there was people that were known
you know but a lot of them were we were
all in our 20s or whatever just trying
to figure out you know various aspects
of Life yeah you know and we were all
learning and trading from each other and
seeing what was up and it was uh you
know it was just days of and there also
wasn't a bunch of money or rep involved
yeah it was kind of like the last era
before that era started yeah it was so
we were all young innocent and dumb and
you know and all that kind of stuff but
less of a competitive nature maybe yeah
we were all I mean honestly I came home
with so many seeds from that event and I
gave away you know thousands of seats
yeah for free
yeah we just trade it yeah oh you've got
some Sweet Tooth by Blockhead from Steve
you know oh give me a hundred of those
and I'll give you 100 of this into this
into this and this okay cool you know
and it was like try it out
yeah it hadn't been monetized yet no one
really believed that you could make a
bunch of money in America selling seats
yeah I bet especially that era it wasn't
that it just didn't exist yet so it was
like all these heads each with their
everybody was happy this to like if you
could get people you respected to grow
your beans oh yeah that was everything
but man that was like you know and then
they hit you up and they were like dude
I found fire in your weed yeah now
you're like rocking around you feel all
good about yourself
you know good job and uh
you know and uh yeah in the Forum era uh
Caleb was white trash rednecker
inspector
now he's CSI
yeah who's terpogs I've never heard of
her
oh my gosh
we're gonna bounce around because all
those different things sort of interact
so just to kind of like put a
um you know Ron's parties were where a
lot of us made friendships with each
other
um where a lot of us met for the first
time it brought together different
disparate groups of uh weed heads yeah
all from their 20s through their 40s you
know 50s
um it went on for a number of years uh
it you know it happened in the in in the
Falls there was a lot of fire outdoor
and I should also mention
because this is pretty important to that
era where this is before the Urkel and
the and the purple craze really took off
yeah and so
um that's really important because all
good weeds still got grown and was sold
yeah there really hadn't been waves
where it was like get this one cut
yeah and this cut you can sell all of
that that hadn't really happened yet
um I I attribute a lot of that to
[ __ ] Jason King too for hyphen cops
up so [ __ ] hard that era I mean you
know it's it's it's hard I I don't
necessarily attribute it to him I
attribute it to the brokers
sure because I can't talk about other
areas but like in Mendo let's say 0405
if you wanted to have a 50 lighter and
you wanted to sell every gram of your
weed you grew yeah and you had
granddaddy purple or Urkel or something
along those armendo perps it all went
yeah if you had Sweet Tooth by Louie
maybe not yeah maybe not I mean you
probably could I'm not saying you
couldn't yeah but there wasn't buyers
shooting up from the bay like give me I
got I got room for x amount find it yeah
give me that sweet tooth yeah you know I
mean but you know because all that all
that work I should say that like so
and we'll talk about that um at some of
these things but
um what were the all the popular things
you can think of were at that party both
his flower and hybrids yeah and seeds so
the white family was crossed into
everything
uh DJ shorts the blueberry family was
crossed into tons of stuff uh Brothers
Grimm was crossed into a different
amount of stuff yeah
you know and then you know a bunch of
Classics and things like that that would
go around vikai was still doing big
stuff Federation was still doing big at
that time uh people I can answer that
question someone just said where's Jason
King he's on Maui uh we'll we'll talk
about that in a minute
um because that was actually well that
that'll overlap but it really was it
really was like you know you hear about
the legendary Harvest festivals that
happened in Humboldt or Mendo small
little Gatherings and stuff
um that's really what it felt like to me
yeah it felt like being able to go to
one of those type of things and back
then you really just talk shop and weed
with your close group of hermit friends
yeah
so getting to getting to go to like and
hang out with dozens of different people
for three or four days and chat and chat
it up
uh really set the foundations and a lot
of the a lot of the friendships and
stuff uh for later yeah it really made a
big difference I think
um Frank you know friendships were
forged there transfers were made there
but you know ideas of things
yeah for a long for a large part of it
and I think like when you started coming
in heavy
like it was all a bunch of that stuff
yes yeah it was still very much around
like when I first started coming in
heavy I was looking for the blue widow
clone I was looking for the the sweet
thing clone I was looking for all that
[ __ ] yeah they were looking for all that
and that was like that was everywhere I
mean that was like what everybody had in
clones what they had in flour and hash
and seeds and all this different types
of stuff yeah you know Kyle was there
documenting it for High Times although I
don't think Ron let him actually made an
article about it yeah because he wanted
to keep it like on the down low and not
[ __ ] it up you know yeah for sure
um but uh but you know it was
interesting and the reason why we're
gonna kind of Bounce Around to all this
different types of stuff is it all
overlaps yeah right so
um somebody asked about Jason King it's
probably a good time to chat about that
a little bit sure so at that time uh
there was this guy's name's Jason King
and he had this idea that I'm gonna take
a bunch of pictures of famous strains
and then I'm going to write my own Super
opinionated blurb about each one of
these things yeah and he called it the
Canon Bible and I don't think anybody
knew what he was doing at the time uh
would be would matter but what he did
which is super cool is he came out with
about three cannabibles yeah and they
sort of document this whole like late
90s through early to mid 2000s era
right before the Clone Wars where all
these specific clones of kush Urkel sour
all that started just dominating and a
lot of these random hybrids started to
be coming hard to find yeah
right
um so he came out with his Canna Bible
and I remember getting it and uh one of
the coolest things about the first Canna
Bible was that the entire first
introduction
uh is written by one of my weed Heroes
uh Rob Clark yes right and Rob did Rob
did this thing where he wrote this big
introduction into the Canna Bible which
honestly
I'm not sure anyone could have done that
and given as much legitimacy to Jason
King
Ron Clark writing a big long seed
history in Clone history introduction
yeah because like I've said before Ron
wrote the Bible for seed breeding Rob
sorry Rob Rob Ron Rob Clark wrote the
Bible for seed breeding marijuana botany
he wrote hashish uh he's legendary he's
an encyclopedic knowledge he's
definitely like one of the Elders of the
whole marijuana thing yeah you know uh
he's made lasting contributions to
cannabis and so him writing that and
what he did is he outlined which strains
which was a huge debate even back then
yeah which screens went to Amsterdam as
clone onlys and which strains went to
Amsterdam as seedlines yeah and a
timeline of who gave what that was kind
of brief but who gave what over there
yeah and then a timeline of like all
these different seed companies and what
years they release different versions of
things yeah that was one of my favorite
the his chart on the uh released C
companies it was the first time I'd
heard of like lowland seeds and all that
[ __ ] you know really the Pearl stuff is
him someone asking that yeah Pearl is
all the Pearl stuff is related to Rob
and so so for a lot of us that you're
trying to piece together all this [ __ ]
here's a guy in the know that knows all
these various seed companies and
breeders and work and all that and um
you know he he outlines this thing yeah
okay so uh you know so he so he comes
out with this thing he writes his big
long thing which is amazing it's my
favorite part of the book no offense to
the rest of the book yeah and then the
rest of the book is a bunch of Jason's
opinionated comments on different
pictures of weed he's taken and what he
thinks about them yeah from all over
right so I get this thing
and uh I'm super nerded out by it and I
love it okay well uh flash a little bit
and there was this gentleman who uh just
passed away not that long ago but uh
um his name was Eddie Lepp yeah okay and
Eddie Lepp had a farm in Upper Lake
which is about 20 minutes from my house
um and he grew a bunch of wheat there
yeah okay and he really blew it up he's
he's one of the he's one of the best
best
he was one of the early biggest
flaunters of 215. yeah like I'm gonna
follow the law come get me and so a lot
of people
um that uh a lot of people met there
yeah right and so I met Jason King uh
both there and I should should say at
some of those early Ron parties okay
yeah and we became good friends
right yeah uh through you know through
those connections through hanging out at
Ron's parties and then through
um you know he was he was a photographer
and trying to document weed and
everybody back then was fascinated that
Eddie Leck was willing to fill a field
full of cannabis and be like come get me
yeah yeah
you know uh and so you know and and and
so I decided to help Jason with his with
his project you
know he wanted to make a second can of
Bible
right and I'd lived in Mendo at that
point a number of years and Matt as
you're well aware uh weed was weed world
was still insulated then yes very much
going to get a bunch of pictures uh and
you're not gonna meet all the right
people without an in yeah yeah it's
still kind of that way for the old
school guys though you know what I mean
like but nothing like that guys were
hard to talk to but nothing like it was
yeah before you couldn't even find how
to contact an old guy at least now they
have like maybe an IG page or some some
way you can track them down that's true
when I first got into this I remember I
tried tracking down DJ's short to to
speak to him you know no dice you had to
find where he was going to be speaking
and see him in person if you wanted to
get a hold of him at that time
we'll bounce around just so everybody
knows I'm gonna talk about Eddie and
that and that whole era because that's
pretty cool but
um so these things will all overlap
because they're all going on basically
at the exact same time yeah Ron's
parties uh Eddie's scene at an upper
Lake
um the stuff that I haven't talked to
Canada Bible all this stuff is all like
happening and and is part of the same
flow same few years right so
um so I become friends with Jason and I
decide to
um help him with his project yeah right
um get him introductions to people let
him meet other people that can help him
kind of navigate through Humboldt Mendo
um and document and all that type of
stuff so
as a result of all that
um you know and I should say this is
that I I was pretty good friends with
Jason back then I haven't we've drifted
apart he's lived on Maui now for a long
time and I don't I don't go to Hawaii or
haven't since I had kids so we've kind
of drifted apart we're still on good
terms
um he's a super opinionated guy and he
used to drive some people nuts very true
very true like there are people that
will be like that guy drives me [ __ ]
nuts I always got along well with him
yeah right and on top of that I was very
sympathetic to what he was trying to do
yeah just another weedner trying to
[ __ ] put the pieces together yeah I I
strongly disagreed with them about
certain things oh you know yeah and all
that you know and we would battle about
you know all kinds of [ __ ] you know
um but that's not that's not any
different than today with people
um but he was documenting and there's a
lot of there's a lot of things in there
you know like you talk about like the
bull ride there's a lot of stuff yeah
that fell off the Wayside that's
documented yeah you know
um and uh and so I start helping him
figure out this different stuff
right uh and and you know and me and
Eddie and some other different folks
um started helping them put together the
candle Bible yeah right and by helping I
just mean making introductions and and
you know
can this dude with a camera come to your
scene yeah
because that's kind of crazy right you
got to have some trust yeah and I bring
a dude with a [ __ ] camera yeah to
your scene yeah you know uh and just so
people get an idea this is pretty funny
um I remember uh Jason got a 12
megapixel camera
yeah with a super nice lens on it to
start taking pictures because the first
can of Bible was all film right yeah
that 12 megapixel camera with a super
nice lens was over eleven thousand
dollars then oh my God I'm dead serious
dude over 11 000 because I was at his
house he actually rented this house from
Eddie Lepp that was in Lake County not
at Eddie lapse property but a separate
home yield yeah so I used to like I said
I lived 20 minutes in there for we were
so we were together all the time
and uh you know like like I said before
about rock about Ron's parties at the
time I was growing the super skunk
um the uh the the chemdog 91.
um
uh the black the black domino the snow
the Trinity a bunch of the Superdog
crosses and hybrids
um all that type of stuff and so
you know I start helping them get all
this stuff photographed
and and documented and you know and it
was pretty neat in that regard
um because
uh you know they um there's a lot of
stuff that was like that's been lost
yeah but there's a ton that's in those
books but there's video but there's
picture evidence and there's various
aspects right and uh
you know so
um if people are interested because of
that close relationship
um I had a bunch of stuff that ended up
in that book
um the the I grew the dog both I was in
this process then of growing a bunch of
my favorite strains completely organic
and then full of salt
yeah then in the same room at the same
time right next to each other and then
doing a bunch of blind taste tests with
me and my friends and trying to actually
see yeah which is better right so I so
there's there's uh the chem 91 is in
there as both dog and chem dog yeah
grown both ways uh my Mendo perps is in
there the snow the Trinity my super dog
seven cut that I lost is in there which
is a hybrid between the uh myself and
the guy from Staten Island made this
line basically a super skunk chem dog
line
um the purple effects yeah uh which is
uh Mendo perps crossed with FX which is
a cool story
um
and actually somebody said coral reef
that's not mine but uh our buddy Fletch
has been hunting for that for a super
long [ __ ] time yeah so if anybody
knows where the coral reef is uh hit us
up
but anyway like that that that
um that super dog thing is is the odd
connection that me and you have where I
spent years and years and years trying
to figure out who made the [ __ ] Super
Dog by asking around the whole cam fam
all that [ __ ] and at one point I
couldn't get any [ __ ] answers like
half half the people would say yes it's
diesel it's the same thing it's just
another day you know we made it yeah
yeah yeah the internet to be that way
but I remember before we met I remember
in 2010 I made a super dog 2010 trying
to recreate what I had read about in the
Canon Bible because I could never
[ __ ] find it and many many years
later when we finally interacted I
realized you were the source of the
super dog and that was really
interesting because it was such a big
long Chase for me because of that book
I I remember I mean I I don't really
want to tell the story of how I lost it
all but
um I I remember like I mean I had it at
all those Ron parties I passed it out
freely to a bunch of people
um I gave a bunch of Superdog hybrids uh
to mandelbrot
and it ended up being a lot of the basis
of a lot of his males uh that he started
using to get started because even back
then everyone had to use pollen yeah uh
not that everybody doesn't use pollen
today but everybody had to use like
males yeah like full regular males
reversals were
six seven eight years away yeah then
um so I I didn't even we didn't even
know it was the only reversals anyone
ever heard of is accidental herbs yeah
that was reversals and sometimes if
people wanted to make accidental harms
they would torture their plan
rodalization
they would make it dry out they would
make it almost die they would [ __ ] with
its life cycle they would just torture
it and see
can I get it to pop a bunch of pollen
right yeah
yeah like I I don't have like I lost the
super dog I lost the purple effects but
there's write-ups in that book of it
right which is pretty neat because then
there's there's at least pictures of it
yeah that's how it got documented and
why we we still know about it yeah and I
should tell I should tell a funny story
just because so uh Jason had this
girlfriend named Rebecca back then and
um he uh she was from North Carolina and
they had this strain that is is
semi-known right now called the
Mothership
yeah and it was this old ass weird
sativa
um and Jason just raved and raved and
raved about it and so he got his
girlfriend's friends to mail it to him
in uh in Lake County yeah right so
you're thinking today you know with all
the mailing Tech that people have you're
thinking some like small innocuous
package or whatever yeah so this this
[ __ ] thing shows up and it's a box
that's about a foot a foot wide and a
foot you know this and two feet deep
right yeah it's a big [ __ ] box you
know and we open it up and inside are
two motherships with a bunch of with a
bunch of stuffing around them in one
gallon pots tied to steaks and they're
like they're like 18 to 24 inches tall
yeah so instead of the person mailing us
cuts
they mailed us like one gallon pots of
dirt and 18 to 24 inch tall plants in
that box that's all there was you opened
the box and it's like two plants in
there
yeah that's wild but it was so unusual I
think I don't think the post office was
hip yet to like weed and like especially
plants in the mail sending big ass
plants in the mail no probably yeah and
there's actually in that Canna Bible
there's some uh there's some pictures of
that Mothership because I was one of the
first people that grew it
um because I actually had running Grow
rooms and there's pictures of the
mothership at Eddie Lep's property
there's pictures of the mothership for
my greenhouses and stuff it was a really
unusual plant but
but yeah it got mailed to us in the most
sketch way imaginable I remember in
Canada Bible if I think it was the
mothership that at one point Jason King
was trying to say this has to be related
to HP 13 because I've never tasted
anything like this that was one of those
extreme speculations that he was uh
known for I mean I should say I mean
he's my friend and everything like that
but you read the descriptions of like
the dog and the chem dog and different
things yeah and I even wrote down like
lineage in history for him and then when
he went to do his artistic
interpretation of what he wanted to
write you read it and you're like oh
that's [ __ ] yeah oh well oh well but
that happens all the time people talk
about all this journalist quoted me
incorrectly or totally out of context or
whatever else so but at least that's a
documentation and it was there yeah you
know
um and well so one thing I'll say and
then we'll move on and we'll talk a
little bit about Eddie's situation right
is that
um so we did uh I'm gonna lose my train
of thought but
um Jason decided to do a can of Bible
release party
for the second candle Bible and he
decided to invite everyone that
contributed to the book
with pictures right and everyone that
helped him put together and who's who
and um
they uh and he rented out this very this
very magical place which I don't know if
most people have heard of there's this
place called ore Springs in Mendocino
County and it's a natural Hot Springs
um and you know so it's got all these
like cabins in the woods and stuff and
all this beautiful Redwood and it's
right next to the monkey huh no I said
yes okay and it's it's right next to
Montgomery Woods which has some of the
tallest trees in the world
right I think three out of the five
tallest redwoods are all in Mendocino
County right next to this this hot
springs yeah so it's pretty magical
place right
so he does this thing where he throws
this three-day can of Bible release
party
right and we all get to come and we all
have our little rented cabins and
whatnot and it's the same thing like one
of Ron's parties essentially it's a
bunch of seed swapping and trading and
all this different stuff and had elapsed
there and and Rob Clark's there and and
you know uh Caleb and Sean like all just
all the people I already mentioned a lot
of the same people are there and a lot
of people that contributed to the book
Eddie Lepp his whole Entourage and all
these folks right so I got to meet uh
one of my heroes
at the time who's that
I got to meet DJ Short [ __ ] a that's
one of mine that I got to meet too what
a coincidence yeah so
um and that was that was kind of intense
because you know uh as we've mentioned
on previous podcasts you know if you're
on a weed nerd on the forums you've got
all the this is way pre-cooky too right
you've got all these like you know test
grows and stuff on the forums of all
these beautiful blue families hybrids
yeah and blue and blue work and you're
like holy [ __ ] yeah so you know I'm in
my mid-20s or whatever and DJ's
significantly older and so you feel like
you're meeting an elder yeah and you're
just starting to [ __ ] around you know my
buddy from Staten Island and myself
we've been breeding for a number of
years at that point with our super dog
and different things
um but we finally felt like we were just
getting started and here's this guy
that's like was released in Europe in
the 90s
yeah worked with sag Martha worked with
Dutch Passion had Canadian stuff had
this whole movie and everybody back then
was kind of on his jock
yeah wouldn't you say oh yeah yeah
everybody
I mean he was kind of a famous guy then
you know he's internet famous hem hempy
vikhai uh you know there was some really
like famous internet personalities on
those early forums yeah yeah
DJ's work was one of them he stood out
yeah yes I did yeah and he was one of
the first American breeders since the
Breeders who first brought their stuff
over to Amsterdam like Sam and Rob and
all those guys he was like the next wave
of people that got famous yeah and there
wasn't that much competition either yeah
people say happy was a [ __ ] and be
had a lot of good points but man was he
a tough character he was a [ __ ]
Booker he was a he was he was if you
said something I mean a lot of those
guys like Tom Hill and stuff if you said
something ignorant they just tear your
[ __ ] head off yeah he can't even be
put in that same category he made he'd
stuck as an idiot yeah he was he I mean
you know I had to deal with him too much
right so anyway I um
you know DJ is at this at this Canon
Bible release party right and he shows
up at the time I'm all excited but to
him it was probably like there was a
bunch I was a custody right yeah so he
shows up and he's got Manila little
manila envelopes you know with just you
know 50 and 100 of all his lines yeah
which I think back then was only four or
five yeah it was only a few lines at a
time that he would ever sell and they
were just super expensive for for the
time too yeah he had blueberry
um and he had huh flow and a blue velvet
yeah and maybe the Moonshine yeah blue
moonshine or Old Time moonshine one of
them yeah blue it was blue moonshine
blueberry yellow and blue velvet yeah
those four and so uh CSI and I get to
talking to him you know
and uh I have to say and he's still
around and stuff and all that so he's
gonna be kind of irritated at me but
um it was my first experience with
realizing that a lot of these old-time
breeders
don't know that much
hmm yeah I mean I thought here I am this
guy's this guy's been doing it 15 20
years longer than me yeah you know he's
made all these amazing strains
everybody's getting all these amazing
hybrids out of him and he's releasing
all these inbred lines and who doesn't
like the word Juicy Fruit tie or purple
tie or yeah this or that so you're all
[ __ ] pumped
and then you start talking to him and
he's vague as [ __ ]
yeah it was yeah like super vague
yeah he's um I think that is one thing
that I have found with people that whose
opinion I respect everybody that has met
DJ Short including me has had the same
experience except that he and with me he
just told me I don't own my own company
and that was oh you know he wasn't he
wasn't he was open and he talked for a
long time and we talked for hours over
multiple days yes
together he was super jovial and and
conversational and all that so I don't
want he wasn't it wasn't like we were
talking about Hindi he wasn't a dick
yeah yeah you know but but you know I
kind of feel like having being a weed
nerd myself and talking to tons of
breeders yeah um if there's one thing
you can do you can talk in detail about
your own [ __ ] yeah you should be able to
because it's your [ __ ] and it's like
you're [ __ ] a weed nerd and you're
[ __ ] into it and it's you know it's
your passion and you know and you can
just do that [ __ ] off a memory you don't
need and he just kept saying stuff oh I
have to go back and look at my notes
yeah I'd have to check my notes and you
know I'd ask him like why didn't you
know did you ever did you ever back
Cross or did you ever use any of your
original genetics again yeah and he was
like no you know he's like at the time
he was like I still have thousands of
seeds but they're so old and I haven't
stored them well I don't know if they
pop yeah
right
and so I just remember
like walking away from there and uh just
being like just I just thought I was
gonna get a wealth of information yeah
and in the hours and hours that I talk
to him I don't I don't even know if I
got too many tidbits yeah no
you know and then if you read his book
now it's gonna sound like I'm dissing
him it is a very very rudimentary way of
growing inside it is yeah definitely now
the one thing I will say that I think is
super cool about his book is he does
describe a bunch of uh
uh weed that he smoked when he was
younger that's my favorite part of the
book and then he also does this thing
where he has this I mean we didn't no
one used the word terpenes back then but
he tried to make like an olfactory chart
yeah like a smells chart and break down
what smells are related to what yeah
it's a really good chart and it was a
fantastic chart I highly recommend it
still because anything that trains you
to speak about things in language is
helpful yeah yeah so I mean he was
talking about like squirrel cage fans
and you know I mean that's kind of like
you know he kind of grew in trailers in
Oregon and uh
use very 80s Tech and never really
Advanced right
um but be that as it may despite being
very disappointed by talking to him
about things I still bought like 400 450
of the seats yeah every line he had the
Velvet the Moonshine the blueberry the
flow I bought you know I don't know yeah
75 to 150 of them yeah right
um and I and I I went home and I grew
them all out
yeah
um I think is the name of the book is
like cultivating exceptional cannabis or
something like that yeah that's it right
off the top of my head something like
that it's got a really pretty flow plant
or something on the cover yeah extremely
purple I think it's a flow but some
other people have said it's a blue
satellite too like there's some some
discrepancies on that as well well one
of the things I mean when you
interviewed uh Chimera and red yeah you
know
um you know one of the things that
Chimera is good friends with DJ so he's
not going to say anything rude but what
he did say is he kind of basically
admitted that he thought that everything
that he had was like the same line yeah
and it was just different Express like
DJ would see an expression within the
line and he would be like oh this is its
own thing it's blue velvet yeah and if I
just breed stuff with expressions like
that it's its own thing
but that's not really what was going on
either because he was crossing opposite
to to opposite when he was doing line
breeding working directional which is
what you don't do it was very artistic
take on breeding for the time and he and
and In fairness like we said before I
they were writing the book as they were
going you know like these were guys just
getting into canberrating there was no
books to be had you know at the time
when DJ was doing this so mad props to
him for [ __ ] doing what he did I I
was able to uh
work at the bunch of his work that I'm
stoked on I'm not as stoked on his uh
human work
um as far as human breeding but other
than that you know like as far as
cannabis breeding I I owe a big debt of
gratitude to him I mean I'm not but I
just you know it's one of those like he
that's the conundrum right is this you
see all this amazing stuff you see how
it all works you get it yourself and I
grew out imagine people listening I grew
out 450 seeds over the next year yeah
and uh
you know I'd like to say I found a few
Keepers that I I miss yeah I did yeah I
did I it it was unbelievably beautiful a
lot of it
especially pre-cookie there was
lavenders there was Blues there was Pink
There was purple there was various
shades of in between it didn't have a
lot of Terps uh and it didn't have a
very potent High most of it yeah yeah
for sure um but when I outcrossed it to
different things I got way better weed
yeah then anything of the pure lines I
got from him so you can imagine how
[ __ ] excited I am right because now
there's no seed bank there's no
middleman it's like I'm getting hand
written manila envelopes from the guy
yeah the real deal Holyfield
am I gonna find the fire
yeah here it comes right oh [ __ ]
labeling backing everything up I mean
you know how it goes when you're running
hundreds of things and you want to keep
track of it what the [ __ ] yep you know
it's uh it's a huge pain in the ass yeah
I just recently did that I mean people
are talking about you know popping 450
seeds in the in the chat not finding
anything I just recently popped almost
the same amount of uh stuff from from uh
blue lines and uh went through all of it
and had a very similar experience now I
I I will say something because there is
some there is like a an economic aspect
that we don't talk about right where
back then
um you know most fire indoor was you
know four to forty five hundred yeah a p
yeah so it was really easy to grow flour
and you have a side room or two with a
couple of Lights in each for
experimentation yeah you know the the
rate you know a 12 lighter could was was
everything you need in life if you
wanted to be so uh the economics were
really easy to allow people to
experiment and [ __ ] around yeah now
things are super tight and it's gotten
quite hard in mathematics and economics
are much more difficult right in this
particular period of time yeah um but
back then
you know it was like that's what kept
the cropping from being boring I got a
question for you this is a good question
this is from the chat but it's a good
question and relevant where did that
Swami guy come from was he around when
you were hanging out
so I no
no no no no no no no
that's weird see Swami
I did not I mean he's a pretty
recognizable character
yeah you know yeah you wouldn't have
even if you didn't become friends with
them or whatever like you wouldn't have
mistaken him no I don't think so no and
you know we'll get we'll get to that I
don't wanna I don't want to break it up
but we'll get to that
um when we talk about the authenticity
part in a little bit here yeah sure
um as as far as that goes because
there's a bunch of people that one of
the things about cannabis I'll talk
about super briefly is that you can just
sort of step out of the Shadows yeah and
then people are like I don't believe
where this person came from if I'm I'm
I'm who I am I would have known it yeah
you know
um so you know it's it's one of those
things where uh
there's a lot of shady characters in
cannabis
and there's a lot of and there's a lot
of people who make good and bad opinions
about people on the internet that you
have never met and you don't hang out
with in real life yeah you know Matt and
I are friends in real life yeah yes you
know like we're real life friends
made real love to each other so you know
platonically from a distance you know
all that
um but you know it it's different and
you have a bunch of people who become
Fanboys or girls of different people and
attack whoever they want to and stuff
like that you know and it becomes
difficult because they don't know their
enemy and they don't know their friend
yes either they know like a a social
media construct of that person sure
which is not the same thing no so but
we'll get to that in a bit so scrolling
back you've got you've got Ron's parties
right yeah uh being sort of a Nexus for
this thing you've got uh you've got the
can of Bible parties which were another
Nexus bringing people together you know
um yeah but I was I have to say I was
super disappointed because I really feel
like
you know if you take home 450 seeds from
four different lines from a breeder and
uh you don't find anything you really
think or want or want to keep you know
yeah that's super disappointing yeah
that it is disappointing that's a lot of
money it's a lot it's a lot of money I
mean he gave me a good deal don't get me
wrong it's not like I paid full custody
because I'm at the no he'd like to make
money too but the the yeah but the the
size of the room the amount of just
everything that goes into the economics
are growing it's a lot of money it's a
lot of time
and you know like I talked before it was
like you know there's there's eight or
ten American Elites of nl5 haze yeah I
ran 60 70 you know five days and didn't
find any of those Keepers yeah but other
people did yeah you know
um so DJ was a disappointment just in
the sense that he comes from like a a
different generation of weed nerd I
think yeah where they're just not that
deep into detail yeah you know I mean
one thing you can say about Rob Clark or
Sam Skunk Man is whether or not you want
to believe a bunch of what they say or
not they're heavy on detail
yeah a lot of the old a lot of the old
guys you talk to
um you know they're light on detail yeah
they don't remember or they try to make
it they did it
yeah but they just don't like it's even
the same thing with like the sour
stories or a lot of the stuff that
happened in the 90s that we try to get
to the bottom of yeah they didn't know
it was going to be important
I'm pretty sure DJ thought he was always
going to be important based on have you
met him I'm pretty sure he always
believed he was going to be yeah I mean
like I said over that weekend I probably
talked to him for five six hours seven
hours yeah we were there for three days
all we were doing was like literally
smoking weed and hanging out and
shooting the [ __ ] and eating food dude I
would have loved to have had that
opportunity with him I just it just
seemed so not interested in discussing
anything with me and it was it was it
was hard because I I did look up to him
so much and it's not that I lost respect
for him but it's just like the more I
learned about breeding uh Hands-On the
more I learned about why his lines
turned out the way they did and why I
was having such a hard time working
those lines you know um it all made
sense in the end yeah I mean you know
I'm not dissing him because like you're
[ __ ] around the 70s or 80s or even in
the 90s or whatever it's like you learn
as you go you know you bottleneck
something when it's early on and that's
what you got
yeah you know I I'm not dissing him by
any means because there's a lot like I
said there's I think his lines are
overly inbred
yeah
but some of the most Fireweed at those
Ron parties was outcrosses of blue of
blue work yeah so there's nothing wrong
with having an inbred kind of unique to
the Cannabis scene line and it takes
some outcrossing to really bring out its
true character no that's kind of what
what breeders would want something very
stable and worked you know I don't think
that's a disc necessary now of course
how do I wish that DJ would have
repopulated his juicy tie and his purple
tie and his original lines every four or
five years and kept fresh seed of the
original things yeah sure of course I do
do I wish he was interested in them and
didn't just let them go to [ __ ] even
though he had them yeah but yeah I do
um but you know I mean everybody looks
back on when they were younger and was
like boy do I wish I did this yeah yeah
I mean who doesn't have those regrets
about their 20s yeah you know I don't
even remember what happened in my 20s so
right so that shit's [ __ ] up you know
and so so that's happening
um all these kind of Bible things are
happening they're all getting documented
in that regard and Eddie leps was
another
place that was kind of like Ron's
parties or the Canon Bible parties where
um people overlapped a bunch yeah
because people wanted to come out and
see this guy is growing a thousand
pounds in his front yard
yeah holy [ __ ] yeah he's a wild one now
now it's like it sucks because you know
uh what happened to him is he ended up
going to jail for him and his wife ended
up going to jail for 10 years yeah
um and you see Gardens way bigger than
his all over the place now yeah and he
didn't do people should know this he
didn't just go for it okay
he did this crazy thing this is probably
worth mentioning where
the law said you were allowed to have
six plants and a ten by ten yeah so he
mapped out his farm in 10 by 10 grids
and he collected right
um you know he collected medical cards
for each grid yeah and each medical card
was tied to a specific grid
yeah and you could give him
your strains to grow in that grid
and he would do a certain amount of work
like feed it and water it and this and
that but like you could come out there
and do your own daily thing and your own
various aspect of different things like
that you could put in more work yeah if
you wanted to and really make your 10 by
10 nice and then there was I don't need
to get into that part of it but there
was a split between him and you yeah you
know so honestly it's like he didn't
just like blow it up and go for it
he literally had 10 by 10 plots with six
plants per plot yeah tied to a medical
card and he would just stack hundreds of
them yeah he was just challenging the
government to challenge their own like
little at gray areas of the law is what
he was doing pretty punk rock I'm like
yeah super punk rock super rebellious
and he wanted to have Eddie LEP Gardens
all up and down the [ __ ] the highway
yeah he literally felt like most people
wouldn't be able to grow their own but
why couldn't you come bring your medical
card to Eddie left's Collective yeah and
grow your own fairly near your house
where you could go tend to your plants
on the weekend yeah you know and what
happened to him was he he had this huge
plot in his front yard I'm not going to
dig him out I got some posters from him
but a bunch of pictures and stuff but
it's too hard to show like on the thing
um but anyway he
and then the the last year he had he
decided to get seven acres across
Highway 20 from his house in Upper Lake
and he was going to grow about 13 acres
of cannabis
yeah dead serious 32 000 plants yeah
that's a lot for the time yeah uh 32 000
plants all documented
right yeah all with all with and I
begged him not to
yeah because I was like dude I don't
think the DEA I don't think I don't
think they'll let you get away with it
yeah like I'm worried like they'll come
down and they'll bring the hammer down
you know
um yeah some photos of that are in the
can of Bible 100 there's a whole thing
on Eddie in the can of Bible actually
yeah
um you know and and there's definitely
pictures throughout the can of Bibles
that are from Eddie's spot uh you
probably won't recognize him if you
hadn't been there but anyway
um
so I begged him not to do it uh some
other friends begged him not to do it
but there was other people that thought
he'd be fine and they were really
pushing their boundaries yeah they were
pushing it hard
um and uh you know he got raided by the
DEA it cost him a lot with 32 000 plants
you know and he he him and his wife got
10-year sentences
yeah uh 10-year Federal Federal
sentences and the [ __ ] the the shitty
thing about Federal sentences is that
you have to serve 85 percent of the time
it's not like the state where you can
get off halfway for good behavior yeah
and him and he was a Vietnam vet and him
and his wife were older his wife passed
away in prison sadly yeah um and then he
got out and uh you know the world had
changed
he went from being this like Rebel
Maverick kind of center of attention
which to be honest he was kind of
egotistical and yet you know he tried to
form a cannabis church and yeah
you know he's [ __ ] that's you know a
lot a lot of characters right so yeah
um but he got out and the world had
changed now there's all these
[ __ ] doing Gardens his size
yeah and it's all fine
and you know he gave up you know um he
gave up a lot for that yeah he got
hammered pretty [ __ ] hard and there's
people there there's people that I I
mean I'll mention a few people I guess
you know
um one of the one of the Skittles crew
that like that spun off into Dying Breed
and now is his own person Shiloh
probably a bunch of people know
um I I was like the second person in
Mendo Shiloh met yeah um him in Dallas
uh who's got another you know who he
works with now
um they both were working at Eddie's
there was a bunch of people that became
kind of well known later that were kind
of Eddie's Farm hands back then yeah you
know and we're out because it was a big
deal it was a big mess it wasn't the
most organized character either so you
can imagine
you know he was definitely king of his
Hill and he spent a ton of time
entertaining and being himself
you know yeah and then you're trying to
grow thousands of pounds yeah
you know uh and uh you know and but we
were all young then a lot of us hadn't
none of us really made our names
anywhere you know it was all people that
you know it was just it was a smaller
world yeah you know for sure
um and so but Eddie had a bunch of
parties at his house he had a bunch of
gatherings at his house a bunch of
people from spyrock and Bell Springs
would come down because they were
shocked that he could they did big [ __ ]
up there but they lived such a crazy
lifestyle
um they were shocked he could do it
literally like you drive I can still I
drive Pie's house pretty often still you
can see it from the highway
yeah his old house that he lived at for
a long time
um yeah and that's the house that's in
the can of Bible
you know
um and and it was like a who's who of
legalization guys uh I should I should
say something else
um you know uh his last year's
um Jack Herrera moved and got a house
right down the street from Eddie
passed by that house too Eddie uh Jack
Herrera was at a bunch of those parties
um I have some signed books by him and
stuff like that he was over there a
bunch just hanging out you know yeah um
you know he had he had some health
problem right there on the 20. yep he
had some health problems and some
Strokes some stroke issues and stuff
like that so some of his last years he
was you know he kind of had like a
um you know sometimes some parts of your
face don't work the greatest yeah but
his mind was still there even though
sometimes he struggled to get out
certain things yeah um but you know Jack
is Another Hero yeah he had a whole
Cannabis Cup made after him he was you
know he wrote the book on the hip
possibilities yep um you know it was it
was kind of a it was kind of a smaller
world
yeah but it was all those bronze parties
the can of Bible parties Eddie lepp's
whole situation this was all sort of
like a NorCal you know uh Emerald
Triangle Lake County kind of thing that
was going on where a lot of people were
fine were starting to come off their
Hills and and and meet people
you know and it was pretty it was it was
pretty integral to what came later I
think yeah
yeah it was a lot of us that our our
middle age now and are trying to pass
down history we were looking up to
people like Eddie Lepp or Rob Clark or
Tom Hill uh who is a cantankerous old
man uh yeah
yeah yeah I mean he was like I'd love to
get him on here but we'll see well he
was a little he was a little nicer in
person but man uh if he didn't know you
and you said something dumb on the
internet you know yeah he was gonna he
was going to uh eviscerate yeah familiar
at all your ego he would rip it out of
your [ __ ] and make you feel like the
smallest little [ __ ] in the world yeah
people are saying there's very weather
there's people saying oh I might have
met you back then not so it's very
possible
yeah you know that you met me
um or I met you I mean there was a lot
of comings and goings then even if those
parties at Ron's parties like
um it's not like I got to meet and like
made lasting relationships with everyone
there yeah some of them were 20-minute
conversations some of them were ours
yeah some of them were in the tight
circle of people I was hanging out with
all weekend because that's how it worked
some of them were on the periphery I
mean it's just kind of one of those
things and none of us were none of us
were anything man yeah we were all just
a bunch of young weed nerds you know
yeah Tom was like yeah I agree Darnell
Tom was super nice to me
but you read some of the stuff when
people ask them dumb questions online
and holy [ __ ]
yeah right yeah I mean he's he was
highly intelligent some people don't
suffer no Foods no he was highly
intelligent and he didn't have a lot of
patience yeah I I yeah I I can't I can
definitely relate to that sometimes yeah
I mean but you you see that you see that
even now like you get so burnt out by
dealing with people you know yeah um I
think the same thing happened to Sam
Skunk Man
to some degree oh yeah yeah you know he
was probably nicer and more chill and
then you get you have to answer the same
50 questions a billion times and you get
accused of all this [ __ ] and all of a
sudden you're a cantankerous old man
yeah it's very easy to fall in that
category
you know but those guys were all legends
all heroes to us Vic Tom Hill hempy you
know uh these were all like leaders of
the scene you know
um and and Old-Timers to us yeah you
know Tom's got to be I mean Tom's got to
be 20 years older than me
I I don't know or maybe maybe I don't
maybe 50s
you think he's only in his 50s yeah I
think I think you're pretty old actually
I think you're probably older than him
you're in your 60s yeah you know it's
all the Oil of Olay yeah it keeps keeps
me young or whatever but
the reason why I'm babbling about all
this [ __ ] is it's where a lot of people
because there was essentially like there
was essentially like uh
what's the best way to put it maybe the
best way to put it is that in the 90s
most weed scenes were very isolated to
themselves to very small circles it was
very risky it was illegal everywhere no
one was really chatting The Grateful
Dead dead tour fish tour that kind of
thing there was some overlapping things
because people would meet and not be as
scared because nobody knew where anybody
else lived yeah
no I'm not dude I'm 45. Matt's joking
960. he's lying I'm 40 I'm 45 no I'm
definitely not 60. definitely not
um
you know but but you know I mean I'll
say the same thing too because I just
saw uh my buddy who I was talking to
earlier today uh skunk via uh skunk va's
on the thing right I go to Ron's party
and I am so hoping to meet all these
legendary people and strains and [ __ ]
and I'm like just hoping to get hooked
up you know and not to be a dick but
like I felt like I had the chem dog and
I had the super skunk and I had the
Mendo I felt like I had the best weed
there yeah I was like I had weed that
tore people's head off
yeah you know
and and uh you know it's not to be
bragging or anything like that because
it was literally just the luck of the
draw and the luck of my friends yeah
you know
um and uh and dead tour you know it was
one of those things where
um
it was it was sort of like a huge weed
Emporium yeah and it made a lot of these
connections and it made a lot of these
things that I tied in and the whole
reason I came out to Mendocino County
um was because I had a buddy who lived
in Ukiah which is in the heart of Mendo
um who after 215 passed was like dude
get the [ __ ] out here why are you living
in Chicago yeah so it was literally
connections from dead tour that like
brought me out here right
so getting back to what I was saying is
that
in Northern California and in Dead shows
there was a weed scene
and on the forums it developed a weed
scene and in the Emerald Triangle there
was kind of a weed scene right and then
these parties and these events and stuff
was sort of like the first mixers
yeah they were the first places where
these scenes started to like overlap
or the Forum scene and the Mendo and
Humboldt scenes and the Grateful Dead
scenes and all these different groups
that have ties to different circles they
start like a Venn diagram the circles
start Crossing
yeah and I honestly think that's set up
kind of everything for the American we'd
seen for later
I think so I really do like none of us
knew it at the time no by any means it
wasn't like we're like oh we're here for
history you know it was just it but it
did it was it was the merging of things
I mean I should say even back then this
was a few years after Ron's parties but
like um you know I mentioned the purple
effects that's in the uh that's in the
Canna Bible
maybe I should talk about that for a
second because people might be
interested in that
um the purple the purple part of purple
effects is just Mendo perks right yes
and the effects was this old garlic bud
strain that I got from uh the head
grower who worked for Tim Blake yeah now
Tim Blake now is very famous because
he's the founder of emerald cup
but back then he was just a big uh
gorilla outdoor indoor uh farmer yeah
and his his main worker was about my age
they are the purple effects and they
gave me the effects which was a super
golden gorgeous Frosty turkey thing
right yeah and uh you know there wasn't
any reversals but how the the purple
effects got made
um in the Canon Bible is that I had a
system that got a little stressed
because I had an air conditioner issue
and it took me a few days to get it
fixed and you know as as CSI will tell
you you stress the Mendo perps and the
[ __ ] it'll harm yeah right so the
Mendo perfs hermed all over the effects
that was right next to it
and me and a buddy got about a thousand
seats Jesus 800 to a thousand I mean at
the time we were hella pissed and the
reason why we got that many was because
we had like these six or seven you know
quarter pound uh six ounce you know
effects plants all around it that we
couldn't sell yeah they're a truck full
of [ __ ] seed
but we cracked this thing and it ends up
being super terpy
um you know and all that and it ended up
in the Canon Bible it was gorgeous weed
um and you know I should say that
there's been some battles amongst the
crew we'll talk about that too but
um some of that weed exists still I
don't have it I lost it in a bus but
some of that weed exist still and it's
in
um it's in the Rose
it's in the Sprite
um it got passed around at some of Tim
Blake's early and you know people should
know that Tim Blake had this spot called
area 101 in uh north of Laytonville
right yeah and he threw a bunch of weed
events up there and he threw um a bunch
of like essentially like weird Raves and
different kinds of like musical
Gatherings and and all that kind of
stuff and it was kind of like a scene
and you know the first half a dozen
Emerald cups
we're all super local events held there
yeah
um and so I passed out a bunch of seed
there was a gentleman that used to work
up there and used to work at reggae a
bunch called fuzzy
um that's not his real name but that's
his nickname and uh
you know and all that and stuff and so
you know he ended up getting the purple
effects from me and and that's who the
you know Tony Mendo and those guys got
it from yeah and it got blended into
Skittles and it got got all these
different things you know and it it
lives today
yeah you know uh no but that was a total
that was before Femmes that was
literally an unintentional [ __ ] up uh
where in summertime the AC went out for
two days yeah and you know got hot and
then I put a new AC in and everything
was good and then the Mendo P just threw
through pollen yeah and I had and I had
a feminized cross
um people are asking what about
California black rose as far as I know
it's the same thing same thing um so
what happened to them is like a lot of
cannabis terms uh Rose is trademarked
yeah Rose is a very specific kind of
wine and there's also another seed
company that has a totally different
line called Rose as well Relentless and
that's not related to I don't think it's
related to the same time Greek one but
yeah don't quote me now that I think of
that I don't know
so they had to change it uh because they
got because as you get legal and you
start entering these things and stuff
you start getting sued yeah you know
Girl Scout cookies and thin mint is
cookies because they got [ __ ] sued by
the Girl Scouts yeah you know the reason
why Skittles has Z's
yeah you know as they're trying to skate
around these these trademark laws right
so
Rose is Russian OG
crossed with Skittles that's the Z
cross the purple effects that's the e
and it took second place I don't know
three four years ago or whatever at the
Emerald Coast so what I got out of them
and and this this one's been I think I
have a screenshot of it it was Russian
Kush Oz Kush effects crossed back to
Skittles is the claim yeah something
like yeah yeah so it's close to yeah but
they had the the seeds that they had
were purple effect seeds from from fuzzy
that was from me yeah because back then
it was like there wasn't any I mean in
the same time frame
um I should say this too but you know uh
my buddy from uh me and and uh uh skunk
vie's old friend who um with the chems
and stuff we were working on these super
dog projects together and Crossing them
to all kinds of different hybrids and
and clone only as we had
um and my buddy manual brought uh at the
time who wasn't into seeds or breeding
wanted to get started with weed and I
ended up giving him a bunch of seeds and
some clones to get them started on this
project and he ended up becoming pretty
well known
um some of the stuff he got famous for
was based off that work some of it was a
little different from different things
yeah um but the the reason I brought
that up isn't to like lay claim it's to
say that back then we were very free
with trading things yeah because no one
ever thought that they could come out of
the woodwork and lay claim to anything
yeah
it's all like [ __ ] you you can't breed
with my my cut that's mine that's my
seed line I want Matt knows this more
than me because
um I I've avoided so far a lot of the
weed politics by giving away a bunch of
seeds for free yeah and when you sell
seeds like Matt uh you end up getting
you know I want half the seeds because
you use my cut in this one cross I want
rep I want you to mention me I want you
to give me money uh it's my [ __ ] you
don't have permission
so many [ __ ] I've had to give just
because of seats it's not fair not fair
yeah it's not you know I mean do what
you love do what you love so it's what
I'm good at so yeah yeah I mean so there
you know there's an aspect of politics
but this was before that politics
yeah people just swap seeds people just
swapped you know people just swapped
cuttings people swapped you know all
this different stuff it wasn't like you
know you didn't want your name attached
to weed yeah because then they'd [ __ ]
find you what the [ __ ] is that yeah it's
ridiculous you know you'd be you you'd
get you getting [ __ ] you get you get
in trouble yeah right you don't want
anything named after you what the [ __ ]
is crazy you know yeah and then and now
it now it's come full circle it's 180
degrees and now it's like someone's like
I didn't breed this cut but I did make
it famous so therefore if you're making
any money off it you must give me money
the role of the mac and it's in yeah and
it's it's in my terms yeah yeah you know
I want seeds I want money I want rep I
want all three and all this different
stuff but it's just like those things I
mean it's even like you know people were
asking way earlier on the thing that I
have to sign a disclosure for DJ
yeah DJ came up with all that all that
this is my [ __ ] you can't do anything
with it way [ __ ] later yeah yeah at
that time there was no at the time there
was no I mean people should give credit
you know I mean I just saw a homie
mention that people should give credit
you should say that I got this from this
person you know you also should
um if you got a cut from somebody
um you should give it back to them if
they lose it yeah it's really good
etiquette you know
um I've had multiple things that I've
lost and I've tried to get back from
people I I mentioned the purple effects
that's one of them it exists I can't get
it back without trading other things for
it yeah which I think is uh super shady
and a breach of the code
at least the code when I came up
um you're definitely supposed to do that
there's some honor I mean half the
reason people trade things is so you
don't lose things
yeah because angry girlfriend angry
boyfriend bust fire landlord moving
accident whatever you know yeah all
those different types of things
um
you know you you trade things back
amongst people you know yeah I mean one
of the reasons you know I'll say this
because he's because he's listening or
whatever but I mean one of the reasons
why the chem 91 didn't get lost
yeah was because there was a tight group
of uh you know four or five of us myself
uh skunk VA I see Collective my buddy
from Staten Island who all had it and
all lived in NorCal
and you know we all kept it alive
you know people sometimes people got in
trouble some people had to move
sometimes you had to get back from
somebody or whatever and it was like we
were all heavily invested in making sure
these things lived
you know yeah I mean that's that's why a
lot of these cuts are still in our group
you know like in our tight Circle
because you know we all move around we
all [ __ ] yeah you know he said he's
just saying I'll just say I'll just say
this uh and I I gotta keep thinking
because I keep wanting to say his name
but skunk yeah I like I have a hard time
bullshitting at PACE and reading
comments at the same time
um yeah I mean he did you know he you
know
um you know there were some people that
lost it I mean my whole name you know he
just said that I had to give icy back
the cut like five times yeah my whole
name not so dog is because our buddy
from Staten Island drove up to cic
Collective and got a bag of dog and
brought it back and it wasn't the dog
because dude was dude dude used to party
and he got mixed up and mixed up his
clones and he grew a whole room of chem
dog and it was like Romulan or something
like that
you know yeah it really was
um we had to give it to him back because
he was like what do you mean it's not it
it has to be
you know like no dude it's not so dog
it's not it we had to call him up
homie was all excited he's like I've
never seen it look like this you know
and I was like the reason why you've
severed me I had stuck my head in the
bag because I was in the bag I was in
the car with Staten Island I told it
before and I looked up and I'm like it's
not so dog it's not dog I don't know
what you're talking about you're
tripping
you know and what he said
that's crazy that's good because you
know they used to be yeah they used to
be best friends and I'm not you know
there's and I should there's aspects to
stories I always leave out because
they're personal and I don't think
they're super pertinent yeah I'm just
stoked for us because I want to get both
those [ __ ] on here at the same
time it would be cool to get homie to
get to come talk because a lot of the
story people should know and that people
are like oh not so wasn't there this
that whatever else a lot of the stories
I have
um you know come from Staten Island or
come from skunk VA talking to them 20
plus years ago yeah before the forums
before the fame before he got on and got
his handle skunk VA you know before the
cut was getting traded when it was just
our little crew that had it
yeah you know honestly like they don't
come from me they come from my memory of
like what I remember about sitting
around shooting the [ __ ] and growing
weed and and doing [ __ ] together
yeah you know
um it would be it would be a really neat
uh thing to do
um both to bridge that gap between the
two of them and get them to talk back
and forth you know yeah
um and you know we've been trying to get
dude on here for a long time actually
I've been trying to get stuffy a too
he's just so shy he's kind of a he's
kind of he's kind of prickly but I mean
I he him and I were him and I were you
know me and um and him and and skunk VA
we've all known each other a long time
yeah really long time way back and so
you know at certain point you know you
bury the hatchet about different things
um it's hard you know it's hard it's
it's hard being in weed and having all
these like interpersonal you know you
mix business and friendship
yeah you know and people have different
memories about [ __ ]
yeah you know and all that so uh you
know it it uh but yeah it's good I I
spoke to uh uh right before the show
actually
um uh skunk VA and I were talking about
uh chatting back and forth a bunch via
text about some stuff and uh we have a
ray of Hope on something that we maybe
thought was long lost so if if it's if
it so develops I'll report back
um but that's what that's what we try to
do it's like old friends trying to look
out for one another yeah you only make
it through this world you know the
people are much more important at the
end at the end of the day than the money
or the fame or the [ __ ] yeah I'm I'm
big into people you know I need enough
money to survive you know but I'm big
into people yeah you know so
um it's I like to see my friends doing
good I like to see and we've all you
know all of us are like semi-autistic
weed nerds in some way or whatever you
know and like you it's odd you know
living alone or living by your you know
living amongst uh you know small groups
of people and living weed and taking a
bunch of risks and staying secret for a
long time like me showing my face is
[ __ ] nuts
yeah you know and now I show it weekly
yeah
you know and
you know so I just I just thought it
would be it would be cool because this
era is like right before kind of Matt
came into things yeah
which is like I apologize because I keep
trying to get uh shows done where I make
it like more matte era than mine
um because there's a lot smaller
there's an era where like you know I was
having a bunch of kids and had some
issues or whatever and and Matt was
super engaged uh when I was a little
less engaged but so far I you know I'm
gonna drag him Kicking and Screaming
into his era where it's mostly him
talking and me shutting up but he keeps
making us do these things where it's
it's a little older
stuff yeah I think I think it's a lot
too because I've been you know doing the
live feed for a long time and I think
for
this many years I think people are more
excited to hear from someone else for a
bit and I I'm excited to hear like from
an era I wasn't a part of and I think
nobody gives a [ __ ] to hear what I have
to say about something I wasn't a part
of and I don't either so I think it's
it's it's not just about my ego on this
thing I think it's good to to get all
aspects of history on here and you know
there's a thing too where it's like I
mean we didn't know back in the day
that the chem dog was going to become
super famous uh yeah it stayed alive
um because our buddy from Staten Island
used to take it to
like you could meet him outside of any
Jerry Show Outside The Warfield and
probably buy a 400 ounce yeah you know
um you know all that you could uh you
know
um when when Jerry Garcia died you know
um and he decided to and and you know
skunk VA came back to California you
know he got cuts from homie and he
started he started growing because all
of a sudden he was settled down
he wasn't traveling and seeing shows and
stuff and that's where some of his
Polaroids come from of that old skunk
cut you know and you know small group of
us were growing the dog and we were
always we called it you know no one
called the chem 91 and all that that's
all like later we all called it the dog
and you know uh skunk VA and our buddy
from Staten Island they mostly grew
organic
um so they didn't want to call their
weed chem yeah they weren't going to
call it the chem dog I think that
picture I think that picture the super
skunk for me at least and what I'm
interested in is one of the most
important pictures that anybody could
have kept that and some of the Josh dog
pictures
um yeah those are specifically the sour
picture and or pictures of sour pictures
of the old Super Skunk super super
[ __ ] important for solving that weird
mystery of like was this super skunk cut
the same as the original Super Skunk cut
that is hard to that was hard to figure
out yeah and uh it helped a lot I mean
there's a thing too like part of the you
know we don't need to go over it again
um but we'll talk about it just really
briefly we were talking about like Ron's
parties and these and then the triangle
and the dead scene and all that I mean
the whole reason that the Francine
um got taken out east and you know the
super skunk came West and all that stuff
was all because of Jerry shows yeah that
our friend and and skunk VA were at and
friends of his from back east and
smoking weed together at the show and
then people wanting that stuff and so I
don't need to you know I wasn't there I
don't need to tell that part it's you
know that's that's he's told that story
pretty eloquently and stuff like that
but it is it is showing how those
circles overlapped yeah you know and one
led to the other and stuff like that you
know and so you know huh let's lock in
Skunk the a for next week next Friday's
got the aop on and he will be happy to
to be performing thank you skunkier I
don't know if you said I don't know if
he's we locked him in but if we did um
chat again this weekend I have a I have
a line on something I thought was long
lost that's dear to both of our hearts
so I'm trying my damndest to make sure I
can get it back to all of us uh yeah but
we'll see you know and I do believe I'm
not particularly uh uh superstitious
um yeah but I do believe in in the
energy of the plant and I do believe in
the universe a bit like making things
come to you and I can say for everyone
out there
uh for me at least the number one way
that you get the cuts that you want and
you get the things that you want in
cannabis is by treating the plant the
right way and having the right
intentions yeah
that's what I say because that that's
going to long term that's going to get
the right people to trust you yeah and
that's going to lead to what you want
and I do believe the plant has an energy
and I do believe the plant wants to uh
wants to
um you know wants to find people that'll
keep it safe
I agree I really do I don't know there's
not I can't prove it obviously but I
believe that there's collectors out
there and the plant hides yeah in places
where it's hoping that someone cares
about it and isn't just monetarily
attached to it yeah but loves it
you know and a lot of the things that I
have
um I wouldn't have because I would have
gotten rid of them as soon as they were
unpopular
yeah but I personally liked them and
cared about them and then there's
friends of mine that feel the same way
and that's why they have their [ __ ]
you know yeah and so it's it's a general
theme of among our friends yeah it's a
theme you know and if you get it's like
you get trusted in circles and like you
know maybe we can go into this there's
an aspect of like authenticity that we
were going to talk about before right
because we are kind of getting an hour
and a half into it so maybe we can talk
a little bit about this and there's
there's aspects of things where
now that I'm being public okay and I'm
starting to tell some of these stories
um I should say that there's a lot of
things that maybe like five or ten
percent of the weed Community knows
pretty well yeah
um that becomes difficult where how do
you let the other 90 know yeah so
there's a lot of like accepted facts
among small groups of people that want
to trade this kind of information right
sure and then you want to get it out
there and you get [ __ ] attacked yeah
and so you know Matt can attest that he
tried to get me to do this for a long
ass time and I wouldn't
right I mean well I mean you were just
watching what happened to me and you're
like [ __ ] that I don't want that in my
life
I mean I did I did Caleb's event up in
uh that's right you know and it was like
I showed my face I was in front of a
huge crowd yeah you know of people and I
was just like oh my God you know I mean
I didn't get my real name but it's still
at the time it was difficult yeah but
what it comes down to is that if
what convinced me to do it is is like if
you don't try to get some version of the
truth out there what you believe to be
the truth and it's just going to be
overwhelmed by [ __ ] yeah right and
there's an aspect where it's like and I
really get upset about it sometimes
where there's this IG thing where people
pile on each other
yeah okay and you know Matt's a villain
on IG yes I want to be to a lot of but
to a lot of people that don't know him
in real life yeah you know and if we
want to fast forward a bit before covid
um Matt and I
there was other friends that helped and
stuff like that so I'm not trying to
just to diss anyone I'm not mentioning
but Matt and I and a few other friends
kind of like uh got this idea to throw
what we called like the can Illuminati
party
and it was sort of kind of based on
Ron's old parties and some of those old
Gatherings but more modern yeah and we
decided to do it the same weekend as
Emerald cup
you know because
um
everybody would be in town
yeah so we rented a huge house
and invited a bunch of people over
on Friday and Saturday night of emerald
cup
and both years you know we had hundreds
of people come through the house yeah
right and believe it or not nobody
punched Matt no oddly enough nobody
attacked Matt there's a lot of people
that you that you don't imagine that
like respect him a whole bunch
yeah I don't know about that but they
didn't punch me yeah you know a lot of
friends you know there's a lot of
friends you get a bunch of collectors
and breeders and weed nerds and people
in the industry that come through and
want to hang out with each other
yeah you got to realize that like we
were trying to throw an event where it's
like those guys spend all day at their
[ __ ] booth
talking to customers and trying to give
their customers a little bit of
one-on-one time yeah right and then at
the at night time you know they get to
come out and hang with a bunch of people
just like them
yeah and trade weed amongst people just
like them and shoot the [ __ ] and you
know trade cuts and talk about [ __ ]
and do all this various [ __ ] you know
yeah and so we really had a good time
those couple of years before covid
[ __ ] it all up yeah that was fun dude
yeah we had you know we had a lot of
people we had you know CSI and body and
kind of I mean you could go there with
hundreds of people there yeah who's who
not everybody but a lot of people you
know some people were busy or burned out
or whatever you know yeah um and so we
were trying to recreate some of those
like more innocent time parties yeah
and you know and you know and I brought
tons of weed and various friends brought
tons of weed and we just have like a
huge table full of jars that were
labeled and anybody could freely smoke
yeah whatever they wanted
um and even even like just like the
forums there was a bunch of friends I
made on IG that some of the first time
they smoked the headband some of the
first time they smoked the real chemd
some of the first time they smoked this
different stuff
um was at these parties
they might hear you talk about it but
they don't actually see your week yeah
you know and then they get a chance to
do it and then you get to share a bunch
of your weed with friends and you get to
do all these different kinds of things
you know and so that part is really neat
because that kind of I wish you went too
dude we're gonna have another one after
covid
um
you know there's uh you know it's it's
just like a who's who of people that
have been around for a long time and you
would not believe how little beef there
is
there wasn't any beef it was just a
bunch of friends it was smoking out
eating a bunch of food having a great
time you know trading beans trading Cuts
Making Connections putting faces to
names right yeah all that different
types of stuff right and so you have an
aspect where
we've had some issues this week where
you know you start having these talks
week by week and like I said Matt's a
bit of a villain online and because now
I'm coming out and we haven't even hit
some of the controversial topics yet but
as I'm coming out now at all stuff
um you start getting enemies
you start getting people that are
annoyed that people are listening to you
or that believe your version of events
or you know on IG or on various discords
they want to like disparage your
character and say you weren't around and
say that you didn't have anything or
your weed was [ __ ] or your seeds suck or
whatever and honestly like it becomes
really hard because a lot of people that
are listening you don't know the person
you're siding with and you don't know
the person that you're against in real
life yeah
like in an honest real life yeah no you
know so it becomes hard how do you
choose you know how do you make stuff
happen I mean there was people that were
accusing me this week of not even see
the chems until 08. yeah you know and
and then I came out of nowhere and that
all my stories are lies and not so it
just means the stories are not so
let's let's be fair though like the the
people that were doing this were people
that were in the Outer Circle of our
friend group and never made it quite on
the in circle because they were they
were bad people and they fought people
over or they did certain things
yeah you know and that's my point right
so Matt will come out and say this
person's a scammer he's stealing Cuts
he's trying to [ __ ] you over he's trying
to take your money
yeah and then that person and like and
and some Bots and like a bunch of fake
accounts and a bunch of people that
bought seeds all attack Matt yeah you
know he's a [ __ ] he's a Jew he's fat
he's a biss he I got it
yeah Jewish Nazi all these various
things they're getting attacked and so
as I become a public figure a little bit
like they start attacking oh I was at
that party as weed sucks this and that
everything else and it's fine people to
throw barbs it's part of it yeah right
and I'm not even saying you should trust
me but what I am saying is that you know
weed as a lot of people lived in the
shadows
yeah and it's not documented and the
reason why we're doing a bunch of these
stories is because we want to get oral
history out there and we want to do it
in a conversational fashion that doesn't
bore you to death yeah
and we try to do that and then that
steps on toes and then people are
Furious and so they they can't [ __ ] with
the story
right
um but so they'll [ __ ] with Matt or
they'll [ __ ] with me or they'll say
you're a liar they say oh I know for a
fact he didn't touch cam until after 08
or he didn't have this or his this his
headband is watered down or whatever
they want to say about math it's just
the 707 yeah just some [ __ ] and it's
like you know and it's like you don't
want to spend all your life [ __ ] like
refuting a bunch of [ __ ] you know
because it's like everybody that knows
me knows me yeah you know and Matt and
vice versa you know and so we're trying
to get truth out there we're trying to
to get truth that like we're not making
any money off of
you know a lot of these a lot of these
podcasts are like weed infomercials
here's three hours of why you should buy
my seats yeah let's talk extensively
about you and why you're great and why
you're integral to the story and why
you're a cannabis historian and why
you're so amazing and this is going to
help you make money
[ __ ] I should have been inserting myself
into all this old [ __ ] God damn it yeah
you know and it's like you do need you
know we do plug for two or three minutes
some stuff that Matt's doing or you know
CSI or different people at times because
there is a financial element to like
making all these different types of
stuff work right yeah to some degree
um but really what it is is that now
that I'm old and I'm in my mid-40s or
whatever uh there might be people that
are 23 that want to hear
yeah or it might be 40 and want to hear
the real truth and then eventually you
just have to decide because there are
some real scumbags yeah that just come
out and insert themselves and then rely
on if you speak up I'll blow up your
[ __ ] life and is it really worth it
yeah I'll attack and attack and attack
and attack and I'll [ __ ] you over and
I'll make your life miserable for weeks
yeah so shut the [ __ ] up about what you
all know yeah and there's so much of
that honestly it's coming from so many
[ __ ] angles like it is a headache
it's right for sociopaths it's Rife for
shade balls beans have always been shady
and they're not getting any less Shady
yeah
you know they're just not yeah you know
no and there's no way there's but
there's a bunch of us
you know who have been around long
enough you know I mean there's this
running I'm not going to call call them
out or whatever but like I don't even it
was like a super long time ago and like
me and skunk VA were talking about
whether or not we were going to go to
these like Dead shows in the city
right and he's telling me he's like man
because he was he's a little older than
me and he was on tour for longer than I
was so he has more connections than I do
to be perfectly Frank because he's about
six or seven years older than me
um yeah you know he was like dude we
could go but he's like then I'm gonna
see this guy I know he doesn't pay his
child support
and I'm gonna see this guy and he owes
my friend 15 grand and I'm gonna see
this other guy and he and you know these
people's backstories and then it's like
you're going to see some people you're
like so stoked on
yeah and then you're gonna see some
other people and you're just gonna be
like man why can't you be cooler we were
friends
and you're kind of a [ __ ] bag yeah pay
your kids you know yeah pay your child
support pay my buddy back you ripped him
off when you were down and out you know
yeah and that goes on in weed worlds yes
and then uh what city San Francisco at
the time at the time both uh him and I
lived in Northern California he lived in
Sonoma I lived in Mendo so we were we
were thinking about going down to SF and
catching some shows at Mountain View or
something
um you know and that's the thing is like
a lot of times I'll talk about things in
like a general sense
um because you start calling out
individual people and then the next week
of my life is [ __ ] bad [ __ ] trying
to defend themselves yes and you know
and blowing themselves up
yeah and me and homie Matt and I and me
and skunk via we know a lot of history
yeah not all of it is not all of it is
is beneficial to the people
no unfortunately but then you can't you
know it doesn't pay to spend your whole
life trying to warn the fam Unity about
you know jack off because it's
whack-a-mole yeah I tried that I really
did and and it just it did not pay off
it was it was detrimental to my career I
will say I don't recommend people do
that for any reason whatsoever if you
have a an interest in being successful
yeah I mean I uh so yeah you know I mean
there's there's that aspect and so I'm
not saying trust me or trust Matt I'm
saying like if if you're giving us your
time every Friday night you get to talk
to us at length and ask questions and
stuff eventually
you have to maybe you can hear enough of
things that you get a general sense of
Who We Are
but I will say that IG is an image and
that sociopaths are very very good at
curating an image yeah you know they do
best and um you know and yeah someone
just said nobody's perfect people aren't
perfect you're right
people aren't you know
um people aren't perfect and I'm not
even trying to judge people that's why
I'm not calling anybody out by name
yeah I'm just saying a general I'm just
saying a general state of events I do
have someone I was going to call out by
name but um it's uh it's getting late
and there's one more big thing I wanna I
wanna get put aside so it's not just my
opinion I'm actually using their words
um yeah I'm not gonna it's not even a
big enough deal really but it'll just be
funny it'll be fun with someone I'd
looked up to
do it
do what whatever you're about to do or
you're not no no I I I still need some
of the um the ultimate the details yeah
yeah so because I don't want it just to
be my opinion I want it to be a dude's
own words sure no I get it yeah so I
mean and that's kind of what we talk
about like when people are like the can
Illuminati you know yeah the can
Illuminati is not like some kind of
organization or membership there's no
dues you know there's no one that
controls it what it basically means is
that you're enough of a weed head that
you care enough of the history to hold
on to strains to hold on to seeds to
want to dig for the truth
yeah and you talk to other people like
that and then basically it's a it's a
like-minded group
of people and we know who each other are
and it's like even amongst that group
there's not even really Trading
no there's just like dude like once you
know it's like uh you know a skunk VA
and I were talking earlier today about
it it's like we're not going to trade
anything no like it's like oh you need a
couple of these and and I can get you
this or whatever it's it's not like a
trade it's more just like
you know this is what I have this is
what you have yeah you know I don't
think there's anything wrong with
trading because trading is perfectly
acceptable especially if you don't know
each other but once you've been personal
friends for a couple of decades yeah
it's just friends helping friends yeah
you know and a lot of the ways that this
stuff exists like you know our history
that's really why I'm chatting is
because I don't want all of our history
to be lost no
I wanted to be out there in some kind of
form and it's almost all oral
yeah and and with a lot of the forums
going down over the years whether it be
from the feds you know getting a hold of
the icmag server to uh you know can a
collective pot pimp any of the the the
seed Depot any of those that have gone
down they had a lot of uh information on
them like sea Depot a lot of people that
people look at today as old school
Heroes and whatnot or really trustworthy
people all popped up on seed Depot and
their whole history is gone because
that's that site was gone the dude
disappeared after [ __ ] everyone over
that owned it so
um that's gone but it's in a lot of
people's memories so this is really the
only chance we have to put that out
there yeah and so we're just we're just
trying to We're just trying to like
regurgitate stuff and get it out there
and get different versions of things
yeah you know
um and and you know like like anything
you know some of these stories there's
people that have different memories yeah
there's people that have different
versions even like the three or four
people that were there might not tell
the same Tale
yeah they were the ones that were there
I know I got a nickname for being a
power bottom at the last party and I'm
pretty sure I was power top pretty sure
you know but I mean it's cool because
then you get then you get you know these
parties these gatherings and stuff they
really are bonding
yeah these really are where human
connections are made you get to smoke a
bunch of your good friends weed you get
to see them in person you get to hear
what their voice sounds like and and
hear them laugh you get to break bread
and food with people
you know yeah
um and you get to share weed and share
experiences and so I think that's you
know what maybe we can get the candle
can Illuminati parties together again uh
now that kovid seems to be dying down
and there's lots of people that are
either been infected or vaccinated and
it's not so much like the plague yeah it
was for a few years where it was
shutting [ __ ] down yeah um but those
kind of gatherings are important and so
tonight you know we're almost at two
hours so I'll probably shut up here in a
second but I just wanted to give like a
general random overview of some of the
overlapping things that were happening
in that era yeah it really set the stage
for everything that came after
yeah it was really where a lot of
friendships were made it was where a lot
of trading and a lot of seed exchange
was done it was where a lot of cuttings
and a lot of people smoking other
people's weed and learning happened and
then a lot of those guys
um ended up becoming super well known in
the community
yeah you know
um so you know it it it uh you know but
you don't know it at the time
no that's that's the funny thing about
history is you don't know if you're if
you're making it you don't know you know
so
um but really what it boils down to is
we're all just people
some of us care about the plant
yeah uh some of us care about wrapping
money and and and you know scamming
people and there's a big conflict
between those two right now yeah in the
community there's been one for a long
time
yeah but it's gotten more public and I
mean even like you know Matt's been
doxed before you know and even some of
those comments I was referencing that
we're not going to mention this week
people were saying my real name
yeah um not that I cared to some degree
because
um it's it you know like I'm showing my
face every week so yeah principle of the
thing though you're not saying your
Christian name every week no I'm not
saying my Christian name every week or
anything like that you know and so you
know but but what's funny about that is
that I can use that later to prove
something that will like blow them up in
the face yes
yeah and I've been pushed enough enough
times by this human being to that you
know just uh it sucks to have to do it
but because they're saying such extreme
[ __ ] like there's only a few things in
life that I take real personal is when
you talk about my friends family or you
call me a [ __ ] Nazi like I spent my
whole young life just literally fist
fighting Nazis and being punched by them
many many many times so I take it very
seriously when someone accuses me of
such things so yeah
and I'm a Jewish Mexican yeah
there's not there's not too many Nazi
Jews you know it's kind of unusual but
so anyway Matt if you want to do your
plug because we're almost two hours this
year or whatever
yeah so we have our patreon it's called
the breeder Syndicate patreon the way to
find it is to go to Google and type in
breeder Syndicate patreon if you go to
patreon and type in preacher Syndicate
it's not going to come up because it is
a plot Channel and you cannot search pot
channels so go to Google type in breeder
Syndicate patreon uh tomorrow I'm gonna
be watching fights if you want to you
know hang out and do some fight watching
we could do that
um we have uh the the Santa Cruz goat
farm
um fem lines the the reverse arcade of
train wreck lines
um for sale right now on the site go
check them out my boy Pat's a [ __ ]
killer dude and he he made some killer
things including the Santa Cruz Blue
Dream
um train wreck which I'm really really
stoked to see
um we also have uh me and csi's uh
Hawaiian lights drop I'm about to make
the Hawaiian lights hybrids public so
everybody can [ __ ] join in and and
grab that [ __ ]
um so go check it out
um yeah so I think I think that's it go
check out Speak Easy they do all the
editing at the podcast and stuff so go
give them support and follow it and
we'll also say one thing after Matt did
all that you know we're getting up to
200 230 250 people a week now doing this
every every Friday
um thank you all for listening yeah
thank you all for taking time out of
your night to [ __ ] with us and ask
questions as always you can reach reach
me on IG you can message me
um he's been approved improving or
approving people so I've literally
approved like 1500 people this week and
it keeps going if you really want to get
approved send me a message
[Music]
um and I'll see it and I'll do it faster
for you I'm trying to get through but
everyone I really appreciate you giving
us your some part of your Friday night
and we're gonna try to get more topics
and more history out there and keep it
fun so thank you all so much thank you
guys uh see you next week cheers
[Music]