what up fam it's me Chuck dog AKA Chucky
pin AKA Chuck God Chuck Chucky Chuck
Master you know what I mean what's going
on guys and girls I hope y'all are doing
okay I know I am I've been away for a
little while not by choice but because
YouTube isn't really happy with me and
Matt how we've been cursing and showing
plants so we can't be doing none of that
moving forward for a little bit y'all I
am working on some stuff some growing
videos some tips some little plant
videos so we can showcase and show off
the guys and gals gear from the Discord
if you haven't by now subscribe like
comment join the patreon it's $5 a month
you get into the Discord you get a 30%
discount on all Riot and a few other of
the guys and gals gear on Matt Riot's
website uh right seeds.com and you get
to hang out with truck dog and all the
cool breeders and all the other people
that are in the community get to kick it
with them Matt ain't going to be here
tonight he's had a little thing pop up
I'm not going to sure be sure if I'm
going to be able to upload this so
please bear with me and have some
patience uh I'm just going to get well
this is actually tobacco and I'm smoking
tobacco inside of it so you know we're
going to hang out I'm going to smoke
tobacco and I'm going to tell yall some
stories I'm going to give you a couple
little tips things like that people keep
pouring into my inbox saying stuff like
Chucky what what do you mean by some of
the stuff you're saying in these
episodes with Cana with growing bigger
plants and one gallon pots stuff like
that well I wanted to go on on a
freaking uh grow log a video grow log
with y'all and show you how to how I do
it you know I don't really think there's
one
right way to do it people get good
results with all kinds of ways but there
are people out there that want some help
and they want some tips and Matt isn't
really into the growing stuff or giving
you know he's more into the breeder and
the history aspect of it so I'm going to
get y'all some videos it might not be on
this channel it might have to be through
the patreon it might have to be through
the Discord it might have to be on
another Channel but I'm going to get
y'all some freaking plant videos I'm
going to teach you guys how to do the
[ __ ] that I do it Ain the best in the
world but it will get you from the seed
to harvest I can promise you that but
one thing I wanted to talk about today
is a couple well main the main thing is
I freaking hate trilus Nets I hate Nets
I hate trying to train my plants under
one I hate trying to do a pollen Chuck I
hate popping new seeds and I'm trying to
watch out for hery Hermes and uh you
know interx traits I'm looking for this
[ __ ] and I can't cuz I got to freaking
net and my plants are tied up you're
going to say chug dog the plant the net
the plant the Nets all this [ __ ] it
gives you going going to give you more
yield bro that's what they're for I know
that I know that's what they're for but
something I can't stand is when I'm
freaking working with different plants
and I'm doing some chucking I see some
Herms at the end of the run that I
didn't see cuz they're all netted up and
I hate trying to get it all undone
freaking up my buds freak my seeds are
falling off cuz they're hitting the Nets
and [ __ ] when I'm pulling it all out so
today I wanted to give you a little
quick tip a little quick quick thing
some of y'all might know what this is
some of y'all might not know but $5 on
Amazon get you get you a little bag of
these you going to say what are them
well these are plant training Clips man
these are freaking awesome I'm going to
show you how they work I'm going to tell
you something a little bit about them
and you're going to learn something
maybe if you don't uh you know whatever
just enjoy the show sit back relax work
on your garden that kind of stuff get
you some smoke fire one up for Chuck dog
throw something in the comments for me
let me know that you love Chuck dog let
me know that you love Matt in the show
whatever let me know if you hate me that
[ __ ] gets me fired up too I'm trying to
make love later to my wife so I need
something to piss me off so let me know
in the comment section and let's get it
popping but back to the clip y'all y'all
know me I'm going off on tangents at all
[ __ ] times oh we said a f word but we
should be good I don't know maybe we're
not I
apologize but the way these work are
pretty simple you got a plant multiple
plants whatever you're working
with and you got a couple tops maybe
maybe couple branches growing too fast
too far up past everything else maybe
you want you into that hard training
that that tough training where you take
them stems and really uh you know high
stress train them and bend them down I
used to do that I like that kind of too
myself but I kept noticing when I got
them big [ __ ] fans rolling you know
sometimes and when you got them cramed
in there like I do um sometimes you can
pinch off that that circulation of or
the flow of the water to those tops and
they can die on you not always but it
does happen it always happens to your
best plants of course the ones you love
are the ones that going you really want
to yield out for you and see I'm popping
a lot of seeds and genetics that I don't
really know anything about so I got
these little clips and I'm ready to go
so basically they way they work and I
love them on these Blue Dream crosses
from Pac that I'm rocking out cuz these
things grow if you ain't ever grown some
blue dream y'all they grow like crazy
I'm talking in three and a half weeks I
got almost three foot of growth on some
them they're freaking crazy and that's
from seed bro I'm talking from when that
pops open that thing's up up harder and
stiffer than your boy but my thing is
here and this
thing this is one your branch is
sticking up it's sticking up with
another one going this way but for the
sake of the demonstration of visual
pretend we got two uh vertical branches
going up a little taller than the rest
of them or the rest of the plant and you
get all this really great growth down
here but there ain't no freaking light
to it so what you want to do these clips
are awesome cuz you can reuse them you
can wash them they're plastic I Ain a
big plastic fan but what I mean what
what are you going to do so you take
that first you take that wrench you tuck
it in there just like that and then you
want to make sure you ain't covering up
any nodes or anything so you want to get
a spot where you got some space to do
this is and then next thing you do you
take that that Branch God Dam take that
rest of that Brun and just slide it
right under like
that now all this growth popping out
here is going to go go out and then up
and then you going to have a real nice
canopy with a few seconds of work and
then what's cool about these is you know
two or three of these per plan will do
you do you good cuz you can go back in
there later that night or the next day
take that one off and and move it up or
move to another one then keep
keep working them I really love them
because it you know like I said you can
reuse them and they're on the Fly I mean
in seconds like I said so go check them
out if you need need something like that
just a little tip for some of you new
guys and gals out there getting into
growing Nets uh pipe cleaners stuff like
that can work too I really love the
little green gardening wire with the the
rubber uh casing on there cuz you can
use that for supporting your plants you
can use that for hanging stuff you know
hanging your plants up uh you can use
that for a lot of stuff you can use it
for uh you know all over the garden so
you you know don't sleep on a little
stuff like this you don't need a lot to
do a lot you just need a little
Ingenuity maybe a little bit of a brain
and just me a little few bucks and get
you rocking but I really wanted to talk
about some other stuff but we're going
to save it for the breeder Syndicate
episode on Sunday that's uh two days
from now if I get this up and I'm not
talking about it I'm talk about this
video if I can get this video up in time
tonight it'll be 2 days from now so
we're going to rock out Sunday night at
900 p.m. Eastern for the breeder
Syndicate TV episode for now on we're
going to test that out for a little
while see what works it seems like more
people are tuning in on the weekends it
seems like a lot of people come in on
Wednesday late I know a few of you guys
on the Discord uh say that you really
like it on Wednesdays so I'm sorry but
it is what it is we're going to move it
around just a little bit and uh see work
goes from there but I did pick up some
kind of recreational Bud that we joke
about a lot some starts with the well
we'll save it we'll save it but we're
going to compare it to the blueberry ex
from Matt I got a lot of experience with
that growing that one out smoking on a
few jars of that for a while so we're
going to compare them and you know I
think the results are going to be pretty
interesting so tune in to that also uh
it's going to be a solo episode so yeah
uh we'll get back to the guests and
doing interviews and stuff on the next
one but I want to try something out a
little different and see where it goes
from there you know as far as mat and uh
stuff's tune in every Friday at 900 p.m.
Eastern is well for that cuz me and Matt
we going in and there's some kind of new
uh diseases and some kind of new uh cold
sores for the plants out there that we
were going to talk about tonight we're
going to talk about it next time and
then we're going to talk about some of
Matt's old work some of his older
strains there's a few that stick out in
my mind when I'm reading through the
list and I want to know some more about
them okay you know as far as my garden
stuff's concerned I'm rocking out it's
70 Dees outside I'm preparing for a
little bit of outdoor growing I I kind
of suck it out there growing I don't got
a lot of experience in it but I'm
learning quick I feel like I'm going to
rock out I'm going to use H&amp;L soil uh
mix this year and I'm going to I'm going
to come strong with the SU I'm going to
come strong with the everything I'm
going to get them covered up I'm going
to do what I got to do this year to rock
it out uh you know stuff like that you
know we'll jump into a little story real
quick before I let you guys go at the
height of my my my hustling career you
could call it the Kentucky trap Lord you
know I was riding High I was living the
dream had two or three girlfriends
making good ass money I had a dup duplex
I was rent out and I was having a good
time you know at this point I hadn't had
a real job for a while for a few years
and I really was depending on the
hustling to get me where I needed to be
and uh you know I rocked out with my
main plug if you want to call it that I
don't know what else to call it without
getting me in trouble on YouTube we'll
call it a plug as the the kids say these
freaking days we had a plug for almost
10 years that had really excellent
quality that really put me above all my
competition uh in my local area so if
you want to know more about it go check
out the breeder Syndicate uh TV episode
number two with scre TR to talk about it
a little bit more but mainly um my dude
he ended up being late to work one day
and was took the the bypass and was
going a little bit too fast and ended up
getting pulled over by state boy back
this has been a while so a little bit
more serious but it wasn't extremely
serious getting caught with with buds in
Kentucky but at the time he got pulled
over and he had enough on him to make
the car stink we'll just say that and uh
the cop was like man I know you got
something on you if you tell me what it
is you know I'll be cool with you all
this you know all the [ __ ] they say to
get you to do what they want you to
do anyways dude goes along with this you
know I got this this this so he still
goes to jail
though I didn't know this at the
time but I'm running out of weed
meanwhile hanging out with the dab holes
getting dirty with the Riff wrath and
I'm hitting dude up saying so I'm seeing
him every two or three days at this
point I'm hitting him up where you at
where you at bro I need you I need to
come get something well two days go by
after I ran out and I'm I got enough for
me to smoke about I don't know a zip or
something like that right and uh I'm
smoking on it and somehow I I don't
remember if his mom I knew his mom's and
stuff so she would write me sometimes or
she would you know served me or whatever
if he was out of town and I think it was
his mom's hit me up and was like hey uh
he's in jail I was like in jail for what
and she told me what everything that
happened but uh she's like yeah he's in
jail for a month and I'm like what the
hell what the hell am I going to do bro
anyways he they let him out on work
release like a weekend and he gets a
phone somehow but they let him go to
work and he texts me and he tells me
like everything like the rest of the
story tells me it's going to be a month
or something and then when he gets out
he wants to lay low for a little while
so I'm like [ __ ] what the hell am I
supposed to do cuz I'm out of weed and
my people are blowing me up like
freaking Dominoes on Friday night where
when is it going to be in bro when you
going to have it when you going to get
it when you going to do this when you
going to do that you know y'all know how
it
is
and I'm trying to figure [ __ ] out cuz at
this point it's been so many years of
just messing with this one guy that I
burned all my bridges or didn't burn my
bridges but I just had talked to any of
those other guys that I messed with
before uh not mess with like what you
guys think but you know getting that
work and uh so I'm hitting up everybody
hitting up cousins hitting up stepdads
all of them in the whole
County you got wait cuz I I need
it nothing this is back when droughts
were actually a thing for people that
don't know what a drought is towards the
end of the year you run out of Bud and
there ain't nothing there ain't nothing
you can do about it
but so finally one of my customers this
chick I wasn't even really calling my
customers she go she one of my other
customers was like hey hey this chick I
know needs some stuff herting her dude
so I'm like you know all right I got a
little bit left I need to make some
money so I go and meet him out in this
Back Road on Lane dead end type [ __ ] on
a [ __ ] corn farm dude and it's not
even their house it's some old lady's
house that's not there I don't really
know but I meet them out there to give
them the stuff and I tell my buddy if
you call him that he's kind of a buddy
or whatever he's been messing with me
for a while you know and uh I told him
like dude I'm I'm almost out of Bud bro
do y'all know anybody and the chicks
like my
uncle my uncle he he grows and he uh
he's got he's got bud right now and he's
out in this one place uh that was like
basically like 40 45 minutes away out in
the middle of nowhere like nowhere
nowhere and she's like he he can get you
whatever he wants you you know and I'm
thinking like I I didn't jump on it then
I thought about it for like a day or two
and finally I hit the I hit them up
after I got their number through uh my
buddy and I was like yo that chick uh
she said you give me stuff or uncle
whatever can we can we do something he's
like so he h hits some up and she's like
yeah I'll I'll text them and I get her
number and all this stuff and then
within like 3 or 4 hours I'm picking up
her
and she when I'm when I go to pick her
up she's like you mind have my boyfriend
rides with me and I'm like dude really
sketch the [ __ ] out right because I'm
thinking like all right she hops in the
driver's seat and I'm in I old Monte
Carlo and he gets in the back and my
thought is is like dude this mother this
dude could let's just say he could mess
me up from being back here I can't even
hardly see him right so before he even
gets to the car I'm putting the the rear
re mirror so I can see back there you
know
and he was weird and the chick she was
all right she's kind of hot dude like in
a weird way you know like a country
weird way like down and dirty kind of
stuff like you know I probably would but
my point is she's like on the way out
there she's like talking about how our
uncle's kind of kind of cool but he's
kind of crazy too and there's a chance
he's going to meet me meet us at the end
of the road on a a ATV or something with
the weapon on them and all this [ __ ] I'm
thinking like dang like I gotten robbed
a few years before that and uh I was
like I'm not really prepared to get
robbed again so I had brought I don't
know if youall know what I'm talking
about but those magnetic boxes you could
put on stuff I had I had the money in
one and then I had something else in the
other one if y'all know what I'm saying
just in case [ __ ] went
South so uh basically she's telling me
all stuff about her uncle and he's
redneck as hell and and I got a lot of
family members out where that live out
where he's at and they are kind of crazy
out there they're kind of real redneck
you know like don't have neighbors type
stuff just farmer people real good
people but some of them are crazy bro
like anyways so we're getting out there
almost the dude and the chick they were
cool but I mean not some people really
like I said you'd really want to hang
out with I'm pretty sure they were on
some other [ __ ] to be honest with you
but chick was too skinny bro like really
skinny but you know teach own but uh so
we get out there and of course dude's
waiting for us and this dude I don't
even know how to like maybe like a
younger Colonel Sanders like silver
black goatee kind of real dark like dark
hair up here with speckled the silver in
I mean he look like got big mustache
like [ __ ] Bert Reynolds bro and he's
sitting on his
ATV with a uh with one a stick you know
what I mean uh on his lap like trying to
be all intimidating and [ __ ] and I'm sit
here thinking like dude I could run this
guy over right now if I wanted to but I
was thinking like man I do need some PT
I don't know if y'all have ever been in
the the sketchy [ __ ] situation when
you're out but you got to get some PT a
lot of stuff was right like I said I had
bills and everything right on this [ __ ]
so
I pull up and I roll down the window cuz
I ain't getting out with the dude and I
was like what's up man he's like you
know not much bud how you
doing I'm good he
says my niece says you want some some
green I said yes sir he said will follow
me back to the
house I like you know I'm here with
boyfriend her on the way back this one
mile Gravel Road in the woods with dude
on the four-wheeler he and he takes off
bro like course flying I don't know if
he's showing off or trying to get back
to the crib set me up whatever so I'm
taking my time thinking like what if
this all how's this all going to go bro
and uh I got mosquito in here bro and uh
so I'm following dude it takes off on me
and I'm like where the hell is this
dude's crib at I'm talking girl she's
like it's up here it's up here and dude
in the back's getting a little
squirly
and we pull up and dude's already inside
and then she gets out of the car and and
boyfriend gets out of the car and they
just go right in the
house like real quick like like this is
sketch but I'm sitting there and the dke
opens the door and he kind of weighs me
in I'm just like [ __ ]
it and uh go in and smells like weed you
know soon as you walk in and I don't
know if y'all had them Stoner friends
that got [ __ ] trash
bongs I mean ashtray stacked up with a
mountain of Ashes uh roaches like every
[ __ ] thing bro and this is back
before I really seen anybody dabbing
it's like probably the first time I can
remember seeing somebody doing
concentrates and it's his son there's
other people in this house when I go in
I'm like [ __ ] I don't like this at all
dude hell like not the way I like to
operate you know I like to be chill bro
like I don't really want a lot of people
I don't even really want anybody other
than you there really but like I said
desperate times ca for desperate
measures and and I had to do what I had
to do so I went in and uh like I said
they're in there dabbing and the son
introduces himself to me and the other
son introduces himself to me and like
get a talking you know kind of seeing
everything's cool before dude pulls out
the buds and getting a feel for each
other and uh he's like you know you want
to try this this [ __ ] out I'm like what
is it and he's like it's a it's a dab or
a wax or whatever he said at the time
and dude I'll be honest looking back it
was some of the worst [ __ ] I ever seen
in life like green as [ __ ] terrible but
you know I'm like [ __ ] it I these guys I
got to be cool whatever so so I smoke it
with him that was cool and then after
that the dad he hit it and then like the
other brother hit it and the chick hit
it the boyfriend hit it and uh like
uncle gets high so he he's kind of
getting cool with me and he's asking me
[ __ ] and they're like yeah we grow and
we got the plants in the other room and
[ __ ] and they're like you could see it
if you want and I'm just like this is
weird bro like I would not be showing
some random dude I barely met my [ __ ]
and uh I guess they were just excited
that somebody else other than them so
they were wanting to show me and [ __ ]
and uh I just like kind of peeped in
there and they had like the uh metal
highlights and [ __ ] going and they're
growing like five gallon buckets you
know stupid like stupid Tech like the
way they were doing it was terrible and
uh the dude's like you know you want to
see the bud and I was like yeah he's
like I know I got three or four flavors
and I make used to my dude at the time
having a few flavors for me I got
excited cuz I was like okay generally in
Kentucky at the time if you if people
had multiple different you know bags or
strains or whatever Cult of ours
whatever you want to call them usually
it meant they they were doing pretty
good and and they you know that was just
a good sign usually if it had one
usually they want and done or they just
yeah I mean who really wants to get
stuck with the same [ __ ] like part of my
whole thing was having something new
every few days and and just having
something new and fresh every few days
so dude had a few different ones and he
he pulls them out in five gallon buckets
with lids on them which you know I've
seen people do it that way but he pulled
them out and dude this [ __ ] smelled so
goddamn gross bro I'm talking like
straight up hay pulled way too early
still wet still green bro I mean I it's
terrible
terrible I I wish I could tell you the
prices
but let's just say uh pretty shitty bro
I didn't get ripped
off I ripped myself off really because I
could have said no but at this point
like I said this is all I had left so I
was like man you know I I was like I
could maybe make this work like and I
kind of like Bartered him down a little
bit on the price and I just went with a
smallest like amount I could get out of
there I felt like without offending the
dude and enough to get me through you
know cuz
I at this point I like didn't even
really have smoke for myself so uh
everything's cool it give him the money
and [ __ ] I but I got to go out to the
car first and get it out of the magnetic
box I'm like [ __ ] I forgot my wallet in
the car bro and I feel like everything's
cool so I didn't really worry about the
other thing so I get the get the wallet
and I come back in and I give him the
money and everything's cool and he's
like you know if you need more or
whatever hit me up blah blah blah and we
end up leaving I take the girl
home and the boyfriend home back to the
spot I picked him up at and I end up
giving a little bit just to like you
know say thanks for helping me get
scoring and uh nastiest bud I have ever
freaking seen home grown style and all
my customers hated me for a week you
know I ended up finding something else I
think like a week after that and then
dude eventually got out of jail and
started messing with me again and we got
to knocking but it was hard man and I
[ __ ] man that was sketchy dude and
that what's what funny about that not
really funny but later like two months
later that that house those people got
robbed by one of the sons and his
friends they came in and took it all
dude so this kind of [ __ ] that would
happen all the time in Kentucky like if
someone show you some [ __ ] or somebody
had some good [ __ ] they were [ __ ] not
too long after that it was done so but I
hope y'all enjoy the story I hope y'all
can relate I know I've been through a
lot of sketchy [ __ ] I know I've I've had
a lot of fun doing it I miss it
sometimes I don't miss it now I mean I'm
living in somebody's garage I can't
really talk [ __ ] broke as hell but it is
what it is and I'm having fun and we're
rocking out for breeder Syndicate we're
rocking out with Matt go to Riot
seeds.com pick up some of the laundry L
list of genetics that are on there
they'll blow you away I'm working with
some freaking Blue Sour right now that
is runchy as [ __ ] no blueberry turps but
runy and I'm excited I'm pumped I don't
know go check out all that good stuff
join the Discord join the patreon y'all
I love y'all I love myself sometimes I
freaking start tweaking my nipples and
[ __ ] and I start I start loving them
myself sometimes but I love y'all more
and have a good weekend I'll see yall
Sunday peace Michigan baby