welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
revolution welcome to breeder Syndicate
I'm Matthew and I'm here today with
little Hill cultivators um to today
we're going to be talking about not just
the legal scene but some of his past in
um the Cannabis world like his whole his
whole Adventure so I'm real stoked to
talk to him today he's been around a
long time and uh welcome dude pleasure
to meet you thank you um how long you in
growing and and how did this whole
Adventure get started let start there uh
I think 02 is when I popped my first
seeds um sweet Toth number three I I was
in college and uh couldn't afford to
smoke weed as much as I wanted yeah and
uh happen upon overgrow.com and it's
kind of saw the blueprint there so uh
you know a lot of people were real
sketched out early on when they found
overgrow like worried like should I post
should I not did you have any of those
concerns at all um yeah it felt a little
weird but I you know I didn't lo I
didn't like register I didn't
um I didn't post for a long time yeah
and then eventually I just had some
burning questions I needed to ask and uh
I got them answered so it was super was
super helpful very helpful tool for
starting yeah I think that's kind of how
we all got our little like people just
kind of slowly step into the forums when
they first get there it's like do I
really want to engage some of these
people are kind of
brutal yeah yeah just just who's looking
at this it's like O2 so like the
internet's still kind of new yeah you
know
um I I loved looking at the pictures
that's that's one of the things that
really drew me there can you think what
kind of strains were popular at the time
when you were hitting ogrow the the two
that I remember the most are sweet tooth
number three from breeder Steve and and
Cinderella 99 from Brothers Grim those
were those were very popular and
everybody was raving about them yeah
definitely at the tops of spice of life
and uh Brothers Grim was very early too
yeah
and and looking back on it all that
spice life stuff was great um big
yielding Frosty plants great smells easy
to
grow um he he had some good stuff there
yeah yeah he really did and then later
on with Legends too did you ever get you
try do that stuff I think I did grow Lui
yeah Legend ulate IND yeah I'm I'm
pretty sure I did grow that one I mean
it's very similar to to Sweet Tooth yeah
just a big cner Cola mold
prone um big yielding Frosty fruity
smelling yeah yeah yeah that's great I
actually um skipping ahead 20 years um
somebody showed me some Northern Lights
5 that you guys did he he flowered some
out and the smells I was getting off
that Northern Lights was very
reminiscent of Sweet Tooth oh
wow in a long time that's cool dude
that's cool so let's let's whip it back
around to how long have you been kind of
um working inside the legal system of
candidates the legal part um let's see
California passed prop
64 in the end of 16 I voted no on it um
as as most most people did up here yeah
uh so then 17 the county came through
with structure
to become legal within the county to
become registered so I did that and that
kept the county off my back which was
the biggest fear sure
um at the time uh and uh then in 18 the
State
Licensing State Licensing thing came
online so January 18 I I submitted my
application yeah and uh sort of bit the
bullet and and went for it and what have
you been growing recently during that
time do you only have with California's
medical scene I know in a lot of other
places you can only grow what they allow
you to grow inside their thing is it
does it work like that um well I
transition well it the the license the
county allow me for 10,000 square feet
of flowering canopy yeah which was maybe
a slight reduction of what I had been
doing
previously um and I had to change things
around I had to I I had a big flat up on
a hill I I basically abandoned and and
and came down to the valley floor uh one
because I felt more comfortable kind of
being out in the open down there and
then two it was just just for
regulations and stuff it was going to be
easier to operate plus I have I have
power down there there and I did not
have power up on the hillside yeah so it
just made a lot of things easier um and
I I kind of abandoned outdoor growing um
and converted everything into green
houses to light dep all my square
footage yeah I I had always felt like
light de was the future um yeah it makes
sense pulling off two crops getting that
first crop out the door and and kind of
like you know getting some r Vue coming
in instead of uh instead of just
hemorrhaging money until you know God
knows when you might actually get paid
you know the outdoor I usually just sat
on for a few months anyways after the
season and having a big depth would
allow you to do that and and not need to
make a fire sale what's your thoughts on
like uh it's kind of random tangent but
uh autoflowering versus light dep like
as far
as like being able to run those multiple
Cycles is one more advantageous than the
other you
think I mean you're going to be you can
grow a r wider range of what's popular
with light dep yeah with Autoflower I
mean I know they've come a long
way um with an outdoor license you used
to not be able to pull tarp on an
outdoor license but now you can wow yeah
um but I'm in the mountains I have some
elevation uh it's it would be tough to
pull off to
I can't start very early outdoors and I
can't can't go very late Outdoors so
trying to pull off two crops Outdoors
without tarp like maybe an Autoflower
crop in the spring summer and then
replant with something fullterm
um that would be tough for me to to to
squeeze in
and um well this all goes back to
probably what we're going to talk about
in a little bit is market demand too
right like because it's driving the
market what if an Autoflower might
actually work it doesn't necessarily
mean that it will work in the market
right right and and the Market's
competitive super competitive and
growing from seed you're going to have
some variation and and and and figuring
out which seed is good stuff to run and
then getting a ton of it because you're
going to run High numbers um it's just
that was you know when the price when
the price was higher and and things were
not competitive had I had an out store
license I definitely would have schemed
it up because then you can plant your
autos and then in between your Autos you
can plant your full-term stuff and get
those some veg time early before you
actually chop so yeah what were we
talking about um let's move into uh how
you got started like uh on the forums
maybe you touch on the bog
stuff okay so on overgrow when I found
it uh bog was posting like great
pictures of of the plants he was growing
and he would post the he had these like
long running threads of uh keep it
simple stupid how to how to start
growing and his methods were really
simple and he would chime in every now
and then if you had a question
and
um that's I basically just copied his
formula on my first grow and uh it
worked well and I was grow I grew I
bought some sweet tooth number three
seeds um
from Gypsy but I forget what the PL
seeds direct or something like that yeah
and
uh did did it did great it grew great
weed too and his his formula was so
simple it was just a rich soil mix uh
blood
meal U bone meal uh lime green sand kelp
worm castings and then just using a pure
blend original
um ferments yeah and
uh man I grew great weed it it was it
was
outstanding and like knowing what I know
now I veered away from it over time you
know and experimented with other stuff
and salts and and eventually came back
to rich soil mix compost
teas um I don't do ferments but I
certainly will be experimenting with
that in the
future um because you can make them
really cheap on site yeah and uh that's
uh that saved some money but like
feeding feeding the microbes having a
rich soil and feeding the microbes just
to me just grows Stellar pot every time
even if you screw it up yeah um it just
it just it's it's tough to beat it's
tough to beat and its scale like I don't
like going to the store and buying tons
of spending tons of of money on on
nutrients organic or otherwise yeah
right yeah know so I feel like if I can
just mix it into my soil in the spring
you know after a soil test um and add
water like that's ideal yeah I came in
during a much um different time like as
far as nutrients and the hydro store
boom and all that stuff so when I came
in like I was really I had to go through
the the time of understanding that it
was like a used car lot and the guys
that that work in the hydro store aren't
really Growers I had to go through that
and like trying to play Magic magician
with all the different nutrient bottles
because I was pretty sure one was going
to finally make it more DK than the
others you know so it's cool to hear
someone that you know started with
something super simple and and didn't
have to go through that crap yeah that
was that was the wisdom in bogs thread
on his
howto and I mean he started way before
all that yeah and like I kind of did too
there weren't a whole lot of options in
in too like there are now or like there
were five years later yeah and I know
it's something I commonly see with
people like something's wrong in their
grow so they think it's their nutrient
line and it's like no it's it's not your
nutrient line like there's some other
variable it's all the same [ __ ] in those
bottles yes all marketing same company
making it for different compan pick pick
one and dial it in and dial it in for
the strain yeah it's it's not your
nutrients whatever's wrong in your thing
it's it's not the nutrients the
nutrients are probably fine just figure
it out yeah
exactly and um you know I I I've been
watching your Instagram live feeds and I
highly recommend other people like
follow it's uh is it _ Hill cultivators
yes on Instagram and it's been some of
the more um fascinating content I've
seen in a long time time I watch it
every time you upload something and uh
you know the other day you were talking
about specifically the legal market and
not knowing exactly where your flowers
go or where direct people to get them or
what name they'll be under I thought it
was totally
fascinating yeah so the way the legal
Market set up
is everything a cultivator sell has to
move through distribution sort of like
same as alcohol in California
um sort of sort of sort of like alcohol
um there's some exceptions uh I I can't
sell direct to consumer or direct to
retail I have to move it through a
distributor who then sells it
to another distributor or a brand that's
a distributor or has a license with a
distributor and they sell it to retail
yeah and so I don't most of the time I
don't know where my flower ends up I
don't know who ends up buying it I don't
know what brand it's in I don't know
what stores it's in and that disconnect
and a lot of the time the distributor I
move it through doesn't know either yeah
and so like I'm kind of used to that
since back in the day you didn't really
ask yeah but now it's like okay like
people are hitting me up like trying to
find my flower or or they like my feed
and they want to you know support me or
or see you know I actually good weed and
yeah and like I've got also at the same
time I've gotten great feedback from the
one store up here in NorCal that
actually attaches the farmer's name to
the to the produce they buy um organic
can and mocan in Santa Santa Rosa and
Hopland they are retail but they also
have distribution for themselves yeah so
they're able to buy wholesale they
package it but they keep the farm name
and logo with the product so when you're
looking on their menu you see all the
farm names yeah next to the strain
that's amazing and that's that's super
cool and and they're one of the few
places that do that and to me it's a
no-brainer but I mean other people don't
get it you know like you don't just see
you don't you don't walk into like a
wine store and just buy cab or buy Mero
you you you see the vineyard or you see
the winery where it's made and the
location and all those things about it
and and so that's a cool thing that they
do so just off of those three pounds I
sell them a year um I'll I'll get one or
two people hitting me up saying hey man
this was great I bet you know and and
and and they appreciate it and I'm I'm
stoked to hear that and I think they're
stoked to know that they're actually
talking to me the grower and it's not
some
like you know social media sure you know
person running running the social media
yeah that happens a lot too that happens
a lot too yeah yeah I mean I'm it's my
operation is just me I mean I have help
but like it's it's just me there's
there's no team in the sense that like
it's my business and and I I mean I
certainly have help on the farm
absolutely and and I couldn't do it
without him but um like there there's no
administra Administrative Office it's
it's my living room table you know yeah
exactly yeah
yeah that's wild to me man like just we
we did an episode recently we called the
name game just about like trying to
explain to endlevel Consumers that maybe
aren't as nerdy about strains and don't
grow and aren't as died into growing try
to find a way to reach across to them to
to for them to understand like look if
you want to know exactly what you're
smoking and use it as medicine you have
to be a lot more aware of what Farm's
making it you need consistency you need
you know reliability and all of that
just all of that was so missing in
what's going on right now and I don't
know how they can rationalize this as a
medical system when there's nothing
medical about not being able to give
reputable reliable results yeah AB
absolutely there's you can change the
strain name anytime you want at at any
at any stage through the through the
cycle you
can um a brand can be buying a strain
and run out and buy either if they can't
Source the same strain they'll if it was
a good seller they'll just throw
something else in that bag under that
name yeah I watched it happen as a brand
like I don't know how that's good
business you know um who knows man and
even if they do find the same strain
it's probably from a different
grower and so then now there's varying
qualities and and and and and is it
actually the same strain did they think
it's the same strain as one you know
grown Inland is one grown Coastal is one
grown organic is one grown
differently um you you don't know and
they say like you know in the farm to
table type type atmosphere like know
your grower like yeah know where your
food comes from well know where your
weed comes from and exactly um that's I
mean I'm a farmer right so I'm super
biased but like to me that's a
no-brainer do I know where all my food
comes from no but like I know my meat
comes from I know where my eggs come
from yeah and and I like that and I and
I like the fact that I'm supporting my
neighbors with that as opposed to you
know some [ __ ] in Missouri or
somewhere you know with a billion
dollars in a bunch of different
companies that doesn't really give a
[ __ ] besides looking at the the the
profit report you know yeah I I had this
experience the other day when we bought
some Louis OG and this is when I was
doing my little experiment to see like
if if dispensaries in Bakersville
because you know Bakersville sucks dude
like this is the the worst place in
California for weed ever and there's no
connoisseur quality anything but I
wanted to see what dispensaries had to
offer and my um my lady liked the Louis
OG we got it was an OG it was a good OG
I don't know if it was Loui but it was a
good OG yeah so two days later called
the same
place deliver the same stuff again get
it it's a a berry like a berry um
Gorilla Glue this time but it's label
Lou
and so of course I hit him up I'm like
bro this is not even close to the same
thing they're like yeah different
phenotypes bro sorry you know like
phenotype speak to me bro it's it's such
horseshit yeah it's horrible it didn't
make any sense yeah they I mean that's
funny because node Labs had a picture of
their OG Kush on their Instagram and the
picture is is is Gorilla Glue like yeah
everybody knows it and I chimed in a
bunch of other people know chimed him
like dude that's gorilla goo like it's
it's obvious that's not an OG and yeah
what do they know like it's just some
person around their social media they
don't know anything funny is you should
mention weed shitty and
Bakersfield um for a while up here this
was years and years ago when you had a
bag of uh not so great uh OG kush yeah
um the joke was to call it Bakersfield
OG that's [ __ ]
great Tahoe or San Fernando Valley or
whatever it like oh this looks like
Bakersfield OG exactly this is a it's a
weird spot like people not from
California don't quite understand how
lame Bakersfield is but it's a very
special special little
hole yeah yeah yeah let's talk about
some strains now that we're talking
about strain names and trying to keep
them uh stable let's talk about high and
lonesome's poodle nuts because I know
this is one of your your classic
favorites yeah it's it's my all-time
favorite smoke um
back in like the
2010s and before maybe the eights the
seven six I was mainly just growing uh
purple Urkel and gra
apape um because that's what was popular
and I I really like the flavor of it the
high was not as good but like that's
what people wanted especially down in
the Bay area where I'm from yeah and
uh like I I you know it's kind of a
[ __ ] to grow it's really slow
veg um
I love the smell of it you know it's
nice and dense leafy but dense and um I
got a hold of the poodle nuts from from
40 ounce U we had we had traded some
Cuts because we were both down in the
Bay Area yeah and uh and he just
selected the poodle right he selected it
it was a Urkle phenotype he ended up
running with like for production another
phenotype that was more that was a
taller plant it probably was you more
kimd related I think it might have still
had some color but the poodle nuts was
an Urkle phenotype for sure squat U very
purple purpled up the same way same
branching leaves yeah the branching the
liness in the
middle um the nug structure was
different and it just had it had that
Urkle smell with the
fuel which back then I just said it was
like Urkle with some spiciness to it
because gas was really a term people
threw around yeah but it it was purple
gas it was the first encounter with
purple gas I ever had and I mean it it
took over right away like yeah as soon
as I started growing that over grae ape
um it vegged a little faster um it had a
much prettier nug the nug you know very
swollen kix's yes um still leafy still
squat but not as squat it had uni
stretch out a little bit more if you
tried yeah so anyway yeah i i w a i w a
uh a Cannabis Cup up in Humble with it
with some indoor uh poodle nuts and and
and like one in a landslide and you know
there was there was some good weed up
there but uh bet I mean it just had
everything it was just prettier than
anything like off right off the bat it
was just prettier than just any green
weed up there so I bet that helped but
it was super tasty and uh and uh people
people took notice we we smoked so much
weed that day you couldn't tell high at
all yeah I know what you mean but even
though that I think I'm pretty sure it
was a uh that was one of the categories
you just you're you're smoking you're
taking like two Puffs off of you know
for 40 joints yeah and uh you just you
can't tell high it's it's all flavor bag
appe peal smell all that stuff yeah
that's how it gets by the end of our our
uh party sessions too where every I mean
when there's 60 jars up there and it's
over over three days it's like at some
point you stop evaluating High because
you're so [ __ ] up the whole time just
can't yeah you just can't anym and I
mean if you smoke the right thing it can
cut through but sure it's it's really
hard yeah that is few and far between on
something that'll cut through over a
dayong sesh you know yeah sure
yeah so we have another one old Betsy uh
this is a a old school one out of San
Diego yeah um so bud bud up in Humble
sourced it from
delmare um grew it indoors and it was it
was novel you know really
smelly um unique structure sort of
branchy purple
stems
um then he gave it he gave it to CSI who
grew it Outdoors one
year and the next year it was half as
Garden
yeah and then so so CSI passed it out to
a few
people including me he passed it to a
few people before I had an outdoor
spot and I saw it catch on yeah um
quickly uh and so I I think I ran 10
beds of it on my first outdoor year in
uh in I think this was
and uh yeah 10 beds did great it was
half my garden the next year that's a
good sign dude that's a really such a
unique strain you could take three
cuting off it take the tops like October
7th and then give it two more weeks and
then take like the almost the rest of it
yeah but then wait for all all the there
wasn't really lar it was just small buds
they were still dense though on the
inside of the plant and then let those
go as long as you can and they would
purple up up and then take those and and
they'd be smaller but if you mixed it
into your other pounds it gave your
pounds some color yeah D and uh I mean
back then people didn't really grade too
much um and it kept its
smell you know by next April you it
still smelled great in the bag when you
were selling it and and and that's
that's unique a lot of especially a lot
of the hype the more hype stuff um
that's for sure it's just it's not bread
to do that or it's not selected to do
that no not at all selected to sell now
yeah yeah Betsy slowly making its way
through uh more current circles and it's
fun to watch like Growers from a
different generation grow her and like
experience her and be like oh my God
where what is this you know it's like
what we have it's a blast from the past
it's probably got a lot of skunk
genetics it's it's it's almost
definitely Dutch Origins right yeah I
would think so yeah so I mean it's it's
it's it's it's a it was a winner and it
I mean it took over people's Gardens
that's that's how good it was like
almost almost like as long as you could
sell it and I I sold it under Mango kush
yeah because because his name sucks
shitty name yeah it is it is like like
of course it's endearing to people who
know it like of course I think one of
the reasons it never caught on was
because of its name like it's its sister
to the cut bull rider which totally
caught on I mean you have Drake with
bull rider genetics like uh using a fake
bull riter to put on his clothing store
now so it still has some name value but
Betsy just never caught on so yeah yeah
weird yeah and and uh but it it it
definitely caught on in gardens up here
yeah for sure up here Trinity humble be
um and it's kind of funny if you if you
meet somebody who knows Betsy like it's
not that hard to trace back to who we
know in common oh I bet this happened to
me last year I'm like oh you know Betsy
let's figure out who our common friend
is because you know the circles are kind
of tight yeah I've tried explaining that
to people too like a lot of how how
clone circles work and how they've
always work and when you see people that
aren't necessarily connected to anyone
pop up with a clone it's usually either
ill gotten or fake just because of how
tight those circles were and how well
everybody knew each other and how yeah
how close people were to their word to
it so you knew that if it was making
outside the circle either someone
probably stole it or it probably wasn't
it you know if it's from a random
outside the circle yeah I mean and in
the circle people share pretty freely
sure um I've never hoarded genetics and
if somebody wanted it i' I'd do my best
to get it to them because it's a it'd be
a benefit you know to them yeah big time
I think that surprises people the most
is when they come from outside to inside
like one of the Clone circles that that
they they realize how open it is once
they get inside like nobody's really
like trading nobody's really even caring
it's like oh you want that cool here you
know but yeah they ass knowing somebody
yeah
like being trusted yeah trust trusting
somebody that okay I know I know you I
know you're not a cop and yeah or or or
or a shitthead and and
uh like I don't know like I don't really
know anybody that hoardes clones for for
the most part um the people that do I
know right away like they're just on
some other [ __ ] and they
think I don't know I don't know why they
think that their clone is so special
that oh I don't want this clone to get
blown out it's like dude like you're
growing what a couple hundred pounds of
it maybe like that's it's gone like yeah
No One's Gonna experience it nobody's
gonna hear of it or know it or
anything and there's no way the Market's
going to get oversaturated now
occasionally that can happen like look
with like blue dream or train wreck or
something but
like I mean that that's few and far
between it is you know so yeah that's a
good point dude yeah just you're you're
gonna be better off openly sharing
because then people openly share with
you and and you're going to have access
to more stuff and you'll benefit greatly
and at the same time you'll probably be
able to get those genetics back if you
lose them it's a good point and you know
the best advice I was given in cannabis
was uh our buddy CSI told me never tie
yourself to one clone never get
emotionally involved with one clone
because it leaves you stuck in in a
corner and once that's out you're done
you have no moves that's it and it it
was amazing advice because just from all
the other angles but like now you're
emotionally tied to one thing and you
sit there obsessing over it what's the
point of that you know when there's so
much there yeah I mean it's also like
things are so trendy too that if you're
not open-minded enough to what's next or
what's better and you don't think
anything's better than this stuff you
have from 2005 like yeah right you're
getting passed you're getting passed up
you know exactly and and and and and you
like the chances of what you having
being that great are are not very good
no no very SL To None yeah like
o few few few strains make a comeback
like sour diesel or OG kush or yeah um
I'm trying to bring the P Nets back I've
been trying for a minute oh we will get
her back yeah been I've been looking
I've gotten some mislabeled Cuts I even
got one I don't know if it was the real
one or not and I lost it due to my own
cloning mistakes yeah I was flowering it
out and I'm like oh [ __ ] this is Rainbow
belts
[ __ ] so like I made that one and then I
got it back and I'm like oh this isn't
even poodle nuts this is London pound
cake well you know close I even bred
with it and I'm like [ __ ] now I got this
whole breeding project going on and I've
got all this London pound cake S1 and
crossed Kim D and how did London
poundcake Express for you what does she
smell like do you know it a
75 it's funny it's kind of fragrant and
veg and it's kind of squat so I didn't
notice right away and
then and then it kind of just started
smelling more like gelato to me and it
didn't have that urk and fuel yeah it
threw me it took a while for me to kind
of
like realize that it wasn't the real one
and by then everything's pollinated and
yeah of course it's good weed it's like
it's it's not bad at all yeah in fact I
wish I hadn't lost it but I basically
just gave it up because I was pissed and
didn't keep a mother yeah you know but
now I was real real I'm like oh man
that's it's pretty good weed yeah that's
funny dude yeah that's the other thing
about poodle nuts that I'll never forget
and URL has a similar trait where in veg
when you take cuts it smells very skunky
in the room yeah poodle nuts was like
seriously I could be in my living room
taking cuts my chick in the bedroom be
like get a stunk walk in people say talk
about weed being skunky in veg that
plant I don't think there's anything
more skunky than bu nuts to me in Veg
it's crazy I I I agree another plant
that used to really smell besides like
Urkel was the genius cut oh I never got
to grower yeah it was it was kind of a
weak finicky plant and and and and
lateral branching and cool unique uh nug
structure and and good skunky smell to
it um great
High um but it was also very skunky in
veg
interesting yeah yeah CSI has mentioned
that one a few times to me over the
years and I've never I've never I wish I
had made some seed with it honestly I I
don't have any more Apollo 11 seeds I
grew Apollo 11 a few year a few times
and it was good weed yeah I wish I wish
I had more of that um that's part of my
seed stash that got lost I grew a lot of
13 I never never grew much 11 but 13 I
grew a ton of it probably wasn't too
different yeah I don't I don't think so
this one was all a lot of grapy
Expressions on big huge Jack ha type
buds oh yeah oh yeah no it wasn't grapey
at all for me though the Apollo 11 was
just skunk was it yeah that [ __ ] out
very weak
stems not a great commercial plant but a
pretty plant yeah kind of like not a
huge stretcher but still had like very
narrow
leaves yeah that makes sense plant cool
Plant so poodle nuts
uh yeah I I have some I had some old old
s1's from a from a from a from a run
from
2010 that I've kept in a bag in the
fridge and I got three to pop this year
so I have I have three s1's growing
Outdoors right now they all look very
similar the the tallest one of the bunch
is is very close to the original smell I
think yeah but like the leaves are all
green which is unusual where the other
two the leaves are starting to purple
because it's you know it's fall it's
almost October
and uh the temps are the temps are
cooling off one of them doesn't really
smell at all or or or or nothing close
to what what I'm looking for and then
one of them is like very Urkel kind of
down there but it doesn't have the
spiciness to it or the gas to it yeah so
I mean that's that's what I got out of
those I have clones of all of them uh
I'm gonna I'm definitely keeping them I
I my plan next year is to run I have a
bunch of hybrids of it um the the reason
I wanted it back was to make a sour
diesel hybrid with it yeah because I had
done that accidentally back in the day
and the one seed I got out of a sour
diesel was just a diesel tall diesel
structured plant with purple flowers and
that poodle nut smell that's wow and and
a great potent High I'm I'm thinking the
sour diesel helped the high a bit Yeah
and uh I I want that plant back and I we
only grew out one but you know my buddy
agreed that it was a good plant
yeah so I want to make that cross again
it just crosses good to to uh to kushes
to OG I grew some uh triangle to poodle
nuts from zo zoi last year very
impressed very impressed with how well
the smell carried over yeah the color
didn't carry over the structure didn't
really carry over but the smell those
turps were there in that in that bud
which was really cool yeah me and me and
H lonon crossed it to the the blue
bondet stuff we use which is like a
really short squat blueberry but in the
end it made for this beautiful blueberry
version of of the puut just stuck to
that structure and just super blueberry
Berry turps on top of all that skunky
right it was beautiful oh nice nice well
I have some of those seeds they're going
to get popped next year that's right
yeah and uh I gave you the last of
highend lonesome's I think what it was
is poodle nuts cross poodle
nuts
poodle nuts cross dog Walts I think
that's what it
was was
it it was poodle nuts to like a a
brother yes and
backs yeah yeah yeah made those he made
those a long time ago though so I hope
they'll pop they're old May been I never
knew he made those I would have bought
some for sure I yeah I think he only
passed them to me so they're with you
yeah those are getting Pop N here too
and then there's the F5s of dog wal that
still exist too if those don't work we
have those and then did high and Lono
make those yeah yeah okay yeah and that
was just taking not the poodle nuts but
other lineage
just I'd have to ask him but I think he
always use poodle nuts in it oh okay but
I have to ask him maybe that might just
be a a open pollination maybe I don't
know yeah okay yeah well I'm popping a
bunch of crosses I got it cross to kim9
W from zoi I got it cross to North fire
cookies that that old s Raves about oh
yeah yeah um what else do I have across
too I feel like I'm missing a couple now
yeah shout out old SG shout out zi rest
in
peace totally yeah that was a bummer he
was he was doing cool things at for his
breeding company it's too bad he had to
go it's kind of shocking yeah yeah
totally all right so you you've done a
lot lot um of grows of modern stuff too
obviously you're good friends with CSI
can you talk some about your experiences
with the Skittles and sherb stuff so I
know that's going to interest a lot of
people okay um yeah I I I'm growing out
now his uh Skittles to sherbet
cross um I think I've got 20s something
females going I had one plant completely
Herm out but I killed it before before
it
uh uh blew pollen yeah and
uh it was it was very hermy very
surprising but boy hermy up the Wazoo on
that one uh it was almost more male
flowers than female wow um I'm glad I
caught it
anyways um yeah so there's 20s something
of them I would all but two smell like
sherbet um or maybe all but three smell
like sherbet and then two of them are I
would say the bud structure of looks
very Skittles yeah um but the smell is
sherbet um various Heights uh one of the
shorter ones is definitely a skittles
phenotype and then one of the like the
medium height ones is a is a skittles
phenotype smell wise anyways um and then
one of them is probably the most pungent
of the bunch and it's like a sherbet
strawberry smell and so I of course I
didn't have cuts of that one so I went I
went back I think it was last week and
and and we took uh we took cuts off the
bottom and uh those those cuts off the
bottom they have little flowers on them
but they will revert fairly quickly when
after you Roo them yeah I've I've I've
done that a bunch off SE I do a lot of
that I I actually sometimes prefer it
yeah because then that I mean that
allows you to wait for one and then like
and not end up with this big vegging
plant but also like um you can if if if
you don't want to take cuts off
everything you can just wait for the
smells you want to yeah I took cuts of
everything and and and pretty quick here
some of them are going to get uh cold
but um yeah did you get a lot of did you
see any Skittles type stuff as far as
TPS go yeah off two of them have a have
a have Skittles smell okay so that's
good I mean for two out of out of
what 18 20 something yeah yeah so so
just so people know that's kind of a
range to expect even even in like
Skittles s1's how dominant the actual
really really uh desirable turp is in a
lot of those things yeah I've noticed a
lot of Skittle crosses give off like a
strawberry scent yeah which isn't bad no
but it's not Skittles and to me Skittles
is is just one of the best smells in
cannabis period yeah
it's like an extreme grapefruit to me
like if you grapefruit RH is what I get
from it but also if you think like green
Skittles sometimes that it's that too
yeah it could be that definitely I
definitely like if I think of the old
sweet pink grapefruit clone though it's
like that the extracts of that is what
the Skittles I wish I had that cut yeah
right like I grew it once a long time
ago yeah um again a cool Plant uh
probably Northern
lights um really great smell to it funky
structure um I wish I still had that
that just was that it had that real just
like skunky Funk that that weed used to
have and and you don't see that at all
really anymore it's no you don't you
know so I think that's that's part of
why especially with prices being so low
um I feel like there is room to
experiment a little bit or or or or also
it's more important to experiment and
and and do some pheno hunts even though
space is at a premium just
because
like you can't get stuck growing all
this same garbage that no people think
they
want if you don't show them something
else they're not gonna know they like it
more exactly you know and and and so
it's that chicken or the egg thing like
why is everybody buying all this [ __ ]
purple gas garbage that that that that
the high is not that great and the
flavor is just meh and and it's like
well that's all we're growing right so
yeah what we're letting them demand the
market show them show them what good
weed is and and and hopefully you can
find some that'll still test high enough
to actually get bought in the first
place yeah that's that's kind of like
another barrier is a lot of this old
stuff won't test high but then again a
lot of this old stuff hasn't been tested
with 2023 parameters which everything's
over 20% now you know bro my all my
blueberry stuff like all that blueberry
work I've done is all testing like 26 28
have you ever heard of blueberry test at
26 or 28 bro in your life no the yeah
blueberry is not super
potent all my all my blueberry hybrids
even pure blueberry is testing like 28
25 which maybe maybe the blue bonnet
maybe Lone Star worked it special which
I think you did but like if that even
still like being able to take blueberry
that high even in in one move in an
outcross still is not really feasible so
I think that a lot of these old lines if
they were tested under today's
parameters might actually like really
shock the [ __ ] out of people when it
tests
that right not because they're more
potent now but because everything tests
higher now and Labs have to put out good
results or they don't get business and
exactly they don't get repeat business
from
people so dumbb to be buying based off
THC percentage I know people think
they're getting a better value but the
reality is they're just getting shitty
weed yeah I mean that's that is what it
is and and you know it goes back to the
education part how do you get how do you
get the end user who are not Growers to
want to be interested enough to learn
about like maybe sativa indicia and
hybrid are not the best descriptions of
a high you know how do you like how do
you explain that like THC percentages
are is like a s 1970s 1980s thing that
we moved on from there like yeah I don't
know how I don't know I think I I think
you just do the old free sample like try
try this first yeah bro you're right
you're right
that's it sounds it sounds so obvious
but yeah and when you can do things like
tastings or have events where you can
like pass a joint to
somebody like that that's how you get
that's how you spread it that's how you
like help especially the Young
generation realize that you know what
they think is that great is not that
great you know and and there's there's
so much else out there there's there's
such better highs out there and and yeah
I mean so people maybe don't realize
like in 200 say five to 2010 the only
things testing over 20% were like OG and
Kim dog y but like old SOG super silver
Hayes will get you absolutely ripped and
it will cut through any other thing
anything else you're smoking you'll get
high all over again and that's like 19
100% And so I mean even things like
poodle nuts which aren't never tested
super high would test like 18 19 I think
I had it as high as
23 um W which for that for that time
period was really good that's huge yeah
um I mean I don't know what it would be
now it would probably be you could
probably hit over 30 with it
yeah so I bet you could yeah just buying
off of like the numbers are [ __ ]
anyways so what are you really buying
like people used to buy weed based off
smell because that was the best
determining factor of of the quality of
the weed yeah you know the flavor it's
what gets the mouth watering you know
it's you know so I just had a collective
write me on IG the other day and asked
me so we have one of your strings here
but we we're about to put it on the menu
um what do I put it under index sa
hybrid and I had I actually sat there
all stoned and I was like let me have
this discussion with you kid you know
like Inda HD so like the retail when
when when clubs dispensaries started
opening they latched on because that was
the General consensus is that these
narrow leaves are sativa and it's like a
up euphoric busy Speedy High and the
indas were these broad Leafs and their
couch lock and then there's hybrids and
they just latched on to that because
they wanted to sell the consumer a
feeling yeah right so needed to tell
them something so like what do you want
to do you want like a daytime thing or
you're trying to chill out at night and
they wanted to sell they just want to
sell them yeah you know something and
they just lashed on to it like it's a
fact and it's not a fact at all and and
it's not even the the taxonomy of the
plant has nothing to do with the
chemicals in it no not even and even
then I don't even think can tell
chemically the difference between sativa
and Inda I doubt it right you can't tell
by tpin I mean they could both have
trinoline yeah I was gonna say even like
even like CHR has trinoline so that kind
of erases that one right right so I mean
you know if you show these people a real
sativa or a real narrowleaf drug
cultivar they would probably thumb their
noses at it oh for sure that that's you
know that's another discussion about
like the newer kids on IG that are like
buying land races and stuff that you
know like they're like I'm going to buy
some Indian Land races and blah blah
blah and they have no clue that they
don't even want to grow like this jungly
thing that you have to flower as a
Seedling this big you know or it's going
to be 20 feet tall like there's a lot of
um I don't know what you'd even call
that right they they don't have the
patience for it they're they're not
going to get anything that they're going
to be able to sell to anybody they're
going to get made fun of
like sply hairy weed and then they're
going to just decide that that's no good
and and go you know go get purple purple
gas you know yeah exactly I mean it's
like there's no floral structure really
there and I don't think that they
understand that there's Bud that even
looks like that without floral
structures you know yeah yeah yeah it's
yeah it's definitely a different thing
and um watching the new generation move
in and try to navigate the weird world
of cannabis from the start it's been
really really funny to watch because I I
did it myself I know exactly what
they're going through I I made every
idiot move you could make you know
they're they're growing up thinking Sour
Diesel and blue dream or sativas yeah oh
yeah for sure you for sure I mean sativa
I
mean blue dream just based on its
genetics is 5050 at best yes yeah
probably 75% yeah broadly Afghan
yeah yeah so yeah for folks out there
call call what you think is an Inda a
broad leaf cultivar and call what you
think is sativa a narrow Leaf drug
cultivar and and leave the sativa in the
uh in the indicia stuff
for you know the Chads trying to sell a
feeling I mean you got pins made of
disate with with a sativa or a oh Inda
label on them so trying to explain that
to people too like why there's no point
in even picking up a distillate pen that
says hybrid indic like there's no
difference in any that it's all it's all
hybrids anyways yeah and and honestly
people react different to different
tpping so for some people most PE most
people something broadleaf is really
gonna like be a couch lock yeah or have
this more sedata of high but other
people it's going to make them get up
and clean their house yes you know and
it just it just reacts with people
differently and that's your body
chemistry and and what's going on with
you at that moment is is going to react
differently and set and setting you find
the same weed all the time once you find
something you like you're probably never
going to see it again it kind of sucks
you know like I I learned this later on
in life from because I was never a big
psychedelic kid I never really got into
that stuff but learning about set and
setting and psychedelics and and I never
understood how people haven't applied
that to cannabis because it's just there
was set and setting with Heroin they're
set and setting with all kinds of drugs
um there they did some studies where uh
people would overdose on the same amount
of heroin if they were using it in a
place they weren't familiar with so like
versus their own home where they're
comfortable so setting is a major part
of everything whether it's cannabis or
anything you're consuming you know so um
I think that's one of those things
that's left out quite a bit Yeah so like
yeah absolutely like people get paranoia
and anxiety sometimes and yeah that's
because of where you're at in your head
space or maybe where where you are like
maybe you're not comfortable around
these people or maybe you have something
on your mind that's uh that's wearing on
it maybe it's not a good time to to to
to get loaded but yeah
um yeah people Overlook that and also
like with with with increased potency
with with the way things are it's like
don't smoke the whole joint just yeah
you know take a puff see how you feel
and then go back to it you know I had to
learn that myself you know like going as
a kid I would just puff tough like hard
all the time and then as an adult my
hormones change dude like I there's
times when my chick boox by she's like
dude just take a hit don't like it's the
morning it's your first hit just take a
hit you do not need to smoke The Whole
Bowl like yeah it's it's certainly
something I learned
um that I couldn't I was kind of more of
a nighttime smoker um anyways when I was
a heavy
smoker uh unless there was like some
social function where we were smoking
during the day but I I I kind of learned
especially as I started growing more and
more weed and kind of putting my ass out
there a little bit more before
legalization
um that it it's instead of like
relieving all anxiety it started to
amplifying it yeah and then
so I barely even smoked for a few years
because I just wasn't enjoying it yeah
and then when I would smoke I had no
tolerance and I'd get ripped and
paranoid and feel uncomfortable for 15
minutes so it wasn't fun but then as
time went on I kind of
learned um set and setting or I just
call it time and place yeah like there's
certain activities that I know will be
enhanced and better if I smoke out first
yeah like before I go on a mountain bike
ride or before I clean my house or
before um I got a bunch of like
monotonous work to do in the greenhouse
where it's hot that's a great time
because you just put on some music and
you zone out and you don't really have
to think and you just get to work and
it's the same thing like when you're
like I used to trail run it was great
for that because you don't in your head
just thinking about other stuff besides
how tired you are how far away from the
car you are or whatever else is going on
and all of a sudden like you realize oh
my lungs aren't burning like this is
great like I could I could do another
mile yeah and so it's for for me that's
that's where it really works um and and
I love it like that's and I smoke more
now because I know when are the right
times that's important I think that's
super important and that's that's
something I had to learn myself like I
know if I'm having a super bad like
stressful day that it's probably like a
lot of people use it to relieve stress
when they're having a bad day I cannot
like it will spin me out and put me in a
bad black hole no matter what no matter
if I'm like I dab all day like I just
even as we're sitting here I'm dabbing
and it doesn't really affect me or make
me too paranoid but there's certain
times where if I'm in a real bad mood
and I
dab to the Moon just like not anywhere
good you know I need back rubs
please yeah and in that sense it is a
medicine and we're kind of using it
medically to improve things but also
like knowing when not to not to use
that's what I figured out and if I'm
super annoyed over something it's
actually good to smoke out because then
I just kind of stopped dwelling on it
now yeah and and uh you know I just kind
of move on you know my personality is so
opposite bro like that that makes me
Hyper obsessed when I'm like that oh
it's a worst yeah so people just got to
figure it out for themselves and it's
not for everybody either but for most
people that figure it out it enhances
their life greatly yeah it is it is very
specific especially for me this whole
journey like I've had a LoveHate
relationship at some points with
cannabis because it's put me in such bad
mental zones but once you figure that
out the set part the time and place it's
it's it does change a lot and and you
realize it's not one it's not a cure all
and it shouldn't be a cure all it
shouldn't fix all of your moods and it's
not weird if it doesn't you know yeah
totally totally all right so you've been
growing a lot of or is there a specific
TKS one that you like a lot or have you
been growing a bunch um I just have one
I got from Roots Nursery
um it's funny when you talk to people on
the legal side and
if you can establish that they're from
the old days like they're so much cooler
and there's more passion and they
actually know what they're talking about
so that these guys were absolutely that
um and so we just talked about tons of
[ __ ] and he grew out I think he only
grew out a pack of s1s but he selected a
good TKS S1 and and it's very much OG
and to I I don't know how TK it is on
that Spectrum where like TK is on the
earthy side yep and like sfes on the on
the pinea side but um it's a little
early for to to really tell but it's
I've seen it indoor um I've seen it
grown out indoors and it's just OG
that's awesome and so yeah I'm I'm
stoked to be growing that I'm gonna grow
it again next year for sure that's
that's my favorite side of TK
personally yeah yeah I I was always fond
of sfv like any to me but to me like any
well-grown t or any well grown OG is
super dank yeah I don't care which one
it is I'm going to enjoy it like 100%
right yep if it's grown well
and yeah that's you know that's that's
all I really care about and does it
check the box and is it grown well if
it's grown well it's super dank and
people that have never smoked it are
just going to be blown away Y and and
I'm growing it I'm growing it again
because I stopped growing it just like
everybody else for a long time and then
realize it
like you know I'm guilty of following
the hype too but just because I'm a
commercial cultivator I got to grow what
people want even if it's not as good as
what else I could grow sure and so I got
away from growing ogs a lot of people
are growing them again now because
they're realizing like you know what
this this [ __ ] carbon fiber or
whatever is not that [ __ ] great yeah
you know and and and so like you know
the the price is the same either way
like I'm I'm growing [ __ ] OG I want
to grow some good smoke I want to grow
something that like maybe you know
somebody Associates with my name at some
point and and and and just realizes that
like holy [ __ ] like o OG is still king
for a reason you know or one of the
Kings for this season I've been getting
asked more from act honestly not even
from seed buyers from breeders and other
Growers hey did you keep any OG Cuts bro
cuz nobody kept them nobody [ __ ] kept
nobody kept him I couldn't [ __ ]
believe OG is rare
now
it's Cuts right right and and and and
and it's and it's tough to Source stuff
that nobody has anymore not not just
because like like it's hard to find the
person with it but like somebody's gonna
[ __ ] you at some point and just give
you a cut so I I think I sourced the sfv
from these same guys they were skeptical
as well so they
they they they first they tested it for
for hopl and vroid and and that's good
and then now they're they're flowering
it out next to the TKS one to see is
this really sfv what's going on with it
so they're they're skeptical as well
they're note it until they know what it
is where do you source sfb to this is a
good conversation like oh I didn't see I
didn't even ask them where they got it I
felt like that wasn't any of my business
and I would just let them kind of do
their thing but
but with sfv where would you Source it
to what do you mean who's the original
sourcer sfv who brought that online who
brought that
exact that's not I mean at this point it
was spread around so much that like you
could have legitimate sfv and not know
like really where it came from at one
point because that's that's a problem
everybody had it at one point how do we
now now that it's disappeared like
pretty well disappeared as far as like
this cut sfb there's one person who
brought it to the table and held it
there's never been that so now that it's
kind of like me and CSN were talking
about this specifically so I wanted to
get your opinion like how do you how do
you even go about sourcing an sfv who
would you go back to because I wouldn't
go to Josh D for sfb because his cup was
never called sfb someone else labeled
that I don't know I don't know it would
have to be somebody from Southern
California yeah I don't know who put
that moniker on it and I don't know that
there even was one sfv I don't either
could have multiple correct and you know
people people would really get nitpicky
with what's oh that's a good one or
that's not a good one and I'm like yeah
dude like if you grow it well like it's
a good one and if you don't grow it well
like okay okay oh I don't like sfv the
sfv I saw was garbage and now sfv is
garbage not really you just saw some
Bakers field OG is probably because
bakersfi OG bro yeah you know
yeah seed line didn't help you know he
released a OG and on out and then
darkart Nursery started selling
sfv and I I asked them myself they don't
[ __ ] know they're just employees that
don't [ __ ] care but they they would
use the description of
swerves to on their SF and I was like
y'all don't did y'all grow this from
seed or did you Source a cut like just
[ __ ] tell me like they wouldn't even
know nobody [ __ ] knows anything they
don't nobody there knows anything you
know they're really they're just
employees yeah they don't want to get
[ __ ] peppered with questions from a
grower who's [ __ ] anal about that
[ __ ] no no and that's that's the hard
part with a lot about with a lot of
these nurseries is that you'll find out
like you go to them and these are people
who are supposed to be holding the
clones and like libraries for people
they don't give a [ __ ] about genetics at
all so like when you're were talking
about this Nursery you're working with
that they were cool what were they
called uh Roots Nursery Roots Nursery
like that's a rarity to find like legit
rning super Rarity um and and I'm
shouting them out to to maybe throw him
some business honestly because I don't
want these guys to disappear they're
they're doing good stuff and they have
good cuts and they're doing they're
doing feno selections they're doing
breeding but they're also holding some
of that older stuff yeah so so uh and
and they know what they're talking about
they're they've been around you can just
half hour on the phone with them you
know yeah you know yeah instantly
totally so all right let's move on to
the Phoenix let's talk about this bad
girl yeah Phoenix uh I got a bunch of
seedlings from CSI in 2019 to flower out
uh I got I think he gave me 120 but I
think we ended up flowering out 111 okay
and
uh for whatever reason maybe some didn't
make it or maybe they were just runty
and I didn't want to bother because run
runs weren't going to runs weren't going
to make the cut anyways yeah not not no
yeah not for what I was selecting for um
you know there there were some shorter
plants that had great noses on them from
the from the
T1000 um that's what Phoenix is is T1000
to TK so it's a TK
batross and uh I mean it's really cool
looking through that many plants I've
never looked through a hundred a 100
plants before from the same from the
same line just to see the spread and
then and like you could put them most of
the plants would either be like green OG
types or like would have purple leaves
but still green
bud and be and have more of that musky
or cookies scent but they would look
like cookies crosses as opposed to just
pure
cookies um and so the Phoenix is from
that group and then the outliers were
like one plant that looked absolutely
like cookies like beautiful if you
scroll down my feed to 2019 there's a
bunch of pictures of it really pretty
really really Frosty nug um it was kind
of a it was kind of a short not very
vigorous plant though um I doubt CSI has
a cut of it anymore but but that's the
one he wanted from me yeah um and then
there was yeah like a couple
T1000 um phenotypes which were shorter
but like had great turps on them the bud
was kind of
leafy um but like so this this one that
I selected it had it was extremely
vigorous top 10 % Vigor
M um great CX to Leaf
ratio the bud didn't really purple up
like it can a little bit and I'm sure
indoors it would be easier to manipulate
yeah but but even even even growing out
late in the fall like you might get some
kexes near the stem to to purple up but
it doesn't really want to purple up yeah
and uh um it's it's got good potency
it's got good yield Vigor like I said
and then the main thing I was looking
for is like I want something with like
big OG
structure and and good yielding but I
want some of that
urel turps in in that flower in the
flavor of it and it and it's the only
one out of all of them that had that
yeah so so that's why that's why I
selected it that's why I've kept it um
and I I I passed it to csi's brother and
they grew it out last year and they're
keeping it and they're still running it
that's awesome which speaks a lot which
like you got to give it to other people
cuz like it's my baby but like until you
give it to somebody else and and see
what they think about it you know does
it stay in their Garden or not you know
how how good is it really you don't know
because you're super biased and that's
why tot that's why you pass it out like
hey I think I got something good here
try it yeah you know like I don't I
don't want to pass on something that's
bunk you know but I think it's good but
like I also understand my own bias
towards it yeah so it's just I'm I'm
growing a bunch of It Outdoors right now
um it's looking and smelling great I
can't wait to smoke some um it's more
flavorful than your traditional TK yeah
because it's got those Urkle turps to it
but it's got the TK potency yeah which
is a tough thing to kind of try to match
up for some reason urle CHS just mean
low potency or sort of that more like
lethargic High I mean look at cookies
it's a to me in my opinion like some
kind of OG heral hybrid like at so what
you're seeing and there's not a lot of
like people don't brag about screaming
potency in cookies but it's like they're
taking it One Direction and this is a
chance to take it a better Direction
with more turbs and better potency I I
think so um it's not it's not a pretty a
plant as cookies is it's more
traditional looking but it's got a
really good calx to leave so um I mean
that that alone just kind of makes it
and it and it I've grown it I've grown
it indoors I've grown it in a very
climate controlled Greenhouse I've grown
It Outdoors yeah I've deed it in the
middle of summer um it's different in
all in all of them it looks different so
it it might check all the boxes
depending on how you grow
yeah I mean it's it was really pretty
grown in my climate controlled
greenhouse and grown indoors um I had a
little bit more trouble trying to get it
to yield there for some reason and I'm
not sure why yet but um Outdoors or in
adep um it's it it's
chunky yeah yeah it's pretty I've seen
pictures of it I want to smoke that yeah
yeah all right then we have let's see
what's the next one oh one more thing I
called it Phoenix I called it Phoenix
because it's the only mother I kept
through the 2020 fire my whole place
fire ran through my whole place and and
I lost some structures uh I lost the
crop for the most part um and uh it was
a it was a very hectic uh fall that year
to say the least and I'm still barely
I'm still struggling to recover from it
honestly but um that's why I called it
the Phoenix it it needed a name the the
the bat cross didn't really have a name
I was calling it back to the triangle
for a while which which I thought was a
good name um I think Caleb came up with
that though
um but then I've just decided to call it
Phoenix and yeah be done with it well
it's memorable that's for sure yeah
totally all right uh we'll show some
love to heart attack from Shabad heart
attack kush yeah so that's from 707
Seedbank before he was even was 707
Seedbank um it's it's it's a Kush CLE
cleaner phenotype which is
a uh OG to Jack cleaner Jack a jack
cleaner back cross mail yeah the cleaner
something like that oh you're right yeah
yeah yeah it was the Jack backcross mail
it was a backcross mail that lauran uh
originally did yeah and he was using
that mail and then he gave the mail to
707 seed bank and because he loved it so
much and he made a [ __ ] ton of the same
Ross that's awesome and uh this heart
attack feno was just like one out of 10
to one out of 20 would be this early
flowering it was a little
shorter um very
frosty um Jack TPS with like some like
puke smell on the back
end and uh not not the not the best
flower like it could get really ly in
the middle but it was early and that was
that's that's why it it it appeals to me
is you know back when I'm running
outdoor I had my garden like basically
four strains and I would start with like
early you know middle late so the
Harvest was always staggered in coming
in because you only have limited dry
space so yeah that was one of my earlies
along with purple wreck and
uh yeah I I I grew the [ __ ] out of it
for years um luckily my buyer didn't
mind the the the Jack turps but which I
know a lot of buyers just would thumb
their noses out for a while yeah for
sure and uh yeah I think I think that's
changed especially on the legal side um
yeah I'm sure you know these TPS come
and go and Trends come and go and I
think that uh a lot of people haven't
really had a good and it's like a pretty
Bud too because it's so Frosty so um and
it's good smoke it's tasty it's it's got
a great High good potency it also washes
really well yeah um so I think uh I
don't know I think it'll make a comeback
so I'm gonna do a I'm gonna do a little
feno hunt next year of it with some uh I
made I made f2s with it so I took a few
Kush cleaner uh males and and crossed
them to the heart attack cut that I was
that I was using and it's it's based on
directional F2 oh is it a directional
F2 because I used that one female I
wanted right so yeah and then just
multiple males just to you know get
everything in the mix so there was one
you just mentioned and we almost forgot
and that's the purple rack which is
absolute one of my favorites of all time
for sure yeah purple wreck was also
really early funny story about that one
I also got that from 40 ounce um I think
I got it the same time I got the the
poodle nuts he bought the seeds from
from DNA yeah um it was the Reserva pada
line which yeah I came out later to find
was just seeds they bought from guys up
here in NorCal yeah one of my one of my
one of my friends up here uh he
accidentally seated his garden one year
because he missed a
mail and
uh I forget what line that was it was
like I want to say it was like oldtime
something maybe the Sweet Tooth or God I
don't remember which line it was but he
sold them all that seed and they bought
it I don't know I don't what was
whatever that you could probably find it
in in their old catalog or something
whatever that line was but then so I get
this and it's like it's great weed it's
like it's like train wreck on a on a
shorter plant uh still purples up you
know really good yielder like absolutely
chunky um super dense buds but still
dense but like a train wreck yeah
structure to the bud yeah and and still
had rubbery stems it was just a shorter
plant
and
uh you know I'm I'm showing some jars to
at a friend's house in Humble one day
and and uh I probably had the poodle
nuts with me and I forget what else I
had but maybe some Sour Diesel and I had
showed him this purple wreck and we were
just talking about and he's like oh yeah
I I made these
seeds so he uh he made a couple of
crosses and sold them to DNA and then
like you know I Circle back around I
didn't even know this person at the time
and yeah and then now now he's a really
good friend and uh I brought him the
from the seed he we waited he never
found a phenotype like that when he
popped the seed that's funny like that
he's like [ __ ] this is the one I was
looking for so funny they g a lot of
popularity um it got brought out to
Colorado it was popular there for a
while I had a buddy in hoping grow it
for a long
time
um
uh I grew it I grew It Outdoors for a
long time just because it it was early
it was Heavy um it kept its smell you
know you know until well into the next
year um the high was me you know it's
kind of
irly you know but other than that like
it it checked every other box like huge
yields or huge yield potential early
just those that's just all that's
winners uh purple wreck was one of the
first urle uh strains I could smoke
where it wouldn't give me Paro instantly
that's what URL was always one of the
ones that got me so bad every time still
is it was like this one was like 20%
Urkel and like mostly train wreck but
you could kind of taste and smell the
KKL like on the back end which just kind
of nice about it and I mean I love train
wreck back in the day that was one of
the reasons I wanted to start growing is
so I could grow my own train wreck and
yeah of course I couldn't get a clone of
it so of course not yeah I mean and then
and then then once I did I grew it out
once and it was like oh this is great
and then I got a Urkle cut and I'm like
on to the next
one after the big hunt right right yeah
after finally tracking it down after
many years I grew I grew some s1's out I
grew some hybrids from uh from JoJo
Rizzo and they were good I grew his s1's
out they were good um his uh Sour Diesel
Crystal locomotive was awesome Yep um I
don't yeah no I did grow Crystal
locomotive too just pure and that was
also really Frosty it just wasn't train
wreck yeah um but those s1s were train
wreck for sure yeah just locomotives is
[ __ ] totally underrated strain from back
in the day yeah I had some of those
seeds in my lost seed stash as well I
still got some in the fridge from a
friend so yeah you ever want to run them
they're there um all right so now we
could talk about something maybe more
modern that's in your garden which is
the uh Mochi runs
you want to talk about that a little bit
sure Mochi runs is just a shot in the
darkk uh strain I bought from a nursery
just clones I bought from a nursery
um just wanting to run something that
kind of like was what the market was
wanting which is candy gas and uh I was
I was pleasantly surprised with how well
it grew it a lot of vigor a tall plant
really really
Frosty
um great you know has that runt
smell um I don't know who bred it yeah
um I don't even know if if if if that
Nursery selected it or not
but just just a just a great plant
for what the market wants right now just
great for a grower and runs is fine I'm
not super into growing runs I don't
really want to grow runs um but this
plant just I don't know it's all the
things that runs is but like without the
headache of a of a kind of a finicky
plant yeah yeah so that's not bad at all
and one nice thing about runs is it
doesn't want a lot of food and I don't
feed a lot you know and so I don't push
my plants very hard um I you know I feel
like that's one of the ways just to [ __ ]
up the flavor of it and I
agree definitely one of the ways you can
get light yields too if you don't if you
don't have it dialed in but um yeah for
sure
uh it yeah it's got that it's not super
it's not super hungry like uh like uh
like well I mean a runs plant is not
super hungry so I I appreciate that some
of the some of the purples can be like
you know food
ODS and uh I don't know just just good
weed and honestly I don't know what's
Mochi about it or I know nothing about
it just a shot in the dark yeah you know
so who knows right yeah I think uh
supposed to be aochi gelato cross to
runs if I remember correctly but okay I
don't know what any of that means yeah
that's probably that's I mean it
probably is what it is but yeah who
knows it could be ice cream cake to runs
who knows yeah right yeah all right
let's get into some philosophical stuff
here um what's hedes for you uh and and
how much do you hes and how much do you
grow for yourself and for your own
tastes I mean you talked a little bit
about this but like so what's Hees for
you man I know I got some headies from
old SG this winter he he grew some
Destroyer out which is like I think it's
Tai Colombian yeah it's a meow
Tha yeah I think you're right something
like that yeah he sent me a bunch of
different phenotypes and one of them the
number five was just a [ __ ] head
ringer so good um absolute head ringer
Head and Shoulders more potent than than
then all the other phenotypes he sent me
yeah that was that's what I would call
some
Hees um for myself like I grow
especially this year I'm growing way too
many strains so I'll just snag what I
like the
most
um so I mean this year it's definitely
going to be those poodle nuts s1's it's
definitely G to be some of the Skittles
uh phenotypes from the Skittles sherb
but I'll keep some sherb as
well um Mochi runs for
sure uh Phoenix for sure it's just
basically I like I like smoking
flavorful stuff I don't care about
potency as much because it all gets me
high and if I'll just smoke more if I if
I need to get more stoned like I'll
smoke M perss all day and I'll just I'll
just smoke twice as much you know yeah
um because M pers isn't potent but
correct super
flavorful um so yeah those um what else
am I going to keep oh definitely the ogs
I've got I got two different ogs from
707 seed bank that he
selected um one's the 707 OG which is a
a three back cross to to sfv I believe
yeah and I'll definitely be keeping some
of those for the head and the 707 Kush
which is
to his Kush 4 backat cross yeah and I'll
definitely be keeping those he says that
one in
particular motorcycle driving by got
love that he
says he says that one in particular is a
serious head ringer so um I'll
definitely keep some of that um when I'm
trying to impress some
friends uh what else do I have going
that I Really Wanna oh I have some
actual Skittles pure Skittles going too
I'll definitely be keeping a few jars of
that yeah um it Well Done Skittles is
just so tasty it is very tasty yeah so
like the tastiest weed that that's
that's what's in my jars for the most
part you know trying to understand what
something is I'm growing you know but
like if I don't like it I'm not even
going to get through the jar you know
yeah I'm with you
yeah that makes sense I mean hes hes is
different for everyone and I I think it
just tends to be Whatever Gets You takes
the edge off that you like the most
whatever Edge need to be taken off that
you like the most and it sounds like
even though you grow for the market
you're still growing stuff that suits
what you love still yeah well I I find
that e like bulk for Market but you can
still get off the stuff that's good that
maybe
isn't going to check that box of super
high THC with the strain everybody wants
um yeah and you know some people's hes
has to be potent because they smoke a
lot and and I totally get that but you
know I'm a timeand place smoker so um it
it doesn't so I can and I like smoking
tasty stuff yeah do you ever smoke
extracts or anything like that not so
much anymore
um I don't I don't make them either
anymore
so um no I don't dab I stopped dabbing a
long time ago um I just my tolerance is
not that high yeah and I mean dabbing
just you know sends sends you through
the roof so it's always weird for me
like I can I can dab just fine and not I
don't know it doesn't really affect my
tolerance with flow I don't know why but
it's so weird like I get so much more
high off flower than I do off dabs like
interesting I'm wired so [ __ ] weird
dude like oh you know what I I will hit
a a live Rosen pin yeah and again it's
for the flavor and and Rosen pens just
happen to be super convenient yeah but
like I I know a couple people that make
them and I and I know you know I they're
using good flour and their process and
I'm there's no [ __ ] and um you know
they're they're just Hustlers on the
traditional side and yeah they make a
really
really good product and I go to a store
like I wouldn't even I wouldn't trust
you know yeah whatever they say it is
like I don't know if it's that you know
no that's that's something I Lear myself
those Rosen pin the disposable ones are
great and uh yeah I just I always have
one from a friend I don't think I've
ever tried a rosin pen yet oh it's it's
just it's just super flavorful that's
that's what I'm looking for when I'm
getting high just like have it taste
good I want that taste to be natural not
some [ __ ] you know in it yeah I want
to taste what this weed smells like you
know not the added TPS right no no added
turps no no added anything you know
clean yeah and also like you know it's
my neighbor so like I'm supporting them
over some [ __ ] company you know yeah
and that matters to a lot of people
totally should
should all right here's a here's a
philosophical topic that I'm really
interested in with the the breeder
Syndicate a lot of what I've been trying
to do is a group based effort to kind of
push back on kind of everything going on
in uh a push of education but you've
talked a lot about like the difference
between unions and co-ops I believe is
what the way you had worded it can you
talk a little bit more about that
because that's like something I'm super
interested in and I don't really know
the definition between the difference
between union and Co-op okay yeah so I
mean I'm talking Co co-ops and people
say unions sometime like Growers need a
union like no we need a co-op unions for
labor for for labor to organize and and
get better rates and get treated better
and I'm all for that you know that's a
good thing because you know businesses
take advantage especially if they have a
monopoly on the employment or if they
collude with each other you know to keep
wages low to to enrich themselves um
co-ops is for producers
um small mainly small producers but I
mean it could be big producers but but
really we're talking small producers
that can't afford to Market themselves
can't afford to um capture these
economies of scale that the big boys
have yeah and so so sunkiss did this
with orange growers uh Ocean Spray did
this with uh
cranberries you know
Ocean Spray that name that everybody
knows because like you think Ocean Spray
you think cranberries that's yeah that's
what they do
um the the the cranberry Growers like
probably up in New England or somewhere
started it and it's just a brand they
started and
collectively um you know they're selling
their cam cranberries through this brand
they're they're they're licensing the
name that maybe some other company buys
their CR berries through the co-op yeah
and then they licens the brand the the
oceans spray name so you want to make
juice with them you want to make sauce
with them or or whatever the case may be
um there's a lot of value in that name
so those
Growers are negotiating better prices
because now that Co-op is one of the big
players collectively made up of many
small farms absolutely now together
they're one of the major players and if
you did the same thing with cannabis and
took all the 10,000 squ foot Farms up
here you'd have I don't know how many
acres 80 acres of canopy space which is
a ton of weed which would make us one of
the biggest players in
cannabis
um you you you'd have them collectively
marketing and and creating brands for
all that product to flow through and
since the Growers own the brand they
capture that added value yeah so now
they're not selling wholesale or they
are selling wholesale to the co-op but
then they have equity in the brand so
they captured some of the markups right
yeah and and and and and that's really
what it comes down to like individually
we can't afford to hit every store and
try and sell our product you know and
the cost of marketing the cost of sales
the cost of packaging all those things
can
be combined so everybody pays a little
piece and then we capture all the value
and I ideally it's a big enough company
that you know it could even vertically
integrate at some point and instead of
striking distribution deals and extract
deals and edible deals and and all these
things we could all just do it in house
or we license our brand which would be
the only authentic brand in cannabis you
know FL Cana tried to do that they tried
to co-op the image of the small Farmer
for themselves yes they did but at the
end of the day all they cared about was
raising a bunch of money to get to tell
investors look look at all this weed
we're going to get from these guys you
know and look how much product we're
going to move and give us these
Investments and they're great at doing
that but what they were shitty at was
selling weed yeah and treating the
farmer right so yeah rather than just
co-opting an image like we are what we
say we are it's not an image it's us
yeah you know so we'd be the only
authentic brand in cannabis there's
there's dairies that that do this too
like
tillamuk yeah it's just
you know let us all do this in-house and
let these small farmers that are forced
to sell wholesale and barely I mean
you're either barely making it or you're
slowly dying absolutely for sure but if
I could get a hundred more dollars a
pound at the end of the day whether it
be through you know some type of
dividend at the end of the year or or
however it would work like that that
makes it all happen now I'm making a
living like it's just farming the
margins are tight they're probably going
to they're going to be tight forever
that's fine I just want to make a Liv
yeah you know at the end of the day
that's it and it's tough to do selling
wholesale and competing on wholesale
prices with the glass houses that are
just putting out thousands of pounds a
month and it's terrible and it drives
the price down on everybody I mean
that's their [ __ ] business plan is to
drive the price down so low and just
they can afford to take losses they can
afford to take losses for ear money
because they've got all this investor
money to to collapse the market and then
hopefully they want to be the last
standing yep you know exactly so if
they're the last ones
standing and all these small farms up
here go out of business these towns go
out of business the whole economy up
here goes out of business your your
friends everybody's in the weed business
up here in some aspect whether it's
you're an accountant working for a bunch
of Growers or [ __ ] hell even the [ __ ]
police you know like grows what are they
gonna do with all their time what are
the [ __ ] most of their families are
involved in the grows like realistic I
mean their families are involved in the
grow they've been making a living
robbing Growers for for years exactly
they're funding if if there's no if they
don't get plant counts and they're going
to lose their budgets and which means
they're gonna have to cut jobs and so I
mean know I hope they do lose their jobs
some some aspect I want to stay in
business so you know you know the whole
economy is tied up with this thing and
if you go down Main Street like
Garberville or Hayfork these towns that
are like 100% pot for the most part
90% there's no tourism there's no um
really other viable industry yeah um
maybe logging a little bit but um you
know it's just a bunch of shuttered
businesses yeah and that means that that
many Less jobs now the people that
worked at that restaurant you know the
the the 15 people it employed they don't
have jobs now you know up in northal
right now like Trinity Holt Mendo like
is it looking can you visually see
places closing down because oh yeah yeah
yeah absolutely like you can see a whole
strip in a building of all the
businesses are are shutter they're
they're
done as a result of the weed Market as a
as a result of the collapse of the weed
Market yeah yeah absolutely sad totally
yeah I mean it these are these are
businesses that technically have nothing
to do with Wei now of course the grow
stores have all Consolidated so there's
only a few bigger ones left yeah yeah
which which is is fine um it was bigger
go home because for a while like
everybody wanted to open a grow store
and they did so every little
hole might be a good grow store and half
the time they're just doing it to get
you know super discounts for their own
grow yeah right you know and so I don't
know there's there's there's still a few
up here that are that are gonna survive
but like yeah go through hay for just
shuttered businesses restaurants um
salons uh daycares uh like people are
moving there's there's just not as many
people now and so yeah I mean it's it's
a real thing the the economy up here has
always been Boomer bust it's since since
white man showed up it's been fishing
and logging and tan barking and a little
bit of prohibition alcohol running and
uh gold up in Trinity yeah
and and it's just boom and bust boom and
bust anytime you have that that that
natural resource extraction business
it's all boom and bust and when logging
busted in the 80s 70s 80s um all these
little Mill towns you know lost their
Mill which was their main source of jobs
which is why the town was created in the
first place you know the people just
kind of stuck around and grew weed yeah
right and the towns didn't die and then
medical came through and and created a
huge new a revive the
boom and you had the green Rush which
you know these Town these little towns
were humming in the spring and in
harvest season humming like every other
truck had like was full of like supplies
and potting soil and you know it brought
tourism from the migrant trimmers ton
yeah tons of business um yeah you'd had
all the trimmers come in the fall yeah
and I mean you know they would be in
town spending their cash at night you
know at the bar or buying clothes or or
whatever you know they they they you
know they brought a back Bunch back home
but like they still spent money there
yeah like go to any bar during harvest
season on like a Friday night and it was
packed you know shoulder toosh shoulder
and most of the people didn't speak
English it was awesome it fun you know
people from all over the place yeah and
uh so it's it's not like that
anymore because you don't have this huge
influx of of people and you know if you
weren't in the pot industry and hated
pot or cannabis for some reason because
you know you're just like that which
there are people up here like that sure
all they see is the negative aspects of
it even if they're like even if they're
benefiting financially like even if
their Plumbing business or you know
whatever business is still benefiting
yeah um they would you know they look
they see all the people on the street
and they would get all grumpy about it
and I don't know man it's just like
that's probably what it looked like in
the early logging years and the early
Gold Rush years was there just like
people on the street you know trying to
get on you know and so I mean that's how
their anwers probably ancestors probably
showed up here the same way so I don't
know you know so it's it's sad to see
and it's sad to see a whole like sort of
culture and Industry up here sort of
slowly die
or it's it's dying it's transitioning to
something else but I just feel like if
we could
Empower all the small Growers to unite
and this has been tried and people are
still trying to do it now yeah um I've
definitely tried and I'm just trying to
like spread the idea to people that like
oh [ __ ] like this could work yeah it's
tough to get Growers to agree on things
and as soon as you join something that's
the last time you get everything your
way yep so it's it's very it's very
difficult um a lot of us are
Growers yeah United we're we're the
biggest player in the industry um we
have the best product we have um the
best genetics we have I mean just the
knowhow up here the knowledge base um
and every facet of growing including
compliance and um extraction and like
most of the innovators are up here you
know and especially on the traditional
side like that's the real heart of the
of the culture and that's still up here
as well
and all those genetics that people have
never seen before are still up here yeah
a lot of it was generational yeah
totally and
so I don't know just like to me it's a
no-brainer but it's just it's very hard
to get people to come together yeah it
is and uh it it certainly is helping
right now that the price is so low and
people are realizing that like oh [ __ ]
like but damn like if I could just
package up my ounces and get like 30
bucks or 40 bucks an ounce like that's
more money than I'm getting wholesaling
right now so but like oh [ __ ] now like
how am I going to do sales well you know
like why don't you get together with all
the other Farms on your
road and and and and make one one brand
and everybody just chips in to buy those
10,000 myar bags yeah and and and and
you fill them up with the best stuff you
have and you you know you you hire
somebody to do sales and so like you're
all paying one person so you're just
paying like you know one fifth of that
person's commission or salary or however
it works yeah yeah you know so I don't
know that's that's my dream that's what
I think could be the savior of of a lot
of people like me that like that are I
mean if I was in this for the money I'd
have quit already oh yeah sure you know
the money was nice like there's no
avoiding there's no getting around that
like that was good I wouldn't be here
without it because how else how the hell
else would I buy land yeah exactly yeah
but you know I would have left a long
time ago and a lot of people have
they've it's like okay this this isn't
profitable anymore I'm gonna go on and
do something else or live somewhere else
or on the flip side of what you just
said you took your money and bought land
a lot of people didn't they bought toys
and didn't reinvest their money into
this all I ever wanted to do is grow
weed like that's that was my toy yeah
you know that's what I I want to spend
my money on a Greenhouse yeah you know
not a you know whatever a sports car or
a giant truck or something you
know yeah or for kids I don't have any
kids so that's that's yeah dogs are good
enough bro dogs are good enough dogs
dogs keep me busy yeah so anyway so yeah
that's my whole Spiel on co-ops and uh
boy if anybody sees this that you know
if you're a legal grower
um hit me up on Instagram or something
you know it's going to take like Minds
to get through all this it really is
like I I've seen no other way through
this when I started the breeder
Syndicate like the name the idea behind
the name it's like a a bringing together
of a group of people like Minds like
that want to come together and achieve a
goal and yeah I want I see what what I
was seeing when I was starting this was
humble Menino Trinity County I'm not
even from there but I have a lot of
friends that are from there and their
families are there and I care about them
and I realized oh my God no one no one
that's been doing this their whole life
has retirement plans there's just no
retirement plans and there there are
things we can do to make it a softer
landing pad for a lot of people who pay
the way for us to be here and there's
ways to do it there's things you can
establish and and even thinking about
[ __ ] like that seems very pie in the sky
or or thinking about having a a
conglomeration of people to push back
against the legal Market by bringing one
Big Brand together seems very p
so doable it really is you know it it
it's and it's been done before exactly
and there's also there's all these other
small co-ops you never hear about but
they're just buyer co-ops for like so
that Mom and Pop hardware stores can buy
drywall yeah at a cheap enough price to
compete with Home Depot y buy all that
company exists for is to just buy
drywall and bulk and distribute it to
all these like Mom and Pop hardware
stores yep
and they do exist and and they allow Mom
and Pop to survive and compete you know
by capturing economies of scale and and
uh you know that's that's that's what
it's all about I mean even just in the
legal realm you know like when it
happened like you know half my friends
converted to legal and half of them
didn't yeah
and most of them are not growing anymore
on E it doesn't matter which side yeah
but but most of them most of them aren't
you know either they went legal and then
gave up on that and and and went back to
the to the traditional side or or they
got jobs yeah you know and the people on
the traditional side you know they've
gone from outdoor to indoor because
there's there's tougher enforcement now
and and and they're they're red tagging
your
property so everybody's kind of
transitioned a little bit and you know
just depending on how how well you were
situated for the transition it was a lot
of it was just luck that I'm still here
I've I've been fortunate to have a lot
of good luck and it's just by like it's
dumb luck it's not I didn't foresee
everything working out how it did it
just happened to work out that it it
worked out for me because just I
happened to have a a good property for
it you know yeah and and I've made
sacrifices to have that property well
that's the part that's not luck right
like that's the part that's not luck and
there are Reas you can make it's kind of
luck man
like you built
it when it comes down to it
like yeah like I could I could have
easily bought a property closer to town
that wasn't so remote and tough to get
to I mean that was kind of good for the
old days but it's a huge pain in the ass
now to live a life but at the same time
I never could have afforded this
property close to town it's you know
it's it was cheap because it was so
remote I mean that's that's all it comes
down to it's it's 90 minutes away from
any type of town and whoa that's out
there bro oh it's out there yeah it's
definitely out there and that used to be
a good thing and now it's now it's not
so much but I admire it I do I'm still
fortunate to to to be in it you know I'm
GNA I have at least one more year you
know
um before I really got a look and see if
this is working or not yeah well
hopefully hopefully people will get
together and realize their the the power
in collectivism because there's true
power in that and I think there are
reasons why people don't know that yeah
the need to capture added value to your
product and absolutely um you know some
of the trade organizations are working
on consumer direct sales for small
farms um there's a thing called the ship
Act at the national level which um I
mean it hasn't been voted on yet but it
would be a writer on some other Bill to
say like when that when legaliza Federal
legalization does happen we're giving
small farms under such and such a size
um path to re retail sales themselves as
opposed to um having to go through
dispensaries and stuff yeah and that's
that's what the small farm needs to
survive is is is is farmers markets you
know let let that small Farm sell direct
to their consumer people want that
anyways but then they can capture they
cut out the middleman and capture the
added value of making retail
sales and I mean the wine industry
already does this with their wine clubs
and their tasting rooms yeah they you
know you can come to the vineyard come
to the winery taste taste what there is
to taste buy a bottle or two or or or
whatever hang out um
every every Farm's not going to be set
up to do that but collectively we could
definitely set something up like that
and join our our wine club let let us
send you an ounce a month you know yeah
you know buy a subscription get an ounce
a month or or or whatever it ends up
being I don't know but um they already
have SE like it yeah let I mean those
wineries when you go byy to Wine Country
and buy wine there like you're paying
you're paying an inflated price you're
not getting it cheaper because you're at
the source you're paying more for it yes
right I don't even want I don't even
want to charge more I just want to
charge retail a fair retail price just
so I can make a living you know and show
people like yes like this weed is better
than what you're finding in the store
and you know what once once enough Farms
are able to do that and like actually
have a client
base yes hopefully they can sell direct
but to the people that can't get shipped
weed or the people that can't show up to
the farmers Market they're going to look
for it in a store yeah and so that'll
drive sales to these dispensaries that
are fighting us tooth and nail to not
allow us to sell consumer
direct so yeah right it's so no dude I
think I think it's one of the most
important things uh to talk about is is
the power collectivism and being able to
to push back against the corporate [ __ ]
going on I I saw this with 64 like I was
like oh the probably going to make it
more illegal for us to grow more illegal
for corporations to sell weed which in
turn makes it more legal for them to
grow weed with the right licenses more
expensive for us and then they'll break
us MoneyWise gotcha well I mean I mean
the old the old cow growers association
hezeki Allen like he had to fight tooth
and nail just to not set California up
as like a six licensed State like some
of these other east coast states where
yeah you know there's just six licenses
and that's it to let to let these small
farms like uh one one of his buddies uh
uh Casey O'Neal said a long time ago if
you don't have a seat at the table
you're on the menu yep and that's and
that's exactly what it is so that's why
you know getting Behind These trade
organizations that that are made up of
small farms and then there's one broad
Trade Organization made up of these
small farm trade organizations that
lobbies at the state level to to to push
back and to to these these huge money
corporate interests that can pay
lobbyists and lawyers to to to write
regulations for for the state to say no
you got a whole region up here that
needs something else yeah and there
there are voice and and that's why you
got to be you got to be a little
politically active in cannabis and that
goes back to the 215 days too yeah it
does you had to educate City councils
you had to you had to you had to be you
had to be an activist if you're going to
be in cannabis because you had to like
you had to you were pushing through new
like Virgin
Territory and you weren't just going to
set up a shop and just do business you
know because there's going to be forces
coming back at you so you got to be
active and pushing against them yeah so
yeah I mean like that old term all
politics is local like realistically a
lot of people pay attention to the the
you know nation's news every night but
pay attention to what's going on
immediately around you and get it
matters so much more who's on your city
council or your Board of Supervisors or
your Planning Commission like especially
if you're in business in any business in
that area that's going to play a much a
much bigger role in the success of your
business because they might just
regulate you out of business yeah that's
for real you know because somebody's
gonna be in their ear wanting one thing
and if you're not in their ear chirping
about the other thing you're you're yeah
you're gonna get put out of business
you're you know you're gonna you're
going to let Walmart move in unless you
say something about it and they're and
you're done you know
Walmart's definitely in your your
supervisor's ear you better you better
be in the other ear talking about n this
is [ __ ] they can afford the lobbyist
we just have to be as smart and as
active more active and smarter more
active and just unite finally we've
always been independent and when the
price was high it was easy to be
independent yeah you know and now it's
just like no like you gotta you gotta be
if you want to do this you got to be
thinking 10 years ahead what you want it
to look like and start now yeah because
somebody else already has that vision
and that's what they do for a living is
manipulate things for their benefit you
know and we're kind of all just all
learning to come out of the shadows and
and and kind of learn how the system
really works you know yeah well dude
we've almost hit two hours so I want to
have you back again like this is awesome
we could talk about tons of [ __ ] and I
know people are gonna enjoy this and
like we have Forum stuff to talk about
we have all kinds of stuff we could do
so cool um dude been an ABS absolute
pleasure let's talk about some of your
uh the places where people can find
you
um well uh Instagram uh little Hill
cultivators um you can hit me up DM me
um to find my
product and I know mocan and organic can
don't have any right now but they should
soon prop to them again yeah totally uh
they they they've been supporting the
small farms up here for a long time and
and and and giving us our our
recognition sort of they also do a cool
thing if you are in NorCal like in
November December they do this cool
thing every year and they've been doing
it since before 64 where they'll sell a
taste of the like it's called a harvest
box or something like that where it's
got 28 grams like individual grams from
28 Farms of 28 strains and so you can
like it's they call it the taste of
harvest or something like that and so
like they'll go through all you know
they get entries maybe 60 Farms submit
yeah yeah and they just pick out the
best 28 and uh I've been lucky enough to
be in it for the past I don't know maybe
four years yeah and so I hope to be in
it again this year I we haven't that
that like that hasn't been settled yet
um well if they
watch listen listen yeah still support
them because they've been supporting
small farms like even if I don't make it
like I don't I don't care
yeah they're still doing good work um H
yeah and right now that's the only place
um I think you could you could find me
um they definitely don't have anything
from last year so I think they're gonna
get reup with some Sour Diesel and
awesome I've already smoked it and I'm
I'm fairly sure it'll it'll it'll do
well so um yeah so that's that's where
you can find me all right any props you
want to give to any of the homies from
the past future present any of it uh
yeah all all all all my all my buddies
up here CSI
um I don't know I seem to have like a
lot of friends on Instagram too that
that do good work
um uh my old Mentor
seaweed
uh um his name didn't really come up on
on on this run but uh it did on that
last one we forgot to record yeah so for
people that don't know we had like an
hour's worth of awesome stuff not
recorded because I didn't hit the record
button so this is round two but yeah we
get to some
more yeah um yeah I don't know just to
Trinity County um and the people trying
to make it happen up there um they
they're a rare breed and tough people
and um so Props to them and then humble
and Mendo as well everybody's kind of
been through the ringer yeah and uh I
don't know yeah that's about it all
right brother well thank you for your
time and we will be having you back
again soon this is awesome and uh we'll
see everyone again next week cheers all
right right on thanks
guys want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon in our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it
out