[Music]
reality falls
i am
[Music]
worries
to
[Music]
so
all right
we're going to kick off now with the
first part of it which is human origins
and we'll start with the fact that the
bible says that in the beginning
in the beginning you've all heard this
was the word
but in order to explain everything that
followed after that the word would have
to be something on the order of this
as you can see
supercalifragilisticexpialidocious
it had to be a heck of a word to cover
all the ascension the sense of intuition
over time the creationists
changed it they expanded a little bit to
three words
god did it
god did everything
and that's all you needed for an answer
why does it rain god did it
i did
everything god did
and that worked for a couple thousand
thousand years that was all you needed
but then 145 years ago a new group of
people came on the scene the darkness
with what they thought was a better
more rational explanation which is that
nature did delete god
that nature and nature only
did it it was a line drawn down the
middle
god here nature here
and no mix
no next
145 years
and then the creationists tried an end
run by bringing in a group of much
smarter individuals much better educated
than the original ones and they are
called intelligent designers
intelligent designer but still basically
god is at the bottom of their theory as
well
everything is so complex it couldn't
have happened by accident
therefore god didn't do it
only recently he has a
much smaller group of individuals
started putting forth a theory called
intervention and i'm one of those
i'm an interventionist and what we say
is that it wasn't a god with a capital g
an anthropomorphic god it was a group of
gods
multiple people multiple beings
small g
gods and that
they that's our mantra they did it
my god did it
they did it
and that accounts for everything
in its own way that's come to be on the
earth and that's what i'm going to be
showing you here basically tonight in my
beginning next slide please in my
beginning okay am i beginning to book
everything you know is wrong which is
not here you can't you can't get it we
tried to ship it here and it didn't work
out with the publisher a lot of problems
australia the long time etc you will be
able eventually if you wanted to get it
through duncan road's nexus magazine
so
if you want keep in mind
if you want to order it from the states
direct
go through barnes and noble
the barnes noble has the best shipping
work wwwbn.com
barnes noble all right what i'm trying
to show in the cover here is the
interventionist point of view boiled
down that the
gods multiple gods small g handed the
spark of human life to the primitives
that were on the earth at the time
by means of
intervention
via
genetic engineering which is symbolized
by a test tube
that is the theory that we are
genetically and genetically engineered
species product and we'll talk about
those samples by the next slide
in the beginning
in the beginning what every one of these
is apparently going to be cut off at the
top and i'm sorry for that i don't know
how to fix this but in the beginning
what you have is the cloud so in
the bible's beginning was the word in my
beginning was the book and now in the
beginning was that the cloud of dust and
gas
swirling around in over
about 10 billion years down to about 4.5
billion years ago where the solar system
took the shape basically that we know
now and the earth was basically
coalesced out of the cloud as the
proto-earth next slide and then that
proto-earth for 4.5 to 3.5 billion years
ago
the proto-earth which is deceiving mass
of magma being bombarded by asteroids
and meteorites it was just an impossible
place to live as you can see excellent
then as it began to cool off over time
from 3.5 to around 2.5 the next billion
years
and we have cooling enough to where you
have mississippi plan beginning to show
that's still supposed to be multilateral
but at least the bombardment of
meteorites and all this stuff now
there's no one would have thought at one
time that life could have begun on earth
at a time like this
so the theory was that life didn't begin
until around 2 billion years ago when it
was cooled off enough to have water at
least
and that inorganic
molecules were somehow swirled together
and became a living thing nobody quite
understood
but since nature was at the core of
everything according to the darkness it
had to happen
it just had to happen they couldn't
quite figure it out didn't matter we'll
figure it out we kept assuring everybody
we'll figure it out and then about 30
years ago that was what they taught us
what all you you were taught which kids
being taught today your grandkids can
talk
but about 30 years ago they found out
that in fact
life had already come to earth around 4
billion years ago
back when it was seething magma you saw
what it looked like and everyone pretty
much agrees that's what it was this is
what came prokaryotic bacteria now if
the real
beginning of life recipient life had
really started the way they say it would
have been something extremely simple
kind of like a virus it would have been
about the size of one of these little
spots in here like this
instead is this really large complex
kind of one single cell bacteria
called prokaryotic bacteria now
the one thing that distinguishes it is
though it has a number of dna strands it
doesn't have a nucleus
the dna is not held within a nucleus it
kind of floats free and loose that's
what distinguishes prokaryotic bacteria
and it came at about four billion years
ago only about a half a billion years
from when the earth was first beginning
to coalesce out
so it's
extremely unlikely that in fact
impossible that life formed on earth it
came here whole and complete
why because it didn't come in only one
form there are two types of prokaryotic
bacteria the archaea and the true
bacteria
two types
distinct different types
so it absolutely is for certain that
life came here now the question really
is
how did it get here was it directed here
was it sent here was it delivered here
on purpose or did it just accidentally
show up somehow
is the question that has to be answered
now for the prokaryotic bacteria
the thing you need to keep in mind about
it is it is indestructible
indestructible that's what's so cool
about it
the earth got what it needed exactly
when it needed it when it was just
beginning
if you want to turn a planet into
something that can support higher life
forms you've got to give it something
that will turn
the environment and turn oxygen in loose
in the atmosphere
in the water to tie up the free iron to
turn iron into rust iron oxide and then
have an excess of oxygen so that higher
life forms can live on that place
exactly what the earth needed which in
these creatures right here to do that
that got early on two forms all of them
indestructible early on
pretty neat what an amazing coincidence
amazing coincidence
okay and two billion years ago
remember we've gone now two billion
years approximately four billion years
with the procare two billion years of
the prokaryotes from four billion years
just those two kinds and then suddenly
around two billion years ago these
things appear out of nowhere just like
the prokaryotes did
out of nowhere come the eukaryotes
strata with that and suddenly you have
to travel
and they're extremely complicated
hundreds to thousands of times larger
than the prokaryotes with a nucleus
surrounding many many many more strands
of dna this is a sophisticated yet still
one cell creature pumping out much more
oxygen much more efficiently but they
couldn't come any sooner because the
earth wasn't
prepared these are fragile these are not
indestructible these are destructive
so they couldn't come until
the earth had been fixed
to a certain extent by the prokaryotes
two billion years of prokaryotic
activity allowed these to appear and
when they do appear
the darkness went with the prokaryotes
they can argue that well they came from
you know maybe space from a meteorite or
something like that
but the
eukaryotes have to be explained in
practical terms and what's the only way
that could have happened if you don't
see any transition from prokaryotes to
eukaryotes i mean from no nucleus to a
nucleus from none of this to all of this
how did it happen
what they say is this yet
that after a couple of billion years of
living side by side
the larger prokaryotes suddenly decide
to eat some of the smaller prokaryotes
and instead of becoming food the smaller
prokaryotes change their physical
structure into all these different
things including the nucleus of the
eukaryotes
that magically somehow
they
they cannibalized each other and it
worked and a new much more sophisticated
living thing
came to be
and for as absurd as it sounds it's
gospel among biologists it's ridiculous
but it is acceptable next
now this is how this is how they say it
happened
these
turned into all this
it didn't
it's ridiculous excellent
after another billion and a half years
from two billion years to around 560
million years ago
just round it up to 500 million
give or take
another billion and a half with the
prokaryotes and the eukaryotes pumping
oxygen into the atmosphere tying up the
iron making iron oxide and having an
excess of oxygen suddenly
out of nowhere
you have the seas filled with creatures
this is called a cambrian explosion and
it's exactly what it was thousands of
species of animals and plants none of
them looking anything like anything we
have on earth today except the horseshoe
crab that's the only thing that's left
and it looks kind of like
maybe even the descendant of this one
other than that
they don't look like anything we have
today
and yet it came out of nowhere within
about a five million year period which
is an idling compared to of billions of
years that have come preceding that
the cambrian explosion
there it all is all 26 animal phylum
animal follow that we have today
came
at the same time
again overnight
no catastrophe nothing leading into it
it just came when it came happy and it
was big
this is the timeline to show you what
i've been telling you
the beginnings at 4.5
and then you have the bombardment and
there are the prokaryotes around 4
billion years ago while the
bombardment's still going on prokaryotes
prokaryotes prokaryotes down here 2
billion years ago and then the
eukaryotes joined them and noticed that
they're still the same today as they
were when they started out no
appreciable companies no
darwinian evolution at all it's the same
you would think that the first and the
simplest would have had a heck of a lot
we told you
but they don't seem to know
they seem to breathe as true today as
they did then
anyway so the eukaryotes and the
prokaryotes continue on and right here
in this little blink right here that
little window is the five to ten million
years when the camera explosion occurred
and then after that came the full
panoply of complex life as we know it in
only the last five
point five built half a billion years
500 million years so it's a small part
of what
came before
all of complex life as we know
and how didn't happen
well next level what the darwinians
tell us is that this is the way it
happened
it went from each survived reproduce
it's about reproduce to this guy who can
stand here and say what's it all about
that it was the fish became amphibians
amphibians became reptiles reptiles
become mammals and birds and mammals
become us
macro evolutionary two parts to this two
parts
macro evolution and micro revolution
this is macro evolution this is species
into species into species into species
and this is the the cornerstone of
darwinian evolution is macro evolution
and darwin himself said
i can see at this point in time when i'm
doing this in the late middle late 1800s
1869 when he published his book
excuse me 1859
that we are short of transitional
species in the fossil record but now
that we know
to look we're going to find the species
that are going to exist in the cracks
here that are going to show
a transition here from one to another
the missing links they're going to be
found darlin said if they are not it
will be clear that my theory is wrong
well they've been looking now for 145
years and they still don't have
one single solitary unambiguous
transitioned from one species to another
and the problem is there should be
hundreds literally hundreds of them
now what they argue is that well we
don't have a complete fossil record yet
you can't hold us to account on this
because the fossil record is not
complete that is true it isn't complete
but what they what the reality of it is
is whole sheets of it are completed
you'll have whole sheets that are
complete and then you have sections that
aren't complete then you'll have more
sections that are complete and you'll
have sections that aren't complete
and so they're hiding behind the fact
that the fossil record isn't completely
filled in
but the truth of it is within the areas
the long sheets the long periods of time
that are complete there are no
transitional species so they know the
theory is wrong and they've known it for
quite some time
but they can't acknowledge that it's
wrong because the creationists are
standing right there
knocking on the door saying well if you
don't know what's going on we want our
theory to be taught in schools
i don't want that the darwinists don't
want that i don't blame them the
creationist point of view should be kept
in churches where it belongs
if they weren't so belligerent about
that
the darwinists could acknowledge and
admit what they don't know and we have a
much better chance of getting to the
truth of what really happened
but as long as the situation as it is as
it is with the creationists we're going
to be stuck with the darwinists
pretending
that somehow
darwinian evolution and the transitional
species are going to be found and
they're not
next slide
all right this is microevolution
this is indeed a real point of fact in
the world around us these are hawaiian
honey creepers darwin saw this
phenomenon of creatures adapting
themselves in part on the galapagos he
saw it with darwin's finches he saw the
tortoises he saw it with other things
and what he said was okay if we can see
changes in parts as clearly as this
we can extrapolate
we can assume
that changes in whole bodies are not out
of the question and in fact we're
logical and he's right it is logical
to assume that but the problem is it
doesn't work in reality the evidence is
just not there there is no macro
evolutionary his micro evolution is
clear he saw it he saw it first and
documented it
but there is no to this day true macro
evolution
it doesn't extend past the parts
the honey creepers still the honey
creeper still reproduces like a honey
creature still just like underground
nissan all these are hungry
that's the key
micro evolution yes macro evolution that
looks like this is the macro evolution
of man supposedly we start out around 4
million years ago maybe 5 million years
ago as a couple as a pair of upright
walking chimps and upright walking
gorillas known as the australopithecines
and they go from around 4 million years
ago 9 billion now 4 million to around 2
million years ago when a new type of
being appears and these are called the
early homos the early men
we met homo erectus off me homo villa
sono erectus
down to neanderthal and then suddenly
around 120 000 years ago you have a new
thing that is again as completely
different as this one is from this one
from this one to this one
pro magnet pro magnum around 120 000
years ago in the fossil record
and what what they're trying to tell you
make us they want us all to believe that
this is somehow a transition when in
fact at each of these stages there is a
transformation
whole and complete these are upright
walking chimps and gorillas these are
more man-like but they are still very
unhuman-like
these are your true humans only 120 000
years ago in the fossil record so you go
from 4 million here for these guys down
to 2 million of these and then down to
120 000 for the grown magnets keep that
in mind next slide
now walking is the key
go back if you would please know we let
me stress them walking is the key to
what makes these and these
be considered pre-humans
walking walking is the key
and what walking is according to
darkness is the sure
sign that
something is on the way to learning to
be a human they say that this has this
is a process of learning it starts with
walking they used to say the brain was
first and everything followed that until
they found these guys at times they had
brains like gems and gorillas and they
said all right well then it was walking
walking came first not tool use not
brains walking
so walking is the key
walking is very important now the thing
is do you really learn to walk
can you go from being a quadruped
down on all fours to being upright on
all twos can you
biologically change your body to do that
by sheer adaptation yes you could
and here's how you have to do it and
here is the theory as it's put forth
believed and preached as gospel
that
as the forests of africa began to shrink
some group of quadrupeds decided to get
out of the forest move out onto the
savannahs
out on the savannas
and begin to stand upright more and more
and more and more first first just stand
up to look over the grass and then go
back down stand up to look over the
grass for for lions and tigers and
whatever and do that
over and over and over again for
hundreds and thousands of years and in
that process as they're standing up to
look over the grass of the predators
that are coming to eat them they end up
at the end of those thousands of years
standing upright like us becoming
upright walking creatures
now this is again theory as it's taught
and as it's believed and this is
preached
the problem is how do you get through
thousands of generations when as soon as
you come out of those trees and walk out
on the savannah you are nothing but a
walking snack treat
you have no fans you have no claws you
have no tough skin or anything you're
just a big bag of food moving to the big
cats out on the savannah
it requires that you have generation
after generation doing this
altering their their bodies as they move
as they learn to stand upright
couldn't happen you can't get from the
beginning to the end
because everything in between has been
eaten by the big cats before they could
reproduce
off
you understand it couldn't happen and
yet that is what they t because
from their point of view it can't happen
any other way
that has to be the way it happened and
yet common sense tells anybody that it
could
so where do these walking creatures come
from it's clear that they're walking we
have the tracks at leotoly of 3.2
million years ago perfectly upright
and we have lucy at 3.5 million years
ago
hips and everything pelvis arranged to
walk upright
so we know they're walking upright
how if they didn't if they couldn't
learn it in the way that we just
described we just talked about
where'd it come from
perfect answer never talked about
perfect answer next slide the myosin
and my scene here goes from around 25
million years ago out here to around 5
million years ago right here into the
plastic
in those 20 million years
you have two dozen
two dozen
genera of
apes
apes not monkeys monkeys are from 35
million years to 25 million years you
have nothing but monkeys so they've been
around about 10 million years but when
the apes when the myosin apes hit the
scene hit the fossil record they
dominate
very few monkeys lots of eggs
lots of eggs and guess what
a bunch of them now we're talking
tailless
apes
50 different species
a couple of dozen genera we're talking a
lot of different kinds we're talking
from small ones
given size
up to man sized
up to giant size touch that roof with
their heads gigantopithecus
every size ape you can imagine
and guess what else out of those 50
different species
24 generic have come only four survivors
on four survivors
chimpanzees gorillas give them some
orangutans
what happened to the rest of them
what happened
well they say
science tells us that all of these all
of these were quadrupeds down on all
fours because the only four that came
out
that they acknowledge are water pads
but you have the real problem next slide
with the short arm base
a bunch of them like procrastinate for
example have arms that are equal in
length to their legs
and so they try to say that well
they must walk like this
because
if you're a quadruped a true quadruped
your arms have to be longer than your
legs for you to walk comfortably for you
to locomotive it's not walking for you
to lock them up comfortably your arms
have to be longer than your legs
so
keep in mind our arms are shorter
than our legs
significantly shorter but the myosin
apes have arms that are equal to the
length of their legs approximately which
means that their arms would dangle down
around their knees if they can walk
upright
these are the short-rapes are a real
embarrassment and this is why you don't
hear much out of the magazine
because they don't want to imply that
they were walking
but they were
there's no other way for a short armed
aid to locomote comfortably
except on two feet
so it's very very fair to assume that
those short-armed ioc names were walking
upright and that what we find in the
fossil record at
four and five and now they're arguing
six million years ago walking upright
versus nothing more than five teenagers
walking right out of the myocene doing
what they've always done the short arm
base walking upright next slide
so what they try to do with three humans
to make you think
to to brainwash you into believing these
things really were
pre-human
is that they put these butt ugly heads
on human bodies human looking bodies
and you come to believe
you come to think that that's how it was
when in fact there's nothing at all
human about these bodies of the
pre-humans
bones are different bones are thicker
heavier arms are longer
nothing about it's the same next level
and here we see the early now again over
here to the left with this thing's given
out on me of the australopithecines
isn't working at all
so let me just give it up just use my
hand since i'm so close anyway these are
the australopithecines would be here
this is homomobilism erectus neanderthal
and then over here
pro-magnum right in there now all of
these are indeed transitional forms tran
transition
this is a transformation from these
to this just the same way that you have
a transformation here from the
australopithecines to here
transformation and then you have
basically the brain just getting bigger
that's basically it the brains are just
getting bigger but with the skulls
themselves the bones are very heavy
compared to ours very thick compared to
ours the brow ridges are very heavy and
thick compared to hours the eyes are big
brown night vision eyes you guys like
this you've got night vision noses look
how big and wide the noses are and these
little passages
big wide flat noses you got a mouth
sticking off the face these teeth are
jutting out it's hard to see this but
they do
they have no chance at the jaws from
here you see they have no chance to just
slant back
this guy pro magnum comes from all this
with exactly the opposite in every way
he's got
a forehead they all lack a forehead they
just go back from the eyebrows
very reduced brow ridges very reduced
eye sockets and poor night vision a nose
pinched up off the face
a mouth squashed back in flat and chin
sticking out
exactly the opposite
and yet somehow that's supposed to be a
transition that you go from this one
looking pretty much the same this is
missing and suddenly
totally different and that's a
transition
that is somehow a natural flow of events
no even the darwinists acknowledge that
can't be
so they say all right well yeah we
acknowledge that real problem we're
going to plug that hole with a missing
link that's going to go in there
and show some transition
well the problem is
anybody that knows anything they need a
couple of dozen
to transition from this to this you need
a couple of dozen
species in there to show that they don't
have a fingerling
there is no missing link
in the human chain never has been never
going to be
there is no missing link it's just a
plug and a huge gaping hole
in darwinian theory because again
they're trying to keep the creationists
at bay as long as possible
as long as possible and they'll do
anything
say anything pull any absurdity out of
the hat to keep the charade alive
that's how it works
okay well if everything i'm telling you
is true and these guys are not
pre-humans as we're told what are they
if they're they're in the fossil record
they lasted for millions of years and
they walked up right what are they
they are hominoids
hominoids
hominoids of human-like creatures that
are not really human homologous what are
hominoids next slide you have here we
have that they are they're all over the
world every continent except antarctica
bigfoot sasquatch
yowie
almas
they have names wherever they are in the
world they are everywhere in the world
there are deep forests
jungles and swamps and they live in the
part of the world parts of the world
that we don't live in
now we think that we are everywhere that
we know everything about our planet that
there's no place that we don't really
know about that we have been on
and that is absolute garbage that is so
untrue in the united states alone which
is a very populated country very well
covered country
in the united states alone 25 of the
land has never once been foot surveyed
never once foots and mayors go in there
why can't get in there it's too hard
too difficult the terrain is too
difficult that is where they live
here in australia i don't know
what it is but people were telling me if
you fly over huge parts of australia you
just look down it's just a blanket of
trees
people never move
i'm sure it's the same year
it's the same wherever you get the
reports of these creatures living
upright walking hair covered
primates
just upright walking chimps and gorillas
myoscene apes they've been going doing
like this been living on this earth this
has been their planet since the myosin
20 million years ago
they've been out there making their
living
living in those places where we don't
live
right now to this day fifty percent of
the arable land of the earth fifty
percent take away the ice caps take away
the deserts arable land fifty percent of
it
consider terra incognita we don't know
what it is we basically don't know
what's out there
we don't live there we live in about
half
to any extent in about half of the arab
land
of the earth
there's plenty of room for them to roam
to be to live
plenty
perfect example next level
the panda
was the
1800s you know how now in the last 50
years we hear about the commonwealth's
bigfoot says watch out for all that
in the early part of the 1800s
it was panda stories kept coming out of
china of a black and white bear that ate
bamboo
and of course every expert in the world
knew that was impossible
that there were no vegetarian bears they
were omnivores and that they were black
and white
brown
other color bears but not two tones
until in 1869 a french naturalist
sent the hide of one back to the french
museum of natural history and they
stuffed it and knew what it looked like
and then every scientist who had been
saying that such a thing is impossible
said well we were just maintaining
healthy skepticism as scientists are
supposed to do instead of admitting to
the fact that they were just ruling it
out because it was beyond their their
conception their imagination
and so they said now that we know
they're for real we're going to get off
our thumbs and we're going to go out
there and we're going to be the first to
bring another one in
such juan province china is not that big
place
it's just tough rugged terrain
mountainous with bamboo forests instead
of regular forests but other than that
how long do you think it took to bring
in the next one when they knew it was
there and it was sending in top quality
teams
to find it long they took
60 years
60 years and then over the next 20 years
they brought in half a dozen more and to
this day it's really hard to go out into
those jungles i mean those baby forests
and and find a live panda from the wild
why what's the panda doing nothing it's
a it's a brightly colored slow-moving
dim-witted animal
that really doesn't do anything that's
in the day doesn't hive doesn't anything
sophisticated to stay out of the way
getting caught
the problem is we don't function well in
its environment
but we think we function well everywhere
excuse me but we don't
we do not
and so
imagine if you will
a creature that is bigger
faster lives at night eats anything can
really move
if it wants to
and it's absolute master of its
environment and it is smart
now imagine going out and trying to find
that when you can't find pandas
that are really stupid animals
it isn't going to happen deliberately
you're going to see these creatures
accidentally and that's how it happens
when it happens and it happens about 150
times a year around the world good
silence
about 150 times every year
okay when it happens
evidence is left behind
and the evidence in most cases is tracks
in most cases it's tracks we have right
now
over the last 50 years that we've been
keeping track about 10 000 plaster cast
photographs are both of tracks
all of which according to the darwinian
paradigm the darwinian mainstream is
impossible because why
hominoids can't exist
they can't not that they don't exist
they can't exist on the darwinian
paradigm crumbles
it crumbles
so
is it hard to know one way or the other
whether these things do exist based on
the proof that they leave behind yes
because they're big creatures they're
heavy creatures and they leave tracks
and tracks are indeed
readable
there's a whole branch of science called
technology that does nothing but read
the tracks left in fossil shales and
other fossils of creatures that lived
millions of years ago well if they can
read those tracks and tell you what
those animals look like they can read
the tracks and homomorphs and tell you
what they look like but suddenly when it
comes time to read a homonym track all
rules are out the window and they have
to be false and you can't even get them
out of their offices hardly to go out
and take a look only a handful
of scientists that support the reality
of homonymous will go out and take a
look you can't get them to go why
because it can't be real not that it
isn't it can't be real well here's what
you get when you go out and take a look
when a living
fleshy foot with all its multiple bones
makes a track in a suitable medium in
doing so it pushes the medium out
sequentially smoothly flowing out and
what you get it lines cracks in the
inside of the tracks called compression
lines
vertical little lines along here
very easy to see
next slide if you take a
phony foot of any kind
wood plaster plastic it doesn't matter
it is not going to articulate the way a
real living fleshy foot does so when it
goes down you have to press it or stamp
it and when you do that the medium
pushes out in a completely different way
you get these these impact ridges on the
sides and the lines crack on the outside
instead of the inside
now we can give this little lesson to a
group of first graders of six year old
kids give them magnifying glasses with
as many tracks as you want out here
phony and real and they won't miss one
that's really how easy it is
and yet every track that shows the
compression lines that they
that the real ones produce
in that case in that case only can't be
true got to be faked some kind of way
the fakers have figured out how to do it
how to produce articulating feet that if
instead of making fake bigfoot tracks
all over the world
all they have to do is apply that
technology to prosthesis and people with
with missing limbs
could walk a heck of a lot better
and they'd be millionaires to boot
and remember all this faking has been
going on for like 50 years
next level
here's how human foot works you have the
heel coming down because our ankle sits
to the rear of our foot so we have a
heel strike we come down hard on the
heel the momentum swings around the
outside of our arch it cuts over here
into the ball of our foot it comes out
our toe our big toe axes and thrusting
mechanism our four other toes act as
balancers and they pull up and leave an
undisturbed line of medium underneath
here while this flattens out next slide
and what we see is a drawing of exactly
that we see the heel strike we see the
momentum swinging around the arch we see
it cut over under the ball we see it
thrust out through the big toe we see
the four toes here acting as as
balancers and leaving an undisturbed
track of medium
in there that's how we walk
next slide this is how hominoids walk
all of them this is a bigfoot track 16
inches long seven inches wide very
typical track it was just taking a
really nice soft dirt road so you got a
real nice clear print you see something
very different
you see an ankle set up here toward the
middle of the foot you see an extended
heel you see a widened heel you see a
shortened forefoot you see a very wide
forefoot you see all five toes acting as
balancers you see the medium through
here so the thrusting mechanism is the
whole four foot here
and most importantly instead of that
swinging around the arch and having an
imbalanced kind of walk this thing has a
no heel strike the foot comes down
together and the line of momentum is
straight up the chute you can see that
right here
a totally different foot
a totally different foot walking a
totally different way from us and guess
what tracks of leia told me 3.2 million
years ago that's how they look that's
how they walk
and furthermore they walk better than we
did
because that foot instead of like us
coming down heel strike toe out heel
strike toe out that foot's coming down
smoothly smoothly
this thing is walking better than us
it's keeping its knees
unlocked
bent
so it's using its muscles it's muscles
in its thighs muscles in its behind
the way to do it the right way to do it
its joints don't wear out like allergy
if you look at us walking in slow motion
we're actually doing it wrong we're
doing it inefficiently
we're locking our knees we're throwing
ourselves through our hips
and over time our joints wear out as we
get old all you have to do is go to
nursing home you can see it it shouldn't
happen if you were walking correctly
something is wrong these guys do it
right we do it wrong
here's another one and it's a different
foot and what what this one shows is
that there are different feet among the
hormones
fundamentally the same but check the
difference in the toes these toes are
all the same size it's called the peas
and pod type
but again still all five of them acting
as balancers four foot ankle underneath
extended yield
the same the same different design but
with different toes we all have the same
fundamental foot but they have different
ones very unusual
next slide
dermal ridges in the best humanoid
tracks dermal ridges show up very
clearly what are dermal ridges they're
the fingerprints your fingerprints of
your feet
you know how when a baby's born if the
hands are too small to do the
fingerprints they just do the whole foot
boom print the foot
fingerprints on your feet thermal ridges
what do they say what does the darwinist
say when they
see a hanoi track with dermal ridges
whoever faked it took the time to sit
down and carve them in
when in fact they're so so fine and so
complicated and each one is unique
remember each one is unique
just like fingerprints
lasers couldn't do it
and yet somehow those fakers have taken
trouble to sit down and make a foot that
fully articulates so that it leaves
compression lines and it leaves dermal
ridges those fakers know their business
see how silly it is
it's absolutely absurd next slide
this is a stride comparison with a six
foot man you see the track here and a
track here
see how it is if somebody was in need
faking them and wearing fake tracks
because they they make such
they go into the mediums in such depth
that we can
judge how much they weigh we know
they're weighing 500 pounds 600 pounds
700 pounds 800 pounds depends but you
can tell for the medium technology can
do this it's amazing what they can do
that means that the person who's making
these tracks has to be in the range of
seven eight feet tall themselves and
they have to be very heavy people to
begin with and then they have to put
three or four hundred pounds on a
barbell
and carry that
[Music]
you know
making the tracks
the problem is if it's a human foot it
it has a it's going to have a deep
heel prep it's going to have the
standard
heel impact that we have and those who
are just not visible in the hominoid
tracks
it's clear that these are living
creatures making these tracks that don't
walk the way we do it don't walk
anywhere close to us just forget about
the size differential the walk is not
the same next level
but
here is the differential and i mean the
difference in the way that your foot's
put together
this has been studied by broken prince
he was an anatomist human animus put an
anatomist and he said my estimate is
that 31 of the total foot length is
behind the ankle joint compared with
only 23 percent of the humans so you see
you're looking at a fundamental redesign
why because it's so much bigger denser
thicker heavier body
all the homonyms whether they're small
or whether they're big and by the way
there are different sizes of them there
are pygmy size there are human size and
there are the giant size bigfoot
sasquatch those are the giant size you
always i'm sure you've heard you have
tall ones and you have more human we
have the same thing there everything
seems to get lumped around the big ones
because the big ones are so awesome but
there are many that are seen that are
human size there are different types
like the miocene apes just like my sea
names they are these are my c names
living today among us it's their planet
they are the indigenous upright walking
primates of planet earth
okay so we see the redesign the next
level
we also i want you to keep in mind the
difference of the motion
the forward motion the way the momentum
carries much better here than here
next slide this is a look at the
difference in the shadow of the area
that they put down and he says thus last
line thus the sasquatch foot had given
us in lessons does the suspect squatch
foot at a given statute has just to
trace over twice the surface area of a
human foot
at a given size twice the surface area
why because it's supporting whatever
that given size is supporting much
bigger body so you need a much broader
platform and a much thicker sole
to be able to walk barefoot for the
entire life supporting that so it's as
you saw in the other drawing it's
thicker on the bottom around the sole
okay next slide
now here's a comparison of a standard
ten and a half's
foot about my size and a standard eight
foot fifteen ten by five and fifteen by
six and a half but again keep the
bigfoot
look the hominoid look in mind
it's very different than the human next
life now we see another pair of them
and these it looks like this because
instead of being in dirt this was taken
from a from clay from hardened clutch
but otherwise in every other respect
these are hominoid tracks are they not
well they look exactly the same widened
heel ankle up to the way they were those
are those are hominoid tracks are they
not don't you agree
well they aren't as it turns out they
are not contrasted they are in fact
without doubt neanderthal traps
the anderthal tracks taken from the cave
toriyama italy 30 000 years ago no doubt
about it neanderthal artifacts in the
cave these are neanderthal tracks
looking exactly
like hominoid prince of this day
which would lead one to suspect that
perhaps neanderthals might be
homonoids rather than for humans next
level
in fact we have the feet of the
intervals we don't have the feet of any
other pre-humans it turns out when wild
creatures eat you the first thing they
go for is your feet is like you know the
cherry on sunday or something you know
but for whatever reason
we have very few females out of the
fossil record
but we have whole feet of neanderthals
because a few of them got buried
a few got here and so what we have is a
comparison here on the info foot human
foot human foot the end of the foot and
look at the difference
you have the huge extension of the heel
here relative to this you have the ankle
moving forward and widening compared to
this you have a flattening of the arch
compared to this and most importantly
look at the kind of sway that you have
here in our foot you can just see the
imbalance caused by our momentum working
around our arch as opposed to this big
flat
solid thing with the heel the big wide
ankle by comparative comparison shifted
forward the widening of the forefoot the
forefoot being the thrusting mechanism
the big toe here being the dominant one
the four
as opposed to these big all five of them
working as balancers
this is a very different it's the same
bones it's amazing it's the same bones
completely redesigned for a different
function and understand that this foot
is wrapping around here like it's a big
wide
foot relative to this one within here
everything that you see in a common
motor foot
is sitting right here in the neanderthal
foot
next slide
same
with the comparing with the drawing see
the
difference
very clear
just what the guy drew
is what you get and what you see
pre-human feet are hominoid feet
there's no doubt about it
all of the pre-humans that's all the
australopithecines that's all the early
homos up through neanderthal
to pro-magnum
those are nominees not three humans
just miocene apes living their lives and
leaving their traces in the fossil
record humans don't appear in the fossil
record until 120 000 years ago suddenly
overnight like everything else
so what they what they do now try to get
you to believe part of the brainwashing
is that neanderthals which initially
were considered roots pretty much like
what they are they're now just ugly
humans wearing firms
why because neanderthals clearly lived
during the ice ages in where the ice
ages were at their works
so somehow they were living in sub-zero
temperatures and so they wrap them up in
fur you take any of these guys and you
put them one night above the arctic
circle just above the arc circle
which is not as bad as it was during the
ice ages and those those folks are dead
one night
yeah
first not gonna make i'm going to get a
human through that you have to have a
different physiology to survive that
kind of climate
and the neanderthals clearly did because
they did it for a couple hundred
thousand years
they were covered in fur
have different physiology than we do
so if you want to see the true face of
neanderthal
next slide it's going to look an awful
lot more like this
which is grill than anything like what
you just saw like what you were told to
believe what you were taught to believe
nothing human on the horizon until you
get to pro magnum everything prior to
that looking like this covered with hair
um
next slide
now if everything i'm telling you is
true
how how where we come from
if the earth belongs to the upright
indigenous
primates from
well i choose to believe the best
evidence that i have
is from the work of a man named
zechariah sitchin which i'm not going to
go into in great detail here just to
tell you that summer
the original culture that we
have that we accept that scientists and
scholars accept as the first one around
five thousand years ago consumer which
is modern-day iraq tigers referred to
these modern day wreck where the war's
going on
that culture appeared out of nowhere
they came from the stone age out of the
zagros mountains supposedly down into
the valley there and produced this
fantastic culture that gave us over a
hundred of the firsts that we attribute
to the society now how did they do that
how they produce a culture that was as
good as in many ways better than the
later egyptians greeks and romans
come right out of the stone agent boom
just explode this wonderful culture how
do they do that
well
we don't talk about it
they just leave that one off the table
because it's just too impossible to
explain and all you really talk about
the sumerians if you went to school you
were taught anything about experience at
all you were talking thank you you did
it right
of the hundred and some things they
introduced next slide they introduced
writing uniform
and why because we have over 100 it
would be that would be denied if we
didn't have the hundred thousand plus
tablets many of which got stolen by the
way when the americans invaded you might
remember the both tablets and cylinder
sales were
confiscated but disappeared
but nonetheless only it's unfortunate
because only about 20 of them have been
translated at that point
but the 20 were translated many about 5
000 of them told things about their
history most of them were about business
and business deals and
who knew how many sheep or whatever but
about five thousand of them told stories
that the sumerians believed about
themselves about their history
that's all considered mythology
our scientists consider it total
mythology because it just can't be true
the things they were saying
they were saying things like this that
multiple gods came down from the heavens
lived on the earth needed a slave and a
serpent created that slave of a servant
in a a house of fashion basically a
genetic engineering map and not only did
they create humans to be their slaves
and servants they created domesticated
plants and domesticated animals
to give the gods their needs
now whether you believe that or not
doesn't matter i think the evidence is
there that somebody was here whether it
was the annunaki as the sumerians called
him or somebody else somebody a
superculture was here in the dim past
and they left their fingerprints all
over the place we just refused to
acknowledge that their fingerprints are
here
one of the things that these people left
us
with a legacy of as an explanation for
how the earth came to be like this
the earth itself
all
liquid bodies in a vacuum formed
themselves into a tight spherical ball
you've all seen milk get loose in the
space shuttle and all that all forms
into a ball this is what liquids do in
the vacuum
all other natural bodies that we know of
except for the meteorites and comics
which are started out as pieces of this
supposedly the planets exploding and
things like that to create them
but anything that formed as a viscous
mass which clearly the earth did
forms in a complete smooth ball
what happened to the earth the sumerians
have an explanation our guys are still
trying to figure it out
that's in my book it's in sichuan's book
if you want to find out more about it
the point is there are some answers next
slide
another
basic proof of the existence of these
multiple super people super gods or
whatever you want to call them are
megalithic structures around the world
megalithic structures that sexual mind
like these if i was standing here i wish
i was in this picture i'd be about right
my head would be about right here that's
how big they are
high in the mountains of above cusco
impossible for humans to put this
together and yet we're told that they
did
and the same holds true for tiwanako te
ote wakan
paul beck in lebanon
stonehenge around the world any
megalithic structure we want to talk
about
humans somehow did it because nothing
else is allowed no outside intervention
is permitted so they have to explain it
in
rational
natural terms and so they just say
somehow they did it but we can't do it
today we cannot begin to reproduce this
kind of precision
in our work today
playing one stone every 8.5 minutes now
right there that story is over with
right there that story is a fraud that
story is absurd
and yet if they the egyptologists will
not hear
that it couldn't be done
more than that they weren't just
slamming these things into place like
these look like they were but still they
were being laid pretty carefully because
they're all flat and they all worked out
such that they went up to the top
perfectly but here's what's the amazing
thing they were covered with polished
limestone each of which was placed to
perfection
and it couldn't be any other way because
if you have mistakes down at the bottom
the size of the postage stamp go the
size of the car at the top
every single stone in these three
pyramids had to be perfect and they were
next slide thank goodness after that
while they were stripping off the
covering limestone they left a few down
at the bottom so you can see how
marvelous the workmanship was and here
it is this is a connecting line between
two of the stones it's the width of a
human hair next slide
see it coin
connecting line right here
we cannot in our wildest dreams
put stones together with this kind of
accuracy
not in our wildest dreams can we do this
on a massive scale this is a rolex watch
folks built to the size of the mountain
thrills
impossible
today and yet somehow these primitive
people did it using ropes
stone tools and wood rollers to do the
stones would they did not have and
they'll grow in the nile valley they
would have had to import them from
lebanon which would back then
3 500 years ago would have been you know
tough effort
okay next slide
the sphinx
you've all seen it too i want to look at
this wall over here for a minute next
slide
i hope you've all seen the mystery of
the sphinx and seen the idea that this
is caused by running water these these
are running water marks after the sphinx
was carved out the walls were smoothed
over and gouged by running water well
what does that mean
that the sphinx was carved at a minimum
of eight to ten thousand years ago
before the desert desiccated in that
area
with me
it's more likely that it's more like 15
to 16
000 years ago to have it sitting there
and give enough rain time
so that all this could happen
well fifteen to sixteen thousand years
ago no egyptologists don't come up with
that but they've had it pretty much
crammed down their throats so some of
them are beginning to say well yeah i
mean that happened but then the pyramids
were still
made within that 100 year period but
they're trying their very best to get
the sphinx back on the page and at the
same time as the pyramids
next time but however or whenever it was
done one thing is for sure when they cut
these stones out of here they move some
of them they move them up here to build
two temples the sphinx temple and the
valley temple
next slide
and as you see this looking the other
way now sinks here
swings temple valley temple you see the
size of some of the stones and they too
were by the way covered with those
perfect polished limestones that got
stripped off to build buildings in cairo
which i think it's one of the great sins
of the past
people doing that ruining the beauty and
perfection of these things nonetheless
they didn't use what we're left with
next slide
we have
this is me back when i was younger and
had hair and was cool and it was a
snappy dresser
no it's not true but i've never had hair
and i was never cool and i'm still not
sniping
but anyhow this was another guy but you
see 170 tons of stone
just one of them
in the pyramids 1500 not that unusual on
the inside all of it perfect again
perfect
but here's what it takes to move
170 tons next night today
this big bumper right here
and to move it from where you saw that
drawing out it would be three or four
days to set up each time to move it just
a little bit
then you have to put it down you have to
roll this thing forward and rebook and
do you know
eight and a half minutes
eight and a half minutes all you got
to move 170 tons of snow and there are
stones all over the world
way bigger than 170 tons
one of my favorites is the ancient 1
thousand one thousand one hundred and
seventy ton obelisk the unfinished
novelist at asimon
pink granite one of the hardest stones
in the world
cut out obviously with
some other stone that was harder than it
but we don't know where they would have
gotten that but nonetheless they carved
it out of this hole in a hole
the guy had taken the pictures up holder
on blowing and there's the edge of the
wreckage about 15 feet deep in a hole
and yet as you can see it's been worked
and polished and it's pretty much done
and they're just finishing off the spire
[Music]
and something is digging out
pink granite
and chunks the size of the seats that
you're sitting on
some big machine just gouging
and as that machine presses down
it cracks it finds a fault and it cracks
it and those building it with that
machine just say oops we're broken they
unhook it off the nose and they go away
and they just leave it for us tomorrow
correct now understand they fixed a
bunch of them i mean it did a bunch of
them perfectly you've got optimus huge
gigantic analysts around egypt and then
they got stolen and taken to other parts
of the world
but here's this one which is you know
average size
problem
problem how do you get it i'm opposed
better yet even bigger problem
how do you cut it loose
from its base
with the finest drill we have today
covered in diamonds
you could not make it go through there
the weight would press it down and
compress it and not let it go
how did these primitive people cut this
stone which is very much loose
according to the darkness according to i
mean according to scientists rather
according to the deuteronologists
some poor schmuck got down there with
his little stone accents and went to
hammering
and somehow worked his way all the way
through and underneath
and worked their way
they would have been crushed and there's
just no physical way to do this
and but if you could if you could
somehow do it next slide this is what it
would take to move only a thousand times
it doesn't get much bigger than this
and yeah you have stones in ballpark
ball back lebanon that are two thousand
times two thousand times
and yet there they stood up in a wall
high up in a wall
and a
template primitive people did that
it's just like the hominoids how why
because they had to
no intervention is allowed are you
laughing are you coughing
okay
good job okay you need some water
[Music]
all right
if it's if it's true next slide
then
they weren't if they were here we have
other evidence to show that they were we
the as i said earlier domestication of
plants and animals
well the story we're told now is that
all domesticated plants and animals and
pretty much seems to be this way all
domesticated plants and animals come in
a period from ten thousand years ago to
five thousand years ago
ten thousand years ago to five thousand
years ago we've had none since really
that amount to anything
the big big big ones the sheep the
cattle the goats the corn
the maize i mean the corn wheat
barley all that came
within that period stuff we really use
now how is that explained
well in terms of the plants it's
explained this way somehow these stone
age people
looked out of the cave one day
and one of them got the bright idea that
hey if we pull up some of these grasses
and grains and cereals that we're
looking at which are out there today
in california
with their little bitty tiny tiny seeds
that are the size of pepper flakes
or salt crystals
and hard as salt crystals
and biochemically only suited to feeding
grazing animals
this this stone age wizard got the idea
hey if we pick through those little
pepper flakes and soft bristles and pick
out the biggest ones
and they're marginally bigger than the
others and we plant them figuring out
how to plant and grow and plant them and
make them produce
and then we pick out the biggest ones of
that
then we're just
over
a couple of thousand years or more
over a couple thousand years or more
those little bitty pepper flake salt
crystal seeds will grow into something
we can actually use you know seed easily
and use in our hands they will soften
the seeds will soften and turn from
rocks into something that we can
actually cook and eat and and the
biochemistry of them will change so that
they're not suitable for
animals anymore but they're suitable for
us that our bodies can use
it won't that be cool
and that cave guy supposedly talked all
his buddies into doing this
and doing it for generation after
generation after generation after
generation planning and sewing and
picking out the best and somehow doing
this something we can't do today
i've not been able to reproduce today
but somehow these this genius did it and
not only that multiple geniuses did it
because this was done all over the world
in different places at different times
within that 5 000 year window
and you get things that go from being
these wild hearty grasses like teosinte
into
from this to corn next slide and you go
from this hearty little perennial that
can just grow anywhere anytime doesn't
need any um to this which is
riddled with genetic defects i mean
riddled to the point where it can't live
by itself without human intervention
corn as we know it that won't grow
doesn't matter we need it we use it
we're happy to have it
but it is clearly not a natural
not a natural species or anything
this is natural this is very natural
same thing with wheat and ember early
weed in them
same process where you go from these
little tiny
grass-like
things into a much bigger seed a much
plumper seed softer seed and its
biochemistry changes from feeding
animals to feeding us
these these
stone age geniuses somehow pull that off
and more than that next slide what every
what they had to do with every one of
the domesticated plants that they were
going to turn into greens and cereals
and grass and little maturing food they
had
to solve the problem of ranches and
blenders now blooms are
the husks that wrap around the seeds and
raches are this area right here where
they break off
now in the wild rages and blooms have a
cycle where they're pretty tough when
the seed is broken
to hold it on to the stem
during wind storms and rain and all that
but as it matures and when it matures
they turn incredibly brittle
so that the seeds can propagate you know
you pick up a dandelion
right that's that's the righteous
letting go
inches and blooms the seed popping out
of the moon the rage is letting it go
that's how wild things are well if the
rages in bloom stay the same it didn't
matter how big it got you couldn't
harvest it
because when it ripen what would happen
if you hit it with a scythe every one of
the seeds would drop on the ground
couldn't collect it
somehow the rages had i mean the glooms
had to be
made strengthened
past the period of ripening so that they
would
they would hold together
during harvesting
somehow the righteous had to do the same
thing but the righteous had to be set so
that when you harvested it and got it
back to where you wanted to
to thrash it and get the seeds out
in the thrashing process the racists had
nowhere to let go
it had to be perfect it had to be
precise for every single cereal grass
and grain that was domesticated
so in addition to the biochemistry and
the change in the cytosol you had to
solve these two problems for each one
each one was different each one had to
be perfect as perfect as the stones of
the pyramid and they work
and they work
that's what's impossible to accept that
humans could have done this
impossible
next slide
same thing with the animals except it's
different instead of making
little bitty seeds bigger
and softer and all that they took big
tough bad news animals and shrunk them
down made them gentle
gentle their spirits change them
psychologically change their brains
wild goats domesticate again wild works
cattle domesticated cattle shrunk them
down and made them docile and made them
domestic so
they could serve me
give the gods their ease as it says in
the sumerian texts no doubt about it
next slide
same thing with pigs from
wild boar to domesticated pig imagine
bringing this sucker the first one and
what they say is of course the farmers
that were growing those domestic
domesticating the plants were at the
same time domesticating the animals
another one had the right idea let's
take these wild bad news animals bring
them in live with them
and turn them into things we can use way
downstream from our lives
not going to happen
absolutely absurd imagine the first guy
bringing anything behind
these big barks cattle bad news wolves
tournament of dogs just didn't gonna
happen next slide
the cheetah the king of domestication
okay
this if nothing else proves it this does
that genetic engineering took place in
the distant past
the cheetah is a hunting cat a cat
designed to hunt at a very high level of
efficiency not that cats aren't good
hunters
but nothing is like the cheetah on the
savannah
it's the fastest animal in the world by
far
70 miles an hour
good resource of 140 top speed
okay
not only that it is designed to hunt
it's got a different aerodynamically
designed body more like a greyhound than
a true cat you know how heavy lions and
tigers and all the hunting cats are this
one is slimmed down like a dog like like
a greyhound
more than that it's got a different
attitude it doesn't have a cat attitude
it's one of the very first domesticated
animals we have records of it going back
almost to 10 000 years ago in asia india
and africa it was very widespread very
tame the pharaohs used to hunt with
these guys
okay they were hunting in animals
designed for that purpose
there has never been a report of a
cheetah attacking and killing a human
they have dog mentality
in cat bodies they have dog-like bodies
in the sense that the bones are much
lighter the lungs have been modified the
breathing rate has been modified like no
other dog nor the cat
but more importantly than that yet this
they have dog
feet
with cat feet soft pads and retractable
claws you can't make a turn at 70 miles
an hour
but with a dog foot a thick heavy pad
and a permanently extended claws
you're running on track shoes you can
turn at 70 miles an hour
the cheetah among all cats has dog feet
more than that you see this brown fur
that's short-haired dog fur
steals black spots
cat fur
cheetahs sit like a dog
they get dog-only diseases they get
caffeine diseases
now as if that isn't bizarre enough
about cheetahs guess what they all have
the same dna
same chromosome package they're clones
you can take a cheetah from africa
and you can take a cheetah from asia
you could strip their skin off of them
and swap the skin and it would heal
you could trade hearts
no rejection
they're all the same
now
when faced with this evidence what do
you think
the darwinists and the geneticists and
the scientists said what do you think
they came up with
there had to be an answer and it got to
be a natural answer so they came up with
one
these cheetahs got squeezed through a
bottleneck a genetic bottleneck and
here's the bottleneck somehow
somehow before 10 000 years ago
every cheetah on earth
in asia india africa all of them died
except for one breeding pair or just a
couple
and then they repopulated from those
that's why they all have the same teams
because it came from scene two original
ones
isn't that plausible doesn't that make
sense
no of course not
it's just an excuse
and yet it's taught as preachers believe
like everything else they put out it's
garbage
our next slide
there you're looking at
somebody else who got put through a
bottleneck
we've got put through a bottom same
thing everybody in this room has been
put through the same kind of bottleneck
that the cheetahs went through why
because in 1987 as you see here
newsweek magazine it was found by a
study of mitochondrial dna of women
around the world
women have carried women
produced and carried mitochondrial dna
forward we all have it we must have it
but we don't pass it on he passes on
through the egg so they did a study of
women around the world and they found
that
we did not in fact descend from any
creatures four million years ago which
is what they went into the experiment
looking to prove was it closer to five
or eight or you know when did we really
separate from our last common ancestor
with the apes as it was believed at the
time
they found that
the oldest of us
the oldest dogs were only about 200 000
years old
200 000 not millions of years old we
were like brand new
a brand new species which matches up
pretty well with the promagnons at 120
000 years ago if our mitochondrial dna
says we're only between 150 and 200 000
years old that matches up pretty well
when our apostles begin to appear
and furthermore the oldest of us come
from southern africa
making avenue black
if there was
you can imagine how this went over in
the south of the united states
but nonetheless that's the way it would
be the oldest of us come from southern
africa
and we only start up as a species around
50 to 200 000 years ago so what does
that mean just like the cheetahs
all of us got wiped out
and you know that we have
animal rectus all over there you know in
india and china
in asia
and in africa
all of those got wiped out
the ones that were going to become us
leaving only a couple or a couple of
pairs
to produce us within the last two
hundred thousand years same bottleneck
same kind of story that worked with the
cheetah
they it to work with us and it has
worked people just you know
no question
well it's not true we we are supposedly
descended from primates and yet
all of this about us is not the same
we don't have the same bones same
muscles same skin same adipose tissue
same body hair patterns head hair and
nails and different
skulls and brains are different
locomotion is different speech is
different sex is different genetic
disorders we have over 4 000 genetic
disorders folks
how would we get over 4 000 genetic
disorders work into the whole gene pool
in only a couple hundred thousand years
when you consider that at least two
dozen of them actually two dozen by 24
or 25
kill you
dead
before you reach the age of maturity
before you can pass that on before you
can reproduce
how does a disorder like that
get into the whole gene pool how can you
find it among eskimos and watuses
there's only one way
they were put there and put there just
like the corn's genetic disorder just
like other domesticated plants and
domesticated animals and genetic
disorders were put there because they
were the results of cutting and splicing
in a lab
as they were being put together mistakes
get made
it's the only way you get
that many genetic disorders and genetic
disorders that kill you before you can
reproduce
but most importantly our chromosome
package has been reduced from 48
chromosomes with all other primates
to 46.
how do we go
for to be so much better supposedly
while losing two full chromosomes that's
a lot of dna
how could that happen
next slide well we look and we see a
comparison of human chimp drill and
orangutan and you see that as you've
heard there's a lot of similarities a
lot of similarities between us and so
they use this as an argument to say well
you know it's clear that we evolve from
them
because our gene package is so close
it's only that funny little change
from 48 chromosomes to 46.
a little bump in the road but otherwise
it's clear to see that we evolve from
that but let's look at that change next
slide
here we see it in
just so happens the second and third
chromosome with the champ and the
gorilla and orangutan they're separate
but with us
look
they've been fused
fused two genes fused
this doesn't happen in nature
that's only done in the lab
you don't see that anywhere else but in
the lab just like you don't see the
cheetahs chromosomal similarity anywhere
but in a lab a genetics lab lab rats
clones
we
just like darwin said
are domesticated animals created to
serve a purpose
five the super race whoever you want to
call them
who were here and who built the pyramids
and created the domesticated plants and
created the domesticated animals
[Music]
[Applause]
this is the storchild skull antrina's
question the star child is composed
undeniably mammalian bone with the major
human components evident from the bone
sphenoid temporal parietal and occipital
back here
however each part is profoundly
redesigned with the bone itself
astonishingly reconstituted into
something uniformly less than one half
as thick as normal weighing one half as
much as it should it feels kind of a dry
gourd in your hand right and by the way
the model is the same weight so you'll
see right the real human skull you see
how thin that bone is there
it's like that all over
weighs half as much half as thin it's
incredible uniform
taking 30 points of reference on it 0.1
30 points of reference on it and
comparing them to the average of those
same 30 points on 100 normal skulls the
result calls 10 standard deviations from
the statistical norm off the chart the
next slide suggests but do not yet prove
that the star child is from a me other
than a normal human
this is significant folks
next slide
what we see in comparison of the two
skulls that were found is that they're
completely different now let me give you
the background on how they were found
about 1930
a woman a young girl about 15 years old
of mexican heritage was taken by her
parents to visit the old family
homestead in a small village about a
hundred miles southwest of chihuahua we
do not know exactly where that building
was so we can't just run back there we
think we can find it we don't know it at
this point there it was but at that
village she was told not to go into the
caves and the mine tunnels in the air
that number one it was dangerous number
two it was just forbidden there was
taboo don't do it
tell most any teenager anywhere what not
to do and you know
find a way to try to do it
so she snuck off
and went explore
and she went into a mine tunnel and she
found a human skeleton lying on its back
and she got close to it she noticed that
there was what she called a misshapen
hand
coming up out of the dirt beside that
skeleton
lying on the ground
and that hand was wrapped around the
upper arm bottom
of the human skeleton
and she noticed as she got even closer
that the dirt was all crumbly and
beside the skeleton and over that hand
that was coming up so using your own
hands and this bears out because in a
mine tunnel there would have been no
rain there would have been no compacting
in the soil and it would have been as
loose as the day
that the grade was dug which we know
from carbon 14 testing of both these
skulls was 900 years ago plus or minus
four years those skulls tested out that
way so we're pretty likely that this
story is true so with her own hand she
dug out and she found the full skeleton
there
and she said that it was smaller than
the human and the human is about a five
foot tall female so the skull the
skeleton would have been about four feet
tall
and that it had a misshapen body
that's all she said because she didn't
know that some years after her death it
would be important
but she from the age of 15 she smuggled
the two skulls not the full skeletons
just the two skulls
back to the states
shellacked both skulls on the outside
you see that shine is from shellac
put them in a cardboard box and just
kept it
until it came
time for her to die in the early 90s and
she willed them to another couple
friends of hers
they put that box in their garage and
kept it for five years but it didn't
like
two skulls and a cardboard box in their
garage so he said the wife said find
somebody else
so they had a younger couple that they
knew that were ufo
knowledgeable they were into ufo stuff
and they showed them this call
but we showed them hostile they said
would you like
so they did
and they contacted me because of my work
in human origins that you saw i was
already known for my work with skulls
and
bones already
so they contacted me and they said could
you
take this and get it tested by
scientists to find out what it is
and i said yeah sure this is so cool
this is so unique this is so different i
mean an idiot can see
that surely scientists will jump all
over this and we'll have this tested out
probably within six months or so which
could have been the case if scientists
were really scientists interested in
finding out truth or not
they're interested in keeping their
peers off their necks
and covering their bodies
and so we couldn't get the help that we
wanted and anticipated and so now here
we are instead of six months down the
road with answers we will
be six years
six years
geez it is sorry it's a visual
performance by everybody involved
including myself not much of a
fundraiser
i just don't know how to do that glad
any kind of thing that fundraisers do i
just put it out there and tell people
here's what we need here's what we why
we needed
i expect them to cough it up and they
never do
because it turns out that in the states
at least
the ufo community
is very social
they like the game they don't want the
game over with
they all say they do they all say they
want answers
and you present them with something that
might provide answers might really
absolutely convince everybody that this
is a real phenomena
and they skitter the other way they
don't want the party to be over
and that's a fact that's what i found to
be the case
you can argue with that if you want to
but that's my experience
it's fun it's a social thing and they
don't want it and so they don't really
support it very well
so that's why i'm talking to you almost
six years later
and you're still struggling but for one
woman it would be over with and this
would be back in the you know unboxing
but for one moment
okay now when you look at the two things
that's that's the back story that's how
it all came to be when you look at two
things the first thing you notice
obviously is the eyesight
if i stick my finger in a human eyesight
yours line anyways don't go about that
deep about two inches
our eye sockets are deeper and bigger
than you suspect
put them in the star child as you'll see
for yourself it'll go maybe up to there
not quite an inch at a steepest point as
you notice the optic framings where the
occupant opening blood vessels and all
are come into or back at the center of
the cone in the back they've been pushed
down at the bottom here if this thing
has eyes like we do they're sitting
about right here
rather than
back in deep like out but if it has eyes
like we do because it's so shallow
they're sticking off the face like frog
eyes
in a very dangerous position for a kid
growing up just doing the normal things
that kids do
and get popped right out of their head
so maybe it doesn't even have eyes quite
like we have
but one thing significant about it is
when you take this and anybody any any
specialist that will say anything about
it they'll say well it looks like
i mean look like it's got to be as
bigfoot can't be real and the cheetah
and all that it's got to be
got to be some kind of genetic
or
birth defect genetic defect and birth
defect because that's the only two
possibilities now let's look at it for a
minute
genetic defect
no genetic defect produces anything
approaching this we've looked at every
manual every book every
thing we can find
and not just me we have a craniofacial
plastic surgeon named ted robinson in
canada who spent six weeks trying to
find anything similar to this can't find
a genetic defect that produces anything
like these effects
so eliminate genetic defects you take it
to any specialist and they'll all say
the same thing that that birth defects
one time only
sperm egg misconnects
are capable of producing anything
absolutely anything is possible
it's just like this huge big garbage bin
where they can dump anything they don't
want to deal with
birth defect
one time only sperm egg misconduct but
in fact there are rules to that game
sperm egg misconnects everything is ugly
everything is asymmetrical
nothing is all encompassing nothing is
all unconstant now you can have
something born completely without a head
you can have something born completely
without a brain you've heard of those
i'm sure
but
normally they don't live they're dead
out of a shooting
this thing lived
and lived apparently for quite some time
as it was
well 900 years ago plus or minus 40
years you were born in a primitive
isolated village in mexico and you had
one thing wrong with you you had a cleft
palate you might make
you had two things wrong with your face
and your head
you were now skating on thin ice they
might choose not to keep you and start
over with some new ones
you were born with three things wrong
with your head you were done for life
you were a faulty copy and you were
gotten rid of it that's another reason
why we don't have 4000 genetic disorders
in a natural way because
nature weeds out the defects
and all animals parents get rid of the
faulty cockpits and humans did that too
only up until recent times infanticide
was not a problem in the old days if you
had a faulty copy you got rid of it and
so
that being the case
one would have to argue that
something with everything wrong with its
head
everything
there's nothing right about this
nothing the same except the parts
would not have been kept would not be
allowed to live
could have lived
and yet
not only that it is symmetrical
it's not asymmetrical it's not ugly it's
not lopsided
like any other birth defect that you see
the skeleton of if you see it
it's wonderfully well put together she's
put together different its genes told it
to grow in a completely different way
furthermore it's so subtle
it's so subtle and it's symmetry that
you can look at these eye sockets and
you can look at the copy and see you can
look at it and you cannot see anything
other than my nice smooth scoop in both
of them your eyes
see nothing but smoothness but yet you
put your fingers your fingers are much
more sensitive
you put your fingers in here you can
feel a dent right here
right here
drag your finger at this angle right
here
you'll feel a little rise right in here
right here and you'll sit back down into
another little dent right here
absolutely perfect on both sides
absolutely perfect and subtlety shifts
the train of the eyesight
no possibility that that is a defect
causing this
one
its genes told it to grow this way if
this genes told it to grow this way
those genes are not human
this is not the way humans look
this is not the thickness of human bone
this is not the weight of you
oh excuse me
behind in here people that know the
gossip
um before they also look at this
holes
for
yeah it's in here you can see it right
there
they're in there
the pictures aren't always revealing of
everything but the optic nerve holes are
in fact there and both of them and yeah
they're there
round little round holes you can see
them they're not as clear on the model
as they are in the real one let's say
are they bones that come out because
um
this is just broken off here okay the
lower part of the face is broken off
but
it was there at one time and we have a
piece of maxilla that we'll see later if
you just wait probably most of your
questions will be covered as we go
through but yeah oh i see what you're
talking about yeah okay here's a point
that needs to be made and the gentleman
is pointed out
in a normal human skull
the cheekbone wraps around here and as
you see it wraps in and forms part of
the orbit of the eye that's what he's
talking about you see how it folds in
and there's no line of demarcation and
this line here comes down through here
you see that the orbit it's a rounded
piece of bomb
here but not so it snaps off clean
a pretty major difference we don't know
how this happens
here because that could not happen there
but it's just one of many many
differences that you're going to see
good point and thank you for bringing
that okay next level
okay we see a side view again the same
parts of the bone
now this human skull was cradleboarding
you take these two experts and they'll
say oh it's a it's a cradle-boarded
hydrocephalic that's the first thing
that pops out
but most of their mouths
a hydrocephalic because the head the
cranium is swollen relative to that
swollen and misshapen hydrocephaly
meaning water on the brain longer
cradleboarded because of the flatness of
the rear of the head
and that's all they want to know i mean
you start beginning to give them
arguments about why you know it's not
hypocritical it's not credible they're
showing you the door they have made
their statement they have explained it
in their terms in natural terms
creditwood and i just felt it forget
about it i mean i had the late stephen j
gould himself the man the number one guy
do that to me incredible word i just
felt the most to google it's not for
this reason i don't care what it is it's
natural
take it away
standard response well it's not this
isn't crazy what it's called
right here
now cradleboarding is very common
in primitive cultures
what it is is mother has a baby she's
got to go to work in three or four days
back to work they need her hands so
she's got to strap her baby on her back
if she is stooping and bending and
stooping and bending she can't have the
baby's head lolling around like that
because it will snap his neck
so she has to tie the baby's head to a
board to keep it on her back so she can
work and it's very again very common
what you get because a baby's bones are
so soft is the back of the head that
comes out as flat as the board you put
it on as flat as that table if you feel
the back of her head
it is as flat as a board
i mean no bumps at all
you feel the back of this head you can
feel it for yourself
and you feel the subtle convolutions of
the bum
was never credible
never created and it's not a
hydrocephaly because as you'll see in
among the visual pitch down the middle
up here and if it was pressure from
pushing from the inside the brain
pushing out
that crease would not be there
it's not credible it's not
hydrocentrified however when a skull is
crediborted
the cradle boarding always stops at the
knot at the rear of the head called the
external external occipital pro tumor so
the indian reach around everybody and
feel that knot in the back in the center
of your head right right here
okay everybody has that
it's a knot and your neck starts right
underneath
if you were cradle-boarded as an infant
it stops there it goes from the crown up
here to there it's about the size of the
palm of my hand the area that gets
flattened
but you can't go past the end because
you're tearing into the neck muscles if
you do that
this thing has no medium
as you'll see in a moment and his neck
doesn't start to go down here it's got a
very small neck this neck starts up here
and covers all this area here
excellent
let's see those lines just to show that
it's balanced we're not trying to fudge
it
oh excuse me can you go back real quick
sure
here's your hole
your
cheek bone
see his little nub right here cheekbone
is going to come up attached here where
it's turned
you can get two fingers up through here
in the real skull my two fingers fit
very easily up through here
a couple soda straws will fit through
here the chewing muscles that come up
and attach
chewing muscles they come up through
here
go up through here this whole area right
here you can see it clearer in another
place
chewing muscles cover this whole area
storage out you come up through here
and cut around your much much reduced to
children's it's a much smaller global
face
and and when i say reduced i don't mean
they're going to grow as it gets older
they
you're born with them
fitting up here this thing was one of
them fitting down here
born different
neck
all this
and that completely reconfigured like
everything else
rear of the head
box the sutures you know about sutures
right a baby's born with all this wide
open with ligaments in here little
patches of bone so that the head can
shake to fit through the birth canal
over the next two years or so these
sutures close up and the last one closes
up here at the top the soft the soft
spot where three will come together
all right looks like the occipital here
is not simple has been just stretched
out and flattened see the crease
down the middle here and the top
this area here which is now a dent
is where the indian should be
right here it's not and you see the neck
muscles attaching and going through here
big big
fossa where the magnets attach and go
through well you see they don't attach
till down here about an inch below where
they should so the neck is a much
much smaller much reducing neck
just like a much reduced face
and the crown again completely different
relative to which
these bones here called marian bones
indicate that it's more than
four and a half five years old it's up
in the teens maybe even twenties
not necessarily a child but there's a
lot of debate on how old it was when it
died because its teeth look very
childish
top of the head
showing a difference the staining by the
way
on the starch island you saw on its
cheek is from the fact that it was
buried in soil
and probably picked up some stains from
the very next slide
okay here we see that the underside now
this bone right here the basal part
basically
is missing here
this bone fuses in all of us by around
the age of 25 so this one was post 25
this female when she died
but the one died
and by the way we first thought
initially that it was its mother maybe
you know that her baby died she buried
it
because that's clearly a death and a
suicide
and she
laid down to die with her wrapped his
arm around her arm cut her throat to the
poison whatever she lay down there to
die with this
child that had died or this being died
whatever it was that's what we
originally thought
now we know because of genetic testing
she was not its mother
they're not genetically related they
were husband and wife they were a
caretaker a child and
lovers
we don't know what she had enough
commitment to it to bury and die and
kill herself take her own life to be
there
so anyway so she was in her 30s
her teeth are flattened down
like horse teeth
you can see the cusps all running away
but that's eating a very gritty diet of
corn
grit
so 30s is a good age probably for her
with this we're not as sure everything
here is much smaller you see the
condyles how much smaller relative to
these
you see the mandibular fossa
right here
as opposed to the size of that so you're
just looking at a much reduced
roll of face here but this indicates
a death agent death of less than 25 if
needed
this is an
x-ray
of the two and you see the human eye
sockets and the frontal sinuses of the
spront size is normal of human little
cauliflower and you see with the star
child completely missing no funds not
even vestigial not even nubs nothing
this thing didn't have
sinuses at all that's very immune
and notice if you will look at the
normal eye sockets look look at these
kind of this this flare thing to go in
here that weird
we don't know what it means but that's
how it came out of the x-ray also notice
if you will how the brain kind of looks
when this fills up solid and you have
here a kind of brain
okay here we have some real strong proof
against hydrocephaly from the outside
you see the veins
the brain presses up into the bone and
because the bone is soft and this is
from when your baby bone is soft the
veins make dents in your bone it kind of
wraps around the veins and you see the
tracks going all the way up here you see
the same thing you see the tracks going
up all the way so but then you see this
this bulge in the rival that you don't
have
it's the same area here so much more
correct this was the area by the way
that was a little extended in einstein
to make him a jeans
look a little bigger than her
so
it makes you wonder
anyway next up
the t
okay we have the little piece of maximum
upper right maxilla this is this piece
of bone right here from the middle of
your upper jaw around to the right okay
this is the size
forget how it looks here it's real small
and it's basically the size of a child
this is the nose openings and opening
for so it had it had a breathing
capacity like we have
those opening like we have
and these are the two teeth that were
there this tooth has been lost to dna
testing unsuccessfully enforced the
first time around we still have this one
if you look in these holes here you
could see other teeth
come waiting to come out
and you x-ray this and you see four
teeth up in here so it's pretty clear
that it has a child's dentition and
that's why we call it the star child
initiative
we were told well it's got you know
teeth down teeth up it's small it's
weird it's a child
so we call it the star child for a very
long time before they began to really
wonder
if the wormy and bone issue might
indicate that it was older than a child
you still don't know about the next
slide we take a close-up of the
remaining tooth what you see is a lot of
a lot of wear on the enamel
shearing across the enamel to that point
right there you see pitting with the pit
here in the mirror pits and you see this
crack here this is called phrasing this
is like an adult
two career pattern
seen in what seems to be about a four
and a half five year old child
hard to figure
again still won't have answers to the
next slide
now
when now it gets interesting so
we cut some bone to do some dna testing
karina was there when it was cut two
things happened
the geneticists who had dealt with it
cutting bone for quite some time and
knew a lot about it said
boy this with a dremel blades boy this
is tough to cut this is much tougher
than
it should be for such thin bones this
thin like bone you think it just cracked
through like an action it didn't it was
resistant to the dremel adrenal blade
being a circular blade and you know a
little thing like a kind of a flashlight
like that
okay so
and now with that it produced a profound
profound smell of burning tooth you know
when you get your teeth drilled that
smell everybody recognizes it's not in
them
it's collagen that is collagen i didn't
know that until fairly recent
that smell is burning collagen not
enamel
bone is made of two things hydroxy
calcium hydroxyapatite or apatite and
collagen
mammal is distinctive for tooth so that
is burning
collagen that you smell strong spinal
columns so we were surprised by those
two things but the hardness issue was
the one to god and they said you want to
have this tested now the dna proved
first time through
they took the bone like this piece like
this and they put it in the normal
dissolving
fluid which is called edta an edta is
just a dissolver that you take normal
bone and it will dissolve it away in
about a week
and then they go to work on taking away
everything except the dna and do the dna
testing
they said well it's so thin and so
different so like you know it's probably
going to be maybe three days maybe four
days and edta will dissolve
ten weeks later it looked the same
weeks later it looked the same and not
dissolved at all
so they said we're going to put a
detergent in it called tween 20 and
that's pretty strong and that should
take it
now you should take at least some of it
down so we can work with them they put
the 20 20 in it poop gone overnight gone
gone gone
completely dissolved overnight
that was a surprise too
but they used what the liquid was left
and they they tested it and now the
mother
her mitochondrial dna and her nuclear
dna came up really beautiful no problem
the assumption being that in 900 years
being in a mind tunnel not being rained
on not being dried out not being
bleached by the sun all that it should
be the dna should be well preserved and
it was in the human
star child only difference being it was
buried
its mitochondrial dna its mother part
that comes from his mother came up
beautiful no problem the nuclear dna
which is the from the inside of the
nucleus you know in the cell the
mitochondrial dna flows outside the cell
and it's like little chips of stone and
it's very durable the nuclear dna is the
chromosome package inside the nucleus
and it's fairly fragile
it didn't for whatever reason come up
they tried four times each time the
mitochondrial dna came up easy the
nuclear dna did not
couldn't figure it out they said well
there must have been some kind of weird
degradation going on
it's understandable buried might have
been very acidic soil it was buried in
got some staining so we kind of excused
it away we just said we're going to have
to wait a while until the primers get
more sophisticated to get the nuclear
dna but we believe nuclear dna is here
because the mitochondrial dna is so easy
to recover
okay
so they said in the meanwhile you should
test the bomb
for to see about the chemistry to see
why it's so hard to cut
because that's unusual
not worry too much about the smell the
smell is the secondary
finally this the lady who put up the
money for the dna testing
she had taken a partner named grant
singleton who's now partnering in the
deal
and
he now runs cognoscence and he arranged
to have
the bone tested with the scanning
electron microscope
at the royal holloway scientific
institute in london which is a castle
really big castle that's been converted
into scientific institute
so in the scanning electron microscope
this is what
we saw
this is a cortical bone layer outer it's
like a sandwich bone is like a sandwich
at this time the cord of the layer
outside and underneath and the inside
are the cancellous holes and in here is
where the marrow goes
the marrow moves
bone
has it doesn't have vessels and things
like that it has it has these holes and
and the marrow just kind of loses
through the cancellous valves
so when they looked at the scanning
electron microscope and took the
pictures and they saw this they said
holy smokes what is this
these things here
see these
these are not known
involved
never seen before don't know what they
are next slide we're going to look at a
couple of them up close but these are
just samples of others that you can that
we're in many of the cancellous holes
and stores home restraints mixed up
look at that one first we call it a lot
now this looks like a little thin piece
here that got wrapped up somehow in this
came out here and all this is wrapped
around it
we first saw this we thought well it
must be some kind of capillary of some
kind
but there are no capillaries involved
it's not the way bone is set up
what is it next slide
this doesn't look the same it's more
like threads or hairs
what is it
no idea
next slide
this was a piece of just another area of
the same piece of bone which by the way
is as big as my thumbnail or your
thumbnail i'm not a big piece
cut out a storage hole but up here
use your thumb
the blade was cutting as fast as it came
to the end of the cut and let up on it a
little bit the speed is we got a rougher
cut here now just
we're going to focus on this screw right
here next slide
see what you get look at these ready
like things start to appear next slide
closer
see
it here up to here to here shredded now
this chips of stuff were just the bomb
residue thrown out by the cutting
process and you saw it all in the
castle's holes
look at this little knobby thing here
next slide
up to there here it is up here
you see this going up and we see
this whatever it is is a different kind
of thing and this is a piece of it
but it's shredded folks
understand it resisted the dremel
whatever it is
stronger than the bone
that's what's amazing
now you see this going up this is this
stuff thing here goes in and disappears
into here and there's another piece
growing here
that's different
and it looks like fans out here so when
we saw this
the experts in with us said you know
this looks like it might be fungi or
bacteria or something that's wrong on
the bone since you cut it
why don't we have it tested by a
mycologist or at least looked at my
mycologists and see what they say
mycologists being specialists in fungi
bacteria we took it to three in england
including the very best england has
that's my colleague he said i've never
seen anything like this i've never seen
this in mine no idea what it is but
there are 30 000
possible examples of fungi or bacteria
maybe i don't want them all
and you need to have it tested to find
out what it is for sure which we agree
with we do need to have a testimony test
called long talk and intelligence fairly
sophisticated fairly expensive but it
can nail this down one way or the other
but he says i don't think this is
bacteria or punch it looks like
something
built into the bottle
now what also is weird about it is it
these things are high in silicon they
have about 25 silicon
whatever they are
you see here in the base of it
hold
now on another one that's not out of a
cancellous hole it probably came from a
cancellous hole but it got sheared loose
and it ended up here it could have come
from here we don't know but this is
no
no idea what it is
i'm going to look at this piece here
see how it is
praying mantis and notice here it shred
it off it didn't cut tears
so our thought was well maybe this is
part of what's making it so difficult to
cut maybe it's some kind of fiber
network that's laid through the bone
that keeps it resistant to cut it we
don't know
some things we have to find out this is
all fairly new
this is about
these are about four months old and what
you're going to see later about six
weeks old this is all new stuff hot
cocoa you're some of the first people to
see this
okay
what we did after the first scanning
electron microscope though that was
better it's a little more than half and
it just doesn't fit the same frame
now this is the inside surface of the
human female skull
notice that this is
an increstation made up of silicon sand
and dust and grit that is just collected
into about a sixteenth of an inch layer
on the inside of the skull this is
normal for 900 years in a high desert
environment
next level this is the end outside of
the human feet and female skull the
shininess again due to the shellac
that's prone
and see these dimples this is definitely
on the surface of skull again perfectly
normal this is what you would expect
those dimples would be under
the encrustation you can see it now this
is the inside
surface of the star child and you do see
the nipples they're very shallow but you
do see them
and what do you notice no infrastructure
even though it's buried for the same 900
years you expect whatever you see but
for some reason you don't see
this is the outer surface of these
storage rounds you see no dimples at all
here you see a comparison of the two see
the human female inside with the
infestation at what would expect let me
see here
next slide you see the outer surface of
the human with the dimpling that is
normal and you see on the outer surface
of the star child with no doubt
anybody can see
there is a significant difference
between these two
it should be
you know it doesn't matter how deformed
you are if you're human
being
think
whatever's left should be human
okay
now what after that was done
a guy that we contacted who's a
specialist in this said
we're going to now take the bone and
instead of cut it we're going to take
the cut piece and we're going to snap
we're going to break them both the human
and the starchild and get what are
called fractured edges and then we're
going to take them and polish them down
with lapidary tools with the jeweler
tools
when they're very slowly and very
carefully
take it down
flatten it out and make sure that no
crud gets in the cancellous holes
because they were looking to see what
causes the toughness
and because it looked like some of the
layers of the cortical bone seemed to
have a chemical chemically or enamel
and so the thought was well maybe we can
find some sign in the starch album of
enamel rather than of layering rather
than what humans have which is sort of
like concrete so this is the human
polished
one side the outside the upper the
outside of the head there and you see
polished
how clean the bone is do you know why
when you die when you go you carry
within your body the bacteria that are
going to consume you down enough
over time
mother nature cleans her plate if she
didn't we'd walk out of here and it
would be thousand foot high piles of
bones out there
mother nature cleans her plate how does
she do it she puts in you when you're
born the bacteria that are going to eat
you up when you die
and there are bacteria in you that eat
your marrow out
and that's why
normal cancellous bone looks like this
like it's been licked clean
because it has
and also normal human bone looks like
alabaster
it's beautiful it's polished and shined
like this
so how it looks next level
this is just the other side
and this is the inner layer and that is
the layer of infrastructure that you saw
flat on a while ago and you see a little
bit of like layering here but you see
it's very irregular and
it goes down kind of like in sheets kind
of like again or concrete but again you
see how clear the cancellous holes
they see this star child you see
difference it's kind of milky it's got
thicker manding here
and that's what read out like enamel so
that could have something to do with the
toughness
but you see the cancellous holes into
that milkiness you know what the
milkiness is from guess what collagen
found out
collagen remember i told you that that
smell the first cup was so stinky bad of
a bone collagen guess what
this piece of bone
one half is thicker than it should be
carries the full load
the full load
of collagen
like a compressed computer file
we don't know how that much collagen
alive for that matter how much collagen
is there but it's clear to see that it
is with no shine there's no alabaster
look it's a creamy milky that's caused
by the added collagen which we don't
understand
but most importantly you notice anything
at all kind of weird about this
look dead center
this little speck here
what does that look to your eyes
you see any grayish there yeah
next slide
we missed the first time you didn't miss
this
look at this
how did the bacteria not eat that away
next slide
close up on this
this
what do you think that is
that could be one of two things
desiccated marrow
which is the most likely thing
or
some kind of inorganic mineral that got
left behind somehow that the bacteria
couldn't could meet and couldn't
dissolve except no such thing as none
no such thing as known to be in bone
marrow
so either way you cut it
this is extremely weird
extremely unacceptable
extremely potentially historic
because if this is desiccated marrow
guess what that's organic
guess what else
the geneticists had it
had it in hand
and couldn't find nuclear dna with human
primers
and what does that tell you it's not
human dna
that's why they were getting the
mitochondrial dna but not getting the
nuclear dna because the primers were
going after human
nuclear dna and they weren't matching up
now if it's inorganic which it could be
if it's inorganic
we still have to find out what it's
doing there what it's made of
what's it doing
folks this is very potentially the
historic thing you're looking at here
because even if it's not alien connected
it's the weirdest human thing that
anybody's ever seen more so than the
elephant man
this is a big deal
just beginning to bubble up to the
surface of consciousness around the
world
the cutting edge next level
here we see a back lip and this was
flipped the bonus that was flipped where
open did the slide setting just made a
mistake this is the top of the
top side inside the pawn
but anyhow the point is there you go
look at how much there is next slide
getting back right
next slide close up
it's just astonishing i mean everybody
that we've had eight major big time
scientists
in england from the royal holloway look
at this including mycologists and they
all say
gee this we have no idea business but
you have to find out next time
these are the tests that we need just
some of the tests the most the major
tests we need a third dna analysis which
is now underway simply exceeding the
nuclear dna and we assume we're going to
get enough money to pay for it we
haven't yet but we're going to confess
the detailed dental analysis of the
animal service in the chemistry quality
talk tests
as i said earlier tests for the bacteria
in the fungi a detailed analysis of the
fibers in the residue fibers in the
redstone what are they what are they
made of to know that microtomography 3d
data on the internal structure what's
making it so hard
it did inductively couple plasma
spectrometry and laser arrangement
spectroscopy for trace elements are
there trace elements in here that don't
belong that trace elements are things we
don't have normally on earth the things
we've never heard of are combinations
and shouldn't be
test all that light elements stabilize
itself analysis strontium will have
isotope ratios isotope ratios and
analysis what they tell you is where the
thing lived what its environment was
like
what it left behind its own
what what its
environment was
it's amazing what they can do with these
things they're very sophisticated
they're very expensive but before they
get they're just amazing x-ray power
powered diffraction crystal bio-mineral
to tell us about that
more scanning electron microscope
examinations on multiple fracture
surfaces hope to see more of the fibers
to see more of the red stuff and try to
see what it is transmitted like
microscopy for structural features again
looking for hardness electron probe and
or ion probe inclusions
just stuff they they want to know i
don't even understand mostly analyzing
crustaceans inside those skulls and
visit the recovery area in mexico take
soil samples to make sure that matches
up to make sure that the saline
resonation came from where the skull
supposedly came we assumed that they did
and
we absolutely have to prove it the clay
model reconstruction invasion features
that's something we just kind of like
we can use that but we're going to use
whatever we wanted to get to do the
testing first because that's more
important
but
what we have to do what we've been told
by the scientists now is that we are
working on
who hears me without being mad
okay that we are working on
something that is so important that it
has to be done at a certain level
of sophistication now next slide
and because of that this is
this is what has to be done we need
between 50 and 100 000 probably more
like a hundred thousand dollars
and belinda by the way
mackenzie the lady put this together
cognizance and all that she put up 50
000 pounds which is basically a hundred
thousand dollars and we've gone through
that now
in the past two years doing all the
stuff that you've seen with dna and all
that
and so we need now to double that over
again
so we've got to find somebody with deep
pockets who's willing to it's not a
business deal this is a scientific
endeavor where we're trying to move the
line of history forward
we're not in this to make anybody a
bundle of money they're doing this to
answer the same kind of questions as if
we had found lucy or the lake turkana
boy or anything like that and you can go
to your college or your university
whatever and get a million dollar plan
or two million dollar grant or whatever
you need to work two three years and
find all the answers we don't have that
luxury we do this by the skin of our
teeth we do it on a budget but we get it
done
this is what we need
we have been told that because it's so
important when we stand up in front of
the world to announce whatever it is
that we have
and we're facing that bank of
microphones as you always see at a press
conference
we have got to be able to stand there
and say we've covered every base because
you know and i know that the critics are
going to say
have you done this test have you done
that test and you've done this test have
you done that test and if i have to say
no
to any of them
they're going to say well what are you
trying to hide
why didn't you
how can we believe you did this and this
is what you say it is if you didn't do
these things
so now we're kind of boxed into where we
have to do all of it to cover the bases
but if we can do that
and make our case
we've got enough sample enough bone to
where anybody else out there who wants
to criticize what we did can take the
sample and repeat the test with
themselves
that's the beauty of the starchild
there's so much of it
and it takes so little to do most of
this stuff
pieces the size of your fingernails is
all it takes
it's amazing it's a wonderful thing so
this is what i'm here for and this is
what i'm asking you for is help to get
this done
i don't say anybody here is able to do
it but if you know anybody that is
please contact them have them go to the
website starchild uk.com and read
through tell them what you've seen and
what you've heard
we're the real deal we handle the money
properly we do what we're supposed to do
with it and trust me if you don't
believe anything else believe that i'm
not in it for the money or anything else
i just want it over with
so i can go back to my world and my life
as a human origin researcher this is not
my game
i want this over here
thank you for coming
appreciate it very much i won't keep you
any longer with this you can clap now if
you want to
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
for those who have stepped forth into
the enigmatic and complicated world of
ufo research
they know that it is rife with division
but here just like religion we have
another reason for the numerous splits
as the enigma really comes down to the
individual human experience
[Music]
there are many who have claimed that
they have been visited by aliens or
beings from other dimensions
the vast majority like people who see
ghosts and apparitions believe in the
data from experiences they encountered
with their very own eyes
[Music]
[Applause]
the unconscious mind remains a mystery
because we are simply not conscious of
it
we must imagine what it is like inside
this huge domain on the other side of
our daily realities
occasionally people recall their
encounters in this strange world in
dreams and more interestingly lucid
dreams
whereby we become conscious of elements
of our unconscious world and even
interact with them
[Music]
[Applause]
if we remain neutral then we avoid
excluding any possibilities that have
yet to emerge in our conscious and
unconscious minds
we avoid putting ourselves into any
frame paradigm as in the case of science
and logic
perhaps we need to abandon any previous
notions or ideas about this phenomenon
to gain headway into the unknown
what are the ufos
are they emanating from ourselves
are they here only because we have the
capacity to perceive them
perhaps they are ancient archetypes that
we have forgotten within the sands of
time
whatever they are
they are very real to the experience
they are real to countless thousands who
encounter them more and more each year
as the sightings continue to multiply
what are they trying to tell us
[Music]
if we can understand the ufos perhaps we
can better understand ourselves
[Music]
now
the real fox mulder is free of the
demands placed upon him by government
what are his opinions on ancient
asteroids black technology and the
psychology of belief in ufos and last
but not least
aliens
[Music]
so
our world all the other world all the
planets all universes parallel universes
whatever there may be every blade of
grass every
um animal
is interconnected in some way shape or
form
some say the end of mankind is near
some say that economic and financial
turmoil is part of the process along
with global warming warfare and the
spread of mass psychosis
[Music]
children are prescribed drugs to keep
them calm the climate is changing all
around us while celebrities become our
gods and materialism the new mantra
we live in an era where we're obsessed
by celebrity we live in an era where
everyone wants a route out of their
ordinary lives and
people want a quick effects these days i
mean the idea the idea of of learning a
trade from your father or doing a
five-year apprenticeship has gone out of
the window people now want to go on big
brother and become a celebrity overnight
people want to be a wag
is there a reason behind this modern day
madness
are our material lives making us truly
content
if i want to know what the truth is
i have to live truthfully
and as long as i live as truthful
to myself or and to others then i'm like
in the vibration of truth
therefore
it will resonate with me or not
[Music]
but there is a ratio to it all
a rhyme in reason behind everything that
we do and everything that affects us
does this really happen by accident this
whole universe and us living on this
planet in this fragile atmosphere
in this one place in the universe it is
beyond thought it is beyond words but
there is a purpose to it
once people
start connecting with what they think
and what they believe
once you start taking the more innocent
point of view that their ancestors took
i think they still hope the survival of
this human race because if they don't
they'll poison ourselves off this planet
eventually i think like mad magicians
seeking to rule the world men of renown
have fleetingly seen the epic nature of
the ancient code in its alluring essence
but all too often they fall into an
abyss of their own making choosing the
wrong side of the code
[Music]
but today we too have missed the point
in our everyday complacency
we choose to exist in a waking sleep we
spend time naming things and separating
them classifying endless parts and
pieces without remembering the whole
the one
from which all things come
it needs no hatred nor warfare
it needs no drugs
it simply is
[Music]
for you
are the key
to the code
once you've found that point of
connection in yourself
where you are
part of
nature part of the world around you and
it is part of you
then no secret no
quantum
physics quantum spirituality
can get anywhere near
that point of unique connection
because you found yourself and you found
your own
god within yourself
[Music]
reality
reality falls
[Music]
[Applause]
on a dark winter's night in january 1983
the sleepy welsh village of clanila near
aberystwyth was buzzed by a strange
flying craft of some kind which hit
trees scattered shiny metal debris over
four fields and flew off apparently
unaffected
[Music]
one farmer witnessed the debris and
cleanup operation one national newspaper
carried the story
one civilian investigation team made it
to the site
one collection of strange metallic
debris remains
[Applause]
[Music]
witness for the first time ever in
graphic detail
genuine pieces of a crashed ufo
[Music]
along the wilderness road they come
behind them the struggles of the
revolutionary war
before them the conquest of a wilderness
the journey is long and arduous
but it leads to a land of promise
day after day the party follows the
unfamiliar trail
bigfoot
also known in north america as the
sasquatch or the omaha
was the sasquatch here before the
indians
[Music]
thousands of indian locations are named
after the boss of the mountain or the
wild man as the bigfoot was originally
called by the amerindians
indian cultures generally regard the
wild man with the greatest respect
he is viewed as a special kind of being
perhaps because of his seemingly close
relationship to humans
many indian elders regard him as
standing on the border between animal
and human consciousness giving him a
supernatural kind of power
but as special as he may be
there is no tribe that suggests that he
is anything other than a physical being
living in the same physical dimensions
as humans and other animals
he eats
he sleeps
gathers and communicates with family
members
[Music]
it seems that the wild man may indeed be
of a varied and widespread clan
encompassing every continent of the
world they all have one very distinct
trait in common
an exceptionally big human-like foot
[Music]
our search for this film brings us to
the great state of kentucky
the bluegrass state and the home of the
kentucky derby
[Music]
throughout the last 100 years there have
been many wild man sightings in
in kentucky
in there
listen
yeah
there's something moving
in this tree line along the edge
it looks like they're hearing it over
there they're damn brighter
light from the road the blue light
that's getting brighter
and brighter
dude look through here
look through there right now
what is it you can't see it but the
camera picks it up
[Music]
on
we can't see it but the camera can't see
it's moving
take your camera off of them
just stay there
don't lose it