welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey in defining my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
what's up everyone so welcome to
um I guess what we're calling legit Or
Nah which is the review section that
we're going to be doing going to
different collectives and getting like
not necessarily old school strains but
strains
predating the cookies era and
seeing if if modern day collectives have
what they claim to have in flower
because a lot of people that have have
that are tuning in even or are new to
Growing never experienced a lot of these
clones and are relying on their data and
their input
to be from these places
where they get their where they get
their opinions to base their judgments
on these strains right
um this is where they maybe go get their
clones if it's a you know a clone
Nursery flower place you know those
places I think still exist right
so I I thought it would be kind of
interesting to do this
um you know I've I've also been doing
reviews on stuff that is modern because
I've stayed away from it for so long
and I you know it used to be when people
would ask me that I just be like oh
like I don't care you know but um
yeah I guess
there comes a point of where like I need
to know because now I've isolated myself
from that part of the community for so
long that really I just don't know
anymore like past gelato I just been
like I don't care but I need to care
because I can't give valid input or
anything on it other than it has cookies
in it maybe it sucks you know and and
that's not always going to be the case
and as I'm learning through these
reviews so without further ado
one of the first things I wanted to
check when I went to any Collective was
OG Kush
I wanted to see
first I get a lot of messages from
people uh that are that are newer
Growers and they ask like what's the
best OG cushy line I've never tried a
pure OG Kush and I want to experience it
I want to have you know a good data
point for it
and I you know for me OG Kush has been
around so long that it's almost like uh
second nature thing to know what OG Kush
is and I I tend to explain stuff oh it's
kind of OG cushy you know like assuming
everybody knows what that is
um
when it comes to OG Kush of course there
were a lot of old clones so Louis OG is
one of the old classic ones coming out
of La probably an OG Kush back seat is
best as best anyone can tell it doesn't
seem to be if it's a hybrid it's so OG
Kush dominant that
um you don't see any at least I don't
see any of the um other parents traits
if it's a hybrid you know
um to me it's just a classic classic
version of an LA OG Kush
um
our buddy bitter still holds the cut
resin lung held the cut for a long time
passed it to me pass it to bitters so
it's still in our group
and um it's something that you know we
can smoke flour of from the original cut
still so it's also a good reason I
wanted to choose Louis OG it's something
that we still have access to the flower
something I'm very familiar with very
familiar with
and with this it's kind of giving people
some wiggle room too like um this is a
review of uh fto which is free trade
Organics or just one of the many
companies that sells locally here I
think they're from LA but they probably
drive it up to Bakersfield or whatever
um it says small batch Exotics so that's
how you know it's dank it says exotic
um that's a joke that's sarcasm for
all of you
um
yeah it's it's it gives a little wiggle
room because OG Kush is OG Kush like
as long as it's a really good OG
it can look like a good faithful
representation of what Louis can express
so it can almost fly under the radar
even if it's not exactly it
it can hit close enough to where it's
splitting hairs that's what's beautiful
about OG Kush right so I want to see
essentially if they have a really decent
old-school OG Kush so whether this is
truly Louis or not I could really care
less I want to see if they're offering a
decent representation of old OG Kush and
um yeah on their label they actually
list it as
I don't know if it's too
King Louis OG
and indica so you know and there's the
uh code you could probably scan it from
this if you want to I don't know if that
helps them in any way but hopefully it
does
um
so first off I'll talk about the flower
um yeah I'll show some pictures here
probably gonna make it get like pushed
into mature audiences which whatever
um I was not necessarily impressed with
the look of the flower
um the texture felt or the look of it I
should say the look of it looked like it
had been handled a lot if that makes
sense and it'll look like it'd be
handled a lot
you know by someone wearing gloves like
I could tell what that looks like it
almost makes the blood look more oily
because the the resin is being kind of
it's been handled right and that's how
it looks and you can see from the
pictures
um that I'm posting I don't know where
it's going to insert it probably
somewhere yeah
um but yeah
it wasn't impressive looking so when I
opened this up I was like man
man okay well I'm probably gonna be you
know I figured it was just going to be
as expected for a dispensary experience
like just low end grow mid Z oh gee
but I will say I will say
I was pleasantly surprised
looks can be deceiving
definitely looks can be deceiving and
obviously they were the bottoms of the
bottoms of the bags not much love given
to them they were manhandled but
um
it did it did have some good qualities
then I'm gonna um I've already smoked it
done all that but I'm going to try to
see if I can bring up anything else
right now while I have it here and since
I'm going to be doing these reviews and
it's the first video I'll talk about
what I'm using to do the review since
this is important too
um I have my C2 that beautiful breeder
Syndicate Edition
um C2 Custom Creations pipe and then I
have of course my ash catcher my lovely
Ash kit I should have cleaned the bowl
but it was pretty fresh
um my ash catcher from C2 I love this
thing the easiest ash catcher I've ever
cleaned
and you should have your [ __ ] you know
pretty clean at least clean your water
right so you can flavor or whatnot
and um then I have
for the second way because that was of
course combustion method because you're
only going to get so many flavors that
way and frankly the high is less complex
than um
using what I call the or not what I call
what is called
the rip tick rip master
it is a vaporizing wand
that there's a hole in the bottom here
and there's this rubber gasket that
seals to the bowl and then there's holes
on each side in each direction that make
this the air kind of spin up through
something like that the heat goes
through it it works and honestly I you
know I've owned volcanoes like really
nice volcanoes and I've given them all
away uh after getting this because I
really think this is the most perfect
smoking device for me for me in my
opinion for me to evaluate high and
flavor
nothing's more accurate for me it
doesn't just go popcorn you know you get
full ranges of experience
um
if you've never smoked blueberry through
one of these things I highly recommend
it
when I say blueberry I mean real
blueberry you know blueberry tastes like
blueberries
which is I guess rare unless you're
having fun stuff of course
anyway
I also wanted to give like a um a less
less experienced smokers take so I'm
having Brynn kind of my my lady chime in
on some of this she she's she smoked
most of her life but it's always been on
and off and once we met like she never
paid attention
any care for strains or you know of
course most people don't most people
don't so once she met me she got you
know introduced to the weird world of
giving it crap about strains and all the
weirdness that comes along with that and
the complexities and um slowly I've been
trying to get her you know to try these
different things or remember what's what
What She Likes what helps with what and
I got some of her input on the smell
taste high as well
and I found it kind of interesting
because usually we experience things so
different like I smell blueberry and
she'll say ooh peppery you know or
that's bright
sharp like different words that I like
don't work for me when I describe smell
she she's an artist so she she has a
whole different way of thinking and she
she thinks in terms of like color
texture it's it's very unique when it
came to um the Louie this was her input
the smell she said it smelled like
someone with bad breasts wished lemon
floor cleaner which
I mean that's fairly accurate like I get
lemon floor cleaner too so
yeah the Ben Brett thing I would
associate more GMO but
like whenever she smells GMO she just
goes
you know like
like she wants nothing to do with that
so this one she does this is she
actually really really likes this
um case coated my tongue like the syrupy
stickiness of lemon heads which I
thought was awesome and hella
descriptive and the high
calms me down enough to focus but
doesn't put me to sleep with no anxiety
um
or it doesn't put me to sleep and it has
no anxiety
um enough that I was able to sit down
and read 12 chapters which her sitting
for longer than five minutes is an
insane idea and um
it's it's getting her to the point where
she can sit and focus and read which is
great for her
um so yeah I don't know like
hopefully maybe some of you you guys out
there your ladies may take some input
from that if they're not like is super
into this and as dorky as we are about
it like maybe that might resonate with
them some more I'm not sure but I wanted
to bring that in because I thought it
was really interesting how much it
aligned with me so I'm a sparkle Bowl
and uh I'll tell you what I what I taste
uh dream combustion method
so like I said
looks can be deceiving
this has exceptional old
traditional
mouth coding OG Kush flavor it's exactly
like I would have wanted
um I've gotten other ogs from
collectives even the same same place I
ordered from which was called Highway 99
collective in Bakersfield they were
offering a marzo gene it was going to be
the first review but I felt that it was
such a
piss poor representation of Mars
that I didn't like smoking it and it
just got kicked to the side like it was
that bad I was super unimpressed with it
this
while it was it's obviously not the best
grow of it
um
I shouldn't say that it's not the best
handling of it it might have been an
amazing I think it was probably a really
good grow because the flavor's there I
think it was probably not the best
manhandling of it
but the uh flavors there the highs there
it's got a nice relaxing
anxiety-free OG kushai because OG Kush
tends to be anti-anxiety for me it's not
always for everyone
um but it is for me but the most
important thing is that Flora cleaner
mouth coating
um
lemon floor cleaner I guess is the the
best way to put it Pledge some people go
pledge some people go like soapy like
floor cleaner to me is soapy so I often
use soapy to describe it but floor
cleaners furniture polish is more
accurate Maybe
um if it doesn't have that to me it's
really hard for me to call it a good OG
Kush because that's what I want out of
it that's how I feel OG Kush expresses
best now there's people who feed it
heavily you know get OG Kush to be more
earthy smell more fuely gas but when I
when I get OG
I want furniture polish like this I want
to I want it mouth coating it needs to
be completely unique you need to know
that's OG Kush
um there's plenty of things that that
aren't OG Kush that are earthy uh kind
of cushy you know but that don't have
the furniture polish aspects to it
anyway so that's that's it for the uh
the flavor portion of the combustion
overall
it tastes like OG Kush should when it's
combusted
but there is a whole nother level you
can take something
when you use
vaporization techniques especially Vapor
wands heat wands
um
you know I I
I'm not sponsored by these guys at all
you know like everything's been bought
and paid for from them this was actually
a gift from my buddy Iris back in the
day he was the first person to turn me
onto this and I I made fun of him
thought it was his uh anal torture
device I still think it is
um
you know we all use it for that at times
but it works great for for this too it
also doubles and works great for this
um but I do think that the uh
the design could be improved on a bit
and um it's really hard to get a hold of
now these things which is a shame so
hopefully and I know some people are
working on some new wands because these
these things are that good so we'll see
what comes in the future but for now we
are using the rip Tech and I highly
highly recommend any one devices if you
want to experience flavor and the high
complexity of any strain
so I'm going to give this a go with the
oh Louie
and with these you want to let it kind
of heat up for a second and then you
draw in really slow
like it's like it's your dad
and there's a world of flavor and OG
Kush that unless you vaporize it you
won't experience there's like candy
there's a like a Lemonheads candy in
there that is super sweet
citrus
almost an orange
the complexity is so far away from the
the harsh tones of gassy fuel
and what we expect from that it's just a
world apart
and uh yeah
this this is this is definitely whatever
cut they have is an old OG Kush cut
whatever it is and I dig it and I'm glad
that at least some people you know if
they got lucky enough to
um by Bud from this cut they've got to
experience OG kush here locally recently
[Music]
foreign
there's something indescribable
about the flavors you can get out of
vaping there's something that runs
through all of them
that I think is uh
probably just the flavor of cannabis in
general
but it's super Pleasant and and I never
experienced this with the volcano
I never experienced this with any of
those devices
um
my friend Warren brought a stores pickle
like portable thing but he had this
device attachment on top of it it looked
almost like a puffco or a Carta type top
it's more like a card I type top
and it was bigger
and with that you're able to get some
pretty good flavors that were were
similar
to what I saw with the rip Tech it's the
closest I've seen closest but it still
had some of the popcorn stuff
um
but it was close it was close but this
is a Next Level and for the um the piece
we were using for the rip Tech is
another C2 and this one's a double
ratchet they actually talk about this in
the C2 episode that we did recently
season nine episode one
um it got stuck into the mature section
you know for the adults so go check that
out
um what else do I gotta get in here uh
go check out our Discord patreon I'm
gonna try to do more of these
um
but yeah if you have access to ftos
King Louie
like I said this specific batch looked
like someone maybe
handsies it up a little bit too much
um but it's not bad it's not bad I don't
regret it I regret the Mars OG I regret
that I fully regret that I don't regret
this so
um shout out to them they did a great
job with the um growing of it really
good job with the flavor
um high is great
and uh overall it was a pretty good
value too I mean I think they're
charging 35 and eighth which is probably
standard for nowadays I don't know I
don't know what people charge for for
weed now but uh it wasn't uh I'm not mad
at it you know what I mean like I was
mad when I looked at it but I wasn't mad
after and that's what counts so anyway
that will be it for this Edition you're
not gonna be that freaking long it's
just me rambling Stone so
maybe maybe it'll be the last one I
don't know maybe this totally sucks and
everyone hates it but we'll see
check you later
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate
check out our patreon and our link tree
or description below our merch site is
officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is top notch
I've been saving old designs for years
for this purpose so please check it out
syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out