to that
oh man i i got a ton of questions
one question around you know kind of
antic antagonistic behavior uh there's a
lot of rumors that you had a secret
twitter account and you would kind of
semi publicly post under a
different name uh can you confirm it and
i have you ever you know posted or
interacted with ufo twitter from an
account other than the official willows
i'm an intel guy
i mean
i collected that man
it's not a yes or no but but
you know there's a lot of things that
people do to confirm and deny
information and to to see if it's if
something's real and legit
um so you know i'm not saying that i did
maybe friends of mine had or family
members had but you know
collecting intel is is
what i do that's always been what i've
done and so you know people are i'm not
going to confirm it a knife i've had
another account on i mean first of all i
don't like social media i i do look at
social media from my my twitter account
which is the only thing i have i don't
have instagram or anything else
um simply because people are willing to
take the time to write something i think
they at least owe eyes on it right so
someone's going to take the time to say
hey lou uh i really liked what you did
or hey lulu that really sucks what you
did um you know
honestly there's a couple times where
people have called me out thankfully
because i may have made a mistake as
everybody knows right on my twitter page
one of my my tendencies i will always
hold myself accountable and there's been
i think two or three instances where
i've said something it either wasn't
taken properly or maybe i
miscommunicated it and within 24 hours
of it being brought to my attention i
readdressed it i said oh hey mia coppa
guys you know great catch great call you
know this was my intent apologies if it
was lost in translation or if i made
mistakes something that wasn't my
intention and you know here
here we here we go so i think um
you know that's that's that's one of the
ways to hold yourself accountable is is
through
through listening to people even even
with dissenting views again not
not the hecklers out there people that
are just trying to cause drama and
trauma that's not that's i don't look at
those uh but people who have honest
questions or comments or concerns
i look at those
um what are any other follow-up
questions rather before we get to our
i appreciate that uh yeah
let's let's move on to the game i think
i got whatever okay all right unless you
got a question michael uh well i do have
one but uh before we go to the game and
then we can hit that one after totally
up to you yeah your mic's still a little
funky really
yeah this is what happens when you don't
do shows in 10 months michael
all right like get it together all right
so luke can you hear me uh it's it comes
in and out a little bit yeah i'm not
sure what's happening
um but all right let's let's see what
yeah real quick hey yeah let me know let
me go a little further on this and
let me um
let me give a little bit more direct
answer to to rather here um
look there's things that i do with
because i have that blue little check
mark
on my on my name that actually hinders
me from doing a lot of things that i may
want to do if i want to get on twitter
and ask somebody about
purple curtains um
you know if i do that it's it's it gets
really tough
so
it's common for a lot of people to use
anonymity in order to to to research
things
um i'll you know i'll ask you the
question
rather um
you know
some people say well why would you want
to be anonymous well but let's face it i
i doubt that your real name is rather be
splitting
yet you use it because it's helpful and
effective because you're not quite
comfortable providing out your your
personal information
i get it and i respect that
but the same holds true for other people
the same feelings and concerns and fears
you may have is precisely the same
concerns and fears that other people
have and probably including myself
that's a great i mean yeah i feel like
it's a soft yes but i think it's a great
answer man and and um yeah what do you
what were you gonna say rather
well yeah actually it's not a crime
right no it's definitely not a crime
that's for sure
but there is kind of a weird dynamic
going on in ufo twitter and i think that
you know there was a an account that was
almost an open secret that was yours and
i'm not sure if this one actually was
yours or not but there's a lot of people
on you know your supporters who would
kind of clamor and
on to what that would say and kind of
you know rallying cry and it it seems to
kind of stoke fires a division rather
than you know uniting people and uh
you know frankly i found that a little
disappointing if that account really was
yours but you know i do understand well
i don't know you you haven't asked me
and let me ask you this bureaucrat one
right now
i
i see that on there right now that it's
not me right now i'll tell you that yeah
it was that account was deleted i think
in november and someone took it over
um so so that account that's posting
right now definitely isn't you but so so
let me ask you another question
if i may rather um if i if i called your
mother a hooker
how would you now being honest i'm not
that i'm not saying that i'm asking you
hypothetically if i were to call your
mother a prostitute
or
your partner or your kid
how would you feel about that
yeah i i would not like that i
i hope you don't know those implications
no no no and i'm not by the way for the
record i'm not saying that but i'm
asking you a hypothetical that you now
being out okay let's say rather be
squinting what's your real name and
everybody who you were and people were
were calling your family people
disparaging things like that
knowing
that it wasn't true and knowing that you
couldn't come out and defend yourself
publicly because it would never stop the
moment you feed the seagulls more and
more seagulls come right the more yeah
the trolls more and more trolls come so
yeah so i'm asked hypothetical how would
you
deal with that a to set the record
straight with facts and data okay
at the same time trying to to
to
continue to fill a type of behavior
people do do make disparaging comments
on me uh all the time about twitter and
stuff and i personally i think the best
strategy is just to ignore it you know
it's it's
you know usually
traders
well but understood if i were to accuse
you of a crime and you don't address it
i call you i say you know what i caught
you yesterday breaking and entering into
a neighbor's house stealing everything
that they have and killing their dog and
leaving and by the way i've got proof
and evidence to show it
it would depend on who's saying that
right if it's someone of your stature
stature i probably would feel like i had
to respond but if it's just some person
anonymous person on the internet i would
not respond see i disagree i think an
anonymous someone on on the internet is
has just as much voice as i do with the
blue check or anybody else this is where
you and i disagree
i think that's fair everybody every
person in your audience right now that's
listening has just as much
of an opinion and entitled to their
opinion as you do and as i do and as
everybody else that's where i disagree
just because you and i have a microphone
in front of us doesn't make either one
of us higher statute or more important
it makes us more of a target for sure
and more susceptible to the hatred but i
i it doesn't make the sting or the pain
go any less
and
you know i've
maybe i'm a bit old-fashioned i'd come
from a long family of revolutionaries my
father was in the bay
you know
i chose a career that tends to be a
little bit i guess
somewhat similar um but to me
you know people are the most important
aspect of any conversation the entire
topic of ufos and uaps doesn't mean
anything if you don't have the
conversation about people themselves and
what it means because ultimately
it's how we deal with information as a
species which is going to dictate how we
deal with the topic of ufos and
therefore i think everybody should be
part of that conversation everybody's
entitled to an opinion and everybody's
opinion should be taken equally until at
which point it's proven that they're not
that they they don't they don't have
equal voice because they're not
interested in the truth they're just
interested in agitation and again
let me let me say this i'm not attacking
you at all rather i'm just i'm playing
devil's advocate here because you ask me
a very direct you ask me a very direct
question and i think you deserve a very
direct response but also one that that
that is helps me explain my position on
the topic i think everybody is entitled
to defend themselves and i think it's
terrible and repulsive when people can
say things and you are expected not to
defend yourself especially your
credibility when you've defended and
fought for your country people friends
have died
for that privilege i take that very
seriously when people accuse my wife or
my kids of something yes i take that
very seriously and that's part of the
problem i think with with society today
we don't have honor we've lost that
somewhere we've lost
the fact that
defending your loved ones and defending
your friends and your family is
something we should be doing
and anybody who takes those attacks
there should be consequences unless you
have damn proof and evidence and i this
is why we are in the situation we are in
as a society because no one is held
accountable
no one's held accountable and i think i
personally think it's it's i think it's
disgusting i think this is why we're in
the situation we are right now and again
i'm not playing again not not attacking
you here rather than just giving you my
honest feeling in my opinion from my
heart so yeah i'd just like to add you
know all the the attacks that are on
foot or anyone who's paying attention at
all can can see right through that and
that's obvious bs all that all that
stuff so you know i i commend you and i
can see how that would be you know
not not make you feel great and you yeah
i want to respond but yeah it is it is
yes in my opinion as well
i mean look we're humans