um you know but can can we say
that
at least for right now that the truth is
cloudy
can truth be cloudy
sure i mean truth is also it's also
relative there are personal truths and
then there are universal truths right
your religion your cultural affiliations
you know those are all your political
affiliations those are personal truths
they're true to you
but then you have universal truths like
gravity right and so therein lies a
conundrum sometimes personal truths can
be conflated with with universal truths
so we have to we have to be mindful of
that but look lou here
anybody who is in the government and by
the way they can verify it knows i still
hold the t at top secret security
clearance right there's a reason okay
a if i tell the quickest way for me to
have my security clearance revoked or
suspended is a if i provide an
unauthorized disclosure i provide
classified information in an
unauthorized manner the other way is by
lying if i lie just like i can't talk
about national secrets i also can't lie
to the american public because that also
will hold a be held against me for
security clearance reason so i always
have to ride this very fine line and
people just assume oh he's
disinformation
i can't lie to the american people
because i will have my security
clearance removed because that is a site
part of the psychological evaluation
someone is a is a is a confirmed
pathological liar that is an indicator
usually of some sort of of psychological
issues those people can't hold security
clearances
also