to sort of help kill you or help kill
ufology a little bit okay so the name of
the game is called stick with it let's
move on or bs
all right so that's how you have to
answer the the uh the topic that comes
up stick with it let's move on or bs
so let's start with a with a big one you
ready
roswell
stick with it
cattle mutilations
let's move on alien abductions
and by the way let me count let's move
on for now
yes great okay that
perfect
uh alien abductions
move on okay underground military bases
alien bases
yes
wait what
did you say yes bfbs oh bs oh okay all
right yeah why because i saw rather
space too okay yeah okay yes total bs
underground alien basis all right uh
grassroots uap efforts like the big
phone home
stick with it baby yeah all right uh
false flag operations
they've existed in the past so let's
let's say let's move on home simply
because okay let me clarify uap
false flag narratives
well we know that actually has occurred
in the past so we can't say bs and
i don't want to say stick with it
because it's not occurring now so that's
why i said let's move on simply because
there's elements that that that have
some truth on that in the past but i
don't i don't see that right now as
being
at least publicly there's some
resistance that i'm facing inside the
government but that's not your concern
and that's you know a fight that we have
to deal with um it's more obfuscation i
think than it is false flag
got it
alien hybrids
let's let's move on we don't have enough
yet all right public uap hearings
stick with it yeah uh secret space wars
on mars
yes yeah thank you uh susan goff will be
more transparent in the future
uh is there a layer even more harsh than
bs by chance oh my god okay moving on uh
pressure the air force to be more
transparent
stick with it
dino beavers
um
i have no idea what i know what dino
testing is on a car i know what a beaver
is
and i know i don't know what that is
yeah dino beavers like
skid walkers at the pentagon
i know about the wolves and stuff like
that but not the dino beavers uh okay
all right so pass i'll give you a pass
um
skid walker ranch
stick with it okay
and last but not least who's lou
i don't know i never saw it okay all
right excellent excellent all right um
yes by the way yes by the way i would i
would say yes um lower category yeah
yeah yeah well yeah susan so strong you
blow your hair back
i mean people are coming to me like who
are you really not married i'm like dude
i got married arapahoe county not
florida okay
and they're like oh who's this picture
of these two girls i'm like well the
lady behind that woman is my wife she
didn't want to be in the picture so
you know if i was having an affair with
somebody um
it would be really hard to have done
that um so it yeah it's it's garbage man
i mean it's like i said look look at the
source of right who
put i'm not gonna mention names but but
look at the source and do a little
digging and you'll see um you know
you'll see who's a liar okay so one
other question about skinwalker and this
is one that i