welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar that corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate the videos on this channel the
Breeders Syndicate 3.0 are compliant
with YouTube policies and does not
depict or promote any sales or
distribution of any substances these
videos do not violate any YouTube
Community guidelines and is intended to
educate the public about historical and
scientific aspects of hemp plants this
video does not promote idolize nor
glorify any illegal activities or unsafe
consumption of regulated substances we
are not doctors or lawyers this should
be super obvious with that said some
people need to be reminded about this do
not take anything we say as medical or
legal advice of any sort we are just the
best at what we do live with it all
content is copyright of the breeder
Syndicate 3.0 2024 section 107 of the
fair use act thank you for your support
I am Matt here with breeder Syndicate
and today we have Chucky pollins with us
co-hosting and we get to have back
the what would you say the legendary I
think he hits that status mad Jag he's
here yeah in my mind wizard it's a
wizard dark wizard um yeah so we're
going to talk today about mad Jag's
Journey with something we like to call
Mex 40 and uh how he first acquired it
what he's done with it since uh what
tests have been done on it Etc and uh
yeah we're all pretty stoked about it so
it's great to have you back badj thank
you so tell us about this Mex 40 where
where where did where did the journey
start all
right I spent most of my years in the
verie valley of Arizona which is about
the center of Arizona and the four towns
there are Jerome Cottonwood Camp birdie
in Sedona and I lived in Cottonwood but
I got to know a lot of people in Jerome
because it was the hippie capital of
Arizona from 19 late 60s to present more
or less although it's got gotten a lot
more uh fancy people there in the last
20 years yeah and back in about
1974 73 I was in Jerome and I went into
this store and met this lady she had her
own store she was an artist and she
carried other art artists on
consignment introduced myself we got to
know each other a little bit but many
many years went beyond that because
shortly thereafter I got married had two
kids whole world changed and um but she
kept her store going for over 30 years
and
she and I both have had um serious
tragic events in our Lives four years
ago roughly four and a half and I was
going through all this stuff in my shed
and I found this huge drawing it was
about two and a half feet wide by four
feet tall all pencil drawing of a early
girlfriend I had in Jerome named Linda
[ __ ] she'd be happy to be famous so
there's her next one minute of fame um
and it's a photo of her from this a
drawing of her from the side nursing her
daughter um
and I I've been carrying it around for
years and years I got it from another
friend who had died and I inherited it
so I said I'm going to take this back to
D to this lady and um I called her up on
the phone and said hey you know is it
all right if I stop by I have a surprise
so I stopped by gave it to her and she
was so happy because she didn't have it
was from 19 19 73 72 when she drew it
she had no artwork of that magnitude
from back then so it was a she was very
happy to get it back and we talked for
three hours hadn't seen her in roughly
years
so we
exchanged histories and talked about all
the people she's been in Jerome since
1973 she's still there she's never lived
anywhere else she is the she knows every
human's history there all the people
that I knew and some of them that aren't
around anymore um one famous guy who was
a grower in one of the Canyons not far
from magad Canyon that's funny he was
walking home from the spirit room or
Paul and Jerry's the two bars and he had
a six-pack and he tripped and fell on it
and it pierced his his liver and he died
on the street Jesus
so she filled me in all these details
and I was like Wow and and I said well
do you smoke still and she said well I
didn't for many years but I started a
couple years ago went cool and she was
growing on a rooftop in in some
containers but she was still paranoid
even though it was legal in Arizona now
but she so she she said it's just an old
habit because she got busted in college
and and swore that she would never ever
get busted again yeah and I well you
don't have to worry anymore yeah and she
told me that when she closed her store
about three years ago she moved her
giant safe to her home and she was going
through it and she found this
baggie the old style baggie that you had
to lick to roll it in
clothes way before zip locks or press
locks and yeah said there was a bunch of
seeds in it and she she remembered her
friend um who this lady friend of hers
who was kind of a low-level dealer you
know when a some good herb would come
into Jerome she would get you know like
five ounces or something like that for
her friends and such yeah and it was
1984 roughly and that's when
CIA everything suddenly became CIA there
was no more no more seeded weed coming
from Mexico cuz they suddenly realized
where the money was yeah like 10 20
times more expensive than than brick
weed yeah absolutely I think and she
believes she remembers that they would
take Whenever there was some Cincy that
came through there'd always be a few
seeds that someone would find and they
they'd keep them treasure them and
judging by the look of the seeds when I
looked at them I would say there is
three varieties here so probably three
different loads that hit town and found
five seeds in this load and 15 in that
load and not in loads but like in what
they got maybe just ounces so they kept
them and they went into this baggie some
of the seeds
were you know typical like we see today
marbled with nice design there was these
really tiny seeds that were the size of
sesame seeds and they were perfectly
dark black yeah round round
and I'm like wow I haven't seen many
seeds like that before and then there
was some immature seeds kind of tan or
couple that were white too yeah I don't
think they knew better to doubt
it you know seeds 83 so they uh she
found this baggy and she went wow I
wonder if any of these would grow so she
took five of the marbled seeds planted
them and
to her surprise they came up and they
grew up on her rooftop and then when she
went up to check and she knew about how
to you know sex males and females she
saw m was a male and she pulled it I
hadn't met her at this point because it
was
2022 and um when I met her it was late
2022 and we got together and she pulled
out this herb for me I still have two
ounces of it in the fridge oh wow she
was a little too early she took it too
early it still had nice you know
crystals and and but it wasn't I said
what were the percent of the you know
pistols were that turn red or brownish
and she said about 50% oh okay yeah she
took it real early yeah and anyway
that's how that started and she said um
are you a grower still and I said oh
yeah but it's been in my backyard mostly
in recent times or in New Mexico this
other place and she said oh well I have
some seeds and she pulled them out we
looked at them and she said you can have
the rest of these and I got about 30
seeds from her um as you know five I
sent 10 I sent to you five for you and
five for your friend who is the germ
cell germ specialist
and I didn't plant that year but last
year I did and I decided since the wet
paper towel method didn't work
and whatever the gym specialist was
doing didn't work I thought I have
nothing to lose so I didn't keep track
carefully of the ratio of which were the
little tiny black ones and which were
the model ones but I planted them both
and six seeds came up the first seed it
took nine days in March W in Arizona
when it was in the 80s in the day yeah
to nine days just to poke up and the
other
five it took two or three more days up
to 11 days which I had given up
basically at about a week I went you
know I don't know but I I kept waiting
watered them yeah and I ended up with
six that's crazy two females and four
males the one that came up first must
have been one of those separate loads
because it has super it was really
strong and grew nice and it turned out
to be a female well it was a female oh
let's let's segue here farmer Freeman is
this company in Washington DC that yeah
that's right yeah I sent one of a little
clipping off a leaf today and I I bought
10 more um tests for this season and
they sent back that I had two females
and four males so the one with the most
Vigor and that was growing the fastest
and came up first was a female oh that's
interesting that's a mail and all right
I had them in one
gon root maker pots hard plastic yeah
and
eventually um they were put into five
gallon roof root makers I didn't put
them into the big uh 100 gallon soft
yeah I had 100 gallons and 230 gallons
two years ago in New Mexico but I sat
them on top of the old soil in all these
pots let them out and if looked like a
bad storm or something was weird going
on I just carry him into the green room
inside set him in the window and they'd
be fine I did that all the way till I
moved back to Arizona in November and
then I brought all six of them home but
during the summer when I had my annual
party on Labor Day weekend my friend
from Germany came over for a month and
another friend dread 420 he came over
for two weeks he lives in Monaco of all
places and we met in person at spanis in
2019 in Barcelona um I met 10 people in
person one in fact is dread he just goes
by dread and he's an American I think
he's from New York he's lived in Spain
for like over 20 years he worked with
Charlie Garcia oh W all the Legends erom
grower who went by Musta
Funk yeah had all these people it was
really cool and he came for a month and
I had never cloned anything before I've
never grown indoors either so I I had
him show me how we bought one of those
little boxes you know they would hold I
think 20 20 slots for clones and I
cloned um a bunch of cuting off the
female that was so vigorous MH and
that's what I ultimately seated with the
last flowering of the four males um and
I seated it just in time to get seven
weeks for the seeds to mature and almost
all the M seeds matured some are just a
little lighter color which I separated
from the the perfectly yeah mature but
I'm sure the lighter ones none of them
were white or tan um they had plenty of
time and then I
took two clones that or four clones that
are females and since I had other two
other male three other males I took
their pollen they each kind of
pollinated about a week apart it was it
was very handy and I separated their
pollen took one of the Clones pollinated
it and these clones were were basically
one one bud this long one C out of the
ground they didn't even have time to get
or anything but they were females from
the mother and I thought you know here's
three different pollin so why not po 81
and each one of those yielded about 40
seeds yeah they're only this long yeah
they're just tiny I think the big female
which grew to about 2 feet tall two feet
wide I think it had I haven't counted
them but 200 seats
yeah
and well but let's let's talk talk about
some of the taxonomy of these things
like did you see were there some that
were more broad than the others that
finished way earlier that you could
tell um well the Clones were all
clones of course if you're talking about
the the two females they were entirely
different and the one smaller female
that was half the size of the large one
that I used I gave to my friend SATA in
Boulder area he's been growing for I
don't know four decades he knows more
about Mexican strains and Colombian
strains than anyone I've ever seen on
any Forum that's awesome he he loves
ptoa and that's his favorite and he
won't smoke anything that has um indicaa
it's purely sativa everything he does is
sativa fact my favorite fudge that I
indulge in now is he made with Cambodian
cross with Colombian he calls it
lumbo
yeah aome so wonderful man it is so
beautiful pure sativa two old strains
yeah so they all what did he have to say
about his experience with this he took
the one he took he said this one is
talking to me which is good because I I
wanted to keep the larger one for C and
it was starting to get purple stems was
only 10 inches tall maybe maybe 12 and
he he said this one's talking to me I
said well then you should take it he
crossed it with Colombian I mean
Cambodian I don't know the results right
now he went to Argentina for like three
weeks with his wife he's he travels
someplace new every year in the world oh
that's nice a year younger than I am so
he's been around a while and his wife is
she's um a widower a widow
and has kids so he's like a stepfather
now and and but he's such a scientist
holy [ __ ] and Stoner and Stoner that's
awesome and the plant he took was very
similar looking to the one I kept they
they thin leaves there was no broader
leaves on the two females that's
awes now that I've taken the pollen from
the last um the last pollinating male of
the three and and pollinated the female
I have a seed growing right now that's 5
weeks old and it has broader leaves and
I've asked a couple people have you had
the experience I'm using um T5 LEDs yeah
not not foressence I bought one of those
fixtures that holds three and three so
six and it's four feet wide two feet by
four feet and I have these the four
phone letters under it right now and the
one plant growing in the middle
and it's Brer leav and I asked friends
on forums is it your experience that the
that under close LEDs like this it's
6500k so it's the vegging yeah light
span it's not the um flowering light
span and they said oh yeah they're
always wider at first and I'm going oh
so we'll
see because they're not indicia looking
but they're that in between
kind of South American Central American
a little bit broader leaves so did any
of the males have broad leaves at all
you saw or they all pretty narrow too
hold on a second I'm gonna look at a
photo you want and not record it or no
we can put it up [ __ ] it I
mean so so you had you said you had four
and then you had three clones of a
female
or you had a mother and then three
clones of her right that you that you
hit individually with each male I had
more than three clones but I gave them
to SATA and a few others just because I
didn't have a use for that many but
right initially I had two females and
four males I started with one big pot
which I didn't know anyway I had a male
right in with both females and my at the
parties people said you know you should
probably take that mail out and get rid
of it so did which I wish I hadn't but
did and but I had three males after that
and each one flowered like a week to 10
days later than the next and the last
flowering one is the one I used on the
mother herself okay gotcha the earlier
two I used on two clones and each of
those clones were like stocks I'll I'll
find them right here for you um
excellent have have you a chance to
smoke uh any of this stuff or or sample
any of it I have I especially the uh
ones that my lady friend grew
um which there's a person involving Ivy
so I just called it Ivy's mother and
it's um I had a a question from high and
Lonesome uh he's one of the the main
dudes from our Discord I don't know if
you know anything about him but uh he
was just asking and kind of curious you
know how does that how does I guess the
ivy or how does how does the Mexicans
that uh the Mexican stuff that you're
working with now compared to the stuff
you were growing back in the
canyon um I guess go ahead except for
the very first year of growing I didn't
have anything identified as Mexican per
se right we we had well no that's not
true we had wakin which was sold to us
brought well okay let's step back I'm
High
um the earliest Hawaiian was wakan
brought to Hawaii that most people
believe got crossed with Tai that was
brought to Hawaii yeah and we had some
of that and my friends in Hawaii sent me
the seeds so indirectly I think was wak
at least half wakan the rest of our um
plants were we planted a shitload of
Colombian because my best friend back
then was Colombian and we had no idea
that it wasn't going to be ready till
like Christmas yeah it was it was
snowing on the rim above us on
Thanksgiving and these they weren't
ready the buds were the size of my
little fingertip oh
no 10 feet huge plants but they it
wasn't very good smoke and we we sold it
but it was sad because it needed to go
to to Christmas if more it was true
equatorial you know
Colombian the wakan mix the quian they
called it grew to 12 to 14 feet tall wow
that's why we were also speculating
possibly Tai yeah because Ty grows so
tall reach for the sky and that was just
a very that's the second year I crew but
that was the very first year in Magi
Canyon then after that
we had some seeds left over but that's
about the time I met Robert Clark and
bought a bunch of skunk number one
1979 for the
1980 well 1980s when we had two gardens
goting and it was virtually all skunk
number one it's a good thing I bought a
lot because I wish I saved a lot but
yeah I bought a lot because um it was
we had foot tall plants and we came back
in a week the first week of June and
they were all gone and we had a plague
of grasshoppers that year and they ate
hundreds and hundreds of plants down to
the ground but the roots were still
there and we kept watering and most of
them came up but we replanted also and
oddly enough by by flowering time they
the ones we replanted the first week of
June caught up with the ones the others
so wild it was a lucky deal but yeah I
had bought 3,000 seeds and we started a
little seedy seed area like four feet by
five and just filled it with seeds and
we had mesh over it like um scream so
that no bugs could get it and once they
started growing up we just stick our
hands in the mud and pull one out stick
it over here in the mud walk across the
garden stick in there and they all
survive they're such a Hardy plant yeah
they truly
people we said they truly are weed
because it's hard to get rid of weeds
and and yeah but they they had
um they were leaning more towards sativa
I would say the skunk number one the
width of the leaves they we had none
that were like Maple Leaf uh you know
Tom Hills Maple
Leaf yeah that looks big and fat none of
them like that so I did get a few seeds
of Afghan number one Afghani number one
yeah they were fat as heck um but I they
just gave me a gift of 50 of them I
think um because we bought so many of
the skunk and I would have been
interested in those just to see how they
were I don't remember actually even
planting those 50 that sucks
yeah we ended up with
275 females
and um over across two
gardens it took a lot of work every week
we went in for three days I can't even
imagine how much work that would be I
like yeah I was 28 and my partner was 29
and but we were like so fit that oh I it
wasn't a problem we drink tequila by the
fire at night and go get up and hike to
the next Garden a mile away and then w
we would only water after the sunet yeah
we never watered when sun was in the
canyon because we did all kinds of tests
one of them was go up to the rim while
the other person started watering before
the sunset and it was like mirrors or
the water was mirrors we no can't do
can't do that and then the next thing
when because we had open little
plots we did a test it looked like it
was shining in the morning you know the
mud so one of us went up to the top sat
up there I know I did and looked down
and it was like like mud
mirrors so we started piling up huge
piles of oak leaves and every time we
watered before the sun came up we spread
the oak leaves over the mud perfect
couldn't see a thing and once they grew
up into big plants they were touching
you know I mean you couldn't see any
watering so we actually pulled off one
or two waterings at the end of the year
you know just like the hour before the
sun went down we started to get yeah a
little chilly over back then I mean
growing up you know doing stuff in the
black market myself there was always
like a edge of uh you know nervousness
or a little bit always a healthy a
little bit whenever I was up to
something so I couldn't imagine back you
know in the 70s or the ' 80s doing this
so I mean did you did you ever get
comfortable with that kind of you know
doing what you were doing that lifestyle
or or whatever or do did you did you it
was it every day you were just like this
could be the
day um that was always there that was
always present but part of it my I had
two I had a partner who would smoke when
in the garden and I had we had a third
partner who just helped us here and
there like prepping it the beginning of
the year he was from Switzerland and he
lived in the verie valley for two years
but at the end of the year he he lived
in the garden for three weeks straight
and he get high all the time I never got
high at all ever until Harvest and then
I would have one puff by the Fireside
and just to see what it was like what
skunk like you know right but I always
wanted to be straight enough so that I
could hear and not be too high and I
would let them it would it didn't matter
yeah but one time we were asleep in our
tent and I Heard a Voice and I was up
and Dr in less than 10 seconds honestly
I didn't have my boots on yet but I went
out the tent and it was coming from up
on the rim above us it was hunters and
they and then we heard a rifle shot and
they were after a deer and um that was
the closest and the scariest call of all
that one you bet and you guys didn't
carry weapons right you didn't I carried
a big throwing
knife I don't know what the [ __ ]
for yeah bears bears in there the first
bear I ever saw in Arizona was in that
Jag Canyon um but they run from humans
they you
know but yeah never know when you need a
throwing knife you know oh go ahead I I
was just going to say I don't deal in
Black Market [ __ ] anymore and I live in
Mich now so it's legal but do do you
ever miss that kind of I don't know uh
any kind of excitement from that you
know back then do you ever missed that
kind of excitement I don't know now that
it's legal there's a bit of it that's
kind of not as cool or fun to you or to
me at least um there was something fun
about just doing something maybe you
shouldn't be doing and getting away with
it I don't know I kind of miss that
sometimes yeah yep I know what you mean
um yeah I I had enough of it so I really
don't miss it right yeah right I'm just
so happy that we can be open here in the
southwest except for Nevada is no
Nevada's legal now right I'm not sure I
don't know Utah is not because the
Mormon aspect but um all these others
you know Colorado New Mexico Arizona
California Washington Oregon
Michigan yeah Michigan Illinois New York
Massachusetts my sister lives in Boston
my roster friend Ricky lives in Brooklyn
um but the black market is still big
there because at 300 to 350 an ounce in
the dispensaries for New York um people
go that's ridiculous you know right and
you don't know the quality you don't
know what chemicals are being involved
and um everyone still has their old
friend that's the grower and yeah
yeah they uh have you have you uh just
sorry track just got one more question
for you have you visited any of the
recck stores uh like the rec
recreational uh weed stores and have you
have what
them I've visited five in
Arizona um and one was a co-op before it
was even legal medically and these guys
were like wow running on a shoone I
don't know how they did it I parked like
500 yards away in a in a shopping mall
and walked to their store because I knew
it was being watched and yeah it was
like 2010 or something and
um it was I went in and they had a giant
safe inside that they kept everything in
yeah it was kind of crazy I bought some
um what's it called Tig
um it's from
Ace Ace SE oh Mali tiger no not Malawi
something Tiger and it was they
classified as super sociable and it was
great it was laughing gas I mean it just
laughed it was so nice um and that's
cool that they had that that's kind of
like I've never seen that in a Rec store
ever you know what I mean two grams from
them and walked around the block so I in
case I was
followed they disappeared I don't know
what ever happened to them but I've been
to about five regular um Recreation
stores I got my medical license in 2012
though so I could go to the dispensaries
yeah I went to a couple dispensaries oh
yeah and one I actually gave the guy
some weed and we were going to work
something out where he would but he was
presently at that time getting all his
we from California and not exactly
legally yeah yeah he'd drive over in his
pickup truck and get a bunch and so you
get a better deal you know you buy 50
pounds and he was in glob Arizona he was
going through the Arizona California
checkpoint like that yeah ballsy yeah
Savage they are mean there they are not
nice yeah okay um so do you want me to
grab
okay Bing this is this the stuff that
she took too early and you see the
shriveled leaves are really small
yeah really thin you could definitely
tell it was a bit early but yeah I know
it still developed and the little little
color on the branches um not purple
purple but it's not green yeah and you
can see there's plenty of resin on these
and I took I did a one toe test and then
I did a three to test which is how I do
it and yeah one to I didn't feel much so
I went huh so but I I didn't calculate
in my mind that hey THC was 5 to 7% back
then on on good weed so I took two more
Puffs and about 15 minutes later when I
was going gosh I guess it's not even
that strong it hit me and it's we used
to call creeper weed where you you take
a bunch of hits and then you go huh and
then all of a sudden it just creeps up
on you and I got a nice little buzz it
was very smooth and it really reminded
me of Mexican from the old days um the
very first year I grew in 1976 was with
seeds and my friend who was a dealer in
Temp and for two years he took the best
he kept seeds from the best loads that
he sent through and he sold a lot of
weed to the campus area and temp
and what more pictures you found
them what flavors did you get on that or
you know profiles as far as like the
smoke I know you said it's a little
early probably wasn't super developed
but uh is there anything you can
describe about the way it tasted
uh no um I've never been that good with
Aromas um the flavor it was mild it was
it didn't make cough or gag or anything
so
whatever whatever she did the way she
she said she put it in paper
bags she cut it so it was fairly slow it
wasn't just sitting out in the sun like
some people yeah
right these are these aren't my photos
these are comparison photos of
Zach um plants that were posted on icy
mag I think um how do you how do you
think it fared uh in comparison to zakas
this looks a lot more narrow leaf and
yeah it does it looks a lot more narrow
Leaf um than the
zakas it reminds me yeah just even
growing some of h&amp; L's manga like the
outdoor [ __ ] I grew it looks a lot Sim
not you know obviously the same or
anything but that kind of narrow leaf
look like there was also an email that
came with it that talked
about the primary Aromas
right I think this is it is cinnamon
Pine hops wood from the tur yeah yeah
cool so beta cine alpha pinene alpha
humulene beta pinene um perene
oxide beta trans aamine terpinolene and
beta mercine wonder if that would end up
smelling like
like a slightly different Super Silver
Haze um you got a uh how many weeks are
you looking you know when you're talking
about flower in these you see this one
can you see the one I just posted shared
screen see there we go there we go oh
nice yeah this is oh I can't see it now
hold on this is the
uh the mother plant that was much
vigorous than the others and that's
that's the width of the the leaves these
leaves are wider than my lady friends
that shriveled up there you know that
yeah these are what I would call in
between yeah this was typical Mexican
looking weed in the background are cone
flowers eonia eonia good medicine yes
it's great medicine um oh wow I can page
Sue
these I was do an aerial photo Down On
It Up close yeah that's cool to see you
can see if they meet up or don't meet up
the eonia serations add blueberries back
there to your blackberries something
okay now I see how this is working okay
I'm gonna open another file and find
um this is the first week in November
when I brought them back the four female
clones that I'm I was grooming to be
mothers and there'll be plenty of um
clones able to come off these this was
at the beginning of November but I'm
going to show you a pH photo from two
days ago and
uh I took two of the bulbs out so
there's only four bulbs because they're
just growing too much for one gallon
pots I took them out of the pots three
weeks ago and trimmed one inch off the
root ball put them back in with build a
soil 3.0 fresh yeah and they love that
but it's just making them grow faster
yeah um I don't need them bigger I need
them in your
hands yeah keep the lights right and
touching
them it's about the best you can do and
keep cutting off the tops high above
them the light oh yeah yeah I
mean so let's see
let them get all root bound all kinds of
things you can do all right you if you
ever got time mag you got to come to one
of the events that Matt and the guys put
on dude it'd be
awesome we'll get him there one year yep
all right so
there's what they look like now well a
week ago the little guy in the little
girl in the middle I hope it's a girl
that's how broad the Le are oh
interesting
H yeah but the the mothers two of them
are very kind of yellowish green they're
all in the exact same soil and these two
are deep green and huge and because I I
pruned them all back when I did the uh
root pruning too they just have tons of
little fresh man this plant right here
could probably create 40 clones right
now without even I I am terrified of
root pruning that's one thing I I like
I've tried it a few times and really
really like chewed up the the big main
tap route didn't know what I was doing
after that I was like I'm not cutting
out Ro this is how the leaves the actual
width of them yeah and that's the one
yellow look at the stock it's the size
of my index finger yeah and that's only
since
September and these are all clones of
each other these are all clones off that
mother yep and that one's just not
liking the soil for whatever reason yeah
or the light or something something yeah
identical soil build of soil 3.0 um is
is the mom directly in the center or
more in the center than the other ones
cuz you know with H&amp;L some of his hazes
I think the am it it doesn't like that
direct light it likes to be on like the
outskirts it's kind of weird the
mother's long gone that from the Six
Original plants I seated her with the
last
and but I took clones off her before I
seated her and these are her clones
these are her babies so these are
identical plants to the mother
genetically got but I don't know why
phenotypically the way they're growing
they look slightly different but that's
why cannabis is a [ __ ] sometimes
because that's the the more the more you
grow clones of each other the more you
grow clones in volume you'll see that
happen all the time it's like and and
it's it's what we run into when making
feminite seeds too you can have you know
20 clones of the same thing spray all of
them to reverse the same exact way and
eight of them will reverse and 12 of
them won't that happens very very
commonly okay
here's this is the little clone box this
is from this is from September and
that's what they all look I did it looks
like here one two three four five like
six clones
Yeah
couple I gave to satva and others and I
kept the four of these and these These
are the big plants we just looked at so
each of them is a potential mother you
know easy for
cloning there you go a nice little clone
Dome I didn't fill it because a nice one
though never seen one looked like that
only had like nine branches um and I
didn't want to
take away too much from her because I
was planning on seeding her within the
next week or two after that so I could
get at least six to eight weeks of um
seeds maturing yeah I didn't want to do
all this work and end up with a bunch of
unmature immature um seeds but anyway
and we've been talking about releasing
some of these seeds right um on the site
or through the Discord somehow making
them available to
people so we'll see how that goes I I
think it I think there'll be big
interest in it I just hope credit card
processing goes back up soon that's
really yeah really you know you don't
have credit card processing oh it just
went down this last week oh it's the
same one most see people use and uh yeah
they went out for everyone all right
here I'm going to show you
no [ __ ]
sorry it's all
good
well you I
know just I can always edit I know it's
a lot of
editing you got leave that one in there
that's that's that's
comedy leaving the edit
yeah true all
right hey uh do you think do you think
Rob Clark's a a he more heavier partyer
than you madjack you think he parties
harder than
you oh
yeah this is just you want you need to
open those first and then you link to
that I know I just opened can you see
one I just opened
what can you see the one I just opened
no no you have to reshow the file
yeah okay In fairness I I did just drop
this on him last second as far as like
him sharing the file so well we used it
a year and a half ago but I don't
remember it from them yeah
fortunately it's all good dude all right
that's the female that yielded the seeds
okay there we go and
this this is what she looked up close
she was just starting the flower you can
see just a little
bit just starting and these are two
males or are they let me see that's the
female I think this is the other female
that SAA ended
getting and they're sitting on top of
a 100 gallon tank yeah it held 12 one
gallon one cubic foot bags so it was
kind of expensive but I had two of those
and those yeah that's expensive for seed
making they created these monsters but I
I set these out every day in the Sun and
and until it got to the point where we
were going to get some cold rain in um
late September in New Mexico so then I
just brought him
in but they're narrow narrow enough
leaves definitely
yeah you know what's interesting is
there's a lot of uh similar looks too
with that and blueberry like EJ's
blueberry which also has some Mexican in
it supposedly it's better knows yeah DJ
Short was us in
Mexican you know I won't tell the whole
story but um I introduced Rob Clark to a
friend of mine that owned land in the
Ozarks about
1978 and 79 and they were going to do
something there and I can't comment
comment on it because I don't really
know yeah he he they sent me a photo or
two of the area and it looked like man
swamp I bet yeah fuing Ozarks that's
crazy yeah what in the hell would you
even do in the Ozarks it's from Chicago
and he bought a bunch of from us um he
gave an ounce of madj to MC Jagger at a
party in Chicago oh
yeah Fame never heard about it but you
know he it had our sticker on the side
and everything yeah so that was fun
that's
sick okay well anyway you've seen a
little bit of you can't use these photos
anyway so no they're going to go up so
here's the test results from December
4th um you they're in
that oh Chuck where'd you go I don't
know maybe his
internet so oh he's on a phone
this
is these are the results of my sample I
I put in okay from from that female that
two- foot female yeah not my
girlfriend's and I will share the screen
here IV number two and it was a little
bit different it was 6.7% THC yeah and
and also the tarpine profile compared to
the other one is different so that's how
that corroborated that there's more than
one load from Jerome from
6465 involved in this she stopped
smoking in
19 um 85 sorry she stopped smoking in 85
because she was pregnant with her her
daughter and that's when she put the
seeds in the safe in 85 so they came
from 84
85 but now when I got this test done it
showed that
yeah there's definitely two strains or
varieties at least if not three
yeah I'm interested to see now that I'm
growing one of the seeds to see um I
have to get it to flowering and I don't
know how to do that actually under the
lights unless I get the mothers to you
and then I can just use the lights I can
turn it to yeah that makes sense light
dep and yeah just so I can get a couple
flowers and then I can have them tested
and see how they compare to this yeah I
wonder I wonder if the the THC Remains
the Same a lot of people that that are
newer to cannabis think that THC is and
all be all like that that go shopping at
dispens you know number one was
something like 12% yeah or 14% And it
was mindboggling po yeah I I saw a woman
walk out of a bathroom after two toes
into a table do a front flip knock all
the drinks over the table
cancer and we went in the bathroom my
best friend and I and two ladies and we
we got caught by the head dancer and we
had to leave the room but they finished
the maybe they had three toes but she
she couldn't even
walk that would suck trying to dance
after
that we were sitting there they went
right past us and into the table
and yeah I just mainly wanted to point
out that um L THC isn't the end all be
all this is more of a breeding tool
something something to have U the
building block exactly it's the it's the
beautiful Turing that that's what I
can't the aroma of these plants now is
right back to the 80s I mean it's like
someone just took me to an early Garden
it's so it's this just beautiful Aroma I
don't know what to compare it to but
it's definitely high in the lemon limey
um tpol leine side yeah and I need to
ask SATA because he loved this that's
his favorite that
those
trinal penal and lemon and lemon yeah
lemine um he looks for those because
they were all their their effects are up
yeah he he only up weed he said and his
Cambell lumbo is definitely up for um
man when after about an hour after I've
taken it I just want to do something
dance um fix entic weed my car whatever
you know clean the house yeah kind of
reminds me of the coke days yeah I was
like I know what else does that else it
does that brings it up except it's it's
a more of a dreamy Edge than
now when I'm cleaning the house it's
more like nice yeah I bet I bet so we're
going to try to make these available
asap for everyone and uh see how it goes
yeah I'm pretty stoked on it I'm stoked
to see people's results with them um
yeah is there anything else you wanted
to cover well just yeah go ahead CH yeah
go ahead I just I wanted to ask you this
because I'll probably never get another
chance so uh I don't know if you even be
[ __ ] see these dude it's the beaver
uh Beaver brand do you
know uh Rob Clark gave a bunch of these
out to us said I don't didn't know if
you knew anything about these they're
basically the lab
quit
well there was a brief
period no it was after I grew um you
know Sam skunkman Dave Watson he
collects lab
he collected collected and I sent him
madag labels but when we got five loads
of of 500 kilos a th000 pound we got
5,000 pound loads from Mexico in 1984
roughly and the first one we got had
labels on every 25 pound cellophane
wrapped and we were like what the [ __ ]
and it turns out that the guys it was
meant for were in California but they
didn't pay in from the last load so they
gave that load to us oh
interesting cool there was loose labels
too and I sent some of those to
Amsterdam to um Dave and he was very
happy to get them there he was him on IC
mag in his media collection yeah if it's
still there you can see his label
collection he has he had a hundred
different labels I think you know that
he just passed away last week
yeah and the
uh one was they weren't beavers they
were they were they weren't skunks
either the raccoons there were raccoons
in a wagon yeah I remember seeing those
on the on the icy mag a load of weed in
the back of the wagon and there's
another label too I can't think of it
right now but I sent I did I knew he
loved them so I sent them to Amsterdam
so cool I still never been over there
Rob Clark invited me every year because
he would go to Amsterdam for Christmas
but I just um last time I was there was
1969 and that Wow first place at Club
par Paradisio in Adam I tried to smoke
hash I didn't smoke cigarettes so I
couldn't I took a hidden cough Gad and
some guy came up and he had a shoe box
full of Turkish weed for
$15 and I looked at it and I just went
no thanks but I did buy a a sugar cube
size chunk of hash and I I brought it
back to the
US I didn't smoke it till the um few
months later my first two joints I
bought in
1966 from the only hippie in our Chicago
Suburban high school and he um I stashed
him for two years I I was still not
quite sure if I wanted to smoke them yet
so I really didn't get high till 196
so that probably would have been
Colombian yeah something Colombian I
don't know in Chicago then yeah I don't
know 66
well my my grandfather was getting weed
from Mexican or Mexican brick weed from
down there I guess around that time so
uh and he's in up Northern Kentucky so
it could be possible probably right it's
not too too far from Chicago I'd say
it's more likely Mexican than it is
Columbia
just because the Columbo connection I
think came after Mexico Mexico was
sending weed in the 40s to the US okay
people were sneaking it in and that's
when that
whole deal the the freaky movies about
you know it'll make women get raped and
just silly stuff um what was the name of
that famous movie Reaper Madness is that
what you're talking Madness yeah that
was the 30s 40s wasn't it yeah yeah
there yeah Reaper was in inner cities
definitely and probably out west in the
Hills too because you could just hop on
a horse and ride across the border back
then there was no yeah that's a good
point there was no walls or fences even
you know yeah and if they if if you had
to prove you're an American they' just
ask you and if you could speak English
say yeah I'm from Tucson they'd say
okay when I started going to Jamaica all
I had to have is a uh birth certificate
and I had my original birth certificate
but it was almost tattered from folding
so many times and oh I bet but that they
would accept that and um yeah and Rob
Clark met me in the grill and for two or
three days we were going to go on a seed
hunt um it didn't really ever happen
because other ex extenuating
circumstances but we had a good time
together in a
he was married then and I met his wife
who was just this really cool hippie
lady um can't remember her name right
off hand he just got remarried again I
think last time we talked to him he said
he was getting married uh or something
like that I think so he got REM y i i
see like in hash church I think or some
different interviews on YouTube I've
caught him over the last 10 years on a
couple yeah different people
interviewing
one was like an hour
long yeah he was cool we got to party
for like two or three days and fish and
a bunch of the guys H&amp;L especially and a
couple other guys brought a bunch of
good weed and uh just Happ dude he's he
was fun yeah I'm I could not keep up
with him the first time he came to see
skunk number one in our garden we hiked
him in and he was blown away he said you
growing it out of dirt and I said what
do you mean
and he said well where we grow this in
Northern California it's fluffy black
soil and ours was hard packed brown dirt
yeah that we had turned and then planted
and then watered and it compressed and
he had this little zip case when we were
in Cottonwood and he zipped it open and
he had Tai he had Colombian he had
Mexican he had all these separate little
vials with pre-made joints in them and
he one
it I took one hit off it and I was
laying on the
floor room and he smoked the whole rest
of the joint by himself I bet yeah I was
never in that League no well
he he he partied we there was one night
I think all of us maybe slept a total of
like two hours and then we got on a boat
at like 600 a.m. and fished for eight
hours and then did it again the same
night and he was just he was like the
Energizer but dude yeah that's cool my
friend from columia I saw him smokeing
ounce in a day um Jesus I've never seen
except for a Rastafarian or two um do
that just basically chain smoke all day
yeah join after join after join Chucky
Style no that's cool all right well I'm
excited to see people plant this and
cross it with various plants because
this is these are going to be all
new um hybrids yeah this is like a a
missing link for 40 years um that has a
chance now and we didn't mention this
but I'm pretty sure the reason why my
lady friend succeeded and I did in
germinating these was micro rizy because
we both use really good quality soil
that has lots of mic rizy in it and when
you do the wet paper towel method or The
Germ method there's no micro rizy
involved and it took nine days for that
one to first come up because older seed
coats are thicker yeah it was kind of in
stasis over all those 40 some years in
the safe because um was never touched
never got any human germs on
it and she pulled them out and then she
put the baggie back in
next year when I met her she gave it to
me and I was I oh my gosh a baggie
baggie that's crazy yeah that's that's
the wild part is I think the missing
link in germinating old seeds is micro
rizy you have to put it in real soil I
used build of soil 3.0 she used
something she bought on the internet
that was it said it had micro isy that's
the only thing that made it unusual it
was cheap um but it it worked
promix I don't know she I've got the
name of it somewhere because she she
kept the records
but I really like the guys that build a
soil I've gotten to know them over the
years I bought 40 bags at $3 a b $30 a
bag um in Colorado Springs two years ago
because Albuquerque had run out uh Santa
Fe to they had all run out so I drove up
to Colorado Springs to a nursery that
had like 60 bags and I bought 40 of them
wow that's a good deal you said three
$3 30 each yeah it was 122 $1,300 for um
40 bags and three and a half hour drive
those two 200 gallon ones took 12 each
12 bags Jes 30 took three and a half
each so I was I had like four left over
out of oh my God yeah that's an
expensive seed making session
yeah but the one plant was close to 12
feet tall and the other one was it was
it
was um my friend from California from
Davis it was his old seeds from old
collectors and it was aapco gold crossed
with Santa Marta gold so it was pure
sativa and it number of people smoked it
and said it's one of their favorites and
the other one was from ET who yeah he I
called it ET special he got the four
different varieties in it from he grew
up he was a hippie child he grew up in
San Francisco his parents had a poster
shop during Ashbury days that'd be
killer he grew up knowing all these
people all the people that were the
early he knew people in the bowl you
know Brotherhood of eternal love yeah he
gave me some of these seeds that were
really nice and that plant was like 8
feet tall and 8T wide
nice and it was CIA but I found three
seeds on it yeah when I manicuring it
three seeds so they're in the collection
here ready to go this year
awesome so we'll talk about how to get
this from A to B because I'd love to
bring you the Clones you said you had to
get a a bathtub installed first yes yeah
the bathtubs uh right where everything
else needs to be could it be moved I'll
it needs to be installed is what it
needs to be but yeah it's going to take
three three-ish weeks to get it done but
clly me out bro yeah get her done hey
and tiled that is not just the bathtub
though it's all got to be retied I'm
gonna have to trim these um four mother
plants them again yeah just take another
two inches off them they'll back out the
the nice easy do the clones and I've got
a I've got one of those cabinets with me
that's unassembled I'll be glad to give
you if you want for cloning cabinet oh
that'd be cool I'll check it out think
it has 20 slots uh I only use six or so
that time yeah that that that little
cloning thing like I'm used to like just
regular domes throw Pearl Light in them
[ __ ] 10 in X 20in tray and a [ __ ]
7in 6 inch dome but that looked like it
was like all proes a fan
it has has a strip of Samsung LEDs
across the top two strips yeah and it's
got a
little is that AC infiniti's product or
is that a different brand AC Infinity
beautiful and bigger one this is their
smallest one they make one little whole
I think
80 yeah yeah that looks those look nice
yeah they're nice it was only like
$50 and it was so nice I kept
I brought it I B two and one's in New
Mexico and one's here and I'll be I'll
give you the one that's here because
it's not assembled yet it's got a timer
on it so you can set the time for for
how much light you want on the Clone box
I for my friend chose what 18
hours is that I would assume sound right
or something anyway it worked very nice
in two weeks had them out of there and
into the one gallon pots yeah it looks
like it has like a temperature sensor
control in there environmental control
that was a separate little um one I
bought and just put in there yeah yeah
those are cool I'll bring all those but
if you can hurry along your yeah I shall
do my best your bathtu because
yeah people would like to get these for
this growing season coming up and in
your state I'd say probably March is
when things are happening right yeah
outdoors I think so April at the very
latest yeah well we'll work out how to
get the SE how we can get this done I
might have to just drive over with the
seeds one day and meet you and hang out
that'd be great I don't trust the
male can be squirly they're too valuable
to take that chance
yeah just there aren't any more of them
I did I will say this I did keep five of
the original seeds from my lady friend
of of the Marvel ones and they're in the
refrigerator so
good we can actually start from scratch
if we wanted to at some point cool yeah
oh yeah all right well I I shall get to
editing and have this up for Friday
really it's what time do you usually air
on on YouTube 6 P p.m uh 6 p.m Pacific
okay that'd be 7 here yeah cool you know
I have this reggae collection there's
this company called reggae collector in
Japan that advertises on discogs and I
sent them this I took two days to write
down the the name of every album I have
in 12 inch 45s small 4 and I sent them
an entire list and I haven't heard back
from them in a in a u a week so I
realized I need to call
and they're open from 7:00 my time is
when they've been open for an hour I
accidently called them about right it at
the dot and the guy who answered spoke
only Japanese last week oh no I couldn't
I couldn't tell them so I sent him a
link from like a Dropbox I use Mega
mega.nz in New Zealand and I had it all
on there so they could just click on it
and read it all the 45s I have real 45s
this small ones um have the the store I
bought them from stamped there's eight
stores in Kingston and mcrill savlamar
moay um I bought them all in like 1978
and 79 um and they're pretty collectible
yeah they used to handstamp them and
like try to write sometimes they'd write
on the top what it is just on with I've
got some of them where they stamp the
actual record on really yeah yeah on the
in with the giant Circle right next to
it you know what's funny is all those
old reggae 45s when I go through big
huge stacks of them most of the time
they look like someone used them as a
frisbe like they're they are rough they
are rough like most of mine have never
been playing played awesome and the
12inch
45s I I played them once just to see if
it was worth recording yeah to make it
digital and they're Flawless that's
awesome I'm hoping to sell this whole
collection they said if it's if you have
over hundred records they will come to
wherever you are if you know if they
read the list and that's what they want
um but you know hopefully they hit you
back soon I told them I can go as far as
Phoenix Phoenix oron I'd be glad to meet
you if you didn't want to come to my
house but I it be kind of fun to have
them show up at the house yeah yeah it
would and I'm sure there are other
people in the US that are on their team
you know because we have to be able to
evaluate the quality of it oh sure yeah
and there's there's a lot of um reggae
collectors in England too that'll come
out and do that really so if you have
any other sources of Po players please
send me a link to my not my phone yeah
yeah emails emails are the way of old
people texed everything goes back in
circles Matt I wouldn't be surprised
we're back at emailing here
soon G be hitting each other on each
other's pagers hey man I have a flip
phone still I don't have a smartphone oh
really that's probably smart I can see
the it's a 4G it's made by Kyo but it's
rubberized it's waterproof not resistant
waterproof feet you can drop it in a
creek pull it out um it's mostly used by
people in construction industry there an
orange button on the top side it's a
push to talk and it turns it into a
walkie-talkie if you have someone else
who has one and you can just talk
instantly you don't have to go through
the phone um it's really cool and it has
a browser but the browser is this big
yeah tiny little thing so I've tried
using it once for Google Maps and it was
worthless yeah it doesn't have a Cy
board you have to press three times to
get a c two one and to just do a text
it's a pain in the ass oh I bet that T9
is what it I think they call it or
something like that whatever they call
that back
then you know how you had to press three
three things or whatever to get the oh
yeah although there's a couple that have
four the
W very end there's four
choices oh he used to be really good at
that [ __ ] as a kid I don't know about
anymore well the reason I've C is I
don't want to carry and be bothered by
emails in the day when I'm emails are
for my laptop I have a laptop that hooks
up to Verizon so when I'm traveling yeah
that's okay but in my life um I like to
sit down at my laptop that's plugged
into a 24inch screen and do everything
here
um texts I don't mind if someone sends
me a text in it's text but send me a
link I have to hand copy the link onto
my here like
https write it all down yeah so if you
would send it to my email um i'
appreciate it any absolutely to the
reggy guys yeah so um any other Punk
stuff you're looking for or old ones I
got the first Black Sabbath album in
it's pristine condition oh that's cool
yeah yeah I was surprised to see the
Cockney rejects in there though I was
like oh that's real Punk I've never
heard of them oh they're punk punk
they're they're British um from Cockney
like there boys yeah they they did a lot
of the um early football anthems stuff
like that really yeah W what something
they play yesterday at the Super Bowl
something like that yeah maybe you're
just a little more
Punk maybe just a t I didn't watch the
Super Bowl I didn't watch
thats I like the olypics I like the
Olympics seeing people trying to break
the record for pole vault or something I
was a poter when I was in grade school
seventh and eighth grade God yeah no I'm
too short bamboo go to the rug store and
get poles and we tape them on every
joint and we could get those to bend
You' be I bet not like the fiberglass
poles yeah but um yeah H yeah I think I
did eight once yeah Chucky told me he
wasn't going to watch the NFL yesterday
cuz he doesn't like the clothes on the
men he likes them to be oiled up and
holding oh [ __ ] oh
yeah I was open just a jock straff and
wrestling well I you know I'm still I'm
still a young buck so I was hoping for a
nip slip or two but from what I
understand it didn't happen but no
nothing exciting happened I was [ __ ]
with um just re up potting all night or
all day and then today I was up potting
until just literally I hopped on here
with you guys so I'm [ __ ] worn out I
I have to go upstairs I have to carry
all my soil up and downstairs so
oh out
yeah oh yeah I got a [ __ ] ton of stuff
going right now dude but anyways well my
friend who helped us airdrop our hoses
2inch rubber hoses and 50 gallon 50
pound bags of blood meal and bone meal
into mad Canyon um I got together with
him a few weeks ago and two two other
people from that era up in Cottonwood we
all had breakfast together talked about
stuff he's not a he doesn't fly Much
Anymore he's four years older than I am
and he but boy the story is I bet yeah
kicking kicking pipes out of a
helicopter down a canyon we took the
airplane it's a cessa and we took the
door off and we had I was in the back
seat we took the front seat out yeah see
and I had these bags piled up with we
wrapped rope around them we mummified
them because the first time we dropped
them just with um lots of tape and stuff
the bone meal
exploded no problem but the uh blood the
bone meal when it exploded made a giant
white circle about 30 feet oh [ __ ] and
we were oh my God we when we got back to
we raced out there and cl went down in
the canyon and spread dirt over it and
stuff but um we mummified them with
cheap sisle rope so that when they hit
the most they could do is break a hole
maybe this big yeah and a little would
squirt out the side no problem we
dropped probably 600 pounds of between
300 of each and it took three flights
and I would hold I got good where I
could hold the rope and push it just at
the last minute and hold it in the air
50 pounds and and he'd say no I just
open my open my fingers
and but we lost one roll of 100 foot
roll of 2in Hose it pretty expensive we
found it two years later in a juniper
tree on the oh
no where it landed and we even hiked up
there but we never looked up in the
trees yeah thought would be on the
ground it wasn't there it's fun were you
doing this all in your robe up in the in
the plane did you have your robe on
while you're dropping them out the back
no that our
future thought that we would do a movie
or a book and um that was fun my first
wife made all those costumes she used to
make costumes for
bands and stuff so she made those long
robes and we became the Wizards of the
rim yep yeah that those those are what
attracted me to the story was seeing
these pictures of these guys in Wizard
robes I also hired a guy from a
local photo shop in camera shop in
Phoenix that we got to know we brought
him in for three days and he shot 30
rolls of 35 millimeter oh wow fil he's
the one that took a lot of those photos
and he we took him up in the dark and
and drove out the like four miles out
the 4wheel drive Trail so he didn't know
exactly even where we were yeah and and
that that wasn't really necessary but we
were you know just being smart case he
got busted or something he was GNA
develop these photos at the company he
worked at and you
know that's that's great stuff it was
fun well Chuck where do you live now in
Michigan yes sir I'm originally from
Kentucky though I went to cazo college
for a while I'm not too far from
kalamazo maybe uh I'm up by uh kind of
out on the outskirts of Battle
Creek okay in the country yeah it's
great dude uh I've I moved up here uh
for my old lady to do some school and
stuff uh and then of course uh I wanted
to grow weed legally so here we
are you know I was Kentucky still uh
they just went medical last year so
uh it's kind of great to be able to do
you I didn't hear you sorry oh New
Mexico went legal last April for
recreational hell yeah yeah yeah I mean
you know you could probably speak on
this better than anybody I'm going to do
my thing no matter where but uh not
having to and you mentioned your friend
uh talking about how she was on the roof
still kind of hiding out and still had a
shocked from you know years before when
I moved up here it would freak me out
just my plants I had a couple plants out
outside or when I was smoking dude uh it
would freak me out a little bit still
for a good solid like 6 months every
time a car i' tell her get out get
out you know I don't know it's silly but
and I I've given away all I mean like
those giant plants in from New Mexico
two years ago I've slowly but surely
given away all of that I did trade a
little bit to a friend who's a distiller
and makes his own whiskey and wine and
stuff and um but yeah it's it's just fun
I mean no one's after us or it's just I
love it I didn't think I'd see it in my
lifetime hly no really I mean [ __ ]
long time it took well a com aomin like
easy access to good genetics like
through the guys and the Discord and
stuff uh and then like even equipment
like uh like you ever showing earlier
stuff like that now it's like the best
time to be a young dude or anyone really
in in starting to grow and get into it
you know there's there's still good
stuff about it look up head grower on
Instagram have you did you check that
Matt yet I can't remember yeah he's um
got a beautiful Greenhouse his
father-in-law goes by the name budo budo
and they're coming I know who that is
they're coming up with or they already
have come out with that as a brand budo
and they've got labels made and uh
his um head grower he was interviewed by
James La loud loud right yeah yeah James
loud about call him something different
yeah about five interviews ago and he he
looks like he's straight from India he
probably has hair down to his knees and
he wraps it all around and it's all on
top you know like the sados wear their
hair yeah and he's got a beard and
wow he looks like he just came from
India is it is isn't budger friends with
uh CSI
too there's buo there's yeah
budo is that's someone different than
bud budler is different than budo okay
budo um for years was um on IC mag under
a different name yeah and I haven't met
them
but my friend from Davis he comes to the
party in New Mexico every year and by
the way Chucky if you want to come to
New Mexico for Labor Day weekend um last
year we had seven states represented and
and Germany and Monaco and we had a
total of 20 people um from seven
different states and they're all the
youngest grower there was 45 and they
all been growing for years and they all
get they could they brought some of
their best and and when they leave they
leave it for me and I in turn then take
it back to Arizona and or in New Mexico
just give it all away yeah and um one of
the guys is from Chicago he and his wife
drive all the way from Chicago they've
come every year for four years now
that's cool they bring the bong and the
bong is active from 7 in the morning
till midnight in The Green Room
one's testing each others and oh well
you should try this and it's really fun
and I take them on little four-wheel
drive um excursions in the area up to
we're 12 miles from Colorado border so
there's several passes that go through
to Colorado into really remote areas and
we go to um Trinidad which is the first
town in southern Southeastern they have
30 Rex stores in a town of 7,000 people
because it's closest to Texas H that
makes sense and but now that New
Mexico's legal and they're popping up
like weekly um they've lost I bet
they've lost 10 of their stores already
in Trinidad I'm sure yeah because all
you have to do is drive across from New
Me from El Paso and there's 10
stores yeah that's big and you can buy
two ounces a day in that's in Colorado
the limits one a day per store in New
Mexico you can buy 2 ounces at once go
out the door come back in and 10 minutes
later buy two more ounces and you could
literally buy two pounds from one store
by just going back and forth in the day
into it because they don't keep they
don't take a photo of your license they
don't keep records um only if you're a
medical patient then you have a limit
but if you're a Rec wck patient it's so
weird they don't have so they're sucking
all the
sales from Colorado man big time well
they uh just here they just literally
went from in when I moved up here you
could go in and buy 2.5 oun walk out
come in but now they got it to where you
just they have to re it's a separate uh
uh receipt or you know a different order
so but you could stand there now though
and literally just get as much as you
want it's kind of crazy actually wow wow
I mean there might be some kind of limit
but I mean I've went in there and got
more than needed you know what I mean so
uh I don't know so I've never been to an
arbor but it's the boulder or Berkeley
of Michigan it's always been kind of the
activist place and I'll bet some of the
early weed that I had when I was at C
theoo came from an arbor well that's
where we uh had that little party with
it wasn't too far from there actually uh
you know you know uh St the lake was uh
St Clair Lake s St Clair that we
right for any particular fish type of
fish yeah a bunch of stuff Walla there's
uh small small mouth is while we were
there of course there's large mouth and
some other [ __ ] uh but a yellow perch do
what well Pike right I think so yeah I'm
not real familiar with those particulars
fish but we were there for Smallmouth
for sure cool
wow all right wow that's cool yep all
right gentlemen I think we have enough
to wrap up okay and I'll talk with you
in the next few days yeah you will and
find out how to um get the siege to you
within the next week let's say okay
sound good cool right take care I'll
talk to you soon peace brothers all
right peace see
you want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link treat or description below our
merch site is officially live we have
all sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies
to sort you out and shipping is super
fast and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope Hope you
join our Union of breeders and Growers
come check it out