welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
cannabis strain history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
hello everyone welcome to the breed of
Syndicate my name is thousand fold and I
am not your usual host
I'm a breed of Syndicate member and
collaborator and today I have the unique
privilege of welcoming Matt Riot onto
his own show
it's an episode that many of The
Syndicate members have been requesting
and it's going to be all about Matt
I've come up with some questions and
I've also collected questions from other
Syndicate members
uh Welcome Matt to the show
thank you how you doing today Matt all
right thank you for uh doing this it's a
it's an awkward one like we've talked
about you know to have an interview of
me on our own show and I've kind of put
it off for a long time like yours uh
just because I don't I don't like taming
the pool with me much but because people
were asking so much I you know
what are you gonna do
I think it's a really important show and
it's an absolute honor for me and I also
was thinking this like it's such a matte
punk rock move to be like let's just get
this guy who no one knows who has no
cloud in the scene to interview me
I mean you're good I I you know we did
the we did one for people who don't know
we did one
um not really an interview but it kind
of you know you filled with questions in
a um a chat form on our our patreon
Discord and it was really really good
like I felt really comfortable so I
thought this is perfect perfect timing
um yeah
yeah I almost forgot about that okay
yeah yeah that's true
well we're going to jump right into it
and we're going to begin just with your
breeding work
um so the first questions I guess are
how did you get into breeding at all to
begin with
so I you know like
my interest in strength well first off
my dad was a grower and a dealer so like
I've been around the black market as it
were my whole life whole life entire
life he was in and out of prison so I
didn't live with him but you know it
means my dad
and uh
you know I got into plants by him at a
young age but there was no like passion
for it at all like I got into other kind
of drugs as a kid and much later on
um
one of my buddies had moved to Alaska he
got in trouble in high school and had to
move to Alaska my buddy Josh shout out
to Josh
um and he came back like After High
School a few years later and we were all
hanging out at my house and he was the
only one that was really like a heavy
Stoner and not a heavy Other Drug user
you know he was just a stoner for the
most part of the time and he bring over
this dank and I'm like ah what is this
and I was smoking stuff that was just
trashing my brain like just getting
these songs and he had the story that he
brought about this string called Matt
nuska Valley [ __ ] and when he
told it to me he told it to me as Matt
and he's got Valley Thunder [ __ ] which
is kind of cool because later on I
realized he actually had his [ __ ]
together and knew exactly what it was
called and where it was from and all
that and he was just a kid at the time
so that's when I started getting an
interest in actual strains and he
brought over High Times and showed me
what White Rhino was White Widow you
know some of that started the bud of
what people would call White Rhino or
white widow would show up in our groups
you know and like we get to smoke that
and I'm not sure if it really was you
know but
um that's kind of how my interesting
started when was this 2000
2000 it would have been right after high
school so 2000 2001 somewhere in there
when we started getting those strains
and right after that I mean it took a
few a few years after medical started in
California it took a few years before in
our city there would be places that
would kind of pop up as collectives
right so it took I was trying to
remember it would be about 2004 2003
before they started really popping up in
Oildale in like the what's known as like
the ghetto ghetto of Bakersfield this
place called Oildale
um predominantly Caucasian and a lot of
meth use in that part yeah and that's
where the collectives were though you
had to roll through there to go there
because that's where the cops weren't
going right and it had to be outside of
City Limits and that place is outside of
technical city limits
and I remember going in there and they
had this is the first time I saw the
list of medical strains that were in
California they had Scentsy star it's
Urban Poison
blueberry
um what else is on there white rhino
White Widow and maybe one more
um I can't remember what else skunk won
or you know it wasn't OG Kush at the
time yet
um but yeah that's what was considered
medical strains in California so for a
long time I just assumed if it wasn't on
that list it probably wasn't medical
right because that's like our
understanding of medical and California
medical at the time was very very
minimal
um it wasn't until I moved to San Diego
where I had more money because I was
working at Sony doing uh their their
vital help and support web development
stuff
and I had extra money and I could
I could grow like I got lights and I
started growing doing [ __ ] on my own
buying seeds and experimenting a little
bit you know
um
that's that's mainly when I started
getting into strains but I really didn't
know what I was doing it was like anyone
that just jumps into the c community at
first right like you're trying to feel
your way through
um so I was going to High Times you know
the typical skunk magazine and looking
at who was in there what strains are
cool and of course High Times you what I
didn't know at the time was like you
open high times and it's one long ad
one long almost paid ad in many cases
yeah but a lot of them look like
interviews and articles but a lot of
them are paid ads in ways where like
people do parties for High Times and
High Times will reward them with an
article right or an interview but in a
way it is an exchange and if you don't
do those exchanges you're not in it I
didn't understand all that so I thought
that these people were the best at it
you know like they were the ones every
time in High Times and that's when I
started like buying seeds from BC Bud
Depot places like that
and uh
in doing that I had collected you know a
large portion of strains they spent a
lot of money at first on like DJ Short
Stuff
um what else Dutch Passion DNA a lot of
DNA about us about so much DNA stuff
um
so at this point were you buying these
seeds to just to grow with or had you
already been thinking about breeding no
at this point I was just buying to grow
and and I was already I mean I wasn't
thinking about braiding in the sense of
breeding right at that point I was
thinking of making more seeds for myself
because this is getting very expensive
you know yeah totally but I was more
into keeping clones because in
California that's what I understood was
clones so I was more into popping seeds
to get clones to trade clones at that
point
um because like that's that was kind of
the hip thing to do in California SoCal
was like have clones you got this rare
clone oh no you know but I but most of
them weren't buying seeds most of those
guys knew nothing about buying seeds
from Amsterdam or England none of them
did all the guys that had clones none of
them would do that so I was the one guy
in our group that was buying seeds from
outside the United States and bringing
those like selecting a cut and and
passing those around so it was weird for
someone to pop up with all these strains
and I was such a noob I went on
Craigslist
and posted that I was wanting to trade
here's my clones wanna trade like that's
pretty newbie right like but at the time
like
it was such a wild west of the medical
cannabis community that it wasn't as
crazy as doing it like
where people are killing people on
Craigslist type [ __ ] you know like it's
still pretty early on
um yeah and that's where I met this dude
Doug
and he was the main inspiration for
breeding uh understanding breeding but
he was like my introduction into who is
a man named James Gonzalez who also is
known as James hodd how did those two
Crews kind of uh you know work out for
you so yeah so when I met James uh that
was through Doug and Doug and James were
doing a partnership in a grow and I
brought over a bunch of my shitty I will
say shitty selections of BC Bud Depot
and like all these like Spanish strains
that I thought were Dutch right like the
Cincy stuff all the DJ Short Stuff which
a lot of it didn't pop but what did was
there and he was willing to trade me for
some of the rarest clones in California
at the time and I didn't know that like
I had no clue how rare these things were
at the time it's only in retrospect that
I understood what he gave me like he had
like fire oh G he had a very good cut of
Apollo 13 which at the time was super
rare
um
what else was there
I mean he had the Hog's Breath because
where I first saw that anyways that he
had he had a whole library of
amazingness oh chemd he had Kim D like
long before anybody else he had Kim D
wow okay and um like that's super early
on for Kim d That's he would have been
writing the the crew that got it via
like sub-rop or those guys from crazy
composer he would have been right in
that line
um
and so like he was working on a grow
with James and that's how I met James
and James owned unified collective in
San Diego
and after meeting James I would go in
there all the time like just you know
like go in there kick it talk breeding
talk about my interests and passions uh
buy clones from him he had an amazing um
he hadn't made he had a big jar of seeds
of bubbleberry just a massive jar
sitting up on the front counter and you
could reach in grab it for you know
it wasn't even that much money he was
charging I think it was like a dollar
seed or whatever at the time you can
grab it and give him 20. you didn't care
um and it was amazing amazing
bubbleberry we used that in some lines
too and he had clones um what did he
have he had the peht which is the potent
evolved hybrid type from Neville or
early on
um it became known as Ed Rosenthal
superbud later and he had a really early
cut of that which just phenomenal
um he had Northern Lights of course it
didn't say five one two none of that
just said Northern Lights
um
Williams Wonder he had that the MLB
Williams Wonder Major League Major
League bud
um there was a lot more in that crew but
I would go in so and we would stop
reading
how old were you
I was probably 25 26 27 somewhere in
there I was older and my I was I wasn't
a young man at that time by my
by my idea of life experience I in my
mind I got into this very late
um right because a lot of people around
me were older but there were a lot of
people around me that were younger too
and
um with the urban Growers society that
was kind of inspired by James because
what we were seeing and this is
something that annoyed him and he kind
of passed off onto me and he worked on
his Collective with this on his own and
he helped me with mine and it was the
idea was all these collectives are
majorly benefiting
from medical patients like real ones
like terminally ill patients
and charging them full price
for it like they're opening these like
the people that are opening these
collectives are doing this on the basis
of medical the people that were opening
these were not terminally ill for the
most part not not like
any sort of medical anything they were
doing it for recreational which for me
is fine but if you're doing it off the
backs of medical patients and these
terminally ill patients if we really
believe what we're doing and we really
believe in the passion for this plant
and its medical abilities there is no
reason we should be charging them that
in my mind there's no like not 10 bucks
not 20 bucks not 30 bucks if you care
and you can afford it you should be
putting your own livelihood into this
and at the time because the whole the
way it was it just felt like it needed a
big pushback so that's what that was
about and James and me put together you
know I think it got up to like 43 people
in the community that were all growing
that were all giving away their weed if
they're meta for totally ill patients
you know that that decision that moment
I mean did one of the questions I had
for you was you know
what other influences kind of had an
impact on some of these decisions and
yeah what what do you think drove you to
this kind of like more communal spirit
because that's to me that seems rare in
that so part of part of that was my best
friend's mom who raised me died of
pancreatic cancer and that was when I
was
20.
no 21 I was 21 yeah and she raised me
like that was like my mom as much as my
grandma or my mom that must have been
devastating it was horrible and um and
he had died a year before that my best
friend so it was is like double and oh
my God we and no one was taking care of
her so
and she wasn't a pot smoker but she had
when she was young so she was willing to
try cannabis
um during those brief months it was six
months until she passed and I was trying
to find any strain that would help her
any anything you know like it was all
black market [ __ ] at the time so it was
like I was trying to find anything and I
saw that like it would help her get out
of bed come to the table she was able to
eat dinner and hold it down for a little
bit you know like it just gave her just
that much comfort so that was part of it
like that was part of that passion like
that burning feeling in my stomach that
something had to be done for these
people because I saw it firsthand and it
was someone I loved deeply you know um
the other thing was in communal spirit
I moved out when I was like 11 of my
parents house my actual parents house
and moved in with my grandma my grandma
was awesome she raised me great but like
other people raised me too I was kind of
a street kid at that point I just did
whatever I want like I guess you caught
latchkey kid or whatever
um
and in doing so like I would go to punk
rock shows and play shows and in that
Community where we were at it was a very
small community here and that's where I
got that Community spirit I had older
dudes taking care of me like whether we
were fighting and making sure I didn't
get hurt
um uh whether I was drinking too much
and they're telling me [ __ ] you grow up
you know like you can't do that you know
or whatever it was it was a communal
Spirit we all kind of raised each other
in a weird way and and what their life
what happened in their lives deeply
affected my lives and I brought that
everywhere with me I try to go because I
see the powering in in numbers in the
power and people and the power in love
as stupid as that sounds for me to say
it really is true like the power I mean
I completely love and I can't see it in
The Syndicate yeah for sure like we care
about each other and it's very
passionate and like but we also trust
each other very deeply and inherently
and we have reasons to you know like
we've the actions built that but yeah
that's what that that's what that idea
came from
that's cool that's that's such an
amazing set of stories
um
so I guess the next
to me the next logical thing to go on to
is what would you consider your first
real breeding project
my first real braiding project where I
was breeding breeding
I was doing a few things at once at two
different locations
um I had
see if the Clockwork cut when I was
first given it it wasn't called
Clockwork Orange it didn't really have a
name
um yeah I got a few different stories
from Doug but the one I believe because
I don't even like telling the other one
because it's just so asinine what I
believe was that he went to a coffee
shop in Amsterdam and he ordered some
Alaskan ice Bud and in that bud there
was like two seeds and he brought that
home
grew them and one of the plants looked
like a monster it looked like like we
weren't used to a lot of mutations at
the time and seen crazy Leaf mutations
and whatnot and this thing it had what
we called the crinkle Leaf a lot of
people associate that like OG KB or the
legend cut
those weren't big cuts at the time so we
wouldn't associate it with any of that
so we called it the crinkle cut
well
when I saw that plant it was it was
super potent
um
it was
it was just super Frosty super dank but
those leaves bothered me and I looked at
it I thought No One's Gonna grow this
this isn't a clone anyone's going to
want to pass they're going to think it's
diseased whatever so in my mind I needed
to put that into seed and shake out that
tray because I Knew by this time that it
could be done that you could shake out
trades
and I tried for a good year and a half I
did some VX ones and stuff and I
couldn't do it accurately I could not
find a potent version without that
crinkle Leaf formation so at the time in
my head I thought it was a link trait As
I understood it and stopped I stopped
with the best selection that I had from
those seeds of my own and that's what
became the Clockwork Orange cut and it
was just a crinkly Fino from those seeds
um yeah
what else did you do with that cut
um let's see what else do we do with
Clockwork we used it over the years
um it became our Flagship strain a lot
of people assumed it was orangey
because
of the name obviously but like
um wait I don't have it up here anymore
but like I'm a big Clockwork Orange fan
and like it's one of my favorite movies
and in our city there's not a lot of
citrus in that movie no no
but there's a lot of Ultraviolence in
that movie and that's the way that cut
made me feel better violent dude like
you up yeah like you got a bat to your
legs
um yeah it was just super potent so
that's that's why I named it that but a
lot of people expected that and it took
a long time to explain that
um but we used it over the years on
almost everything we did s ones we did
several iterations of s1s that would
always sell out every time we had it
um the bx1 we sold those which was the
uh Clockworks the Neville skunk to the
Clockwork
um and the Neville skunk was in Devil's
hay skunk one
um what else do we do
I don't know I mean we even we did A
Clockwork Cola that was kind of cool
that was the AK-47 RC Cola cut which
never gets brought up it was an old cut
passed around on skunk magazine
um we did Clockwork cookies which was
absolutely amazing for its time but like
looking back like who gives a [ __ ] about
a copper of cookies right like of all
the other things I've done with it like
he cares about that and we did the
Clockwork piff which was a big one and
someone is still taking through
generations right now which was the um
the uh doggy style d73 piff
um from New York City
cross to a reverse Clockwork Orange
uh yeah we we crossed it to everything
we could that we had at the time slammed
it to everything like most pollen
Checkers would you know
um yeah after after
I think it was about 12 years I decided
I don't even think I decided to let it
go I think what happened was that was
with the mobs in the tissue culture
thing if I remember correctly
oh yes it was it was and um a certain
company a certain company
um killed it and that's how I lost it
there are s1s out there
um
but I just decided to kind of move on
not because of anything about the strain
but I'd worked with it for so long
and one of my best friends CSI gave me
good advice to never tie yourself to one
clone
because when you do that you don't have
if someone if someone starts working it
you'll feel super passionate about it
and then what do you move to you're
you're tied to one thing and you're kind
of one trick pony at that point so yeah
it's best to you know not just tie
yourself to one thing and have that be
your whole try to make it a legacy
because legacies aren't created they're
that's something you have nothing to do
with you know what I mean like really
your actions but not how everybody
perceives you
you got to be like Voldemort right he's
got like these horcruxes it's
distributed yeah in the last the horcrux
is mad like that I use that a lot in
life that that analogy to a lot of
things because like it's a it's a great
analogy you know from it's interesting
from a systems perspective like it
it makes sense to have one big
dependency is extremely fragile it makes
for an extremely fragile system so it
totally makes sense yeah I mean
diversify
yeah and the other thing I was going to
say as well is that like you mentioned I
think uh you have friends who are still
working with the S1
um yeah
is that chronzo with bronzo has the
Clockwork pith Denali has the Clockwork
S1 cut and he has a bunch of the oldest
ones
um the S ones are out there in the
community they're getting very old
though I don't know how well they pop
for people now
um yeah but yeah no like everybody who's
smoked in Ollie's cut is mind blown that
it's as strong as chemd and you know has
a kind of no ceiling High that chemd has
but it's totally different
yeah
yeah no very cool yeah thanks for
telling us about that so yeah you
mentioned a couple of other projects of
viewers from earlier on I'm not sure
like what order to go into sure but you
know you have banana juice Stuff
strawberry cream Bubba kushwork diesel
work yep so let's see where did I start
um in that order
I want to say banana would probably come
first
yeah so my banana Obsession came from a
banana OG cut from Doug that was one of
the cuts that he gave me and I remember
growing it in Fire OG next to each other
and being like oh okay I see I see the
direct relation between these two they
look identical they have totally
different terp profiles because they're
separate parents whatever the Diablo
OG's parent was is more spicy peppery
whatever the
um banana OG's parents was was more
skunk 20 right so I was interested in it
and banana was super rare at the time no
like the the overgrown days had already
passed right because we were about 2008
2009 by the time I start really working
into bananas so by this by this point
banana had come gone and left
so it was novel it was unique and not a
lot of people were using it and
um yeah so I was like this I'm gonna use
this [ __ ] so I got it used it and was
making beautiful beautiful banana cuts
that were super potent banana seed lines
that were super potent uh the most
interesting of me was a cut that came by
a guy named his online name was Hugo
himself
and he was a very good friend of mine
over the years like he started off on my
Forum early and we Envy became like
we're still closed to this day me and
him and his wife and um he brought me up
into Platinum banana OG cut and that was
what it was called in his area Platinum
banana OG and this thing was just fire
above fire
um banana OG was originally a seed line
called ogier's cush and it was from
Oregon kid and that's where people were
finding these banana Pinos and over the
years these got called banana OG that
would pop up out of these ogiers Kush
packs and so it wasn't it wasn't a seed
line called banana OG early on it was
actually called ogir's Kush but there
were many people popping these seeds and
that's how these different banana lines
were amount banana cuts and this one was
just so fire so I was like oh I got an s
on this I have got to S1 this
so I was
ver during these years I was not as
versed on pollen control
and I had previously done a Bubba S1 run
right before this
and when I made these Platinum banana
ogs ones I think the cut that I selected
it was an outlier and I've seen a few
other cuts that were like this over the
years from the same seed line and I have
a feeling that there was Remnant banana
OG or I'm sorry uh Bubba S1 reverse
pollen in the room and that was what
made the Platinum banana OG s ones was
the Bubba and not the banana OG it did
reverse but I think the pollen might
have been unviable and they're still
pollen floating pollen floating in the
room of the um Bubba because I was just
not I was not versed on that at all what
I was doing and it made for some of the
most beautiful
like
Expressions I've still seen today super
black
Frosty as anything and just so Banana
artificial Laffy Taffy banana came out
of that line and that line got me a lot
of like a claim because it was really
good but again I don't look at it as
like my [ __ ] because it was Oregon kids
really and uh random Bubba pollen you
know
what was like the um the effects of that
like
um so all that stuff tended to have the
OG Kush High which is
very hard to explain but it is a
full-bodied like cerebral High which
what most people consider a super hybrid
at the time like medically it would be
like considered hybrid type high but
really it's just a full bodied full
complex High to OG kashas and it's why
it's so special and and this carried
that on very well Bubba Kush
um when grown well could do the same
thing it has a very similar type High
and um combining the two just really
really nailed it for its time I will say
for its time it was special to me and I
think it was special to a few people and
that's one of the ones that I actually
am proud of is that work but again like
after years and years of doing this you
you learn
to kind of drop any kind of ego from it
and pride in what you have done
but more pride in what those have done
before you and that you were able to put
out
if that makes sense yeah I can I can
understand that at some point it kind of
becomes its own thing in the world and
has its own life outside of your voice
right yeah right like and I'm proud that
thing exists but it's not much more than
anything that like I kind of went you
know and that's how allbreeding is in my
mind
I mean okay in terms of like the
timeline
the this this work comes also before the
the great tissue culture debacle yeah oh
yeah yeah that was fairly recent in my
mind like five years ago or less maybe
four or three or four I didn't realize
yeah that was real reason yeah
yeah okay okay so
um right before that I had the bubble
work and the bubble work was it was just
like I got a hold of the Bubba Kush
clone um I want to say that was from ape
PNC people's nursery care shout out to
ape he's he's a lot of my stuff like the
strawberry cream cut came from him
um he had a great great he had the best
I will say the best clone Nursery
up until that point I had ever seen with
the best provenance and I will say to
date it is the best Nursery that ever
existed with the best provenance because
that dude did his research the cuts that
he got like 90 of the time were accurate
which is way hard and during that era
way harder you know
um he was legit dude's still around and
he's still legit so yeah I
he's not often talked about by breeders
from California
um he worked a swerve early on and was
an early owner of Cali Connection if I
remember correctly one of his first
partners and was responsible for you
know a lot of swerves cuts but he
doesn't get named much so I figured I'd
bring him up now because like he's even
who lumpy sent me down the cookies crew
stuff really early on before anyone else
had it and that Apes the one who brought
it down from lumpy you know so I want to
give him a lot of props here he's a cool
dude
that's cool yeah thanks for sharing that
so the Bubba the bubble work yeah it was
it was
not new for cannabis because a lot of
people like Oregon kid and all them had
done bubble work before me CSI all of
them had done public work before me but
it was years later and as we know in
cannabis things are cyclical and by that
time no one was making Bubba S1 CSI had
kind of dropped from the scene
completely to do his I think he was
doing his own thing cropping and stuff
and not really working online not
dealing with online business so
um that was a time in the market where I
could come in and make s1s do Femme work
and it was a time when people really
really did not like what I was doing
they're feminizing and still today
people don't like it for the most part
okay we're gonna I have a question
specifically on on firms and reversals
later on but I did want to ask a
tangential question here which is okay
as an outsider I find it interesting
because why Bubba Kush doesn't get named
uh as much as OG and the 911 you know is
that because it's kind of like under the
umbrella of OG or kind of in the shadow
of OG Bubba doesn't seem to get its own
mention a lot even though there's a lot
of work done with it you know I don't
know why there's like the OG Obsession
about the Bubba
um Bubba Kush is half OG Kush as as it's
been told as I I would agree you can
smell OG cushion it if you grow it
certain ways
um I think it's always lived in the
shadow of OG
um it's a lot I don't want to say it's
harder to grow because it's really easy
to grow Bubba it's very hard to cure and
dry Bubba to get it to be right and a
lot of people lose Bubba in the Cure
um a lot of people say Bubba's Booth
because of it you know and it doesn't
have the super rounded high that OG Kush
has or the THC percentage OG has most
importantly okay but it is potent and it
does have a similar quality of high I
should say maybe not as Skyrocket potent
as some of OG's will get you but it does
have a similar quality high and yeah
though I think probably the THC
percentage because that's so important
to people in California and collectives
is probably what keeps Bubba from
kicking up to the top because it's
usually like 18 to 20 you know
it vidges really slowly as well yes yeah
it's a it's more squat than OG but it's
still kind of depending on how you grow
it you can make that thing grow lanky
but it is slower to grow than OG
um it's not as slow as things like Urkel
but it has a reputation for being slow
so okay
okay no that's super cool
um
if you're happy with the you know that
account of your Bubba work uh shall we
move on to the strawberry cream yeah
yeah so strawberry cream I got from
again apnc and I didn't know much about
it for years
um other than first I didn't even know
if it was the same one from CBF didn't
know
um I by the time I got it it was right
when ape was closing up and he had
closed shop we lost contact at the very
like I gotten it
a month later he was gone and we lost
contact so
I didn't know much about it I spent a
lot of years trying to figure it out and
I was convinced it was an herb beer
because it grew exactly like that plant
Earth beer and I started growing these
and it smelled like it
but what I found out was that it came
from Strawberry Cough which Strawberry
Cough is supposed to be strawberry
because of a string called Strawberry
Fields And we haven't identified that so
I have some suspicions from breeding
stuff in my head what it might be
um but the story goes that uh CBF got
some s1s of Strawberry Cough from
goldeneyes
and goldeneyes was a female on overgrow
um she worked with black Russians some
shishka Berry stuff and uh and the
strawberry cough and when he popped him
he got some males and females which
probably means pollen contamination
which makes sense she was doing a lot at
that time in a small space
and um he crossed those two together and
that's what started strawberry cream
and this line was so resonance
so mold resistant
so strawberry and it bred so strawberry
and everything it touched was just bag
appeal to the to the nines turpwise
amazing The Hive was a lot a lot less
than you would say like an OG kosher
Bubba Kush it wasn't the same kind of
high it was so much more mild I would
put it in the silver Pearl era category
of Highs real quality so it always took
away my anxiety which I like you know it
took the edge off but it wouldn't like
lay me out to where I felt like I was
always saying something stupid you know
I didn't get stupid mouth and I like
that I hate having stupid mouth and you
know what I'm talking about where like
you perceive yourself as saying
something stupid like if everything
comes out of your mouth and you're like
did I see something stupid like I think
I kind of weird and this is not that
kind of weed
um but yeah bag of Peel to the nines and
cedarberry Farms stepped off the forums
for a while
so it was really hard to hunt down and
during that time I did a lot of work
with it um I bx1ed it and I crossed it
to
um Johnny Blaze from Legend seeds uh red
from Legend seeds I believe made Johnny
Blaze and that was in Neville's Haze DJ
Short Blueberry mail
um the reason I did that was because in
the room I had Santa Cruz Blue Dream
right next to it and I noticed that
these two cuts and I used to have
side-by-side pictures of all this stuff
but and I probably do somewhere on a
hard drive but side by side they looked
almost identical it was very hard to
tell the difference of them in flower
and because of that I was like oh Blue
Dream will be the perfect outcross if if
I want to make a regular seed line and
again I go back to bx1 making regular
seed lines of this stuff because I had
caught so much Flack for feminized seeds
over the years by this point we're
talking 2000
9 2010 2011.
of my strawberry work because it's about
I always put it about a three year
period because that's how long it takes
to do serious work on lines for me to go
from
popping them
to testing and running them
to possible bx1 if I'm happy or to
finding out that I screwed up you know
so about three years to figure out
whether I'm doing good with the line or
not to the point where I can sell it and
and get it out there in mass and the
testers have gotten back to me if I use
testers
um
uh where was I at those three years I
was doing strawberry
brain fart
strawberry cream and you forget what
you're doing
yeah
um I don't know
uh the strawberry oh yeah CBF was was
gone during those years in 2009 2011.
and um so it's not like I could reach
out to him and talk to him so I was
releasing this work
um the Johnny Blaze was the outcross in
it because the Blue Dream stuff
and
it was just it was phenomenal everybody
that got it liked it and I also had
during these years I had an East Coast
Sour Diesel strawberry cream from CBF in
seed that I had traded for by this point
and I had already
um during the first two years I had
crossed East Coast Sour Diesel
um the
the choco cut I called it but it was
just east coast Sour Diesel
um across that to a strawberry cream bx1
mail
and I did not like the results but I
popped
CBS East Coast Sour Diesel strawberry
cream and immediately everything was
fire every last seed from that line was
a keeper and so I used a mail from that
line in further work which also made
more strawberry work and some of the
most famous work that came from the East
Coast Sour Diesel strawberry cream or
the stuff that came most popular was the
strawberry switchblade
and again that's uh yes in that
strawberry vein it is my
when people ask about my strawberry work
and what I think I liked best I would
say the strawberry switchblade only
because it had the potency of the sour
it had the looks and smell of strawberry
cream and it had the color of one of the
parents which was a double purple Doja
I'm sorry it was double red dojo
which was a hybrid a double purple Doja
and it was just blood red beautiful
magenta with blood red leaves it was it
was gorgeous and that trait passed on
pretty regularly in the the strawberry
switchblade so it was like the best of
all three parents constantly lining up
well
but like realistically cvf's line was so
good and so true breeding for whatever
reason I don't know if he had taken it
generations and that's what I got or it
just light the allows lined up perfectly
but for whatever reason his line was so
true breeding to anything I touched with
it was fire whether it was strawberry
switchblade
um what else the the the uh what I call
it strawberry champagne which was the
Clockwork cookies cut cross to um
across to the east coast of our diesel
strawberry cream
uh there was a there was I didn't hit a
lot of stuff during that because I was
trying to do more selective breeding and
only hitting certain females that I
liked a lot with it
but in doing that I came out with some
stuff that I really loved and that
strawberry switchblade was for sure one
and it still goes around and cuts all
over the place
um yeah
yeah I think that the strawberry
switchblade has some mythological status
within the Syndicate and it gets talked
about quite a bit it was in magazines a
lot too which like some of the stuff
like Clockwork Orange and strawberry
switchblade my Platinum banana OG my
bubble work and what we'll talk about
with the diesel work we're all featured
in Skunk magazine heavily
so a lot of that can I think contributed
to its mythological status more than me
or more than the strain necessarily
earned on its own because
back then in print was like
every every grower and Breeder's goal
you've got to get in High Times you've
got to get in skunked that's your goal I
mean that's when you made it you know
like that was the thing and and for me
by the time it was like those years 2010
2011 I had already figured out the High
Times okay right and I had already been
told by Danny Danko at this point if you
do not work with us you will never make
it and I will guarantee it and at that
point I was like
[ __ ] you watch me watch me watch me
[ __ ] watch me so I worked with
skunk magazine extensively and that was
because of the Rev and like we were
homies and had I not been homies maybe
that wouldn't have happened but thank
goodness I thank goodness we were and
it's crazy to think that like that era
of print media
kind of gatekeeping all this stuff
wasn't that long ago no no it wasn't and
and up until the the Marlies bought High
Times I think
it was still the standard that if you
did not it's it's I mean maybe not as
much now
but up until fairly recently if you did
not advertise in high times you didn't
make it and for the most part if you do
advertise in High Times now as a breeder
you still make it
yeah so it's still it's still looked at
as a respectable source yeah and I'm
still blacklisted so that's never gonna
happen
and I don't want it to I wouldn't want
it to anyway you know what I mean like
at this point yeah
yeah I feel like it's definitely lost a
lot of um it's shine with with other
people in the community as well so yeah
even and not to run to it you know
you did mention the G's will work oh
yeah maybe that's a good segue into the
diesel work so the diesel I got really
early on from Bodhi my friend body and I
haven't talked about him as much yet
with how much of an influence he was on
my clone work
um but he was a major major reason I had
any of the rare clones from the online
community that I did
um
and I guess I could talk about this part
now because it is relevant
um yeah during these years people were
locking me out of cuts specifically
uh well if people don't know what that
means it means in the cut circles
because there was still only a few clone
circles that that really had the cuts
the rare cuts and stuff like that
when we were trading
people would tell Bodhi or other
breeders yeah you could have this but
make sure Matt Wright doesn't get it
and it was because I was doing fem work
and they did not want their clones S1
they did they thought that if I asked
one of their clones the value would drop
in their clones the trade value would be
worthless and other people would grow it
and their cropping would be hurt like
their their money in their pocket would
be hurt from cropping so don't give this
to Matt Riot and in some in some
respects I get that like I get why they
thought that way at least in my mind if
they understood breeding they would
understand how hard it is to get the
same representation of the same exact
cut like that you know like
it's asinine but I get why they thought
that and a lot of times it would be
people that I liked and that were my
friends
doing it to me
and for people I considered friends
doing it to me and locking me out of
cuts because they wanted to protect
their money and then it would be that
awkward conversation where like yo bro
like
I get that you're you know you're a
breeder and that it's not fair and it's
kind of [ __ ] and it looks like I don't
like you but
I don't want you feminizing my cut and
your words not good enough
yeah I never ever did it never feminized
anyone's anything that had any
stipulations on anything but that never
mattered it never mattered because the
potential was there if it's in my hands
for them to be scared
and
yeah that was a big big problem like as
far as sourcing cuts it was very hard
like I had to and I think it's a lot of
why I I started this historian side of
stuff and tried to get into anthropology
was because I had to go to sources to
get the cuts because it wasn't just like
when people locked me out that I would
just be like oh [ __ ] because I mean I
feel like I should sign post here for
everyone that you were one of the I
guess pioneers of fem work reversals
yeah yeah I mean yeah I guess like in in
in American breeding
there weren't a lot of us doing it there
was OG rascal
me CSI had done some work I believe Hyde
had done some work Chimera had done some
work uh and there were others but like
as far as doing it big with a big name
big name you know like one of the the
top 50 breeders that were putting seeds
out big there are only a few of us and
nobody wanted to mess with Rascal
because he was a gangster like he looked
like a gangster like a gang banger like
no he's gonna mess with Rascals except
me like an [ __ ] we're friends now so
yeah but like he didn't catch the Flack
that I did but I caught so much [ __ ] and
it didn't help because of my attitude
because like when people would do that
to me I'd be like okay [ __ ] you I'm
gonna go to the source because you're
making up roles on a clone that you have
no rights to go to I'm gonna find out
who the source is and I'm gonna go get
it like yeah that's how this works and
it didn't always work you know but a lot
of times it did and that caused a lot of
derision
and delusion you know maybe like from my
perspective like it caused some ego
melting and hatred because all of a
sudden the cut that they locked out
locked me out of I got and I could pass
freely because I went to the source of
the person I said did you lock people
out of this cut and 99 time they'd be
like fun I don't care who has that cut I
you know 99 of the time when you get to
the source that's exactly how the source
feels
you know it's more people down the line
that have no reason no permission to
lock people out of cuts
where that pops up
yeah
yeah and did you set the stage
you're becoming an easy target as well
unfortunately yeah my mouth didn't help
because I'm very like people didn't know
me know I you know like they see me on
the breeder Syndicate now and me and not
so talking and I try to be I like I'm I
got a mouth like on there but I'm a very
reserved version of who I used to be and
that's some from growing up and
experience right but I was very
reactionary and I still can be I don't
have much of an edit button but like
when people challenge me
it's not it's like I I've always had
that in my life I was a short kid like a
punk rock kid in an oil Community like
oil worker Community when that's not
acceptable like I've always had these
challenges and people challenge me I
push back hard and that doesn't bode
well I mean do that to [ __ ] a
thousand people online over you know two
decades yeah people are gonna get super
pissed you know like it doesn't do well
and jesel was a cut from chem dog's crew
and it was one of the ones that didn't
have any stipulations so I got it from
Podi
and it was one of these cuts when I got
it I realized holy [ __ ] this is skunky
this is so skunky
and during those years people weren't
really looking for skunky stuff I mean
some people were but it wasn't like all
the rage roadkill skunk that people try
to die for now right wasn't that I want
to ask at this point as well like did it
have much of a reputation at this point
at all it would it was in the Canna
Bible so people knew what it was that
was the other thing like with clones
like anything that made it in the Canna
Bible from Jason King got legendary
status so this was in there as one of
the examples of the cam chem dog family
but for whatever reason because it
wasn't called chem or dog and it wasn't
sour or something it flew under the red
radar is diesel which meant G
geez diesel like G is the chem dog's
name like we call him G so G's diesel
but it was called Gisele and just
because the name I think it wasn't a
catchy name it just never caught on but
it was passed to a few people and those
few people were great Growers and loved
it because they saw all the skunkiness
in it and uh it's a hard grow it's not
super Frosty it can harm
so a lot of people dropped it it's paid
no attention to it and over the years
that's kind of what happened and so I
started working with it and the lines
that I worked with it were super
resinous and super Frosty and super
skunky and they you know those gotten
skunk magazine some of those got a claim
um we did
jesel crossed to a West Coast dog Suge
Knight oh gbx1
we did
uh what else we did jesel cross to
something called chemdog D DNL diesel
Northern Lights from um JJ New York
um we did
I mean diesel Blue Bonnet later on uh
diesel East Coast our diesel strawberry
cream
um I don't think we ever did A Clockwork
diesel Unfortunately they were never in
the room flowering at the same time to
do it so pretty much jesel is like
become one of my loves of my life like I
love the smoke of it I love how it
breeds it is what I believe is a great
representation of a of a of a super
skunk from Neville
um yeah
and I mean on that note and I you can
cut this out if you don't want people to
know this here but there you have been
dropping hence that you might be
returning to some diesel work with CSI
oh yeah yeah I know that's fine um yeah
uh CSI I tried convincing him for years
so he had the cut in 2006 and totally
forgot that he ever had the cut but like
it's on his clone list you know of stuff
he had so yeah he just forgot what was
like and stuff and he didn't even
remember he ran it didn't care
um but I kept bugging him for years I'm
like dude you have got to try this cut
like it's so good and so skunky and you
know I mean like he gets told that by
hundreds of people all the time about
Cuts so it took me three years and years
and then he finally you know gave it a
whirl
and he's like holy [ __ ] this thing's
great like he's not a diesel fan in the
first place he doesn't like sour
um he doesn't like smoking sour not a
fan of how it breeds really and so the
fact that it was more like of a diesel
Lee type cut than it is by terp wise
more of a diesel type cut and looks than
it would be considered a chem type cut
and in smell it's not chemi necessarily
it's skunky but not like burnt tennis
ball rubber
um he just didn't seem to have much
interest but he got it he's like oh my
God this is great and so we are doing a
uh an S ones and a full reverse line
together of jesel to bring it back and
to bring some big time diesel reverse
back and and cry babies done some work
with it as well and like I you know I
passed the cut to people in our crew to
like bitter and cry babies got it now
and denali's got it people people are
running it I think um Pax running it too
uh Santa Cruz goat farm so a lot of
people are going to be doing a lot of
diesel stuff and and and that's all
because of Bodhi really I mean he kept
the cut forever and passed it to me and
without Bodhi doing that I never would
have had it and all these other people
wouldn't have had it so shout out to
Bodie
I think it's really cool that you get to
return to it um again and yeah I'm so
like life was a bit like that I don't
know if you feel this way but I feel
like life sometimes works in spirals you
know you kind of come back but it's not
exactly the same but you're still back
in the same place it feels like yeah
um and it makes me feel happy that like
because a lot of people don't know but
me and CSI we've been very good friends
for
five or six years now I think really
close friends but before that we weren't
like we weren't enemies but we just
didn't really talk much I would try to
poke in and um this is one of those
stories where it's like a almost like a
teaching regret story right
and it's one that I tell to newcomers
when they make similar mistakes
and
I when I first heard about CSI and saw
what he was doing I was enamored with
his breeding skill and his knowledge and
his ability to to hunt down history and
and even on his old Forum posts which
were around back then to look at
watching him just level people that
would try to scam they would try to just
be corrupt he would level them and he
would level them with their own words
and let them do it and just ask like two
two word questions and let them
disassemble themselves in front of
everyone it was It's Magic to watch and
he can still do it but he does it less
you know because of the the Flack that I
caught the fact that he caught you know
like people were [ __ ] nuts when you
do this to him
um but I would love to go dig through
the Forum archives with some of those
and they're not most of them aren't even
there anymore which sucks yeah all those
forms are gone you know most of them but
um
yeah so like I I I I wasn't enamored
with his work so I sent him a message
early on and I was like hey
I am good friends with blank and it was
someone I thought that he was super
close with and that I knew had gotten
clones of CSI stuff
so I assume that they must be super
close I know that this dude's gone to
his house and he says they're good
friends so I'm like okay I'm gonna name
drop this person that's a good friend of
mine that I've done like I've given him
money I've given it like his truck was
getting impounded so I [ __ ] let him
stick his name on a collab and sell
seats to a seed bank and give him all
the seeds for free to keep the money you
know like things like this big things
and I assume this was a very good friend
of mine so I said this is a mutual
friend
I would love to speak to you more dude I
really really into what you do well
this is where that moral of the story
comes in
always be careful how you introduce
yourself to people because you never
know what their real impression is of
the person you're name dropping if you
name drop a person and you only have one
chance to make a first impression
and if you name drop someone
that is bad and a scammer and all that
[ __ ]
no one's going to talk to you and for 10
years he stayed away from me because of
that because he's super careful like he
doesn't want to invite chaos in his life
and I don't blame him like he's a busy
man you know like yeah yeah he doesn't
do the Forum drama stuff anymore at all
like it's just not in his life so
he was very hesitant to talk to me so
several years ago Emerald cup we had a
booth next to each other I was working
with NCGA and splitting a booth and I I
noticed CSI was next to me
at the booth so and he never really
responded to my message and I knew he
had seen it
and through other people I had heard
that he didn't like what I had to say
about like males and Femme seeds and
stuff like that which and in the end he
was correct he was absolutely correct
and I was a noob so
he had all these other Notions about me
so I went up and I shook his hand said
hi I'm Matt all right seeds uh really
appreciate you and your work and what
you do for cannabis nice to meet you
that was it
walked away sat down because I knew he
was busy like I was busy people were
coming up grabbing seeds you don't want
to take too much of people's time from
there this is where they make the most
money in the year
and so after that
um he messaged me or he emailed me
or no it was on Instagram
he messaged me and he's like hey here's
my number hit me up
and so we talked and he explained you
know some of the preconceived notions
and he said he really respected that
despite all of that that I still came up
shook his hand like a man and and walked
and didn't like say hey why didn't you
do this why didn't you email me back you
know like any petty [ __ ] it was just
like man dude hey dude I respect you and
that's that
Annie appreciated that and then we
started talking and and
quickly became best of friends I mean
you know we're very close friends our
group's big we're all best friends in
our group but yeah I mean like uh we're
very close and he's one of the people I
would do anything for and and it was
weird because I went from going from
someone who is an absolute fanboy
Fanboy extreme like because there's no
one bad in my mind still there's no one
better in cannabis that's ever done it
not Rob Clark not anyone no offense to
Rob because I think he's a god of
cannabis but as far as breeding work
showing it having all of it
and and the amount of reading work the
real reading work that's gone in and the
years of it no one's done it more no one
does it better no one's done it more
precise and to go from that to being
someone's close friend and a man and men
and he mentors me in ways like teaches
me things and I get to learn from him
that is a mind-blowing process that's
happened to me a few times over the
years and despite all of the
opinions online about me and the the
magnitude of [ __ ] disgust that it
seems like people have I've been
fortunate to work with who I have
yeah and we will come back to some of
those events as well but yeah that your
friendship with uh CSI sounds really
special yeah and the same goes for Bodhi
too because like I hold body in the same
esteem
and he was probably the main inspiration
for what I made and what I worked with
early on even before we were close
friends I just saw what he was doing and
I thought God that guy's so cool he's
doing something no one else is doing
what like purple kush double purple Doja
this isn't what the Dutch people are
working with this is freaking cool you
know it's beautiful and so he was a
major inspiration for my early work and
it was the same kind of deal we became
friends and slowly became very close and
over the years definitely a mentor in my
life a hundred thousand percent of
Mentor in my life not just with breeding
but in life how to deal with people how
things how we should look at things his
perspective is so unique he's a
beautiful human so yeah
no really cool and yeah those two
figures especially definitely strike me
even as someone who's this far away
um as being really special spirits and
you know in the community and it's crazy
but also you know they they both
recognize you and what you were doing so
that's that's really that's a that's
that's a trip and it's an honor and and
to this day I still have trouble
wondering you better believe it dude
yeah I just it's hard to understand why
you know what I mean but it's I I
nonetheless I respect them and I thank
them you know like it's not like uh
something I've ever overlooked
very sweet
all right so we've got a big one coming
up which is about all your blueberry
work and and how you encountered it to
begin with and why you decided to keep
going with it
um we did talk about the fact that you
might still want to have a dedicated
blueberry episode later on so maybe this
can be like a miniaturized version oh
yeah yeah
so
blueberry the first blueberry I ever
smoked was from this I won't say his
name because this is like we were doing
a lot of other dirt
um this dude in town and it was after
the medical clubs it all opened up so
this is like 2000
three or four and he was bringing in
kilos and kilos and kilos of [ __ ] um
blueberry and it was phenomenal
blueberry it wasn't
it had a blueberry flavor that would
Zing the tip of your tongue it's so hard
to describe but it wasn't as blueberry
smelling as what I love in blueberry but
the fact that it was seeing the tip of
your tongue and had a little bit of a
blueberry taste was just phenomenal and
it had a great high so it was one of the
ones that I smoked very early on that I
was chasing so when I started buying
seeds and learning that you could import
seeds from Amsterdam and and actually
the beginning of that seed buying
experience the UK became very big it was
the end of importing seeds from
Amsterdam direct and when the UKC Bank
started popping up and one of those
early ones was like seed Madness uh UK
seed Madness dot Co dot UK not sure if
they're still around and if they are I'm
not sure that that's the same URL that
that's what it was during those years
they were great people nice people not
scammers and maybe a few years after
that like the attitude popped up but
during the years these years a lot of
the the seed banks were on forums and
they were small British forums where
people bought their seeds yeah and
they're not around anymore to look at
none of them hot pant
um canazon kinetics
Cali
something rather it was a bunch of
little tiny seed banks like that
and
um that's where I I went to seed
madness.co.uk and that's where I bought
all of my DJ Short Stuff
and I remember I had gotten a big bonus
at Sony
and I spent a large chunk all at once on
blueberry
flow
very flow
f13 Coco Kush
Vanna Luna
I think those are the main four there
might be an oh great Crush
those are the big five that I bought
early on those five
um and Dougie had a clone of blue velvet
Blue Heaven and blue moonshine
so I got to run all this stuff and
after spending a
ridiculous amount of money so much money
on blueberry
I didn't find much that I liked I found
one can I get you to pause there I just
wanted to ask you like how why were you
interested in those lines to begin with
because of that that zing on my tongue
that was like literally like it was
unique I never had that and it was like
wow that's what blueberry is I'd like to
I'd like to
check that out again
and um that that was literally it it
wasn't even the blueberry smelling
cannabis that I had quite experienced
yet that it like been like oh my God I'm
obsessed but the other thing was DJ
shorts books
and pictures they were the most
beautiful plants I had ever seen in my
life they were
beautiful purple the leaves were purple
purple how they grew was real unique
um they were just so unique looking that
it was just it stood out in cannabis so
much during this era there weren't
really a lot of purples you received
there was um not a lot of purple Urkel
work online some
you know but um there was a purples are
kind of rare so things like double
purple Doja popping up and sputting it
one and two those kind of purples were
and blackberry stuff or rare hard to get
and people were chasing it and it was
being kind of gate kept and DJ shorts
work was another way to get into purples
and breed with purples but we all knew
it would take selection because we had
heard you know that maybe you won't find
stuff you like in every pack of DJ
shorts the the major problem I had was
the seed germination rate was very very
very low like we're talking
four or five packs of one thing didn't
pop at all
and I germ rate by this time my germ my
germ skills at this time were really
good
and hog was helping me pop these and his
were excellent so it was like I can look
back and say probably not my fault this
time and later on normal to have that
kind of
germ rate even for that time barely yeah
like the seeds that were the seeds you
would get in packs dude during that time
probably even now I don't know I don't
buy other readers packs they were they
were a lot of immature seeds in here
like not just small because small seeds
can be mature right small seeds come
from all plants
um some plants have only small seeds
small black ones with no tiger stripes
some are big fat gray and modeled with
no tiger stripes
tiger stripe for people that don't know
are is a thin layer of sheath that can
come off the skin like the husk if
people don't if people don't know that
so like it's not necessarily A
descriptor of maturity but it's a great
way to tell and look you know it looks
better when they're all like that but
the seeds you would get in these packs
were just totally immature no wait or
heft to them you could squish them pop
them in your fingers with no problem you
know things like that so that was common
but five packs that was not common and
what ended up happening later on was
they had to replace every single DJ
Short pack that they sold during this
era
for every customer because everyone was
having these germ raids so yeah it
wasn't just me at this time it ended up
being a big deal for the UK buyers
um
let's see what else was there
so we went through those I found two
flow clones that I kept and I had an f13
that I really liked I thought was
beautiful but no blueberries there was
nothing that was that was Hardcore
blueberry nothing that was berry berry
berry smelling and that was
disappointing to me because I thought
like
that if you go through enough of his
stuff you're gonna find berry berry
berry right like
I was excited I spent a lot of money and
what I got I got a few beautiful plants
I got some that smelled like floral
incense floral incense and slight Berry
like the slightest
you know but by this time I had already
smelled the Dabney blue cut a little bit
which was blueberry muffins a little bit
and I thought this is phenomenal I know
there's better I know there's better and
shortly after this a guy named estartes
from um a form called pop pimp gave me
DJ's mom cut of blueberry
and this one had more Berry to it and
was purple and beautiful and it can
breed Berry plants not often but it can
right
um
so yeah that's when we started the berry
Obsession in the berry work eventually I
was working at a place called BCC
as their Master grower that's what the
title they gave me master grower at
their Collective
um to grow and they were letting me
breed at the time and someone brought in
a
a jar of Bud and when I got this bud I
smelled it and smelled like peanut
butter it was amazing like like Jiffy
sweet creamy peanut butter and I was
like oh my God and it had seeds in it I
was like dude uh to that I was like dude
let me pick these seeds out and he's
like yeah just be careful you pick them
out and I was like okay cool so I
uncarefully picked them out destroyed
the bud
because that's what you have to do to
get all the good seats you know destroy
the [ __ ] out of the bud and I asked I
was like hey dude what is this he said
um because it was being sold to
Strawberry Cough and I knew that he
changed that [ __ ] all the time like I'll
collected I said so what is this he said
we only had a strawberry cough but they
brought it in his blueberry but it
doesn't smell like blueberry I was like
okay so I made a mental note you know
they said it was blueberry whatever this
is peanut butter this is great so I took
those Seeds home
popped them
and out came the most purple
blueberry
smelling tasting plants I have ever seen
by this up to this point it was it
looked like what What DJ Short had shown
as Oregon purple tie back in the day
and it was purple blueberry zero peanut
butter in it now some of the other
parents were Frosty peanut butter
Afghani type plants with this one
had more what people would consider
narrow Leaf traits
and just purple blueberry and this is
the cut that I originally named right
Berry and that I used for all of my
earliest blueberry work
so this was like in in a way you the
very first moment of actually having
what you were looking for this is the
moment where I was like this is the one
with the taste and smell of blueberry in
the looks but what it didn't have was
any sort of potency but what it did have
was medical relevance what I noticed so
when I realized this I was out of all my
weed and I had a tooth abscess at the
time and I was like in tears and pain
right I didn't have dental insurance
nothing I was in pain it was my very
first tooth abscess I didn't know what
was going on but I felt like I was dying
and I S and you know like ibuprofen
wasn't helping nothing so I smoked some
Riot bear because it was all I had and I
expected nothing to happen it was just
what I had
and immediately the nerve pain went away
from that tooth
and I wasn't in pain and I was like holy
[ __ ] this is magical you know amazing
and then when other people I saw I
started giving it to other people in the
um in the crew that had like back pains
nerve pains and they were experiencing
the same thing they were getting
anti-anxiety effects and complete relief
from nerve pain but they didn't they
didn't get high and at all so they could
go to work do stuff
my goal was to make some potency with
this so I crossed it into an OG Kush
Pakistani to trolley regular sea lion
that I had for a male side and I made
what became called Riot Barry OG
and from there I selected oh actually I
didn't even select this one a dude named
Jeremiah selected a clone from that and
he gave it back to me and that's what I
used in my lines is Riot Barry OG and
almost every line from from
um
2008 on or no I'm sorry 2010 on would be
with the riot Berry OG
yeah strict yeah so would this be like
your first generation I guess of
blueberry work it would be because I did
release the riot Berry seeds originally
right yeah I guess separately true and I
think I even gave out a bunch of the bad
seeds that I had left is there a
shitload of seeds in that jar so I even
gave those seeds out but uh I I made
f2s of original Riot Berry so what I
thought would be a blueberry version of
that clone in male form which I who
knows to this day if it was correct but
it made a nice Berry line so the right
Berry was the first one but Riot Barry
OG was where I was like [ __ ] slam it
out of the park this is potent enough to
be relevant Frost it to everything see
how it breeds and it was true breeding
for the blueberry tree this is where I
made things like blueberry cookies uh
which we call Cookie Berry and which is
probably my most knocked off line today
like renamed we made something called
cookie Berry diesel which was during my
uh when we were doing the day record
these diesel bx1 for the male side when
we're crossing that to everything that's
when I made the cookie Berry Diesel and
um that was crossing cookie barrier best
selection of the cookie Berry which was
the right Berry OG Berry dominant Fino
cross to Girl Scout cookies form cut
reversed in 2011 made those and then
crossed that to the original diesel bx1
which was the project following
um
um the the cookies reversal
so am I right I'm thinking as well that
you one of the earlier people to
work with cookies yeah um in 2010
cookies kind of popped up and by 2011 it
was almost a race to some people to get
it put out
um I it became a race when people found
out that I got the cut from lumpy and
was making s1s because like there
weren't many people feminizing at that
point and
um
and that they knew I was gonna put it
out pure right so first person to put
out anything cookies that I recall was a
company called can adventure and they
put out a cookies crossed to some sort
of train wreck hybrid right so
it was like I think they called it
cookie wreck well
not even two months later my reversal is
done and we're testing it like we're
already in the middle of testing by that
point and I have train wreck cross to
cookies I have cookies crossed to pretty
much everything in my room at that point
because I want to see how this unique
weird plant that people are obsessing
over parades would be the first person
to see how it raids reversed
um so I put out the cookies pure and
then not even a week later swerve from
Cali Connection put out his version of
cookies Femmes which when people
actually and and people were buying his
versus mine When people grew his out it
was just OG Kush and we're super pissed
and BC Bud Depot within a week like the
same week as mine came out put out their
version of cookies and animal cookies
because I did cookies and I almost put
out the animal cookies s ones but I but
at the last minute after I made them
someone said that I'm not allowed to so
I didn't uh NorCal I see mag thank you
for that one because uh he said I wasn't
allowed to
so I didn't but
um
yeah uh BC Bud Depot released a fake
version of animal cookies which ruined
that line and name and then they also
put out a fake version of cookies too
but like I said when this happens
people just jumped to the cheapest or
who has the biggest name but that
doesn't necessarily mean any of those
people have the Clone because they're
the ones who are advertising in High
Times and get the first sales doesn't
mean that they have the ability to get
the Clone or the morals to do it
correctly and that's what people saw but
it took almost a year you know for
people to grow these things out and see
who actually had the legit [ __ ]
and by that time in that year other
people had gotten it and were starting
to make crosses and release them with a
real cut
and what I had done with it meant
nothing you know and and by that time
when I when everybody got the cut I
didn't want my name to be associated
with it anymore so it was like I'm gonna
sink back into the Shadows that I even
use this [ __ ] you know like instead of
trying to be like nah man I was the
first that I was just like like nah you
all have it I'm good it was the same way
with like working with gelato 33 you
know I was the first one of the first
with that cut and the first to make s1s
the first to make gelato 33 with with
Skittles and [ __ ] and
which became runs and I'm like
you know I don't want anything to do
with this stuff
um but it was the reason I say that now
is because in retrospect it just became
hype stuff when I was doing it I wanted
to see what was in it because nobody
else was working with it it was unique
yeah of course yeah and so okay coming
coming back then to you a blueberry
Journey after cookie Berry
what happens after that so after cookie
Berry and the right Berry OG stuff I
lost my my right very OG mom the the
blueberry one in a um a plate I got I
got this plague of
something which probably was hplv
looking back but a plague of something
killed every mom in my room including
that from taking clones in from outside
clones and not being fastidious enough
and using the same razor blade [ __ ] like
that just being not being fastidious
because most people weren't the time if
you're if I'm being real like we didn't
know about hplv and all that [ __ ] so
that took out the mom and I was like
okay I've made the best blueberry [ __ ] I
could ever make I'm done I can move on
and that's when I moved on to Strawberry
work right
but I sold out of all of these seeds
people bought all of my seeds and during
these years
I wasn't making a lot of money so like I
was literally selling every last pack of
everything I had and because I'm not a
[ __ ] bag like I like to think I'm not I
didn't
continue to pretend I had these Cuts or
seed lines just to keep making sales
yeah so the lines were discontinued I no
longer had the cut and I was done but I
felt like I had done everything I could
with blueberry at that point
but so we jump to what I told you about
was when all of my clones got lost with
the tissue culture person who will
remain nameless because he doesn't
deserve to be named
um
when that happened I lost every clone in
my room
and I was like oh my God I need to I
need to do something new
and I had always had this long affinity
for blueberry and during those years I
hadn't smoked any and because I sold
every last seed of everything I had of
of my right burial G stuff I was like
hmm
I wonder and I remember during my
blueberry years on breed Bay there was
this dude named Lone Star and people
would talk his blueberry up all the time
like this is the most blueberry thing
I've ever had and of course my ego
during those years didn't let me like oh
really let me check out your blueberry
mine was already like [ __ ] your
blueberry I got the best one right like
I don't need his [ __ ] you know I need
his [ __ ] for I got the best one they
just don't know right
so when I lost everything I looked in my
seed collection and realized that I had
amassed a massive massive selection of
all the blueberry lines that I could
find over the years like I just
collected slowly and subconsciously was
collecting all these things so I was
looking at my seat stash what should I
pop and I was like huh I really love
blueberry and I'd like to jump back into
that and um I popped everything that I
had not every not every seat of
everything but every line right seeds of
every line and a good amount uh I could
name it but it it's just pretty much
think of every old DJ Short Line you
could possibly think of in every hybrid
that would like you know the BC hybrids
and whatnot so I went through these and
I really wasn't finding anything and one
of the lines that I'd been given was
lone Stars Blue Bonnet from Bodie had
kept him over the years
and in this line there was a female in
it that was just phenomenally blueberry
phenomenally blueberry and there's this
male
and I don't usually go by STEM rubs but
he over the years of running blueberry
even for my first experience I learned
selecting with blueberry even in females
there's a purple stripe that runs down
some of these stocks and there's certain
traits you can look for that will show
you some of the more blueberry terp
Expressions yeah if you're lucky if
you're lucky it doesn't always denote it
but it denotes it enough to where it's a
good place to start right and we all
need a starting point and that was my in
my mind that was a starting point and
there was this male in the room that
would raise its families
not like 85 80 degrees from top to
bottom and he was you know he grew
pretty big he grew fast his family is
instead when I say praying like some
people think about the top leaves
praying you know the top little sets
praying when they're happy this was
every family from the bottom angled like
this like it's raising its [ __ ] hands
straight up
and I was like wow he has the purple
stripe stalks his stem rub smells
insanely like blueberry
I'm gonna give this dude a shot
you know I'm gonna try this and see what
this male does and so I became more
hyper focused on the the male with my
females because at this time I had
masked some of my favorite females in my
collection ever right so because of all
the all the Clones getting wiped out
I had to go back and resource so during
the time I'm popping all these seeds I'm
also resourcing my whole library from
people I got it back but there was a
there's a dude that I haven't named yet
that I absolutely love that I have to
bring in at this point because he helped
me amass my library back
and this is Matt Elite from Elite
cannabis one of my best friends on Earth
um he's one of those dudes that like
really wants to remain nameless in
cannabis so he's probably gonna be
annoyed that I even mentioned him you
know but um
he's a beautiful human being and his
sourcing on cuts and him and um Dave
from Elite cannabis they're sourcing on
Cuts was phenomenal as good as me or CSI
or anyone and he held a lot of the rare
chems and day Wreckers and stuff and so
I was able to get day wrecker back
things that I worked with earlier all
the OG Cuts trying all that [ __ ] I got
back
um and the cams
and
um Bodhi Dro came he's like he wrote me
a message and he's like I heard you lost
your whole Library
I'll be up in a week that's literally
all he said I'll be up in a week and he
came up and he dropped off all these
plants he drove them up to me or drove
them down I should say to me what a
[ __ ] angel I mean like this dude is a
rock star in our community and
uh just like he is so busy and
he drove me down clones bro and CSI we
had one of our meetups for the can
Illuminati which we'll talk about later
little maybe
um and we we met up and he brought me
clones too like really rare clones so
during this blueberry work I have a mass
one of my best collections ever just be
I mean and it was only because the
community and my friends stepped up and
saw what I'd lost and knew how tragic
that would be for them and gave me those
so I was like I got a mail
let's see what he does you know with
this F with this female some of the
other selections from DJ stuff were real
interesting this round including one
from his blueberry line that came from
seeds resin lung had
um from one of the lectures DJ gave in
California at a collective so he had
kept these old seeds of flow and this
and I popped those the flow really
didn't do much the um
there was one blueberry that was
semi-blueberry smelling with a little
bit of shitty Backwater but it was blue
and it looked like every single cut from
his book that I would have ever wanted
so I had the looks
and I was wondering if this male
injecting this male into that line would
pull those blueberry dominant genes out
further that blueberry scent and we
would have a line that looked like DJs
but smelled like possibly like the blue
bonnet right so all this was done on
remembering the stories about lone Stars
the trait of the purple stalks the stem
rub and a wing and a prayer
so I went into this with that
had all the clones from my buddies
reamasked I had the selections from all
the different blueberries and we did our
first Bonnet run
and
that mail ended up being so good
it by my perspective
and by a lot of other people to be
honest like and and saying that I I had
very little to do with it like the
selection was pure luck and a little bit
of experience but the work was done by
Lone Star and Vic High who he got it
from and the blueberries he got from him
and people before him DJ Short even so
when I inherited this line
it did the work and I was just lucky
enough that I paid attention to the
traits of him raising his hand even you
know like it was kind of like I felt
like the dude spoke to me in a weird
[ __ ] up way yeah
that's how I felt from the jump I
genuinely felt that pick me was what I
word for word that's what I thought he
was saying take me and um it ended up
being
producing the best lines expressions of
lines that I have ever seen to date
consistently it consistently puts these
up
so it became the community is just
reinforcing that yeah yeah right like
and it became this thing where like
I don't know that I ever want to move on
from it and it it's it's hard because
when you find a male that is true
breeding cannabis like this and can
makes consistent stuff that is so rare
because it's so hard to select male
traits in cannabis because they look
different from females and their
expressions look different from the same
expression in a female
that
picking is such a shotgun method
that when you fight it's like you won
the lottery right it is it is a lottery
ticket it really is and it doesn't it's
not a lottery ticket in the sense of
this is going to make me money it's a
genetic lottery ticket in the sense of
how it breeds
yeah and that to me statistically the
most valuable tool right so I tried to
back him up and not only that the place
that I gave him too I said you can share
this mail with anyone
anyone who wants it can use it because I
feel like it's a valuable breeding tool
not just for injecting blueberry into
lines but it has a similar like anxiety
anti-anxiety effect and a similar pain
effect so the original Riot Berry that I
had found so this this is not just a
breeding tool it's a medical tool so I
felt like it would be very selfish of me
to sit on this and to not share it so I
gave it to a major Nursery but there it
contracted hplv and was put to sleep
so the work that exists with that male
exists
and the mail is gone the mail is gone
unfortunately
but I do have more seeds of the F1 the
original seeds and I think that
I'm hoping that he pops up enough
that he will show up again in the amount
of seeds I have the f2s I have the BX
ones and what I've noticed is in these
lines even in the hybrids whether it's
blooper skunk blue resin Kush any of
them there is a male and in The Punchy
booster as well which is how we selected
The Punchy blue stir stuff for our
newest work the all the males do this
and every single one of those males
breeds blue traits and blue turps so it
is looking like it's a link trait to at
least
it may the blueberry chirps come through
even when that trait doesn't show up but
it for sure shows up when I see that
trait
and it reads true when I see that trait
so you've got like a strong
correspondence yeah yeah correlation and
yeah causation and correlation type
thing yeah and it seems to be true
across all lines which means it's true
breeding across all lines and that's
special so I'm not as upset as I was
about losing the mail because I really
think you can go through any of these
hybrids and select that trait and find
something that will breed just as
similar as the male did for those Terps
maybe not look
but Terps effect and potency and all
that and that's the other thing that the
blue bonnet line had that mine never did
was it extreme recreational potency
um one of the cuts yesterday or yeah
someone had the blooper skunk tested
yesterday now diesel does not test hide
ever it's like 15 16
consistently in from places that are
more reliable for testing and consistent
with their testing so he hit me back and
he's like this Line's testing at 27. so
thank you whoa and I'm like wow a
blueberry that injects that kind of
potency and everything is so phenomenal
I mean we're getting results back on the
blue resin Kush that it has you know 7.5
percent total Terps five percent mercine
5.5 percent mercine in the in that one
and uh summer 3.5 Mercedes number five
percent mercine in small pops like six
seed pops
so yeah it's breathing true for a lot of
wild extreme traits so it's all it's
almost like even if I wanted to move on
because I feel so strong about its
potency it's medical relevance
I find it very hard to move on I feel a
responsibility with it even if people
don't care
even if it never makes me any money
you know because trying to resell
blueberry like I've talked about is hard
people have had experiences with DJ
shorts positive or negative so if it's
positive they're like I've already found
a good one if it's negative I've already
run blueberry why would I want to run
one that shit's boof you know that's a
lot of the attitude I get so it and it's
it's I respect it because I had that
same attitude for a long time
I think I do want to ask you about you
know what the future holds but this is
also a good time for me to ask one of
the questions I got from one of our uh
Syndicate members absolutely and it's a
hard question go ahead it's from J I
don't I've never known how to say this
guy's name jebs ziggs yeah yeah
okay Jabs exhausts if you have one
what's your favorite expression or plant
tip ever popped out of the bar Network
um so I have to say my maybe it's part
two or top three I'll give you a topic
I'll give you a top three
all for different reasons
um
the silver Pearl Blue Bonnet which we
called the cream
one because it lets the silver Pearl
come through so well with all of the
other Bonnet traits except for the berry
um my favorite expressions in that line
are the strictly silver Pearl traits
with Bonnet potency and Bonnet type High
which is pretty close to the the silver
Pearl type height real quality
anti-anxiety not a ton of um cerebral
like the dumb mouth stuff that I talk
about but um everything else so that's
one of them because I love the smell of
silver Pearl it's one of my favorites
um a second one would be Punchy blister
and that's because I've always really
enjoyed the great combination with
blueberry uh like the blueberry jam when
you tape like a picture taking grape
um jam and combining it with blueberry
jam and smelling it like Smuckers like
insane insane
mouth-watering delicious smell and grape
amplifies the blueberry and blueberry
amplifies the grape
so that's one of those ones that is just
so extreme and it's so loud
um across the board when you have a room
full of popped Punchy booster seeds it's
mostly all you're smelling in a room
even if you have like other strong cams
rog's in there that are putting off dank
smells this stuff's so loud great
blueberry with no skunky smells that is
just wild wild wow yeah it would cut
through it cuts through yeah it's crazy
so that's one for that reason and I love
the smell and taste and the potency is
screaming you know it's way up there it
has THC percents that everybody loves
and the third
out of the hybrids would be the blue
resin Kush because after seeing the test
results of the amount of nursing which
is a is something we know has as major
medical effects and the THC percentage
uh with the extracts I know it's going
to be probably one of the most medically
relevant plants that I've ever ever had
the pleasure of releasing
and because it was a project between me
and my boy resin long who I love a lot
that's my boy so yeah it's a few few
levels of of love for that and the
medical part I really do think it's
going to be the most medically
important plant that I've ever touched
and I don't know if that means that it
will be in the future and like people
will take hold of it I just know that
the potential is there for it to be that
foreign
well I had a few questions to kind of
round out this uh section on your
breeding work okay
um and I guess these are these are more
like narrow questions or more focused
questions okay
uh first one I have is what were some
notable you know quote unquote failures
or quote unquote dead ends
um in in some of your work
so um the first one was a lot of people
don't know this but like I did Auto
flower breeding feminized Auto flower
breeding really early I had no idea yeah
one of my main
um mentors in feminized seeds who taught
me well there's a few Shanti Baba was
one you taught me how to make Femme
seeds and he was resistant to it he did
not like them at the time and he let me
know that but he was also willing to
teach me which was Unreal like do you
have one of the best breeders on Earth
teaching you that was phenomenal
um also Ernesto from Buddha seed Spain
who most people don't know his name or
his company they think of big Buddha
seeds Milo but Buddha seeds it was from
Spain and a lot of people don't know
they are one of the biggest sea
companies on Earth
um but it's not because their Autoflower
work they are one of the resellers of
seeds meaning they're not resellers
they're one of the major retailers of
seeds in Spain bulk retailers
um
the only competition they had for a long
time was like a dynafim
um mimota but they were one of the first
doing it before that and they were
retelling like Greenhouse or vonas
anytime you're buying greenhouse seeds
you're actually buying seeds from
Ernesto during those eras or Nirvana or
any of those places
um and he taught me how to make femini
seeds and he taught me how he was doing
it and how he was breeding for auto
trades so I started with his work called
white dwarf
and it was a white widow crossed to I
believe a low rider number two is what
he chose or maybe is low rider number
one and he bred that in and made a very
what we considered potent Autoflower and
so I brought this to America I feminized
I reversed some of his Autoflower
uh females and we made uh
um what do we buy it with
there I think we combined it with low
rider one ourselves if I remember
correctly that was what we popped it was
low rider one or two ourselves to make
our line
uh White writer I believe we called it
which I hate the name now
it's a name it's like sounds nazi-ish or
something like white rice it really does
and that's the name of a Nazi album like
punk rock album that I didn't even know
about so like
yeah it's not my favorite anyways so it
was a great line for an auto line but
with this at the same time I was also
popping white or purple Widow from Des
Shaman seeds this is ingamar De Shaman's
company who made white widow so I
thought like for sure I was gonna get
the best purple Widow ever
what I got was an auto flowering perm
that was totally purple from birth
but because it was totally purple like
from the jump and it wasn't like
environmentally purple and it didn't
turn purple later on which is what most
purples were would turn purple later on
it was a true breeding purple I tried
breeding it into the
white Rider because it already had the
Autoflower trait which wasn't advertised
on the package ever
um
because it had that I wanted to see if I
could outcross the or like
in Cross that without bringing in the
hermit trait
and I had the line purple writer
and it was all her rooms
it was all herbs it's [ __ ] all
autoflowering but it's all Herms and I
took it to F3 and released it like
wasted time on this [ __ ] and um yeah so
that was that was my worst line without
any doubts I made an auto flowering
true reading harm without any doubts
that was the worst line but there's
other lines like I have a green crack
bx1 that I made using the Platinum
banana OG the X1 is the outcross and
um with green crack crossed in twice and
it was so far away from Green Crack by
the bx1 that I just stopped
and just cut the line killed it
I gave it out to friends
um but yeah it just didn't release it
because it was so bad
it wasn't bad it was a great line but
like people would have liked it it was
Platinum banana OG though like it was
not green crack so the name was a total
misnomer I probably could have changed
the name and sold it
but I was so mad that it was so far away
from where I wanted it to be that I was
just like screw it
bird seed gave it to the bird you know
I've realistically like I found some of
the packs left but Chacha got a lot of
them
um
there are so many times like that though
a lot of times it was the BX ones
because interesting I would try to make
a bx1 line
and not go bx2 or bx3 because to me
there's no point in taking stuff that
far you should be able to take it to be
X1 lock in a single trait and that said
if you do it correctly and have a male
breeding line and I always wanted to
make a male breeding line
as opposed to the s1s during a long
period because it just got so much [ __ ]
for feminine seeds and everybody [ __ ]
hated me it was locking me out of cuts
because I was making Femme seeds so I
started doing the bx1 thing you know
well that's a good segue because
the next question is actually from
Shawnee yeah and it is on it is about
Femmes it is about reversals because as
you've alluded to you know that it was
quite a controversial thing for you to
be doing at the time yeah so the
question I guess from Shawnee is kind of
like taking a slightly different stance
and it's like looking back from where we
are now
how did reversals eventually become the
norm and if you could go back you know
how would you explain to someone that
had that you know more conservative
mentality of why reversals are useful
wow okay so how did it become the norm
you know I think because I know one
thing about this is that I know that
there are a couple of myths that float
around that kind of like trigger slash
signal you right yeah so at the
beginning I I guess I got to talk about
the beginning and the myths to start
this so at the beginning there was a
myth that femini seeds because it's
missing a male chromosome would ruin
cannabis The genome the genetics as a
whole
like that was a real concern like that I
was doing GMO work
and that I was going to ruin cannabis
because of feminized seeds
um Americans tended to have this
attitude the Dutch had I didn't notice
this attitude over there except with a
few companies like Mr Nice and stuff and
he wouldn't be considered Dutch because
by this time he'd moved to Switzerland
but he wasn't you know Amsterdam for a
long time he carried the attitude of
that
um a lot of people also carry this weird
I don't want to say I shouldn't say
weird this very religious Christian
mindset that if God God didn't feminize
seeds therefore it's unnatural breeding
and I want nothing to do with it
God doesn't come into play when they say
that they just say this is unnatural and
I want nothing to do with it this is not
organic
and I don't want anything to do with it
um so those were the two main mindsets
that were going around I can't think of
many others
um fans oh all fans Herm that was the
other one right like because of my
experience with shamans
yeah which a lot of people had that
experience they were buying from
Amsterdam and they were popping
feminized seeds and they were getting
Herms but the what they didn't really
take into account was that they were
popping regular seats and getting Herms
too at the same rate
from Amsterdam and it was just wasn't
specific to films yeah but the myth was
set anyways because it was like oh fems
are new
I'm getting Herms
Benz cost more so I bought Femmes
expecting better this sucks right [ __ ]
these things
and
it was a lot of that
basically
my main argument to like the god
Community or the organic Community was
that in nature
cannabis is an intersex plant that's
right
and it wants to be intersex and only
because of humans human intervention and
breeding we have pushed this plant to
try to choose between male or female
that's not natural
to push it and to make it and to breed
it towards that direction that was only
done by man in man's intervention so
using their mindset technically we are
restoring cannabis back to where it was
as an intersex plant
onto the missing chromosomes destroying
cannabis
foreign
all it takes is Crossing in a male to a
feminized plant
you're back to regular
yeah
um there are and also like there are
things called autosomes that control uh
that are not that are not the sexual
chromosomes of the x's and y's that also
control sexual expression in cannabis
and trying to explain that to people is
really hard because they don't even
understand chromosomes and autosomes in
the first place but it contr it just
shits all over that argument because
there's already autosomes controlling
this which is why in feminine seeds you
can have a pran a plant that expresses
fully male with no female traits or I'm
sorry yeah fully male no female traits
send it in to be tested and it'll test
all female because that's how cannabis
is it can express amazing yeah it can
express all female without any female
corrosis chromosomes because the
autosomes are telling hey we need we
need uh balls here
so that's an issue that people don't
take into account because they don't
it's it's way beyond their
comprehensions level of cannabis right
yeah um
all fems harm we kind of this it's
really [ __ ] in [ __ ] out which a lot of
people do understand you put in [ __ ]
you're gonna get out [ __ ] so if you have
two plants that are uh naturally
intersex and want to remain intersex and
you feminize one or you feminize that
plant and pollinate itself like the
likelihood is that its progeny will have
those same traits
yeah and it's not because it's feminized
meanings yeah yeah and and actually
because it's feminized it actually takes
it two generations or like it not to
generate it takes it what would be
several generations of regular
inbreeding
further in and so you're getting more of
the recessive traits including the
intersex traits so technically because
it was [ __ ] it amplifies the [ __ ]
but if it wasn't [ __ ] it wouldn't be
Amplified if that makes sense so fem
seeds no it doesn't contribute to more
of the Herms but because it was [ __ ] you
were always going to get the herbs
totally so yeah so it's it's a weird
kind of like self-defeetist type model
yeah like it's it's you're set up to
fail in the first place by what they
chose and the BR and the genetics you
wanted anyways
um how it became popular I really just
think that it was over the years of me
selling Femme spray
um people started their attitudes
changed it was funny I noticed the big
change was when breeders that were [ __ ]
talking feminized seeds majorly started
buying the Femme spray off me behind the
scenes and started doing it and started
playing with it and realized oh it
wasn't that hard
I can make Femme seeds and I could
charge more for this these things are
these things are fire you know and then
there were breeders like Canada
who didn't buy my spray but saw the
advantages of it and he was a well-known
figure who was really well liked and in
in the community already and so by him
doing feminized seeds
it's kind of okay CSI popped up he's
super respective he popped back up I
should say and he was releasing femini
seeds now too he's respected so that's
okay
you know OG Rascal never caught any
Flack really for it that I remember
because he was scary
and intimidating so you know it just
slowly the attitude changed to where
they weren't people that you could [ __ ]
talk they can Femme seeds
and more people were buying the spray
and doing it behind the scenes and
realizing I can do this
you know if I don't have to mix these
chemicals and do all this hard [ __ ] I
can do this you know yeah I mean you you
basically provided a platform yeah
people to actually start doing it
um and it's a funny thing you know I
think about that product of yours and
the the thing about it is that it's
almost too good like once someone has a
bottle of that stuff I bet you they
don't really have to come back to you
for years yeah that's that that became
an issue like I'm creating competitors
too in the market
but yeah yeah I think and that also
became an issue of contention for a lot
of the [ __ ] [ __ ] talk after the fact
right one of my main people that hates
my guts and [ __ ] talks me everywhere
hates me on the premise that I created
competitors for him I he said you are
arming the enemy
literally word for word
so yeah um it's yeah it's I didn't look
at it that way
no and I mean that's the thing right
like you're playing a different game
like for a lot for these people it's
like a zero-sum game right whereas for
you you you're just thinking about how
to better equip the community yes I'm
thinking we're on a Level Playing Field
and if they do this for these clones
that they have maybe they're clones that
I don't have and I can get those s1s and
I can look to that line finally because
they use my spray and they did it right
like that's my mindset it's gonna be
more dank out there for all of us
yeah and and another charitable
paraphrase of that is that like you
thought it would be mutually beneficial
it is me yeah for sure it's mutually
beneficial absolutely and like groups
The Way Way groups work and the way they
Thrive best is when everything's
mutually beneficial because everybody's
working for each other and it doesn't
have to be a one-to-one type thing like
people think all the time sometimes
mutually beneficial means
100 people buy that sprayer I give away
100 bottles of that spray which is also
the case to other breeders and I say
you know like you know if you like it if
it works for you just drop me a little
ad or like say you liked it make a post
with it so you loved it and you get to
see very quickly how many people respect
that
or don't so you it's there's all kinds
of things that are usually been like it
was mutually beneficial for me to see
that they weren't good people or that
they didn't respect me like I'd hoped so
that's mutually beneficial for even
though it cost me money
it wasn't so much that I lost
the the outwing of losing that money for
shipping and stuff
it was worth it to see that this
particular person isn't worth doing
business with in the future right yeah
so there's that Mutual beneficial too
like benefits come in losses oddly
enough
yeah for sure even because
information is still a benefit right
data all data is a benefit to me if
you're a nerd if you're a nerd and you
pay attention to [ __ ] all data is a
benefit even bad data even erroneous
data it's still data
no very cool no that that was a great
great response and a great question from
Shawnee as well yeah I'm glad that he uh
he got that in there
um so okay zooming out uh a little bit
more and just thinking now about this is
the last question for the breeding work
section sure
the future and I know probably again
quite a hard and like very open question
but you know what what do you think the
future holds for your breeding work
right now because I'm so focused on The
Syndicate uh be it this podcast be it
the Discord the patreon Discord or
or a close friend group
I've been focusing more on that in
community building than I have on plans
because it takes a lot I mean
realistically it takes a lot of time
like people don't know how much is
behind the scenes stuff goes on but like
it isn't even just me like guys like
thousand Shawnee cry baby not so we are
working on this [ __ ] all way more than
we probably should that's healthy right
so so like breeding for the future a lot
of it is going to be collaborative stuff
because I feel like
this was built to not only just
I didn't want to ever prop myself up
with this [ __ ] because that just looks
like a used car salesman that's why like
I was so hesitant to do the episode in
the first place but to prop up friends
who maybe are way better than me what
they do or at least I feel that way and
haven't gotten the shine because they're
quiet
or because they don't want to deal with
sales they don't want to deal with the
drama of sales because drama comes with
sales and having a seed company every
time people start hating you
um they don't want to deal with that so
in doing this I spent a lot of time on
that and my future like I have the
projects collaborations with CSI there
can be a lot of those
um there's going to be a big one coming
with knots of dogs CSI and The Syndicate
that I'm going to help with
um that one's gonna be big like people
have been waiting for not so release
this is the feminized not so release
coming and it's coming soon very soon so
you know I'm stoked on that one
um
we have I mean The Punchy project I just
did here locally I'm getting to teach
someone as I you know teach someone the
the blue bonnet traits that come through
in The Punchy stuff and like getting to
teach on hand which I I've always been
the student like it's fun you know
um I think that that does sum up in a
way like uh what you're just saying
right like you were kind of leaning now
towards other people and kind of like
um equipping other people yeah and I
mean like I realized like
this is my livelihood too
as a seed company it's always it's it's
been my livelihood and I'm pretty open
about that like making money off
cannabis some people denounce and decry
it but like I really feel like if you're
good to it in the plant and advancing it
like there's not there's not a lot of
disrespect going on there you know
um
but I also feel like in doing so we owe
it to build the community forward and
saying that is one thing the actions are
way [ __ ] bigger and I watched and
waited and waited and I've never felt
like I'm the right person to do this for
many reasons and we haven't gotten to it
it's already like far in on the
controversies but like
we're gonna head there next so okay I
mean this is a good way to segue then
like
I don't I didn't even know if I was the
right person to do this but no one was
doing it
and if they were they were doing it
I feel were selfish agendas
yeah and even though I may I'm not even
the right person to do this because of
my rep
whether deserved or not
I did it and I hope someone does it
better even like I'm it's not even like
it's not like this is the only one that
can happen I want everyone to do this it
would be so much better if everybody had
syndicates out there I will say this as
like again a relative Outsider you know
just home growing hobbyist sure as
someone who's kind of explored quite a
few of these different communities
I and of course I'm biased now you know
I'm kind of entrenched in The Syndicate
but it is by far the most genuine
Community like canvas community that
I've found where you can have actual
genuine interactions with other people
that are meaningful and that don't have
just this like constant backdrop of
marketing and sales which is what you do
find at many of the other discords and
communities sales pumping hard hard hard
yeah like all the discords are
structured like shops basically yeah
yeah that's what they are they're
structured to be little cult shops
if we're being real like little mini
cult shops like here's me on a pedestal
on the man let me tell you what to buy
and that's something that not only me
but Shawnee and other moderators like
people that aren't breeders remind
people daily in our in ours because yeah
we want to kick over every statue in
cannabis like not to disrespect but to
for people to realize anyone can pop a
pack of seeds from anyone not from me
from anyone even idiots you know like
you could buy seats from idiots and pop
a pack of seats and find something that
is as good as any Elite cut out there
it's anybody can do that you can educate
yourself better to have better chances
at finding a good breeder who does
actual work that has the real clone that
you want with the traits you want that
increases your odds and probably a
better way of spending money and your
your Investments but anybody can pop
anything anytime that's equally as good
as anything
that I've found and that's what we want
to reinforce
um pedestals
they lead to nothing but disappointed
you know because no one's perfect
um
most people are [ __ ] most breeders
that like Flex like they're rich and
like you want to be like them they're
not you know like that's a that's a
smoke of mirrors
these aren't those days of Rich breeders
um no yeah
okay cool well that no that that's a
really nice kind of statement about you
know at least part of your mission with
The Syndicate and we'll come back to it
again
um
for right now you know I didn't want to
ask you you did mention it already sure
why do you think you know you are such a
divisive figure you know what's happened
you know I'm not I I don't know any of
these specific events but do you want to
speak to any of the controversies
straight for people yeah so
all my life
I can't she didn't say it all my life
too after second grade probably is when
I became a little bit of a um I don't
say a monster right but maybe maybe some
people might apply that
um
I
the word polarizing has been used to
describe me my whole life especially
through High School
um
adults used it a lot in high school in
regards to me because I would push every
button and push every boundary
um
I would fight a lot you know I was a
short kid so I like had a big mouth and
that big mouth would make me fight a lot
like I didn't really like fighting I
didn't want to get in the fights but
because of my mouth I had to
and
it's just it's one of those things like
some people are on different spectrums
and my spectrum is very little filter
and I blame it on a head injury
but but
yeah I know like I've always had that
title of being a polarizing figure and
when I came into cannabis it was no
different I mean I was a basically a
punk rock guy
trying to bring those ideals
into the Grateful Dead type Community or
in some cases the hip-hop rap
dab type community
um
and I was seeing a lot wrong on forums I
was seeing people say things that
weren't true
I was seeing people openly lie to each
other and stab each other in the back
just do nasty [ __ ] and so I'd say
something
and early on I realized the most common
response is oh man bad vibes bro
why are you bringing bad vibes here
we're good you know like hey man we know
all that bad vibes you know that was
that was really what I got and just and
these forums I mean people again I talk
about this all the time but people
nowadays trying to back read the forums
can't unless you're really good at using
the Wayback machine and some of these
like clandestine forums are gone like
not even on that site they weren't big
enough for that you know they weren't
being indexed
um
on these sites they were mostly seed
banks and seed bank owners as we were
talking about had agenda so like like on
the discords
if you spoke out against anyone or said
anything about anyone including them on
their forum
you're gone
well
I seem to think that I was going to be
immune to this or something or maybe I
didn't care I really genuinely don't
remember what I was thinking at the time
or why I think it was just emotional
reactions to like this isn't fair why is
this person getting [ __ ] over or why'd
you keep my money when I sent it to you
ever I'm going to tell people this so
that they don't have the same thing
happen to them you kept my money where
is it
um or any number of things you know like
this breeder [ __ ] over my friend I
have proof like why are you selling
their seeds are you a scumbag too
so I just pretty much removed from every
forum
uh one of the biggest I think things
that is stuck that dry that drives me
the nuttiest is a story about the the
black I'm sorry The Blood Rose
so my buddies I had a buddy named skunko
from Florida wonderful oh my God he's a
wonderful Dude biggest heart
his sister was going through
chemotherapy at the time and I had given
him a bunch of seeds that I had made
early on and it helped her
a lot tremendously he said and I didn't
ask for anything for it you know it was
just whatever or friend so about three
years later
he had gotten a bunch of seeds of this
line called black or I got him from a
dude named Heath Robinson uh called
Black Rose and I'd given them to him
tons of them I think like 80 seats
and he made a bunch of crosses with it
and he's like dude I want to give these
to you because what you did and I was
like yo like to people that know me like
anybody that knows me especially now
that is a friend I'll say nope I'm not
gonna keep your seeds your get money for
them I've not you're getting half
because that's how it works like half is
what's
I don't work any other way and not not
only because I feel like I'm a generous
dude I feel like
I feel like that leads to resentment if
people aren't if everything's not 100 or
like even it will always lead to
resentment or could potentially and I
don't like losing friends like I want
everybody to feel like we're all on the
same page if I'm making money you're
making as much as me right
yeah so he sent me the pictures for it I
put them up and this is when I just
started working with the attitude
just started working with the attitude
they got the seeds put up the pictures
which I should say that was a big deal
at the time oh yeah I was I was the
second American ever on the attitude
when you're on the attitude it was like
making it in High Times it was me and
sub cool
so
I had to hit up the attitude when so so
I'm sorry Heath Robinson went on the
attitude saw those pictures like there's
my pictures I was like and he emailed me
I was like oh
he's like well it looked like the mom
the best and I'm like oh brother because
he didn't know like he's not right
and I wasn't looking all over Heath
Robinson's pictures I didn't know every
single picture of his and every single
one of these plants it was an f8 which
very uniform and magenta they all look
the same so like I I was like okay take
it down now and put up a thing saying
this is Heath Robinson's this picture
blah blah blah we will have pictures
when it comes so that was all done Keith
is pissed
eighth is nine shades of fist
and he goes on [ __ ] Rants and raves
on and forums and to this day Matt is a
picture Thief Matt is a clone Thief oh
Jesus that's that like and it was up for
probably three hours
Max [ __ ] but for that that three hours
it's been 15 years of Matt is a picture
thief and clone Thief
and like I'm not gonna blame it on
skunko I should have done the the the
work because I knew Heath I should have
I guess I should have asked him are
these pictures yours but I never would
have assumed that like no but that's
like an unknown like you didn't know you
didn't know that like I didn't know that
skoko didn't even know that wasn't what
you do because and the thing is in In
fairness to skunko that's what people
[ __ ] did
right they put up pictures of their mom
plants
as the seed plant saying this is a mom
expect to get something like this that's
what people did so I figured that's what
he was doing
but yeah anyways yeah that's the heath
Robinson controversy um early on when I
got the seeds
um I gave him I'm sorry I gave his buddy
this is where it gets kooky real kooky I
gave his buddy this guy Nutella on the
Canon Cabana I gave his buddy a bunch of
it was the very last
of my Apollo 13 seeds I think he got is
something like that and he want it was
something very rare that he wanted
Brothers Grim was gone there was no
Apollo 13 sub cool hadn't made Apollo 13
px1 it was all there was and he wanted
him so bad and I was like oh bro I don't
know and he's like hey I'm friends with
Heath Robinson I know you like purples I
can get you a bunch of those seeds dude
I was like all right well fine here take
him and he sent me the seeds
but he's had the idea that he had gifted
me these and I had done nothing with
them like I had not sent him anything
back
in my mind I had traded his friend for
those seeds
right so he's mine I'm a [ __ ] thief
who did all this
so it didn't reciprocate yeah it didn't
reciprocate and then used his picture
so when I say perspective is everything
I get his perspective it's because he
wasn't informed and we never spoke after
because he lost his [ __ ] and because I'm
the person I am I was like you you don't
know the story [ __ ] you right
so that's how that goes
it was bad on my part because I didn't
do my due diligence which I mean it was
a granted it was it would have been a
lot of due diligence secondly I didn't
react the way I should have
because I mean it was a very easy
explanation but I felt at the time if I
explained that I'm going to be throwing
skunko under the bus
who's a very sweet heart person not a
breeder has no drama in his life and
doesn't deserve that
yeah or
and all to placate someone who's being
an [ __ ] to me and actually his crew
got something and maybe his best
friend's lying to him and telling him I
didn't get anything but that's not the
case so I'm thinking you're a [ __ ]
and you roll with [ __ ]
yeah so that's that's literally the
whole basis for every clone Thief clone
this clone that he stole this from me
he's not
is it
in a nutshell
um and and when I talk about me and res
dog having the dark mark
it's true like I really really truly
believe that
um there's no one else who has the [ __ ]
stain on cannabis like when you mention
their name except for me and resd dog
and resdog actually snitched on people
and this is my dark mark is the heath
Robinson Black Rose Fiasco and you know
it's bizarre to me because you know I've
never heard that story before but it
just seemed like these really in the end
quite I know they're not small but you
know kind of small things that just
added up in quite a step way
yep yeah things that last you like three
hours like and I didn't even know the
attitude and me so that was the first
step with the attitude where I was like
oh I gotta tell them take these pictures
down
second thing that happened
was sub cool
went to them because me and sub cool
were not super friendly but we didn't
like fight yet like we weren't friendly
but he did not like that another
American was on the attitude with him at
odd if anybody knows Monty yeah or new
Monty this was Monty
so he went to I would say her name was
Natalia that owned the attitude I think
she still owns it at the time and said
Matthew Riot is a bad [ __ ] person and
you shouldn't do business with him and
she actually showed me the screenshot of
the email
and she said you know if we go to
parties with sub cool he's our biggest
money maker
and I believe him if he says you're a
piece of [ __ ] then I trust this man and
we're not gonna do any more business
with you thank you
wow at this time
I was making this is when I was making
serious money once he's like that was
the first time I'd made serious money
when you make it to the attitude you can
make serious money
and yeah and I thought that was awesome
you know that I was doing that and I
felt like I had finally made it you know
and
we are helping my grandma with her her
um
her her nursing home bills at the time
because she had been in a in a meadow
like a really nice one she didn't want
me taking care of her growing weed you
know so she wanted to be a house where
we just drunk she's an old Mexican lady
so yeah so
um or was I sorry
we were talking about the controversies
um that was yeah my brain brought me in
some and I was like what is this and
then I got all distracted with my ADHD
no that's okay you're essentially
telling us about the attitude oh the
attitude okay
yeah um so he said you know oh so I was
helping take care of my grandma at her
nursing home with money at that time and
it was really secure I thought because
like I had this great relationship they
were buying seeds and that came to a
[ __ ] sudden halt
so it caused a lot like livelihood wise
like I had to sell her house
to pay for her medical bills like
granted she wasn't living there but this
is the family's house now that had to
get sold
and the whole time I had to hear her cry
about wanting to go home and there was
no home to go to
oh my God so that which for me like that
rage that I had for sub cool and it was
just like compounding [ __ ] like that
like there must have been traumatic it
was hard it's hard but and I [ __ ] you
not after I got released from the
attitude it was going from making like
10 000 a week
to
holy [ __ ] I made 75 over the period of
the next four months because me getting
removed from the attitude meant
everybody saw it
and it confirmed that everyone thought
that I was a [ __ ] bag
because it was public you know like them
seeing that happen
my God and yeah and I was like it was it
was devastating because this is not even
this is during the heath Robinson thing
too so it was like just
compounded compounded and that's
probably when I became the most hateful
and the most mean
possible yeah and I was like dude all
these people think I'm an [ __ ] all of
them think I'm a [ __ ] bag heel they all
think I'm a bad person
[ __ ] them I'll be the worst heal they
can [ __ ] imagine
you know like and I'm gonna make the
best stuff I can while I'm doing it I
will be the worst [ __ ] hero every con
artist I'm gonna figure out everything
everyone's [ __ ] done every dirty
[ __ ] Deed all these [ __ ] you know
that are pulling [ __ ] on me I'm gonna
figure out everything they've ever done
genetically and [ __ ] press them up
against the wall and make them [ __ ]
pay and that's what I did so this is
like the the origin of the like
anti-hero slash villain knock yeah this
is this is the origin of Matt Riot
proper granted I had that name or since
I was a little kid in punk bands
um yeah like like my best friend's
sister who is a riot girl back in the
day like and that's like a feminist punk
rock organization that's right I'm
political yeah I would be real like a
chauvinist little pig to her and so
she'd call me a riot boy because I was
being a chauvinist Pig which is the
opposite of right girl you know so you
call me right boy so that's why that
name's stuck right this is the the
Genesis of
that name in cannabis and why like heel
is associated with that name that those
months and granted at first I was
getting kicked off forms and pushing
back
but this is when I was like uh
no like I'm gonna get the best at this I
possibly can to where my I'm not
throwing breaks from a glass house I'm
never gonna make these mistakes like
this again
ever yeah and I'm gonna [ __ ] nail all
them to the wall every last one
including subcool
because I felt like it was done to me it
was a little bit of a victim mentality
which is stupid because in reality like
there are things I could have done to
probably have a better reputation I
could have kissed his ass I could have
been nice despite not liking him and
everything would have been probably
hunky-dory but
I mean hindsight right hindsight yeah
and and I didn't need to be mean I
didn't need to question everyone at the
beginning like that's true other people
were successful because they didn't do
that and it probably would have been
successful and
so it's not the way the way I was
thinking at the time was you did this to
me
right yeah so that had to change in my
mind and it took a while it took a while
to change yeah yeah because that I don't
want to ask you about that next which
was like what was that period like of
like recovering getting back on your
feet after this
it took all the way
up until probably Instagram okay
right and
people [ __ ] hated my guts I'm not
even kidding you like it just every
every day I would have emails saying
like hey I heard you're an [ __ ] can
you tell me why you're not and my first
response is [ __ ] you I'm not gonna
politic for your likes if you weren't
around during that time and you the
first words to me or I heard you're an
[ __ ] you're not gonna get a response
and this was daily everyone just
so I didn't make a lot of money dude
yeah I never made a lot of money in
cannabis seeds I just didn't yeah that's
that that was the last time I made great
money in cannabis
um and I don't care like I got to breed
anyways and I managed but once Instagram
came around and live streaming happened
I was able to go on live streams and
people were able to ask me questions
directly and see my face see my
mannerisms hear my words and for some
reason that changed a lot not everything
it's been very slow
but
it changed it did change something and I
don't know why I think it's still
happening I think it's still happening
as well probably I mean like
and to me that's a very slow change but
you know I don't know why I I guess be
and the way I looked at it was I'm gonna
do this because I don't see any other
breeders doing this they're competent at
this and if I do this and I speak
confidently
hopefully people will learn enough to be
able to then ask readers the right
questions to get them to put their feet
to the fire like essentially
I think yeah another another take I have
on this is that your strategy kind of
shifted to just being like look I'm just
gonna like do the work yeah that's it
like and and that was the part of the
heal thing too is like I'm just gonna
work as hard as I can and [ __ ] you
yeah exactly let the work do the talking
right exactly
yeah that's this is the best I could do
is this a good point to segue then
because I was going to ask you next you
know the next section is going to be
about returning to that sense of
community spirit and I think one thing
that I is obvious to me in talking to
you today is that
your ties to the community
uh pervasive like you you know whether
for good or bad you've always been
interested and invested in community
relationships yeah and the furniture
cannabis I don't go away
bad Furniture someone's someone
someone's Lazy Boy
but you've built this thing called breed
of Syndicate and you know you didn't
mention you didn't name drop this thing
which I'm not I don't know if it's a
meme or not can Illuminati but how did
you come up with the idea for The
Syndicate when did you mean not so like
how you know what were these events like
um I'll probably skip one part and then
we'll go straight into The Syndicate so
um
how did I meet not so he was he was
good friends with CSI
um and CSI knew him as the Mendo perps
guy for years like going to old parties
in in Mendo and back to back to the NCGA
parties a lot of people don't know about
um
and events he met not so dog there in
mindo and not so dog was of course known
as the Kim 91 [ __ ] menopurps guy
and one day I get a message on Instagram
from a dude
he's like hey I heard you got this
Afghani clone that's skunky tell me
about it
so we start talking
and the guy's super nice and super
competent I'm like who is this guy
so I asked Caleb have you ever heard of
this dude he's like yeah it's my buddy
that's my boy that's a mental purpose
guy
and of course not so hadn't mentioned it
he's the mental purse guy that he's had
anything to do with Cam he's just some
normal dude asked me questions about
Afghani no it's not in the Forefront he
doesn't put that in the Forefront back
then and um so I start having more deep
conversations with him and the guy is
just an amazing talker and only that
like he's got amazing things to say and
amazing history
and during this time Discord popped up
and I was on one from someone else who
created
and I brought I was like hey I have a
friend named not so dog and I think
everybody should hear him talk let's do
a voice chat for the first time and
let's see let's see how people react to
him because I think he's got an
interesting story and that was the first
time I interviewed not so unrecorded for
three hours on a Discord called the
Northwest 47 back then I don't know what
it's called today or if it's even
existing but
um yeah that was the first time I
interviewed knots and that's when I
realized me and this guy have chemistry
and maybe we should do this more often
and talk about other things
yeah you start dating we started dating
weekend boyfriends and he was a good
kisser
and it was just the way he held me so
tight at night that the chemistry body
chemistry and maybe it's his pheromones
something about it
um drove me to him
yeah yeah
and like yeah okay so you meant not so
and then when did The Syndicate concept
arise
The Syndicate concept kind of rised
early on when I realized that
me not so CSI everyone's not going to
have retirement
um there are people above me that were
getting sick older people were getting
sick and had nothing and I'm like we
need a union guys
something like thinking like totally out
of the box like impossibly maybe but
that was the first idea of The Syndicate
was just like this has to happen you
know and then slowly our friend group
started getting bigger and bigger and
there was more interest and
it's just like we all started talking
about strains and history and bringing
what we had to the table and it became a
24 7 thing on our own little area
and this group formed and we'd all
decided that it was time to try to take
this bigger and that's when we started
doing reader Syndicate podcast
and that was it like we just kind of
fumbled our way through this and made it
here after I don't even know how long
it's been a few years maybe
yeah how long has it been I I'm yeah
I've never known that actually I assume
it's like a three to four years
something like that yeah
yeah okay yeah because that was you know
you mentioned thinking about the
livelihoods and the sustainability of uh
breeders and breeding yeah um and
because my next question was gonna be
you know what is your hope for this
group of people what is yourself the
ultimate goal for The Syndicate would be
for everybody that the Legacy farmers
and uh to be taken care of with
some kind of Union I don't even know how
that works I don't know how it happens I
want to I want everyone to have health
care I want everyone to have the same
thing that everybody else should have
yeah
um
I want I I like there to be a place
where people can go where they know
people have at least done their due
diligence to find the history right and
have that accessible and not be just a
gender-filled history and
that's been that's hard that's hard
because yeah when you're when you make
money in cannabis
everyone's gonna assume that you're
doing it for selfish reasons because a
lot of those people are selfish and
would do it for selfish reasons so they
don't understand why they can't
um
but maybe part of that Spectrum side is
what brought a lot of us together too
because we were also narrowly focused in
ADHD on making sure we get this history
right that that's the one thing a lot of
us gel on you know yes like our overall
love Falls for getting this right and
misinformation just add absolutely makes
my stomach hurt
so it's like it's some of that it's some
of my OCD that just inherently makes me
want to push
a lot of it is that I love these people
my friends I absolutely love them and I
want them to do well and yeah I see a
lot of [ __ ] bags progressing cannabis
and I don't understand I understand why
and how that's happened I don't
understand how to fix that and I didn't
see anybody else really giving it a try
and this was my best attempt at it thank
I mean I still got other stuff
trying this at all no nobody's trying
but
the people that have stepped up whether
it be you Shawnee not so
uh goat farm high and Lonesome bitter
Denali everybody ZB like
yep it's it's it's been necessary for
everybody to be a part of for it to get
where it's at and so like I don't like
talking about me starting anything
because
it wasn't me that started it it formed
and became it I just came up with the
name we'll say that it emerged right it
emerged yeah it definitely emerged
very cool and that's really special to
hear because I don't I'm sure you've
alluded and implied a lot of these
things when we took when you know in
other podcasts and in our chats and
stuff but I think it's really cool to
kind of like
you know hear you talk about what your
hopes are
um I appreciate that
was there anything else you wanted to
mention about The Syndicate
um because otherwise I think we can kind
of move towards wrapping up with a few
like uh lighter quicker questions I mean
the The Syndicate like it's probably the
thing I when I have a pride of anything
it may not be breeding but the fact that
this is forming and that when I'm gone
I'm hoping it'll still be here and
people will take the reins or if I
retire or whatever I'm hoping people
take the reins of it because these are
such beautiful people that have
assembled like
it's just amazing and if I have any
Pride or anything it's going to be with
that the people that have all come
together and that I had any part in that
whether it was just choosing the name
and that you know or doing the show and
if I had any part in that that's going
to be my pride like I love the
bonnetwork and I love I love cannabis
and I love what I've done in it
um I love this a lot and I'm more proud
of
this because in cannabis everybody else
I I just consider everything I've done
everybody else's
you should be proud it's really special
thank you I appreciate it
um
yeah yeah it's I I'm you know I know
again like I'm no one in in cannabis
world and don't have any aspirations of
being anyone but again even as like just
an Enthusiast at home like it's been
such a special experience and yeah such
a special place you know the Discord
patreon is one of the things that were
like early on I was like God I don't
want to charge people that was the one
thing I did not want to do is charge
people for info and part of getting into
the the Discord patreon is paying five
dollars to get in and I was really
resistant to it I hated the idea
absolutely hated the idea but when I
realized like
if we do this we in order for it to
succeed it has to get bigger right it
can't just be us and in order to do that
I'd have to bring in new people
and if it if I felt like if I opened the
flood gates five dollars would be enough
of a barrier to keep out people who come
in just to fight
yeah and stuff like that and it was very
effective at it
very very effective at it so while I
regret
having to charge anyone for anything on
that level at the same time because of
that
it seems like everybody's happy to pay
that to keep the idiots out you know
what I mean like so it did work it's
effective uh as far as keeping trolls
out people people going there just to
cause problems and for a while we opened
it up for free
to see how it went right and that was
fun it was interesting and we gained a
lot of new people by doing that too that
are really passionate so yeah the
Discord has been a great place for
everyone to kind of like commune find
each other and really start digging into
history in ways that I think they
probably never have and and I really
feel in ways that have never been
offered for cannabis Community ever and
I've been a part of most of them
yeah and and for me you know in in this
conversation today what I love is that
in many ways we've come full circle like
you
you started with the community Spirit
yeah and we are still there with the
Syndicate you've carried that on really
strongly and of course it was great of
course to hear all your breeding work
but it's so cool to hear about this side
of things the community side because I
don't know if I've encountered another
figure in this scene who is as Community
minded as you and it makes it so ironic
uh it makes those controversies so
ironic yeah
um in that context you know I and you
know what's funny is like there are a
lot of people who have joined over the
years and I've learned like when I when
these people like hit me up in DMS and
are like nasty and ugly to me I just
usually say I'll see you in three years
bro if you're still around I'll see you
in three years
and without it without fail dude I've
gotten so many messages like bro I am
sorry you're right like because usually
if I say that I go through the [ __ ] and
I see they're working with a scammer and
I'm like hey man I'll tell you what in
three years you're gonna find out this
dude's a scammer You're Gonna Know It
And when you do will you come back to me
or you know station like that almost
without fail it works every time so a
lot of people get it over time what the
with the propaganda pushback was and why
it happened and
you know like realistically like my
mission in life isn't just to make The
Syndicate it was to get misinformation
out of cannabis and the only way to do
that is to hold people's feet to the
fire and by doing that I did that to
individual people
over a period of 17 years now
and I've amassed an army of people that
[ __ ] hate my guts and this is true
and like people in The Syndicate have
actually watched this happen many times
over now cycle these people pop up mix
it up and fight you know and in I've
learned to deal with it a lot better I
think you know because I mean it helps
when there's more people than just me to
witness the the craziness because for a
long time
yeah there wasn't anybody but more than
me because people are terrified to
associate with me they would people
would harass friends of mine that
weren't even breeders they would just
rash them you know yeah you couldn't
even you could not post and grow Riot
seed stuff on forums because people
would harass you off the forums get like
every time
people had nothing to do with me would
get harassed for growing my [ __ ] and
showing it so
time to change we've got you back a bit
I know it's it's weird it is very weird
to have
like I mean you see it when I get sick I
feel like I'm like I've got to [ __ ]
get back to it but it's hard to remember
that there's other people that like care
as much as I do now that can run with it
and can carry balls you know
that sounds good what I mean really cool
no yeah I love it [ __ ] love it
okay well thank you for that that was
yeah super special and um we kind of
like to me we've kind of covered the
bulk of like the critical questions that
I wanted to ask sure I would say that
like I've maybe got another 20 to 30
minutes tops yeah and um I've got a few
Community questions that kind of didn't
necessarily fit anywhere but they're
still pretty cool perfect let's nail
them
um so one is one that I had for you
which is you know I've said this to you
in private that like I think part of the
direction change that you've experienced
last couple of years you're actually
becoming more and more of like an
archivist journalist type I know you
don't you wouldn't maybe consider that
yourself but I do yeah a poor man's
version
and I guess in terms of like the
investigations you know are there any
other major lines or names that are
still kind of like at the back of your
mind they're like I want to get to the
bottom of that are there any you know
there there's a few
um G13
only because I'm like
5 6 of the way there and no bunch of it
but someone is secret squirreling the
last part and
basically gatekeeping that info from
getting out
interesting
like he's just making shorts of some of
the hash plant discussions yeah it's
basically like he went and talked to the
guy
and
no one's allowed to talk about what he
found
because he wants to one day maybe do
something with it like a book or
something maybe one day
okay and I find that extremely selfish
and that is bizarre cowardly and just
like little [ __ ] [ __ ] but
um Romulan was a big one big one because
there's so much myth around it and
trying to go and track down Romulan Joe
there's so much myth around him that's
one that I've wanted to do
um maybe one day we'll see that
um
you know what's interesting you
mentioned archivists and stuff
um very recently one of my old close
friends from like Junior High that was a
skater kid that was a skate and smoke
pot together in junior high out but you
know
um he hit me up and he still smokes he's
into strange stuff but he worked for
DreamWorks Studio as an archivist
and now works for a major university and
he's so good at his job that they he
gets paid sabbaticals for two or three
months during summer to go archive
whatever he wants
wow and to do serious stuff and this
stuff in his stuff is presented at the
Library of Congress and these big
displays and museums and [ __ ] yeah so
it's serious stuff and he wants to do
one on the history of punk rock and
Bakersfield when I was a big figure in
that oh my God and he wants to cover
cannabis maybe eventually and like to
get like the Cannabis history covered
and displayed in the Library of Congress
that would be so huge to me
and it wouldn't be my work it would be
because he's a real archivist and
Anthropologist and does this real but
like to be even a part of that
yeah
yeah I mean he's gonna need people like
you yeah that's why he reached out like
yeah it was phenomenal I like he's gone
so far in life it's crazy that's juicy
all right that's my first time hearing
that yeah
all right well next question from PBJ
girl okay what is something that you
wish you knew before you started
breeding looking back oh God it would be
um first not to be so aggressive with
pulling in front of people
secondly the name drop thing from Caleb
CSI
don't name drop people when you first
meet people
because you never know what their
feelings are truly going to be about
them
um I would I would have learned about
the Spanish bait and switch earlier that
everything you're buying I'm sorry yeah
everything you're buying from Amsterdam
comes from Spain and that's probably not
going to be what's on the packs
and
um generally speaking people are [ __ ]
Liars
like plants not the people yeah yeah be
critical critical thinking critical
thinking critical thinking confront your
own biases critical thinking
yeah
nice no it's a great answer yeah okay
another good one from PBJ girl a little
bit more personal
if you weren't a musician and you
weren't a breeder what do you think
you'd end up doing in an alternate
universe so my my in Canada or in in
high school I wanted to brew beer for a
living which I don't feel I'm too far
off like yeah
even in the same yeah even in the same
family of plants but I wanted to bring
here for a living
um art probably would be another one
even though I suck at Art I wish I was
better
um I I thought I was gonna be a musician
growing up but I'm not you know like
professionally
um I don't know that I would love that
life after watching a bunch of my
friends friends that live that life
um try to succeed only if you have like
majorly succeeded and it's hard it's
hard on them it's a hard life you're
traveling constantly
yeah
um
I'm not I don't know I'm not good at
much like when people say that it's like
oh no I'm really not like I don't
I like reading a lot you know I have my
UFO stuff that I do like I don't I talk
about sometimes on the show and I even
had a podcast for a bit but like as much
as I archive in cannabis I probably have
archived three times as much in ufology
and have studied it more than cannabis
so that was always my main Obsession up
until the even the past few years that
I've decided I'm done with ufology
but I can see that it comes from the
same place right oh yeah yeah oh yeah
and dude the same character type of
characters show up in ufology like it's
crazy like they even look like the
person they sound like the person and
they act like the person but they have a
different names and it's [ __ ] it's
[ __ ] up so [ __ ] up I guess like in
these kind of like marginal like opaque
uh worlds of like weird like uncertain
information you might get some of the
same programs it is crazy they even look
the same it's so weird
so weird okay
well I have a final question and it's
kind of like
um
one of those like fantasy breeding
questions I I I it's from hippie stick
and he said okay oh sorry I they I don't
I don't actually know I'd like to know
what your Ultimate Fantasy breeding
project would look like if you had
access to any Cairo sweet line from
anywhere or anyone through cannabis
history and maybe because you've already
kind of spoken about
the potential of blueberry maybe we just
exclude blueberry entirely from this
from this like hypothetical project yeah
where would you go what would you do I
if I had the chance to go back in
history
I would work with my old friend Neville
and
I would find out what Afghan T was
and I would see if I was right about
super skunk
it would be to to settle the question on
super skunk is it is the is the Afghan
tea
just the best skunkiest representation
of super Stockton is that what we're
finding in the jesel Kim D stuff like
that is all Afghan T representations and
I think it is I'm pretty sure
um but I'd like to know more that's one
line one cut
line even in the in what was called the
maple leaf Indica that I would like to
find more out about
for sure for sure yeah
it keeps me up at night
I love that because instead of like
choosing something to actually like like
work with or work within a new way
you've chosen to be like no I want to
confirm information yeah it's just
confirming data like data points that I
have I've it's like to me it's the
equivalent of like is there life on
other worlds or
um you know did Jesus exist or you know
anyone does it's like mythical did I get
super skunk right am I right
about this it's one of my life like it
keeps me up at night me and not so have
spent more hours on the phone and online
talking about this one single thing than
anything else like I count days worth of
hours talking about this [ __ ] months
worth of hours so it's one of those
things like with breeding projects like
I didn't really think like I think I
could pretty much Source whatever I need
to make whatever Turf I want or need in
cannabis like if I really set my mind to
it and had the years and the time and
finances I could probably do it now
um
but finding out what something was
that's missing from history
that's a lot harder that's more
challenging and I think I got this one
right I think I do and I'm not usually
that confident about stuff but I am I'm
pretty confident on this and if I'm
right about this it means a lot of
people lied
and I can correct a lot of stuff
yeah
no yes that's a great question
um
those are the questions I've got for you
today Matt
okay that's good I mean like I think
this is an excellent even part one if
anybody else wants to go back and touch
on stuff this is thorough as [ __ ]
I'm glad I'm glad and you know again
thank you for the opportunity and thank
you for like all this stuff that you've
done like
I know like I don't represent anyone in
saying that but in in a way I do I know
that many other people are grateful for
so much of this so much of The Syndicate
so much of the work that you've done
um
it's it's still at this moment right now
absolutely bizarre to me that I just got
to do this conversation with you in this
interview with you
but I think it also the fact that I am
here talking to you like this I think
also
in a way uh embodies this that Community
Spirit of yours were you like so anyone
can have the chance
to do this yeah right and I think we're
interviewing me doesn't feel very
special to me
um like it doesn't feel like a special
event but I felt like
I felt like your questions are really
good I like how you speak and like
realistically
I I just I never really
felt the need to interview me ever again
like I've never done it on the show you
never everybody my interviews on the
show like that but I just I felt like I
didn't need to do it and I felt like it
it would be bad
for me to do no and you were the only
one that really really took the reins
and really made it happen
so thank you for doing that
no you're so welcome
um and you know going back to those
feelings of like uh do I really want an
interview of myself like I I think it
goes back to something we were talking
about earlier which is that like
at a point this becomes bigger than you
yeah you know and in a way it's
it's bigger than your feelings about
yourself yeah you know and I know that
that's really hard sometimes to actually
stomach but
yeah it is now I'm gonna force you to
edit this just
well yeah I don't know I don't know how
to wrap this up but you know I think
yeah this is super cool super cool thank
you so much oh I guess you could say um
if you enjoyed this conversation go
check out the patreon
um our discord's there uh this is how I
met thousandfold
um you know like like it's not just
about people that have been in the scene
forever that we're friends with this
Mission isn't about the best grower this
Mission isn't about who knows genetics
the best or who can speak the best with
me it's only about heart it's only about
heart that's it and those are the people
I want around me or people with good
Hearts has nothing I mean we may have
cannabis in common and we're Growers
um some people aren't that can
contribute to The Syndicate and they're
just as important as me or anyone else
so it's it's about heart that's it
that's what I got to say
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out