ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
what's up gene
what's up guys good evening thanks for
coming
oh yeah
all right now to you you kicked the show
off i kicked the show off
you're the kickoff guy i'm the kickoff
guy
uh well you know thank you for another
friday night of your time
uh we got uh besides the normal kick we
got uh our buddy uh i guess we'll call
him mean gene on the screen
uh he uh him and i live in the same spot
pretty much
uh we kind of both
uh lived most of our adult lives in
mendo we've kind of seen like all the
various changes that have gone on we
both have a bunch of similar breeding
interests in various aspects and so we
thought it would be cool to uh we're
gonna do this a number of times we
thought it would be cool to bring
him on and talk a little bit about
just uh some of the some of the history
stuff that went on in mendo
some of the changing of the times and
some of the stuff that we saw from long
ago and some stuff that he's interested
in and we are and so on and so forth
so
that's kind of where we're at
awesome yeah so yeah gene tell us tell
us about some of the stuff you saw
growing up like what what are your first
memories of of strains specifically
oh i mean like
i can tell you like originally i
remember
hanging out like with my buddy sai when
we were little and him like getting bud
from his brother
and being like oh this is this is this
is good this is a good good pot or a
good weed this is bud you know check it
out it's bud and that was before
he was probably he was a year older than
me
that was probably starting when we were
like when i was probably like i don't
know eight years old or something so i
was these dudes who smoked weed when he
was like basic basically like a toddler
almost
where i can remember like riding in the
car and like
standing on the back seat in a car
you know out on the 162 on kovalev road
when
i don't know i could've been older than
like
three or four years old and he was like
a year older and people were passing a
joint around the car
and he's passing the joint for the
adults and he's like
taking a hit while he's passing it and i
remember just being like like
like it was just the weirdest weirdest
[ __ ] to me but he's just one of these
dudes he's one of those dudes who like
you'll be at the i remember being a
reggae on the river when we were
i don't know 20 or something and a dude
walk up selling acid and him just being
like dude i'll eat a [ __ ] sheet right
now dude just give me a sheet i'll eat
it just so you can watch somebody do it
dude like
and so he was like
his brother was like a dude who had um
like always the cool [ __ ] like
the guns and fireworks and
[ __ ] z28 and the [ __ ] serwin vega
12s in the house and you know other [ __ ]
going on you know and like uh so that
was like kind of when i was little that
was kind of the exposure i remember of
like early out and going places with him
like his cousin's houses and [ __ ] where
like [ __ ] you see in movies that you're
like you're like damn like people are
people are like living like this like
the kids are straight feral all the
adults are like straight partying and
it's a free-for-all and
um
but like uh he's always been one of my
coolest friends as far as like just like
a super super cool dude that's always
had my back and [ __ ] and uh
so like going back then i can remember
back then like um
as far as like
my peer group having weed but as far as
just weed like weed was always kind of
around was just pop i remember being
little in here and smelling people
smoking weed and you like know that that
pop smell like it's like some someone
burning sage or something or usnia or
whatever you don't really know but you
smell it like oh they're smoking pot you
know and then uh
getting a little bit older um
to the point when actually having like
an interest in what was going on and
seeing like a high times magazines and
[ __ ] like that or little a little bit
before high times probably a year before
i saw the high times
um
we like started there was i i used to
live up at um
uh what's ariel 101 now which was
originally check lodge or grape wine
station and
i like that was the first time i ever
saw indoor was there's this big shed
still there if you 101. you can see it's
this big steel building like just past
the creek
and i remember going in there and there
was like the the big parabolic thousand
watt lights
and seeing these big thin leaf plants
that were like
to me they were huge but i was like
eight and a half or nine so they were
probably like
no six feet six foot tall plants or
something they seemed huge and i
remember him being like up on a little
platform kinda and then the light
being all the way near up by the roof
and being a few feet apart and that was
like my first time seeing [ __ ] like that
and then right around then
was when my mom was given that that um
manila envelope that was that had seeds
in it to grow indoor and it was like you
got to have indoor seeds to grow indoors
we thought which turns out it's not true
we didn't realize it until like the mid
90s when i tried growing a bunch of
different other [ __ ] randomly which most
of it didn't really work out to be that
dank but at least you could you could do
it it was weed and then all weed was
weak it didn't matter if it was as
killer as the northern lights but the
northern lights was killer and that's
what was in that envelope and uh
my mom popped a few of those she got one
plant that was a female she saved some
of the other ones we ended up planning
those years later when i lived in
healdsburg down in sonoma county that
was like 90
493 i want to say it was eighth grade
for me
so it had to be right around in that in
that time period and um
so that was but that was like the first
strain i remember having where it like
had a name was northern lights
and then when i was a kid i didn't know
about it but my mom and and her
boyfriend like uh who's like my dad
george
they had stuff that they got that was um
they got this stuff from a friend out in
george's neighborhood that was the that
was uh the missouri
and they really liked it and then
i was talking to george the other day
and he said that about 70 in about 76 he
was in san francisco at the beach and
these dudes had brought back a couple
pounds of seeds from afghanistan and he
said that was the time you ever saw
afghani weed which was interesting to me
because i i thought more like here the
other stories i know are more like 84
humboldt 78 so he was like no it was 76
and that was the first stuff and he goes
that was different than the missouri
that and that i got from charlie brown
and um so he was telling me that and
that was cool because it's all this time
and i still you still get new
information right yeah
so that was cool [ __ ] and then uh
he was like i wish i would i wish i
would have hung on to some of those
those were really killer and the
missouri was a much bigger plant with
like the big long buds and yeah um
so but that was that was before my time
but that was like you know stuff that
was
it had i been aware of what was going on
that was stuff that was being grown you
know yeah but yeah
but yeah so then so then really the
northern lights was like that first
thing
and then i remember that being around
and uh
the first clone i can remember
besides that which is probably around
the same time if not
right at the same time i remember willow
had just come out the movie willow right
yeah yeah so that's 89 i think
and we
this lady's house up in leggett and she
had this weed that was purple
which was really cool because to me like
i had always seen you know pot like
still what i call pot like is like
general weed it's not really
not any distinction you're just talking
about some pot has some pot right
she had some [ __ ] that was
purple weed and the smell of that is
still what i smell in the urcle and
um
like when i do all the breeding with the
cherry pie i'll get these ones where
like when i label my bags so that i
remember what kind of plan it was the
throw
like legit purple smell
on it to like so that i know like this
is that one that's kind of like that and
that used to pop out the stuff i had
called the big red too
um and if you really grew a lot of deep
chunk the sweeter ones you'll get some
that are really more that style and then
i even got a lot of that smell
when i smelled a flat that a dude had
brought to the emerald cup that was um i
think it was green source gardens
brought a flat of all these afghanis
that were recently imported
and
he had grown them to see what was in
them and some of them were good some of
them were bad some of them smelled like
cheesy they were all different smells
but a couple of them had that smell that
i was like that's like that that legit
purple smell you know and it's easy
because
it's an early smell right like you know
what it smelled like the first time you
smelled someone cooked broccoli yeah the
first time
nail polish remover or like it's like a
smell that really stuck with me um so
those are like the two oldest things and
that clone resurfaced when i was living
out in this neighborhood west to here
um
and it was a lady who i was staying with
and her neighbor who's a guy who what i
call perp came from which is the purple
stemmed stuff that wound up being real
and uh
they both were growing it and i saw and
i was like oh this is that [ __ ] and and
and it turned out it did come from the
same lady and um
you know for me that was a really long
time apart but for those adults it was
just a little while right now you know
how it is four or five years
there was that so there was those and
then um
you know
around back in those days i didn't see a
whole lot of different stuff i remember
seeing like some
some brick weed that was supposed to be
um
that was supposed to be tie and i don't
know if what it was but it was very
string very dark very compressed not a
lot to it but people who smoked it would
get the giggles really [ __ ] bad and
get higher than a kite it was way
different than other like
the other like bricky weed that i've
seen or like when i bought like
colombian brick for
20 for you know
what you know 20 bucks a quarter pound
or some [ __ ] or 100 per pound in costa
rica you like go through the whole thing
and you get like a cup you get a little
bit of bud and the rest is all a bunch
of garbage and then yeah you smoke it
you get high for 15 minutes you fall
asleep you wake up with a headache like
this wasn't like that so i was like yeah
it could have been maybe it was thai
weed i don't know like someone had had
put away or something
but that's so that's like going up you
know not a lot of different variety that
i can really remember
all the way
until
93-94
and in that era old-school smokers
remember it was like somebody passed you
a joint
and if you're like if you're like a real
weed head and you really know your [ __ ]
you're not like is this
the burps is this
sour diesel you're like is it bud and
they're like yeah it's bud and you're
like all right and then you smoke but
you know if they're like oh it's shake
you're like oh no i don't want to smoke
that so back then
didn't get attached to stuff very much
it was either like this shit's really
killer or it's not that killer and then
uh
around i guess it was around 94.
i
i started hanging out i had been living
in healsburg for like a year and it
sucked i went to eighth grade down there
and uh
most people were square or the people
who weren't square were skaters and they
were pretty pretty soon to turn into
tweakers once they hit high school later
yeah
and uh
and then like the mexican dudes were
really cool to me
and the skaters were really cool to me
but the squares were kind of like ah
this dude's like you kind of tell i was
like more of a stoner guy right
well it was kind of weird going to a new
school because it was real there was
more of that separation i live in a real
small town when i was going to school
before that and there's not enough kids
for there to be any separation because
you can't have a whole group of one
thing or there's just three guys or
whatever right
so
basically
i was down there and then i came back up
north
and some of my buddies had actually
started growing in the bushes and [ __ ]
and they were they were like carrying
buckets to go to to to water and stuff
like my my buddies uh on on instagram
their og foundation farms and um
and uh
and uh goddamn what's what's his what's
his thing it's
uh ancient ancient future pharmacy
yeah yeah and so and then those guys and
our other our other friend uh nick rock
was in that neighborhood and there was
like a few
uh my buddy little willy and um and
there was like a few people who were out
there and everybody was kind of into
and i went back there and started
hanging out and they were all talking
about the flavors and they had like po
they had like a harvest under their belt
and they're talking about oh we have
this one this is oh these are the buds
from over there this is the one from
over there and they had named all the
plants by the location like this is this
one from the top of the pond or this was
this chunky one or whatever you know and
and then like whoever the seeds were
from so there was like chunky marks that
was like from the from from mark who was
chunky or the plant was chunky and i
never really thought of it and then
there was tall marks which came from the
the taller mark you know the other guy
who had the
taller and so they had all these
different [ __ ] and they would be like oh
and all these ones are tasty and those
ones aren't and i was like damn okay
[ __ ] i didn't really know anything about
that with weed like flavors and exactly
what they were i just knew like i still
to get high and i would smoke and they'd
look at me and they'd be like
they'd be like um
uh
you know
why do you make that face when you when
you i get like the bitter weed face
right maybe like why you don't like the
smoke and i'd be like nah i mean you
know if you kind of cough out smoke and
[ __ ] it's all harsh and all that yeah
and so then i wound up having a little
bit of the northern lights
and they smoked it and they're all
that's tasty and i was like oh this is
tasty okay [ __ ] i've just been like
choking on it you know
paying attention to how they were
smoking hitting it a little lighter
taking it the deep inhale blowing out
the smoke before you cough like the
basic things you know you're more
seasoned smoker when i was a kid you
know and so um
then that was when i started to then see
all the variety and when we would go to
school you know we'd smoke at lunch and
people would bring the stuff from their
parents and we'd find out what they had
in bell springs what they had in spyro
what's what this girl's dad grew or what
this girl's dad got from
from you know
bill graham presents people give it
hooking them up weed because they were
it was the people who were into that you
know all the dead [ __ ] and
um
so then like then i started to see more
of the variety and uh in that time
period around then a little later was
when i saw like the effects which is
what you know like uh
uh
i think crossed the mendo p with the
with the effects to make purple effects
which became really popular and is in
some of the most popular things now
um
stuff that we called garlic bud that i
don't know that it was garlic bud as far
as the strain but it was really that
crazy gnarly
it's like even more gnarly than deep
chunk where the the bracts grow like
from the center of the bud all the way
out like they're really long and narrow
and caked with resin and almost out
inside with the purple stripes and the
crazy funk and
um around then two was when i first saw
like big blue
um
and then you know going into the later
90s
uh we saw
monkey balls which people call deep
chunk
and
um
you know then right around then was when
you start to get the clone wave and that
was when we got things like sweat
train wreck
mr nice guy
green queen did you ever see snurvel up
there
i never saw nerville i've heard of it
but we did never
snow bud we did see
um
what was in the same old time period i
mean a little later was blue dream snow
cap
um
but there was one that was really
popular and humble called the mist which
was
supposedly like a matanuska mist thing
or something and
people really loved it who loved it now
people say it's minty it doesn't have
much but it was a really beautiful plant
it got these really nice buds that were
kind of shaped like this and they were
just chunky and covered in resin and i
crossed that with a big blue and i got a
couple great plants out of that that
were really nice but it's because they
kind of lean to the blue side on flavor
it wasn't the most
outstanding ship it was really popular
and humble for people to crop that that
mr nice train wreck
dream queen
did you see that uh did you used to see
that blueberry skunk
that uh remember sasso had that and like
like guys like tony mendo and craig and
all those dudes that way back when we're
kind of working with him did you ever
see any of that blueberry skunk that he
ran
i'm not sure man we had one up here that
my buddy called
super skunk
and it was not super skunk he said it's
blueberry northern lights
and it's very resonance and to me it
smells almost like penny royal
or like a hint of spearmint or something
it's it more in that realm of
like
i don't want to say herby but it's that
kind of a thing where it's like that
really cuts through you know how
peppermint is or penny royal if you bend
is it's like it's like that really
like sharp herbal funk and uh
that one was cool and i don't i mean i
don't know if that would have been the
same thing i mean he called it super
skunk he knew it was blueberry northern
lights so maybe that was kind of a
similar thing i don't know i don't think
i don't think that blueberry skunk was
related to anything we call blueberry
today
you know uh in terms of what became
famous and associated with
you know but yeah
but it was kind of like that i would say
like the late 90s there was kind of like
like he was saying like you
maybe the late 90s early 2000s was
really when like the name strain game
really began
because
like what he was saying i remember stuff
where most of the time weed was talked
about like where it was from
yeah
yeah i mean like um a lot of people
called sam that's
don't leave that because
that whole era when i talked about all
those clones at the same time everybody
was growing salmon creek big butt
so that was a popular what did that what
was the chirps like on that one
the me plane some people said it was
very skunky and loud yeah to me it was
it tasted to me really soapy and good
and i thought it was really good weed
yeah and the plant was unreal i watched
um
those same buddies of mine um
uh og foundation and ancient future i
watched them put in yellow starts like a
foot and a half tall yeah on like live
ninth and an average like five pounds
off that [ __ ] you know yeah it was it
was huge and that was in rows where they
weren't even spaced they could have just
kept going and going but they were just
you know gave them whatever four feet of
space and they were five five pound
mohawks of buds you know it wasn't
the dude who went missing up here
that they called rasta man he used to
grow
these plants and my buddy worked for him
um
who now is uh cowboy buds i believe cow
not cowboy butts cowboy chronic
uh and he
used to work for him and so they had
pictures on their fridge that were like
photocopied pictures
and i remember looking and being like
why what are what's in this is there
something in this picture i don't see
and they were like yeah it's weed and
i'm like where's the weed i only see the
trees you know yeah and they that's all
weed like all that is
also it's just a golden field with big
old madrone trees growing in the middle
of it and that's the weed and they were
like that's the weed and i was like holy
[ __ ] what does this guy pull and i'm
sure he was pulling 15 18 22 pounds or
something off of those because he it was
a straight he was one of the first
people who really had it and circulated
it in salmon creek
and um
it was yeah i was wild dude but uh but
that was a big one but that but that's
all to say that at a certain point you
didn't have to call a big bud you could
just say hey do you have do you you know
do you have salmon creek packs like sure
yeah
yeah um and i think i think that like i
mean we used to get and that the other
thing that i mean maybe i'll like rewind
a bit about a couple of things for
people that don't live up here area 101
is tim blake who ended up founding uh
emerald cup
that was his kind of like
you know was right on the highway right
on the 101 it was kind of like a
gathering place he threw like some mini
festivals and parties there he got in
trouble with the county numerous times
in the beginning
and uh i don't know how many of the
first um
the first emerald cups were there but it
was kind of like a gathering place north
of leytonville
you know and reggae on the river is like
right across the border uh from mendo
ins it's like basically like as soon as
you cross into humboldt from mendocino
county you're basically at
uh you're basically at the festival and
that's kind of where
everyone would gather
in uh in the middle of summer and see a
bunch of reggae it was kind of like one
of the few things that would like happen
up there
you know and when i was i'm a little
older than than gene i came out to see
the dead in the in the 90s and then
obviously there's a connection between
the bay and humboldt mendo
and so i got dragged up there
and i have in 95 i think it was 94 95
was the first time i came to mendo
um and i went to uh we went to reggae on
the river in humble and there's like two
things that will stand out for me
forever from being from the midwest and
coming from a police state one was a guy
walking up and down and selling buds and
the buds were like in a five gallon
paint bucket with the colas sticking out
the top and just like the ability for
someone to like walk around openly
and and show wheat
yeah which was so sketch where i came
from was like crazy and then if people
have never been there there's like uh
um
like the river runs through it right
there and you can kind of like look up
and there's like cliffs and where the
cliffs are that's where the 101 is you
know and so they'd have a bunch of at
certain parts of it at least and so
they'd have a bunch of cops up there
directing traffic and all that
and i had friends that were like in the
know
so we got like uh you know riverfront
camping which is kind of nice right and
i'm pulling tubes
you know i'm pulling i'm pulling a tube
and i look up and there's a cop looking
at me
right would you like where i'm from is
like an immediate bust
yeah yeah and he just waved
and let me go on about my business and
when i was like 18 or something like
that 19 that was like the most shocking
thing
for sure that a cop and i could like
look at each other
from a distance and like he sees me
doing drugs essentially yeah and he just
waves and goes on about it instead of
like radioing me in and i was like ready
to like throw the bong and run
because that was training
yeah that was like kind of like my that
was one of my first inclinations that
like living up here was kind of a total
bubble
yeah it is you know was it was really it
was a real bubble you know because it
wasn't like it was accepted people had a
lot of mis people would come here and
think that it was like weed was legal
and everybody liked it and everyone got
along and this and that and it was it
was still really underground it was
still cat and mouse with the cops
um the era that that gene is talking
about when his friends were starting to
grow weed nobody grew weed real like
i don't want to say nobody but for the
most part you grew weed in the woods
you grew weed in the manzanitas you you
didn't grow weed like right out your
back door
um you know you put some distance most
people most people would try to put some
distance between their house and where
they had their patch
because they didn't want to get raided
you know
and like he was saying carrying buckets
of water figuring out how to run water
from point a to point b even to get your
plants fed
um and you know back then
you know i don't know what prices he was
getting but weed was like 4 500 or 5 000
or more a pound
so you got away with 20 25 pounds of
shade grown manzanita weed
and you had a phenomenal year
yeah you know the scale of everything
was different in the sense that like you
didn't have to grow like some enormous
thing like you know you didn't have to
grow hundreds of pounds to make a living
you know if you got away with 20 or 30
you were set
you know and then the trim scene and all
that other stuff really wasn't that big
of a deal so everyone was kind of just
learning
and like the
like like train wrecks salmon creek big
bud the effects like you mentioned there
was some name things but there was still
a lot
i don't want to say until the purple
craze when when people started demanding
uniform pounds
because like with outdoor at least from
my experience up here
like people would grow the same strains
but they would mix pounds and mix phenos
yeah right so you'd get three four five
phenoes in a pound a lot of the time
you know and that was perfectly
acceptable
yeah to do that like so you'd have you'd
have weed from the instead of the weed
having a name
it would be like from whatever town or
area like oh this is some white thorn
this is some panther gap
this is from my buddies out on spy rock
you know and you know he mentioned that
too spy rock and spyroc and bell springs
are pretty famous
weed growing communities mostly because
they're mountainous and they're way out
in the middle of [ __ ] nowhere and so
they're remote they're hard to get to
so cannabis really wasn't like like
like permitted out here it was more like
a kind of a cat and mouse game and there
was a few enough people that you could
get away with it
um you know if you were careful
but everyone we know got camped
sometimes
i mean there used to be an old joke that
you would like you would plant three
gardens and one was for you and one was
the cops and one was for the thieves
and you hoped that one of them came
through
in a way
you know because you could go like the
same thing you could st you could go
you know on on you know harvest moon or
whatever with full moons during fall you
know you could get people out there that
could go with some contractor bags and
they could steal 10 or 15 or 20 pounds
and back then that was that was a ton of
money yeah so you could go and check on
your crop and it's gone
the whole thing is gone
trauma
you know yeah and at that point even
when the when the clones started taking
off and it was like everybody wanted to
grow
train wreck it wasn't because oh if i
have train wreck i'm gonna get a higher
price or people will want my weed faster
you could sell any weed you had it just
had to be dried right and it had to be
mature and it had to be trimmed good you
know yeah
it was only the only reason people were
growing clones then was reliability so
if you would grow a train wreck you knew
you were gonna get a good crop with a
lot of weed and you liked how it how it
was to cut down and how it was to trim
and then
you know it was reliable like you know
you're gonna get something good out of
this so you grow the clone and and then
also somebody tries this clone it
doesn't work well for them in their
garden or the way they grow and they try
this other clone and it works really
good for them so they're like okay so
then that's why people got stuck with
the clones
the first clone that carried a premium
in this area was urkel and urkel was the
one
that totally shot everything to [ __ ] as
far as the
the um the diversity because before that
somebody was like oh i like this clone
and somebody was like oh i like that
clone and urkel came and it was like
well that's cool but this urkel you can
sell right now for like 48 a pound half
wet
so you're selling 12 ounce pounds and
you're like it might look good if you
don't know how to grow it yet and you
think it's done at seven weeks and it's
really not
but it didn't matter as long as you
could get it to go
at first it didn't even really matter if
it went purple but it after just a
little couple runs worth of time going
by
if you could get it to get dark
people would show up and they'd and
you'd be like it's still wet and they'd
be like well let me see it and you'd be
like well can they do no just take that
put it in the bag they're like we'll
take it down south and we'll dry it in
our bedroom dude and we don't
that it's not going to be a pound when
it gets done because people were so
hungry for it
and uh that's super accurate because
before urkel before the purple wave and
probably 0.30405
was kind of that was kind of that wave
he's right every good type of weed sold
if it was grown decently well and it was
dried it was dried well and it was
trimmed well
people would just there wasn't a name
strain game people weren't coming up
here with like okay you need to buy x
amount of peas and it could be these
four strains
it was like go get some good weed and
bring it back
yeah you know
and it's seedless and it's trimmed
and the the day it's ready
you know it's it's all a matter of if
somebody
of scheduling it had nothing to do with
whether or not you could find a buyer
you have the right product or any of
that stuff it was like there's weed okay
it's gone and then
everything would be you know back then
it was there was only one big wave of
harvest the outdoor not the debt
and so it wasn't this constant thing of
there always being weeds so it would be
like there would be a bunch of weed
never a flood and then it would be all
drought for most of the year and i
remember being like okay it's august
or july or september and like like for
reggae on the river we used to save our
best
uh
you know og foundation got me doing that
because he'd be like oh this is my
reggae stash i'd be like oh [ __ ] i
better save a reggae stash too so you'd
have like some buds that you came across
through the year that were like the best
weed and you'd be like oh i'm gonna take
two grams of this and set it aside or
i'm gonna take five grams of this and
set it aside and then if you could show
up a reggae on the river the first
weekend in august and have a sack of
weed like this it was just like epic
because people were like
[ __ ] how do you have that you know
stash some people would still have weed
and people who were either had
the good fortune to have a ton of weed
or
who like had certain um either
connections or lack of connections where
they just wound up with wheat in august
like you would have weed but it was a
big deal
in the summer months to have weed back
then yeah and this is no this is before
cell phones too
it's before the internet or any kind of
forums so for a bunch of people in
humble so in southern humble and mendo
like wrecking on the river was not only
like a
it was two days back then but it wasn't
just like a big weekend of fun you could
actually meet someone
where like they wanted wheat
right where like everyone you knew grew
weed for the most part if you were in
those little circles and so a lot of
people made a bunch of connections to
other parts of the state or wherever
wherever you know because they would
bump into people and like like he was
just saying like you know they'd smoke
some weed and they'd be like oh my god
this is amazing can you get me more of
this
let me give you my number and you can
call me after this event and like let me
try to come up and get a few pounds let
me try to get this let me try to get
that because it was like there was so
much demand there was a little bit of
indoor going on for sure but not
nothing in comparison to demand
and when outdoor came in i wouldn't even
say it was a flood there was just more
weed
yeah it would never flood it would never
was just
and then it was unavailable and that was
like the two you can get it
if you had good weed for years and years
if you had good weed you could probably
sell it within three to five days of it
hitting the bag without too much effort
and it didn't really matter what it was
um it mattered if it was nice or not but
it but the name game the specifics of it
like i said you could get you could sell
somebody 10 pounds it was a mix of eight
different phenos
and if it was good it would go fine
yeah you know if it was good
you were good
all the stuff they look for now
no that that didn't really matter
um and so as a result of that there was
like a bunch of diversity
because there was a lot of hill people
that had their random strains that
they'd grown for a long time or their
friends had given them you know not
everybody bred but
uh you know gene and i have talked about
this before kind of one of the most
common ways people would breed because
they grew from seed every year is every
two or three or four years they'd be
like oh i should make some fresh seed
and they'd take all their sexed males
that they vegeta pots before they
planted in their holes and they'd put
those sex males like on some other part
of the hill
away downwind you know and then they'd
have their females growing in their
patch and a lot of times they would go
and collect male collect male pollen and
then bring it back and like
brush it on their favorite females
bottom branches from that year
and mark them
and then you know when they harvested
you know they'd get x amount of hundreds
or you know whatever seeds and that was
their next two three years worth of
supply
until they were like oh these are
getting kind of old i'm running a little
low i should do that again this year
which if you do the math you realize
that those those things that are the
modern weed
like the most modern weed like it's the
new it's cookies or it's whatever it is
you go yeah it's probably only really
in a lot of cases was only a handful of
generations
displaced from origin
you know like a lot of afghanis they're
not actually 30 generations after
afghanistan a lot of them might only be
three or four generations later because
someone's like oh [ __ ] my seed's seven
years old you're like well the ship
should in 81 it showed up in 85
so then you go well when i was seeing it
it was 94 95 96. like [ __ ] somebody only
made seed twice since it showed up from
afghanistan or three or four times like
there wasn't even that much improvement
which
uh was what i was what i was gonna say
too about like all the weed back then
you go oh it didn't have to be special
it was like it didn't have to be special
but if you saw the weed now that was in
those bags that only had to be dried
good and only had to be mature and
seedless you'd look at it and you go
what is this one yeah what is that
it wasn't like the weed was undeveloped
in in a genetic sense or it was
unrefined in a breeding sense it was
like no [ __ ] was bomb and and we
actually
what we have now that's our very best
stuff is kind of the remnants of what
was then kind of just normal
weed you know like because a lot of this
stuff that was
uh in the hills in california was like
really [ __ ] good and everything that
amsterdam got was just them going oh
whoa they have crazy [ __ ] in oakland
they have crazy [ __ ] and humble they
have crazy [ __ ] in santa cruz and then
all that stuff they took it over there
and then didn't even really have
experience with it
and and tried to do some stuff and some
people hit and some people missed and
then people wound up going oh
this modern weed it that's so high in
thc it's so heavy yielding and you're
like no the ship that i saw that was
bred twice after afghanistan was already
like what people now look at and go oh
it's holy [ __ ] it's space weed it's like
yeah that was what that was what you
know like that was what came over
there's not genetics don't work in a way
where traits just miraculously appear
although they do it's very rare and a
lot of that really good [ __ ] it was it
was already
it was already there in what we were
seeing at reggae on the river and
somebody sat from santa cruz that showed
up to sell their pound or whatever you
know like stuff was
stuff was crazy i think probably when it
showed up you know and i i would add to
that that uh i was smiling when he said
that because
one of the one of you know when you
apply capitalism to all this stuff right
a lot of the modern breeding
is when you know you get some stuff and
it's amazing and you're like okay well i
spent a lot of time and a lot of effort
and this is a result of me being really
smart
when we all know it's like it's a lot of
accidents and you're already starting
with good working material to begin with
you know
a lot
yeah i mean
whole traits out of thin air you can
like if you want way more resin there is
ways to go okay i'm gonna take a plant
that gets way more trichomes per square
centimeter and i'm gonna take this one
that gets huge heads but it doesn't have
very many combine them and wind up with
the best of both worlds and have
something that has way more resin with
way bigger heads and your numbers shoot
way up
but you still have to have those two
traits have to be there and separately
they were still pretty [ __ ] good
because you already had one with a whole
shitload of resin but the heads weren't
huge and you had one with huge [ __ ]
heads so both of them were already
pretty good [ __ ] weed right so like
and in a lot of cases when we find
something that's like that you're really
just finding that plant that already had
the combination in the first place and
you you might think you made it through
combination but really if you would have
grown 200 girls of one side you'd go oh
it was already in there and then i
thought i made it and you didn't [ __ ]
make it you just found it you know so
it's like
really with all that it's really like um
you're really kind of more discovering
than you are creating you're trying to
find some good [ __ ] it's like you're not
you're not making the gold you're just
[ __ ] digging through some [ __ ] to
pull out some nuggets you know yeah
that's for sure
and i think to some degree that's why
the 90s kind of remains like a lot of
the backbone of modern breeding
was because of all that diversity
because it was before the name game book
because
you know like the last 10 years of
reading not everyone there's obviously
outliers and people that do different
stuff but like in most modern breeding
it's like take all the most popular
things i can find and blend them
together and hopefully i get a little
version that people have some clout with
right where you know weed in the 90s was
back could be vastly different because
there wasn't pressure on it for it to be
the same
it just had just good it just had to be
good
and the other thing is it didn't even
have to be pretty
it just had to be good and by good it's
like if it got you high huh
your life smoked dude yeah your body i
don't know
back in the day people who bought weed
when they showed up they smoked the [ __ ]
can you imagine look at that you you
could not sell weed without them smoking
a few joints with you and making sure it
burned right making sure it wasn't harsh
making sure their customers weren't
going to be pissed off so a lot of times
you could go at some weed and they could
be like oh this is a suspect i don't
know about this weed and you're like
well let's roll some joints and hang out
for a second and then if it was good
weed
they i mean in modern times it's like
name
look
does it have any larf does it have nose
what's your price point okay
and like [ __ ]
shitty buyers have you guys had to hang
out with for like two hours watching a
movie just to do a transaction that [ __ ]
sucks i mean it depends you know it's
it's like it it uh you know there was a
whole industry of it up here there was a
lot of people that didn't like to do
that and so the people that were even
the people that were willing to go to
the bay
right like i remember
um you know going out spy rock and you
could go talk to people up there
um that like you know that they had
indoor they had big underground indoors
and stuff like that and you could get
weed for like 36
which was dirt cheap and i used to tell
them that i would like take it to the
bay and i would get way more for it
and they'd be like but you have to do
that
if you come to my driveway and we and i
can be at my house and you give me this
i'm happy
yeah
as a 22 year old 23 year old kid i was
like that's so dumb you know and i'd go
to the city and i'd make my margin and i
party and i have a great time and then i
hit my 30s or 40s or whatever and i'm
like oh man that makes perfect sense if
you can just come to my door
and be fair
and then go away i'm cool because like i
got dinner to cook and i got some kids
to take care of and i don't want to go
all the way down to the [ __ ] day
you know and then the fair away and it's
still 50 and 8 for most people you know
yeah it's still
three prices when when when pounds were
about to hit basically six grand
wholesale
and the it was like whoa eights are
worth [ __ ] 50 and 60 dollars that's
[ __ ] crazy but at least pounds are
worth 6 grand to the farmer
yeah and now
you still pay now people are selling
hundred dollar eights yeah ten people
i don't know you know this shit's really
not worth any money you know
that's crazy
that's where i have friends that joke
with me right now that they can go into
a dispensary and they can go buy a 600
ounce
that's
or they could go buy a pound that's
probably better for cheaper
yeah
yeah i saw 600 an ounce weed and it was
[ __ ] hilarious yeah i was like
i mean i understand maybe that there
could be something that would be worth
that if it was like
really hard to grow and it [ __ ] took
24 weeks and you've never tried anything
like this but it's like it's just some
bud that people used to sell for really
cheap and it's not even as good of a
version and it's like selling for 600 an
ounce and you're like [ __ ] okay i mean
the sad part is is that you would think
with legalization typically it makes
quality go up and price go down
because you take the risk out of the
equation
you know and there's there's a risk
pricing in there but so far with
cannabis the way we've structured
california it's kind of done the
opposite
weed in general is way worse than the
215 era and it's definitely more
expensive
yeah it'd be different if you were
producing a molecule right like you're
producing a molecule so like at scale it
doesn't really matter you get rid of all
barriers and obstacles and [ __ ] and then
all of a sudden you're going to be like
dude we're producing this molecule like
[ __ ] crazy and it's it's not illegal
anymore so yeah we dropped the price
still producing it and then but with
wheat it's like weed doesn't scale very
well i mean we
we've
so hard to scale that even when you go
from seeing somebody who grows like like
the best weed that i've ever seen almost
every time comes from people who have
like less than like a dozen lights if
they're growing indoors
and
yeah the one light is we used to have a
we used to have a bunch of friend mutual
friends that would
you know they would work for older cats
and they would run these 1500 lighters
right
but they would come get their head stash
off me because i had a 10 lighter
and we used to joke that like you just
couldn't get
off that hundred light you couldn't get
as good a weed
you couldn't give it as much attention
you couldn't whatever it was it was just
like the little
minor fi and that's kind of what
happened is like people used to be able
to make a really good living off 20 30
40 100 a couple hundred pounds
and then you could treat that stuff
right you could dry it right you could
cure it right you weren't overwhelmed
you could have just a few people helping
you and you could do the little things
that kept it nice and now they're like
how do i grow these 10 licenses i have
and i've got 2 000 pounds coming down
and
costs are through the roof and i have to
do osha and all this other [ __ ] and what
suffers is the weak
you know they start looking around at
like what ways they can cut corners
and you know it's they're not evil
necessarily by any means they're just
trying to survive because shit's all
rough
and or or they just don't they've grown
100 or 200 pounds their whole career and
that's been happy for them and then they
get asked to grow 2 000 pounds
and they just don't know how to scale up
you know what because their system that
they had for them when it was smaller
worked amazing
but their system didn't scale so you try
to scale it up
it's like cooking
you you like oh i'm just gonna double
the recipe
it doesn't really work like that you
can't just double recipes you know you
like you sometimes you have to do it in
batches so if you can have somebody
and say okay you're going to do you're
going to do like this many runs and
maybe you're going to get more runs in
or something then people can keep it
exactly the same and then everybody has
a ceiling so some people can scale a lot
better than others because of the the
way that they do things
like as simple as i grow i probably
could have scaled pretty well because i
don't do anything very special and
that's part of why i'm able to get weed
that i really like because i just kind
of let it
do its thing so it's mostly the soil
and then i really try to make sure to
really like pay a lot of attention to
harvesting and and drying it
and uh so like it's it's doable but it's
still i could still never do enough to
be a big brand you know i just couldn't
do it let's let's let's be clear too
right so
um i mean i came out here when i was in
my early 20s so i didn't grow up here
like he did but my experience is most
weed growers back then were back to the
landers
hippies
uh people that decided to grow weed
because logging ended and they needed a
way to support their family
you know
these aren't people that are like
amazing at logistics
you know these aren't like like
sergeants that are like okay you three
do this and this is the efficient way to
do that and this and that and everything
else they just figured out some kind of
way that worked for them it's at a
smaller medium scale and then you try to
like commercialize that and all of a
sudden their experience is only so good
at that part because
now it becomes logistics
now it becomes like you know like now
you're a conductor now you're trying to
like move the orchestra around and like
you're used to kind of just winging it
you know and even
when stuff becomes really super
competitive in that kind of a that kind
of a thing
a lot of the people it's like back when
weed was rare if we got weed and it
didn't suck and it was good genetics you
were like wow this is really good weed
but then when things get more and more
competitive a lot of the people too who
you're like oh they have killer weed and
like it's it's like you're like well but
is it like is it really that killer but
it has to go up against people who are
so knowledgeable
and are going okay well you know this
you gotta have this particular watering
schedule and this dry back and all these
different like very specific parameters
and then it's like
it's like yeah their weed was really
good but it's not it's still not
competitive and i'm not saying that's
everybody but that's a whole section of
people too where all of a sudden now
when there's a huge flood you're like
well this weed is just not like there's
always been people who who
would would be like oh dude i have this
weed and i i'd look at it and i'd be
like oh cool it's nice you know but at
the same time i'm like it's not
competitive though
you know and it's something that i can't
i like can't bring myself
to tell people that
i just am like yeah it's it's good you
know but like you could you you kind of
you just kind of look at the reality and
you go [ __ ] have you seen what people
are doing
like people's [ __ ] is crazy
and we some of us have always been able
to do it like like i was saying like
people i know ladies who had one light
or two lights and every time they would
have weeds you'd just be like holy [ __ ]
and to this day people doing all the
most scientific tricks they can't they
can't do any better than these ladies
with their two lighters or their four
lighters or their one lighters still the
best weed ever but
that was never everybody and there was a
point when if you had weed you were like
yeah
and this is the funny thing like with
with especially with old school growers
and growers in general everybody always
thinks their weed is the best like i've
never met i've only met probably a
couple people who can look at wheat
objectively and go oh it's good because
of this but i missed here and i missed
there and this would have been a little
better like this and and to really be
objective and like and and and logically
look at stuff it's generally like this
is mine and it's the best you know yeah
and so that's really i think been
something too that is a big
barrier for people to get past
um
to be able to look at stuff and go well
[ __ ] maybe i need to
maybe i need to figure out i need to ask
people more questions i need to be able
to look at this and be able to and be
able to like tell the difference between
what this one is and what that one is
and how do i make mine look like that
one because mine looks like this one and
that's like you know that's an important
part of really doing any kind of process
to really break it down it's like you go
to a restaurant and
they're not really doing very good
business and you're like dude people
want food especially like here you know
and i've seen like all these places like
pizza places or whatever it is and
they're like i don't know you know we
make great pizza and nobody's buying it
and i'm like guess what people [ __ ]
buy great pizza like
you don't have to twist people's arm to
buy a [ __ ] pizza they want the pizza
they just don't want your pizza and the
only
your pizza be the pizza people want is
to like ask somebody like dude how do
you can i maybe like get the starter for
the dough
and then like how do you do your dough
and what temperature is your oven and
what is in your sauce can i get the
recipe for your sauce and you know like
those little things and what's i made it
like this what happened what went wrong
and then all of a sudden like in this
area and not so knows this if you had
good [ __ ] pizza in where i live
you would stay in business for [ __ ]
ever and you would make it
right oh yeah but
there's been every pizza place has come
and gone and some of them are good here
and there and like it's like okay you go
there and you go oh this is great and
it's inconsistent and this is just an
analogy to to what's up with weed too
you know like you really have to [ __ ]
um
constantly try to figure out what it is
now if you were one of the people
who just happened to [ __ ] make some
[ __ ] and it came out really good and
everybody loves it then [ __ ] go with
it if the recipe works it works but if
it's not working you got to know when to
look at it and be like [ __ ] what what do
i need to do you like you you have you
ever watched like what's that bar rescue
or those shows
you know what i mean like the gordon
ramsay he comes in he's like no dude
we're going to make a [ __ ] bruschetta
and it's going to be bread and you're
going to put tomatoes on it and balsamic
vinegar and some [ __ ] basil you guys
are making this [ __ ] crazy concoction
and nobody likes it and you look at it
[ __ ] simple just stop doing all this
weird [ __ ] and it's the same with the
with weed and the weed market you know
it's just it's it's a weird it's a weird
thing and then there's so much
that is done on that level and so little
that's done on the really crazy level
that you know it's it's like
i'm convinced if you're really still on
that level that people still want your
weed but if you're just a little bit
below it it's like what the [ __ ]
what are you going to do
networking too is tough yeah there's
there's an aspect where
people kind of went from
like trying to grow the best weed they
possibly could uh which
never happened exclusively there was
plent but you know there's a lot of
people that like you know now they just
try to grow like decent commercial
you know they're trying to grow decent
commercial at scale and like and the
decent commercial is rough you know and
so
like the name strain game part of the
reason why like you know the purple
craze happened and then right after that
the kush and the sour and and and cookie
and all that
um part of the reason why that exploded
so much in our area was because people
wanted to just give the broker what they
wanted
like if the broker was like all 58 of
these look good i'll take them all
you know and then they look at this
other guy's stuff and he's got some nice
stuff and they end up taking ten when he
leaves the guy that had the variety
looks at the dude that got cleared out
and was like can i get that from you
what is that i want to get the thing
that the dude is going to come and clear
me out
whatever that is i want it
yeah
that's the sourdough starter for your
crust you know yeah that's like that one
that's the [ __ ] sauce right there you
know and that's what what's funny about
urkel is that there was a time
in which
there was an endless demand for indoor
urkel from our area right and basically
like every big grower i knew
ran indoors of urkel
and then when the purple craze ended and
it went on to sour and cush and these
other things fast forward ten years and
there was like six dudes that held onto
urkel
when we both knew dozens
and dozens of people everyone had it
that was reg that was what if you had
weave like probably circle yeah or a
very
type of weed you know there was
blue dragon and purple nepal and grape
ape and it but it was like purple with a
sweet fruit loopy you know
it's also that i should we should
mention too it's also that kind of thing
where like that craze was one of the
first times where
people wanted to give their own name to
something whether it was different or
not or whether it was just a slight
variation or a bag seat of whatever
there had to be gdp and gr and grape ape
and purple urkel and purple dragon and
you know and platinum purple and
you know and it was like this thing
where it was like people it was like the
start of people wanting to differentiate
their little thing
didn't matter because it's very
different
yeah because the name had worked you're
like well
[ __ ] people you say it's purple urkel
like everybody everybody wants it you
know the names were really working and
it was the same like in la if you had
some weed that was really good you just
call it such and such kush
and then to combine the two when the
purple craze ended people were like oh
people don't want this blackberry
anymore i should call it blackberry kush
because the cush name was
this is the this is the purple kush this
is the blackberry kush
it's just like that cush you want but
darker electric it was
also a purple flow cut up here that
finished in early september
that was originally purple flow and this
stuff must have been i don't know like
five percent thc or something you
couldn't get high off it it smelled
really nice and sweet it smelled really
similar to what the blackberry clone was
but it turned way darker
and it was done so early and fast and it
got tons of these huge buds everywhere
and everybody started calling that
blackberry kush and online i've seen a
lot of people
call that one blackberry and i'm like no
that was the purple flow it was purple
flow for like maybe a year or two and
then all of a sudden everybody went it
kind of smells like that blackberry
clone and the blackberry wasn't very
stony but it wasn't as no stone as this
[ __ ] flow clone this flow clone
nothing it was like you could not hide
off this [ __ ] yeah and uh and then after
a while then that became the blackberry
clone and i would ask people like so the
one that didn't get you high at all this
blackberry i'm like when did it finish
because the other one was like early
october it was still very fast and would
want to autoflower but this one had thin
leaves and it was very purple way more
purple where the other one was very
frosty and pretty almost like a bubba
but with a little bigger features and it
tasted really good didn't get you that
high but people didn't give a [ __ ]
because you smoked something else to get
stoned but it tasted so good and then
the other one came in and it got really
big for like two seasons here and
everyone grew it and then all of a
sudden everybody was like you know what
i'm literally like not getting any
[ __ ] effects from this okay
and there's and then
he mentioned it before but there's an
aspect we should probably talk about
when when the name game happened
in the beginning of any of these name
games that occur if it has the name and
it's and it's similar or the right cut
it just all goes
like if you know it just went right and
then as more and more people get it the
quality has to be nicer and so sometimes
people would have a hard time getting
like purples to turn purple in the
middle of summer because their rooms
would be too hot and it wasn't like you
know people didn't have great like
environmental controls back then or
something like that and then you'd get
some like green purple that was like
harder to sell and so like that's kind
of like what happens when like when a
market starts to get saturated with a
particular strain is like the best
versions of it still go
but it loses that like if it's it it
goes
because like early on if you had kush or
you had sour you had purple or whatever
and you had it it went
and then as more and more people got it
quality became more important and you
actually had to have like really nice
version of it for it to go as easily
yeah
you know
um
but you know that's kind of like
that's
there's an aspect to it where it's
you know he's right in the sense where
you know the name game happens and stuff
gets stuff gets all mixed up but it
really is
like you know if you've been around for
a long time you can see a lot of
similarities in today's weed mashed
together that's really old weed
you know like we really actually haven't
gone all that that far away from things
i will agree with that we've mashed it
up in various different ways and we've
added all kinds of different names which
just kind of obscures
but we really haven't we really haven't
like people think now weeds better than
it's ever been
and that's kind of probably just patting
yourself on the back
yeah you know weed's been really good
for a long time
it just mattered whether or not you had
access to really good weed more people
have access now than before
but i don't know that weed's any better
than it is before
you know in fact it might have been
better 20 years ago
on average
you know on average i would probably
have to agree
with what we have now
yeah you know and then there's another
thing too when it comes to names and
stuff like that where it's like
obviously we're in like the the
marketing era where everything has to be
candy or cake or or desserts or sugar or
like evoke some kind of image
um but you know back then it was like
you know he mentioned it before but like
you could get some weed that like gave
you like brow sweat
and you'd call it the sweat
i'm not even saying that's it but that's
like how a lot of names came about
nobody would name it
nobody would name anything sweat today
nobody would name anything dog [ __ ]
nobody name would name anything like
there's a million names that would that
would never work
you know
um i mean the mendo p that i found it
you know i i didn't know exactly what it
was so i just called it it was purple
from mendo
so it became mendo purple
and at one point i was talking to my
buddy who showed me some weed that was
really balm and it was like
it was kind of smelled to me like
a mix between with like what i call the
legget purp smell and the and like the
the purple urkel smell in a sense
and my buddy
was like yeah i got this from this guy
on belle springs he's he's the guy who
because at one point people were saying
oh
urkel is just a plant from the mendo
from the mendo perps right and i've
never seen no perps
and so uh my buddy showed me the buds
and i was like damn this is bomb and it
was some kind of balm afghani it was
super good [ __ ] and this guy was like
yeah i'm the i'm the guy who um that
that the mendo perps came from
and what's funny is i don't even think
the guy was lying i think he heard about
the mendo perps that was yours that got
popular
and that people were rumoring urkel came
from
and his weed he probably had called
mendo perps because it's a pretty vague
[ __ ] name right it's like black
afghani very poor very vague yeah
whatever it would or like big bud or you
know what i mean snow bud like these
things could easily be reused by
somebody like um imagine now when you
try to name strains and you google it
people come up with the same [ __ ]
idea for a lot of yeah it's really hard
and i mean even it was even regional
right like like you just said snow bud
like if you got snow bud from eugene it
was the eugene snow
if you got it in the humboldt it was the
humboldt snow
if you got it somewhere else in oregon
it was called oregon snow and the
humboldt guys and the eugene guys and
the oregon guys all thought that theirs
was the first one and everyone else got
theirs later
yeah because it's where they saw it
first
yeah you know and so i was talking to
caleb at one point and i told him about
that guy and i asked him like about like
the perps what is it and i was just
curious because he
he seemed to have done a lot of work
with all the different things and goes
dude the mendo purpose is totally
different than the urkel it's not even
in the same ballpark
and there's no way that there's any
truth to that and i was like oh okay and
it's the same as like when one of the
first times i really bullshitted with
them a lot of the show i was like yeah i
go when i was in maui
in the late 90s or the early right
around 2000 somewhere in there there was
this weed that my buddy lance used to
always have that he called dog
and he was always like this is the dog
and i was always like
damn this is some fire [ __ ] weed and
i wasn't really familiar with any of
like the cam and the diesel and all that
[ __ ] came later for me because i wasn't
seeing a lot of clones
and i was seeing more like i said that
lineup of the humble clones those more
like commercial ones that were around
and [ __ ] and so
i remember talking to caleb and being
like yeah i don't know like i might have
because this is after i'd been reading
[ __ ] online and stuff i was like it
might be
the it might be the um the original dog
bud i'm not sure because these dudes
were in oregon and they were in maui and
they had it and then years later i was
able to talk to my buddy gabe from over
there and he goes no i know the dude
who had that and he says that he found
it in a bag of chem dog 91 and he found
scene and he popped it and they called
that the dog in maui and that was right
around that time period and i was like
all right well that makes sense but the
names are so trippy because them just
going oh we got it out of chem dog we're
going to call it dog then you get that
weed and then you hear the stories and
you're like well so is it that and it's
so easy to like think
that that could be the real
lineage and then be like well no because
this information disproves it but that's
why it's good to keep track of all of it
to go okay and then it turns out [ __ ]
that dog that's really good [ __ ] weed
right it's a really good clone like yeah
and then years and years later
caleb runs a bunch of uh you know a
couple rooms of chem 91 s ones
and a bunch of them look like that maui
dog cut
yeah so of course because
because you know so it probably was
like you could put some pictures that he
took right up against some really nice
pictures of that maui dog from 99 or
2000 or whatever and they look almost
identical
and so you could imagine it being bag
seed
coming out of
coming out of that weed
you know and that's one of the things
like that's one of the coolest things to
me about s1s is when if you just if you
do that you can if you do an s1 because
i've gone up there and i've seen
you know a half a room of of urkel s
ones and half a room of mendo ps ones
and you can tell just by if you're a
breeder at all that these things are not
related
like you don't see any similar
expressions whatsoever right
yeah and that's the same thing with this
feed that was that that he was calling
mendo perps and saying oh i made the
mendo purpose i don't even think that he
was i mean this [ __ ] was some nasty
mendo
perps it just was not mendo perps it
wasn't
the same thing to this day i'm still
like [ __ ] i wish i could get some of
those seeds because they were these buds
that were like
way chunkier than any of this other
stuff and a really cool obviously
afghani probably pure
really sweet really nice but probably
totally unrelated to both
strains you know what i mean sure but
like
not not without value just because it
has a funny name or a funny story you're
still like [ __ ] i want to get my hands
on that
on that stuff and you know that at this
point is probably gone like he's
probably from now from from a long time
ago he probably like ah purple went out
the door that was in the purple craze
yeah and then
he probably started growing diesel and
didn't even keep his seeds you know
because i mean it's i mean the purple
craze had
what 15 or 18-year break between when it
was hella popular before it got hella
popular again
right yeah 15 years something like that
it went you know 0506 everybody
i mean i don't know
cookies cookies brought back purple weed
in 2011
yeah so it it really only took a little
break but as far as like urkel type
purple even sweet purple like gelato it
took between urkel and gelato to be back
where people wanted sweet perps and not
doughy perps or whatever not so missed a
big era where there were a few of us
like me and bodhi and a few of us that
were only doing purples
so yeah we didn't let it die but it
definitely died down i just mean in the
sense what i was more speaking of in
terms of like
like the market demanding it so much
not that it was
down but like there was an era when we
were talking about like in the mid 2000s
where like purple like purple weed was
the thing
and everyone wanted purple wheat and
like purple weed never went away
but like i would say the last couple
years
all of a sudden all my friends have been
like well i guess purple wheat is is is
in again
people say my weed out you know i
haven't heard i haven't heard oh this is
fire but it's like not purple enough
in a long time
but that's what you used to hear about
that summer grown urkel
you'd be looking for it's earth but it
like it didn't it didn't darken up on
you you know like it didn't get because
it was hot in summer you know so it'd
stay kind of greenish and they're like
oh it's not quite purple
darks that's green grapes we don't want
that yeah
yeah the purple craze too is interesting
because
it was the weed that made people want it
initially it wasn't so much that it was
purple
um and it really popularized stuff being
purple for a while but it's trippy
because like
we in mendo there was always a lot of
purple weed all the way back because the
purple in a lot of cases comes out of
these old afghani types
and so people had purple it wasn't that
it wasn't a thing it was that there was
no premium on it people were like some
of them are green
some of them are purple some of them are
50 50 and it didn't really matter at all
so some people had had like real
varieties
that were like they're purple like this
[ __ ] is purple my buddy jed and his and
his dad they had like
this purple that was just straight solid
purple and it ran really late and it was
really peppery and dank
um not so might know these guys they're
from between like here and willets but
it was like the most
purple
um
like it was so saturated you know but
that's like also how like big blue was
which i saw as early as the
as the mid 90s you roll a joint you lick
the paper and it bleeds through and the
whole paper turns purple where you lick
it
and um and then even that way back
before that like you asked me what's the
first weed i can remember like 1989 was
a common popular clone which when i say
common and popular i'm from a small area
yeah with a group of people so
it's popular and common if it comes from
leggett and willits it doesn't mean that
there's 2000 it's not like now where
it's like oh it's blue dream it's
[ __ ] all over the states or whatever
it just means that like
it made its rounds and it wasn't just
one or two families that had it it was
actually something that was like you
know it got around and uh so as far back
as the 80s there was already a clone
that was around and that people were
really liking that was like it was
purple and it was kind of more of a red
or purple as opposed to a blue or purple
it was really [ __ ] pretty
but um
yeah
on top of the weed that would turn
purple just naturally there was a lot of
afghan blended stuff in mendo that would
turn purple with the cold
uh if you let it go if it got a light
frost or something in october especially
if you took like all your what people
used to take their their what we call
the first cut
and they would take all the big tops
first because you were scared of those
rotting you know and you wanted to get
some money in the barn and then you
would let your seconds your second and
third round sit and a lot of times and
you and you'd want those to ripen up a
bit more and so a lot of times those
would go through some more cold nights
and those cold nights would bring out
that like latent afghan
um you know purpleness so there was two
things there was like weed that just
turned purple naturally in most
conditions and that was like that was
around and then there was a lot of weed
that if you grew it outdoor and you let
it run late and it went through some
cold weather that it would turn purple
but it took some like in the 30s nights
to make it pop and sometimes it's like
being too like basically overdone and
created and not really that good a weed
at that point like a real purple a real
purple weed has to be like you could
like grow it indoor
and it'll be purple or you can grow it
outdoor and cut it before it turns to
[ __ ] and it'll be purple like even urkel
outside
didn't like to get um
purple as much
indoor it was easier to get it purple
and outside
it for whatever reason and i've seen
this with a lot of things like hindu
inside would get a little bit purple but
outside it would never get a touch of
purple right
and then um
it could i don't know if it's like the
spectrum or what what it is because i
know it's not just cold because indoor
you usually have it more controlled
but um but urkel was one of those ones
where
it wasn't that great in the weather it
it was very kind of hairy on the inside
and it would like to start to get a
little bit of mold outdoor
if you were not in the greatest area and
then you would have to cut your real big
chunk
and then when you left you would leave
the small buds like he's saying and then
they would turn really dark and it would
be like your little buds that weren't
that great even if some of them were
little people like this that weren't
trimmed very well but it would be really
dark and people would be like those are
the ones we want that stuff oh
people wanted color
at that point and that that but that was
like her time when color mattered was
with urkel whereas before that it was
like a purple you know green is a bomb
and then
we want darks and that was that was a
weird time
let's start moving in
to nowadays what you're working with up
in mendo now currently gene like what
you're seeing around the scene nowadays
as far as breeding goes what you're
finding around nowadays that that you're
enjoying breeding with
other things comes to mind
there's some p there's some people who
have cool things that are from back in
the era we're talking about where they
they used to have um
cool stuff and then you talk to them and
they're like they were actually like
into plants and stuff so they've kept
things
and so there's like cool little things
here and there that kind of pop out
um and i always try to like check them
out just to see if because every once in
a while something's really really dank
yeah um
but like for the most part i really try
to focus on like digging through the
stuff i have because i know that i
haven't done a good job of really
um exploring all the stuff that i make
because i'll make a lot of stuff and
then i'll
i'll pop whatever looks really the most
attractive right away yeah all breeders
that do it for a while have a pile
of
it's one thing
but
your instincts aren't always
going to be correct so like i'm always
like i try to avoid trying to pick up
too much stuff here and there
so i try to kind of like take what i
consider to be my ones that are really
like the backbone of what i've done
and then
do outcrosses with them here and there
to make cool stuff but then keep really
trying to like focus on them so those
ones are like like pina grape soda skunk
the jarrow and root beer stuff which are
kind of almost the same
um
the lime stuff which is really my
favorite and then i have like the
various kush lines that i do
um
that are more like the og type stuff and
then like the more little odd like the
sky cuddler kush or sky cut their double
kush and
um those ones are all ones that i try
i'm trying to like
find what's really the best in them and
take them those directions and then you
know i put out a little bit of them for
other people to do the same thing when
they're a little looser so that it's not
all left up completely to me saying this
is where it should go because some
people they like
everybody likes something different
somebody wants to
somebody wants the straight og one and
i'm like
i like some influence from the og but
og's a thing so i'm not really making
anything if i make this og so i like
have it where
i did one not so saw a little bit of the
og work that i was doing when he was up
last time
it's like very it's very kind of
targeted there and it's kind of reached
that point where it's good
the high i like a little bit better
um than og just but some people maybe
wouldn't because they want the more real
intensity but it's a little bit more
clear i'd say
um
but uh yeah i mean i just i'm always
trying to like figure out really
narrow it down but those ones that i
named are like the ones that go back
the most and that have been the most
well received and that i've explored the
most but what's [ __ ] up is that like
in those same years when i made all this
different stuff there's all these other
things that i didn't ever even try yeah
and
and for a long time and then not so
knows how it is here like
you could make a lot of seeds and if you
weren't on the internet like who's ever
going to want to grow
all the seeds
so
you're like thinking you're doing all
this [ __ ] for nothing and after a while
you kind of just feel like a geek like
doing weird [ __ ] for no
for like no end like what is ever gonna
i i can only get to some of them nobody
wants to grow anything i don't [ __ ]
know anybody i only know these few
people so i have like these few friends
like my buddy's mom
grows them for medical and kills it and
my one buddy couldn't get cloned so he
decided to do a big run and then he
killed it he wants more seeds and you
know like there's these little pockets
here and there but like i wasn't on the
internet until
so like i said forums
um my buddy reservation labs who who
used to work with me up here
who's not from here he was on the
internet and i wish i would have known
he didn't ever talk to me about it i
remember him
you knew about
[ __ ] like he got all this [ __ ] from
me you know yeah and so it was one of
these funny things where i was like i
wish i would have [ __ ] i like there
was no there was no reason for it to
come up really yeah other than if i said
we should do but you know i was like i
was just like doing weed [ __ ] he's like
what do you want to be on the internet
for like that'd be he probably thought
i'd think he was sketchy for being on
the internet with weed like probably
say like
where like you live up here and i i
would say that probably like
people have uh people have a lot of
misconceptions about what it's like to
actually live up here you know uh our
bubble is is really weird in that regard
and that you can be really insulated and
like everyone you know my everyone that
you hang out with for the most part
might grow weed but that doesn't mean
that like
you're tied into the larger community
like i you know i kind of call it when i
got on ig you know i did the forum thing
a long time ago but then i had a break
and i kind of felt like i crawled out
from under my rock
because we i was just living that like
mendo life you know or came out of the
closet
yeah you know however you want to put it
however you want to put it you know but
you know even with with him with seeds
it's the same thing with me with you
know people ask me about my collection
of clones and i've tended to try to keep
things that i like but it's a total
[ __ ] because you know he's talking
about trying to get friends to to grow
his seeds
me getting friends to back up my strains
that aren't currently popular
[ __ ]
it's so hard you know i mean even when
times were easier four or five years ago
people wanted to have mothers of the
things they were currently blooming for
for flower
they didn't want to back up a bunch of
stuff
you know and then it would get popular
again and people would be like hey do
you still have that
man that thing that you had was super
amazing could i get it and so i end up
like having people back up stuff for me
but i try to like stuff it with people
that actually love the two or three or
four cuts that go their direction
because i'm like oh if they love it
they'll hold on to it you know and i
think there's an aspect now
and i don't exactly know how it's going
to change but
i would say like maybe five or six years
ago before the the
maybe when would you say what would you
say gene the the
it started getting blown out bad about
five years ago huh before even the
legalization started there was like a
year or two but
for seeds at least there was a thing
where like emerald cup and some of these
different things as you guys both know
there was a bunch of growers with extra
money in their pocket
it would come to these things and they
would want to get some fresh seeds and a
lot of outdoor growers wanted to grow
from seed because there was this idea
that seeds got bigger than clones and so
on and so forth you know and had more
vigor or whatever and so people were a
little bit more willing to experiment
but now
it almost like there needs to be like
some kind of change in the regulations
or laws because
like the nurseries just want to grow
what's popular
and then they want to sell popular
clones to
people that have you know the ability to
grow flower and those guys want to grow
what's popular because they can't even
sell direct to the public nor can they
sell direct to a dispensary they have to
convince a distro to buy it
and then that distro
you know has to um you know has to come
back and uh and decide to sell that to
like a shop
where the days where where you know gene
could have a friend go into into a shop
in the bay and say i've got some i've
got a couple duffel bags of some
fireweed are you interested
those days are gone
yeah
so
so even even any breeder whether it's
it's him or you or caleb or anybody else
even just getting someone to be able to
see it
someone to care about it
you know somebody could grow a bunch of
his stuff and be like oh my god this
shit's fire you know or or whatever and
then the distro is like i don't care
and then the public won't even see it
and then yeah and then too with with
like with seeds growing from seeds it's
hard because
uh you know
there's not really nobody really has any
seeds that are so true breeding
that you can grow them and then have it
be like a true harvest batch
where you can say
all of these are
yeah thc
whatever you know whatever it is
like um
like uh like the uh
i haven't tested a ton of them but like
the grape soda skunks the ones that we
tested they're like in the mid teens on
cbd the thc is almost not there it's
like turned into almost like a hemp line
but it's really [ __ ] dank you know
um and is really close to being at that
point but
even if even if you got it to be there
it's like he said like the distro why
would the distro want that they're like
no we want something with whatever in
the name it has to sound like
relevant with this little box that we
know is definitely marketable you know
so
um
you know it's one of those it's one of
those weird things but just seeds in
general because of that it's like okay
they're all a little bit different
you know um
like i have a lot of things
they're always in the the low 20 percent
thc or they're always in the mid 20 thc
so it's like you can do them but it
doesn't really like
um
it's still it's still hard to translate
to the market if it's not and then
that's why like over the last
however many years i mean i got my hands
on
cookies when it was like unknown
basically you know and i i didn't even
really i was like cool
you know this is what these dudes in san
francisco have and everybody really
likes it in that circle and [ __ ] and
um
i started doing stuff with it because
it it was neat [ __ ] it reminded me of
neat old
stuff you know
and um so then like over the years i've
tried to do like i did like the stuff
with the gelato and all that
just because you look at how it is and
people are like oh those were really
cool but do you have anything that's
like the stuff that people are talking
about do you have
you know gelato 41 do you have blah blah
blah and i'm like well i mean
you know people you want to give people
the seeds that they're going to grow and
that's how it's turned into um
a a weird thing where
like i'm like running parallels you know
like i have like all the stuff that i
really really want to do and some of
that really actually is [ __ ] that has
that stuff in it i do have cookie and
gelato work that i really really like
yeah but at the same time you're like
you have to have these things that
people know okay i can get my new clone
that's a new flavor where when i go to
do it
i can have
something where people are gonna go okay
i can this is something that is actually
can go on the market and everything's
been like
put into such a small
such a small box now that you kind of
have to
go with the flow to an extent you know
like you can't just no no i'm just gonna
put
acapulco gold everybody will like no
they're not gonna want it
they've been talking about like doing
some like
uh making some laws or some amendments
to what's going on where you could have
some like farmer's markets and you could
do direct sales
um
that's really what it would kind of take
in order to get a bunch of variety out
there is because you know i mean you
guys both know like when you used to go
to like a
um you know a high times cup or a
emerald cup or something like that it
was kind of like a weed swap meat
you could crack open people's jars
there'd be some like furry dudes with
from some place some random spot up
north and they had a bunch of big jars
this big of all kinds of weed and you
could crack and you could smell it you
could check it out
and so the way that they have it now
where it's like you can't see most wheat
in a store and you can't smell most
wheat in a store
they really like it they don't really
have like a method for people to bring
new things
you know and like it there has to be
something more than just like a couple
people being able to hype something
right and drive hype you know because
there's a lot of good weed out there he
was talking about it a minute ago but
almost all my favorite weed and what i
mean by favorite weed in terms of like
the weed that gets me the highest
it's almost all between 18 and 25
percent
in thc
you know it's not so hard
most of this 30 club i find to be very
bland and boring week
so there's something lost there when it
gets above a certain quotient you know
or people are breeding for numbers
because people 20 years ago or longer
people bred by like if you were breeding
from high the high is an invisible trait
right it's invisible like you just don't
know so
like a lot of times people things would
get famous because they worked
you know not always like he was talking
about the flow like it barely it tasted
great and it looked cool but it barely
got you high but like a lot of weed got
popular because it worked well
you know and now it's kind of about the
name and the look and the thc percentage
and the numbers and not really much
about like how does it work
and so i think there's a lot of unique
highs on a lot of different aspects
probably in various people's stuff and
you're like well how do i get it to the
public
you know how do i
you know um how do i get the how do i
get the public to shine on me for a
minute and want everything that i have
and so
you know and then nurseries nurseries
just want to sell as many clones as they
can to as many legal farms as they can
so they're picking the 10 or 15 most
popular cuts that they think they can
sell the most of
and that's what's on their menu this
spring right now you can go and you can
look at all these nurseries and these
nurseries have decided
what do i think i can sell the most of
this year
what do i think is a safe bet to mom up
x number of moms of each one of these
things that i can sell it on the legal
market and they probably
they probably have like uh
a [ __ ] ton
of cool strains that they're not selling
to people but they have them
but they're just yeah they just don't
it's like they don't think there's gonna
be
i can't afford to have a hundred moms of
that because i don't know if i'll be
able to sell enough cuts
yeah and it's uh it's all unfortunate
because it all makes sense because you
go well what what are you gonna do you
know what i mean like whatever you're
farming if you're farming
if you're farming tomatoes and you know
people don't want
like this kind of tomato then why the
[ __ ] are you gonna farm that kind of
tomato and if you're the nursery selling
plants to grow
something then why are you gonna if you
know everybody's gonna buy granny smith
apples and your [ __ ] half a nursery
that sells apple trees like you're not
just gonna go but i got a million of
these and people are gonna be like cool
but like where's those ones and then
you're like well but i i have these and
then you're like well [ __ ] you know
it's like joe dirks [ __ ] snakes and
sparklers you know either you gotta have
the ship in people people want like it's
uh
it's just this loop that just gets it
just gets stuck and it um
i don't know it's unfortunate but it's
like it's just i don't it's how it's how
everything is is laid out and i think
part of it has to do like with what
you're saying it would be nice
if you could go okay
uh like there's a system of okay
everybody can get free samples everybody
can look at a jar everybody can feel it
everybody can roll it up and see what
they like
but what happens is it's like somebody
goes in they go
i mean
it's in a bag it's a sealed
i mean what's the number this one has
the big number i can't see anything else
and then now people too say like
oh look at the terpene test don't look
at the thc test and i'm like well high
terpenes don't mean [ __ ] yeah a bunch
something's flavorful skittles only has
like one point six percent or some [ __ ]
yeah it's not even it just has tons of
little which is [ __ ] amazing you know
and then there's like all those things
that are like that and some of them that
are high are really good but it's not
that the numbers never tell you and then
even if you know
that everybody else says it's really
good you might still smoke it and be
like a lot of people could think that
blue dream
is the greatest weed ever because people
love it so much and a lot of people
could think that blue dream is the worst
weed ever because so many people hate it
so much but the only way to know if you
really like blue dream or you hate it is
to smoke it and some people will be like
[ __ ] it's like [ __ ] cilantro right or
garlic some people are like that tastes
like [ __ ] and some people are like that
tastes like heaven and you've got to be
able to
you take blue dream and there's some
stuff like blue dream or green crack or
you know uh or barry white in our area
that get gets blown out and it gets a
bad reputation but if you grow like a
four to six ounce plant or you know or a
half pound plant of that thing and you
keep it kind of small and you treat it
right it's delicious
it gets a bad rep because there's some
dudes that are pumping out eight to 12
pound blue dreams
that are kind of b grade
and they get treated great and then
there's all this weed and there's like
oh blue dream sucks and it's like yeah
that that that version of it does suck
but if you took that strain and you grew
six ounces of it in a 10 gallon pot you
know in your side plot it would come out
fire and it would probably be a nice jar
i even grew i grew blue dream and i
didn't i got it late but it was still
big big ass plant i mean like that's
what was crazy about blue dream was like
i tossed in one out of like a
like a four gallon bucket like an actual
bucket
that my buddy gave me that was a spare
plant and i put it in really late like
as a replacement and i still think i got
like five pounds of wheat off of it and
this big huge pretty big plant good
sized plant i mean you wouldn't have
thought it had that much wheat on it but
dude the weed was all really [ __ ]
killer like i've always grown like i
always had the 25 plants and i um
i was able to always have like really
big plants that were just the same
[ __ ] weed as i as i had like
anywhere else but i didn't have [ __ ]
350 of them you know what i mean i just
had like little gardens so they're big
plants but very you know taken care of
and and you know keeping track of what
um
i think a lot of people who had really
big plants and who had a ton of them
it's like
harvest is october 4th we're cutting
this [ __ ] down or
you know like these different you get
these like real vague growing styles and
for me i'd be like oh okay the north
side of this plant is really [ __ ]
done so i'm going to go ahead and cut
like this section of this plant and then
it looks like the stuff that's on the
very top is pretty close and then i cut
that and then be like oh the south side
is not quite you know big plants are a
whole trip because it's like a whole
garden on one plant so the south side
finishes way later like sometimes like
you know ten days later
two weeks later and the stuff on the
backside is like done and if you go
through and you harvest your whole
garden at once you're like okay sweet
well now we have the backside is [ __ ]
you know 14 days too far and the front
side's premature and the middle is great
but [ __ ] those tops probably should
have come down because they're kind of
[ __ ] [ __ ] off up there now and so
people's stuff just winds up being like
this
this this this vague handling method
that it's not specific enough you know
but um
but like
it is
there's an aspect to him and i have
talked about this years ago where
like there are some strains that can
maintain their quality as they get
bigger and bigger and bigger maintain
their resin and things like that but
there is this ratio of like an in
general
like the there's a range where the
plant's going to give you better weed if
it's smaller it's not in all cases but
in a lot of cases and if you get it too
big it puts so much energy into like the
stems and the structure and you're
building scaffolding around it and it
becomes a huge pain in the ass to
maintain and the stem on the base is
like this [ __ ] big and you're worried
about it cracking and you're like like
gluing it when it splits because you're
worried about rot and so there's just a
lot of things that like make it like
harder like he was just saying harder to
like harvest it in the perfect window
you're just like ride this beast until
it gets to somewhat done and you can
start taking some of it down and you
don't lose it to the million different
things that can [ __ ] with you
you know and if you get 99 of those
that's really [ __ ] hard to like
really keep up with that and if you just
go ahead and take the same clone and do
a big garden of seven gallon pots and
your plants are just these little plants
and that's like oh every bud is perfect
and every plant is totally even and
there is no front side there is no back
side they're too small for that you know
and
you yeah like if you really want good
weed like it is a lot easier to do it in
in small pots i was doing it
yeah or even beds but
you can do it in bed with just
moderate-sized plants you know i mean we
grew giants
in mendo
um because you know there used to be you
know plant counts were pretty intense
and if you got over a hundred plant a
hundred plants
the feds could get you
you know um and then you know mendo was
like okay you know like we'll give you
25.
25 we won't really [ __ ] with you too
much you know you can have your 25 and
you're safe and then so people are like
well how do i get 250 pounds off 25
plants
how do i get 200 pounds off 20 plants
you know whatever it might be and so you
start developing these methods based on
like the rules
blue dream blue dream you know
blue dream and you know oh i'm going to
grow green crack and that's kind of
where green crack or blue dream or barry
white get bad names because people are
like oh i can get this clone that'll
give me this much weed on a reliable
basis and i can put 25 of them in my
garden and that's my season
right and now there's too much b grade
blue dream and people are like blue
dream sucks
they're like no there's just a lot of
commercial b grade blue dream on the
market it doesn't hate
i i have friends who like really love
certain types of weed and like you can
give them the best blue dream ever they
can grow it themselves or whatever in
that terp profile they just [ __ ] hate
it some people hate terpenoline
some people
think some people hate cookie terps
some people hate purp sweet terps some
people don't like chem d terps some
people don't like
gmo terps like some some shit's
different like nobody likes the same
things everybody doesn't like blue
cheese and everybody doesn't like
vinaigrette like some people are like no
dude like some people
ranch on everything and some people
think ranch is [ __ ] disgusting you
know so like when you have weed there's
these profiles of these smells and stuff
where it's like you know some people
love to wear really heavy cologne they
think they smell great when they come in
a room and me when someone walks in a
room with whatever heavy cologne it is
it's probably 99 of the time i'm going
to be like [ __ ] come on dude why are you
wearing
something that's like that smells so
good you know it's just there's a lot of
it a lot of it comes down to to
preference you know like some people
don't look really powerful wheat some
people like really mellow wheat even if
they've smoked a [ __ ] ton of weed you
know like
making all the green onions
is that everyone loves root beer and
while there's 331 [ __ ] people in here
right now gene let everybody know where
they can get your seeds
um so there's a little bit of stuff i
have the um
the uh i have a little bit of stuff at
alpineseedgroup.com
um
speakeasy
has some stuff sometimes
uh llf
um and that's basically the only people
who i know who have anything really
um
here and there
but um what are you working on right now
what are you stoked about like right
this second that you have
inner [ __ ] you're like [ __ ] i can't wait
for people to see this well maybe maybe
we should ask him this it's spring
what have you planted bro
because i see
with green like little greenhouses full
of seed starts so you're obviously
excited about some things because you're
planting it's that time right you're
popping seeds
all right so this would be this has got
i just got to be my last thing that i
talked about because i i thought i
figured that i was going to i figured
lives are about an hour but we've
managed to push into dnf
yeah it's all right
like this
it's a disaster in there and i'm in
trouble but uh
um
basically uh
i have right now going a bunch of things
that are like promising that either i
have like people are testing out for me
and i want to like get a get a hands-on
idea of like okay how do they smoke so
that i can line up what their feedback
is with what i really think yeah
or they're things that i think might be
super intersex prone and i just want to
see a little bit of them to see like are
these things is it just are they is it
intersex everywhere in there
um so that we don't even plant more of
them so if i think that they might be
real problematic or i already know
that they're the [ __ ] but i want to have
an idea of what a few of them look like
i have like 18 little starts going of
those types right which isn't very much
but it's enough to either yeah
or
to
confirm what's already been done with
other numbers elsewhere or even maybe
that i have seen a little bit of stuff
and then the other ones i have a tray of
36 each
so that i can really see
what does
you know what does it look like when you
have basically three packs worth of
seeds
and then
if
it's a home run on that and i'm like
holy [ __ ] every plant is great in this
i can hear that statistically we're
looking at something that's pretty good
and if i look through those and there's
nothing good in if there's not anything
good in three packs of seeds then i'm
like i have other [ __ ] that i can focus
on so it's basically right now a big
test run where i have about 50 things
going i have scentsy star cross scentsy
star cross gyro
i have um a bunch of cookie lines animal
west f4s which are gorgeous they're like
little dinosaurs little rhinoceros
looking plants
um
i have some of my og lines like knots
not so saw kind of the same stuff but
trying some of them more myself
um i have a bunch of lime crosses i made
with the f5 lime
males a pair of males that i really
liked out of a bunch of plants
um i have cherry west cross lime two
different lines of that
i have
uh
what else do i have so
there's like
chem d
lime um
a few other cool things that i got uh
like some cool cuts that i got from
skunk tech that are bomb
that i hit with that lime i have
what else do i have
um
try and place exactly as if i kind of go
walk myself down the rows it's like
scentsy star bat cross
i'm being paged
um it's all good
going down the line yeah all the cookie
stuff the cherry west
i know there's other stuff that i'm not
saying there's some different cush
crosses
um
[Music]
like yes
ogoji jaro
um
pk cross sky cutler double kush
i don't know whole bunch of different
stuff but they're all that kind of stuff
i'll do a post in a while that has like
stuff up and uh
and maybe a list of what all those
different things are but anyway it's
like twelve hundred and fifty plants
basically
eighteen of some 36 of the other
um and
and
uh
you know like i said that was my logic
was like all right there's some that
if i think maybe they're really
problematic like animal cookies bat
cross too sure try 18 or they all hurt
them if they're not all hurt i'm like
[ __ ] all right we'll try try try 36 of
those you see what's it cause you know
or try 50 of those and then like some
pure limes uh lime one cross lime f5
salam one bread to f5 put back on the
originator
um so i have like a targeted
mother of targeted males
that are put back on the more open
mother so that that's a combination
where this is already a predictable mom
but now i have a real predictable
male set that i put back on them
um and then you know lime one back cross
two
and [ __ ] like that just a bunch of
different stuff to look through and um
and uh you know pink champagne root beer
and uh pink champagne lime pink
champagne pina
um and the pink champagne's not like the
original it's a bag seed clone that i
got from these dudes and it's super
killer really really nice plant but
that's what's going down i gotta go
uh burn some beef and um thanks for
having me on and thanks for coming on
thank you good night you know
everyone's gone be sure to check out
speakeasy seed bank they've got some of
our gear and jeans gear um check out
readercinegit.com we have our patreon up
where you can come interact with us all
the time we shoot the [ __ ] all the time
we've got some fights going tomorrow
check out the northern lights drop with
me and you can get it from me or you can
get them from um
inspector over at humboldtcsi.com
um the nl5 drops out and slamming
[ __ ] slamming so that's up go get
them
there's readers packs available
and what else we got we will have caleb
on uh talking about the nl stuff very
soon we went last night so yeah thank
you all for giving us your friday night
and listening for long and uh we'll see
you soon
peace
[Music]
you