[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
live here i'm matthew owner of riot
seeds i'll occasionally be joined by my
cohost not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
[Music]
what's up everyone so we talked earlier
we're gonna um
do a little
spotlight on um
my old man net yeah um yeah we're gonna
uh talk about the uh i think
the return of neville era when it was uh
mr nice 2009 to 2011 i think it was
somewhere in between there wasn't a full
two years but it was in there in that
region
so yeah
um we also we also thought too that
maybe we could do a little question and
answer oh yeah
matt's a lot better at reading comments
and does a lot more uh cultivating over
there than i do so yeah
ask away
you know and and maybe it might get
answered but we were chatting a couple
weeks ago
um sort of about that
that era and there's a bunch of stuff
that started happening at mr nice
because it was a new forum
and you know a lot of old timers and
heavy hitters started showing up and
saying stuff
yeah and so a whole lot of what we know
um
you know from the 80s or whatever in the
early 90s
um kind of got talked about extensively
by the people
10 years later 15 years later um and so
a lot of what we reference is like their
own words comes from that era that matt
was talking about
yes indeed yeah it was kind of cool um
when when neville popped back up i was
already on the forum and it was uh it
was kind of unexpected all of a sudden
he was there and answering questions and
it was like holy [ __ ]
you know
the guy that that
we all kind of looked up to most most
people that start selling seeds i mean
he was the
the dude a lot of us looked up to you
and we were finally able to ask him
questions we had
questions about certain things and he
was more than willing to answer
questions now whether or not we got uh
the most direct um true answers is is
still to be debated but it was a lot of
them were very very helpful and
informative people said mr nice with
shanti baba mr nice's website is is
still up and the forum is still active
it's not nearly as active as the era
we're going to discuss
um but it it definitely still exists uh
shanti baba and neville had a business
relationship that went on for quite some
time and they used howard mark's
likeness and
name essentially
so after
uh after neville left scentsy
he partnered in some fashion with um
shanti
and that led to a partnership with
greenhouse and arjun
and then when um when shanti and neville
left arjun and greenhouse they went off
and did mr nice in switzerland yeah um
and i think it was primarily shanti at
that point but howard marks and neville
i never saw howard marks have much to do
with anything at mr nice when i was you
know really
active um i do think he just owned a
part of it
because they used his likeness and name
yeah i think they i think he had a cool
name
and um i think they used him as uh
you know he had a very photogenic story
yeah and he was sort of at the part in a
time in his life um that selling his
story was a thing yeah yeah and his wife
had a book he had a book there was a
movie a lot of people haven't seen that
was released in the uk called mr nice
that was actually it was it was decent
it was decent about howard mark's life i
mean the the autobiography is fantastic
yeah um you know and just for people
that are listening or whatever he
bought somebody's identity in england in
the in the 60s who never really traveled
yeah and it was actually pronounced
french like mr nice
like nice france yeah like like you're
going to nice
yeah it was actually that's how it was
pronounced but he changed he just
changed it to mr nice
same spelling just different
you know
just different connotation or whatever
because back then
at least he says in the book you know he
bought multiple different people's
identities who were never planning on
leaving uh great britain yeah so that he
could have different passports and
different identities to go around to all
these countries and get away with all
this smuggling
pre-internet days were [ __ ] bombed
before they could check out all that
[ __ ] yeah so i mean in a way mr nice was
kind of a cool seed company because it
was a legendary old smuggler
of hashish and marijuana
and two you know um and neville and
shanti
yep so it was kind of like a sort of a
superstar collective if you will yeah
uh in terms of weed legends
well i mean mr nice i i can't honestly
say that neville was a part of mr nice
at any point
i'm not sure if he was i know he you
know he sold shanti a good deal of his
genetics so they were his actual
genetics when he was having legal
troubles i believe in australia
i think
i yeah i i mean i don't know i think
though that came later actually but what
i do think is that i think
howard marks and neville had a piece
i don't think so because when neville
came back one of the main things and and
we'll talk about this more in detail he
um he was really pissed that shanti only
ever paid him 250 000 for those genetics
when he needed that money and he felt
that he was owed a lot more so he didn't
have a piece he felt he was owed a lot
more because
but
maybe we should get before we get ahead
of ourselves yeah um
because what i think you're talking
about before is like when he was in
australia in the clink
how he got out uh was the drunkers
bought his business okay so this is a
different time whatever this is a
different time but he's had gave him 250
grand was his quote one of the ways that
we know shanti baba had access to a
bunch of this old [ __ ] that he claims to
have
is because neville told us that he sold
him his entire old seed collection for a
quarter of a million dollars yep yeah so
it's verification a lot of people claim
they have old things but how they got
them
the chain the command the chain of
custody is a little suspect a little
dubious yeah yeah you know shanti for
all of his claims uh you know his his
his origin story is phenomenal yeah yeah
we know that he at least had access to
these genetics at one time yeah you know
and so the question is is more of how
many of them does he still have
yes
versus did he ever have access yeah yeah
we know he had access neville gave him a
bunch of their collection when they were
working together doing the super silver
haze mango haze neville's haze thing and
the greenhouse gig
yeah and then at some point he sold him
his seeds and a lot of what
you know a lot of what is sold at mr
nice is claimed to have come from old
neville seed yes
quite a bit quite a bit of the stock
almost all of it except for the the
widow stuff yeah the widow stuff and
yeah it all sort of originates from
clones or old seeds from metal yeah and
it's corroborated by neville said that
you know he he sold them
yep
so i think part of the problem probably
part of the
the interesting part to people is going
to be what neville said
neville is one of those people that it
seems like every five or six years his
life burned down
um and even though he was one of the
originators and everybody grows his [ __ ]
um he didn't end up like arjun or
something he didn't end up filthy rich
um
before he died yes before yeah well
yeah exactly i mean technically yes but
no for most of his life he was not i
mean i'm sure mozart looks down and
thinks how many other people made money
off his music without a doubt but he
died a popper and a dirt grave you know
yeah um but you know
neville was pissed that he felt like he
he started
he started the movement and he's the one
that exploded the dutch scene
yes and he ended up going to prison and
being chased by the dea and having all
these issues and everybody else was
profiting off things hugely that he
wasn't
yeah
and so instead of him ending up being
like you know a ford or you know a henry
ford type of thing you know i mean
actually it's more like this it's like
he was the tesla
not edison
yes exactly um and so you know he did a
ton of stuff and we're all indebted to
him in various ways but
um you know
you know there's the the scentsy era and
the greenhouse era and the mr nice era
and
you know um he had a lot of issues yeah
but what was cool is that when mr nice
set up his forum uh when shanti set up
the forum there was a bunch of forums at
the time obviously yeah i can speak to
them more than i can
um but
what happened is when neville decided
i'm gonna come out of the shadows and
start answering questions
on only mr nice's forum
yes
then
that basically did this thing where all
of a sudden all this stuff we've been
debating forever you could [ __ ] ask
him
the the part that i i found the most
interesting and because
like some of this is missing now like a
lot of the back and forth was during
this time when he popped up it was
almost a
a gang war between the icy maggers that
were like sam the skunk man
oh for sure
i was gonna i was gonna bring that up
that
basically like an enormous amount of
old-timers started popping up
um at mr nice and adding color and
adding depth and corroboration to
various stories
but then there was a camp at
there was like the neville camp at mr
nice and there was like the dave watson
sam skunk man thing at ic mac yes and uh
they took pot shots at each other yeah
there were epic videos they used um it
was an old website called jib jab and
you could do these kung fu
like videos and you could
put what the text says like write what
text you wanted in it and him and
neville would go back and sam and or
maybe like uh cash rock someone that was
friends with sam
um would do the half of it from sam's
point of view like talking [ __ ] about
neville and these kung fu things and
then neville would have one of us
write something funny talking [ __ ] back
at the icy mad guys and sam but i don't
think those videos exist anymore but
they were [ __ ] hilarious and i wish
they did
i mean what's interesting about that is
that for all of those battles there's
not really all that much that sam and
neville disagree on
no no you know like they back up each
other's stories quite a bit
yeah um you know there's a difference
there's a difference in they both agree
that you know neville got haze from sam
yes
um
sam i think is told three or four
different stories about exactly what
neville got yes
neville's been pretty consistent or was
pretty consistent yeah and what what had
happened he had one version and he just
kind of stuck to it yeah yeah he was
pretty good at like if he if he had a
version he stuck to it whether it was
true or not he [ __ ] stuck to that
[ __ ] i mean
it becomes hard it's like we and one of
one of the reasons why we wanted to chat
about this is because it relates to so
much different stuff today
and it was one of those rare times where
um you know matt and i and friends and
stuff we still refer back to tons of
those posts yeah
um because neville explained in detail
uh what he was up to and one of the
funny things about neville
is that not to say that not to say that
uh
he always told the truth or anything
like that but
um because he was first
he was a lot more open
than almost anyone yeah and just saying
not only what his hybrids were
but um who he got them from and how
yeah where after neville everybody
started to clam up
and mysteries of even what it was
yeah uh and where where they got
whatever they used from
i thought i think i think neville
realized pretty early on that despite
people having the recipe or knowing what
strains were in what that there was no
way they were going to be able to
reproduce any of the phenotypes or
anything that he was showing or
selections he knew really early on that
that wasn't going to be the case so
there was no reason to to
uh hide a lot of the the stuff though i
do personally one of my theories i think
he he hid quite a few things on um and
and lied about it but i just saw a a
comment that i'll just interject real
quick we have a i have an old buddy of
mine uh that just commented that he got
some old neville's haze from me
and i brought home when i when i had
brought home some haze from europe one
of these times
and i was testing him out at my house
you know and he had like this 10 by 10
spa he had a big garden in his backyard
in mendocino county uh but he had the
space that was unused and he was like
dude you want to give me some heads i
just have this space i got this section
of the bed i didn't fill in you want to
give me some head that's nice though i
gave them i gave them like four or five
of these haze plants right in july
okay now you got to realize like the
whole back of the thing is full of six
foot tall sour diesels
all kinds of different strains big bushy
strains been in there for a couple of
months and i gave him like four clones
this big
well fast forward two and a half months
and these things are four feet above the
top of his fence
they took up the whole 10 by 10.
i think he ended up cutting him down
around thanksgiving and they weren't
done
it was killer weed though even though it
needed probably another two or three
weeks
but we we tried out these four little
clones and they turned into this
ginormous jungle weed
yeah that went everywhere it was pretty
intense
yeah that other cold chemd that i that i
had um it was it was one of those ones
you could flower as a ceiling it would
be [ __ ] eight nine feet tall just
candelabra style i mean it was just it
was funny too because like the way is
the way his backyard went it like sloped
down and so you really could never see
anything even if he grew huge plants
back there yeah and then i came over and
there's like these giant branches poking
up over the fence where you'd never seen
them before yeah uh but it just got to
the point where that thing was gonna it
was growing eight inches a day in every
direction
yeah so it just like exponentially like
you know yeah shit's wild to watch how
quick it can grow it was and so but
so what you know one of the things is
that when we talk like about a lot of
the when we did a bunch of the podcasts
on like the neville era and the seed
bank era yeah uh a lot of what we say um
you know comes from that later time
uh nuance and stuff that neville
answered
yep the questions um you know in at the
mr nice era and so that also did things
where it brought some people out of the
woodwork
um like uh some uh some pretty big
people in europe were commenting on it
uh and ortega popped in and started
commenting on what he had given neville
and what neville had given him
and so all of a sudden you're watching a
bunch of these like old school legends
that started it
yeah and they're chatting back and forth
about what
what they did for each other yep and
what's what's amazing with that is you
always wonder when you only have one
person telling a story
you know how do you how do you
corroborate it how do you make sure it's
true how do you weed out the [ __ ]
yep
you know and then also you can get two
or three people talking about the same
thing and you know who they all are
and you're like okay well that's
you know yeah it's probably about as
good as you're gonna get
you know so
um yeah so neville neville just openly
discussed all the parentage
of all his strains he didn't really have
any mystery strains
yeah and he discussed how and where he
got all the breeding material
and he was probably the last person to
do that
yeah yeah because to this day like some
of the second round of stuff
um you know like th seeds or serious
seeds or you know some of those kind of
people there's still mysteries that 25
years later we have no idea what the
parents were or where they got them from
paradise seeds why won't you tell us
yeah apparently one of the worst foreign
all this all the second wave neville was
just like here's i mean like to the
point where like we confirmed that you
know he went back to america and he got
g13 and the pacific northwest hash plant
from two grower friends of jorge
cervantes yeah
and he paid 500 bucks for him yep
uh you know our our buddy greg who uh
old marine who uh
you know matt interviewed um you know
they laid out the nl story
back and forth
you know pretty big time and cleared up
a bunch of that so it's like oh i got
the no i got the northern lights from
this guy i got these two cuts from this
guy i got this from over here i got
these things from sam skunk man and
here's the crosses of all
yeah and so it made it like it made it
pretty cool for historians or whatever
to try to figure out um
people just asked about the mango and
the ssh we can get we can talk about
that but it made it really cool to
figure all that stuff out because he
gave the layers
where all the second wave of of uh
amsterdam seed banks
uh it was all mystery
yeah for the most part yeah they were
right yeah they would rarely tell you
what the parents were they would rarely
tell you the origins of the parents it
was like here's the strain name here's
what it looks like here's our
description
that's all you know yeah and there's
like ak-47 or
or collie missed or like
paradise scentsy star
um there's a bunch of stuff where you're
just like oh you still have no idea yeah
30 years 25 30 years on and you're still
even parentage or where they got it or
who they got it from or what it was
bubble gum same kind of thing same kind
of thing yeah you know th seeds same
kind of thing there was various things
they basically just said headies from
america
yeah but you know th seeds people adam
and
uh simon from sirius and tony from sag
martha they all worked under neville for
a time
and none of them ever admitted that they
that they got anything from neville and
used it in their own work ever yeah it
sounds like they probably should have
i would think so you would think that
they you would think that they did it
but they won't they don't say
yeah i know they don't remember i mean
dunn might now
go back and say certain things but he's
not the most consistent no you know but
they just it was it was more like the
they just decided that secret sauce was
best yeah yeah
and from then on
the
you know the pulling the wool over your
eyes about strains became ingrained in
cannabis
and being open was rare
yeah so it's a really it's a real it's
kind of a treat to be able to just
talk about all this neville stuff
and he just laid out what it all was
yeah now sadly like with the rename game
um there's a ton of neville work in a
bunch of our modern [ __ ] but it all goes
by different names
yeah
so you just have no idea
yeah you can trace some of it back and
you can make guesses
right yeah you can make some educated
guesses but that's about all we got and
some of them i know there was stuff that
he would look at he'd be like oh yeah
that's my xyz you know like with modern
strains and he would say what he thought
it was but i mean even for him it was a
guess at that point at that point yeah
and so you know and during this i should
say during this era uh i was starting to
have kids and stuff like that this is
like a really um active era for mac
um and so you were messaging a bunch
with neville you were actually you know
so not only would he answer things
publicly on forums
that anybody could log in and see
but he was actually pretty active in
communication via email and dm
uh through those forums then
yeah and so any number of people had a
bunch of private conversations that
revealed more info yeah yeah a few of us
were really um
we we gained uh what you would i i would
assume would be a friendship but it
didn't work out that way but a few
people were able to to ask him detailed
questions and he would respond he had a
really shitty um connection out in
australia as far as his modem so
the the amount that he could pop up and
talk was very minimal and it was always
frustrating for him
um that's something i remember greatly
um but there were also you know like
when one of these dudes comes back out
of nowhere and everybody wants something
from them you know a lot of other people
showed up that were uh other seed
breeders that that wanted a piece of it
you know they wanted a piece of him so
you had people like charles scott
showing up from um briefer man reefer
yeah and that that was a big part of
what happened and
the falling out of neville and his
disappearance and then and then we had
our good friend uh kanga kangativa he
probably worked with him closer than any
of us um out in australia he worked with
them hands-on and he was doing a lot of
the actual hands-on breeding and
creation of strange while neville wasn't
doing as much that but directing more
from his area but i do know that neville
was doing some work with his son on a
few different things including a g13
line isn't it kanga that provided us
with the one picture of the hazy male
that we think is legit
i think so i think that is the the
kangas pick yeah
it's his pick and it was posted on mr
nice from his tours going over to see
the switzerland era mr nice
um you know breeding projects and
something like that
um because you know a lot of those guys
as shanti and neville has said
you know even though they were partners
with arjun and they were moving a bunch
of weed and seeds through
greenhouse yeah because greenhouse was
sort of like the harbor side for lack of
a better term it was sort of like the
big dispensary yeah right and so they
were still kind of illegally growing
weed and illegally making seeds but then
there is like a packaging wise they
could show up the greenhouse and they
could sell it through them
yep right and so when switzerland open
up these guys finally saw a way of like
holy crap i can do breeding on a
greenhouse level yeah i can do things on
a much bigger scale i'm not going to be
restricted to like these you know these
these canal boats that can turn into
groves and these apartments and these
houses and these different things you
know
um and so a lot of people came out and
visited uh shanti and people like
breeder steve and stuff in switzerland
because all of a sudden they had all
these projects that they wanted to do
and they started doing a bunch of work
yeah making a bunch of seed and we
should also probably say that like the
one of the things that i saw at least as
like a big interest in
mr nice and shanti baba at the time
with the seed bank was that
at that point
neville was famous enough that everybody
wanted access to his old strains even
then
um and
you know
the seed bank was gone and nobody really
trusted sensei anymore
yeah so they sort of viewed what neville
had given shanti as the last legitimate
you know uh source yeah
right because because neville gave him a
bunch of clones and tons of old seed
yeah and then he sold a bunch of that
and so at that point we're talking 2009
2010 everybody everybody had already
figured out that cincy had outsourced
everything to spain right yeah and
nobody really trusted their work anymore
yeah their era was sort of done
yeah
so if you wanted that old [ __ ] everybody
sort of felt like that was the spot
and then neville
and then neville coming online
sort of gave it a ton of legitimacy
yeah because you're asking about his his
old [ __ ]
and this and for people that don't know
like looking back i saw someone um bring
up the cbd era this is before all that
this is before this is during the era
where shanti was [ __ ] militant about
[ __ ] femme seeds being trash femme
seeds are [ __ ] gonna ruin cannabis so
there was no cbd
crew there was none of this going on he
was militant anti-femme and the cbd crew
was some of the first femme worked and
it was done by jaime of resin seeds not
shanti at the time i know someone
mentioned that earlier but that was a
little bit later of an era
yeah i mean uh
we talked about on an earlier podcast
that when matt and
rascal and hybe and others started doing
reversals
it was not met with a warm welcoming
situation by most of the community there
was a lot of breeders and there was a
lot of retail people that thought it was
cheating
and long-term harmful
yeah yeah and so i think i think
you know shanti's cbd work is more like
five or six or seven years ago beginning
yeah there was mostly high mate it was
time made from resin seeds it was
originally it was called resin seeds and
he released a strain called cantatonic
he had a fake hp 13 sour diesel hybrid
he had a few others um there was a mk
ultra hybrid that he had
and um a lavender
lavender bubble gum that he had and
they didn't do so well but the catatonic
did kick these crazy cbd lines so after
a few years of resin seeds being around
they started working into just the cbd
stuff which became a cbd crew so well
you know the reason why we wanted to do
this
this chat or whatever is when matt and i
were chatting about like the beginning
of the fem and reversal era
this is the exact same era yeah it's
just that there was like four or five
dudes at most playing around with
reversals
and the vast majority of the seed
community was still looking at it like
some [ __ ] tech that was gonna lead
us down the wrong path yeah and it's
funny how within 10 years that thing
flipped
and the regular seeds became the unicorn
and the reversals became the standard
operating procedure
yeah
man we have a [ __ ] rock star in here
he [ __ ]
brought skunk he [ __ ] knew everything
i love people um
yeah so
there was the big dust up between icy
mag
and
and mr nice on the forums that would be
like uh me bigger
uh unfortunately hempy a lot of other
people on the mr nice side that were i i
was admittedly kind of drinking the
neville kool-aid i thought [ __ ] those
guys you know it was it did cause a lot
of uh headaches for shanti and shanti
was not too stoked when neville came
back not only because
of the chaos between sam and the drama
that was stirred up there was already
some drama going on between aryan and mr
nice calling each other [ __ ] water
boys and whatnot
so
when neville came back he also like i
said
demanded more money from shanti and
that's what slowly started the decline
of neville there
i don't know that shanti necessarily
liked the attention that neville was
getting either because he was getting
kind of overlooked
uh in favor of neville being there
answering questions and i remember in
some of the private communications if
nell isn't even alive anymore to talk
about it i don't think he'd mind me
sharing private communications but that
was one of the big things was that
shanti didn't want him on the site he
felt this is from neville's point of
view not shanti's he felt that shanti
was very angry that he was there and
getting all the attention on his site
and
he wanted to go elsewhere by that point
this is maybe six months after being
there
but he had a major interest in the
american genetics
too he wanted to know more about the og
kush's the bubba's the g13 he wanted to
see what had happened with that over
time um but yeah his interest seemed to
mostly swing over to the american what
we would call indicas during that time
yeah and i mean there's an aspect too
that
i've told matt this a bunch um but i
feel like the 90s and the early 2000s
and stuff and what happened in europe
uh you know history repeats itself often
and we see it over here in america now
and the various beefs and the various
camps and issues and which side do you
get on who do you believe more
yeah
and it also goes to show that
in a era of prohibition uh and gray area
it's often hard to maintain partnerships
over the long time without one or more
parties getting upset at each other yeah
it gets rough you see it right now with
i mean i don't need to name the cruise
but name most of the faint super famous
lines that are out right now or families
and you know the that stuff getting
famous broke up friendships
yeah
you know and neville wasn't particularly
friendly with any of his ex partners
he wasn't particularly friendly i mean
to some people
but it just depended um i really felt
like
he was friendly to people that he
felt could take him
further in what he was interested in if
that makes sense the the dutch i've said
this a ton too but the dutch have a very
different approach than americans to
marijuana
um they are much much much more money
and business oriented
yeah um
you know and
um you know americans have kind of like
a hobbyist weed nerd approach at least
with some people
yeah uh neville was a blend of the two
and that neville did give a [ __ ]
uh and neville did love weed
but he also was dutch and had a massive
strain of that
like he wanted money they wanted rep
yeah he was an early proponent of if
you're using my [ __ ] you should give me
credit and money
yes and like i said he had he had to
deal with shanti for 250 grand he gave
him all the strains he came back x
amount of years later and said wait this
[ __ ] made more than i thought he
was gonna make he owes me money and he
and and this is not from shanti's side
this is from neville's side neville came
to me and said
i you know what do you think about this
this is the amount of money i got that i
think i deserve more money don't you and
i'm like
so by by that point you know from
you know i i mean i i had a couple
conversations with neville nothing super
deep or as extensive as you did but
my general sense from what friends of
his told me is that he felt like
he broke barriers
and went to jail for it
and then ben and alan drunkers got to
got rich off his company
yeah right and then he left and he and
he worked with greenhouse and shanty and
arjun and arjun got hella rich
yeah off his weed and his seeds and his
work and all the cups that arjun won was
when shanti and neville were there
you know in fact neville arjun got
banned for a couple years for trying to
bribe a cup
after uh neville and shanti went and
remember that
yeah
he got he got pinched for uh um so
neville felt that like he had helped
make other people rich
yeah his whole career and shanti was uh
you know the latest person that was
doing that to him
yeah except for i don't think shanti
actually got nearly as rich as ben and
alan drunkers from senator
definitely not from arjun i think
arjun's probably worth hundreds of
millions of dollars
um yeah
you know so it was a little unfair to
single shanti out
yeah uh you know um but he but he but he
felt like that had been happening his
entire career
yeah
you know and so he felt like
and he and he felt like he undervalued
his company
to selling it to scentsy because he
needed to get out of jail and he needed
lawyers and he needed to get back to
holland yeah and so he and he kind of
felt like shanti did the same thing
in the sense of he was down and hurting
and needed money
and so he took a shitty deal for his
seeds because he couldn't turn it down
yeah but he should have gotten way way
more
yeah i mean 250 grand for that area is
bank proceeds like i can't it blows my
mind blows my [ __ ] mind that chance
he was even able to pull 250k out his
ass you know you got to realize he's got
it
listening that this this happened in the
90s or whatever so
it's probably literally like 480 to 540
000 in today's money yeah yeah there's a
lot of money 200 when we say 250 000
this is happening in the 90s yeah it
probably actually with today's inflation
it would be a few mil
you know i mean because i looked it up
like 20 20 if you made 20 an hour in
1994 which is when i started became an
adult it's 39 bucks now
yeah okay that makes sense so it's
probably double so yeah maybe it was
half a million bucks
yeah which is still a [ __ ] ton for seeds
for a seed dude back then [ __ ] yeah
especially old seeds yeah you know that
like you know and all that and so
um
you know but i mean it's also one of
those things where none of us were in
the room
when any of these deals were being made
so it's hard to know if neville was sour
grapes or he got he got worked
yeah um
from the way he told it
he
it sounded like he was sour grapes and
and like i and at the time i liked him a
lot and i
but even from his important point of
view listening to him it sounded like we
were [ __ ] entitled dude what the [ __ ]
i mean the other part of it i'll say is
that
um
when we were talking about history sort
of the last three big
things that neville did that made a
bunch of money was that 1997
super silver haze mango haze neville's
haze release yeah yeah and
you know taste changed and all that kind
of stuff so
like
after he sold shanti those seeds
shanti didn't have a period like
greenhouse did or like
scentsy did where they just like
dominated and made [ __ ] tons of money
yeah he did he didn't really have that
because because there's so many many
more people were in it there was so many
more canadians doing it there was like a
bustling
uh north american scene hitting it just
as that was taking off the north
american scene had just started booming
during that era so i mean you know
scentsy you know when when the drunkers
bought it from them they got 10 years of
dominance yeah
greenhouse it you know it made
greenhouse the place to visit in
amsterdam yeah arjun and his family and
all that they made so much money by
winning all those cups with for by
buying all those cups yeah well no i
mean they you know they they uh
you know they had they had the white
family and they had [ __ ] all that hay
[ __ ]
from neville and shanti so they won
with white widow and with peacemaker and
with super silver haze and with
you know i mean i know you're smiling
but it's just like that probably was
some of the better weed over there oh
i'm sure i mean barney's farm they were
taking turns buying the cup so yeah you
know and
and all that and so you know people
don't know this but there is we could
get into some more depth on that so like
some of the various beefs that people
might have interest in because
um you know the big issue between
neville and
um and sam at least as far as i
interpret it is twofold one they argued
over the exact
haze that neville got
right yeah and two
um
you know uh neville thought he was a
shady american that had ties to the
government that [ __ ] neville over
yeah so i'll go over this one and i'm
gonna preface this because i know mr
watson has been upset with me even
bringing it up so i will preface this
this is neville's story um everything
i've researched has shown it not to be
correct um as best i can tell i mean
there's no definitive
thing saying someone's not a snitch um
the way neville recounted it was that
when sam went over i'm not gonna say his
real name when sam went over to
amsterdam he went over and he was always
there with the dea handler granted the
dea is not supposed to function outside
the united states but this is the story
i was told um that he had a dea handler
everybody knew who his dea handler
handler was and they in neville's
quote was
he was called sam because of uncle sam
because he was a government worker that
they said they gave him the nickname
which we also know is probably not true
um but yeah he said that neville or that
sam went over there he was the first
person and only person to get the dutch
government's approval to grow cannabis
if i remember correctly which he was
presented for greatly by everyone
exactly because there's an american
getting the licensing and neville
basically said the only reason he got it
was because of the dea handler and the
dea wanted to make money in amsterdam
and control the cannabis uh
you know it's very very conspiratorial
and and a theory but
there's been no proof to any of that uh
that i can tell
and there's an aspect to it where
you know when i first started going over
to amsterdam and really got got started
getting to know some of these people
yeah um or friends of theirs or whatever
is that it became quite evident just
like today in today's cannabis world
that there was camps of friends over
there and they all didn't get along and
they had differing stories and beefs
over origins
yeah you know so neville's version of
the haze story
is that he got you know a bunch of bulk
seed from sam including skunk one
and then he paid a bunch of money for a
bunch of old seed from
you know he said it was 15 years old at
the time he got it from 70ish
um and out of thousands and thousands of
seeds he got maybe eight or ten to pop
yeah
and that's from those seeds is all the
breeding that he did and all that yeah
and uh sam has said that he gave him
seeds that he made while in amsterdam
he said he only gave him clones and the
shittier clones
um he's had a few different stories of
what he's told neville that he's written
down like like at various forums yeah um
so he said that he gave because now
because sam did go over there
and
uh make open pollinations and
reproductions of haze
yeah and he says that everyone over
there got those reproductions and no one
got original seed yes
but wernher did posse and carell at ssc
and neville all say they got seed from
america
yes
from
from sam them directly yeah before he
had gotten the house before he got set
up before anything yeah that he was
selling seeds to make money
uh to get himself started over there let
me answer this one mccormick speaks
really favorable of sam is that because
he knows or because he's got
a hold of some of those skunk and nlc's
well sam had nothing to do with the nl
seeds um mccormick's very favorable
because
it's just
what he does
um
they've been friends for a long time
and you know and i mentioned that and
stuff and so you know a lot of the stuff
that that net that todd sells
um is
stuff that sam has sold through others
for a long time that never got stopped
being sold that yeah i mean like he
claims ancient skunk one and durbin and
this and that and hayes
and you know sam has never wanted to
sell directly to the public
um so he's always wholesaled to people
like sssc or neville or the flying
dutchman or seeds men or
you know because it's legal to buy a
kilo of or kilos of seed directly in
holland at the time yeah
it was legal to do wholesale seeds
within holland yeah and so he just never
got involved with retail and so
todd sells the same stuff that you could
get from seedsman that you could get
from the flying dutchman that you could
get from any number of different sources
and so the sourcing is legit but he
tries to make it seem like they're
ancient and rare and they've never
before been released
when
as matt said they've literally been a
constantly available
forever
it always blows my mind every time
someone resells skunk one to something
new that's all i'll say on it i mean
granted there's skunk one is obviously a
very desirable plant it's in a lot of
strains it's in almost every strain ever
um that's still around there's some
skunk one and almost everything unless
there's like an heirloom does it make
well it makes you know uh
you know and the funny part about this
maybe we should talk about this a bit is
that
like while sam is undeniably a mammoth
influence in cannabis yeah and neville
is also undeniably a mammoth influence
in cannabis
yes they enjoyed immensely
denigrating the other person
as a chump
as often as they could get away with it
yep you know and so you really couldn't
take what they said about each other it
was like really hard because they
disliked each other so much and this
someone asked earlier about the afghani
one why did neville hate it so much well
there's
neville said that he thought it was what
a boring hot dull boring high no flavor
and there's corroboration of this i mean
like remember when the when in high
times when the connoisseur went and
visited
rob his friend yes uh there's various
people that said it was like a
heart-pounding shitty body high yeah it
wasn't that tasty that it just it didn't
lead to too many good places it wasn't
that great
when that popped up
all you had was like colombians and
mexicans so they had a certain specific
height that they expected from from
cannabis and here comes afghanis
and it is much different than the dutch
are used to any of them yeah you know
and i mean the the afghani one i mean is
you know it's mel frank's weed really
yeah um you know the afghani and the
durbin that sam took to holland was
directly from mel frank
and i will go down to my death saying i
think afghani one is the reason skunk is
stunky uh skunk one or super skunk is
skunky and i think that the afghan t was
afghan one and i think neville hit it
because he [ __ ] and that's why he
hated afghani one so much because it was
in every last thing of his that's my
theory no proof it is based on [ __ ]
nothing though don't don't even listen
to me on this mat
but that's that's the funny part is that
when we talk about this [ __ ] okay
there's an aspect where you start
talking about all the various people
there
and then people
start poking holes in that person's
character because it's easy to do
because they all have sus spot stuff
that they're involved in yeah and then
at some point you're like well which of
these shady [ __ ] is telling the
truth
yeah
right because they all have
you cannot be like well this is the more
high character guy
yeah no it's it's real hard to do you
know what i mean like actually no i can
take that back sam skunk man has never
[ __ ] me over neville has
so like that but i mean what i mean by
that though is that like you know for
instance it's the same thing i have with
that tk origins dude or whatever about
the kush
like once sam has written three or four
stories of what he gave neville
yeah well then which version do you
believe because they can't all be true
it's an unreliable narrator so he's got
to be lying about some of it yeah
because he wrote it all down yeah one of
those cannot be
true at least two of those cannot be
true if there are three states one of
them yeah one of them may be true might
but all the but there can only be one
that's true and so all the other
versions have to be [ __ ] so which
version
yep do you go with
yes
you know yeah
and
you know and when you know when we
interviewed corel from sssc
he said that sam gave nev that sam gave
neville seed
yes but sam was on cannabis world or
icmag or whatever talking about how not
only did he not give
neville anything good but they only him
and rob gave him the shitty clones that
they didn't like as much and overcharged
him because he was a dick
yeah
you know and and then he said that he
gave him oped seeds that he'd already
made in amsterdam and he never got any
original [ __ ] yeah but the weird thing
that i'll say about that is that uh csi
and i and matt and stuff we all talk
about how plants don't lie
and strangely even though sam
religiously disses what neville did and
got
the vast majority of the haze cuts that
people hoard and want are from neville
work yeah
you're not finding a lot of good stuff
in any of the positronics hayes sam
hayes direct stuff or even even even the
the the corel stuff i mean there's not a
lot of keepers in america of any of this
stuff you know and so all the stuff you
talk about all the nl5 haze versions all
the you know all most people's haze that
they know of is some hybrid of nevilles
i always wondered why sam never truly
worked hayes
um
being that he was the source for it and
he only released it and ops and stuff
it's the most baffling thing ever yeah
because and matt and i chat about this
too where it's like
um you know we have some friends that
firmly believe sam everything yes and
then there's and then there's me and and
matt who kind of like
com we we acknowledge his massive
contributions and we think he's done a
ton of stuff but that doesn't mean that
we think he's 100 accurate on the way he
throws it all down either no i mean it
would be the same for me if i'm telling
a story if
if i don't like someone i'm probably
going to minimize how much impact they
had on things because from my opinion
they didn't have much impact on [ __ ]
because they were liars but but you know
the two weirdest things to me about sam
is that what matt mentioned which is
hayes was his favorite line
and then he spent the next 30 years
by his own admittance only open
pollinating it trying to keep it as wide
as possible and never doing any
directional breeding
yeah
too much
yeah you know someone said what about
sam skunk hayes sam skunk hayes was so
unsellable for people that it was like
the classic freebie from c yeah from
seed boutique see there was so many of
them these seed boutiques got kilos or
whatever and they could never move
enough of it
so if you bought seeds in the earlier
mid 2000s chances you were going to get
freebies of skunk haze
or skunk thai haze or don't talk yeah
the thunk yeah that's what they called
it the thunk and i'm not dissing it i'm
just saying that like it just wasn't
what people were buying and so there was
way too much of it and so they gave it
they gave a bunch of it away you know
someone asked about connoisseurs
genetics doing in the uk with neville's
old work um i i don't know that
connoisseur he wasn't around connoisseur
was not around hanging out with us when
neville came back he wasn't in the
conversation
i don't know where his sourcing comes
from on his level stuff so i can't
really comment on that i can just say he
wasn't a part of our crew and he wasn't
before that either so i don't know where
he fits in in the equation you'd have to
ask him
so i i mean you know but basically what
it boils down to i'll say this about him
or anyone else
is that most people
um
when they start their own haze lines
they get hybrids from neville
like you know maybe not directly from
him but some kind of clone only yeah or
they got seed like for instance soma uh
his haze work was based off some g13 by
haze a seed that neville gave him yeah
and he found a male and that male was
the start of his seats yeah
um neville felt like the collie missed
and a lot of other sativas in holland
were all based off his nep his his haze
work
and they just didn't want to admit it
yeah they didn't want to say it was just
his
yeah um but you know all the nl5 haze
all the pif all the ssh all the mango
haze all the neville's haze amnesia all
that it's all from cuts neville selected
and crossed
you know or and then people took took
that stuff and did what they wanted with
it and so i know that
i know that connoisseur or whatever he
claims he has some old cuts that were
floating around europe
and he's got you know matt was talking
about some of that some of the stuff
that uh congravido was helping neville
with
something
uh yeah sorry
uh but you know he was doing a bunch of
that what was it it was like neville's
haze mullen baby madness stuff like that
he was doing some hybrids because
neville was basically interested in the
grail of the grail project yeah which
was trying to work on that trying to get
a fire haze line but he felt the haze
genetics were too narrow i actually did
during that time i did one that was a
god it was like clockwork orange the
piff and we called it uh and uh above
afino called the kids grail during that
time
yeah the outback haze comes from that
work yeah there was a bunch of stuff
that now he called it the holy grail
project um and it was basically him
trying to figure out things he could
cross old haze cuts and seed to
that would maintain that crazy sativa
yeah
and so they released a bunch of stuff
with various neville's hazes neville's
haze was actually not supposed to be
released
it was the first step in the holy grail
project yes it was them taking an uh an
a5 and crossing it to the c dad and
getting both hazes in one plant
yeah and it just so happens they found
this crazy pheno and decided to release
seats
you know
right i mean that's pretty much what it
was um
but
there was uh you know so yeah i mean he
would have various partners at various
times shanti was doing things shanti
actually has
i think something he calls grail haze
um you know right now on his site you
know he's got i haven't looked he's got
a couple new haze projects
of things that him and neville were
working on and he just decided to
release
um
you know and i think it's it's all from
that same
same general era when they were crossing
various sativas to each other and seeing
what was going to pop up
you know yeah i don't think it's
anything more than that really
it's just super you know super
equatorial probably
yeah someone's asking about um ingomar
to shaman's haze you know i never got to
run that but i did grow some of ingomar
to shaman's other stuff like the purple
widow and all i can say is that stuff
does not do well in california indoor it
is the i
i have never seen anything herm so bad
and autoflower so reliably
then ingomar de shaman's work grown in
the u.s it might not do that over there
it might be acclimated for outdoor
amsterdam but over here it did not do
well
yeah and i mean a lot of those haste
things it's like they're
they do do phenomenal outdoor like those
those ones i gave my buddy but
you know none almost none of us living
near the equator yeah that's the problem
so you're not you're not you're gonna
have a hard time finishing any of it
yeah i didn't take the time to acclimate
them at the time i didn't even know what
acclimating was when i grew them so
there was no like there was no me trying
to grow it grow a clone of it and also
it was autoflowering so you couldn't
take clones of it anyways somebody asked
do you have any hazes currently yeah i
mean i i have uh
um
you know i have a uh a cube in black uh
i i've got a couple other uh haze cups
i've got the i've got the uh i've got
the dog [ __ ] which i view as an nl5 hey
spino
so yeah i have i have four or five or so
hey someone just said creepy out of
colombia
that's funny that's remember i told you
a long time ago over on mr nice's site
there was someone that was from columbia
that sent me seeds of crippy it was
spelled c-r-i-p-i and i always
pronounced it creepy because i didn't
crippy wasn't a word at the time that
people were using in california so i
just i thought it meant creepy and i
thought he was home i'll mention this
for a second that uh someone was just
mentioning that um
you know uh
metal haze um metal haze came out i
believe in the early two early mid
2000's forum era that's flowers by these
guys dutch flowers and they wrote
amazing ad copy for the time
their descriptions of how they how they
describe their seeds they were offering
was certainly an early case of using
advertisement and language to sell seeds
because they got people drooling over
the ship
right
yep um and i believe our buddy bodie
doesn't he have a metal haze
f3 or something like that he put out
recently yeah he put out one and and the
rev had his cut of metal haze me and him
did some stuff with it
um it's a positronics haze 19 skunk one
according to jojo and he's the one who
supposedly made it for richard
calrissian who sold it as dutch flowers
that's that
yeah so um you know
the uh
um but it you know at the time it was
like metal hey i mean they would always
claim that it would sell out within a
day or two being released yeah and a lot
of stuff did and a lot of stuff their
stuff
they were really good at the forums of
getting people to be hyped up and yeah
their computer and ready to buy when it
dropped
yeah they were early adopters of that
kind of technique i grew a bunch of
metal haze and metal haze f2s from seed
lines and i grew
revs cut and refs cut to me was the
supreme version of any of that stuff any
of that stuff it was so much better than
any of the a lot of stuff that i saw
from the uh the seed lines was mostly
jungly flower that was not anything
viable for today's market it wasn't even
that great of smoke but his his metal
haze cut um the revs was more i would
say skunk one dominant um in its in his
flower time and its structure but still
with a hazy twist to it and a lot of
terpene and i should say before i forget
somebody mentioned that um the dutch
flowers used to claim that it was named
metal haze because of metal halides
yeah and that's actually true um they
went on and on and on about how
growing their haze under metal halides
brought out the
equatorial uh aspects of the sativa
because of the type of blue
um and if you grew it under hps it
wasn't going to do the same thing
it's [ __ ]
[ __ ]
i'm just saying that's what they said
yes that's their copyright but that's
literally what they said they said that
it
but the original description of
positronics haze 19 skunk one was that
it had a metallic coppery smell yes but
that was of course dutch flowers never
ever admitted their sourcing for it no
no of course not no
that's like this stuff all existed as a
metallic haze from positronics but
everybody kind of forgot that that whole
copywriting from that and just moved on
uh no mercy supply i remember them
i don't think they sold much to
the us though
but yeah people were somebody i don't
know hopefully the person that asked me
who was joining see someone said is the
c5 male still alive uh and that's uh
there's a thing called c5 but that's
actually a
northern lights 5 by c ma female yeah
and that cutting is actually in in
holland and it floats around america now
the sea male
uh
shanty says he has it
and there's great debate amongst our
crew if he still does or not he says he
has afghan tea too he says he has it um
yeah the funny part about the the afghan
tea party is what he says is he lost the
skunk part of the super skunk yeah so
male 1 yeah i do think
because i've seen shanti do this before
with the um the g13 widow that he may be
leaving out
um a part of the genetics and saying yes
we have afghan t but it's probably an
afghan t hybrid like ash on one of those
so he says that he still has the
the cmail
we know that for years he had it
neville says he gave it to him
uh you know uh
you know
matt's buddy uh posted a picture of it
from the swiss days in full flower
that we have uh but there's great debate
amongst the crew what he has and doesn't
are you familiar with any of the kiwi
seed stuff the mako haze and the um no i
mean i've heard you i've heard you and
crybaby and friends talk about it i
think
i think damp crane might have bought out
kiwi or vice versa i can't it's been a
while uh i will say that
is my favorite probably it's it's
probably the coolest coffee shop
when i was going it's ambiance the way
it was built uh it would have it had
really nice weed you know it had really
good weed um
often you know and so i like them
yeah you know i mean i haven't been
there in a long time now so who knows
but at least back then they were the
bomb
yeah um
so
uh yeah people have their a5 and c5 does
people are talking about a5 and c5 which
are both
uh nl5 haze cuts one uses the a dad one
uses the c dad they're both alive in
europe and america
um they're super political
uh so it's very hard to breed with them
it's very hard to advertise that you
have
yeah that's been them
big [ __ ] issue like i know people
would like you know the nl5 crossed a5
and c5 or the hawaiian lights crossed to
it would be nice if we could do stuff
with that but
you know politics are politics and
people are [ __ ] and the the thing
about the dutch is that with old cuts
and stuff like that it's all business
yeah so if they're not making money off
it and you don't have permission on it
they don't really want to give you the
right to do it yeah and then you'll get
a bunch of crap from them over it
you know
uh is kind of is kind of the way it
works
you know um and uh
yeah so
you know they
but that's that's an issue you know like
we don't know what shanti still has
no we don't and um
i i did try to to actually make a
purchase a big purchase from shanti some
some people know about this in our crew
where i i was going to buy everything he
had with afghan tea just to see what
what popped out of it but he wouldn't
tell me what he was going to send me and
just wanted me to send him you know
thousand plus dollars on uh on a whim
and i kind of backed off from it i kind
of i wish i would have but like you know
things are getting tied around cove and
i was like
i have i don't know when i'm gonna do it
i have a i have probably like 700 seeds
from shanti that i need to pop at some
point
i still have that big ass bag of mr and
ice gear
yeah i mean i have uh i don't know i
there's like probably 10 things that i
have like 70 or 80 seeds of each yeah
uh you know in the collection of stuff
and do it to it
yeah i mean i had a dude i had all these
plans and then in 2017
and 18 and not 19 but 20 so like there
just kept being these crazy fires
yeah how dare you get burned down you
know and we actually uh our uh my buddy
um and i like we had a bunch of we had
we had a bunch of stuff
uh of shanti's in the field
um and we had someone like my like uh
mendo p by maple
uh and all that kind of stuff
um and it all burned
yeah
you know
uh he's got pictures of it but we never
we never actually got to try it yeah
you know so uh
seed popping became like you know am i
gonna make it through the summer
yeah
yeah that last move i had like two moves
ago actually not the last one i popped a
bunch of [ __ ] and then found out i had
to move they were selling my house i'm
like
that always happens it always [ __ ]
happens yeah it's right dramatically
to figure that kind of stuff out but i
have some i have some i have four or
five hazy things from shanti and then i
have like
four five six you know skunk afghan nl
type things from him just to see
yeah you know
um
i don't even know what that's in
reference to
i'll just leave that one alone
sometimes i ignore the comments
sometimes i look at them but that one i
don't know i don't know
um what
i don't know but but that's uh that's
that word itself you know it really only
has like one connotation in american use
fleshy flaccid member i just flaccid in
itself i mean when do you use it you
know yeah yeah it makes me immediately
think of elon musk for some reason i
don't know why yeah i mean you know
because he probably you know he's
whatever so yeah
um but i you know i will say that uh
yeah ortega
uh there's a and there's a bunch of
mystery around that because
maybe this is unfair but shanti is a
little bit like uh cornbread ricky
and that uh he talks in riddles a lot of
times and even when he explains stuff
that's very i think this isn't this
isn't a diss to either one of them by
the way
but i'm just saying like
they write this these like three four
paragraphs about something and at the
end you're like what does this mean
yeah crime is also very very um
verbose and and uh mystery writing i'd
say crybaby is good at that yeah he's
got he's got a good uh mystery ad copy
uh you know iambic pentameter yeah i
mean there's you know language you know
language matters when you're trying to
evoke
you know
something or whatever and so voters yeah
yeah i mean shanti is sean yeah cryptic
shanti can be
very clear
sometimes shanti in two or three
sentences can answer something that
you've been wondering about for 10 years
and then not answer something else
that's very simple in three or four
paragraphs so i one thing i got to add
because i did say earlier that he was
one of the anti-femme guys despite all
of that in 2008 2009 he went out of his
way
despite hating feminized work not
wanting to do it himself he was one of
the first people to really really
educate me more about feminized work how
to properly do it and not just you know
be throwing [ __ ] at a wall he gave me a
lot of recipes he gave me a lot of
advice during that time and he's
integral
he's
he's very integral into american
feminized lines because of that you know
so despite him having negative opinions
on that he was still kind enough to take
the time to educate me and mentor me on
femme stuff so i thought that was really
cool i would definitely say that uh in
our crew of friends i'm team shanti yeah
i like him you know i think he's done a
bunch you know
to kiss him on the mouth
you know i don't know necessarily about
that
uh but um
but he but you know he he's been in it
for a long time uh he's another one of
those guys that like he kind of took the
torch from neville
um you know he's done a bunch of big
work
uh he's been heavily involved in a lot
of things
and he's done something that's really
hard
which is he's he's he's sold seeds for a
living for a quarter century have you
ever grown into any of the mandalas
stuff
ashbury
um there's some other stuff uh a point
something to be on the brain something
there are a few good ones that he had
mandala mike someone just asked about
that it was a similar era um totally
totally underrated totally underrated
for for the um european seat team i
think he's still around too he probably
and i honestly think too like just so
people know it's not like
i'm expecting if you run a bunch of
except for the haze stuff you could find
i'm sure some stuff in there but it's
not like i'm expecting with some other
shanti's lines that like you would find
something that would just blow your head
off
completely and be as elite as some of
the best stuff of today
um but i do think
that it tie like the genetics tie back
to an era before all of the the
bottlenecking
yeah
and so i think you could blend that
you know i mean like straight up like
imagine you took [ __ ] something like
cookie and threw it on
you know any number of his things mango
haze yeah or nordle or whatever you know
all of a sudden it's like i just it's
just like so much different
yeah you know it's not any of the same
[ __ ]
that you're you know because that's what
happens these days is like it's all the
same 40 or 50 cuts blended together in
different ways yeah
this is really what it boils down to la
nina is a really nice drink
i like la nina a bunch i have a bunch of
la nina seeds
uh and our buddy uh uh yo sami
yeah uh talks about how they've crossed
la nina to various old neville cuts and
the results have been pretty phenomenal
and they get sold in coffee shops and
it's a it's a good thing
yeah um la nina is supposed to be a
white widow by uh mulan bit me madness
um
so it's it's like one of the few things
that
isn't you know uh sativa direct from sam
yeah
i guess you would say yeah
yeah you know uh
its origins are mysterious but both
neville and shanti say that it came from
you know this region of australia
a lot of my friends out in australia
that have been growing for a super long
time outdoors there that are really
familiar with uh
the genetics that floated around there
always go back to indians and thais they
think everything is is indians and thais
basically the bush weed that they have
out there or some combination of indian
and thai whereas like with our american
stuff we have a lot of colombian and
mexicans
out there that was where they were
sourcing that was what it was
that was their import that was what they
were getting free seed
you know um and somebody is uh somebody
and maybe or somebody mentioned the
mango
the mango haze from shanti is still a
line that people find consistently good
things in it oh yeah yeah it's one of my
favorites um you know um and so it's
it's one of those things that even today
um i have i found two mango haze you
knows that i loved a bunch and kept for
a long time
um i lost them in a robbery
sadly but it's good
i prefer mango haze to super silver
someone just asked about wally i
actually talked to wally um
about a month ago we're old friends uh
old friends he's grown some of my stuff
out in australia out back in 2007 i
think
but i was talking about coming on the
show and he said he would but i think he
just recently did a different show so
we'll see what's going on i don't want
to to
you know overwhelm the dude so we'll see
what's going on and somebody asked about
yo sami um yo sami would be a phenomenal
person to have on the show for sure he's
got a wealth of knowledge he started
growing for neville's crew in about
94.95
so he has a lot of first-hand experience
with a lot of famous cuts yeah um but
he's a pretty private person
yeah
and so i don't you know i don't know
um you know he's been i asked him before
um and you know it doesn't mean it
couldn't happen but it hasn't
yeah not yet we haven't had a hefty yet
it'd be cool though i think he was he
was very active on the on he was on the
forums when i was yeah he was extremely
active back then um and he posts on ig a
bit and stuff but as far as like showing
his face and talking and going through
all that mess um
you know and i i totally respect people
for having issues with that yeah let's
have hampi on
i you know i mean i would sooner smash
my nuts in a drawer than bring on hempy
i'm sorry you know in all honesty
for all the people watching the couple
hundred or something that's here um
hempy would be a great ad
he might drive us nuts as far as
entertainment
you know uh he would probably be like
watching a train wreck
yeah i mean at least if he talked he
wouldn't be typing and spelling because
that's yes
yeah he i thought i was i was a raging
idiot
even back then but hepe always had me
beat he was the guy to be like bro can
you calm down a little bit people are
gonna hate you if you say that
me saying that someone i mean i yes he's
cry baby i agree i don't know what i
don't know where it would go
but the entertainment value of having
hempy on
tom hill you know we uh we tom hill
communication
tom hill it communicates with our crew
he would also be a great ad
um a lot of the old timers are are are
very very
their they're characters you know yeah
other characters i mean these people
people don't know we actually have an
interview already recorded
with um
what's his name
i mean do we really want to say his name
i mean okay well i won't say his name
but it was a person who was one of the
original owners of one of the earliest
hydra shops in the pacific northwest and
it was highly recommended by
greg greg because he knows a ton he was
integral to the nord lights crew and all
that stuff but
we haven't released it because some of
these dudes like they didn't really want
to talk weed more than they wanted to
talk about [ __ ] hookers so i'll i'll
say this
which is crazy
the guy talked at such a rate
that i think i got
two sentences in in an hour and a half
he made not so quite if you can believe
it i couldn't talk and matt and i were
texting each other and i would we did
get
i think one or two very interesting
tidbits like half a second but it was
literally like it's no exaggeration it
was probably 30 seconds
of weed talk
and an hour and a half of the craziest
hookers and and
and stories from then and
cops
trump and his conspiracy theories and it
was it was i i mean it was we may
release it one day just because he was
very excited for us to release it so why
you know he was i don't know
we chose to sort of protect him
um by not releasing it because you know
it was it was the thing where it was
like we were sort of interested in weed
history
and he was sort of interested in telling
us all the wild tales of his youth
yeah i think he i think he had a
different uh opinion like he thought
maybe we were interviewing about his
life as opposed to weed and the the his
relation to weed i mean but it was also
kind of like even when you would try to
steer him in the direction of talking
more about weed
he would just mention it as a side and
then get right back to something super
kooky yeah i mean the dude was hella
cool he was [ __ ] hilarious so maybe
we will you know like i i mean i think
now that we're put past the trump era
and a lot of that
everybody's mad stuff i think maybe we
could release it now it wouldn't be as
or maybe it would be a worse time to do
it i don't know i mean i don't know dude
it just it it goes to show that we will
have a poll
you can be very important in music or
weed or art or this or that or whatever
it might be
and outside of that you can be a human
with a wide variety of views
you know uh and a lot of us have some
illnesses
you know one kind or another like
there's something there's something odd
about weed people
you know um
and uh but i mean it was like it's
it there's parts of it that are pretty
risque
too yeah like you know i say some [ __ ]
up [ __ ] and i say some off the wall
homoerotic things even and this some of
this [ __ ] i was like god i don't know if
we can put that out there yeah it was it
was definitely r-rated at certain
aspects of it you know um which is fine
you know but that's that's the thing
it's like you know there's an aspect
where some of these old-timers that are
that were super involved can be tough
interviews because
they're they were kooky people when they
were young
yeah and now they're old kooky people
yeah
you know and i don't want him to get
canceled over or anything [ __ ] crazy
because that can happen you know like
if people think that he said something
too extreme but
i think it's fun and like the duke is an
important part of that pacific northwest
history there's no doubt about that he
was there i mean
he he even was a part of operation green
merchant and and got rid of it he was
definitely involved in tons of [ __ ]
getting him to talk about any specifics
yeah was tough
yeah you know he just he
i mean he was basically like we were the
audience
yeah oh yeah and it was his we weren't
really interviewing him it was like we
were there for his his monologue i did
get a few like of my my
really weird uh
where i try to keep a straight face and
say something totally off the wall i got
like two of those in i got two of those
in the whole time
somebody said eddie left was a wild
interview eddie left well i mean i've
talked about it before he was a pretty
he was a decent friend of mine
um you know he was uh he had huge balls
and he was also a massive egomaniac
yeah you know people are complicated you
know we have we have pluses and minuses
um you know uh neville was complicated
yeah you know neville was uh you know i
mean
you know neville had addictions and
neville had issues and you know and all
that type of stuff but he also had huge
balls you'd be hard pressed to find like
to get a crowd of a bunch of seed makers
together and find more than 10 people
that aren't ex junkies like we are all
[ __ ] up most of us i'm one of the ten
yeah i know you're one of the very few
one of them
but that was uh you can you can thank uh
dead tour for that yeah yeah because i
got i got to see what even like
successful junkies looked like yeah and
i was like whoa
yeah that's intense being a functional
junkie is a real thing
i mean
in the senate what i mean by functional
is like the dude that i was traveling
with he just made so much money
yeah that he never had to do any of this
like the [ __ ] that people like he he
made plenty of money you could easily
afford his habit so you just got to see
it from the perspective of like what
does it do to you
yeah he didn't really have to hustle or
lie or cheat or this or that or anything
like that that wasn't his thing
yeah you know but when he ran out
that [ __ ] hurts that [ __ ] hurts
you know painful painful feeling that's
uh
and the amount and the crazy part about
it is is that to go from like flopping
like a fish and sweating and vomiting
and pooping and
you know fever and all this different
stuff and then somebody shows up and
takes care of them
and he's like let's get some tacos yeah
five minutes later oh he pops out he's
like i'm gonna wash my face let's go get
some food yeah and he just spent two
hours in the hotel like in in you know
unbelievable misery yeah
that [ __ ] sucks and it's for real yeah
but i mean it's that's it's also true
that a lot of that addiction and stuff
was super common up in mendo and
humboldt and all that because it's dark
and rainy in the winter
yeah and especially back in the day
people got lonely
you know and they had a lot of money
because that you know we'd sold for a
lot back then
so there was a lot of people that would
started out as back to the landers and
ended up you know
addicted to opiates or cocaine or this
or that or whatever else because they
were bored and winter
yeah i mean even when i was i started my
career as a [ __ ] up
like everybody during that time wasn't
just selling weed at least out of our
group nobody was just selling we like
because it was this you were gonna get
the same charges didn't really [ __ ]
matter if you were selling weed you
might as well be selling everything
because other stuff made more money than
we so it was it was just it was around
it was common during that time but
what's interesting about that is not not
to dis neville on it or anything like
that but
what's weird is that neville being a
hardcore junkie
is actually what brought him to
amsterdam and they had the seed and he
was part dutch and they had part of you
know they had very liberal policies over
there and they got extremely clean dope
from
from asia uh traditionally and so he
went there to be a junkie
yep and then kind of fell into the seed
game
you know while there so it's it's kind
of like without
without heroin
uh
a lot of the things that we talk about
don't exist
yeah i think it was clyde clyde that
told me that neville got
um he he was
the dutch government had a program for
people to get off heroin they would help
them with the trade and neville was
breeding exotic birdseed and they gave
him money to start the bank that way
uh to get off dope and uh claim that he
was breeding more nutritious
uh you know omega-3 whatever the [ __ ]
you know protein rich
you know yeah
any and he took that money and he used
it to start the seed bank uh which is
super punk rock you know
yeah let the government pay for your
[ __ ] don't have it to be gone and a
lot of the a lot of the pictures in
those old seed catalogs and stuff like
that are from his pho he mentioned it
his photographer clyde who's still i
believe still alive yeah
yeah and clyde and and you know he you
know he went with
uh neville to on neville's amsterdam
trip
yeah
you know the afghanistan trip yeah the
i'm sorry the afghanistan trip and so a
lot of the pictures like in neville's
first catalog of him holding hash
and him hanging out and smoking with uh
with you know the afghans and stuff that
was all his uh his photographer clyde
and
he's talked about doing an interview
with us but he also has
some kind of movie deal
thing with that specific story of the
afghanistan trip so he can't legally
tell it
for some reason like on a podcast it's
interesting in the sense that um you
know uh
maybe i should tell this because it's
kind of funny um but
sam
skunk man and neville both went to
afghanistan at different times and they
both have some pretty crazy stories
about it and sam has this funny story
about trying to get seeds from some of
these muhajideen and some of these
fighters and stuff
and there's this warlord that looked at
him and basically told him that uh flour
is for slaves and women
and real men smoked hash and so was he a
slave or a woman
and
sam got and sam got out of it by telling
him he had no interest
in the flower
that he agreed it was for slaves and
women but he wanted the seeds to be able
to grow to make his own hashish in
america brilliant and so
the afghan warlord decided that was fair
yeah and made him smoke a bunch of hash
with him to prove that he wasn't a [ __ ]
essentially yeah you know
um and uh
yeah and so and then you know neville
neville has a story and and clyde has
backed it up of going over there and
having to negotiate with literal
muajidine warlords
and you know they had a bunch of
american money and were they going to
get killed are they going to get robbed
sound the the story coming from from
clyde and neville
that is one of the best stories ever
especially the one that wasn't published
there's one that's out there that he's
that is part of the movie script that
people have seen but he told me the
stuff that wasn't in that and it sounds
like a [ __ ] nightmare like he was
overdosed dying
inside of this little tiny hut and he
had people trying to get they were
trying to get in to kill them
like they wanted to kill them because
they thought they were americans with
money so they wanted to [ __ ] kill
them
so
this is a funny story about that right
is that
in a weird way
uh when we just talked about how without
heroin neville ever would have been to
amsterdam
when neville went over there to get
seeds uh the afghanistan people were
very worried about cia and d and these
kind of groups and stuff and so they
wanted to make sure
that he wasn't a european spy
yeah right and so in order to prove that
him and clyde had to shoot heroin
because they because they were like
if you're not you know you're gonna if
you want these seeds if you want this
work if you don't want us to kill you
you have to prove that you're not and i
know that an agent would never
yeah yeah that is so they both they both
had to shoot heroin in order in order
and you know they were both they both
partied or whatever on that stuff but
clyde ode yeah clyde decided to die
you know and so then he od in a [ __ ]
hut in some you know
ancient village or whatever and had yeah
you know and it was it was it wasn't
like there was some like modern hospital
nearby
so he od'd on afghanistan on afghan
heroin neville didn't
and they were like okay well these guys
shoot up they made them shoot up in
front of them
and actually use needles and the whole
bit you know
uh and that's how he got the seeds
yeah
and then they tried to kill them yeah
and then they they tried to kill them i
would have died i mean you know i
couldn't have done it you know i didn't
have any
uh i would od for sure
yeah because i have zero
zero tolerance you know but i probably
would have just been right there with
neville but same story i mean sam didn't
have to do drugs but sam basically like
you know the way he tells the story or
whatever it's like you know
uh an afghan warlord was considering
turning him into his [ __ ]
yeah that's gotta suck you know like
maybe you know maybe
and so yeah so
those
there's definitely some indiana jones
aspects to those like uh
yeah going into war zones after seats
we need to have bodhi come on and tell
some of his indian trips
the in season one we wanted to do we
wanted we wanted to do a hippie hashish
trail thing oh yeah yeah remember and we
wanted to put more time and effort into
building it out because it's kind of a
long story
uh and bodhi agreed to do it and it's
just kind of gotten back burnered yeah
but it would probably be a great episode
uh because bodhi has the experience of
traveling and matt and i have a bunch
and some friends have a bunch of
documents and posters and different
things from that era
yeah yeah uh we could always get joe
petrie if we wanted to go
we could get the king of nepal on holy
[ __ ] that would probably be as off the
rails as hempy or
he did a show with um with the blue lies
the other day he did oh yes yes
likely duo
but there was there was you know a lot
of the early afghans and stuff like that
because all the sativas that people have
in america basically came with free
seeds with the kilos
yeah but the hashish didn't come with
free seeds so
sam and nev a bunch of these people had
to travel the hippie hashish trail
and go find them and bring it back
yeah you know um mel frank says that the
grower that he got the afghani one seeds
from in the bay had done that yeah
you know um supposedly the big bud is
from that
you know uh supposedly the steve murphy
that started the nl1 or the nl lines is
all from that
yeah is all from different people going
over to amsterd going over to you know
afghanistan
it was a female that went and it was gut
and the the murphy afghanis actually
they don't know if it was afghanistan or
pakistan but it was a girl that brought
it back young lady
oh my gosh what do i think i don't know
if i can answer that one
um
you know what do i think of the what do
i think of the the burner and the bodhi
collab
um i'll just say this uh bodhi's a good
friend and he's done a bunch of very
cool work
and there's a lot of people trying to
figure out how to survive in this weird
new world
yeah
it's not easy
uh and
um cookies and burner and all those
people aren't breeders
and they're definitely looking to keep
they don't know where to go and they
need help
yeah and they have to bring in outside
help
um because they've had kind of their new
new is sort of the same same
that they've had forever now
and they don't know where to go with it
um and it's sort of irrelevant for
cookie to have new [ __ ] because it's
like now they're a store and clothing
brand and they're just they're just
established yeah if all they had was
that one cookie explosion in 09 to 12
that produced the og kbb and the animal
and this and that and led to all this
other [ __ ]
you know but burner's a salesman he's a
rapper
you know they're going to need to
partner with real weed people
yeah
you know and bodhi's not a scumbag
no he's a very nice guy and i i i'm
stoked about it because i think it's
it's the way to influence
the rest of the the country as it were
that listen to people like cookies you
can finally push them into like better
weed and body knows good weed
and he's a good person
with that said if they [ __ ] if he
gets [ __ ] in this hole
yeah anyway i mean look what matt is
basically saying is that there's a
chance to stand outside and throw
molotov cocktails at every rich
established group that's trying to take
over weed
or you can try to work with them or work
within their structure and move them in
a different direction yeah and there's
arguments to be made on both sides
not every group is monolithic but
whether we like it or not uh you know
rich rich investor kids are taking over
weed in california
yeah
you know and if you if you're not
willing to work with rich investors you
don't have a chance you don't have a
chance in hell you're going to end up
you know on friday nights telling
[ __ ] stupid history stories is what's
going to happen
well i mean you know
this this is fine because this is
actually a hobby for me and i enjoy
bullshitting and i don't care if i make
money but
you know i'll say this too
you know we talked about it before when
i was doing the superdog project 20
years ago
there was no market for american seed
sales
yeah there was almost no way to get a
hold of people to sell seeds to them if
you they were interested in your seats
yeah it was just too risky instagram in
the last 10 years
has created an environment where all
these [ __ ] can start breeding
and selling direct to the public and
they were buying seeds and selling those
seeds and there was there's been an
explosion of breeding
right yes and all that breeding was
based on a bunch of small and
medium-sized farmers and thousands of
indoors and thousands of small outdoors
growing weed and pushing it through the
traditional and the dispensary market
yeah well that's all been cut off now
and it's all a bunch of corporations
pushing with the dispensary market
the traditional market is trashed and
there's not very much money in it and so
in order to sell a bunch of beans and
have phenol hunting and do a bunch of
that stuff growers need to be making
money
yeah they need to be having disposable
income to go to these things and buy a
bunch of seed and look through it and
have a bunch of it not work out and have
one or two things they find they like
yep you know and so the dynamics of seed
making has changed dramatically
yeah um i'm actually matt and i chat
about this i'm actually more worried
about diversity than i was before
you know
uh legalization has been so far bad for
diversity yeah
you know um and the way that they've set
things up you would think that you could
really open it up but you can't
uh they make it very narrow how to make
money
yeah you know and what to try and where
to get it most people have to get stuff
from nurseries and so if the nursery
doesn't want to make a commercial amount
of clones of it you can't even buy it
yeah they've made a lot of rules on a
lot of regulations that you know it's
not as easy like in the 215 era
[ __ ] could go to emerald cup or
high times or whatever and go see matt
and go see bodie and go see swamp boys
or go see whoever and buy packs of beans
and this is my next this is my next 50
this is my next 25.
yeah i'm growing these from seed outdoor
next year
yeah that's gone and then all they
needed to do to do that was money in
their pocket and the desire yeah
you know
and now
now what do you do with all that
yeah that's just gone now now shit's
gone and so it's it's hard you know um
and uh and on all that and so a lot of
that diversity is gone you could look at
the 215 era when we first got on ig
really and
how many hundreds and hundreds of small
medical gardens would you see people
posting [ __ ] that were growing 25 or 50
or 99 plants yeah
tons
different
and now it's not the case and so you
know so none of you get to talk [ __ ]
about bodhi or i'll [ __ ]
deal with all you guys but you know seed
makers like matt or like bodhi or like
see any any of them everyone's got to
figure out
what they're going to do to survive
because the market has changed and the
buyers have changed and the pressures
have changed
and how do you fit in
yeah
i know he changes i hope he changes
things and i hope i hope that he's one
of the avenues that
opens a lot of a lot of smokers minds to
[ __ ] more than cookies and og if
someone's got to do it someone has to
break that mold
and i i hope you know and there's
there's an aspect to it where it's like
you know the the the
the bad part about it for anybody that's
gonna [ __ ]
oh it would be
bodhi decided to save his family by
joining the borg
yeah
the good part of it would be
burner can promote the [ __ ] out of
crappy weed
so what happens if bodhi makes them
improve their thing and he's promoting
the crap out of much better weed yeah
and then people end up smoking much
better weed and then we'll make money
off much better weed and then there's a
connoisseur market that doesn't exist
right right now currently
yeah because you know it's like i
so
you know it there's an aspect to it
where it's like people can throw stones
from outside but it's not that easy of a
thing
where does the seed breeder go you know
you can't even back in the day
how many how many gray area cups and you
know not gray area coffee shop but how
many cup how many events would you go to
a year
yeah yeah you could be you could be a
seed breeder and you could be at one or
two events a month selling seeds to the
public
yeah
easy yeah during some years you could
during some years you know and and you
would there would be a top dog booth and
there would be a riot booth and there
would be a csi booth and there would be
i remember the first year that bodhi was
at emerald cup
right yeah like i didn't even get to
talk to him till sunday because i felt
bad because there was literally like a
80 yard line yeah in front of his booth
friday and saturday all day long it was
like a mad house there was thousands of
people with money in their pocket that
were gonna buy seeds from bodhi and talk
to him it was a beautiful time yeah now
you can't do that because he's not
licensed he's not registered it's not
sold through whatever he doesn't have a
dispensary license he doesn't have a he
doesn't have all the [ __ ] pieces of
paper that allow you to just walk up and
talk to him yeah
yeah
so that's hard so that you've the the
rules have cut off a lot of these
independent types from even seeing you
you know yeah and talking to you i mean
you know it would be funny like when we
would go to emerald cup and stuff part
of the reason why we started doing these
canola candle illuminati parties is
because
none of the br none of the friends got
to talk to each other
yeah yeah because they're all busy
working their booth all day long because
the customer wants to talk to them
to make the purchase
yeah and you don't want to be a rude
[ __ ]
and so we started throwing these like
nighttime events you know uh every night
that every night that had happened at
the emerald cup
so that all the people after getting
done working they could just go [ __ ]
with their friends yeah i wanted to see
who the best kisser was but he wanted to
see his friends i wanted to see my
friends you know and so you know we
rented beautiful houses and we cooked
out and you know we had bitter on the
grill we had a bunch of really good
friends and tons of people would come
you know tons of tons of breeders tons
of movers and shakers and after they
were done talking all day to customers
they wanted to hang out with people like
them and shoot the [ __ ] yeah
because before it's like you're going to
go up and you're going to try to talk to
bodhi or csi or something on on friday
at 3 o'clock
there's six people deep and 50 yards
long waiting to talk
yeah
yeah those are stressful times too like
yeah when you're talking to a new person
every five minutes it's hard to remember
[ __ ] and a lot of those companies made
bank off renting booths
yeah yeah so you know a lot of people
output thousands of dollars and hired
friends to help them run the booth and
move things and stuff and so there's a
cost to it so you want to let people
work
yeah you want to let people hand you
know shake hands and shoot the [ __ ] and
tell and talk about their strains and
you know sell as much of their stuff to
the public as they could yeah
you know
um i mean now this year i think at
emerald cup they finally did this thing
where
there was like a little like legacy
grower section
i heard you know where you know you
could uh you could go see people where
they could have weed where it wasn't
like it didn't have to be through a
dispensary yeah through a distro because
essentially the 215 era cups were like
swap meets
yeah
they were two we didn't know we didn't
know how good we had it with two fish oh
no people could go and sell seed and
they could sell weed and they could sell
dabs and they could sell this and they
could sell t-shirts and they could just
rent a booth
you know have some basic licensing and
show up and you know meet people
yeah and uh you know and you know it um
you know now it sucks
yeah
someone mentioned that the other day
that someone talked about the party on a
podcast the other day one of the things
that i'm we matt and i made a big
mistake on and uh kovid [ __ ] us on the
parties but we're gonna we're gonna try
to bring them back is that yeah i wish
we had given out like a high my name is
yeah because a lot of these people they
don't know each other by sight they know
each other by their handle yeah or we
don't know each other by first name by
first names or something yeah so you're
walking around and you're like oh that
person was there yeah [ __ ] you know
because there's hundreds of people there
not that you don't talk to your friends
all night but it's like there's people
you miss
and maybe you'd walk by him and be like
holy [ __ ] that's so-and-so
yeah
next time i'm gonna have the dank dabber
there you watch you watch oh my god you
know i love that guy if you guys don't
know dank dabbers where it's at he makes
me smile
but it was cool it was like essentially
what we tried to do is like when when
cannabis got super legal we tried to
have like an old school harvest festival
party where the tables were just covered
in weed
and jars of all different kinds and
people could just roll joints and take
bong hits and shoot the [ __ ] and this is
what i brought and this is what you have
you know
um and so uh
you know it it eventually the last year
so we did that i don't think we went to
the cup
no no we just waited for all the people
we wanted to see to come and party and
hang out that first year i went i went
to the cup and i remember i got sick i
was like there are too many [ __ ]
people here i'm gonna go back
and uh yeah but that was what was really
cool about a lot of those old events was
it was organized chaos
yeah
and now the more rules that they put
into place was 64 it sort of cut off the
customers from being able to go
i mean especially like emerald cup in
december
there would be so many people that would
show up with money in their pocket from
their outdoor
yep ready to buy seeds to fino hunt for
the next outdoor yep and that was that
hundreds and hundreds of thousands of
dollars were spent on just that oh yeah
easy lots of money
you know was was was spread out and so
now one year it was gone that was
done so now there's now the whole market
but now not only the seed the seed
makers ability to get in front of people
right and to build their
brand or whatever you know yeah or like
the the seed maker's ability to sell or
even the people that would normally buy
their seeds how little they're getting
for weed right now
yeah really puts a lot of pressure on
seed makers yeah yeah it's a different
time dude you know they have they're
going to have to adapt how they're doing
things and you know we'll see who sticks
and with that i think i've got to start
getting ready to wind it down because
we're going to be
45 minutes
again i'll let matt do his pitches
okay pitches he might have
yeah so we have the breeder syndicate
patreon you can find it by going to
google type in breeder syndicate patreon
if you go to patreon and try to search
it it won't show up because it's a weed
one and they don't allow that so
do google
raiders syndicate patreon and you'll
find us and you come hang out with us we
have a discord we all hang out watch
fights we do all kinds of stupid [ __ ] in
there and um
go check out speakeasy bank they help
produce the show
and uh riot seatco.com for all the nl
stuff and yeah wildlife stuff you can
always dm me on ig
you can ask me questions through there
you can join the discord and you can
hang out over there
uh and everybody again we always
appreciate your friday night sorry about
missing last week
uh we'll be back next week yep
all right thanks everyone
want more breeder syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsteads.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
you