welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate all right hello everyone
welcome uh I'm Matt today I'm here with
Stacy J AKA mure as he was known on the
forums um I've been chasing you down for
a long time you're a very well-respected
member uh of our community and it's an
honor to have you on I don't know have
you done other interviews yet
uh I did uh an interview with my buddy
uh Chip Baker and the okay the what was
it the real dir Baker yeah did that a
couple times but that's it I'm I'm a I'm
more of a stand at the back of the room
kind of guy I know you need to be at the
front man because you have a lot of you
have a lot of history and a lot of
answers and a lot of stuff I'd like to
dig out of you so first and foremost we
usually dive into the easy stuff which
is what was your early intro to weed as
far as just smoking your first intro to
seeing this plant that is
cannabis well I grew up with uh I grew
up around
uh
uh early charismatic Christians and 1%
bikers my old man had a excavating
company and he had a lot of uh
uh bikers who were in a club called the
pagans and and
um so I I one of my favorite most
awesome smells I ever smelled was herb
burning in my old man's office and uh
just the best smell ever and
probably first smoked it
13ish yeah sounds about
right at probably a church
camp yeah so were your parents the
charismatic Christians my mom was but my
dad was uh was a a cokehead yeah or a
raving Coke attic more than cokehead
charismatic
cokehead Evangelical cokehead yeah I had
one of those
too so what kind of weed was around when
you first started smoking like uh what
what what era are we looking
at well when I was 16 and that's when I
became enthusiastic IC yeah um you know
you get out from under your parents Wing
it's easy you got your car you can go
get some herb and so all I wouldn't say
that everything that you would have seen
in the uh the old High Times trans High
Market
quotation there was a variety of
imports
um if you were a little bit older than
me you would be much more Savvy you know
I was you know 16 and getting whatever
it was that the older guys were selling
but you had everything from Jamaican to
Colombian
to I think the first QP I bought was uh
aapo gold and it was down on the DC line
because I grew up in in the DC suburbs
of Maryland yeah and
uh the DC line area was a Trad TR
illegal sales area and where we could
always buy underage booze or or what
have you and and that was real
golden yeah pot
um there was some thae weed um never saw
any Thai
stick and then it just became pretty
much Mexi and
then became Mexi and kbud so there was
there was two kinds of pot it was you
know commercial and most of the
commercial that was getting to me in the
DC area which I sold you know brick weed
and grew my own
pot
uh that stuff was ironically coming via
Colorado Springs and and boulder oh wow
so colle kid Network were you were you
just uh popping seeds that you had from
your stash when you were first started
growing
I first popped seeds when I
was 17 right before I went into Army
Reserves on a bet oh no and yeah and uh
the seeds weren't there when I got or
the plants weren't there when I came
back did they get harvested did they
get no idea it wasn't wasn't
me but clones you know it back then when
I started to grow I I think it would
have been uh the thing that I have in my
in my mind as a Tim stamp of that era of
beginning was uh it was
uh The Grateful Dead version of uh the
the the Warlock shows in h Hampton and
I'm not a big dead show but that's like
okay this is when I started growing so
this is about
89 and clones were were they were really
hard to get and seeds were really hard
to get and I knew some people in
Virginia and they grew like Mass Super
Skunk
um probably the first
real seeds that I popped that were not
you know throw away Mexi seeds would
have been a a hash Haze cross and
ironically again those seeds Had An
Origin they were made in Eagle Colorado
and this old grower that I knew went on
a road trip and he brought these seeds
back and we had a [ __ ] ton of them we
grew that
pot a lot
and it's still what I
consider kind bud it it's still that
that
imprinted profile knows
that I don't know it's like good ganja
when it wasn't good
ganja when there wasn't a lot of good
yeah was it long flowering since it was
a haze
hybrid no we didn't flower [ __ ] long
yeah didn't have a chance to flower it
[ __ ] long right
no no that is definitely learned along
the way yeah but uh you know it was it
was it was was typical it wasn't uh it
wasn't some long flowering thing so this
is all while you're in DC and Maryland
it kind of just like it it's weird to me
because I think about DC and like the
risks involved with that being some kind
of extra Federal
territory well you know
Ironically in the early 90s I believe it
would have been uh during uh the Clinton
Administration that someone in DC in
Dupont Circle MH called at the White
House and
threatened the president and he had
plants growing and he was tripping balls
and I believe that that was the
first cultivation arrest in Washington
DC but but Maryland was scary and
Virginia was really scary at the gross
store that we went to was called Home
Harvest and he was
uh you know from the pranker School
prankster school of thought the
yippy
um uh
early normal organizer and he always put
his grow stores right next to the bong
and dildo stores so that's
awesome yeah I mean it was a great
strategy it worked for him for a long
time all in one go get your bongs go get
your dildos you're set yeah and that
that that store was called Home Harvest
and guy's name was Jeff Edwards and he's
dead now but uh he's a real inspiration
to my business Harvest House and uh
really really good guy really incredible
resource to have you know you've got to
remember that this is the
uh you know just post operation green
Merchant era and everybody was scared
shitless because they were
very free and ordering everything online
with credit cards and all of a sudden
you know
everything uh it came to an end
and you know you went from being
carefree and Casual to people walking
quarter mile down the road to the grow
store yeah yeah it's wild so at what
point did you shoot out to Colorado or
is there any anything we should cover
before then that you can think of uh
well I did uh I did 10 months in San
Rafel Santa Venicia outside of San raell
okay
um not too I mean first time I ever paid
55 bucks for an eth that was shocking to
me I bet dude uh you know but that was
like 94 yeah
uh yeah that was that was definitely not
the not the high point of my growing
career
moved back to Maryland but uh you know
ended up uh in
Colorado from briefly in 97 and then
full-time never leaving again in
98 and but moved you out
there everybody that I knew in Maryland
who didn't um move to the Bay Area
California Northern
California ended up moving to Netherland
Colorado um so I had a a really huge not
huge but I had a a bunch of friends here
and it's
uh it's a it's got a really big musical
history it's a kind of a hippie Enclave
kind of the way like lauro Canyon or uh
yeah similar places where uh band
members in the
70s congregated you had the uh Caribou
Ranch recording studio just outside of
town that tons of music was recorded at
it's a big drug Town Music town in the
90s it was
uh ukab bar hop in this town most nights
amongst like three four places in here
live music and it's a town of about
14400 yeah so um but all that has
changed Colorado's changed you know the
world's
changed Co and all the money changed
Colorado so there's very you know we had
um eight or nine pre-regulation pot
shops in this town mine was one so um
it's not a pot town anymore that's too
bad yeah [ __ ] yeah it's not a pot town
anymore so so when you got Colorado what
kind of strains were kicking around
Colorado that you remember first
encountering the ones I
brought right so what were you bringing
over there I had just um gone to Mark
emer's and uh and bought four grand
worth of seed oh man spent four grand
with him ah yeah
Jesus not me
we all get got some time um I'll tell
you I'll tell you the the seed story you
know or the strip search story yeah this
is one I want to
hear so you know Mark had that magazine
that was basically a format for his
catalog the first I don't know Eight
Pages of the damn thing and and then it
I mean it was like
[ __ ] oh my God look at this it was I
want this I want this I want this I want
this and uh you know it was a mix of
really expensive Dutch seed and that was
in reality probably not authentic yeah
um and tons of BC strains that I wish
still had you know access or even memory
of yeah
um so I go in you know here I am I'm
young hadn't really traveled too much
and uh you know it's Hastings area was
you know junk Ville back then and
um it was
uh I don't know it was kind of City I
was not exposed to yeah
um meet Mark go do the deal Mark gives
me uh handwritten directions to a town
called Tofino on the sunshine
Coast okay and uh got to go
there you know talking it up well the
weather was shitty and and rainy and I
got the worst hotel in the world full of
old creepy [ __ ] yeah like Bor I
I mean it was the only room and it was
just torrentially raining so I'm I'm not
uh I'm I'm not a receipt saver but I
just happen to have the receipt for that
night and uh I come to meet one of the
people that sells seeds to mark from
Europe
and man we hit it off we're gonna go
into business do all this I've got all
this business plans and stuff in my
notebook and and he's like well what
what what are you doing with your seeds
I said well I'm just gonna bring them
home Mark said nobody's ever been
interdicted yeah and uh he's like oh no
you can't do that you gotta send them
back to yourself so I delay my
flight and
uh mail him back meet the guy the next
morning on the street smoke couple three
joints jump in the cab and I feel in my
pocket the big of the day pink Federal
Express receipt yeah and
uh I'm I'm totally stoned in the back of
the of the the cabin I'm thinking when I
get to the airport throw this away and I
have this little nervous habit of
folding [ __ ] up and then rolling it up
and yeah I do the same thing yeah uh I
think the uh a potish is one of the
names for the little nervous things that
you do and yeah so I jump out of the cab
I throw this thing in my pocket and I
walk into the BC airport and there's
dogs at the door and they sit down as I
walk by them and they're like you go
right over there I'm like like holy [ __ ]
there's US Customs in the BC airport no
I mean I had no idea there was like
driving across California line with you
know 300 clones in a cooler and not
realizing there's an agricultural
checkpoint yeah right nobody told me
this so there's
uh there I am the DEA or the the customs
and immigration has got me against
the unworking conveyor belt with my
backpack all exploded all over the place
and looking at all of my seed packages
that I'm going to take and put back in
my you know when I get back to America
along with you know several dozen packs
of Rolling Papers you couldn't get in
the US and yeah my uh written down
business plans that I'm gonna do with
this
guy so this little old lady who is a
supervisor I'm trying to be nice to her
and the other dude comes over and bad
cop with me and and
uh they're all [ __ ] with somebody
else and I'm standing there with my ass
to the conveyor belt and I feel that
[ __ ] receipt in my pocket I'm like
this is the only thing between like me
and 100% good and so I'm watching and
I'm watching and and I eat the receipt
because it's all yeah
yeah and they see me and they scream
he's eating it he's eating it and they
they come from everywhere oh no they
swarm me take me into an examination
room while this uh de or the Customs
Guy starts talking about if do I have a
sign on my house that says what I do or
how long youve been doing all kinds of
like cop mind [ __ ] [ __ ] yeah and
uh they couldn't strip search me because
I was on Canadian territory so they had
to go get a mounty to strip search me
well I have this handwritten directions
to
Tofino well during this period of time
the the Hell's Angels I believe and
other biker groups were kind of at War
and and
uh intimidating Growers and making deals
and there was a long and short of it
there is a um a pot industry related
murder that occurred in
Tofino on the night that I stayed in
that shitty hotel and had the receipt so
until I presented that receipt they were
concerned about me being involved with
that
murder so it was just a totally crazy
weird thing and
uh I made it home and they to my house
how deep was the strip search you know
bent over I didn't stick anything up my
ass but
uh that's what we all wanted to know
no it was it was just uh you know just
uh external yeah just a little Peep Peep
Show little fortunately it wasn't the
Americans yeah right yeah they go deep
they go deep with it yeah okay so yeah
that th those were uh
great seeds but you know in hindsight
I'm pretty sure they the Dutch stuff
wasn't Reon you know the gu's a
scoundrel so did the seeds did you
actually ever end up getting the seeds
that you had sent or was oh yeah yeah I
grew them for years yeah I grew all
sorts of stuff do you remember what what
kind of strange you were trying to grab
at the time specifically any of them
well you know it was you know ciny was
the dominant yeah thing back then and I
I think that
uh I think for the most part the except
for maybe Maple Leaf
indicia I think out of all that was the
only thing from ciny that ended up like
sticking around for a
while um I grew
uh oh no no no no I'm thinking of a
different a different different seed
buying that was the Amsterdam gotta trip
so in the early days there was a guy
named
uh Mike Parks who had a company called
weed seed okay and weed seed was a
British company that went to Holland and
bought seeds and mailed them from
England yeah in uh fake uh Lady D
memorabilia and
uh I went over there
with him and met uh like Simon and
uh oh Saga
Martha I'm having a brain cramp on his
name Tony yeah Tony uh I actually met
him when he was in on the
side
uh but you know
the when I got to Colorado I was burning
through those
seeds um
and a lot
of the
typical stuff that you would hear about
in Fort HS my computer is doing some
weird [ __ ] let me quit something all
right yeah the Colorado strains the
burning through the
seeds well you know I was hooked up with
the 77 guys so I was growing whatever
they were growing let's talk about that
because you know um
I think some of us that were from the
for ARA some of us got a good idea of
the 77 crew but even for me it's kind of
like just this mythical group of guys
that were doing what I wanted to do but
I was doing it decades later so I'd love
to hear some about the 77 crew how did
it get started what was it and what was
the goal behind
it
well so
the there wasn't a whole lot of Internet
Resources obviously at that point so
hemp
BC
um had an HTML website that
was completely basic and I was not
computer savvy at all during that period
of time but all of a sudden you could
make usernames and you could make these
little back rooms yeah and you know like
how I got my name was
uh I had just traveled around California
I was totally in the Mir woods and uh
you know and all that [ __ ] so I
was in a flame war with uh AB hybrid
yeah and uh Ron who you know
npga suggested that I change my handle
um after this vicious back and forth
with
uh [ __ ] H and uh because he went by
Illuminator back then and he used the
big 1500 watt Stadium bulb oh did he oh
yeah he was totally easy to [ __ ] with
Yeah by Illuminator and uh Hy did went
by Illuminator yeah yeah that's funny so
when he found out my name was mure yeah
he he's like you put an exclamation
point on the end of it and I and I kept
it ever
since but the you know so the 77 was
this guy Eric 77 and he was the guy that
passed around the the very orange Calo
yep
ae77 got and uh he worked out of a shop
didn't he what what was his shop he
worked out of
he Berkeley patience group maybe or
lived in Florida he lived in Florida
yeah okay yeah um yeah totally not
California he might have ended up I
don't he might have ended up with Ron in
California at some point but gotcha not
at that point I don't think I don't
think so I think he died down south
gotcha so the 77 was a back room that
was organized by
by Eric and it became the
um Vic High had
um a back room I can't remember what it
was called but a lot of the these people
had their little things and you would
set up things and burn them and uh and
then a group of us you know kind of
congealed in in the 77 and
and I think we all moved from
uh hemp BC there was a early website
called Laughing Moon I'm sure you're
familiar with laughing mooning Moon yep
and they were famous for having some
insanely priced Kong clone yep I
remember the Kong yeah
yeah so I think that that's the first
place I remember strain base maybe being
okay and we had ended up with a back
room
on that website The Laughing Moon
website that became known as the
77 okay so that was like the established
77 base at that point yeah
and you know and and from those guys you
know came the
the uh overgrow and in in cannabis world
yeah so and they had you know you know
Ron was the first person that I went to
and met in California and I I became
close with California people because
there was a
perceived safety with people who are
operating under the California medical
yeah rules so definitely a perceived
safety for sure yeah yeah
so uh
so was the 77 crew was it was it
essentially a way to move clones Across
the Nation to trade or is it just dudes
just hanging out and chilling that no
it's just a bunch of dorks you
know um you know you had
uh I was never into it but the mirc or
whatever yeah yeah Internet relay chat
yeah you know a lot of
those what's that I was one of those
dorks I bet yeah for punk rock though
yeah yeah but you know a lot of those a
lot of those guys had a weird weird way
about
them you know you're wondering what
other weird [ __ ] they're lurking around
on what other channels they're on when
you're not um I always looked at those
those guys a little a little odd but a
little sus um you know it's really wild
to to
see you know really well-known names who
you know started out not knowing [ __ ]
and and you know just this weird little
dorks
on cannabis websites
right bet yeah so but you know the the
77 you know there was a a time where
those guys really took that [ __ ]
seriously and wouldn't you know even
type out the 77 it put asterisks in it
or oh my goodness yeah so you know
secret agent [ __ ] yeah took it super
serious but you know through the years I
traveled to meet a lot of the folks that
I could conveniently and even some that
weren't convenient
and there's always been a extreme
willingness to
share yeah I there's no way that
the 77 was set up to to share clones but
we shared the [ __ ] out of clones yeah
you know this was at the point where
most of us couldn't even post an image
online yeah right
so
uh so what else can I tell you let's see
77 crew we got that tell us some of the
notable characters I mean right around
the time that U Canon world and overgrow
started what what were some of the guys
that that left good Impressions on you
or negative impressions on you for that
matter you know because that's always
interesting negative ones are easy um
yeah you know subcool is the first
negative one that comes my mind same
here it's weird how that works I was
like boom okay yeah well we could start
with him yeah you know he he his he
tried to get me to come to Georgia and
grow pot with him and you
know uh and then it just became series
of disasters after disaster for that guy
yeah
um so he was probably
uh the most
uh the most negatively notable you know
I think um people like Ron uh
NCGA is really uh you know with his uh
his events and the stuff that he did to
support other people in their Endeavors
and uh you know I I think Ron used to
have uh what you call I I think chip and
I would call it the the the old the old
guy rescue program I can't remember
exactly how we we would we called it but
he would uh you know he would take these
guys
from um other parts of the country and
help them get a foothold in yeah in his
area and it was uh it was cool to watch
him do his
thing you know
uh yeah he definitely helped me too same
way same way yeah I mean amazing guy
hold another generation you know you
know and and for me a lot of these guys
were older than me yeah so when I got
into
this you know Circle I I was really a
younger younger one of the circle yeah
you know there's
a there's a lot less of them you know a
lot of them came and uh you know I don't
know did you ever meet scoo or hear of
scoo scoo I've heard of him met him yeah
yeah he I think he was one of the people
involved with like the server for uh
overgrow
yeah but yeah so you know col
ended up getting a lot of genetics
through my connections you know like
the you know nebo's Cherry Lime is one
that
um I gave flat of
100 hundreds hundreds hundreds hundreds
away um and you knower L Ricky Right
Cherry Lime Ricky and he in that batch
there was a strawberry something and uh
Jacqueline orange Jackie O Jackie that's
right um that was from from that era
yeah but uh did he get your sour from
you
too I don't know if he got the sour from
me or not I sent
um uh a grip of those West with uh Ron
one year on his
yearly trip gotcha that makes sense then
yeah and that would have been around
uh
2000ish where did you uh because because
a lot of people don't know like CSI he
attributes his sour coming around via
you so where did you uh acquire the sour
at how did you run into it early on so I
had this dude who was my running partner
at the
time um he he was uh half Pakistani and
uh half white kid from New Jersey no
from uh the bronks yeah and he knew a
bunch of dead heads in Crested but who
had this cutting called Sour Diesel and
it was getting stupid money like
like like crazy I mean regular pot was
4,800 bucks you know yeah so this was
you I I I can't even quote what it was
but it was it was at that time I like
holy [ __ ] and everybody's like it's
different it's different it's different
and I'm like ah there's nothing
different and right
yeah and so I got my cutting from these
guys that my buddy knew from dead
tour and they took all their herb back
to New York to sell it from
crute
um so that's where my my cutting came
from and it's it's still there but I I
think it's there's it's like a shadow of
itself I I I wouldn't ever [ __ ] with it
but it's still grown in in the valley
but it's it's all dead tour related yeah
that makes sense that's all
um you know that's that's where it
that's how it got around so you
mentioned you weren't like much of a
dead guy what kind of stuff are you into
I mean I like I like the dad I like the
dad I like to say that I came for the
drugs and stayed for the
music you know I grew I grew up in a
crazy Christian church and was ejected
from that at 16 and and landed in the DC
Punk scene yeah and uh that was uh mid
80s epicenter man D
Discord yeah um government
issue I never saw a Minor Threat but
uh you know all of those Discord bands
and uh most incredible show I ever saw
was Butthole Surfers open for uh the
dead kennedies that's W and
uh man I never seen anything like that
in my life still to this day it's bet
it's in the top three four shows that
I've seen impacting like Kenedy
shouldn't have even come on stage really
but Hol servers did that good oh my God
I I I was yeah I was high as [ __ ] on a
bunch of pagan crank and it was one of
the most insane experiences ever you
know because we had listened to these
albums sure and you know there's a
[ __ ] tuba on those albums those early
BS yeah and it's like holy [ __ ] you know
there's a big white tube on stage and it
was that you know I've seen a lot of
Almond Brothers and Grateful Dead two
drum bands but yeah you know but hole
servers was the first band I ever saw
with two drummers so yeah that's wild
was great and you know growing up in uh
in the DC area was awesome it was a
small City it was approachable it was
relatively safe and uh it's great music
yeah dude that's a killer time to grow
up in DC I I kind of turn I I became a
real into pot and when I got really into
the pot I really wanted to to grow it
and sell it and that's how I ended up
going to see a lot of dead shows and I
have a lot of Grateful Dead head friends
but you know I'm I'm a lot more into
like early Jerry projects
versus like the
warlocks no like uh like Legion of Mary
and I'm not familiar that stuff with
Merl Saunders and
uh yeah not not dead Jerry stuff yeah
yeah uh but that's all fascinating to me
I mean the warlocks are kind of like a
they were one of those they're often
considered Proto punk in in many ways so
that's one of the bands that always
interests me there's a a record out with
the falling spikes which were Velvet
Underground before they were velvet
underground and on the B side is H the
warlocks that's out there somewhere it's
pretty cool
yeah music nerd history there you
go what do you know about the dhk crew
were you ever were you ever involved
with any of that no no no related I mean
I I I know the name yeah who who was in
it [ __ ] I know um reach reach was
probably in that if I remember
correctly yeah not me no one I really
jive with okay uh Colorado famous lines
and cuts here we go let's hear some uh
we have the peab bud and I I've talked
to you briefly about this before what do
you know about the peab bud
uh the peab bud was grown in a town
called ponia yeah
um it's a name that is kind of a generic
name
um the what people typically talk about
as peab but I believe would be called
um ponia
purple paralyzer yeah yeah
um
and that guy uh that I sent you the
seeds of
yeah the story that he tells me was that
uh you know Boulder was in the early 70s
was a pretty significant hippie
community and it was a an
earlier place of uh for marijuana trade
and sales I I mean I was surprised in
hearing the stories from this guy that
there wasn't ganja everywhere but it it
was a a developing Market at this point
gotcha
um so supposedly some hippies left
Boulder and moved to pay
and that's where the pay the peab bud
comes from same line as as what you have
just just separated 20 some years
ago
um but
that that purple herb was also grown in
towns like Garder which was in the Wet
Mountain Valley where you
have you know uh you know leave us alone
kind of hippie type sure
communities that don't really exist
anymore um not not the way that they did
then but you know that's
uh you know that's the only
really what I would consider like
uh heirloom kind
of hot spot yeah be ponia and maybe
Garder um but these PE you know you know
places like
Leadville it's over 10,000 feet um you
know so a lot of these places where
everybody went to live in the mountains
and smoke ganja and grow ganja it's
really really hard to grow outside yeah
because you can have
um you know four inches of hail in
August oh I bet and it's just you don't
have anything and it sticks out you know
it's like dirt and rocks and and pine
trees around here it's not it's not an
easy easy place to grow outdoors but
ponia is a farming area yeah and you
know I'm sure it it's still there and
I'm sure there's still people just in
the same way that you've
got hippies on the mountain in NorCal
that you know are still doing stuff
that's their own stuff yeah and not what
everybody else is doing so I think it's
here I I've often thought of trying to
do what you do for
Colorado and try to get out there and
capture some of the stories because you
know California is is the mothership in
in my opinion
um and Colorado is is a
long a
longstanding ganja state but absolutely
it's more of
a I mean long before Denver became the
center of ganja in Colorado it was you
it was Netherland it was Leadville it
was uh Durango it it was not Denver it
was everywhere but Denver that's not
where you know until
people started blowing
up shitty
warehouses that that was that was G
ganja was Denver is not a ganja town
that was like 2016 it became the the
ganja Center would you say around the
time of the the legalization the first
Cannabis Cup type [ __ ] well you know all
these early Gardens were you know Denver
was full of empty warehouses that were
sitting and not doing anything so there
was lots of cheap real estate that you
could get into nobody had any experience
I
actually uh ended up in one of these
early
uh warehouses you know
nobody had designed HVAC systems for it
yet yeah nobody could grow pot without
powdering mildew in those environments
and the herb was so horrible that
it it's responsible for the concentrate
bone yeah yeah for sure you had all of
this herb that was so powdery Milo
ridden that nobody could do [ __ ] with it
you couldn't uh blast it there'd be
dumpsters full of
[ __ ] butane cans people smoking a
cigarette in within sight of my store
here there is a house blow up within
sight that way there was a house blow up
J um three houses in the town of
Netherland during that open blasting era
you know
so you know you can [ __ ] about
regulations but that's one thing for
sure that I'm glad we got past people
get pissed when you say that too like
that the extract artist whole idea came
because a bunch of people tried going
weed and were really shitty at it and
had to try to move it somehow which
became the B boom I mean that to me
that's it was just so evident watching
it but people don't like hearing that
well I remember and and even the the the
the gross ass way that that [ __ ] was
smoked on those like titanium Skillets
and yeah yeah oh man fiery red the first
ear wax you get some dude he'd come you
get whatever it was that you were going
to have in blast and and uh
this [ __ ] sold for a $100 a gram and it
was like
gelatinous it looked like [ __ ] ear
wax yeah
um yeah
yeah those days all because nobody could
grow pot to begin with yeah and they
still needed to move it to they still
needed to make a return
therefore and this is how you smoke it
yeah
let me tell you that
too and you know it is really crazy I
uh you know after having closed my store
my last store in February that's right I
have to
buy my uh my cannabis now until I have a
harvest and
uh it sucks buying that [ __ ] man it's
really amazing but
I have a source actually um and it's not
like six-star pinkies up I'm buying this
eight gram tub for
$96 Jesus
$96 what is that 12 bucks a gram yeah
120 bucks after tax out the door so you
know the
the the the the pot industry prices are
have plummeted man really glad
that I'm not in it anymore it's uh but
it's great I can buy I can smoke a gram
a day and not have it really hurt my
pocketbook too bad yeah that's not too
bad right yeah I ended up getting a um
the that canono hyperemesis Syndrome
from dabbing and I don't know if you're
familiar with that but it [ __ ] you up
super bad so I learned my lesson not to
you know dab every 10 minutes it kind of
turned me off to extracts permanently
but I had to go through my own see that
yeah yeah I had to go through my own uh
round of buying my own cannabis because
I you know knocked down the grows and
[ __ ] because I was throwing up too much
couldn't run anything H yeah it's a
[ __ ] it's a [ __ ] I'll tell
you yeah i' I've had friends that have
been unable to smoke and be Growers
and uh one of them just is able to smoke
again now so it's
it's hard yeah i' i' I've gone the 11
months now that that I was told I need
to go fully without smoking once you
know wow 11 [ __ ] months of hell I'll
tell you what dude no Edibles too right
no nothing no canono nothing not a
thing did the amount I was puking it
wasn't even worth it to even try so I
figured I'd do the full 11 months not
try to skimp on it just in case it pops
back up too soon yeah it's a trip it's a
trip a lot of people don't believe it
exists either until it actually happens
and then you realize [ __ ] that [ __ ]
sucks I think of the reason a lot of
people don't believe it is that there
were that there were doctors that were
trying to hang a lot of [ __ ] that wasn't
it that's it yeah yeah there's a lot of
people saying a just neem oil you know
it's just this it's just [ __ ] this
it's just [ __ ] this you know you can
get it from the cleanest source and it
doesn't matter if you're doing it too
much I know for me
BHO live resin I can't smoke it because
it gives me
instant inflammation yeah it's just not
a good experience I like the flavor of
it and but it's just not a good
experience same you know I loved the
flavor of it it was and I was using you
know like a cter or a puff Coast it was
nice and easy push the button three
times could dab every 10 minutes like a
crackhead you know gear what Els you and
then all of a sudden you know ate months
later you're throwing up your guts but
it's it's The Logical end to someone
with addictive personalities you know
like you always here cannabis can't kill
you right well let's see well let's see
let's put this [ __ ] to the test you know
and then I end up in renal failure and
[ __ ] yeah so tell me what you're doing
now dude since you've uh closed Harvest
House right yeah well I'm I have a new
business with a similar name Harvest
House uh Colorado
yeah I've got my space that was my
dispensary uh it's in a little A-frame
in
Netherland and um gonna basically make
it a
a a format
for uh showcase for cannabis and try
to
uh Recruit new home Growers make it the
the the the anti poot store store I love
that and equip people
to build their
rooms uh whether they want to become
familiar with living soil or
salts
um provide a a place for vendors to do
popups provide a place for uh breeders
to do popups glass people to do popups
try to run a a a really cannabis culture
themed session on
Saturdays um once I get that going try
to find uh someone who is interested
enough in plant medicine and
psychedelics that are uh kosher in in
Colorado to uh use the space on Sundays
to give some education and you know
maybe
uh share techniques I I'm not into
mushrooms and dealing with tripping
people so it's not something that I
really have an interest in but I think
that there's a need for education and I
and I have a spot uh so but we're going
to do
uh do the Saturdays starting mid
September and uh the other thing that
I'm doing is I I have a uh a hemp
license where I am doing a clone company
yeah and uh
providing clones walk in or uh deliver
them or or ship them so yeah I mean
that's that's a very successful way to
to do business right now even even from
the seed Market I've seen that uh a lot
of seed guys are just moving over just
to clones um so I'm very interested to
see how that goes for you I think it'll
be successful especially with what you
got going on with the education and
everything else you're
doing well I think it's
uh it makes it a lot more fun if you
can choose what you want to
grow and you don't just have the option
of growing whatever it is that you can
get yeah
um and you know you have a lot of
uh
access these
days but there's still a lot of people
who feel like they have to gatekeep
yeah and you know I'm not one person
that drives with uh you know something
that came through my my hands and it's
you know it's got some like part of me
to it like and I yeah I've never
understood the
you know you know the uh the elitism
well you know Sour Diesel is is a really
good example of you know everybody's got
their their story uh they've all got the
idea of what it is how it got name that
um all that [ __ ] man I I really don't
give a [ __ ] about I
I I am I have always had access to
clones through friends I'm not a a a
clone hoarder I've never been a person
who
um gets tight with [ __ ] and yeah I I've
been shared with freely and I I'll tell
people don't give it to me if you don't
want me to to to well and now sell it so
yeah right not just not just share it uh
you know because I I've given many many
many many thousands of Cl absolutely
away um
and unfortunately not a whole lot of
them have ever come back that isn't that
how it goes though that's how it goes
hey man could you fill my room up can
you flat
hey
hello could I get a jar or like
something hey could I get that clone
back I'll give you a sniff sorry
what you know CSI gave me gred advised a
long time ago and he said never attach
yourself to one clone he said for many
reasons because the second you let it go
it's no longer yours and if you've
attached your name and built a
reputation with it what are you going to
be left with always be working towards
something else and keep moving that's
the best way to do it don't feel like
you've got to lock [ __ ] down don't
attach your ego to it and you know like
it it say it sounds easy it sounds
really easy but when you've get get
something very rare everybody seems to
get that Golem syndrome you know and
once you once you learn to get rid of
that you get to start moving forward and
uh creating new and at that point
everybody else is using your tailing so
who gives a
[ __ ] I mean there's not much out there
that's worth much more than anything
else you know right as a flower so I
mean I I don't think that people do
value a a a clone really the way that
they should
um you know it's a lot of work to to to
make a selection and yeah it should be
um but a lot of these clones were
selected you know two two seeds popped
in a 2x4 closet and just call Delite and
that's
the
Yeah Yeah man so let's see what else do
we got I want to hear your um your take
since you've been on both ends of the
spectrum um legal versus the traditional
Market what were some of the pros of the
legal Market versus some of the pros of
traditional and and what do you think
will win out in the end for uh for guys
like
us well I think that there I think that
there's
a the way we started is not the way it
is now um
you know I was uh an
unregulated
shop I was operating
under medical marijuana rules which were
kind of [ __ ]
um and I operated
through the the promulgation of the
earliest rules and withdrew my
application for my medical marijuana
shop in 2011 as the
regulations took a first regulations
took
effect now in all of that time to right
now I've never seen Advocates win yeah
Advocates have
passion and they
have
emotion and they have often lots of
energy but lobbyists win every time yep
every time so we had a a a
a a
vibrant small business Community
where I grew pot and I sold pot but
that's not what everybody else was you
had people making Edibles you had people
making well there weren't really
concentrate makers yet right at that
earliest Point
um but the state made everybody become
vertical integrated and that caused
people to get into
relationships that were called shotgun
marriages yeah they were forced into a
business relationship
so you had people that were great
Growers you had people that could
Slinger you know and they were forced
together and in my early situation where
I had a a you might have known him do
you ever know no good names left sea
Lucas no fors
well I had a early
partnership where I was involved with a
you know a a Denver Warehouse that was
along with my
um uh my shop in
Netherland
but the
uh we had a falling out at that point a
man divorce ended up with a
uh restraining order against me I
couldn't go get my genetics from the
place and my I I didn't lose my company
I didn't get [ __ ] over I didn't allow
myself to get [ __ ] over but most
people didn't end up in a in a good
situation or prevailing after being in a
bad relationship so that started it all
off and then you had industry groups
initially
marijuana medical marijuana Industry
Group became marijuana Industry Group
Mig and and those people they write all
of it you know and and so if we fast
forward down to today where you know
Colorado was was very Innovative and it
had a
diverse
businesses now
the I am of the
opinion that you have two factions going
against each other you have the hemp
based
intoxicant market and you have the
traditional dispensary
regulated
THC there's a lot of people making a
[ __ ] ton of money in not THC yeah as we
all know and and and not just like like
the the Shady uh High
thca yeah yeah yeah Trend that's going
on right
now but the the
latest changes in the Colorado
regulatory scheme I think really tell it
all
in cannabis is a consumer package good
it's part of the cpg industry it's a
segment of the cpg industry
the seite executives that are brought in
to lead these large MSO companies or
companies that are getting rolled up and
trying to be something they're coming
from the consumer package good industry
yeah so the you
know
pot is biologically active there's [ __ ]
growing on it it's it's got yeast and
mold on it that isn't dangerous yeah
there is the potential for things to be
dangerous and I'm not saying that
regulations aren't
unnecessary but I think that the
regulations are heading in a direction
where the pot that you find in a store
is going to be sterile yeah no however
it is that they sterilize it so pot has
to have a shelf life it can't
have you know when the when the when the
tpes are are no longer being
produced they're beating back those
those that those Fung funguses the black
the what is it
the god they just doing the hydrogen
peroxide dip for the most part on a lot
of this stuff aren't they no they
they're irradiating it they are um all
sorts of [ __ ] you know so and large
companies they irradiate it before ever
gets
packaged
so
now in Colorado before you were un you
were not allowed to sell prepared food
like potato chips and drinks in your
store that didn't have THC in them and
you can't have hemp derive THC in them
either so now the new rules allow for
you to get as much as 20% of your
revenue from selling
popcorn and potato chips and [ __ ] so
it's it's in a
full move towards a convenience store
model in Colorado in my opinion that's
the direction that it's going and I and
I would
anticipate it going that way across the
country
wherever those cpg companies can get the
rules tweaked for them yeah and I think
that the the the end result is going to
be that we'll be able to buy pretty much
pot across the country and at some point
maybe there'll be exclusions but and
some states won't drive ever I don't
know but you go to some [ __ ] hole Market
in Nebraska you can buy a tomato in the
winter time you go to New Mexico or
California or Florida you can buy a
tomato and the type of tomato that you
will be able to buy is dependent upon
how it can be transported and look when
it gets to where you're going to buy it
yep even if you're buying an heirloom
tomato at Whole Foods there's only
certain tomatoes that can
be transported that are airling they
turned to Mush yeah um so I think
that there's going to be store weed
and then I think there's going to be
good weed you know I think there's going
to be plenty of pot plenty of cheap pot
I mean [ __ ] I hear about people spraying
it colors and coating it with thca now I
mean Jesus believe it I mean have you
heard about that stuff yeah it's got TP
[ __ ] sprayed on it in
extra isolate I guess yeah yeah you know
so that means you know what I like is
totally irrelevant you know
so but that's you know there there there
is uh there's a lot of different types
of market for pot and I am a firm
believer that we're going to see a a
homegrown Renaissance I we're primed for
it dispensary herb sucks I quit I mean I
I can't I
the best herb in the dispensary is is
way way way
overpriced
and and it's only a certain type of herb
yeah
it and it's stuff that can
pass biological testing here in
Colorado and not everything
stops the biological
activity I mean I've had
stuff that I have Jarred that was so
Dynamite you know people want they think
they want cured weed I want fresh weed
yeah I I
want you can't get it in the store it's
not
there yeah and you see all this pictures
of great looking weed on the hoof in the
garden it looks
great but someone was just telling me
they're going to send their herb away
off site hours away to have it trimmed
by who knows who for 40 bucks a pound
Jesus Christ so I mean what what do what
do you expect yeah and it's supposed to
be good
weed yeah I I hope there's a homegrown
Renaissance um where I'm at there isn't
a a connoisseur Market of any type you
know in Bakersfield California it's uh
few and far between people that are
going to be like I would rather have
better than quantity quantity that might
get me a little high you know it seems
to be that the the whole attitude is
just weed [ __ ] smoke it you know
around here it would be nice to develop
that but I think it'll take so so much
time so many people getting sick of the
same old [ __ ] but how how how long does
that take to build in a in a society I
mean because Colorado has has a history
of good cannabis but places like [ __ ]
holes like this not so
much you know I
mean Colorado is a place where outdoor
herb and and and Greenhouse herb to me
is a hard cell yeah um we're used to
indoor
pot but you know the dispensaries have
have changed everything you know it's it
used to be called Colorado kind bud you
know yeah that's that's not what we're
we're working with now in general yeah
and you know the homeg grower
culture it was really strong it boomed
it busted but I'm hearing of people
firing up the room again
so I remember there was a little bit
where you were going to different
collectives and showing what you were
getting at different collectives uh over
time and I found that fascinating as
well uh to get your take on all these
different strains and what they look
like and what to expect from
dispensaries when you were going there
what your money would buy you they were
all really
fascinating well I sure love to Savage
the sample Edibles you know
that you know there's so many bad
ideas it's you know
there there's been like uh there's been
bumps there's been uh you know like
nicotine kind of pouches there's been
jello shots the jell shot was quite
possibly the nastiest thing ever oh my
God and and
that you know there's uh how about the
lean the THC lean that looks like you
know purple oh yeah yeah scissor the
scissor yep the scissor oh man and you
know and all the Chads high-fived each
other when they left the boardroom and
thought that was a good idea oh I'm sure
yeah boom yeah we got lean weed it's
gonna take off but it it's sad you know
it's
uh the culture is is
not it's not here anymore yeah I don't
think it's it's
uh I mean I haven't visited California a
long time but I I hear you know the
culture is pretty pretty crushed and a
few people hanging on
and
uh the rosin thing has been really
interesting to watch and uh you know a
couple years ago if you would have told
me that these guys would have
welldeveloped private Brands you know um
yeah I would have been like what like
why why do you have to have your brand
yeah but now these guys are are are
doing well with it and
uh the you know the six-star hash kind
of contest stuff that's a little bit
more than I mean I just like to to smoke
it I don't want to talk about it a whole
bunch right or profile I wish I could
still smoke it damn it how long are you
going to wait I I don't know that I'm
ever going to smoke hash again just
because of how bad it triggered it just
stick when you gonna smoke um flour I'm
just waiting for some uh good samples to
arrive since uh I'm nowhere near Harvest
right now wait for someone to send me
something good we're smoking you know
I'm gonna get back in if it'll be good
wait six weeks all right six weeks and
it's
on well dude is there anything else you
want to get in before uh we wrap it up I
know that i' I'd really like to do some
more check-ins with you and maybe some
roundtables as well sure have you have
you with some of the other dudes talking
about different things different whether
it be political or uh the Clone markets
what have you old strain talks um you
and CSI would be a [ __ ] killer
episode so yeah is there anything else
you want to get in for this this round I
don't think so it was good to finally I
know man with you after trying for so
long it's been it's been a while it's
been a few years of chasing you down
well worth it well [ __ ] worth it
brother but uh you know anybody who uh
is looking for vigorous and healthy
clones in Colorado that you can actually
look at before you pay for them yeah
give me a holler and you can find me at
uh Harvest House Colorado on Instagram
there you go is it uh all one word
uh Harvest
uncore
uh
housecore Colorado perfect yep all right
and I'll put it in the description as
well killer man and dude it's an
absolute pleasure having you it's an
honor and uh we'll be talking again soon
all right dude have a good night you too
brother time thanks sure
thing want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
Catal logs and knowledge we hope you
join our Union of readers and Growers
come check it out