you've had things happen on the ranch
that are creepy i mean
inexplicable call it paranormal but it's
happened it's real right yes very real
in fact uh
one it's almost
like what you would call stigmata that
happened to me uh
we had a rabbi out do a
ritual
that was supposed to summon an opening
to heaven uh which are like a portal is
what you would describe it as down at
homestead 2 and when we did the ritual a
uh thermal uh vortex appeared in the
middle of homestead 2. we got that on
clear data and it was repeatable we
played an audio recording of the chant
back and it happened again well when the
rabbi was there that night he told me uh
off camera he came to me said travis
they said they're going to come to you
tonight
and i'm like what are you talking about
and he said well they said they're going
to they're going to come see you i said
who's they and the rabbi said well
whoever it is that's here
i thought he was messing with me right
uh well that night uh i had a dream
uh i was in my trailer that my trailer
doors were locked and everything and i i
had a sort of a waking dream that the uh
my the trailer door uh opened and my
bedroom uh door slid open and a native
walked in to my bedroom an old a really
old native and he looked at me and he
shook his head and he reached out and he
touched me on the face right there
well and then he then he shook his head
and he walked away and i woke up
startled and i went to the bathroom you
know splash water on my face kind of get
my bearings and when i looked in the
mirror i was bleeding from that spot and
i had a a sore appear there and stayed
there for several days
and and that that was bizarre to me i i
can't explain you know you could
probably explain why the bug bit me or
something i swatted myself but
it didn't look like that it looked like
just like somebody really pressed me
really hard right there