welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate hey everyone before we get
started I just wanted to let you know
that over at Riot seeds.com we're about
to drop some new uh goat farm gear some
of the last of the blue dream uh
feminized hybrids and we have the whole
blue and cross lineup blue ex so I'm
call it blue n blue EX blue cross um
everything's half off right now so
talking $100 and $80 a pack so be sure
to go check that out rid seeds.com and
we have some high and loansome stuff
still we have some stuff from M Elite go
check it out while it's still going um
the sale is probably going to end in
about a week and a half so keep your uh
keep your eyes peeled on R seats.com
hey everybody Welcome to breeder
Syndicate I'm Matt today here with
inspecta and the lovely Miss Jill today
we're going to be talking about the the
reemergence of TGA seeds what it means
what it was where it's going now and uh
yeah so these are the two involved in it
and I think they're coming out with some
um pretty amazing new hybrids with the
space dude so real quick Miss Jill um if
you can give us a quick synopsis of TGA
what is what did TGA stand for
originally like obviously what does TGA
stand for and what did what was the
purpose the green Avenger or the green
Avengers yeah it was the purpose of
overgrowing the planet
[Music]
um as everyone together it was the green
Avengers and then we were the green
Avenger separately as our on our own but
as a as a whole we would be considered
the green Avengers it was our goal to
overgrow the planet with with cannabis
great
strains that's awesome and how long
would you say that it ran as a company
like when did it start and when did it
kind of slowly go back towards Miss Jill
genetics I would say I I believe TGA
started I
2001 we had a slow start we um started
with cannabis World on the auctions
actually and we were selling packs at $
five dollar and they were getting
returned wow times Y and as as time went
on we grew and and popularity and and
people started growing out the strains
and they really liked what they were
getting and the Cannabis uh move
movement started booming um people
started realizing what great medicine it
was and we just took off from there and
we were going very strong we moved to
California and we were doing really well
and then we had a fire in 2017 it was
October 2017 kind of took everything we
had all of our moms and thankfully we
still had some moms with um different
people yeah Seb and I both um split up
in one our different ways at that time
um put doing business together and I
ended up taking TGA and making M Jill
TGA genetics and sub went off and done
his um his own thing with subcool
seeds that's where we went and so during
the time of TGA there was a bunch of
people involved other than just you and
sub right there there were other people
that were helping the collaborative
effort of putting these strains out yes
lots of um several other breeders yeah
and they've made their own name over the
over time um because of the work they
did with TGA as well which is I think
notable yes some really amazing stuff
yes so with that said I wanted to go
over some of your guys's best hits as
TGA early on and one of the first ones
that comes to mind is Jax cleaner and I
don't remember necessarily the genetics
of it it was like a what nl5 pluton um
Lamb's bread
um yeah that was in the pluton I think
yeah and then it said like purple haze I
think the the very end or something like
that do you remember Caleb oh no it had
a way too many things in it it had a lot
in it that pluton from um I think I
think it was s is that ssse
pluton I'm not certain yeah that one had
like lambs of bread all kinds of stuff
in it yeah I remember that Jack cleer
sub had before we had met that's right
and it was a combination of something
called The Cleaner too right or is that
something different Jack's cleaner that
was Jack cleaner and then from Jack's
cleaner
gotcha okay some of the other big hits
like Jack the Ripper obviously came from
Jack's cleaner and uh what do you know
what the parentage of that one was um I
do believe it was space queen yeah okay
so space the one of the first space
queen ones Jack the Ripper and that
became a huge hit for you guys yes Jack
the Ripper and then Jelly Bean after
that yeah and what was in Jelly Bean
that was um orange velvet which would
was originally um named Melvin when it
came to me I got it some from some
patients in Oregon MH and the Rumor was
they had gotten it from someone in Falls
City Oregon it had been around for 25
years at the time I got it so it would
be moving up on about 50 years old now
at this point that's insane that's
insane old ass plant um and and what did
you like about the Melvin when you first
saw it she was beautiful the a beautiful
plant um I I had to rename her because
Melvin just seems like such
a such a silly name for such a beautiful
plant she was she turned the most
beautiful colors almost black burgundy
black and she it looked like velvet the
leaves looked like velvet and she
smelled super orangey um about three
weeks into flour you start walking into
the Grom at first it starts smelling um
like a little bit like burnt rubber and
then goes on you get that real strong
orange smell and it was great for bag a
pill until you know you've had too much
of it you can you can only smoke so much
orange that strong for you know so long
before you start getting a little bit
tired of it yeah it's an extreme orange
and it and it bred well for its orange
traits yeah absolutely yeah and one of
those uh other plants would be agent
orange correct yes yeah that was one of
the first TGA strains that I had tried
was the agent orange and it had like an
orange soda um like orange crushed soda
type expression it was really beautiful
that was crossed with Jack the Ripper
okay so that was Jack the Ripper and the
Melvin yes or orange velvet orange
velvet I still think Melvin's a great
name
though um I have down here Sputnik one I
don't know if that was that big of a hit
or it was mostly a hit because it was in
books and it was so pink I think that um
mainly it was a big hit over the color
yeah it seemed to be a little bit Airy
and um a little more sativa leaning
um but it was it was absolutely
beautiful and it did have a great flavor
yeah yeah and then there's Danny Boy I
remember that being a big one I remember
it being very lemony um um Taco I think
okay Orga c99 I think that was the
taco and then we have stuff like the
quirl what can you tell us about the the
original
perkle we had a um purple urle
at the time it came to us it was called
lavender it was given to us by a a kid
named sticky
lungs when he was living in Oregon it
was a kid from Georgia and I I still
actually speak to him sometimes but um
that's where it originally came from and
then over time I guess we figured out
that it was a purple
Urkle I'm I'm not ever uh you know I'm
not certain on the lineage of it if it
was actually a lavender or a purple urle
but the um purple Urkle that I'm using
now for um quirl is actually a purple
Urkle so there is a change I do still
have offer quirl but the mom is
different it still utilizes space dude
for the mail and it's it's just a
reliable selection of purple Urkle yes
yeah and um I know Chernobyl was a huge
hit it's one that I liked very lime soda
type uh stuff to it um do you know this
story on H what was the uh blood
wreck um blood wreck was a phenotype of
um train wreck and that came via um
dioxide okay it came through another guy
named Scotty and he had given it to
dioxide and um then we used it and um
the golden ticket and and well let's
start out with the golden ticket
phenotype soot type was found by Dany
from uplifted farms during testing
period okay before it was ever a release
strain and it was just a wonderful very
limey type flavor with a just a ton of
resin so we um kept that around and used
that later in life I've got that as
mother of my um Jil Bean lime and I've
got that available both regular and
feminized so that's pretty cool but
later on um the Clone fell into the
hands of um I'm not going to mention
names but he wasn't supposed to have the
clone and he decided to name it Slimer
so that you know people does he have a
lame little mustache is that that person
yeah okay and he renamed the golden
ticket to Slimer on his own yes yes so
it's actually the same phenotype it's
just a phenotype of golden I mean of I'm
sorry of Chernobyl
yeah all right now let's get into Mr
inspecta here which I know everybody's
stoked to see his smiling beautiful face
back but um so I wanted to talk a little
a little bit about like the ideas behind
bringing TGA back and what what
direction you know you wanted to bring
some of your moms in you and Jill
obviously talked at a collaborative
effort and figured out which moms in
your room would work best with theh
space dude so talk about what what some
of your ideas were behind some of these
uh strin you guys got coming out right
um well I grew a I think it was uh Jesus
OG or Jesus OG yeah
Fus um and uh wasn't that a like a a
Hell's Angel OG cross to space
dude okay um I agree with that back in
the day and you know those plants just
had amazing Vigor and just you know it
it seemed like there was a lot of really
good traits that pushed forward on that
so I I I figured based on based on that
you know it would probably hybridize
pretty good with you know some of these
you know oddballs and you know um
heirlooms that you know we all have in
our collection so yeah you know that was
that was my my main draw to it what were
some of the first ideas that you had you
know when you were thinking about what
would cross well with space dude I mean
you know definitely like you know
KMD you know some of some of the
different ogs um some of the worked ogs
you know like
5150 um and then you know even stuff you
know that wasn't around back when uh TGA
was making a um you know space dude
hybrids like you know Skittles and oh
yeah and you know stuff like that you
know even Girl Scout cookies you know
yeah that's a good
point so you know definitely bring bring
some of the old into into you know in
with the new so have you come up with
any oh sorry go ahead Joel I I'm sorry
I'm I'm one of those that really loves
cookies so I'm really happy to have that
um cross with space dude I'm sure it's
gonna make something really pretty yeah
what was it so you had space queen mom
that you kept Jill what what what did
she smell like and and look like we
originally started with two space queen
moms that um we used for uh seeds um one
of them was um referred to as Tiny bomb
and was a phenotype that I chose before
they had ever flowered just based on
structure of the plant and she ended up
being an amazing plant great structure
but the um space bomb she had just or
tiny bomb she had just you know the bud
was just a little bit better we finally
figured out over time that if we just
vegged her a little bit longer then she
would just have you know beautiful thick
buds but in the beginning they had
started out really small and that's why
we had called her tiny bomb but so we
had both of those phenotypes and we were
were um offering seeds from both so one
was a space Gill and then one was was um
space bomb and after time we got rid of
the space Gill because it was more um it
was bigger buds it was you know nicer
crop but it was as resinous and
flavorful as the um space bomb it's just
super strong Cherry it was one of my
most favorites um to smoke just super
resinous and and super Cherry just
fabulous now did the space dude mail do
you know if it ever passed forward stuff
like cherry or is it usually just
tropical
fruit type stuff what does he like to
pass or tend to pass on some cherry but
for the most part one why he's been one
of my favorite males is he lets the
female expressed herself she you still
get the expression of the of whatever
female you crossed him to um with just a
little more hint of maybe a little
cherry or or a little more resin yeah
yeah I remember tiny bomb was really
really resinous too
short little resonance thing so with
that said which ones are you most
looking forward to out of the new stuff
Caleb well you know definitely like the
KMD Girl Scouts uh the the different uh
Skittles z85 yeah you know those
ones probably uh are top on my list I'm
interested in the hp13 one quite a bit
just because you know it's that mystery
clone that no one's allowed to touch see
smell that one will be really unique too
I think yeah and I think the the
combination with the space dude you know
will up up its uh you know its Frost
content and you know probably normalize
some of that HP 13 weirdness you know
yeah and you did do some stuff with um
GDP as well and purple Urkle which
obviously that's one that was already
established but with the GDP that's kind
of interesting you did both yeah I I
focused on the GDP just because it seems
to be a more refined type of you know
URL KKL plant yeah yeah did you get k91
in there I'm sure I
did okay and there's there is a Calo in
there yeah yeah got the Calo in there
that'll be interesting to see how it
compares to like the orange
velvet sister
what's that we've we've named that
strange jil's Twisted Sister that makes
sense that's a good name for it and then
um you got lemon party in there oh yeah
yeah everybody's
favorite yeah lemon party and Irene
Irene will be a great one I think too
yeah very very very much and like you
said triangle so you got a bunch of ogs
in there um and the cookies did you do
any other T cookie types in there uh I'm
sure F1 der or anything like that uh I
don't know if that one got in there
there is a heavy but it it was in there
it was in there just not I didn't make
too many seeds of it yeah Sour Diesel
was in there I think that one could be
really good yeah no kidding people be
all over that yeah so now that you guys
have done you know some reg work with uh
this the space dude have you thought
about doing any feminized works I mean
that's what you're known for Mr
inspector oh yeah eventually here you
know what what what what do you think
you would go for uh feminized wise what
What would most interest you from the
TGA catalog to to pull feminized work of
I mean uh Jill and I have been talking
and um uh probably possibly uh agent
orange yeah you know maybe do some work
with that
yes definitely some orangey work so tell
me a little bit about uh Miss Jill
genetics and what you've been doing
aside from the space dude stuff the new
stuff what else do you have going on
over there Jill um I have a lot of Jelly
Bean hybrids and um they're not just
different phenotypes of jelly beans so I
I hope people aren't confused by that
because I have like a jelly bean black
cherry Jelly Bean Cherry Jelly Bean
grape jelly bean lime um there's a moo
jelly and and Joker's Wild um that one's
awesome most of those are available
regular and feminized um it hits both
sides Some people prefer regulars and
some people don't have the room and
prefer feminis so yeah I'm trying to
offer for both both sides of the fence
um right now I'm I'm just really excited
for all of the new space queen crosses
um we we are still working on getting
some of those out ready and out um and
next like Caleb was saying we have um we
have the agent orange that's coming up
next
so that sounds exciting Mr Caleb what
about you with uh CSI humble what you
got going on oh I'm I'm I'm scaling back
a little bit I've been working too much
yeah you do work a lot you're a
workaholic whether you admit it or not
for sure I admit it I admit
it so what what have you been focusing
on lately any any uh big wins in the way
of uh surprises in the way of uh seeds
coming out
soon
oh um oh uh I'm crossing my fingers
hoping I get a reverse on chem 4 yeah
yeah that'd be nice not that anybody you
know want any of those but you know
mostly to complete the catalog and you
know yeah preserve the last of the chems
that you know are out there yeah you
know so and uh I think you have some nl5
FS too oh yeah just those are sitting
there I I have a a backlog of stuff I
need to uh sort and process he likes to
he doesn't he likes to blow seeds but he
doesn't like to blow so yeah so it's his
own fault don't you got you have some
other stuff though coming down the pipe
right some other feminized work that you
haven't released yet
yeah yeah yeah yeah but but nothing
you're wanting to talk about nothing too
excited about I mean you know um I have
so much stuff in the fridge I
just it's a long list okay how about reg
work you doing any reg
work oh I mean you know the the space
dude is I think the most recent reg
stuff yeah it would be huh yeah um I
haven't really you know been doing a
whole lot of reg work um oh oh
I am doing a a round of the the bastard
biscuit biscuits here so you know what
is that uh Girl Scout cookies that's
right times Australian bastards um f4s I
think I'm working into now so yeah are
you gonna are you g to select any out
and and reverse those and try to make a
th line yeah I've got it like a um 80 90
plant run uh inside and then a almost
170 outside so damn you know there's
definitely some interesting
ones yeah a lot of people missed out on
the Aussie bastard stuff it was pretty
cool looking and very unique and uh
people need to get on that [ __ ] yeah it
needs a lot of work though so you know
yeah can't can't blame him too
much so uh what else are you excited
about anything else anything else there
Mr C oh I'm excited for a vacation here
yeah yeah where you going to go I don't
know you going to go Australia oh yeah
that sounds nice that sounds like a nice
ticket if you go I'm coming with you on
your
dime I'm broke I'm
broke so miss Jill other than the stuff
going on right now anything you're
excited about or anything you want to
tell people where where they can get
these um I do have a list of vendors um
you can find that on my web page um I
need to pick up some more because my ass
has been lagging so I need to get
everything updated on the site you are
on the website um on my website um and
also on my Instagram if you look in the
story highlights there's a list of
vendors that's awesome yeah and all new
ones like the the Kim queen and the
lemon space party those have already
been released so um I guess five new
ones and the space queen queen up3 and
the jil's Twisted Sister those are
already
available and um we can get those back
get those out to you because I know we
need to get that done and um they can
also contact me direct if needed yes and
you will be talking to the lovely Miss
Jill everyone in case you didn't know
she does respond personally because
she's sweet like
that so yeah um I know you guys got
stuff to do but I wanted to make sure
and and get the word out on all this
stuff
and uh yeah I appre appreciate both of
your times if there's anything else you
want to get in get it in now either of
you um you know I I brought this this
book out to share yes let's see it this
is higher it was written by Eric nug
shots and um his partner that he worked
with I'm sorry I can't Dan
Michaels so we have Eric whenever he's
at like conventions and he has Little
Wheel thing that you can turn and watch
the bud spin like I always see like 90
people lined up to do that [ __ ] because
it looks so
pretty and which which one's this this
is the agent orange
okay so if if you um if anybody's
interested in this book I'm not certain
where you can pick it up yet but I think
it's on Amazon I want to say on Amazon I
think you can get it on Amazon okay and
I do have an email if if um they want to
contact you later and get that if they
need it awesome and of course um the
space queen the start of TGA basically
so that's a space queen
female that's a female yeah which one is
that um this one is actually um not our
photo okay it was from um
bcga perfect
yeah great book yeah that's a gorgeous
book it's actually that in my collection
yet very
beautiful
yeah shout out to Eric nice
book I've been w a copy of it yeah and
there's also of course dank and I know
that there's a uh 2.0 of this book out I
only own 1.0 so I don't know what the
changes exactly were do you remember
Jill the changes from one to two um the
first one was a hard
cover really nice like when you touched
it at
yeah and but the 2.0 just it's more
strains
updated okay so it was just more of what
you had released between one and two
yeah and this was
um Ed Ed Rosenthal actually is the one
who um edited and produced all of this
he did a good job yeah of course we've
come a long way with photography since
then yeah I think we were just talking
about Sputnik so there's Sputnik you can
see why people liked it so much oh yeah
it was beautiful pink yeah like um
magenta yeah and that was that was
really new back then people weren't used
to having those colors no and I think a
lot of people don't realize that like
that purple craze that came and went
with the with the kkes and stuff you
weren't really seeing pretty magenta
stuff like that that often would you
agree with that Caleb or did you have
that was more in like the meno pers pan
atrol Kush Style Plants yeah URL is you
know cold dependent or environmental
dependent yeah color most part which
one's that space queen oh is that now
that's one of your guys' space Queens is
that space Jill um yeah that's the space
Jill
then I know tiny bomb has its own page
in there I can really when I look at
this structure I can see it in a lot of
The Offspring that's
interesting I know was just looking at a
picture of plushberry recently that
looked just like that and here is the
tiny bomb so this is it was it was
pretty small yeah yeah really Frosty
yeah now was Tiny bomb and space Jill
both kind of cherryish or did they have
their own distinct sense they were they
were Cherry I I would say space Gill was
more cherry yeah the infamous space dude
there he is responsible for nutting all
over the Caleb's moms yeah nice balls
nice balls son great this and this is
back before people were really getting
this if you can really see this picture
right there yeah blue coming off and
everything pretty cool sub always did
have really good pictures of stuff yes
was he always the one taking the
pictures too no we both did um he was
with functionality of the camera like he
knew how to set the settings on the
camera I didn't more the one who would
set in the auto mode but I was much
better at um setting up shots than he
was yeah that collaborative effort with
your guys' pictures is is pretty
legendary though I remember on breed Bay
uh a lot of people trying to emulate
that yeah I I did get a lot of magazine
covers and and
articles with my photography and so did
he we both did
yeah my my favorite part of the te GA
era was you guys on breed Bay I would
say that was when you guys hit your
stride big I would
say so here is an old High Times
magazine from um is it may of 2007 yeah
May of
2007 okay super old who's on the cover
first article I had written for High
Times so there's a picture of the orange
velvet and the article was um the orange
wave female Growers perspective
so that was the whole start of the um
orange craze that we start you know that
we got into the industry with you need
to be doing more stuff like that now
more orange no more more articles
talking about stuff from the female
Growers perspective just because I mean
you're a fine representative of that
well unfortunately um with High Times
the crew has all changed um it probably
about 2016 through 2018 they kind of got
rid of their original crew and they've
gone with a new crew a bunch of younger
people which you know they're trying to
hit the younger crowd and I do
understand that but um they're not so
much interested in the Breeders or The
Growers anymore more of um influencers
and
um because the industry has become
legalized and so people are more into
the um instant gratification you can
just walk into a dispensary and grab
what you want yeah
you know that that doesn't carry the the
heart that um it carries when you grow
your own and I I I really wish more
people would get into growing their own
um it's it's so therapeutic to grow and
to touch the plants and have your hands
in the soil and and it's it's rewarding
when you you it's so surprising you know
you grow this little plant and it just
it grows into this big beautiful plant
and you have these buds on it and it's
sometimes it's just the satisfaction of
knowing that you've just created
something so beautiful and then you get
to cure it and smoke it and reap the
benefits of of all your hard work and
you always know what you've put in it so
you know you're not smoking whatever
you're not getting the chemicals and and
I know there's a lot of testing but a
lot of stuff still slips through on the
testing oh yeah i' I've learned about
how they dip it in hydrogen peroxide now
to beat the testing and sometimes
irradiate which was new to me that they
irradiate the weed to beat testing oh
x-ray style which is new to me I hate to
call any names out but you know the guy
SK um initials
um he was part of of a group that has a
it's called a remediation machine or
whatever so when they were growing weed
that would be moldy or subpar something
they couldn't sell couldn't pass testing
they would put it through the
remediation machine yeah so you know you
have to worry about those kinds of
things especially if you buy the
pre-rolls you're not you're not getting
buds that have been broken up you're
getting Sugar Leaf or not I'm sorry not
even Sugar Leaf you're getting fan
leaves you're getting whatever is at the
bottom of the bag yeah know it's it's
not
quality yeah and there's something to
say for like seeing people grow
something out that you've made you know
with seed wise I think all of us could
agree that's something really unique and
when you first start seeing that as a
someone who makes seeds it's it's it's a
whole another feeling absolutely and to
see their excitement and and joy when
they grow it out and it's beautiful and
they they feel like they've done such a
great job and they smoke it for the
first time and they're so happy and and
excited with their work yeah it's it's a
lot of fun it's it's great to see your
medicine help people with with physical
or mental issues and help them overcome
things and and like I said the growing
itself is therapeutic and definitely
helps people with anxiety and depression
and for
sure yeah I always know when I'm
depressed if my plants don't look good
they're always a very good uh uh
physical indicator of how my brain's
doing you know y yep I just get
depressed when my plants are
unhappy
reverse happen that way right yeah yeah
that's for sure especially when rooms
[ __ ] you know
fail always fun always fun depressing as
[ __ ] but the good thing about that is
you know you get to learn you you figure
out what it is that you've done wrong
what you could have done differently and
and that's the thing about growing you
can't write a book I mean you can write
a book about growing but you can't write
down everything that might come up
that's true yeah it's always going to be
different everybody's grow everybody's
um environment every strain and every
year might even be different you never
know what's going to happen yeah very
true yeah there's some rounds where I
can't even clone right you know like I
feel like I'm an idiot and have to to
start back from scratch on just cloning
but usually it lasts a month out of the
year and you know maybe if you really
paid attention to that it might be the
same same time of year every year it
might be something else going on yeah
like Mercury retrograde like Mercury
that [ __ ] Mercury retrograde
gets me every
time all right so we
have what's that sorry my clones are
unrooting unrooting reverse rooting yeah
so we have your website what is it Mr
inspector oh oh I think it's like humble
csi.com humble CSI that's so confusing
CSI
humble yeah humble csi.com Miss Jill
what's your website um Miss jill.com
mill.com see that's easy it's not
jill.com Caleb no and you get there
through tjag genetics.com missjill
genetics.com as well and if you're
looking to get pick up some new gear uh
M jill.com that's right get the sexy M
Jill clothing yep and half off right now
so the um coffee cups the shirts hoodies
um dab mats there's all kinds of cool
things do you have women siiz shirts
like the one you're wearing is that one
of your Miss Jill shirts no they're all
black and they same as Gill on them okay
I guess it wouldn't be cool to rock your
own shirt
huh often
do I need one I need to get one of those
I'll send you one okay deal a nice low
cut number yeah little nice big dipping
v-neck for my chest hair
yeah you two CSI oh yeah that's
right I'll I'll hide the v-neck with my
my beard yeah then you have a Santa
Santa Claus hat on top so with that I
want to thank you guys so much for
showing up it turning out and it's a
pleasure to speak to both of you and uh
hopefully we'll see both see both of you
back again very soon awesome have a
night thank you everyone want to sit at
the table with The Syndicate check out
our patreon and our link tree or
description below our merch site is
officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is topnotch I've
been saving old designs for years for
this purpose so please check it out
Syndicate gear.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out