ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
there it is
we are here
how you doing bud
fantastic
let's just start rolling man
all right so uh this is the first
edition of our new thing
i don't know where we want to begin i
thought
maybe
this
thing would be good to talk about like
some some seed bank history
yeah the
you know obviously like now uh there's a
lot of stuff that's kind of coming out
of the woodwork where people are talking
about a lot of famous old cuts from the
80s and 90s seed lines and all that
and i thought that like there was a
bunch of people that
didn't uh maybe didn't know some of the
history behind all how all that occurred
uh and so
obviously since its weed history it's
not entirely exact but this is
everything we're gonna talk about is
the best that we know it right so
there could be some different
information not everything could be
entirely correct but we're going to give
it our best shot to give you
uh what we think and what we know and
all that right
that is correct
so that's the word so
the reason why we wanted to start with
um
like sort of neville and sort of holland
history
uh is it's that's not where like seed
history started obviously like there was
stuff going on in california there was
sacred there was plenty of private
breeders
but
in
holland
that was sort of the first place where
you could literally be a nobody and just
send them money and get seeds right yeah
but kind of in california at least from
my knowledge and experience you kind of
had to know somebody you kind of had to
be connected a little bit
um you know you had to be within certain
circles
uh for instance you know i grew up in
the midwest
and there was no access to seeds there
was no culture or anything like that so
the only places that we knew how to get
weed were dead shows
and holland
um and so you could mail order from
holland you could uh you could fly out
there and buy them direct and kind of
try to bring them back yourself
so
to me
that's kind of where like modern weed
history as far as like most people's
access to it begins
yeah if you were in certain circles if
you were in the pacific northwest i mean
you know obviously it starts before that
but um
neville
put an ad in high times in 84 or so and
that started what matt's holding up
right now is his 85 catalog
um and because hans
because holland's laws had changed then
they were sort of the first place that
could like really make
seeds available to everybody
right
so as a result of that
like that's where a lot of people got
most of their seed stock
it wasn't from connections it wasn't
from friends that those were small
groups
uh you know neville
uh sssc
um you know a couple other small places
they allowed
everybody people from florida people
from chicago people from new york people
from north carolina virginia
wherever to just if they had the balls
to go there they had the balls to order
it they could get it
right
and so that's where
that's where kind of like our modern
story starts and that's where like a lot
of uh
a lot of seed strains and a lot of lines
that became famous to everybody like
haze
northern lights skunk one
g13 maple leaf all these things we talk
about now that have become kind of
legendary
it's really where like 99 of the
population really first started getting
access to it right
um and so neville is kind of unique
in cannabis history
in that he had the balls to start it
and he sort of got to as you know by the
mid 80s persecution in california and
america in general had really kind of
ramped up it was the reagan years
drug laws had gotten intense
and so a lot of a lot of breeders and a
lot of growers and a lot of guys with
seed they sort of took what they had and
they fled
uh to amsterdam
right and so amsterdam basically got
famous because it was able to collect
a lot of stuff that was going on in
america not so much stuff it was it had
itself
but really stuff that was going on in
america
they did do some trips it's certainly
true that
uh neville
the drunkers from scentsy other people
you know some people went to afghanistan
there was [ __ ] that they called
obviously the hippie hashish trail where
people started going to the far east and
poking around looking for seed stock and
stuff
and uh but holland is really where it
consolidated like matt's holding it up
right now if you look on the left page
that he has up there's like an order
form
right and you could literally write down
what amount you wanted of what strains
and you could send them [ __ ] money
and they would send you seats
and uh that was pretty revolutionary i
think because that had never happened
before
you couldn't just ask a stranger for a
bunch a bunch of illegal marijuana beans
and get a hold of them back then
right
and so we thought maybe
it would be good to start like on a
historical basis because
most of the stuff that we grow today in
some way
there's a lot you could trace a lot of
it back
to that first five or ten years in
amsterdam say like 85 to 95 right yeah i
think matt would agree
absolutely that the vast majority of
today's modern cannabis you can at least
tie some of it
back to that era
most of it definitely yeah you know and
so neville did two things right neville
had the balls to start and then secondly
he was kind of able to collect a bunch
of people's previous work
like for instance mel frank
jim ortega
seattle greg from the nl crew
um mel you know uh sam skunk man
various groups like that and then his
own travels
and so he kind of became the first
person
to be able to blend all those things
together
like before him nobody was crossing
skunk in northern lights because the
skunk crew and the northern lights crew
didn't know each other
nobody was crossing an l5 you know with
haze because those that crew didn't know
each other
yes in a way he got lucky
because i mean like imagine today for
instance
you could collect nobody knew
about kush nobody knew about cookies
nobody knew about sour nobody knew about
all these things that are famous in
america and imagine you got to be the
person that blended them together first
and then sold and then resold them to
people so
like that's kind of like what um that's
kind of what neville got to do in a
sense right is yeah he got to be first
you know and a bunch of people copied
them and a bunch of people came along
and added their own thing and obviously
like just like every other breeder
nobody started [ __ ] right everybody
on the shoulders or who came before him
so you all pick up
you know the breeding projects and the
clones and the seeds as you get into
weed as you come around
and then you know you kind of add your
own kick to it and that's what every
breeder has done you know from the
beginning
um in some cases the first breeders in
say like america
uh were taking
all the import lead like the colombian
and the panamanian and the thai and the
mexican and all that and all that stuff
came in
uh from seed you know seeded weed
so literally every time you bought weed
you got free seeds
and so most most breeding in america was
a bunch of sativas
right
because that's all there was with
sativas like if you got hash
hash was afghans but you didn't find any
seeds for the most part
i think this this this is a really super
important part too because most people
that are around today don't realize that
the the influx of modern afghanis and
stuff happened more in the 80s late 70s
early 80s as opposed to have always been
existing and always a part of the
culture
yeah it it changed i mean most i would
say for instance that like most
most things that people were growing in
the 70s
was a blend of sativas
yeah because that's what that's what
everybody had access to right
so
you know it'd be mexican colombians it'd
be mexican colombians and thais it'd be
all these type of things and
afghans were super [ __ ] rare like
really rare um because somebody had to
go to afghanistan or pakistan or one of
those regions
get seeds and they had to go in the 60s
and 70s when travel took a long time
right they had to go they had to collect
them and they had to smuggle them back
into america either mailing them or on
their person somehow right
so but there was literal tons and tons
and tons
of mexican and colombian and thai and
panamanian and all these different
jamaican that was coming in in you know
in bricks and stuff to america and it
was all seated
so you know uh that was kind of like the
and so as a result of that most american
breeding was like
in core groups right
it was just little groups of people
friend groups extended friend groups
that type of thing
you know
uh and you know so
that's kind of how it started and it
really
i mean it really wasn't until holland
that most of america got access to like
a what a lot of little groups of people
were up to doing
you know um obviously like prohibition
was pretty heavy
so
you know you just there was no way for
you to know what what seattle greg and
the nl crew was doing in
the pacific northwest they were trying
to avoid getting busted
yeah and they were and greg's commented
several times that it was just like
watching dominoes fall constantly
watching their friends be popped it was
sketchy and so as a result of it being
sketchy and you trying to be underground
right
that meant that most people didn't have
access to what you were doing because
they didn't want most people to know
what they were doing they had to in
order to be successful you know there
was there was you know some stuff going
on in mendocino county and humboldt
county
and you know santa cruz and the central
coast area that was mountainous
and you know people were getting away
with pretty good-sized things and
breeding and stuff
but unless you were connected to those
crews if you lived in nebraska if you
lived in florida if you lived in you
know chicago like where i was born or
anything like that you had zero access
to those people
you had no idea whatsoever what was
going on you just had you know if you
were lucky you got some imports so
the reason why we thought
uh starting with neville and starting
with the seed banks
is because
neville was really
neville was probably one of the biggest
reasons why
we're all here
uh he sold
between he had when he started the seed
bank
you know he sold millions of dollars
worth of seed millions of dollars
yeah all over america
all over and so what he did is he gave
thousands and thousands and thousands of
people the ability to grow their own
and the ability to get some of the best
american genetics that were happening
that people didn't have access to before
so you know in a way
you know he kind of took
a lot of very famous weed characters and
he made their stuff famous
you know is really kind of what happened
he made it yeah that's he made some rock
stars
you know so i was talking about it
before and if anybody was listening to
like uh you know the first breeder
syndicate uh interview
uh matt matt and kansa got to interview
um
uh seattle greg
and one of the things that seattle greg
said in that interview was that
you know
he sent uh neville a whole bunch of nlc
because he saw that advertisement that
neville put in that in high times
he literally
you know reached out to neville
and um you know he sent neville northern
lights
um and
you know within five or six years of
that time
uh everybody in the northern light crew
has gotten busted
um and it would have been lost a time
and nobody would have known anything
about it other than some legends
um but he had gotten it to holland
before they all got busted and lost it
right
so
um
you know there's a there's a thing when
people are asking questions i haven't
gotten to the questions yet because i've
just been kind of rapping about stuff
but
there's a button where you can people
can go and they can ask questions and
we'll try to get some of those questions
answered a little bit later after we
roll through some of this [ __ ]
um and so
you know i'm i'm in my mid-40s so
you know literally like i said before i
knew how to get seeds i knew how to get
good lead from grateful dead shows
and holland
and uh i went to holland in 1994
and uh
you know i was able just as an 18 year
old nobody to just walk into various
places and buy seed stock
you know i didn't know anything about i
knew barely anything about growing weed
i literally got my first seeds that i
had access to because i could buy a
plane ticket and i could fly to
amsterdam as a kid
and i could buy seeds and i could bring
them back to my spot we could pop them
and uh
we could see what's up
was it still super expensive for the
time like
you know like modern times comparatively
how were the seed prices back then when
you first flew over did you have to save
forever or
so the funny part about it is is that um
seed prices like when you look in those
old catalogs
yes right now
in all honesty you know you see a lot of
stuff for 50 bucks 80 bucks 150 bucks
200 bucks ever
you have to realize the way money works
right now um
like i'll just give you guys for an
example of inflation
in 1994 when i turned 18
20 back then
would be worth 38 dollars today
so seed prices have stayed amazingly
stable over the decade they really have
they haven't jumped because if you think
about it most if you were selling seeds
at what neville was selling seeds for
most seed packs should be between two to
four hundred dollars
yeah yeah um just just even to equate
how much actual money neville was
getting for selling those seats
right
and so
you know they've stayed pretty stable i
mean obviously there's something there's
cookies uh there's some uh when skittles
came out there's some people that really
profited off people's availability
um
and uh
you know they've charged you know 500
800 a thousand dollars a pack for
certain beans but
um
you know see prices for most things like
if you buy stuff from csi or you buy
stuff from
uh riot or you you know other good
breeders that uh you know we like like
shaw and different people um they're
amazingly competitively priced
uh comp you know to today so
um
that's kind of like the
that was kind of a long-winded way to
basically say this hour or some chin
change or however long we decide to
shoot the [ __ ]
is basically about
like maybe giving some people some
information about how neville got
started and how he collected things
and then how he started blending things
and then how those things sort of became
like
the bedrock of
modern cannabis
right
um
because he's the guy that really took it
from very few hands relatively speaking
to crowdsourcing it if you will to use a
modern term where all of a sudden a ton
of people had access to it
right and i don't think that would have
happened um without
neville and some others and holland and
all that so um
maybe
that's sort of the uh
that's sort of the beginning
you know um
and we can kind of walk it through so
matt right now is holding up the first
actual real seed catalogue which has a
bunch of cool pictures of neville's
afghanistan trip
um you know he's holding a bunch of
sheesh he's hanging out with people in
the tribal regions of afghanistan
and um you know so basically when when
neville first started
uh
he didn't know [ __ ] of what he had
right there it is yeah he really did he
didn't know anything that he had he was
just collecting stuff from people right
and he was starting to blend to those
things
and i would say
it probably took him about three years
or so of [ __ ] around
um 85 84 85 86 going into
before he really started to figure out
like what he had and favorites of what
he had
and then kind of like
88 89 90 um that's really when like the
blend started happening that ever that
got made really famous like if you look
in
um
if you look in the book the very first
book
um
you know in the northern lights
greg and those guys sent him like
northern lights labeled one through
eight
but he you weren't able to buy an l1
from him you couldn't buy nl2 you
couldn't buy nl anything you bought a
random assortment of nl that he had
because he hadn't had time to like you
know he inbred those things line by line
but it took him a few years to really
figure out what he had or then grow
rooms in the stuff and even see what was
in there you got to realize too that
like to him
these are just names that are coming in
from these different growers
um you know we have a lot of knowledge
about what these things are supposed to
be now but he didn't have any
so in the first couple years there was a
bunch of there was a bunch of stuff in
there that's weird uh in for lack of a
better term you know there's random yeah
nepalese by skunks you know colombians
by this
african two
yeah you know there there was just a
bunch of stuff because he was sort of
reselling
uh
everything you know everything that he
had and he didn't really have uh
he didn't really have a way to
differentiate that you know so he was
just experimenting so
you'll see a lot of weird things in
there like there's a page
um you know yeah he's got some some thai
by
by uh afghani you know new mexico
again like skunk won by
by nl9 i think or nl8 um he had mazar
mizzari that he got from his travels to
afghanistan he had nepalese
root or alice it was kind of just a grab
bag in the beginning
of
just whatever whatever you know he was
kind of collecting from all these
different breeders right and um
so uh
you know they um
you know and you know and and also just
to go back for a second just to give
people an idea so he was collecting all
that
uh greg mcgregor seattle greg sent him
uh i believe
nl1 through eight
uh according to neville
um and greg and uh you know
who keep david watson who people call
sam the skunk man he had gotten in
trouble a couple of times and so he
took a bunch of seed stock from himself
uh and then some from some other
breeders and he brought that to holland
and he ended up selling it to
uh neville
uh in selling it to uh
the owner of positronics
um
huh bernard bernard yes positron the
owner of positronics bernard um he ended
up just basically you know he had a
couple kids or whatever he was kind of
broke-ish
um and he ended up going out there and
he gave neville skunk one
and hayes from himself
and then he was friends with mel frank
and mel frank had given him afghani one
and durbin poison
um and then another breeder in the bay
who we don't know his name had given um
some some other afghans
and stuff like that and so
85 86 neville was basically just
reselling
a bunch of stuff that he was collecting
a bunch of different breeders that he
had gotten
that's kind of the beginning
well um let's let's
let's start going over some of the base
lines that came out of the the seed bank
era some of the base lines that we see
in a lot of modern cannabis lines today
all right so maybe we'll start
maybe we'll start with uh something
simple like northern lights
yeah so like that if you look in the 85
catalog and you look in the 86 blog
not sure maybe even the 87 but my memory
fails me slightly i think you really can
just buy northern lights
yeah this one says cannabis indica
northern lights in the 86 and in 87 it
just says cannabis indica northern
lights as well just as northern lights
so he got it in 80 he placed that ad an
84. he got the seeds sometime in 84.
it's not we're not exactly sure when
yeah
he kept he started growing them out and
he started keeping the lines separate
and interbreeding them right and so if
you guys send to
the podcast with greg mcallister uh
seattle greg as we like to call him and
um
you know he basically said that like
you know the nl1 and the nl2 and the nl3
those were all pretty predominantly
afghan
they were rated by height and length of
flowering time
and then most of the other
most of the other nl's were those couple
afghans either one or two
blended with basically every sativa they
could get their hands on hawaiians
um
you know
colombians thais
mexicans so it was really a hodgepodge
and
greg has mentioned that they were really
scared to keep notes
uh and they were really scared to like
lay out exactly what they were doing
so a lot of those lines are kind of lost
to time
in terms of what their exact makeup is
uh because those guys didn't even want
to keep track they were just trying to
find good weed right
so yeah
some of them is a mystery but if you
look in those first few catalogs like i
said before you can find you know uh
skunk one by nl9 you can find um
you know five by eight if you will
you can find a bunch of different things
and he started reading them together and
combining them
you know in various in various different
ways and even in the beginning right
like
um everybody's familiar most people are
familiar with what he ended up using
which is one of the things that became
pretty famous which is nl5 by nl2
um but the first year he offered it he
reversed it and he and he and it was nl2
by nl5
uh because he hadn't really decided yet
on like what
you know what worked for him
so after a few years of [ __ ] around
with nl
he basically realized
that um nl1
bred pretty true to itself it was pretty
close to what we call
steve murphy afghan
which is basically the afghani that sort
of got the nl
uh line on its way he got these afghan
seeds from this guy named steve murphy
who wrote a couple cannabis books in the
mid 70s
and this was sort of a wide-leafed
short squat
kind of bubble-like
um lowland afghan
leafy frosty resinous
short
quick flowering thick
dense that type of thing
and then the nl2
was
you know more of a cush type it had
thinner leaves
one thing that people should know is
like afghanistan has an enormous amount
of height variation depending on where
you grow so some of the stuff like the
mazars and some of the regions might
only be like one or two thousand feet
above sea level but then when you get up
into like the hindu kush region the
hindu kush region
is the second highest mountain range
next to the himalayas and a bunch of
those afghan farmers were growing at
like 6 000 8 000
feet these big tall valleys in the
middle of nowhere
and so those leaves
were kind of much skinnier much thinner
um think about like everybody's pretty
familiar probably with like the way that
like what modern kush looks like and
it's like that skinny three leaf
um you know with different nugs
um where like the lowland afghans were
sort of like thick
feathery
um denser looser
more more leafy nugs like matt's holding
up in the picture right there right
so
i think it's 89 is it 89 the first
catalog matt
where all of a sudden
he had figured out which
nl's really worked for him
which ones were stable which ones gave
him good breeding work and after getting
all those nl's
all the nl's pretty much disappeared
okay from neville's catalogs except for
he offered nl1 f3
he offered nl2 f3
okay
and then he found
he grew up a bunch of five and since
five is so famous maybe we'll chat about
that there's this dude named kirby who
uh
um
who took
uh steve murphy's afghan and he crossed
that to a hawaiian which he said was a
colombian by mexican right
and um
you know and he gave that to greg and
greg sent that seed line out as one of
the one through eight we'll never
neville grew a bunch of that out
obviously if you're growing a bunch of
afghan
by colombian by mexican you're gonna get
a bunch of
uh a variety and chaos okay
so he found this one maybe if you want
to show that one nl5 pick again
yeah let me find it so within
the seven within the first few years
he grew up a bunch of this nl5 and most
of it was a chaotic mess
uh
afghani sativa blend all over the place
but that picture that you guys are
seeing on the left he found this one he
called it like a throwback plant right
and he found this one plant that was
almost pure afghan
super frosty super resinous didn't taste
like much
super low terps
um but it uh it had great structure it
had a great buzz
and uh he loved it and so i think by 88
89 90 the only thing that neville was
really breeding with
was you could buy nl1
you could buy nl2
and he had one cut that matt just showed
of the nl5
right yeah you got to realize for a
second that
in america
guys they didn't have neville's an l5
cut
they sent neville a cut
of their favorite but theirs was a
hybrid
theirs was that
blend it was an f1 hybrid of steve
murphy afghan by colombian and mexican
right
and so
and so you know there was there's a lot
of confusion about nl5 and we have this
thing that we call pre-pre
where
a lot of people like to like to talk
about how they have seeds or they have
cuts like from the earliest possible
time that you could have the cut
but people need to people need to
understand that there was always
um there was a north american cut of nl5
that was an afghani hybrid of with
sativa and there was a cut that neville
found
amongst the seed line that is that
picture right there that looks super
afghan and super frosty
right
and so
um by 88 89
almost all the nl you're gonna get is he
used nl1 and nl2 as males
and nl5 was always the this the female
and that was pretty much it
after three four years of breeding with
nl he had decided that most of the
sativa most of the hybrids that were
with sativa that greg had sent were a
[ __ ] mess and hard to breed with and
didn't breed consistently right
and you got to realize too that back
then during the high prohibition times
people wanted consistent producers
yeah
he used to joke
that if he gave you some kind of white
hot fire but it yielded 10 percent less
you'd be pissed
yeah right
and so most he found that like most pure
afghans
didn't cross very well together
um they liked being crossed with that
was one of the he was one of the first
people that really realized
that when you start crossing things you
start getting really neat stuff when you
start crossing things that are totally
unrelated to one another
so people should realize
there never was an nl5 line that was
ever released pure
that's super important as well because
we see that all the time people popping
up with nl5 saying they have the nl5 cut
or nl5 seeds
so
you know the the nl5 cut that was made
famous because people were buying
millions of dollars worth of hybrids of
it really
that was in europe
you know and you know greg has stated
that
by the late 80s they had all gotten
busted and lost all their [ __ ]
right and they didn't really share very
much greg told us that they had shared
the eight a cut of the eight a cut of
the nine
and a few friends they had shared the
five
but that wasn't the super afghani five
cup neville shows in those pictures that
was the f1 hybrid that was colombian
mexican and afghan
right
so
um
everything that nibbles sold
was an nl5 hybrid
he had nl5 by nl2
he had nl5 by uh skunk one he had nl5 by
hayes
uh can you think of any more matt
um as far as nl5 crosses mm-hmm
five hayes and all five by two i think
that what was the other one nl5
one
those are the three most common right
yes
you know a lot of people are talking
about having pure nl5 well that'd be
really [ __ ] hard
because greg says that they lost it all
by the late 80s
and then neville never sold pure nl5
uh there and and by pure
uh to be clear he grew out a lot of the
seeds that greg sent him and most of the
nl5 line was a mess and he found this
one afghani plant he liked a lot
and that's the one he used
so
uh
you know you see a lot of stuff you know
i see some comments you know uh talking
about bodhi stuff and all that and it's
tough because
i'm not here to like you know call
anybody out or anything like that or
obviously there's a lot of people making
a lot of claims
um but
you know that's part of the issue and
that's part of the reason why we wanted
to do these podcasts and these talks is
because most of the history is oral
right it's not written down very well um
even the people that were there disagree
exactly on what happened yeah
right there's some consensus but there's
also
uh there's also some disagreement and
some of these alzheimer's they don't
like each other
they're just flat out
they have beefs and they have disagree i
mean it's not very different than today
right there's breeders today that don't
like each other and they have beasts
with each other and
then 20 years from now they'll be
legends about both
right and they'll be like oh i thought
matt ryan was a piece of [ __ ] he's a
[ __ ] this and that i don't believe
him at all and then there'll be other
people who will be like well matt riot's
story was consistent this other guy's
story wasn't consistent
and most people aren't there
right
and so what we're trying to do with this
is just kind of lay out some like basic
facts
right
and uh
yeah and
i can actually comment on the bodhi uh
in all five thing because i was we were
talking during that time a lot you know
we've been close friends for a long time
and in his goal with the nl5 no he knew
that l5 was never released piers the
seedline however we were trying to find
something closest that we could
find and he was like he was trying to
find it and and consulting all his
friends too saying hey where do you
think the best nl5 seedling would be
that would show the best representation
and at the time there was like dr
atomic's northern lights um which was a
supposed claimant to the nl5 you know uh
lineage and then there was bc seeds
which was the more popular one that had
had been around probably
accepted as as closer to northern lights
than most that was available at the time
so that's what he went with and and i i
agree it was probably one of the better
options at the time but as far as a pure
nlp seedling when you break it down it's
that's really hard to find
because it never because the only people
that had it
you know and by pure let's be clear the
initial nl5 seed line was an
unstabilized polyhybrid
yes
it was a mixture of mexican colombian
and and afghani
right it was never stabilized it was
never pure it never br it never bred
true
right it was a full-on polyhype
oh and that's right squirrel mentioned
the nl5 skunk one yeah that's correct
yeah
nl5 i i mentioned i think neville sold
nl5 by two
nl5 by skunk one yeah
by hayes
um and so but nl was always the
nl was always the mother plant
yeah
i'm sure most people know this but i'll
say it anyway just in case
is that the way we talk about seeds is
the mother should always come first
and the father should always come second
correct you talk about five by two he's
using the mother of nl5 and a dad of nl2
right uh some people get it flipped
around and that's hella confusing
because it is important to know
what's the mom and what's the dad it
really helps to have consistent
terminology when you're chatting about
seeds
um
what about the noof cut
so
you know there's things where it's like
i can't you know
when we're talking about kind of seed
history and stuff like that this is all
stuff that's going on in the 80s and the
early 90s
um and then
you know these these things get
legendary status
and then they pop up in different
generations and by different people and
different seed companies in holland
different seed companies in
later in canada
they start
they start popping out and
[Music]
i can answer that one actually real
quick
yeah so
uh there's there's somebody asking
question about nl5 seed from todd uh we
know quite a bit about that
uh the basic story is that
greg says okay
that
he found that that they found some seed
from him that he didn't know existed for
decades
uh after his sister had sadly passed
away
in her fridge in her freezer inner
freezer
and he gave some of those to todd
uh matt got some of those as well
um and
um
so those
you know it's it's hard to say uh you
know greg admitted
that uh greg admitted that he lost
everything for decades
and then he finds some seeds in his
sister in his deceased sister's uh
fridge
uh that were labeled
and so at best you can say that the
provenance of them is uncertain
for sure
you know it's just uncertain there's
just no way to tell if it is nl5 then it
would be
steve murphy afghan
by
mexican colombian
which which originally greg referred to
as a uh hawaiian but later on he said
what the hawaiian was that that was
actually over there it's a hawaiian but
you know i mean obviously hawaii doesn't
have any natives exactly weed so most of
hawaiian
was sativas from other traditional
regions brought to hawaii and grown
yeah right yeah and so how did bc seed
company obtain nl5
so this is kind of jumping around for a
minute but let's be clear
uh
most of the seed companies in amsterdam
once they realized how
profitable this seed ship was
they would buy seed
from whoever had the seed in holland
rename it and resell it
yeah okay so
um
you know a company bought neville's nl2
f3
and they renamed it oasis
yeah
uh which company is that matt remind me
uh dutch passion dutch passion so dutch
passion you know uh when this is jumping
ahead a lot but you know within a year
of shanti releasing white widow or other
things there was two or three other
competing seed companies in holland
sowing white widow
and they would just take this they would
just lift the exact lineage from the
people that's that first sold the seed
they'd buy
5 or 10 or 20 or however many packs of
seed from that person grow them out
pick a male and a female and start
making and packaging their own seed line
because it was money
and then they get them out right
seeds have always been shady
and everybody involved in seeds has
always been shady and it's already
always been underground
and it uh you know it's always been
somewhat persecuted
and so you know a lot of the characters
to be perfectly honest
lie
and it's hard to tell what they lie
about
you know um
yeah i mean the provenance of a breeder
is only as good as what they can prove
you know and a lot of people don't
demand that proof they don't know to
demand that proof or or have it even
researched
to demand said yeah well well i saw
something we'll get to some questions
here and just we'll go through like a
little question and answer session
um you know shortly here or whatever and
we're not we won't get through it all
today but i just kind of like you guys
can see i mean i haven't even gotten i
haven't even talked yet about the most
famous hybrid of all time which is nl5
hayes
but there's a lot of depth to these
stories on how these people got started
and you know and then other people
should also know that like
you know
some of these later seed companies
uh a lot of these people worked for
nipple
right yeah
uh adam who was part of starting thc
seeds
tony who was first at cerebral and then
made his own sag martha seeds
simon who was also at cerebral and then
made serious seeds uh they all were
right all of them and then within a year
of leaving working for neville or
leaving working for scentsy under
neville to be more accurate they all had
their own seed companies
so it's highly likely
that at the very least they took some
stock
uh some other plants some fathers some
whatever from their previous job
and rename stuff
uh i mean that's the game right but
maybe i should take a step back i'll
talk for a few more minutes and then we
can answer some questions and then we
can do that
but the other part that's cool is that
one of the things that neville did that
other people didn't
is that he actually went to america on
some
speed and clone hunts
and uh there's a dude who is written
most people probably know exactly who
this is
uh he's one of the people through his
books that taught me how to grow weed
there's this dude named jorge cervantes
and uh
neville
met up with jorge cervantes
on one of his trips back into america
and
um
jorge got had new breeders
maybe breeders is the wrong word they
knew growers at the very least they knew
growers in the pacific northwest region
and jorge hooked them up with the g13
cut
and what what became known as the
pacific northwest hash plan
that's right
and so certain people gave neville a
bunch of seed lines
but then there was things like the
pacific northwest hash plant
the g13
um you know stuff like that that ended
up just being straight cuts
that he purchased
and um
you know
george wasn't somebody he used to go by
a different pen name
back in the day
but
yeah he he hooked up neville
with those two cuts and really all we
know
is that neville paid 500
for the g13 cut and it came out of
oregon
and he i don't know how much he paid for
the pacific northwest hash plant
not sure but he paid for that and he
sent both those things back as cuts
right
so
um you know he kind of collected over
the first five or six years he was in
business
through some travels uh to afghanistan
from meeting up with american breeders
uh to going to here to go into america
and buying cuts and seedlines
we haven't talked about that but there
was this uh
very mysterious character named jim
ortega
that gave him
seedlines that became super famous the
garlic bud the hawaiian indica
the um the maple leaf indica
um
and uh
uh the kush four
uh
you know and those ended up a number of
those that have been a bunch of neville
projects um so neville kind of like
neville kind of like was able to
in that five year period you know
or six year period really 84 to 90. he
was constantly
collecting stuff from breeders
collecting stuff from people blending it
together releasing stuff playing around
with stuff and seeing what the hell it
was
is kind of how it got started
in a sense
uh you want to add any of that [ __ ] matt
um actually this this is harkening back
to people are asking about the bcc
company and their sourcing i actually
found
something in reference to just that real
quickly um this is the dr atomic one so
it's gonna be the hemp bc seed bank i
believe and they don't really give an
exact um
anything on how they sourced it but it
does say
uh this state of the art indica as a
result over 20 years of selected
inbreeding they pretty much took
neville's
description the buds have extremely
frosted then they actually sold an nl5
hawaiian indica nl5 haze one hawaiian
haze but again it didn't see anything
about the sourcing of their nl5 and they
couldn't have possibly been around for
it
so
that's a lot to digest and it kind of
gives you like a super general overview
of like what
what neville was up to
and you know some of the people he was
collecting from and some of the things
that he got
um maybe we'll pause for a second and
we'll hop over to the votes
people are and i'll answer some
questions
yeah i'll read them off to you so you
don't have to read them no i got them in
front of me it's pretty easy
uh this app that i downloaded works
pretty well awesome
the first question that got a bunch of
votes is uh getting csi on here
um csi is i could probably safely say
he's a good friend of both mine and mats
um we both uh chat with him uh fairly
often
um you know he uh we're all good friends
uh it's certainly possible that we could
convince him to come on one of these in
the future
um
he's not quite
he's not quite as talkative as matt and
i am and he's a little shy
but he has done it in the past and it is
entirely possible that we could get him
to do it
uh he's a wealth of knowledge
um people call him inspecta for a reason
uh he's got a really curious mind he
pokes and pokes and pokes and tries to
figure out knowledge kind of like
the rest of us everything i just said um
that i rambled on about for forever
uh that's it's the result literally of
years of talking to people
uh years of researching years of you
know
matt got to talk to neville
quite a bit in 09 uh 10 12 years ago
um or so got a bunch of emails and
various kinds of communication
uh there was a couple year period on uh
mr nice forums which is shanti baba's
site where neville was actively posting
and answering a bunch of people's
questions
uh there's friends of his that have
contributed
there's enemies of his that have their
own various stories
and stuff and so
um all this stuff is not easy to find
it's not in any one location it's all
sort of a
conglomeration
of uh
you know just a lot of a lot of work
he cares about history
he cares about um
knowledge uh he cares about the oral
history
i can't say when but we can try to get
uh homie on here
and see if he wants to chat about
various things
the next question is we have like i said
before we have no idea who passed the
pacific northwest hash plan to know yeah
that's right jorge did arrange that that
exchange for the pnw hash plan right um
so it's not public knowledge who gave it
to him we just know it came out of the
oregon washington state area uh there
was growers that that jorge knew that he
was able to hook up with neville and
neville bought them from them
um so
their names are not known to my
knowledge
uh whoever they were
and
uh the maui cut that i have
so the the third that question and the
next question what seeds did i buy in 94
did i find anything decent and the maui
cut are both related
so i was dumb and i was 18.
and in retrospect i went there and i
bought a ton of seed
but sadly
i only bought one or two packs of like
15 different things um
and not realizing at the time that i
would have been better off buying
say two or three or four things like
five or six or seven packs of each
like 20 or 30 or 40 females of each one
instead you know i bought a bunch of
random [ __ ] i bought stuff from scentsy
uh i bought some stuff
from um
i'm trying to think now uh the the
easiest way to put it is
uh i didn't find anything that was
worthwhile on that trip except for i was
at the gray area coffee shop
and i was smoking a joint and we were
young and this old timer was sitting
down next to us
and i mean old timer in the sense he
probably looks something like me right
now
in his mid-40s a little gray whatever
and uh we were smoking and we were young
we were all 18. i was there with some
friends of mine we were like all 18 to
20 or whatever and we were all hippies
had this mission to buy seeds and
smuggle them back so we could grow
i had a two lighter
uh at the time so
really major major player
and uh
i was sitting down next to him this this
old guy smoking weed and we were telling
him our story
and he told me that he was from hawaii
and he lived there since the mid 70s
and every few years he came out and
traded seeds with some of these guys in
holland
um and brought them back and tried them
in hawaii on maui
and it wasn't a very long conversation
we drank a cappuccino i didn't ask him
that many questions we smoked a couple
joints together and a little hash or
whatever
and then at the end of it he was like
well i'm super stoked you kids are out
here trying to find some weed
and he's like why don't you take why
don't you try a little bit of what i do
and he put a handful of seeds in mine
um and one of those became the maui cut
i stupidly didn't make any seeds
uh that era i wasn't even attempting to
breed yet i was just trying to find a
good female to fill my two lighter so
i didn't ask him any intelligent
questions
about it and so i call it the maui
because that's the
island it came from and that's the only
thing i know about it
so it's gorgeous though yeah so really
uh the first time i went to amsterdam i
went to amsterdam probably two or three
times between 94
and 03 probably two or three times a
year i went to like three cannabis cups
in that time
um and i would go mostly i would go in
summer
but i would go i'd try to go a couple
times a year and buy different seeds
talk to breeders talk to various people
learn as much as i could
you got to realize back then there was
no forums
everything was just in books
information was pretty hard to come by
um
you know information was rudimentary
really uh the the way the information
flows now i wish that i could have
listened to somebody like this to shoot
the [ __ ] about weed
but it was pretty hard to come across so
um
the only thing i found on my 94 trip and
i
kept for the gift
everything i bought
was i don't want to say it was bunk
uh but my 18 my 18 year old knowledge i
didn't keep any of it
so
um i still have that cut it's still
grown in mendocino county by others it's
a great outdoor plant it has a bunch of
might be in some popular strains that
are around nowadays
there's definitely in some popular
strains and uh
that cut is
27 years old this year
that's so wild
so it's uh certainly my longest held cut
i've had it my entire adult life
it
paid a lot of bills
i brought it with me when i moved from
chicago to mendocino county in 1998
i spread it out a little bit there
and it's uh
it's been in a number of different
things
i bred with it quite a bit
um you know i gave
some hybrids that i had made
of superdog which is another story that
we've talked about before but superdog
by maui i gave a bunch of that to
mandelbrot
mandelbrot uh found a fino in that that
he called the truth
uh and then he bred with it in some of
his own lines and stuff and so
um she exists in various she still
exists pure with me and some friends but
she also exists in some other people's
work
she might exist in some pretty famous
things at this particular time
but that's kind of how cannabis is you
know
um so there's a couple more questions i
could answer for sure
our friend uh flanville he said what's
my personal favorite clone or line to
come from neville's work
you know
the line is easy
uh i i personally think the most famous
uh hybrid ever made and the most
successful cannabis hybrid that's ever
been sold is normalized 5 by haze
i don't think there's another there's
another line that's more famous
i mean
if you're looking at um
at the catalogs right there right out
there on top in the 1990 catalog
that picture of nl5 hayes
do we know which one it was eight it's
a2 it's a5 852
a52 yep there it is that's the mother of
neville's hate that picture right there
that's the mother of neville's haze
um that cut is still alive
uh it's both in europe and it's floating
around with a select few people in
america
it was found in 89 or something like
that so it's super old
um and
look at all that leaf resin damn
but yeah basically um
you know he got you know it's kind of
long but he got hayes from uh sam's dave
dave watson's sam skunk man
and he ended up crossing it with some of
his indicas
um maple leaf indica
uh called that silver haze he crossed it
with g13
and you had g13 haze he crossed it with
nl5 that became
and the nl5
uh i actually don't think there's
another line as well as me thinking that
it's the most famous and well-known line
i don't think there's another line that
has as many
named elites that still exist as that
line
yeah it'd be hard
you'd be hard-pressed to find one
there's probably four to six at least
famous named cuts in europe uh that are
nl5 haze
the piff the heights haze the cuban
black haze the dog [ __ ] the church
uh all those are all nl5 hispinos and
they all come from
88 to 95.
here's another picture from scentsy
so
um it is
uh
it's probably the most
it's probably the most famous line that
anyone has ever made and there's
literally
eight to ten to twelve cuts of it that
are all have different names that are
all elites
they're all still hoarded
uh and exist on both in europe and in
america so i think it's by far
the most famous cannabis hybrid ever
made
um
since you have this beautiful one
yeah that's super skunk cincy today is
sadly probably bunk
um yeah
neville worked for them that's a whole
story in itself but neville worked for
them after he got busted and got up they
bailed him out of jail
and they gave him a great deal of if we
bail you out of jail you have to sell us
your company
oh
uh he spent like he spent a good chunk
of time in jail and they bailed him out
and
scentsy seeds ended up absorbing
uh the seed bank from neville and
retired neville
as their top breeder
so neville went from owning the biggest
most successful seed company
to having the dea after him spending
about eight or nine months in jail
and then having to go from being an
owner to being the head breeder for
different people
and uh that's another story but they
ended up renaming a bunch of his stuff
um and so scentsy for the first five
years in the 90s for the most part um
that was where neville resided and made
most of his beams
and probably from 95 to 2000 they still
had the vast majority of the original uh
lines that they were working with
uh seed laws changed in 99 and 2000
in holland and most of the original
breeders got raided and busted
uh ben and alan drunkers are
um
dutch businessman for lack of a better
term they will never admit that they
lost a single plant from the originals
you can't get a word out of them that
anything is different than
uh
it's ever been
um but most likely they lost a bunch of
stuff and if i'm correct i think they
farmed out most of their work to spain
they haven't made
a traditional versions of their seeds
and in the the the timeline i always go
by is roughly 2005 2006 is going to be
the last times you want to buy stuff
from the majority of the dutch seed
banks because by then nirvana [ __ ]
all of them greenhouse uh scentsy they
were all farming out to buda seeds and
eventually to lamota
so basically yeah um
sensei sadly since he had about a a 10
to 15 year run
of having a lot of legitimate stuff
i do think that there could be some
things in scentsy that are still real
you have no idea what to know what
and we do know um that they lost uh
quite a few mother plants and breeding
plants over the years but they'll never
admit that so sadly
it's no longer
what they were in the 90s
which was an excellent place to get a
bunch of beans
um and i will say uh seeds if you if if
people want to see what original haze is
like seedsman still
has original haze that they sell i
believe uh
it's all it's all purchased from watson
if i'm correct but if you know people
talk about you know i might have a
cutting of original haze and stuff it's
still around it's still around in seed
form
you know so yeah there's i don't know
there's
we could talk endlessly um
uh
there's a couple things on here that are
they're easy to talk about somebody said
did skunkva head dog use your headband
cut
uh yes and no
i have two headband cuts
one of them we call the la he does not
have that one but there's another
headband cut that's extremely nice
that both him and um
icc uh both have and
mr bob hemphill and some other people
have it's much more of a cush-based
headband
and that's the headband that that he
uses
uh it's a great cut super potent that's
the one that i use as well from elite
cannabis
yeah and then um uh you mentioned the
nl5 seed line was composed of afghani
colombian and mexican what makes this
different than skunk one
um that's a good point skunk one is
afghani mexican
just totally different types of parents
totally different lines yeah i mean it's
it's like saying somebody's italian
irish and chinese you know it's not the
same parents
uh it's just the same region of origin
um certainly sam skunk man was not using
the nl cruz afghans in his lines
um and it's very unlikely the mexican or
the colombians are related um but it
just goes to show how
different blends you know from different
parents can lead very different things
yeah
vastly different
you know um
let's see somebody asked about
i don't know i mean
i've been talking the whole time and
matt has been
unusually quiet while i [ __ ] so i i
learn i still learn when we talk there's
certain things that you said tonight
that i couldn't [ __ ] remember um even
even from being the one who talked to
greg a bunch i still couldn't remember
some of that stuff so i'm just learning
um
so
let me let me ask this there was a guy
that was talking about where can one
find real old-school strains and
genetics
why are all these pollen chuckers with
watered-down herm genetics and trash
gear getting the most attention
all right so there's a couple comments
on that
for one thing
um
and this is common this isn't just for
weed but
um
you know some people are really good at
marketing
right
uh for lack of a better term you know
yeah
you know there's a lot a lot of breeders
um let's i'll throw it out there
again right so if we get csi on here in
my opinion csi is one of the absolute
best breeders that's alive today and
working
i think he the amount of breeding he
does
the amount that he shows his own work
the amount that he constantly cracks
entire rooms of seed that he has made
and shows people what's in the seed
lines themselves
almost nobody does that yeah
almost nobody shows as much
of his own work
in pictures and you can just watch him
grow after grow after grow after grow
after grow after grow on ig for years
just posting tons and tons of pics
of
you know most readers don't test their
own work
at this particular time it's very rare
testing your own work is time consuming
the best way to make money as a breeder
is to make the cross give it a killer
name make some amazing packaging pump
pump pump on ig and try to get a bunch
of hype going
and growing it out and testing it takes
time money energy space
power bills
you know all this different stuff and so
um
you know but the reason why i mentioned
csi is because he is absolutely terrible
at promoting himself
he is a phenomenal breed
that doesn't really self-promote the way
other people
you know and so you got to separate
marketing from talent right
the other thing i should say about that
is that when people talk about term
genetics people act like herbs are a bad
thing right and so and they're not
you know i said this on the live when
matt and i were chatting before
anybody that thinks that herms are bad
is tripping
yeah right herms are inconvenient
in today's marketplace um obviously
having seeds and stuff like that isn't
the greatest
so
you know
herms are just a genetic trait that
enable a plant to create seed in the
event that something weird happens and
they don't get pollinated in order to
continue the species
right from a breeding perspective
they're quite convenient to the
marijuana plant
um from a seedless perspective where
we're trying to grow cincimalia or
whatever you know however you want to
call it seedless they're inconvenient
um but but the marijuana plant did not
develop with the idea that it was going
to be seedless to it seedless is a
failure
yeah right a straight failure okay so
you know it's trying to just like all
other life
it's trying to reproduce and survive
right
and
you know just to be clear too
there is a lot of the best cannabis out
there that's bag seat
okay straight bagsy it's really humbling
as a breeder that some of the best
on the planet
is accidents
it sure is the chem dog came from a bag
of weed bought at a dead show
without seeds in that bag of weed we
don't have chem dog
was a multi-term accident
okay the super skunk that everybody's
hunting after and everybody wants and
everybody's claiming to have rks and
there's rks coming out of the woodwork
and everybody wants to claim like they
got skunk skunk skunk
that plant
permed like a mofo
it hurt like crazy
but because it hurt like crazy if it
didn't herm there would be no sour
diesel there would be
sour diesel is is from
accidental harms right
the reason why people have cush the
reason why kush came to l.a is because
in florida somebody's room hermed and
they sold seeded weed and people found
that seeded weed
and they grew up some seed and they got
what we known as kush
sour diesel cookies
okay
uh chem dog you name it they're bag
seeds
and so you know a lot of people like you
know jump on herms and obviously
you don't want to buy a bunch of gear
that has tons of herms because it's
inconvenient but herms are a genetic
trait like anything else and they exist
and breeders do the best they can to
reduce the incidence of herms
but if you're breeding something okay
nobody
you know
nobody cared that sour diesel hurmed a
little bit
it was fireweed
yeah right tasted great got you super
[ __ ] high
lasted a long time burned great it's a
herm
you know kush came from a herd
cookies came from a herd
multiple homes
so a lot of the backbone cannabis and a
lot of the absolute most famous lines
were not created intentionally at all
they were accidents
that happened in people's rooms and so
that doesn't mean that like you want to
get a bunch of hernia gear that sucks
and makes your life crappy right um
obviously terms are inconvenient
and breeders can do the best they can
to reduce
her hermaphroditism traits but there's i
mean matt can speak to this there's
populations like thai
and other things where herms are like
prevalent
yeah i mean it
it really depends on which line you're
running and it
vastly depends on the room that the the
parents were acclimated in that made the
seeds if if you're if you're popping
seeds from a grower that only
predominantly makes seeds indoors and
you want to run them all outdoors
probably not the best idea you know it's
it's acclimation climate all that goes
into it the intersex traits are here
people have right against them for ever
since people have been breeding cannabis
furs and camilla right but they're still
here and this they're not going anywhere
it's a part of the the genome
and you know man there's there's a
there's a uh there's a lot of there's a
lot of questions i'll try to answer a
couple more before we
before we leave the last question is
caleb using the other headband cut
um caleb is csi
uh and
uh
csi has both of my headband cuts
uh like i said he's a real good friend
of mine i trust him with my whole
library he can have anything he wants
from me basically
um i love his breeding work uh you know
nobody put the mendo perps which i got
lucky enough to crack nobody put more
genetics out there of the mendo perps
and made it a permanent part of the gene
pool more than csi
um so he has both of my headband cuts
um my la cut is a
sort of a diesel type um it's much more
of a blend
you know uh the other one is much more
of a cush varietal they're both super
potent they're both in my kind of
top five or ten cuts that i possess
um so he has both he hasn't had him
forever but he has started using them in
various work and you can buy some of
that work as we speak
um
mr nice i'll ignore that one just
because it's a super long subject
but the sh the short version
is that
after neville left scentsy he started
working with shanti baba
and they made they bred together for a
while and the result of that breeding
was super silver haze mango haze
neville's haze some other things
and neville was hurting for money
and uh he sold
shanti
uh for a good chunk of loot uh a quarter
million dollars or something
um most of his seed collection from the
seed bank era
uh
in the 80s uh unreleased stuff various
lines and things like that
so mr nice
um like a lot of people there's some
people that believe that shanti's full
of [ __ ] there's some people they believe
he's a shady character that he's a liar
but it's indisputable
that
neville gave him a lot of real parents
and neville gave him
uh or sold him his seed collection
um so
there's not very many people that have
indisputable evidence that they have a
bunch of access to the old things
and he's one of them
that being said there's no way to verify
what he has and what he doesn't have and
so there's a lot of debate on what he
has
and
there's disagreement and some people
think he's full of it some people think
he's got all the white hot fire
the truth is probably somewhere in
between i'm sure
he has some of neville's old work i'm
sure he has a bunch of neville's old
seed
it's hard to say exactly
um
what he currently has and what he
doesn't but his provenance in being able
to access it i don't think is in dispute
would you agree with that matt oh yeah
for sure i mean neville neville
uh i mean at the very end is not talked
about a lot but um he felt like shanky
bobo might owe him some more money even
though he wasn't in the agreement
because he had done so well with
neville's line so neville obviously felt
that his lines were being used correctly
and making tons of money with them
there's another thing about australian
bastard cannabis
at csi i'll just say that real quick i
don't know that much about it um you
know csi is a true
breeder um
he is really interested in freaks he's
really interested in genetic
uh oddities
and if nothing else abc is extremely odd
uh in the way that its leaves form and
stuff like that and you know a lot of
stuff
right now is really bottlenecked people
use the same 30 40 50 cuts over and over
and over again and so at the very least
when you buy adc work
you're getting something that is
genetically unique so far
and he's certainly widening the gene
pool of available cannabis
by making it by making it available to
the public
it is probably one of the first lines in
a long time that's totally unique from
what came before
and it's valuable just for that
and it's an ongoing project that he's
putting a bunch of time into
and i'm sure over the next three or four
or five years we'll see a bunch more
work from it
uh
matt can comment on this too but he's
really just been getting started with
his own work on it
yeah yeah um
i see so many people get so mad every
time he posts pictures of people
actually genuinely get hurt feelings
when they see this plant they're like oh
my god what is that piece of [ __ ] you
know
it's it's surprising to me because a lot
of them claim to be breeders or or are
seed makers and have companies but they
don't see the genetic novelty in
bringing in something completely new
that hasn't really touched cannabis
you know as far as modern minds
there's a lot like i said there's a lot
of sameness i'll say this quickly too
the way the breeding has gone the last
20 years as soon as something becomes
famous
everybody crosses it to everything else
so the amount of [ __ ] right now that has
cookie in it kush in it sour diesel in
it skittles in it
um you know you name it in it um stuff
gets red and bread bread bread bread
bread to death
um so to take say cookies
and to cross it with uh abc is crossing
into a vastly different gene pool than
anybody else is using and so who knows
what might come of that that's the best
part you don't know
who knows in a few years where that
might lead that might lead to unique
highs that might open up the gene pool
and make things pop out you're not
expecting genetics
and so people get on him about it
because it's so weird um but he's really
just in the infancy of playing around
with it but you've seen that he is
um you know he's been posting a bunch of
pictures this last week of some of his
work with the abc
you know i don't know you guys could
like this is probably odd because i've
been talking 98 of the time for an hour
and a half
it's all good
i can hear it in my throat um but we
kind of want to just do this thing and
maybe we'll do it like you know
semi-often or whatever
uh we had this thought of kind of going
through the seed banks and it's such a
big subject
we really only touched on a little bit
of the history we didn't really touch on
haze or skunk or durbin or
um anything from jim ortega very much
but those can be for future things
i hope everybody enjoyed it uh you know
i don't want to make it a forever thing
um but we could do this pretty often
and there's also the patreon you can go
to reader syndicate patreon where me and
natto always shoot the [ __ ] with a bunch
of people that are a part of it you can
ask questions all the time and whenever
we have time we go in there and pick at
them and try to break it down
that's really true too um
[Music]
it's on discord
uh and
we have a we have a server there
um you know and yeah you can you can
directly message me on there i generally
answer sometimes it takes me a minute
because you know i do do things and get
busy or whatever but
matt and i are both pretty active on
there and we do [ __ ] a bunch and a
lot easier to ask away and get responses
online so feel free to join that um and
really what all matt and i are trying to
do at this point
is just get
chunks of history and chunks of
knowledge out there to the larger public
uh this is kind of our weed life i'd
like to do is
talk about
you know
or whatever so i hope everybody enjoyed
it
uh and learned a couple things and i
hope it continues
and all that so
uh
yeah
i think that's it