ready go
so
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
hi greg how you doing
good good good good good i mean yet just
uh being 70 isn't all that good you know
your teeth falls out your hair falls out
you know
what
i mean you guys enjoy life and travel
when you're young it's far more fun you
know i bet yeah well you're still around
that's the important thing
well you know
a lot of the brothers i serve with
aren't man i'm one of them
i'm living the last remaining you know
well
i think i think that's a lot of the
appeal and talking to you is that your
experiences and unfortunately a lot of
your peers and colleagues are are unable
to share their stories and so uh well i
have to thank you as an indoor grower
for all your horticultural contributions
obviously if it wasn't for your work
with the northern lights
many of us wouldn't have had the success
we had today
well it was kind of a group effort out
of seattle you know had the lights and
you know we were all young and we're
just tired of smoking mexican
you know i mean it wasn't
i mean it just wasn't doing anything for
our ptsd symptoms and it wasn't
i mean even comparable to anything that
we got in asia when we went to thailand
and vietnam and you know
i mean it just didn't get as well we
basically had to do it i lived in first
fell in seattle i lived in the ballard
area and i was actually shopping at the
indoor sun shop for a few years and
around that time is when i learned about
steve murphy and his books
i'm curious what around what time did
you meet steve
oh well i went to high school with steve
right at ballet
oh ballard high school oh great so yeah
i lived literally lived like two blocks
away from it
um yeah i was growing upstairs and uh i
mean the apartment that i was renting
but uh i knew that
the history was right right in that area
oh yeah you know kevin and
the other murphy family then
i know sean uh steve's son
and uh that's who i've had that's who i
spoke to the most uh sean um just trying
to ask him questions and uh
so that did you originally obtain uh the
afghan from steve murphy
yeah right after my first son was born
uh but he invited this over to a party
and he gave me
four seats
of an afghanistan variety
the said that some friend
brought back on vacation
and that was the uh
uh that was the real wide range
frame that was in his first book
yeah yeah
yeah
i've got a picture of him
i was always curious oh yeah that's the
one he gave me and then we uh we crossed
out with
everything we could get our hands on or
we crossed it with mexican we crossed it
with thai we crossed it with a whole
bunch of stuff and
i got a whole bunch of seeds that we
only got to basically use about one
percent but you know
i mean it was uh it was fun
was it the males that you got from those
feeds that you crossed into them no we
got uh
two males and
two females and we just made more seats
okay
and then we also basically took this
recipe to reproduce and then we quit
available in town you know which was
colombian
we did a lot of crossing uh
and then figured out real quick
or where they were going to be able to
test all these and the cops were banging
on everybody's door and everybody got to
jail it was pretty chaotic
oh i
i can't imagine at that time
so see the
the afghan you got from steve murphy
how how does that relate to northern
lights one is is steve mercy the north
did he call it northern lights or did it
was it just an avenue no it's just but i
came up with the northern lights the
original spelling of the northern lights
that we sort of sent to devil uh was
like lipes
and then it got over to holland and it's
just uh i think there's like
evil's cousin robert
i was basically handling the catalog and
he basically like he changed the
spelling but the original spelling on
the varieties that i made
was i mean like in the northern lights
but that's just the
historical fact that everybody does
yeah so you know that
you spelled it l-i-t-e
yes
by northern lights yeah that's the name
i gave to neville and then he changed it
and we just kind of decided that was
okay because it was already done in the
catalog
[Laughter]
so how did you meet neville i was over
at my buddy you saw a hair salon now you
know the university district
that's by fremont
uh the university district
i mean over there by husky stadium
yeah absolutely
yeah i had a buddy that had a uh like
hairspray still on that we'd hang out
and kind of do things and he always had
a high times uh
for the people to read on the table
there while you're waiting to get your
hair cut
and there was a little ad in the back of
the high times you know and that was
neville's first dad i think
that was the 84 year or so
yeah i think so so i sent him uh
some seats
and
it's about six o'clock in the morning
and i get a phone call the old lady
announces phone call and it's never
said i had a hard time tracking you down
and then basically
and then we basically
talked and she said man i need some more
of them indoor seats panels they're just
blowing the doors out of rosenbaum's
and i thought well that's good you know
i mean they're
they're probably a lot fresher than this
because i mean land gave them the seed
collection
yeah
so you had given some previously to ed
no that comes later uh basically uh
but we talked first for a while and he
offered to pay for my airfare over
the first trip over to holland was on a
uh
i was on like a martin airlines it was
it's about
210 dollars one way and it was a prop
plane it took forever
and they basically uh they picked up the
passengers in oakland and
and by the time they got to seattle they
were already drunk
and then the seattle passengers piled on
and we had about a
10 hour flight over to amsterdam and by
the time and
on everybody got there we were pretty
burned out and everything and i never
was right there at the airport smoking
the joint
what year do you think that was i went
over
like in the earlier
it was 84
and like 85 but then i went back with
the wife
i mean after he bought cannabis castle
so you went over the first year in 84 by
yourself
yeah yeah
the fall and then we went back again
and then i basically i helped him
just i do like a recipe for cannabis
castle
i mean because like he had a
he had a little operation in his wine
cellar in the basement he had a nice
basement
oh i bet have you ever been to cannabis
castle
oh god
i've researched a lot about it and
certainly on the bucket list
[Music]
so did you share seeds with neville
multiple times or just uh when you
found the ad of his
i said never let me see two shipments
there was one
smaller initial shipment and then i went
and i talked to him and i got together
with my people after i got back and then
we shipped him more
i wasn't the only guy that was breathing
you know we had
uh but we had like a team because uh due
to the
art of the police pressure
we basically uh wanted to basically have
all these screens and at least three
people's hands in case
i didn't know everybody gets busted
maybe we can keep it you know but it was
i mean it was a losing battle
so what do you think you're right what
do you think the original cross was with
steve murphy's ass game that you guys
made
well with the app cam i could get more
scenes so i mean
he only gave me four feet but we wanted
to get more seats uh then we crossed it
with everything uh
oh yeah i mean like a lot of exits
okay
do you recall what the northern lights
number one cross was
uh
the northern lights are number one was
basically
uh
afghani
and then the afghani that i got from
neville
do you
know what afghan from neville that was
um but the one he got in uh like a
margarita
about that
i mean when he went over there with uh
clark
curtis uh the
photographer out of hollywood
yeah
yeah [ __ ] are you vertical eye oh
yeah yeah i remember uh
neville told me lots of stories about
how [ __ ] wacky that dude was
how crazy you [ __ ] it's just yeah it's
just
i like clyde nice guy man but he's
hollywood you know
yeah different
i think my friend bodhi's still good
friends with him too
i mean it's just like he's a marine i
think i kind of lost tech i mean like he
came up
and then we kind of lost track of each
other and like i got a divorce and then
i went underground so yeah it's just uh
i mean if you're here or
see him around so say hi from me now oh
we'll do definitely
do you remember which one was the female
or the mom from that northern lights one
cross
no
that was like one third like a way too
long ago and you know like at that point
in time
uh
cheating records uh was they uh i mean
like or any pictures or anything
like that real liability because of all
the costs you know oh for sure i
completely understand
i completely understand
so it's just uh the record keeping back
then now it's all changed you know now
we can basically be scientists
okay
uh then uh
the only people who could basically do
that on a rational basis i was over in
holland that's why i went there
yeah i mean like it wasn't about the
money it was to get the medicine out of
the people that was the main mission
do do you have any memory of what the
northern lights 2 cross was
the northern lights two cross uh was a
uh
it was a cross that we did with the
steve's afghani and then we got an
afghani
hybrid uh
from gone down in olympia that's the one
that called the indian
okay
and
uh right he got it
from some biker in org it was a real
nice uh
i mean like a little tighter butt than
the body afternoons that we were working
with
i don't know
where don got it from
but it was a real nice one and it was
one of my
shorter ones and we made that number two
that's great
huh
i said that's great info because those
the one and two or some of the ones that
neville continued on
well it's it's just so when i went over
to holland you know they were doing some
uh i mean
there were some people breeding a lot
with uh
for the number
two like uh jay jackson did the k2 which
was real nice
[Music]
so if you'll mind me asking how did you
meet kirby nelson i understand he was an
employee of thieves
yeah that's just what hurt me went to
ballard too
we all went to the same high school
oh we just were you in the same class
uh
i don't think so
okay all i know is we all went to
ballard we were all from ballard you
know we are
what can you tell us about his hawaiian
plant
a herby
[Music]
and i
uh
basically traded some clone and he just
said it was a speed afghani cross with
the hawaiian switzerland
oh that's all
oh that's all he told me and that's all
i know but you know i mean it was
i mean it was against future fest all
over the world i mean it had to hype
adventure and it had what everybody
wanted at the time you know
i mean we were able to basically grow a
uh
24 inch bud
on about a five foot
flat with that and that was in uh
i mean 84.
i need to click the winner
i mean it was a winner it was uh
i mean it was just one of them
flukes in nature i
think were all all the genetics
clicked and it all fell into place at
the right time
sounds like it so that's the clone that
you use to make northern lights number
five
uh i didn't make number five what herbie
did
then we uh
crossed number five with the number one
and you know
i mean it just gave us uh
uh the fifty percent says so diva and
about triple the vigor you know
so he crossed the clone that he gave you
with the number one
yes you're correct
so was herbies did he have um steve
murphy's afghani is that the afghani
that's in number five
yeah
okay yeah i think that's where the
confusion was
yeah i was just trying to understand the
history on that line so that that
the clone that he had or gave to you
that was made from steve speed
that was a half game okay
yeah that changed the [ __ ] world the
genetics for good
yeah
i mean like i mean like it won some
cannabis cups for sure
was real happy with it now i mean that
way he bought cannabis castle with it
yeah that's the damage right
so do you think it was a hawaiian plant
that herbie had that he crossed the
steep i'm sorry i'm having trouble
falling
uh
i have no idea
and it's just uh
i haven't talked to herbie and i don't
know if he even wants to talk to anybody
so it's just i don't know what the deal
is there but you know i just
just uh
i mean it all happened a long time ago
and there's basically no written record
but you guys are right about that
[Music]
uh there's been a lot of
a lot of discussion about the indian of
the indian
uh uh the indian was gone down he's
passed away years ago now so
which is how we met don when uh
by the guy that owns the hair salon
raleigh
his name was raleigh
yeah
i mean what he brings a guy over and
when he was an injured worker a lot
older guys
or they weren't given enough money
to derail the rib rights so we set him
up with a full four light operation
and we gave him some seeds and some
cuttings and he did some breathing for
us
do you know any of the lines that don
may have contributed
uh dawn
contributed
half of the genetics
for the number two
yeah that's true
okay and then we got uh
and then after i went over to the street
level then we went down to portland and
we got the hash plant laying the bigfoot
off at george
do you remember what time that was
that was when this is all right before
george did his first book with my
uh officers with my youngest son on the
cover
yeah i have to look at the days i know
what you're referring to
that's pretty cool
when was the last time you spoke to
georgia
the last time i spoke to george was up
in vancouver uh when i basically gave
them all the lead i had left over
because i had to go to the border
and that was years ago
many years ago but we're good friends
everybody well steward you know
yeah i just spoke to him recently he was
a wealth of good information he was very
receptive and
so that's why i'm interested in talking
to everybody from your generation all
the yeah
we traded with george i
kind of forget what we gave him i think
we might have gave him the number five i
don't know but he gave us the hash plant
and then he gave us the big book
but the hash plant was the one
that was a real good one too
that was a real favorite was a real
shitty yielder but everybody loved the
taste in the eye
and that was the one that was that
neville collected obviously when he
visited the states
yeah
yeah i think he went down and sort of
saw george urging the people in portland
what do you think do were you aware that
neville came in and visited the state oh
yeah we went down to the airport and saw
neville and he was grown and had his
head up his ass he was with roger you
know who roger is
i've read the name i don't know who he
is
uh roger granwich i think is the
spelling he was neville's like american
representative first and everything and
he kind of
he kind of flew into seattle and then he
went down to see uh
clyde in l.a and then he went down to
rosenthal he was kind of like a devil's
agent in the
got it
so where what airport could you see
neville at
two is in a
hotel uh just east of seatac
okay
no i'm not sure what one it was a long
long time ago there's a lot of hotels on
there bro
so do you think the purpose of that trip
was to get more northern lights or was
he just coming for genetics in general
uh i've got no idea what was in devil's
mind uh then i knew this is that's way
beyond my page right
that's fair
yeah i'm just trying to piece together
the history of all this what year is
gonna estimate you think that you flew
in
it was like i mean like 85 it was around
christmas time
i remember that it was cold and nasty
and
uh but the kids were visiting
that was kind of
so i
had you sent him the northern lights
five clones before that trip
closed uh yeah i mean this is a roger
came and he sent one
i mean over to neville uh we got one i
mean i knew you know we got him a clone
and he got one of these a glass bowl
prairie and things at some uh flora shop
and
trim the leaves off certainly weren't
necessarily didn't that's how he got it
over the hall
that was pretty genius
yeah
yeah that's what i thought
it got there just fine
but just just to recap you said that
kirby made the ml5 so when you got that
clone you were given it as in l5
yeah yeah that was on the nl5 i was like
finding like herbies uh
cross with the hawaiian and uh steve
murphy's afghani
so you you didn't make the cross you
just got the clone from herbie and seat
of this uh line to give to neville
well yeah we took it to see
and we gave him the seed first but i
mean like he wanted the original clown
but we got him the original clown
okay so the seed metal receives came off
herby's mom
uh
uh by the seats
i mean it's just like he got uh
yeah
okay because what we did after we got
the number five we basically began
crossing it with everything we could get
our hands on and what
and
the issue so what we got looked real
similar that's what went the level
i mean like about the frame size with
that like a mounted figure it was the
reader oh that was the deal you know i
mean it was the vigor and the taste and
it was just our superiors so we
tried to read
i mean like i replicated that by doing
seeds and uh and we've been working on
it for a while but we i mean you know
speeds are variable
clones aren't
totally how long do you think you guys
kept herbies clone
around i lost that when the cops braided
tom lost that after his fun
took over the operation
and we had some crop failures so it's
just i don't know if anybody has the
original clone but then
i don't even know it neville or
where it's just uh you know scott does
yeah
yeah now they might have the original
chrome i mean well i don't i don't think
anybody didn't see that with us
oh
maybe 20 years ago
okay
so out of all the seeds that you guys
made was there a favorite that stood out
to you
yeah we like the indicas the shorter
indicators uh the number
uh the shorter ones with the uh what we
were looking for was more medicinal
value uh
and uh quick turn around
so when you're talking about dawn down
one dawn's the afghani hybrid was that a
clone that he gave you
or those speeds
oh we got both
okay
and then also had something that he gave
us that he called big bud that was uh
man like it wasn't the same as the big
bud we got off at george
interesting
i mean it was
fluffier and it
had more oil
content i think that was the number
eight
of the ml number eight sheet so it was
the the real [ __ ] big bud that had
all the oil glam so we used to go down
to dawn's and get a
i mean like a pound or two and you know
all the people they'd come back and
they'd dump it on the table and they'd
go
for that number eight well every time
they could see the difference
but we mix it all together usually you
know
i mean we're just doing a one two three
light operations
so the numbered one through
ten or the number of northern lights
were those using these afghani or the
northern lights number one that you made
so it just depends on the number
uh the higher the number the taller the
plant
well that's how we kind of
how i kind of determined that it's
simpler for
for devil uh with the more afghani with
the ones and the
and uh the more specific with the others
you know
and the higher you got the more
succeeded
[Music]
how long have you been living in hawaii
greg
i'm gonna die here man i like it
how long have you been there
oh i i mean i was living in
homage county
and the pud was running the new programs
so we couldn't i mean like a ripoff kw
is a day of power anymore so i decided
to retire and move that was in 2010.
have you do you know anything about the
nahomish super speed club yeah it's
something that was like started in the
90s a little group of growers up there
that had a bunch of clubs
no i don't know the guy to talk to
um
ormish county would be john pettit uh
the guy that basically is it uh s
stoopers discriminating where everybody
was getting that surprise
yeah
that's a great place
oh yeah now you were oh yeah you know
what you are
i've never i may have met him i didn't
realize
i used to shop up there because that was
a better place to get the wholesale
supply
no cheaper
five
yeah yeah it's just i mean it's just uh
it's a family operation up there it's uh
john and his mom and his sister it's a
whole family operation i used to
i used to basically get everything up
there when i was working with the city
of
seattle when i got out of the marine
corps
yeah i loved my time up there that's the
homeless beautiful farmer country
yeah
we were living in arlington i've been up
there that's a little further north
yeah it's nice
no i like i believe
it's being produced up there now
yeah
yeah no no
the over
production is going nuts and you know
i mean look what's going on in oregon
soon they'll begin to be selling
concentrates for a buck
yeah it's certainly going that way i'm
not looking for you
but you know you guys are seed breeders
that's a different game you know it's
just by these big guys that
i mean they're gonna
about they think they can go indoors and
make it killing and everything because
you can't compete with the sun like
mexico or the labor cost you know
oh for sure so
did you did you share northern lights
with uh the drunkards family
oh yeah yeah yeah yeah it's just like i
milled uh like a pen and keys the whole
collection
i mean this is how they were real
helpful they gave us the fertilizer
formula that's what we were interested
i mean in mainly you know
it's just that we got neville's
fertilizer cooked
we got ben's foreign
foreign like and then we came back to
the u.s and we made our own fertilizer
and it was a two-part
oh yeah now we had a two-part before
general hydro did
i was called a wonder girl
and then we got busted in the old way
she freaked out
no i couldn't just pour
watson and sam my
you know i mean has always been kind of
i'm better than you and i'm saying i'm
the man and you know i mean he's always
been real disrespectful as far as i'm
concerned i mean like he's done a good
job but my hat's off to him i mean it's
just like he can take his ego and cram
it up his ass as far as i'm concerned
that's how i feel too excuse me you
think that's the universal opinion he
didn't have many friends
well you know i mean i just like to be
real now i'm old enough man i served my
time and i
i mean i
i mean i blood for i mean for like free
speech you know
yeah
i never met sam or roth he came to
seattle after we ran our ad in in the
alexander's magazines
tips
was it the grow like that but i never
met sam
but what i heard about sam was basically
from neville
yeah
was the ad the grow light shop ad you're
talking about
oh no it's when rob
came up we spent about a
half an hour at my house
out in the shoreline district and then
we went to a concert up at parker's
ballroom
and we watched uh quick
silver messenger service oh yeah they're
great
okay and we kind of
and then he met all my people from
seattle and and then basically after
that was a win green merchant
that happened and everybody got busted
you know it was
sent everybody into shock mode
i bet did rob respond to a speed ad or a
lighting ad in the magazine
we had a company and everything although
bearer was going to basically handle all
of the
paperwork over in
holland
we were gonna have just we were gonna
mail the seats out of the u.s and
collect the money in holland but that
never worked out this incarcerated us
gotcha that was the ad was for did you
put in uh since the miller tips for
seeds though yeah
i remember
remember what year that was
i was 85 or 86 i think
alexander's old
i mean my old copies i think wolfy might
have
yeah i have all this
yeah yeah it was uh i feel like it was
from the big ad
and then rob uh like he
yeah i know you guys are the new guys on
the block and this and that you know you
know
and we told them you know
i go like you and sam down in california
and you do
i mean it's just uh but you can't
breathe like we do indoors man that you
guys do i mean it's just i mean like a
one crop a year and we do
you know and he didn't like that very
much so you know
how did you meet george
i just called him up i think after he
began writing in high times
oh awesome
called him up i knew there's just like
he knew everybody down in portland
that's when uh
i mean like i go
tech and george we're having
the white wars on
on the portland tv stations
how did you meet wolf de gaulle
a wolfie i met at a hydro attack right
he worked for kevin
or they're on aurora
okay
and then it's just like and then they
opened up the portland store and then
kevin got busted but he did five years i
mean
i went underground
you like you were
smart i mean that's why i went
underground you know i mean like i had
an old lady and a couple of kids and
then you know
yeah no kidding you name that [ __ ]
thank god for jeff steinborn i mean you
kept a lot of this energy
that's right you mentioned him the
lawyer that kept everyone out of jail
yeah he was like
i mean he was like our gift for from
above everybody loved jeff everybody
still loves you
he and the prosecutor
so do you think steve ever got to
experience any of the northern lights
crosses you made i mean this i didn't
hang around with steve all that much it
was uh i'd see him at the store
you know
but there wasn't a lot of interaction
was he actually selling feet out of the
shop or it was just because no no no it
was i mean it was a gift i don't think
he
i don't think anybody was selling treats
out of the store or the manager jerry
did you meet jerry or the older guy that
does the uh carnivorous plants
that does it's not ringing a bell
he was steve's manager at the indoor sun
shop for
i mean like a decade
i mean
it's just a certain thought
jerry i don't remember the last name man
you know alzheimer's is a [ __ ] you know
when the brain still start rock boys
enjoy yourself while you can
you have a pretty sharp memory
yeah yeah i'm just going to say you've
got a better memory than i have and i'm
in my 30s
i mean it's always good
it's a testament to the thc
[Laughter]
yeah but it takes
i mean it takes a real beating on the
loans man they wanted me to be a judge
in the cannabis contest
and i don't want to be up there hacking
all the time
yeah i mean that's why
you don't want to smoke anyway
i mean that's the last thing i want to
do in public is be hacking an overdose
and poke funny everybody like i mean
like emery did when he got out of the
joint
[Music]
so do you know what any of the other
crosses are any of the other numbers of
their parents
no we didn't keep any records i wish we
could have you know but it just uh
chapters
you know
i mean everything you have they're going
to use against you
so the less you have as opposed to this
or that or that you keep telling
everybody you know
keep the plant count down and don't get
greedy you know
yeah sounds like he's a smart man to
listen to
well if you had one light it was one
thing if you had
20 lights then they he considered a lot
more serious yeah
and it's just the ones they wanted to
get off this
street was the
always these guys that were doing these
big operations and we're also into the
harder drugs
yeah yeah
that's generally the case it hasn't yeah
yeah it's always been that way so it's
just uh
well yeah they carried the same
penalties pretty much back then so you
know if one got more money than the
other most people [ __ ] with all of
them
i didn't it's just all the blankers were
some of our best customers
i think they almost
i mean
kind of demanded to get their name on
hey man
you sell them all there
i mean you know it was a i mean it was a
real valuable
commodity it's not like now you know but
then you had to get your name on the
list
and if you didn't know somebody i didn't
get your name on the list you know
exactly
i had people coming out from all over
the place they flew in from chicago and
virginia and all over the place and you
know
i couldn't do anything with them
you know i didn't get cops swarming
everywhere
and i'm sure everybody's phone would
attack you know we just kind of had to
play them and you know
i got an old lady and two kids and i
can't jeopardize you
but now how are all these how are all
these people playing the ball game
between i mean it's just a night i mean
like a lighting day so you know you guys
you guys have a real opportunity and
have done really well
with newer varieties that are coming out
of the usa because this is where ben's
coming to get his genetics now
how did all these people find out about
uh the northern lights was it just for
the ads that you guys are publishing or
how are they coming out from chicago in
these areas
we
ran though
i made a
couple of ads fertilizer and rockwool
for a while
until the feds closed this down
oh that was more trouble than it were
so how many people were you say involved
that were in the breeding of the
different northern lights
you said it was kind of a group people
well it was a core group and then there
was uh i mean it's just now that's hard
to say
that's hard to say
i mean there were people that came and
went so it just didn't be up around the
actual group uh basically it just kept
changing because everybody was in and
out of jail
so it's just like it's hard to put a
number on it
i understand
well i really thank you for all your
information i think you have addressed
all of my main questions after reading
some posts at uh mr knight's forums
um i hope that uh
matt and i can continue to reach out to
you with any questions we may come
across in our research
okay
anyway you guys have a nice
afternoon or evening or
hey youtube brother
feel free to call anytime
thank you so much greg we genuinely
appreciate all the time and all the
access
okay bye
i mean that the dutch well they come
here for all the genetics now it used to
be the other way around
it was all meant to happen you know