welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
you'll notice with a lot of our
interviews it kind of just jumps into a
conversation and this will be no
different and the ending will probably
be no different as well so
um apologies in advance a lot of our
conversations are all over the place
it's a bunch of us with ADHD so uh yeah
I just wanted to put that in there
cheers
okay welcome to breeder Syndicate
everyone I'm Matthew I'm here with my
friend Shawnee kids and not so dog and
we are here with New York Pete
um was the I guess you would say owner
Runner of compassion clubs in the um in
the 90s in Canada correct yeah and we're
still going so I I started the uh
originally it was called the London
Compassion Club uh back in 95
um
and then
um we went public in with Allen Rock so
that would have been like
97 or so and that's um that's when I uh
split off from hemp nation and did the
organic traveler which was my retail but
they call me NYPD just because my name
is
Petey Pete and I'm from New York kind of
thing so that's uh they don't call me
New York Pete but they call me NYPD NYPD
yeah I'm always scared to lead with that
because I remember when the first time I
heard I was like NYPD yeah yeah
everybody well like a bunch of [ __ ]
NYPD uh paraphernalia like the shirt and
the hat and all that yeah but where
we're from you know that's like everyone
had a nickname like my name is Johnny
kids like Pete has only really known me
as Shawnee kids going back to the 90s
right yeah that's funny yeah yeah and
all of our friends had nicknames
everyone had a nickname you kind of had
to in this industry though right sure
back in the day I didn't want to say hey
[ __ ] Sean [ __ ] you know or Chris
Clay or [ __ ] anybody's real name
you were the king of shortening words
too oh I [ __ ] mixed up everybody and
I and there's evolutions of people's
nicknamese I know has a [ __ ] nickname
and if something like bomb boy worked
for me for years no idea what his
[ __ ] real name was
[Music]
it's a different nickname it's a
different way yeah
in a semi-shady you know quasi what you
know anywhere from completely illegal to
quasi-legal to to gray area to maybe you
know yeah and I always said you know we
have uh we I've always lived in the gray
area of the world and sometimes it's
really dark gray and sometimes it's
really light gray right like you know
I've uh I've had a deal in the black
market because I needed to to suffice or
to satisfy the need of the medical
community that I was part of and I
couldn't grow enough for everybody so
um and that's really really why I
started growing pot I started growing
pot you know one not to sell it I just
wanted to save money and when I started
organic traveler uh in a you know
University Town I had the uh grow your
tuition Campaign which was uh I would
sell you seeds and give you information
sell your grow guides come back come in
on any Sunday and we would have grow
chats and
um
walk you through how to do cuttings or
start seeds or or stuff like that
um because money in your pocket whether
you save it or make it is still money in
your pocket right yeah no don't get into
this industry and I [ __ ] honestly you
know I I won't work with anybody
back in the day especially when cannabis
was illegal if your sole income was
strictly on growing pot
good on you you you're not going to be
in my circle because I think you know if
you're doing that's kind of prostituting
the uh the plant and I've always been a
good big advocate
about you know not prostituting this
plant like use it for what it's meant
for right like it was put forth for us
to enjoy not to you know uh pasteurize
and and prostitute kind of thing so I've
made my entire living off of cannabis
yes but I also had organic traveler
which was a head shop that was legal if
I got busted which I have and end up in
jail which I have and they take
everything that I own which they did my
rent was still paid and there was still
food on my table so before I had ham
Nation or sorry organic traveler or
before him Nation well hemp Nation I was
uh delivering meat I'm a vegetarian I
was [ __ ] delivering meat every
morning from nine or eight in the
morning till four in the afternoon come
home to my garden and that was my gravy
my [ __ ] shitty [ __ ] day job put
food on my table paid my rent and then
all the gravy in life my two thousand
dollar bike hanging on the wall my trips
to [ __ ] Amsterdam or California or
wherever the [ __ ] I want to go that was
great that was all from the Cannabis I
was you know and it's not from being you
know a dick about it I was uh I grew pot
I would have a harvest party and I'd
bring all the staff in from uh hemp
nation and I'd be like what do you guys
want right I'm gonna I'm honest with you
I'm charging you double what I charge
Medical
so I can sell it cheaper to the Met for
people that need it over the people that
want it yeah and uh and you tell me what
you want you don't have to pay for it
you will pay for it in time but if you
want two ounces or three ounces or QP
that's fine you I'm gonna take the pie
I'm gonna put in one of those containers
I'm gonna stick it in my deep freezer
and you come to me when you want a
quarter ounce
50 bucks bring it you know but that pot
is there it's for you I'm not selling it
to anybody else right that could be a
generational thing too because like when
I I felt like where I you know where I
grew up at least it was really important
to have some kind of
um verifiable income yeah right because
you had to have some reason of existing
you had to have some way to make it you
didn't want to go to court and they're
like how do you support yourself and
you're like uh right and you know it
comes from an era where like you it had
to be a side gig because you know you
needed even if it was just a even if it
was just a front like you said like you
had no like organic traveler was all a
front like I mean I [ __ ] never made
money do at organic travel I lost it
when it got to a point of losing about
40 Grand a year I said okay we're
pulling the plug and now by that time
you know I was doing the compassion
Society for
like 20 years
the cops knew what I was doing you know
and then you know in Diva came into play
and Diva came in into play
as I was close and organic like I I same
thing CRA I had to read
and you you kind of need to have
um a reason for like you said what
people see but for me it's for what I
see and what I know
and I I cut ties with some really
[ __ ] great Growers and uh and I cut
ties with people that were just [ __ ]
[ __ ] you know and it was just
um their focus was money money money and
when you chase it you know you're
opening yourself up to the you're more
vulnerable to be taken advantage of or
get busted or you know get Shady deal
with Shady people [ __ ] like that I've
been pretty lucky I mean what I've been
in this industry
um [ __ ] long time 30
how old am I 30 40.
40 almost about 35 years you know and I
thought that I put my name out there and
said hey I'm a [ __ ] pot guy kind of
thing yeah and London London is a pretty
conservative place like it was totally
different than like that's why most
people went to BC because everybody left
BC and that's why I say like they'd be
like oh BC grows the best part of course
they do they're from Ontario like [ __ ]
you know like I went out to BC I lived
out there and I didn't meet anybody from
[ __ ] BC kind of thing right yeah I'm
out there on grow contracts but you know
it was um
what we have here I mean it seems like
it it kind of
I think the marijuana movement started
around here and yes and we are in a very
uh conservative uh town and back when I
started we had a very conservative uh
religious mayor and uh you know I wanted
to make a point I put up big banners
that said the Lord believes in marijuana
do you believe in the Lord you know and
it was not something that she took
kindly but would not you know
um
make us think about it because she would
be giving me AirPlay but yeah more clock
in the morning the [ __ ] Paddy Wagon
showed up and took down my [ __ ]
Banner
you know and that's the thing like
you've been doing this a long time and
and all of that but like the one thing
you've been doing also is like fighting
the law openly right like since what
since 93
you've been constantly more like I think
is when the Constitutional challenges
yeah
on a regular basis right like he's uh
that poor man has been beat the [ __ ] up
in this [ __ ] industry too who is he
uh Alan Young is the uh I say the
Cannabis lawyer in Canada so
um
um and so he's the one that handled uh
Chris's case uh his partner Paul
Bernstein he handled like Ross roll a
big doobie whatever the [ __ ] his name is
if you go to the West Coast you have
John Conroy when you hear constitutional
lawyers uh you're dealing with Alan
Young
do you want to explain the the whole uh
Chris Clay arrest
uh sure yeah so uh I was part of NPC but
in the shadows uh luckily so the first
time he got raided
um
it was uh yeah so with with Chris very
educated well read polite kid who didn't
start smoking pot till just a few years
prior
um read the law and the law
the way that the law was read is it
wasn't cannabis that was illegal it was
THC yeah so
THC is not in the seeds that's correct
we started selling seeds and that's how
I met them because I was going back and
forth from New York to Saint Thomas or
London because I was in college and I
was bringing seeds back and forth Just
trading for genetics for genetics yeah
and so I was helping him with the the
little uh Great Canadian Emporium seed
[ __ ] company and then he realized
well cuttings don't have [ __ ] THC in
them either so he took out a [ __ ]
full-page ad in the uh see I think we've
seen magazine that said uh overgrow your
government and I I'm pretty sure that
Chris well it would have been Andrew who
was the artist coined that phrase the
overgrow overgrow your government right
less overall the government and it was
like it was literally a cartoon of a
seed marching with a helmet on with the
hemp Nation flag on it holding a bong at
like it's a gun and you know and we said
we're gonna sell 30 skunk one cuttings
for 30 bucks or 25 for 25 bucks or
something like that and um
I think by
the seventh cutting or something along
that line uh Jordan who's the
little person I think is a proper name
Howard the Duck yeah he was Howard oh
that guy okay what are you talking about
yeah so he uh I just reconnected with
him too he's back in Toronto and um so
they read he was the one that actually
sold the cutting to an undercover cop
they must have brought or the duck sold
the cutting to an undercover cop yeah
yeah that's why he was arrested right so
Prince was arrested because he was the
owner it was his name on the lease yeah
and uh Jordan got arrested because he
was the actual one that did the um the
sale
and um
and uh and yes but they must have bought
the cutting and then brought it down
because they didn't buy it and then bust
them they bought it and then came back a
little bit later I mean Chris would be
the better ask this I mean I was smoking
a lot of pot back then Chris was spoken
up yeah dreadlock actually back then too
and um and they all did Jordan had
Jordan was like a little person but he
had dreads down to his ass he had like a
lip piercing you know he was yeah he was
uh he was uh that still trips me out
Howard the Duck bro he was only Howard
for like a very split yeah they tried to
remove a lot of it because he was
underage
I watched a documentary on it the other
day on the making of Howard the Duck it
was probably yeah they don't mention him
do they yeah oh yeah yeah
like they had hired him and he was a
little kid and yeah like they initially
shot a bunch of it with him but the
movements from the dummy they had to
move it remove them yeah but he didn't
tell if it was him or not because as you
know if you can you actually email me
that uh oh yeah yeah definitely kind of
it's way worth watching he was in
something modern too with like Colin
Farrell yeah
I'm Irish oh and Bruce is a great movie
I didn't know his name yeah that's him
that's Jordan French yeah and I I hate
to say but I and I joke with him too I
was like listen you know what you kind
of all look alike kind of thing because
there's so many people that times I'm
like [ __ ] I'm pretty sure that's Jordan
and like I don't know if it's not I have
to go look at the [ __ ] credits they
say oh it's not him you know you know
it's just um
and then Prozac back in the day uh which
was another one of the kind of
um I wouldn't call him a Klingon because
he was part of the he was have Nation
family right like and uh you know
obviously Pete rocks was and Pete Miller
and [ __ ]
um
uh there was all and there was a whole
bunch of a whole bunch of us but anyways
getting back to the bus
they they must have took the plant out
brought it they couldn't have analyzed
it they just maybe confirmed that it was
Cannabis and came back later that uh
afternoon and raided the place yeah we
didn't take any of the seeds didn't say
anything about the seeds busted them for
uh paraphernalia paraphernalia to 262.2
yeah and the um and for the uh
distribution
of uh controlled substance or back to
echin it would be called something
different back then I don't know if it
was a PPT like the uh possession for the
purpose but um anyways they you know
cleared out the store [ __ ] made a
mess of it basically tried to shut them
down and
um maybe they didn't realize Chris had
really supportive parents that had money
and believed their son not to be a
[ __ ] criminal like he was treated and
um
and
the Elmwood house we had a grow house on
Elmwood that everybody lived in except
for me because I actually I was
delivering meat at the time and
um
and you know they went there that's
where they busted Prozac and uh his
girlfriend at the time
and uh that was [ __ ] a [ __ ] show of
craziness because as soon as the cops
busted us the phone calls started going
everybody that was at the house was
literally like running to the basement
grabbing pots running out the backyard
throwing them Over The Back Fence into
an empty lot so by the time the police
got there there was literally a trail of
dirt up the stairs through the kitchen
out the back door and dirt still on the
top of the fence I bet yeah throwing it
over and they were just like they were
like yep not on the property not our
problems you know so um so that that was
the first bust
and then since they didn't say anything
about the the seeds Chris and Chris and
I Chris and I got a little bit more
serious about it and started to um
um
get a little bit more into the breeding
buying like you say showing those some
of these early uh scent to see packs and
stuff like that anybody that was going
over there mail us seeds right when did
we start buying seeds like you did you
tell me that you were the first in in
Canada I think Chris was the first
uh Seed Company in Canada because I
didn't know of anybody else that was
publicly
selling seeds right uh way before dark
enemy uh Mar uh Mike upmore yeah Mark
Henry sorry Dark Energy same thing dark
enemy yeah he yeah they removed the
whole chapter from my book because I was
so scared that he was gonna sue me yeah
he was kind of thing but he's a [ __ ]
douchebag
um and then
um
Mike up north at Crosstown he was early
in it
um I don't think Dom ever no Dom never
got into the seat thing
um out west there was nobody really
out west that we knew of
uh NPC wasn't even around at this point
in time so as far as I knew
yeah Chris Chris was the first one to
stick his [ __ ] Little Neck out there
to
um
to to spread the word right like to
overgrow the government so you know and
when they busted him the first time
they uh
they didn't do anything about the seeds
so we figured [ __ ] you know we we know
where the limits are so [ __ ] yeah the
balls of the wall let's get into the
seed [ __ ] business Let's Start
Spreading the seeds [ __ ] everywhere
you know and we started that's when I
was hired to work in the store
um and every Sunday I would do
um cultivation uh counseling whatever
the [ __ ] they wanted to call it with
NYPD yeah and uh and um
it was a uh
it was the point that you know we
started
getting noticed and we would start
getting people traveling to us and then
Chris
got on the internet and everything back
then was raw code and started producing
the uh seed menu online
yeah and it was [ __ ] it we were getting
more hits at one point if I remember
correctly he said we were getting more
hits than University of Western Ontario
that's funny I believe it right because
we had so many [ __ ] people that just
heard what you can buy cannabis seeds
and then you know because we were in the
newspaper sure they're gonna put that in
there so it gives us credibility of who
we are and what we're doing yep and then
uh when they came back the second time
they offered Chris a uh
a
uh a way out an option is yeah to to
um plead guilty to lesser charges and
drop the Constitutional Challenge and
um
and basically sell the seed sell the
pipes sell the bongs we don't care about
that you know and Chris came to us and
said it's up to you guys that I mean
we're we're a nation at this point in
time we were true we were treating
ourselves as a nation so we we had
Minister as minister of Agriculture and
then we had minister of Labor which was
Bill that took care of all the retail
store and all the um uh all the staff
and then we had minister of uh education
which was Sarah and she took care of the
library and the museum and uh and stuff
like that and Andrew was the Minister of
Defense he was our artist but he was the
angriest
he was he just had he was he's a
brilliant he's a school teacher Iran
which scares to share with me now and
his wife owns from Mars which is another
Staple in this town and um
you know so we were set up as a nation
kind of thing we were ready like they
call it as War on Drugs we were going to
take it as a War on Drugs so we formed
our nation and we were ready and uh and
this is like with our early 20s kids
right like you're all like in your early
20s this was in the 90s still this would
be late 90s okay yeah so we were uh
um
yeah it would have been like mid 90s
actually second time yeah because I
opened up organic in 97.
and
um
and we were and Chris has already
banished from Ontario by that time
and the thing was is after the first
raid
like I said we went balls of all to the
with the seat in the seed uh business
and that's when we started again if
you're going through Amsterdam sell it
send a seed so I can breed them and I
was doing what
um what the [ __ ] a big douchebag and
uh Amsterdam are you on no no he's he's
a nice douchebag okay
um douchebag uh so many uh no yeah but
he's the this is the most famous he
threatened to sue us as Legends for when
we were entering the cup with the uh he
thought
Neville fast no no no that and that was
always uh good people but we were using
Neville seeds yeah
hey Hank oh yeah so
Hank is the type of [ __ ] guy that
started doing what we were doing but but
being a dick about it I would I would
openly say Hey listen we got in 20 seeds
of skunk one from uh from the dronkers
and
I'm open breeding those and in the same
room we had an original Haze we had a
black domino we had all these other
strains so they're f1s this is what
you're gonna get when there's no
guarantees here but
you got your grown pot you know now
you're officially a pot grower and uh
they're they're good genetics they're
not you know from where I started my
genetic uh selection was from bags of
weed yeah you'd get [ __ ] and New York
we're not getting the [ __ ] best weed
we're getting [ __ ] Jamaican brick
like when I first started
we would buy nickel bags in East
Rockaway on B15 which I think is
actually in a Beastie Boys song but um
for five bucks for a nickel bag and ten
bucks for a dime bag and we would get
you know a third of it with seed it was
back when it was after people were
saying buying it by the lid right
there's like four fingers in a [ __ ]
you know in a sandwich bag yeah but we
were basically going and buying nickel
bags for
five bucks and you would get
a shitload of seeds in it and if it was
good pot
I would save the seeds right and I
didn't know what the [ __ ] it was I
didn't know what sativa was or indica
was I mean it's all [ __ ] Jamaican
[ __ ] [ __ ] weed or Colombian or or
whatever so when we got certain things
and people like oh it's Acapulco Gold
okay well I'm Gonna Keep the [ __ ]
seeds because I've heard that back in
the high reading in High Times magazines
so I started collecting those genetics
and I would bring them up to Canada and
I would
trade with uh with Chris right and he
would have his seeds from here London is
a [ __ ]
phenomenal place for cannabis for
multiple reasons one because we did have
the Perth County conspiracy that was a
lot of the draft Dodgers that came to
Canada
um
didn't want to go too far north and
we're right between Buffalo and Detroit
and if you look at the uh Geographic we
are surrounded by great lakes so we are
a glacial runoff that all the minerals
and everything got deposited so our soil
here that's why it was such a large
farming Community our soil is [ __ ]
awesome was awesome
right so since we were getting all that
uh and we're all grown pot in the fields
in the [ __ ] uh in the corn you know
we were growing some great [ __ ] pot
and if you got seeds in it which you
would indefinitely uh get something I
was happy as [ __ ] [ __ ] people like
pissed off like oh man it's got seasoned
I was like [ __ ] give me this no
that's a score bro
you smell the pot is it worth keeping
you know yeah give me some descriptions
grow it out see see if I could grow it
indoors you know
um if it came from around here I knew I
can grow it most likely Grow It Outdoors
because there wasn't very many people
growing back then if they were they were
using phototrons and uh yeah fluorescent
lightings and [ __ ] like that
we will the hid Community really wasn't
taking off uh it was in the
90s
in the early 90s I was having some
local kids go and steal [ __ ] lights
from in front of buildings yeah because
there were street lights or something
there were metal halides and HPS APS and
they were either 400s most likely all
400 there wasn't too many thousand Watts
back then yeah I think 250s and 400s yes
we were trying to um
we were growing pot like I said we were
[ __ ] cockroach we didn't know what we
were growing how we were growing it but
[ __ ] man it's it's a weed they call it
weed for a reason the more you do to it
the more you can [ __ ] it up so let it do
its thing give it food give it water
give it air
she's gonna give you back so
um by by bringing some of these Jamaican
strains from New York
and which I'm saying Jamaican which I
think it's going to be it was it was
brickweed so I knew most likely I should
say I didn't know back then but I
learned quickly that you can't grow any
of course here right just but we can
grow it indoors uh people didn't like it
because it was too big too scraggly too
long you know if anything they're
growing up here especially all the pot
that came from the the
60s and the 70s or the 60s when the
draft Dodgers were coming and then the
70s when their kids were getting you
know old enough or or something that
they were growing bad strains and I just
saw
one yeah so it's called Elmwood and it's
supposed to be this ancient genetic that
is supposed to be fire for outdoor
around here so I get a lot of
um
uh seeds
do you know any more history on Elmwood
or is that just basically no all I know
is I wanted the seed forever because I
heard of it yeah all I knew was like
when you get to Northern
London North London Lucan Exeter you
know a little bit further north maybe
not as far as
um not as far as own sound but maybe
kind of in that direction south of
Collingwood oh and South this was the
plant that everybody grew because it was
massive
uh was it the the the best don't know
but you know we would have people that
grew like this this strain is called
berry berry actually you know what this
is berry berry it's a uh and it was my
first centerfold in High Times oh what
what's in it it was just a [ __ ] seed
that a guy came in and says this is the
[ __ ] bomb
wow all right let's let's try it out we
grew it out it was had to be like an F1
uh because it was all over the place but
it would [ __ ] turn into something
like this I was just like
this is [ __ ] awesome and uh they
didn't have a [ __ ] name for it they
was like us taste smells like it might
be a blueberry salad I'm not calling it
blueberry yeah
all right it gets the uh gets the idea
you know what happens oh good
like I was curious when did you first
start uh or when did you first make
contact with high times and start
working with High Times uh
Kyle found me
um
Cushman yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah right I
like to put that out I actually sent him
an email because he's out in [ __ ] the
oakster damn [ __ ]
spreading the uh
the what is he call it now the plant
Chiropractics or something like that
it's super cropping right yeah and it's
an article that's was the first article
and it was like a Grower's interview or
whatever on me yeah and
I didn't make it up I was shown by some
growers in uh in this area and I made
sure it was in the article saying you
know it's [ __ ] phenomenal technique
for people that are growing indoors that
want to grow certain trains certain ways
sure and don't want to have [ __ ] 50
plants you can have
two plants three plants and still get
two pounds yeah you know not it's gonna
take a little bit longer but you know
certain strains obviously work better
for it
but it's manipulating and training
plants uh to grow in a in a certain way
and um
and so when Kyle came through
so short long so short the other thing
with him teaching this is like how did
you learn this like I want I want I
don't want him to acknowledge me but I
want him to acknowledge the lineage of
the history yeah of this technique sure
because people deserve
yeah yeah right especially because I
don't talk to either of them anymore and
the one guy's the biggest dick in this
[ __ ] town when it comes to anything
in general but he showed me this
technique that [ __ ] got me recognized
that's what they flew me to high to uh
the Cannabis Cup to talk about it was
supposed to talk about Canadian
cultivation techniques and it was super
crappy yeah and then they did the same
thing with Soma five years later or
something but so anyways
um Kyle was living in Detroit
at the time and
um he was coming from maybe Toronto or
something
and I he must have heard about uh either
the seeds
or me or
um something can you hear that beeping
curiosity yes what is it like diabetic
thing I don't know oh it's okay and
um
and uh he just popped in the shop one
day at Organics and struck up the
conversation and we hit it off and then
um
he would come back and I would uh him
and his boys we called the Detroit
danksters uh great Growers back there uh
Sally is still there Big John I think is
gone but
um that was that was his crew his boys
super super good super talented growers
in in Detroit
and um but they like the [ __ ]
Canadian pot like the they were coming
through London and I would invite them
basically who I was saying before the
Hampton Nation family yeah so I was like
listen if you guys want
you're paying 200 bucks an ounce but
you're paying us not Canadian you know
and um
I was happy with that they were [ __ ]
stoked because you know they're paying
three four hundred dollars an ounce in
Detroit at the time sure yeah and I just
said you know I'm selling to you you do
what the [ __ ] you want with it yeah we
didn't have vac sealers back then we
were just [ __ ] I was taking you know
freezer bags so taking Ziploc bags
throwing them in freezer bags and then
another freezer bag and then baking soda
or dryer sheets and then another [ __ ]
Ziploc yeah you know and the way that we
got it across was they would have a a
friend
come across go to Windsor to the casino
and the boys were like a guy would bring
his girlfriend not tell her what was
happening and they would go over the
night for the casinos the boys the
gangsters were paying for all of it yeah
dinner [ __ ] if you know the if they
stay the night do whatever and uh the
boys would go there
with a key to the uh to the guy's trunk
didn't even [ __ ] hide it like just
[ __ ] duffel bag in the [ __ ] back
yeah
um
and then would drive across the board
with nothing
and then the uh the next day they would
the buddy would wake up drive across got
all the paraphernalia from the focus
Casino spent the night had dinner you
know that's it didn't buy anything
didn't do anything to the casino [ __ ]
go through no problem yeah right we did
that for [ __ ] years
and then I found out just a few years
ago that uh when they were uh went
across to come by come back here they
were asked if they were coming to see me
by name oh quarter oh and they were just
like okay like yeah he's incredible to
like turn around you know like the the
winds were crossing Detroit yeah coming
from Windsor
um and now I had a uh a run-in
with the Windsor border coming back from
a photo shoot
uh four High Times where I met with Kyle
um and the gangsters
and oh God another photographer [ __ ]
most I think the most famous uh
photographer back in the 90s to early
2000s
God damn it he was there dude he was
shooting also but anyways I was meeting
with Kyle so I brought
all my photos it was right after I got
back from Switzerland so I had all my
Swiss photos I had my Amsterdam photos
um and I got
I got this in the early 2000s then
because you said yes because I was in
Switzerland in 2000
so Switzerland didn't really get going I
don't think I was at the cup and I think
I did the cup in
no I did the cup
quit smoking pot two every two thousand
we've been two thousand and um
so when I that's what I was meeting I
would imagine that's what I was meeting
Kyle for because I brought all my photos
uh which always meant pictures which I
just basically use as proofs and then
slides because that's what the magazine
wanted and then video because I wanted
to uh document
the shoots yeah so when they pulled me
and I was driving my girlfriend at the
time had a
1969 Volkswagen bus
and I had
crazy dreads that were probably just
about my shoulder length but they were
still just finishing developing so they
were all over the [ __ ] place I was
like you know what I'm not Crossing with
anything definitely would never cross
with any [ __ ] pot or anything like
that and um got pulled over
and they said you know we were searching
the vehicle sure I guess I got a pot
leaf on my [ __ ] shirt and they said
do you have any drugs on you I was like
listen this I tell you my name's Pete
young I'm from London Ontario I own
organic traveler which is a marijuana
[ __ ] uh paraphernalia shop
and I can't make it any easier than that
like no I'm dumb not stupid nothing yeah
illegal kind of thing and uh they said
okay well we're gonna search through the
vehicle and make you stand out stand in
front
and I watched the guy go around to the
back and he's a younger custom agent and
he holds up the first slide and you just
see his eyes go [ __ ] this big oh I
bet he thought he found the motherload
yeah I was like ah [ __ ] so I walk around
and I approach him and said Hey listen
you know
not sure how the law is here I kind of
have an idea that you're allowed to look
through anything but there's people's
likeness in these photos that I do not
have model releases for so legally I
can't show them to anybody right and he
explained yes you're right you have
absolutely no [ __ ] rights here uh
we're allowed to look at every [ __ ]
photo every negative for pornographic
material
and he's like do you have any
pornographic material it's like [ __ ] no
I was like you it's all pot it's like
it's me pot my dog and pot me my dog and
pot I was like there might be a couple
titties yeah maybe models that are
holding cannabis and stuff like that but
nothing pornographic and he's like okay
I had
[ __ ] not hundreds but thousands if not
maybe ten thousand photos negatives in
that van
because I brought everything yeah
because that was a money cow for me for
High Times they loved it they and I
didn't get paid for all the pictures a
lot of it came into the grow America
because Kyle needed photos to put into
grow America and I say okay I'm gonna
donate this many but you're paying me
for this many right like if I got a
centerfold I got 600 bucks if they got a
full page I got 300 bucks [ __ ] so it uh
it made sense for me to do this so
anyways maybe that's you know he opened
up another box and literally thousands
of photos and he's looking at him and
it's like pot and I was like oh you want
to see some really nice ones I start
pulling out pictures from from uh
Switzerland which is Fields yeah yeah
not just like a backyard full but a
[ __ ] hectares or yeah yeah and I was
like oh and he's like where's that I
said well that's Switzerland somewhere
in Amsterdam I was like summer here some
are there kind of thing yeah never said
they're from Canada never said they're
from the states kind kind of thing and
he just uh opened up another box and
he's like is it all part it's like every
single pitcher and here's pie he's like
why do you have all this and luckily at
the same weekend they were having the
one of their uh
big Rave convention party kind of thing
I forget what they called it they had a
specific name and I was like oh I was
coming back from there and we set up a
booth to show people to use cannabis
because you don't have to have it tested
for [ __ ] you know bad drugs right and
they had them at these at these concerts
or at these parties where if you got a
pill they would go and they'd scratch
off a little bit of it and they would
test it and say yeah it is MDMA or it's
you know some it's some speed or
whatever they would be able to tell you
um maybe not what's exactly in it but
they could more or less tell you what's
not in it right so I just made up that
[ __ ] literally on the whim that I
was coming from that and I had all the
pictures that's just put out on display
to show the show kids not the you know
smoke pot don't [ __ ] do drugs don't
do hard drugs
they bought it they liked it I [ __ ]
gave him one of my [ __ ] credit cards
said Hey listen I offer uh 25 off any
officer so if you want everyone or you
want to pipe a bong anything like that
you know just show them your badge you
get [ __ ] you get discounts so that
was one of the Techno festivals in
Detroit yeah yeah and it was they were
big back then
I mean I wasn't trying to interrupt or
anything like that but one of the one of
the ways that we used to regularly go
into into Canada
um that um
was we used to go like in especially in
the Detroit scene with Windsor being
right there there was parties that were
thrown in Canada yeah right and there
was a lot of border crossings well they
learned like what hippies and ravers
looked like and they didn't like them so
we used to drive across the border there
wearing like Dockers and polo shirts and
all normal and all of our like real
clothes were like stuffed in the trunk
yeah of what we normally looked like
because we were trying to go back and
forth and look like the biggest nerds
ever yeah right because if you you know
if you looked a certain way you're gonna
get you're gonna get checked out on a
certain level and I just didn't have
that option I had [ __ ] dreads and you
know like I I did the opposite I was
just like I'm driving a Volkswagen bus
okay I got a pot leaf on my shirt and I
got [ __ ] dreads now I'm born in New
York
and I live in Canada so I have a
passport for both
they can't deny me wherever I go if I'm
going to the states no matter what I
look like they can't deny me because I'm
only using my Canadian my U.S passport
I'm gonna come back to Canada I'm not
telling them that I have a passport for
the states or vice versa I show them the
[ __ ] Canadian passport right right
can't deny me I know I look like
somebody that you don't want to let in
your country but I'm a citizen [ __ ] off
you don't have a choice so it makes a
big difference yeah I like that how do
you know you're in the States now
yeah okay all right I mean I uh you know
it um you know I have uh I I have I have
an uncle that does the same thing he has
Brazilians citizenship because and he's
he's American as well and so he uh he
when he goes into Brazil he uses the
Brazilian and he comes back into the U.S
he uses America so it looks like he
never goes anywhere but he's yeah
constantly you know and he just uses you
know and so but yeah I just I just
remember especially in the Windsor area
because Detroit was right there
um as as the years in the 90s went on
they definitely started
um you know I don't know if you want to
like what what you know profiling if you
will oh you know he had an image of like
what hippies looked like or what herbs
Smugglers look like or what ravers
looked like or you know what each one of
these groups was likely to have on them
or whatever you know so well I always I
always tell people that you know I I
kind of followed a certain
mathematical equation for lack of better
terms right the police know that what to
look for right if
um if you're in this industry
so there's going to be uh 90 of our
community
is susceptible to getting busted because
of the way they look the way they smell
the way they walk or talk right sure
it's five percent on either side the
five percent of the people in this in
the movement or industry that never
leave their house they don't go to the
grow shop themselves they send somebody
to send somebody to go buy the
fertilizer go buy their seeds go buy
what they want and then that person
whoever purchases has no idea what who
the person is that place the order kind
of thing that person is never going to
get busted they I mean it's going to be
very unlikely that they get busted and
then the other five percent is where I
fall in I stand on the street corner
with a [ __ ] six foot pot leaf with my
dreads out in my Volkswagen going I'm a
[ __ ] pot guy like they don't want
that they they know who I am they know
what I'm doing
there's ninety percent of the other
people are out there are susceptible to
fill their quota
why the [ __ ] do we want to drag in the
dreadlock who's going to have the
newspapers there so they're like we'll
leave him alone so I'm in that five
percent on the opposite side because I
literally had a six foot pot leaf in my
front window I literally did have pot
plants growing in my front window and
for a certain time my whole front window
was full of [ __ ] peyote and San
Pedros that's so funny and didn't you
also do stuff like call the newspaper
and they would run an article where you
take them to like a cornfield oh no that
was a that was uh like CBC and [ __ ] I
brought news agencies to my my field my
crops let me throw in a question before
I'd lose the threat of it when you met
Kyle did he have a strawberry cough then
did you ever hear anything yeah
strawberry the cough came out of
Connecticut right yeah so those boys do
you know who those guys are uh I know of
them I don't know okay no but I know
basically you know this is another thing
with Hank douchebag
um the uh the cough they named it them
like Kyle [ __ ] said you know it's
makes them cough it smells like
strawberries whatever the [ __ ] deal
was so uh Kyle was with uh HT at the
time
um
and
uh he met the cough guys when I was
still hanging around with him
okay um never got to meet him they were
different direct I was actually I'd have
worn out for my arrest in Connecticut so
I wasn't going to go to Connecticut yeah
no reason to be hanging out in
Connecticut yeah there's no reason to do
a [ __ ] Connecticut
fine it was a speeding ticket so yeah it
was 145 mile per hour speeding ticket so
I never I never went back and I was like
you know whatever but no reason told me
about it and it seemed like a great
strain now I had strawberry Diesel and I
was like what what strawberry are they
using kind of thing like you know is is
did you give them my strawberry by
chance like you know what what you know
and I never really got down that uh I
never went down that rabbit hole to
figure out what it was but from what I
understand from what Kyle told me he's
just like they hit the money shot with a
[ __ ] uh with a plant that produced
this [ __ ] fire pot it was [ __ ]
phenomenal and um
and
[ __ ] do you know what was in the
strawberry diesel you were running at
the time
no no no just because it was that was it
was brought to me as yeah because the
the cough itself did start in
Connecticut and I got introduced to it
it made its way out to Colorado through
people who went from Connecticut to
Colorado yeah um Kyle has always been a
little bit [ __ ] uh you know he dances
around origin stories because it's like
one of the things that because you
worked for High Times he got pretty well
known for you know yeah and so as he's
tried to become like a can of celebrity
some of the origin stories of the things
that he's known for he's gotten pretty
uh you know pretty vague well I mean
because the [ __ ] douchebag he sold
the cough to [ __ ] Hank
right that's why he's the Strawberry
Cough seed was produced yeah is because
[ __ ] and I don't know if the
Connecticut boys got even a piece of it
right I probably didn't
um because and like when when Kyle and I
when I dissolved my friendship with him
was we were in Amsterdam in the middle
of one of these squares me [ __ ]
screaming at him about uh him
backstabbing me kind of thing over the
common story yeah and I was just like
what the [ __ ] is wrong with you like uh
you know he's a [ __ ] skinny little
Jewish kid from New York he's from New
York right yeah yeah
and uh and
I just like I I know you did it to the
cough boys but you didn't know them
right they were just some [ __ ] kids
that you [ __ ] met that called you
because they have some [ __ ] great
[ __ ] pot he got
um
Kyle got famous because of the Kyle
Special Blend [ __ ] pitcher I remember
yeah the hell's the name of the
photographer
I don't remember the names of the
photographers oh I will remember from
for a bit I use a super [ __ ] nice guy
super great guy
um
and that pissed me off and then uh he
tried to
um
he tried to put like I was finished my
first tour in in Switzerland and I was
contemplating if I should go back or not
because Steve is a hard person to
[ __ ] work with they want right from
this town right okay so
um
he I didn't know him when he lived here
but I met him through Steve
before Legends yeah
um
I don't know who I met first actually I
think I don't know if I met I don't know
who I met them all around the same time
I think
right and they were all out in Vancouver
um red and jair he called himself Kermit
for a while
um were Brokers uh Growers not not
breeding yeah Legends started in
Switzerland right like yeah it started
with the uh the Louie and um
and that was just a you know a freak
um
thing that happened with the Ortega
that's what he said yeah yeah and uh but
so anyways yeah so
I know them is Steve
's [ __ ] Wick is [ __ ] this [ __ ]
long yeah and if he if you if he's
pissed off like
when we were in Amsterdam and um
what [ __ ] out this artwork sorry my
memory is [ __ ] now but um is this the
fast spear story no fast fear is my
[ __ ] story the [ __ ] he took my
medal because of my fast fast fatty was
a strain that Hank threatened to sue us
over yeah right because he went back
Hank came through Switzerland saw heard
that we were going to enter all these
strains and he's like well I worked on
these strains so they're mine he went
back to [ __ ] Amsterdam and registered
all the [ __ ] names and when we showed
up he at the dinner
right before uh High Times because all
the with all the people yeah he came up
to our table said Hey listen if you're
thinking about entering these strains
uh I'm going to sue you unless you get
and so red had to go up make a side deal
like okay we're going to give you a
percentage but the [ __ ] douchebag he
wrote down fast fatty
I brought fast spear those guys hated
fast beer [ __ ] didn't want anything
to do they were all Ortega they were all
big [ __ ] uh Indica freaks yeah yeah
because they didn't [ __ ] work in the
field you know red did a little bit but
I was there for [ __ ] months you know
Papa Bear came out there sat in the
[ __ ] hammock smoke joints and [ __ ]
with you know waited and thought he was
the [ __ ] the king we uh We've read
sweet tooth yes um strawberry blonde
um the Louie
I figured also we just basically we had
a uh we had
30 maybe 600 watts in a room
mainly we were just doing cuttings
because the company is called Mr hemp
that Steve was working with and it was
just it was right after they got busted
for the selling pot to a minor but we
still had the uh we sailed the facility
in lagano and um we ended up uh just
taking a mail and smacking it against
the fan in the corner yeah it pollinated
the whole like he couldn't barely see
through the [ __ ] room and um so some
of my seeds here someplace called the
blonde bastard and the blonde bastard
was uh
was a strawberry blonde crossed
um
and they didn't want to do anything with
it so I ended up uh keeping it
let's see what was the uh strawberry
blonde do you remember what was in there
see this is
what I remember
with Steve is he he had a whole bunch of
strains that were were good and I like
um this here is uh uh big funk
wait which was one of his trains and
then uh the strawberry uh sorry the
Sweet Tooth number four gotcha
I'm pretty sure and again Steve would be
better
to understand it and I think part of
this is
um correct and part of it might be
just my interpretation of it but I
believe that he had a bunch of strains
that were
uh or he had he had one strain or he had
a few strains that he thought were
[ __ ] great okay and he found that
[ __ ] resinous blueberry male he
crossed everything with it now
it was my understanding is when he got
the um the the sweet pink grapefruit
cutting yeah in California two cuttings
came up to Vancouver Vic who I'm pretty
sure that's the guy's name not sure what
he was it didn't get the best reputation
with the boys yeah
um one cut and Steve got one cut are you
talking about Vic High yes yeah okay
yeah so but I don't know who he is like
yeah he's no longer with us okay well
you're good really clear yeah right but
uh I have a feeling
um
Steve took that blueberry mail and the
sweet and the the sweet pink grapefruit
and
crossed him
and then grew out a bunch of this
different seeds and
one became Sweet Tooth one became big
big treat one became you know this one's
called Big Funk but that's not his
Original Seed big treat was one of them
um
uh something bud I'm I know I haven't
seen someplace I just don't know where
the [ __ ] they are
um
but uh I have a feeling that Steve ended
up with
um
a bunch of different phenos of that
those two strains and that's what he
started building his catalog off of yeah
and then you know the Sweet Tooth which
was one of his more favorite I know he
wanted to back cross it
um maybe to that same blueberry
or to the grapefruit and that kind of
took different lines
and stuff like that yeah so he had the
uh he had two different shishka berries
yeah the red line
um
the yellow yeah and uh you know so I
don't know
you know did that come from a dip
because that you know he was pretty
famous for growing these big huge long
[ __ ] Spears yeah right there's a
picture of his wife holding him and
they're like [ __ ] three feet long of
just straight colas kind of yeah you
know and um I think you know so I have a
feeling that maybe
the um
the seeds were all from
the same
uh same crosses but just different
phenotypes yeah that he
started
creating new lines and uh I think the
sweet tooth and the shishka berry were
the ones that really stood out
um
the strawberry blonde the big tree the
plum bud
Plum Bud that I just saw that it was uh
yeah that was uh and I know I have that
too okay I'm sure I have all these
[ __ ] seeds someplace man I'm blind as
[ __ ] though Plum I see Plum crossed a
mighty might that was West Coast Seeds
but yeah there's the plum bud
it described it a little bit saying that
it smelled very fruity but it didn't go
into detail
no what the hell is this Gabriella
Island I got yeah
I wouldn't be able to see that
collection I bet you have some cool
stuff in there that I have no idea like
it because I I keep track of everything
but I just write it down and not think
about it anymore
you know like this pungent skunk from
Legends right like
what is that I don't even [ __ ] we
even sold that strain right you didn't
no no and it was just one of the
genetics that you know we grew out that
we liked
um this is from Khmer
what the hell is this [ __ ] stream
calz calzar
colors are so that's a C4 it's like a
Cali or calories I like the C4 it didn't
produce worth of [ __ ] but it [ __ ] was a
good train so like Calio shiske Berry or
something like that yeah
so again you can't if I even bring up
that name with Papa Bear forget about it
like a [ __ ] it's like with red and
Steve you just can't mention and those
guys were
Steve like did you know him before you
got invited to go to the Alps no I
didn't um I knew him before then
um
first time I did opium I was in his
[ __ ] at one of these places [ __ ]
freaking out in his hot tub
um
I didn't know how the [ __ ] I met him I
mean I was a pot guy here he was from
here he it probably got out there
through Hillary
um
and he how did you get the invitation to
to go to Switzerland
yeah Steve's a picky guy I mean you had
to have done something to leave an
impression
I remember you told me that [ __ ] guy
paid me 2100 a week to [ __ ] go there
Jesus yeah I was like not bad and then
it dropped down to and then [ __ ] that's
Steve right I didn't get paid that much
yeah I paid a [ __ ] pot in Switzerland
as a Canadian they're like you know oh
[ __ ] the industry is not what it was
and you know if I can I'm I brought all
the [ __ ] uh pot to Amsterdam from
Switzerland that's for the for the cop
right yeah and what kind of you know I'm
a little Bent by it now I guess I always
have been but they were all Ortega they
were not one and they didn't want
anything to do with the [ __ ] uh
um
um fast fear yeah right I was all fast
fear because I was in the field every
day working I couldn't smoke Ortega I
[ __ ] it would puddle me yeah well I
would uh I was all about the [ __ ]
night queen and the fast beer and now
these strains are all strains from uh
Neville yeah these three seeds came from
uh little Eddie douchebag sorry I don't
like a lot of people which one Eddie
Eddie which one
my Dutchman no oh oh oh nobody likes him
yeah but um so the deal was he was hired
by Mr hemp at the same time that Steve
was and he brought all these seeds that
Neville owed him the story was Neville
old him owed him a bunch of money
and instead of paying him he found a
[ __ ]
box of seeds in the back of a freezer
when he had to jump ship
and gave him to Ed as payment partial
payment whatever so those seeds ended up
in Switzerland they ended up in the
field and we had that's where the
Neville that's where the uh the night
Queen the fast fatty fast beer or take
Devil's Haze probably goes from there I
don't think I don't think we had
Neville's Hayes in our field we had
strains I never heard of right these are
all strains no one's ever heard of
gotcha because they were they were out
of the freezer they were a box that
Neville sold to somebody I meant to talk
to Neville about this before he passed
that and it was like
five years ago six years ago I had
another a new contact
UM through the Mr hemp seed thing
and uh I never got a chance to talk to
him about it what do you want to ask him
uh it was more about the history of this
box of seats okay and what year was a
box of seeds that's why I'm not sure but
I could tell you that they were still
viable in
in
um
2000 yeah 99 probably uh the story was
that
um somebody ordered these seeds
never picked them up
so they got forgotten about in the back
of the freezer when
when time came for him to thaw out the
freezer for whatever reason he passed
them on to Ed
for again what I was told for an
outstanding debt
and uh Ed broaden Switzerland and Steve
plant him and Steve planted them and
then Ed had a falling out with Peter
with Miss with with Mr hemp and he was
gone and I was brought in to replace him
and I they actually even gave me his
phone I still had his phone
when I got there which I think is one of
the reasons why because it was still in
his name and I was calling Canada and
all over the [ __ ] I was sitting in a
field in the middle of the South yeah
why not I was like [ __ ] it like I don't
particularly care for the guy anyways
yeah and um so that's why that's what I
heard did you uh did you have any old
um early Pearl Early Girl silver Pearl
stuff yo yeah back in the back in the
early days of Scentsy yeah
um and then see this is the other thing
that again you know we hear so many
stories and you know regardless of who
the stories are from you know we went
out to dinner with the drunkers a few
times
um uh
uh sativa sisters
um
God Jesus beautiful girl the hell she's
out of the business no she's still in
the business a little bit
um the Amsterdam Seed Company
uh okay
they were out of Canada though right
yeah out of BC uh yeah I have their
catalogs Karen Karen Karen was a blonde
and then big tit with the black gray
hair that
sold everybody out
um I forget her name she's kind of still
in these did you say big tit yeah she's
got big titties
she was uh Karen's partner in the
Amsterdam she's Infamous out in the in
the in the uh uh scene industry what
were you gonna say about the Pearl and
the okay so back back then
um
when it wasn't the Scentsy Bank it was
just the seed bank yeah yeah right so
that was before Neville sold this stuff
to Scentsy it was just yeah yeah so it
would have been Neville now I thought it
was a partnership between Neville
and Ben that was uh that was adversy
Bank
I thought that was that's what brought
the end of the seed bank I thought it
was that when Scentsy seed started
I don't what was it the bus that that uh
made Neville sell to us to drunkers I
don't know I don't know I just know that
basically
the story almost basically the story was
told that Neville was the breeder for
Santi seed bank he did breed for them
for a little bit so but you know it was
all of his genetics yes that he was
breeding yeah so when when the first
um
catalogs were coming out of the sentency
bank you had early Pearl you had silver
Pearl in them
we loved it because again we were
dealing with genetics that were
um
from Neville like these were these were
the original [ __ ] strains like I mean
other than like the skunk and the
Northern Lights yeah you know we were um
oh I just had the name too
uh
uh nuts
damn it I
there was a coffee shop who's who
entered the sweet tooth
um before Steve was that gray area or
someone no it wasn't great Bluebird
Blueberry Cafe yeah who owned that do
you know katsu Bluebird I don't know who
owned that
[ __ ] I think it was bluebird
I should look it up but anyways that's
the one that Steve tried it was gonna
Fireball because uh we're talking about
like Steve's [ __ ] temper yeah like it
was Ariane and um and Luke and everybody
else that was trying to and the drunkers
are trying to calm him down because
they and it wasn't bluebird
they entered the can they entered Sweet
Tooth in the Cannabis Cup
and without Steve's knowledge or
permission
oh man
it was it was a coffee shop though it
was no it was a city it was both they
had a coffee shop see but they were also
a seed company Barney Electronics
Barney's Farm Barney's because Barney
made it Barney's sold they still sell
sweet too yeah so it was funny but see
the the [ __ ] had done it the uh that
guy's like [ __ ] from what we were
told again from the other guys
big [ __ ]
um Netherlands Mafia yeah yeah yeah
Jerry yeah and they were like you I was
telling Steve you can't do it if you go
there you know it's he's gonna kill you
it's going to be [ __ ] you [ __ ]
because Steve
is a big guy yeah I've never seen him
fight but I wouldn't want to see him
fight because he would fight in a
[ __ ] heartbeat yeah and um you know
so
um
but yeah fighting fighting the mob is
not like no it's just taking it he was
going to go in there and literally Fire
Bomb the [ __ ] place like he was like
[ __ ] [ __ ] Gary sucks [ __ ] right so so
anyways um so again this is again where
you know
we're we're like [ __ ] the elders uh
sitting in the teepee trying to
regurgitate stories and we kind of go by
what we're what we hear and what we're
told kind of thing some of us get to
witness it firsthand some of us hear it
regurgitated once or twice and we never
know so that's why like with like I say
with those seeds from you know the this
fast spear this night Queen you know
this fast fatty these and there's a
whole bunch of other [ __ ] strains in
there that you know I was I was told
this story and it anybody that I reach
out to and and hear pieces from they
kind of connect a little bit they kind
of sound similar so about them being
seeds from Neville and stuff like that
yeah it makes sense for the time most
times it was based on his his one of the
things that Neville mentions a bunch is
that it seems like 90 of what he made he
never released
in the sense that he had strains that he
liked that got put on the catalogs but
he'd make hybrids of all kinds of things
right and only a tiny percentage of
those things ever got offered up an
actual sale
we wouldn't um
we wouldn't uh breed I wouldn't breed
anything without somebody else's
permission
unless it was a publicly you know
um uh available anybody can buy seeds
from like sexy you know I would breed
and not think about now with Luke I
wouldn't do that because because you
know he's very particular well and he's
he was small and same as uh
um you know so the small one same as
Soma yeah um
I wouldn't uh I wouldn't read any of his
stuff unless I would you know I kind of
asked him kind of thing and even with
this like with all my genetics my my uh
B-93
I don't want to I can't sell that strain
like people I was offered a lot of money
for it I'm working on a deal right now
to trade somebody for it but it's gonna
be and it's just because I want uh Sam
skunk
um
um I have an opportunity to get the one
of the original skunk one Cuts back oh
nice when we were and Sean you I think
you in town with uh [ __ ] that
epileptic [ __ ] kid yeah yeah which
one tell you so this is just this kid
that um Frills was yeah so he was
brought to me by the TCC the Toronto
Compassion Center uh said listen we have
this kid
uh he's uh he's a good grower
um but he's mixed up with the wrong
people we need to get him out of this
town can you take them brought him and
his mom and his sister to London set him
up in an apartment set up a garden the
whole bit turned out to be a great
Gardener
um
but it went to his head and then of
course yeah that that original story
never finished I think he's still
dwelling in that reality where
he was always a go super big kind of guy
and then getting in in business with
really bad people and it would always go
very very very bad out west like as soon
as he left here because it happened over
and over and over you know and like he
would always be like like when when he
would get [ __ ] destroyed she'd be
like I'm never growing again I'm never
growing again and then he's like buying
or he's involved in these like giant
farm chicken coops filled you know like
it's you know when I when I met him we
he was
because of his and his mom I loved his
mom and his sister
um but they had no control so they would
uh we would grow he would grow a bunch
of pop for the center I would give them
a receipt and then I would give them a
certain amount every week or every month
because if I gave all the money to Tilly
which I did in a few times he went out
and literally bought 200 worth of candy
he's like I was like where's the money
you were supposed to pay your hydro bill
oh [ __ ] man he's like he's literally had
bags of [ __ ] candy and his mom you
know well not just that but I remember
the dude would be like stretches long
stretches of time where all he would eat
is like lobster dipped in butter or
something like that you know like he was
just that type of like it was always
extreme
bending like like uh crazy that was
after me because I didn't allow that
then he he started hanging out with uh
eggboy yeah yeah right they got [ __ ]
busted in my truck yeah with 480 plants
or something and I get sucked into it my
dad got sucked into it because it was
his truck you know and I was just like
and then they drop off a vehicle because
we switch vehicles turns out to be
stolen right so I'm driving around in a
stolen [ __ ] Jeep Cherokee oh that's
uh that's a really [ __ ] douchebags
but that's skunk one that's the whole
reason of story he had
we had him growing the black domino and
the skunk one and this skunk one I had
again it just landed in my lap through
all these connections I would imagine it
would have came from the early Scentsy
days yeah but it was that [ __ ] real
skunk and it was a fine Dutchman I think
it was
is his name Scott does that mean
Dutchman's Eddie Eddie right yeah and it
was a common name yeah so he was
supposed to be one of the original skunk
uh sellers of the scenes yeah yeah and
so he had like some of the more pure uh
his were called the pure yeah you know
what I just saw that here too yeah you
have an old Scentsy skunk one pack in
there you go no I have the old cure oh
yeah the pure I still have an old attack
up here myself yeah probably not as old
as yours though
um
not so missed out on some of the seed
pack showing you missed out bro I did
yeah there's some cool stuff can I just
lose you I just hit a button on my
[ __ ] TV no you're good black actually
black domino was out of anything that I
personally popped from Amsterdam as far
as seeds that were available to the
public that was the nicest thing I I
personally found do you remember the uh
the description they were like it would
leave a man feeling whipped and
something like the description that the
that the boys put in there uh yeah
full-blooded Indica with large bracks
we'll soon have you on your knees and
begging for more yes harsh overpowering
lady simply gushes sticky resin to which
most men seem to have a Fatal Attraction
a word of warning this powerful compact
Indica has had devastating effect on
many a man leaving them apparently
beaten and whipped with a strange smile
on their faces not so usually looks like
this after he gets done with the
conversations with me though yeah yeah I
love that kind of stuff and uh me too
when we uh when Ron was doing the uh
Canadian cannabis cups here in town and
we had the Red Devil I kind of stole
that kind of Mantra from from that to
describe the Red Devil yes making up a
bunch it was a [ __ ] fire strange it
was great strain was a bunch of [ __ ]
that I was saying but um I love that
that's the first time I saw a red devil
I believe it was Greenhouse that came
out with that or at least they were the
first people to sell public seeds of it
yeah
I ended up getting was from a alcoholic
guy that was a good grower from around
here
um
but uh
um what is this
Red Devil yeah Greenhouse it's in your
catalog and uh yeah Afghani Afghanistan
and I've always wondered if if like
Shanti doesn't still we've I've never
known it but like if if you know if he
tries to sell a version of that based on
you know because he sells devil but
they've never explained what the [ __ ] it
is right yeah I heard that too I heard
about the devil but I don't know if it's
uh and again right now was it cutting
brought to me sure and
um
it we just had a [ __ ] great funeral
of it and
I was friends with [ __ ] crazy Ron
that uh hidden Jungle which was a seed
company in uh one of the original seed
companies actually it was before iron
iron seeds
interesting but uh but uh yeah we
entered the Red Devil in his Cannabis
Cup and at one first place
you know I fixed it but did you keep
much Willy Jack stuff around
no yeah he was the one that was doing
like a lot of early girl and black
dollar Repros black white
um
he was from around here too right but he
did his breeding and he was from Ontario
but he did his breeding in Montreal is
that no it's Willie Jack yeah that's
what we're talking about okay Willie
Jack yeah did you ever see Willie Jack
how he did his [ __ ] breeding I know
nothing about Willie Jack I get a lot of
questions about him yeah I don't want to
like literally I did a lot with the
quebeci company that was his [ __ ] guy
um I know again I can't remember his
name but he did a Cannabis Cup there as
well
and uh Willie would basically in his
backyard along his fence line
again this is what I was told he would
grow a male and a female and then five
feet ten feet apart another a different
male and different female sounds about
right yeah so if you were buying a seed
and his seed was 30 bucks for yeah
right yeah but he was saying oh this is
Northern Lights oh this is this strain
this is this train it's like no it's not
he has no [ __ ] clue it might have
some of that in it be honest with the
people you only charge you thirty
dollars a [ __ ] 10 pack yeah you don't
need to make [ __ ] up yeah you know
[ __ ] tell people that this is what I
did this so I breed it I'm only charging
30 bucks you know
but I didn't I didn't like him I didn't
think I thought he was kind of dishonest
well yeah I mean if that's if that's how
he was doing his [ __ ] it's obvious that
like you know the cross-pollination is
gonna occur you know
um that's that's not cool
so
um what's up what are some of the
posters behind you before I forget
um
oh this is a chemo I remember I've seen
before that the uh the one chemo and now
I think
it's the
[ __ ] I don't even remember I know one of
them went pink and I'm pretty sure it
was the Ottawa
cut that went pink could be the UBC one
but basically the auto one one is
probably just a UBC
uh that was poly this is a spice of life
strain tube I don't know who the [ __ ]
Eric is
a hurricane
um so this is uh so let me just let me
get the C pack back in there
uh and I don't mind sending a bunch of
these seeds if you want to [ __ ] try
like yeah me and a me and a good friend
will try reproducing any of the pop
happily
it's so [ __ ] cool UBC chemo all right
chemo poster yeah it was a [ __ ]
centerfold in iPhone
I'm just gonna pick this up so this here
is
where's the camera there we go there we
go so this here is the berry berry oh
nice uh so and it actually says it in
the upper corner yeah yeah and then uh
sorry I have to try to get the so this
here is the chemo that it might be the
Ottawa because it's pink pistol yeah I
think I think it is and I can you know
this is what I've been told but it's
super nice because it's super pink yeah
it's beautiful
um I I have tons of [ __ ] photos of it
dude I see you know I told people for
years like chemo sounded cool but like
and everybody always said they liked it
but the name always turned me off yeah
well again the theory the the history
was like the G13 yeah that it came out
of California and it was used uh for
medical patients that were going to
chemo right and then uh maybe the cut
came out a piece out of um California
might have been called something else
yeah got to UBC they were using it maybe
for medical uh for chemo patients that's
how it got its name but I was just told
that uh yeah it got its name from uh
could be used okay so this also this was
another centerfold it's [ __ ] it's hard
to see because of the uh yeah what is
this one that's also berry berry and um
yeah so you can't really see it it may
be better that way but
um it was like it was a go-to strain for
me for a long time yeah because it was
just uh it was so
um
about this chat is because it we wildly
bounce around there's like all kinds of
of things that I think of that I want to
chat about and then by the time that I
wanted to merged on to some different
year totally different people whatever
it's amazing in that regard because
we're covering so much ground but uh
yeah yeah you said you're friends with
red right yeah yeah we've chatted with
red that's awesome and that's with the
fast spear that's in uh with his no
shirt on this [ __ ] guy he showed up
to the field I'll see if I can find a
picture of this can you take a picture
of that later and send it to me yeah
send it to him so there was Matt there
was this uh we I used to go to these
Harvest festivals in the early 2000s
yeah and there was this guy Matt knows
who he is there was this guy chip
um that started Royal gold Matt and he
had just been out to Switzerland I think
it was an 01 maybe or something and so I
remember the first time I saw pictures
like you were mentioning of those fields
and hectors and huge greenhouses and all
that he came back with all these photos
on his computer
of all these people in Switzerland that
were just starting to blow it up and at
the time it was the largest yeah
they were doing it under aromathery so
we had this is one of a this is a field
here one of the fields with me let's see
oh yeah Jesus yeah and uh it was for uh
aromatherapy
that's kind of a that's us harvesting
some of them kind of I remember way back
then when you were out there somebody
showed me a picture because you weren't
around and it was you sitting in an
armchair oh and you had flower up to
your knees yeah all you've seen in the
frame was like flour up to your knees
yeah it was so funny and for the young
people watching now that are like in
their in their 20s looking at this and
they're thinking yeah that's right there
we did we had terracotta floors and we
didn't have enough place to hang it so
if you the funniest thing is on the on
the table there there's only uh two sets
of scissors
we didn't know it we we had to harvest
all the tops so we went through the
field harvested all the tops brought
them back and we're like we can't even
hang them there's not enough to say so
we just laid them all terracotta and we
just went in and rotated them every day
and that's uh me sitting in the chair I
can I mean for people like Matt was
saying for people that are younger I
think Switzerland for the most part was
the first time that it was like us
seeing like non-land race type pictures
of you know people actually growing on
that large of a scale yeah
it's so bad like people are used to
seeing big CBD grows here is what I'm
saying like people our age are used to
seeing these massive hemp pros and stuff
but people during that era you would
never [ __ ] see this so it was really
it was a really unique time it was a
very special time and for that era like
people in the U.S seeing stuff like this
was mind-blowing at the time yeah see
this year that's we had a company in
town called novaks and you're supposed
to take your bag into different parts of
the world and uh enter it in a contest
right yeah and I basically got the most
votes but they can't they because it
wasn't legal I got [ __ ] uh there was
a do you know Felix
um oh yeah
yeah owl yeah yeah so uh this is his
field in in Switzerland wow
he had such shooting plans but I mean
yeah yeah his uh like his this is his
his what his field looked like
you know do you have any of his stuff
saved
don't think so he used to supply so
impossible to get it's so impossible to
get in the U.S because he just never
shipped here so it was like and then
yeah
the uh oh so this is the Sweet Tooth
Garden
um oh very cool that's what we we
um sorry for the [ __ ] no I've seen
yeah I've seen that picture before I
think that's a great picture yeah and um
I think that one is there's there's a
few of the Switzerland that's activity
that's the skunk one on this side oh wow
yeah so that's the story it's a dark
picture yeah she has the black domino
yeah yeah and yeah before you offload
that let us know so we can make sure
that thing stays alive forever oh no I
have it I'm sending it right now to um
the guy for the skunk one cut so I'm
giving him the uh the
the b-98 the Widow 95 and the um B93 I
think would be nice because it was our
Northern Lights so yeah so this was my
version of Northern Lights And if you
look at the size that's a four inch Cube
oh wow yeah and they were just following
each other like when you see the the
sizes and nugs
looking like it was like it was the best
sea of green plant and it was and it was
an l like was it a pure NL I don't know
but it looks a lot like what I would
picture the nl5 cut looking like yeah
yeah exactly and I thought it was just
you know
um it was yeah it was just a phenomenal
cut kind of thing so there's another one
of redfucking about to lose that's funny
dude yeah he's [ __ ]
uh we would we had such this is in
Switzerland too so we had such a [ __ ]
good time
that's when everybody loved everybody
yeah and uh when he when that guy first
showed up the [ __ ] Switzerland
[ __ ] guy sees the field he gets all
excited he goes home and he shaves from
his like shoulder down to his wrist
shaved his entire arms both sides I'm
like what the [ __ ] are you doing he's
like dude I'm running through the field
with my arms out and I'm gonna make hash
if you wanted finger rub he made it like
[ __ ] 10 feet 20 feet lost his breath
couldn't get a [ __ ] quarter of a
[ __ ] gram off of them but his arms
are shaved and he was done I was like
you got to be fine like it was a good
thought good effort he literally did
shave his [ __ ] arms
right I don't think he got a single
[ __ ] gram of hash kind of thing so so
we made it about two hours in right now
there I know there's so much more we can
cover oh yes um but we could do a part
two yeah I was hoping actually that we
could have you back and we could we
could see if we could get kick back yeah
yeah or or maybe even Chris Clay also
has an option because I know that
like I mentioned before there was about
I don't even know how many questions or
how many follow-ups I could think of
while you were talking about stuff but
then we just tangented it off onto
something totally different which is
amazing no you don't have to apologize I
don't have ADHD too so it's okay
if you read my book like I can
send you a copy if you need or I need a
signed copy right very stream of
Consciousness which I liked you know
yeah it was my book is written that way
because I wrote it as if I'm having a
conversation and I had to hire somebody
to
listen to me take notes and then try to
put it in [ __ ] order that's the way I
talk it's not in perfect order and I'm
looking at it going because I smoked a
lot of pop back then I was like did that
have and I remember it happening this
way and then another story that crosses
with it doesn't line up perfectly [ __ ] I
don't know but I did make a huge mistake
in my book
um and it wasn't my mistake it was a
misprint where it says that I grew a
Cannabis Cup winning strain which I did
it was a fast beer it was my [ __ ] not
my strain yeah but I grew it I'm I was
the one that chose to enter it in the
cup those guys didn't want anything to
do with it yeah I knew it was going to
win because the it was honor the goddess
which was all the female judges
I got hired by sativa sisters Karen she
flew me to Amsterdam just to be a
[ __ ] Gigolo guy [ __ ] because I
[ __ ] have a good time and I like
[ __ ] females and flamboyant and I got
laid a lot
um it's why
um that's why we relate so well we're
not we're now we're now speaking Sean's
language he's just smiling
well [ __ ] it's uh because of that you
know all the all the Growers out there
now know that you can get laid and be a
grower it is possible
I don't know um
so he brought this beautiful hot [ __ ]
yoga girl from Texas to work his booth
and he was all stoked you know he's
gonna get some that chick I took her
home I took her back to my hotel and
then I was like I don't want to leave
yet I was like I got no place to stay I
never made it I never made made my
return flights so she's like oh you can
just stay with me I was like were you
saying she's like oh one of Tony's
places and I was like uh you think this
guy who flew you there paid for all your
[ __ ] is gonna be okay with me coming to
[ __ ] you in his place yeah all right
right yeah Tony Tony you know Tony's a
rocket fight yeah right Tony is the
[ __ ] well I'm the coolest cutest
[ __ ] Sebastian Bach wannabe yeah he
had like long hair very much beautiful
Mane yeah yeah I was like I was like and
here comes this [ __ ] you know uh
Ready New York dread and I had [ __ ]
you saw the pictures my dreads were not
[ __ ] anything of to write home about
at that point I was sleeping in a field
for the last [ __ ] two months I was
like I was eating off of a dirt floor
like you know and I was [ __ ] the
hottest chicks kind of thing just a
simple farm hand yeah
yeah so but um yeah so yeah sorry about
that like I do when I do talk I yeah
going down different veins and oh no I
wasn't telling I wasn't criticizing I
was just simply saying that like as
you've got to take on a bunch of
different stuff there's like different
things I wanted to go off on and then
yeah something totally else interesting
and so yeah wait wait wait wait wait
wait wait wait a second yeah you gotta
take you gotta take notes as we're
talking yeah
this is who I want to talk because I'm
the same way I'm just like I want to
talk about that it's [ __ ] awesome
thanks for joining us on this Canada
Journey if you're ready to start a
Canada journey of your own check out
riotsseeds.com for your seeds and
feminized seed spray be sure to like
share subscribe and join us on our
patreon Discord
welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground