welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
can you kind of Enlighten us a little
bit on on Mark Emery both of you just
give us a quick take from a Canadian
perspective on Mark Emery because we
don't have a really clear one at least
from my era and point of view in the
United States well like one thing I'm
not sure about was Mark Emery involved
in cannabis cannabis before like the
hemp Nation constitutional challenge no
no no no wait well the Constitutional
challenge he started NPC by that time
but you have to remember Mark's from
this town from my town yeah yeah
um he had a bookstore here called City
Lights
he scam those people also when it came
to selling it but um Mark
um I call him the dark enemy for a
reason
um I think it's very suiting it on it
ironically matches his name but he is
somebody that you know in his own word
said he was against legalization of
cannabis
due to the amount of money that he was
making from selling seeds illegally yeah
um he proved this when
um after hemp nation was busted for the
second time well first time was Great
Canadian Emporium second time it was
Temptation yeah
um
the
uh Chris was not allowed to sell
paraphernalia after that
so
we desire he decided that
um he reached out to to Mark who had NBC
and said Hey listen do you want to buy
all the inventory from hemp Nation
because we need to raise the money for
the Constitutional challenge
and he agreed he's like yeah send me
everything and then it was like pulling
teeth to get paid from him and by the
very end of it I mean it wasn't a
shitload of money you know maybe it was
only 10 20 grand or something like that
in inventory but when you're fighting
the government to legalize cannabis
every penny counts sure and Chris kept
getting the you know oh talk to my
account and talk to my accountant at
this time it was in around this time uh
uh friends of mine through through Red
from Legends a mutual friend worked for
for Mark
uh basically almost as like manager area
of sales for his direct seats yeah and
he was doing something like
20 40 60 000 a week in cannabis sales
and Seed sales
wow and when it was all said and done
with hemp Nation Chris Klein uh uh
bankruptcy with Mark Emery still owing
him money and it was only maybe a
thousand or two thousand dollars at the
end of it but it kind of just showed
what the term douchebag and yeah wrote
my use of the word douchebag
I I have to start saving it for like the
appropriate people and dark enemy is I
feel the biggest douchebag in our
industry he you know claims that he
donated all this money and stuff like
that but he didn't he uh he would you
know he did a a interview and I think it
was on like CBC or something
and Jody him and Jody and him were
together for less than a year maybe and
he's sitting there having her like click
his toenails on camera while he's being
interviewed and I think he's my mistake
he got up and he was butt naked or
something like that and I was just like
what kind of [ __ ] douchebag again the
word douchebag yeah uh lets or allows
his girlfriend
who was barely out of being a teenager
at the time yeah but his [ __ ]
toenails on national TV I mean yes my
girlfriend and my my wife sure she would
probably if I asked her to yeah but you
wouldn't ask yourself in a [ __ ]
lifetime ask for her to do it on camera
the show crazy there was a big thing
that came out like he he was just very
inappropriate
I can't say I don't know of any charges
um that were laid I mean there should
have been I do know he did run from
political office here in London and uh
he was dating uh
somebody that we knew he was dating uh
this guy's ex-wife
and uh this guy had I think two kids two
boys
and marked during his speeches kept
saying I'm a family man I'm all about
family you know here's my wife and my
kids and this guy was like dude you
can't call my kids your kids like and it
ended up that Mark I believe was giving
a a
a speech or something down at one of the
parks
and he said that and this guy walked out
of the crowd walked up and punched him I
don't know if he did it on Hallelujah
but like basically punch Mark in the
[ __ ] head said stop [ __ ] claiming
my kids are Jews because you know he's
he was he's a showboater and the thing
is is he has he's done certain things he
used to do something here he fought for
uh
uh for stores to be open on Sunday when
before when it was illegal yeah kudos
for that he uh paid he had some of his
staff or something follow
um minute uh the guy is doing the uh
parking police whatever and walking
around with nickels or quarters and if
he saw an expired meter he'd drop a
quarter or Nickel in it kudos for that
but you know Mark Mark is like the
Donald Trump of the [ __ ] cannabis
industry like he talks to talk but he's
burned so many [ __ ] bridges yeah the
thing is I got into yelling matches on
um on the phone and because he was like
why the [ __ ] you bashing me I kicked him
out of my store when he came into town
he can go to High Times the guy my
competition
as much as he wants but uh I know him
and furthermore when I opened organic
traveler I took over all of hemp
nation's uh gear everything down from
the display cases including the
computers so on these computers I had
access to all the files and all the
outstanding debts that Marco so I was
bad-mouthing him and trying to be loud
enough that he would hear me yeah and
obviously he did because he called me up
one day on speakerphone with other
people in the background and uh and try
to [ __ ] me like try to make a scene
yeah I got the [ __ ] computers here I
can tell you what date you made payments
and what date and how much you owed at
the very end you tell me he's like Peter
who's only [ __ ] thousand bucks a
couple thousand bucks I don't give a
[ __ ] you still love it in colors man we
were trying to [ __ ] change the laws
Chris went to [ __ ] jail for this
um Sarah went to jail for this this
guy's out there making tens if not
hundreds of thousands of dollars a month
yeah and he's gonna stiff some [ __ ]
guy that's trying to fight the marijuana
laws so that he can do that and now this
comes through word of mouth but the
people that tell me this kind of thing
um I give 10 times a thousand times more
credit than I give Mark yeah and they
said you know he'll admit that off
record obviously that why would he want
to legalize cannabis when he makes so
much money off the fact that it is
illegal
and especially in the states he wasn't
charged in Canada he was charged in the
states yeah right like [ __ ] buddy like
moved to the states I mean I'm I'm all
for spreading the seed everywhere we
don't want him use that [ __ ] you know
and what got me also was back then I was
actually
breeding I'll do air quotes because it's
not I was just breeding for seed to get
the seed out there and again we're going
back to the mid 90s kind of thing
um
we would send Mark seeds and this when
he was first started his uh seed
business and uh we would tell him or
whatever it was a buck a seat or
a couple bucks a seat or something like
that and we'd be honest like listen like
I told in the last interview I would buy
seeds from uh Scentsy or Greenhouse or
something and then do a breeding just
using those genetics and saying Hey
listen this is
um this is our Northern Lights we bought
the it's a Northern Lights five we
bought the seed we made our own seed
we're selling it right yeah or we would
say well we liked uh we wanted to blend
it so we did like a Northern Lights
chemo which was something that we really
liked and we would sell Mark the seeds
and he would change the names or he
would remove certain things like he
would just call the Northern Lights
chemo just chemo right yeah
itself better
right yeah so he was didn't want us when
he when it came to what he was selling
and um you know it didn't happen he
wasn't he wasn't selling it as you know
Scentsy seeds [ __ ] Northern Lights he
was just saying hey this is pure
Northern Lights but it wasn't pure it
was [ __ ] bread
by me or or hemp Nation crew and or in a
hemp Nation Garden or my garden and we
were just doing it to spread the Johnny
Appleseed we wanted to sell this yeah
you know we were selling I think it was
uh 10 seats or 25 bucks if something 250
a seat to get it out yeah the thing
right so you know people that again I've
even said in the last year people that
focus on the money in this industry
uh are in the industry not the movement
and people that claim to be in the
movement like Mark does you know and he
he was hiding behind Jody
till the very end right like I don't
know a [ __ ] is wrong with that and I'm
not going to get in any personal [ __ ]
because there's some
[ __ ] he's done to friends of mine
personally yeah I mean if you if you
Google Mark Emery and you look for stuff
it's like there's stuff out there it's
like when he got out west I I think it
got worse you know it's all about ego he
always me and my friends
when we were out in Vancouver we
wouldn't step foot in the shop no like
on that strip like like we wouldn't like
we didn't even want to go into his
establishment like that's how much we
disliked him we just knew like he was a
piece of [ __ ] like [ __ ] him yeah
again he's it's about self-promotion
with him it's nothing to do with the
movement he's not one of them he was
anything but [ __ ] you know he went to
I think it was Thailand before he went
out west
you know uh or maybe it was during
because he went out there and like
dropped a bunch of money on some locals
said hey I just bought this property
here's [ __ ] x amount of dollars I
want a [ __ ] house and I come back you
know when he came back he went back
there the land was just overgrown
nothing built and his money was gone
so yes I I would honestly wish that
there wasn't so many you know he comes
back to this town and he thinks he's
[ __ ] He's ran for political office
last year yes oh yeah and uh it was
hilarious because every time I drove by
him I would call him a [ __ ] douchebag
yeah don't listen you're not liked
around here get the [ __ ] out he got very
little votes and the funny thing is is I
was either driving my Volkswagen bus and
my Volkswagen Karma gear on my truck or
my Mini Cooper or my Jeep I was always
driving something different so he's
probably thought the whole [ __ ] I'm I
know I hope other people join me but
yeah I was [ __ ] yelling at him left
right and Center because
he doesn't [ __ ] live here while he
might live here now I don't even know I
think he moved back here for a while I
can't believe he would go back honestly
like I like when I lived there I didn't
know one person that had anything to say
but negative but negative he he didn't
choose to leave London right he had to
leave he ended up he ended up [ __ ] he
saw he ended up [ __ ] a fireman's wife
and I don't for for some reason I
thought he was fairly high up in the
fire department I don't know if he was a
chief or or something like that but uh
rumor has it yeah they walked into his
[ __ ] bookstore
and so there's a lot of paper in here
this is probably place would probably go
up pretty quickly and sometimes we hit
red lights or something along that line
was said yeah kind of thing right all
right and again could have been folklore
it could have been anything but because
you know I knew the type of person I
know the type of person he is yeah for
sure see that so you know it sucks to
see people like that get all the
attention and it gives us a bad name
yeah yeah people out there especially as
a Canadian like yeah
what the [ __ ] like come on like that was
yeah especially like in BC he kept going
in BC it's like yeah well let's you know
well let's let's get to this so the one
thing that was resounding the resounding
criticism from the last episode was that
there were but one or two really loud BC
Growers that that they were
misrepresented very extreme can you can
you explain to Sean better than me I I
before like when before we did the first
one before we even recorded the first
one in our little homie chat I said
there's gonna be some BC people pissed
off yeah and I have I have a specific
question in mind but I didn't even ask
that question and they still got upset
but I actually went back and listened
and I know what he what the one guy at
least was upset about and and it was
that Pete said it all started here I was
like yup and then there was a comment
about of course there's there's good
growers in PC they're all from Ontario
yeah but he was like this you know yeah
whatever well but
very specific uh Viewpoint right yeah
but
hey doctor that's so I'm Back Where I
Come From right like I grew up in London
so I grew up around like I like there is
like commercial what my friends called
bikerweed right which was just the
commercial right yeah
but once once you've found like that
like fan that downtown family which was
not hard to find you know
um you look you got great pot right yeah
yeah whether you were getting it from
well whatever I'm not gonna name but
like
so me and my friends like you know we
went on tour right we were like [ __ ]
this we're going on dead tour and we
just wanted to like we wanted to see the
shows because we we were heads but we
also wanted to see [ __ ] pot you know
that was like the two were just as equal
so we went down we did tour for a while
that led us to the west coast of the us
and we we saw that area and like
we were kind of like blown away like
number one the cost we could not [ __ ]
believe people were paying what they
were paying like that was just
mind-blowing right because it was
comparable to back home to us yeah and
then when we got to the West Coast it's
like same thing but like the only like
the only thing about the west coast is
we saw new stuff that like names we'd
never heard of and obviously there was
people breeding there right because it
was all this weird new [ __ ] it was the
first time I saw like white weed right
like it looked like mold in somebody's
hand but they're like no that's you know
that's [ __ ] you know resin
and then you know I lived in Arcata for
a while right so I lived in Arcata for a
good stretch and like I was there for a
while so I kind of saw and experienced
what was going on in that area and it
was really good weed like back home
though you know like for me it was like
what we had back home and then I got
back home and like I went into Pete shop
to like chat him up because back home
there's not too many people that you
could talk about that stuff and they
understand what you're talking about
and at the same time it was taking me
out to Vancouver with him right and
Pete's response was like you were just
like disappointed super disappointed
and you're like everybody goes out west
and they think the weed is so much
better there and it's not it's not you
know and I think and like I said I stand
by the what I said before about
um uh all the good Growers
well I would say all but I can't say all
right because we don't know yeah I'm
gonna say a large percentage and I'll
give you a few examples because a large
percentage I I got hired uh after a
state in Switzerland by a one of the
larger brokers in
um the Vancouver area and uh like red he
was named after a different color let's
just say blue and um
and I think he's from Ontario too
honestly but uh so they they brought me
into this middle of butt [ __ ] nowhere
between Jasper and Kamloops along uh I
think it's Highway five and
um
built a huge Greenhouse in the middle of
the Bush off grid I lived in a little
Log Cabin off grid or they already had
a 300 uh 300 bales of pro-mix hiked into
a bush and big huge uh outdoor beds and
I thought [ __ ] right man I'm in the
middle of [ __ ] nowhere I'm finally
gonna meet some of these you know
grassroot BC Growers that I [ __ ]
heard about and read about didn't meet
[ __ ] one person from BC every single
person I met was from Ontario or I'd say
80 from Ontario and the rest were kind
of mixed so when you go out to uh to
Vancouver and the island and stuff like
that
you know yeah ask ask anybody where you
from I'm from BC I was like really where
were you born what part like I was born
in Etobicoke what the [ __ ] is that very
rare
six months ago well no you're not from
[ __ ] BC you know they all in the 90s
it was very rare like most people that
are from BC were born in the [ __ ] 90s
you know yeah like it just wasn't
populated it wasn't populated the
population was Tiny and like what I was
told actually I'm not sure if it's
totally true but I think it's believable
was like in the 80s they were offering
offering stimulus sort of situations for
people to move to BC because it was so
underpopulated and they were even like
doing that to like you know lower income
people like we'll give you money and
we'll give you a free trip to go to you
know the [ __ ] Vancouver area like it
just wasn't populated right so by the
90s
the great majority was not from there it
just that's it's true the Cannabis moved
out there again like why everybody moves
out there they think well you know it's
beautiful it's more climatized and so on
all the power to them for sure you know
but again the genetics and the the
techniques and the and the information
in their heads it's come from Ontario I
mean there's a a breeder out on the
island he thinks he's a pretty great
Gardener I think he's okay you know
um besides you know
um but he's not from [ __ ] BC you know
he's from he's from this [ __ ] town
you know but like recently maybe dark
enemies from here Chris Clay Chris
Clay's from here you know I don't know
about you know some of the other Growers
sure there's phenomenal Growers
everywhere BC definitely has but we're
seeing a lot of podcasts now right like
this where a lot of people are speaking
out and like see Ray not from BC scabby
not from BC Jay not from BC like every
single person that that has spoken out
about BC is not from BC right right I
don't think we've heard what I almost
moved out to BC I mean I got I got bit
by the bug also like everybody and
um just some beautiful [ __ ] people
out there and it is a lot stronger there
because the laws were a lot more
forgiving there it is
um but you know when it when push comes
to shove you ask the people like okay
where are you from
if they say BC ask them where they're
born because you know it's not like they
I'm surprised they got [ __ ] maternity
Wards in [ __ ] Vancouver because
nobody's from [ __ ] Vancouver but
there's some there's some right like
like
less than an hour I was off the plane we
were smoking texts at a time warp yeah
and like there was a whole bunch of
Americans there like like our whole like
deadhead crew that was in Vancouver like
we were strong supporters of the island
organic outdoor you know like that was
good [ __ ] it wasn't good yeah that'd be
a good story for red too if you ever
want to break
but there's a lot of cool people in BC
there's a lot of good growers in BC and
if somebody's like insulted at the fact
that like BC isn't everything maybe
you're not growing great weed if you're
that insecure you know yeah I mean I can
throw like obviously like I Mendo Mendo
has some similarities and humble too
because like as like you know you start
talking about like oh well where were
you born you know and I mean I'm a
transplant out here now granted I ended
up getting here a lot earlier
um you know like uh than most people and
I've lived out here a long time but I'm
not from here right and you know when
you look at the map of Canada almost all
Canadians are from where
you guys are yeah in the large
population Southwestern Ontario and like
I was saying before in the last podcast
where because of how we're situated the
great lakes and glacial runoff we have
some of the best soil in Canada I mean
people don't probably realize this oil
in Canada Canada is a huge place but
like that's mostly you look at it like I
I think it's like 80 90 of the people in
Canada live within 100 kilometers of the
Border or something like that even even
that I was I was kind of like well
because like Matt thought when we said
London we're talking about BC like his
geography is like way out but like
I was trying to explain to like my
American friends that like we can't just
say Ontario we can't just say BC because
it's too huge like BC right I was just
saying even the coastal area you have
all these independent islands that are
like a place in themselves then you have
Vancouver then you have like the the
Vancouver Island which could be split up
in sections then you have the Kootenays
which is like [ __ ] 12 hours down the
road that way like it's just totally
different places and when you say BC
like I'm sure the Coots had much better
um Quality because it was smaller and
the Vancouver area and the coastal area
was so big it was so commercial that it
was just it gets flooded with commercial
yeah it was so [ __ ] flooded with
commercial it was hard to find good weed
because there was so much commercial to
get rid of it was like nobody had time
to even think about quality it was just
like I think it's because a lot of the
organized uh Growers organized crime
Growers yeah
that's where they were going to be
around but when you get into like the
Kootenays to Nelson area you know when
you get into the kind family mentality
that still grow For the Love of the the
plant so yeah again air quality the
movement people not the industry people
if you're in the industry you are going
to be in probably Vancouver uh you're
going to be someplace west of Hope
um and south of Whistler kind of thing
and then you uh get on onto the island
same thing you're going to get more of
the the kind family uh Vibe and
mentality right yeah I spent some time
out in Nelson and win law that area
Nelson and they were just like you know
what they grew phenomenal I named my dog
yeah it was called you know our friend
our I gotta mention because he passed
away I don't know a couple years ago
maybe cormy's arms yeah yeah he passed
away uh not long ago but he he was like
a lot of our friends are there right a
lot of the people we grew up are there
yeah
I would say like of that of like like my
age people that were brought up there
like 90 went to the Coots I would say
like the drum circles I used to have at
organic we used to have all like the the
hippies that would hippie kids I call
them like
kids were your age maybe even a little
bit younger
um yeah they used to all come to the
organic travel of food because I did
drum circles on Sundays or something
like that I say 90 of them ended out in
the Nelson area and probably a good
portion of them [ __ ] played in wasabi
kind of thing like they were all well
but that's the thing like
there was uh
uh in London they were called kangaroo
right this band they were like a little
fun damn band called kangaroo but like
they all like when they
enough to go to college they went there
and like everybody went there yeah but
then you had uh you had uh
um [ __ ] on my dipstick what are they
called Jimmy's band back here Yaki
Mystic yeah
kangaroo and those guys right like oh
Jimmy went with them Jimmy was with them
well that because that when they all got
there they joined up with uh Wasabi
Collective like Jimmy was in there yeah
yeah so I mean that's what I was trying
to get at about you know the the
Cannabis industry and you know I invite
anybody that wants to challenge me on
[ __ ] you know East Coast West Coast
where all the Growers come like you know
you think about it
um yeah it's not a pissing contest you
know it's not a pissing contest you get
yeah and it shouldn't be but it is for
some right and like and that kind of
brings me into my my next thing because
when I talk about you know Legend seeds
right and and uh Sol
um they're from this area right yeah and
they're old friends and I I listen back
on my uh on the last podcast and I use
the words the term we a lot when I talk
about these guys because because they're
friends yeah but when it came to their
breeding and stuff like that Legends and
and Sol
um I was just I wasn't part of their
um
their company or part of their their
group I was friends with them I was
there I might have you know
um did whatever they wanted me to do
kind of thing as helping out a friend
but I wasn't ever when I say we I don't
mean I helped breed anything with these
that is a friend's Circle it was like
yeah it was and it brought me to another
point where in my book there's a typo
which I'm surprised
uh Steve hasn't
come and [ __ ] try to fire by my house
yet but when we were talking about the
uh the fast fear which we spoke about oh
yeah you said that though the last one
you said this already
was on the on the very last paragraph of
the one
um chapter it says I it was supposed to
say I grew an award-winning strain okay
and it said I bread uh sure and but it
taught oh the whole chapter it just
talks about me being a grower and being
a grower there and working for Mr hemp
and you know I answered to Steve it was
his program and uh but the very last
thing was just it was a typo and Greg
brought it up and I was like oh [ __ ] man
Steve's gonna kill me because he thinks
I'm trying to you know yeah steal his
[ __ ] Limelight even though he stole
my medal but uh trying to Jack his STEEZ
you know I think that's a common thing
in cannabis actually because of how in
the shadows and clandestine it is yeah I
do the same thing dude where some of the
stories I tell where it's we it's like
there's people that are known and
there's people that are unknown some of
those people that are unknown wish to
remain unknown yeah you know and so
you're trying to tell history and tell a
story but you have to sort of edit it to
some degree because what you're giving
is accurate information right and then
the flip side of that is that there's
people
that wannabe can of famous yeah right
and they want to aggregate all the fame
to them and so even if it might have
been a collective of friends all doing
it they're going to tell the story like
it was them alone in their basement
working for 10 years and then they came
out with all this and no one else has
[ __ ] to do with it when you know
personally that there was like seven
other dudes and it was this loose
Collective of friends that were all
involved in this breeding happened at
this house then and then this accident
happened over here and then this
happened and it can be kind of weird to
tell stories that way because a lot of
money is made on
you know every breeder and mics except
for maybe Neville but most breeders are
like well no Neville was very clear
about I got this from this person
I did this and this almost all breeders
after him were like this never existed
before I carefully crafted it and no one
else has had any of these genetics ever
yeah
[ __ ] land race kind of yeah like like
they just obscure yeah
I'm gonna break in because like not to
interrupt the flow but I didn't get to
actually ask my question when we were
talking about the BC stuff and I want to
ask this question do it so we're gonna
but it kind of is the same thing because
it's a dishonesty thing or like an
illusion thing I guess you would say but
like that conversation going back to
that conversation when you were
disappointed
um you mentioned something and at the
time you mentioned it I kind of thought
you were crazy like I didn't like I
didn't know because I didn't know right
when somebody tells you something you
don't know you're kind of like what but
you said something about High Times and
hyping
what's that magazine or the store
the magazine that like BC was only got
really popular because High Times was
hyping them to kind of draw attention to
them
do you remember this conversation
no no well what I what I remember which
this could be totally false was that you
were like BC was like hyping up the big
bud because at the time like BC was
really blowing up as like right but you
were like
the magazine was kind of like trying to
draw attention from the US and DEA
attention to to BC
um I don't remember that conversation
but I mean part of that sounded a little
familiar okay I think what High Times is
trying to pimp was because California
was such a huge market for cannabis
Counter Culture yeah right because High
Times isn't a Canada's magazine right
it's a chemical for magazine so that's
why it has so much music it has so much
uh cannabis is only a section of it
right and then for a few years they got
rid of it right they didn't have canvas
for a few years
um and that's when they started grow
America for for a little bit but
um I think because the term BC Bud right
anything Canada was BC Bud right right
right so
um I think they were pimping that
as well as because of the climate you
could have larger outdoor grows than we
could in Ontario okay
um they wouldn't go into Quebec where
you could also have fairly large
outgrows because of the language barrier
um so I think for High Times
I wouldn't say I know for for a fact but
pretty damn sure with my interaction
with them that they were pushing the BC
Bud because of its popularity in
California because your top dollar you
know anything from your tuna cans
[ __ ] anything that was the BC bud got
the top dollar and then I mean I mean
there's a name that we mentioned uh in
our last talk and he was a broker he's
still in the industry he's I think he's
a [ __ ] great guy he knows he knows a
lot of history of this uh of this
movement
from the West Coast but he was a broker
and uh he used to sell be able to sell a
certain type of outdoor
and it was uh it was a pink something
but uh he was selling for twenty nine
hundred dollars
a pound for hours
to LA because it was that's nothing
though people were selling 32.
for out yeah I realized that but this is
outdoor
um what year is this I was Canadian or
U.S what year
oh okay okay
the beaster era yeah I would say like
late 90s yeah so like stuff and I it was
so it was strained I think it was called
sotica
cream sodica cream sodica yeah so we
grew that out in Switzerland actually
yeah and uh the guy that's growing it is
a I'm gonna use the word douchebag again
which I said I was trying not to use but
this guy's a [ __ ] douchebag he ran
the uh farm that I was uh hired to work
on in uh in the interior
and um his name's Jay I don't know his
last name I wish I knew his last name
but I'd say it here too what was the
cream sodaka like I the first time I
ever saw that it was really unique uh
plant uh it had really bright uh pink
stigmas in it where
um it wasn't a huge producer but it it
grew kind of like a really short kind of
like the pink freeze land which I
wouldn't be surprised if it might have
you know again traveled West which a lot
of genetics did back in the day as we
talked about before that was just like
you know it wasn't a very strong
structured plant but it just grew all
these golf balls that just would I mean
maybe a little bit easier to trim but
just look beautiful rock hard it would
give you the the BC bag of marbles again
it's kind of what I call a lot of the
you know any pot that comes across my
desk nowadays I can basically look at it
and tell you where it come from by bag
appeal because you know BC had the
tendency for a while there of not
trimming the pot but shaping it so every
nug looked like a [ __ ] marble right
yeah right you know but I mean is back
when they were making tons of extract
so they were trimming off a lot of the
stuff because they knew they were going
to be able to use it kind of thing and
then you got the bag of marbles the BC
bag of marbles that uh was just kind of
a look so I think that the cream sodica
was um
uh was a strain that was
kind of easy for their outdoor to look
like indoor yeah and that's why bubble
was able to [ __ ]
you know for ridiculous amounts of money
I mean that strain out here called West
Coast dog like that it's just outdoor
for indoor type [ __ ] that's been the
game I mean and where I live in Mendo
it's like that's been the game forever
of yeah Brokers being like well this
outdoor pass is light depth yeah does
this light depth look good enough to
pass as indoor yeah um because where
there was uneducated areas of the
country or whatever they were like can I
can I put this into a different bracket
right can I buy this for what it is but
claim it's the next grade up there's
tons of people I mean again that's the
that's the industry envelope in the
movement the movement right because
there's going to be people like myself
that say Hey listen you know
it's outdoor looks like indoor you know
but [ __ ] I I'm gonna be honest with you
and if you want to be dishonest after
that that's up to you but I'm probably
going to charge you
[ __ ] uh more money you're gonna pay a
[ __ ] tax on something that looks
spectacular I don't give a [ __ ] if it's
indoor outdoor or [ __ ] Greenhouse or
you know small crop large crop you know
hand trim machine trim you know like
there's there's so many variables at the
end of the day if it [ __ ] looks good
smells good and [ __ ] kicks you in the
nuts then what the [ __ ] who cares how
it's grown for me I think like what do
we what do we do when we grow indoor all
we're trying to do is mimic outdoor
we're trying to mimic from other nature
mother nature has the [ __ ] the
formula down where now we're able to
with technology and so on we're a lot we
can better mother nature but for the
longest time we were just trying to
reproduce Outside Inside
I do think we can do everything better
than nature indoor yeah except for the
Sun
no no of course you can I mean the sun
is the sun's still by far is the best
light right and I've done all kinds of
spectrum experience
and all this and you know to some degree
it's interesting too because like all
almost all of the award-winning hash
made in California is all made with the
Sun right you know they don't use indoor
grown stock indoor might get you know
humans are so visual that indoor might
look prettier
right you know
um and I I also wanted to make a comment
when you guys were talking about Ontario
you know just different areas there
could be a lot just for the simple fact
that BC Bud Rhymes yeah yeah you know
yeah Southwestern Ontario nug doesn't
really like what do you what do you call
Ontario weed like so you know I live in
Mendocino County or whatever and like
whether it came from Trinity or
Mendocino or Sonoma or or whatnot if it
went on dead tour it was Humboldt County
organic outdoor yeah exactly well and
that's what I was going to say like what
you were mentioning is you know humble
is the BC of uh
of the states pretty much right like
anybody that was anybody that wanted to
be a pot grower moved to California then
once they were like oh we're in
California now what do we do like humble
again probably didn't have a [ __ ]
Maternity Ward didn't need one because
there was only a few [ __ ] people that
live there and then all of a sudden the
Cannabis craze came and of course they
were like oh well I move up there I can
name it [ __ ] Humboldt County
yeah I'll tell you when I first moved to
Mendocino County in the 90s there was so
few people moving here from outside that
everyone thought I was a cop
yeah oh yeah also because because you
look like a cop yeah yeah yeah well you
know and [ __ ] that dude I I can tell you
I mean we want to talk about dead tour
the first time I saw a cop tackle
somebody on the lot with dreadlocks down
to his ass and then pull out handcuffs
yeah I was like oh yeah yeah no no no
I'd say you can't tell what a undercover
cop looks like but you can tell what the
regular cop looks like yeah I'm like
that you know but the only reason I said
that is because it was before like what
we call the green Rush yeah where people
weren't moving like people didn't move
to the towns that I was moving to yeah
like out-of-towners didn't come there
within five six years as medical
Advanced and sort of the green Rush
occurred it got overwhelmed by much like
you were saying with BC yeah almost none
of the Growers from Mendo were born in
Mendo right they were all transplants I
mean there was a small core certainly
that was from there yeah but if you
added them up by like number it was
probably like 90 90 10.
that's the same thing with BC like again
I'm not going to pull you know I I think
BC has has produced and still does
produce uh phenomenal Growers I'm just
saying that back in the day most of
those Growers and therefore a lot of
their genetics
um came from you know East or south
I mean there's there's a debate on that
too like not so much in but just in the
sense of where is something from yeah
exactly you know like like the you know
we have this you know the whole thing
came from came through that came through
because there's this whole thing we're
like oh the cush is from Florida
well what's the story of the Kush and
they're like oh well is this clone from
the Emerald Triangle
and then pollen from some stuff we got
from Neville and Holland right but it
happened in Florida
right you know so I see and again back
when I was growing the kush before it
was kush kind of thing it was just
basically the you know from the Kush
region of Afghanistan like I would say
if people say well where's the where's
the Hindu Kush from well probably the
Hindu Kush mountains right like these
are they might have you know took a
cutting or a seed you know they might
have brought something back during the
war times you know which a lot of the
genetics did you know come from soldiers
returning from [ __ ] overseas and
bringing seed that they uh that they
grabbed and planted in California
Florida [ __ ] Wyoming anywhere
everywhere sure it was just what ended
up happening is where all the uh cool
people or where the the population that
were like-minded ended up moving to in
Canada it would be BC you know in
California it was going to be probably
San Francisco
or that area
um
following kind of the whole hippie
movement and so on so I would say I
don't say
I shouldn't say that the strain oh their
genetics came from uh Southwest South
Southwestern Ontario I could say that
they most likely came through
and they probably came through
California to get to BC but again when
you get strains like Texada Texas at a
time warp there's certain
um and I was I found some seed that from
Gabriola right like
um where they come from I'm sure there's
people on the island that will claim or
and rightfully so say well Texada came
from Texada because they came from
California and we took uh we took pollen
from Ontario or we took pollen from
[ __ ] you know some seed that we got
out of Africa you know I used to order
seeds from [ __ ] Africa back in ham
Nation days like literally from uh uh uh
seats dealer out of [ __ ] yeah I think I
don't know if it was South Africa the
swazi and swazi pepper and there's
another stream
but uh you know I would use that in my
breeding program
I'm gonna put that in quotations again I
would use that when I was making seeds
and uh
that made that strain from here right
did it originate here yes the seed did
but the genetics that it came from
obviously didn't come from here because
we have very little if any land races as
same as BC has very little to any same
as you know California they might I they
might have a land race there I don't
know of one
right but no no I mean I think I think
most most California breeding if I had
to guess like what the very Inception of
California breeding is it was like how
do we make these sativas that we're
getting free seeds with these kilos
we're getting how do we make them finish
in our area yeah oh well I have some
Mexican and that stuff seems to finish
earlier so maybe I'll take some of this
Thai or Colombian and I'll cross it to
Mexican yeah and it was literally very
like very it was very I don't think
people had goals other than the fact of
like I need this to finish before
January well I think that's where a lot
of the you know genetics were built and
why they were built because I know and
that's why again going back to the East
Coast West Coast
um we had draft Dodgers that [ __ ] ran
the border and uh and brought their
genetics up to Southwestern Ontario
again because being so close to Detroit
so close to uh Buffalo you know the most
southern part of this country
um the soil the so on so forth Perth
County conspiracy the whole kind of deal
um what were we greeting for what was I
breeding for I wasn't breeding for
anything other than I want to take that
[ __ ] strain and grow it in my house
in my basement and I don't want to run
it for 14 weeks right so I'm gonna find
so and again my a lot of my I miss I was
a sativa lover so I wanted if I could
grow uh an original Haze in six weeks
that produced uh that one and a half
pounds per light I mean heaven so that's
where I was that's my whole program
that's what it was about when I used the
I used to read Neville's catalogs and
Scentsy and God anything that was in
that 45 to 50 day range just looked
attractive it did and I just you know I
I didn't get any I didn't believe any of
this [ __ ] I really put the [ __ ] uh
the Amsterdam guys through a lot of [ __ ]
in my years just because I called
[ __ ] on a lot of them because I grew
out a lot of their Stranges and I was
just like this is you know I'm at 60
days I'm not going to argue out of 55 or
60 Day flower right that's fine with me
inside but you're saying 45 today 45 to
50 days and like yeah don't know about
that you know and then give me the
[ __ ] yields I was like yeah don't
know about that you know like but again
maybe again that's business though they
need to they want to sell that seed and
they want to sell that seed to be
um attractive to the indoor grower or
attracted to the North American grower
who if they are going to grow outdoors
they want it to be done uh in September
they proceeded to be done by October you
know I mean when you when you look at
like California history before the
helicopters people were fine with things
taking into November right no big deal
when there was no police pressure and
they weren't worried about their crop
getting chopped yeah November is fine
all of a sudden you get camp and you get
all these helicopters in the sky and
they're like when can I pull down in
September yeah that extra two months is
a real prop three months is an extra
problem we had snow that we had to worry
about up here right like the cops the
cops here go out in August right so the
Choppers are there in August September
maybe kind of thing right because uh we
have to be down ideally end of September
early October if you go anything past
that button rotten stuff like that you
know we still get the humidity we are
surrounded by the Great Lakes we get you
know we get the cold uh the hot days the
cold nights we get Bud rot like you
wouldn't [ __ ] believe you know I
believe I I believe it I mean I I think
as as some of these states like New York
and New Jersey and and a lot of these
New England start to open up and what
they want is they want all these
California bread strains yeah I know uh
because that's what's famous and they
want to sell the name but what they
really should be after is the Canadian
bread stuff well they again but they're
like we were saying before the BC bud is
going to sell the SW Ontario Bud they
don't know what the [ __ ] does that mean
right even the Quebec nug Quebec Bud
they're going to say oh I I know of
Quebec they're not going to know of
Ontario and Ontario is the biggest
[ __ ] most populated state
um it definitely by far has the most pop
growers in it simply because of per
capita the amount of [ __ ] maybe not
per capita but because of the amount of
uh people's population
right but it's um it's going to be a
hard sell to say Canadian Canadian buds
it's all hot they're all going to say BC
bike right and it's marketing that's uh
it's what's going to sell it kind of
thing unfortunately or you know
fortunately whatever to me
I really don't could give any a [ __ ] of
a less honestly but um
you know it is it is hard for
me here trying to sell down into the
states
unless they they knew me or they knew
the uh genetics I was growing and High
Times their office knew what I was doing
because I used to fly down there with
um
weighed out eighths and wait out
quarters in glass jars uh
I also what was it it was a 25th
anniversary party they had Cypress Hill
and Joan Jett and whoever else
um I supplied all the pot to that party
because
High Times couldn't really afford let
alone back then especially the high-end
pot all the super super nice nugs that
you see in that magazine and you see
Snoop Dogg with a big [ __ ] plate of
buds in front of them and big joints
they rent all that pot they rent it they
rent it rent you can rent weed yeah they
rent weed for the Photoshop for the
photo op and then anything that is
smoked they're paying four or five six
hundred dollars an ounce so they're just
when they were telling me that uh
they're like oh [ __ ] man they were all
another [ __ ] big fat [ __ ] uh blunt
that's gonna cost us [ __ ] 300 you
know what a bunch of clowns yeah I'll do
it well you gotta remember what era it
was though too I mean yeah it was it was
it was ridiculous
you know I know Sean was trying to get
us to talk about like our our uh you
know some of our Amsterdam and cup
experiences because we overlapped but
you know when I would go I went to three
cups in the 90s I think like 95 97 98
right right and what I experienced was
that like you were just saying all the
best weed was set aside for like the
celebrities yep and the people that were
gonna pay top dollar for it and the
people that wanted to show up and like
they didn't care if they dropped Mad
Coin so it was actually like one of the
worst weeks or months to visit Amsterdam
yeah because if you were just a normal
person they're like well we have good
weed but we're gonna sell it for three
times what it's worth yeah because
people pay the North American Tax right
you're gonna pay the North American Tax
because we have all these celebrities
coming in and we have all these
musicians and stuff and these entourages
right we've got all this weed and hash
that aside just for them and we're gonna
charge them out the nose for it and so
we can't give it to you unless you want
to pay this like exorbitant price yeah
and so it was like it gets ridiculous
and again New York is the same way La
was the same way New York and L.A
obviously with the highest markets uh I
think ever any place in the world and
when High Times used to do like in the
very back of the pages like the price
prices from around the world and around
the country and how much a an eighth was
and how much an ounce was and stuff it
was always La in New York at the [ __ ]
top kind of thing but with with um with
uh with working with high times and
Kyle knew my genetics like I said when
he was coming here to buy it uh and and
shipping it back to Detroit
I would send uh I would send dogs down
to him
um and we had a thing going where I'd
mail it to the High Times office
and then inside I'd be like I hope this
gets you busted you [ __ ] douchebags
and and putting in all this you know
hate mail with a half pound of pot in it
kind of thing right and uh when the 25th
anniversary uh party was coming up they
reached out to me and said Hey listen
you know would you be interested in you
know selling us pot and I was like you
know sure I was like I I mean we've been
doing it enough kind of thing I said
um what were you guys thinking they
threw out a number and it was something
like
like three grand a pound or something
like that
and I said uh I said and U.S
so I said okay let me think about it and
I'm like thank you to myself what
[ __ ] kind of people do you [ __ ]
morons so I call them back up I say
listen I can't take three grand you know
and then Kyle's like you know Pete
that's pretty fair I was like okay I'll
do this I'll take 2 400 a pound right
U.S
and I'm Gonna Mail a few boxes of jars
so I didn't like I didn't mail Ziploc
freezer bag half pounds of pot other
than what they wanted for the party
which was just a few pounds or something
like that but I mailed probably
at least a pound that was already
weighed out and in and sealed in glass
jars with [ __ ] homemade labels on
every jar and I would uh I would mail
them uh separately
and then when I got down there I sat in
Steve's office I was either bloomy's
office or um
um
there's one other office anyways I would
just I would sit in their office and
they would come in like one at a time
and choose I was like and I was like
listen it's [ __ ]
um
I I think I was
stiffing them a little bit I might have
charged 50 bucks an eighth kind of thing
um because I could and it was like
I was shipping literally jars that were
cured and it was like my my nicest stuff
I got that's a risk I got to sit on the
couch with Jack Herrera and I was super
stoked because I was like listen Jack I
want you to uh smoke this um uh golden
Haze it's my strain I bred it but I used
some genetics that you know with this
nl5 skunk one that made his that Sensei
used to make his train yeah um I used
some of that
uh
uh I used a uh
a version of keeping that kind of blend
in mind because it was exactly what I
wanted in my stream I wanted like I said
before a short fat sativa
giving high from a plant that's going to
finish in less than 60 days and I could
ruin a [ __ ] uh room with nine foot
ceilings yeah and it was like when he
when he you know tried my my stuff and
he's like wow that's [ __ ] really nice
tasty so on so forth
I it made my [ __ ] it made my career
at that time kind of thing just to get
there and and smoke a joint with them at
the same time having
um
who's the head of who is a Hagar Hagar
yeah Hager yeah Stephen Hager yeah so I
would I think I was sitting in his
office actually because he was the head
honcho and uh I was selling [ __ ]
uh quarters and Ace and [ __ ] like that
pre-jarred up to the entire staff kind
of thing and then the party was you know
that night and I was just like they paid
me [ __ ] ridiculous amount I mean and
I took less far less than what they were
offering me because I was kind of
honored one that I can yeah you know
Supply the pot but I was also making a
shitload of money by selling them my
private uh Growers jar collection kind
of [ __ ] so that's a testament to London
because like you don't know how hard it
is like being on on the internet and
talking to weed guys trying to say that
Southwestern Ontario had [ __ ] great
pot nobody believes it nobody
great pot man all you have is [ __ ]
cities and cornfields but again
it comes down to population when you
when you have
10 to 15 times the amount of people
jammed into a certain area
there's going to be phenomenal
pot growers as well as the
the people that really want to find that
unique strain
and they travel the world maybe not for
pot
but due to the amount of people
the population they travel all over the
world and if they [ __ ] find pot in
Thailand or North Africa or someplace
and like oh I got a couple seats I'm
gonna throw in my [ __ ] in my shoe
yeah and it's just because of the amount
of people that we have coming back here
and again why I would always say that I
think Southwest Ontario produces some of
the best
pot growers and genetics
uh passing through
uh in Canada
a lot of that though is due to community
building because like you know the hemp
Nation thing like when that happened and
you were offering what you did at that
place a lot of people learned a lot
even it
literally planted the seed for a lot of
people right because yeah Chris gave uh
gave people the option to buy their own
seed not take bag weed and find a seed
and not know you know what the [ __ ] it
is we were we were kind of weeding out
some of that we were telling you
uh what it is we will tell you it's
going to be something within this range
because it is an F1 we just took this
Scentsy seed and we took this greenhouse
seed and we grew them and this is what
we got
and the mother was this and the dad was
this and this is what they looked like
and that's when they finished and and so
on so we gave him an educated guess but
it was literally planting the seed of
people uh when I started that uh grow
your tuition campaign in in London here
just for all the students right giving
them discounts I had a coupon on a flyer
that gave them a discount on grow guides
and uh and then like I said uh
information the best thing about
information is it's free if you uh
wanted to come down on the Sundays and
we have cultivation talks you know I
didn't mind sharing that I [ __ ] love
talking about that's what we're doing
right now right like yeah we were doing
this back in the mid 80s I mean 90s kind
of thing
it's actually really hard for me
to tell people today with like what
we're doing right now and all the forums
and IG and all the ways that people can
connect how tough it was to get
information
how how small groups used to be how rare
it was to find people that like knew
what they were doing
um and then the other thing is like I
always I'd still consider like 90s to be
like the Golden Era of weed
um just in the sense because
basically any like weed was rare enough
that it could take too long it could not
look that great as long as it worked
really well yeah it was going to gain
popularity you know because there was
there was only so much of it so like a
lot of the famous strains in the 90s
Rose to the top because they were really
good yeah you know yeah and they didn't
really have
I think a lot of people nowadays you
know
um the placebo effect comes into play a
lot with all these new genetics sure
there's a lot of fire out there but
there's people that are just like oh
well this is this strain right oh this
is a Kush oh well and it has the smell
of a Kush but it has uh you know it
doesn't really rock you like some of the
other yeah but since it since it you
know smells like it looks like it [ __ ]
it must [ __ ] be the close enough and
then they're just like oh yeah I'm super
high I'm super high you know I've done
that with my my clients at The
Compassion Center where they were they
were like oh you know what I Northern
Lights doesn't work for me it's you know
I've tried it and it's it's just um you
know I smoked it back in the 80s it I I
didn't like it didn't didn't get me high
okay well the Northern Lights I have is
not the same but I give them the
northern lights that is fire for other
people they're like yeah it didn't
really do it for me I mean your mind is
quite strong tool yeah so I would do the
same thing and I was infamous with my
organic traveler crew like all the the
you know glass blowers that were
downstairs and all this I thought they
were these these pot snobs and they'd be
the same thing like oh yeah you know
what that's that stuff's you know it's
not that great okay well they had that
tasty Bud [ __ ] that little [ __ ]
flavoring cream oh God yeah [ __ ]
plants Juicy J's tasty buds yeah
whatever [ __ ] so I would actually take
some of that and I would take [ __ ]
great pot but you know fragal this one
glass blower uh he was just always
against like yeah I know that but he was
like oh I had this Cherry Bomb once and
it was [ __ ] awesome so I [ __ ] took
the Cherry [ __ ] and [ __ ] yeah did a
little light mist on it kind of thing
and put it in the jar and let it sit
there and and uh same [ __ ] string
that I gave him right yeah made the nugs
look a little bit different made them
look a little bit smaller I was like Hey
listen this is not called Cherry Bomb
it's called cherry blossom this guy just
came through he's from uh
or [ __ ] Peterborough and he opens it
up and he's like oh yeah it smells me
like this is good it [ __ ] smokes he's
like yeah that's [ __ ] see we need to
start trying this this strain I was like
[ __ ] you dude that's the goddamn what's
that we [ __ ] you smoke [ __ ] two
weeks ago you said with [ __ ] you know
it's tasty butt on it and now none of
those guys would [ __ ] trust me to
give him any [ __ ] pot I know oh [ __ ]
no yeah you ruined that [ __ ] you man
that's [ __ ] tasty bud and I was like
no it's actually not kind of thing but
so yeah we've been accused of using that
on uh some of the blueberry stuff we put
out
the tasty Bud stuff like when people
smell like good blueberry stuff yeah
this is a syrup I think a lot of people
you know
um and if you smell my B-93 like it
doesn't it smells like
uh not the blueberry smell but it smells
like a a pint of actual blueberries
right you don't have to see a little bit
more that that sweet earthy Aroma kind
of thing and again it's from it's from
93. that's when we started the seed
right like it's an it's an old [ __ ]
plant kind of yeah I got them I'm going
back to that that era and it would have
been
I would I would have got them indirectly
uh okay or basically it was when he was
first releasing his blueberries if I
remember correctly I mean Tony could
have had it earlier don't get me wrong
but I think that Tony had with Simon and
they had cerebral
in 94. right and then they split and
Tony made sag Martha and Simon made
serious yeah
you know I think Dan I think DJ Short
was with um Tony with Tony and uh they
did the bubble gum and they called it 94
blueberry if I remember correctly yeah
he worked with Tony he sold it through
Tony first and then they had some
falling out and then I think he moved to
Dutch Passion yes yeah he got angry at
all of them and then he and then he
moved it to Canada yeah yeah yeah yeah
and that's the thing is and this is
where
um he met up with Steve and red and I'll
call him the air mechanic because I
don't know of a nickname for him but uh
he was uh
great grower
um didn't do anything huge like 12
lights or something but I I not if I'm
not mistaken again red would be the
better uh
uh information on the background on this
but I believe they bred the blue
satellite
okay I know they were doing a grow out
for DJ and
um
but that was a little bit later so I the
seed that I got was just before that and
that's where I was thinking that it
might have came indirectly
from DJ
um but it would have been like I thought
it would I know it was 93 but I thought
it was actually from him and not from
from Tony from is it is it a clone
that's still alive yeah
oh
um
I literally just killed off like six 75
to 80 of my genetics yeah guys I'm just
I'm retiring I'm tired really frustrated
I was actually there today trying to
salvage what
um one of my staff
from the center he's like if you can
save me all these strains I'll find
somebody to grow to to babysit them for
you until you get over this divorce [ __ ]
and if I wanted to go into it like
out of the hundred and
twenty three
123 strains that I had
I had data collected on their use
medical uses through the compassion uh
Center going back almost 15 years yeah
so because in Canada we cannot say well
this strain works for this medical
condition sure
um what I could do is saying out of the
30 people that suffer from Ms this is
their the top selling Indica this is the
top selling sativa I think that's
responsible actually and it would just
be basically giving them
um well it's data
let's say again it's data to use I mean
yeah
like literally for almost 15 years I've
collected this that's the most important
[ __ ] I had it all [ __ ] ready and
packaged to go into the LPS up here and
I just [ __ ] saw the dark side of the
[ __ ] industry that was just chewing
and spitting out anybody from the
movement yeah and I took a lot of heat
from people I think we talked about this
last time from you know people in the
movement that thought I sold out by
going to um uh
uh into the lb LLP
um legal I mean it's crazy because it's
what you've been working for your entire
life you know yeah it's like [ __ ] it
like that's [ __ ] crazy you can't
[ __ ] steer the boat if you're
standing on the shore [ __ ] yelling
like get on the phone well I mean as
like in the best Direction you can and
that's what I was doing with my genetics
I was like I can't I'm again
strange names or names to me because I'm
I'm out for the medical benefits of it I
don't give a [ __ ] what you call it and
that's going to come back to the dog
[ __ ]
um where it doesn't it didn't really
make a difference now I had a I had a
strain that called warm diarrhea right
oh okay wise
really marketable yeah you know it was
this one strain didn't produce what the
[ __ ]
but holy God Jesus did it ever smell
like dog [ __ ] [ __ ] warm diarrhea like
hot summer time [ __ ] diarrhea
squirted like kind of smell yeah
I know it phenomenal
it's like so I called it that I was like
I don't I don't know what it is it's a
[ __ ] clone that I went to I was
Consulting a guy's Garden he [ __ ]
said these of my strains I said where
are they from he's like I [ __ ] you know
my brother-in-law gave me some of this
and some of that and I found some seed
and this and that and this one [ __ ]
the one plant was like holy God Jesus
that's nasty I Gotta Have It kind of
thing and um
you know with uh with Sam when he was
doing his skunk and um everybody was
like oh it's you know yeah that that and
I was just having this conversation
today actually with my cousin because
he's like I had a skunk one back when uh
back when uh Tilly was [ __ ] growing
for the center right and I'll find the
picture because it made it was a full
page picture in high times and it's this
kid holding one of the nugs up and he's
holding his forearm and the nug is twice
the size of this kid's Forum oh wow that
was my skunk one and it's you know you
grow the true skunk one I I believe is
mainly grown for structure more than
that skunky smell if I'm not mistaken I
think
Sammy was actually trying to get rid of
and I think I was that's his claim yeah
you guys covered this you don't you
don't follow like modern IG culture and
stuff but like there's been a massive
massive movement on finding roadkill
skunk which everyone because I was gonna
out west today
this guy and I don't know his [ __ ]
name I'll find out but he sent one of my
uh Sasquatch the kid that works away uh
who's like the Cannabis connoisseur he
ended up getting
um this [ __ ] jar of skunk one I
opened it up and I was like holy [ __ ]
that's my skunk one it smells like and I
called it roadkill skunk one I didn't
know that was a name called roadkill I
was yeah yeah it's not a strain though
it's just it's just a reference to a
type of expression that can come from
afghanis or skunky plants okay well this
uh this skunk one grew
the the structure and the and my cousin
just said listen if you get it I want to
breed with it because
um
it has
the if it's the same cut that this guy's
sending me I it smells the same the nug
looks the same I have to find out if the
structure is the same because the
structure was what the the skunk one was
all about like yeah I have that big nug
that [ __ ] can hold itself and
um
like I said this uh Tilly kid that was
um growing and we're doing on an ebb and
flow cable and they were just spikes
they were just these big beautiful
[ __ ] fragrant roadkill smell uh
skunk one
so you know and I think I was I lit I
try to put some of your guys podcasts on
I don't listen to podcasts so in all
honesty the first and only podcast I
really listened to was like three nights
ago when it was while I was going to bed
and I wanted to hear what we did yeah
and uh something else came up and you
guys were talking about Sam's reading
trying to breed out the skunk one the
skunk yeah you know actually and uh and
uh focusing on structure and I was like
that's ironic because that's what I
wanted but I was also chasing that
um that super skunk kind of uh Aroma
yeah and it was this roadkill like Yeah
because it doesn't smell like skunk when
you spray it that tarry kind of burnt
[ __ ] stuff it had that [ __ ] you
driving down the [ __ ] road and you're
like holy [ __ ] yeah you know that's
skunk you know yeah it adds that smell
to it so
um maybe I remember that from like
London I definitely remember skunky
smells and like I I I kind of related to
like the Heineken skunky beer smell more
than animal smell right I have a
question for you Sean this is totally
off topic yeah does Canada get green
Heineken bottles or brown greens not so
yeah great no okay so check it out right
so you can say Jesus Christ but I go to
Holland in the 90s and they have the
Heineken Brewery right is like was again
it moved now like but it was in
Amsterdam and they gave tours you know
and so if you buy a Heineken in Holland
it's in a brown bottle right and you
talked you talked to like the the Dutch
about it and I'm like well why why is it
in a green bottle in America and they're
like oh cause you guys are dumb but it's
iconic over there so you want the green
bottle but it oxidizes so it makes the
beer go skunky and [ __ ] yeah yeah and if
you get it in Europe it's a dark brown
bottle okay because we don't want the
light to [ __ ] it up but that tastes the
cost of taste
skunky beer yeah so it's like and he's
like you buy a Heineken anywhere in
Europe it's in a brown bottle you go to
the USA it's in a green bottle and he's
like it's just advertising we have we
have two we had two beers that were like
the pot beers and it was Heineken and
Moosehead
and Moosehead was also in a green box
you know but they both had that very
skunky skunky like to get a six-pack and
and some weed and smoke weed and smoke
like and drink Moosehead was like that
was the thing you know that was like
they paired you know you guys are so
Canadian bro yeah I
haven't drank beer and
like 20 years
I I just I you know I just had to throw
it out there because I was like shocked
when they literally were like oh we only
do that to the dumb Americans right
that's like legit what they said you
know and so I was like oh I guess that
includes Canadians but yeah um what's
funny about what's funny about the skunk
you know uh is that like we're all so
old now right there was this thing that
tripped me out because you don't feel
old in your head even though when you're
getting old where I saw this thing where
like the 90s are as far away now as the
60s were in the 90s yeah
right and so there's all these smokers
that like they all the stuff we're
talking about all this stuff that's like
our youth you know and you know in our
20s and everything else that was so
common this is all legendary just words
now
the reason why they're hunting that
skunk is because it's gone away and
while it was super common in the 90s and
there was lots of weed that was very
skunky or had skunk type Terps
it's kind of gone away
you know and so now it's like you know
we were talking about how BC Bud Rhymes
or whatever but like Northern all these
strains are coming back again and they
don't even have to be the actual strain
anymore
it just has to have the name yeah
because the name is what survived the
population the users are so young that
they won't know the difference they
don't know they weren't they were
smoking the NL back in the day
um they're not smoking pot anymore kind
of thing right so bark this down you
know like the big the big screen back in
my day was like the nl5 skunk one right
like yeah that was the go-to that was if
you know the center of the road easy to
grow big yield depending on what
phenotype you got you know it kind of
was the best of all worlds and it was
again it was an easy grower kind of
thing but uh you know to find anything
like that I think like pot now is so
bastardized yeah I agree it's it's not
as simple you know and sure
my Matt well I did have another question
we were talking about the triple SC last
time yeah yeah right and so do you have
any contact to any of the good old boys
that were part of that group yeah we
interviewed them okay Corel the original
owner okay now was he out of Amsterdam
or very much very much so he's a Dutch
born
yeah okay so but he's not originally
from the states uh trans he didn't no he
didn't move there from no he's he's
definitely Dutch okay so did they have
offsprings of the
their group in California no they said
they never worked with anyone in the
United States ever now what now work
with I'm just saying thinking that after
they were there
that they move that after maybe some of
their colleagues staff or something I
want to find out about the Golden Boy
because the way I what I was told was
that this strain came from
Ontario and I I wouldn't say maybe like
more up Central north of Southwestern
Ontario but it came from the triple SC
or somebody from that group that is now
living in Canada and we're going back to
like like SSC didn't have a strain
called Golden Boy either
they had they had like M1 M2 M3 M4 M5 m6
and then they have they'd have little
names after but it'd be like Nigerian
Kandahar or skunk one or uh
basic five it was very very basic
there's Williams Wonder small names like
that no Golden Boy though
can you ask them though like yeah if you
can reach out just ask them because the
story that I had was it came from
from
their group and I believe it was bred by
them and it might have had like an M24
or something yeah yeah
um
but and it was a it was a 45-day
finishing plant and that's what was so
was a [ __ ] crazy wasn't the best
yield or it was a really weird looking
plant but it was 45 days was it an
indica or sativa it was I I would say it
would have leaned I would say I wouldn't
even say it would leaned either way I
would have to look at some of the the
pictures that's so fast that I think I
even have
I might have the picture that's like
Mighty might fast isn't it dude it was
super fast it was ridiculously fast it
wasn't a great strain on its own but it
was great for breeding yeah and that's
what I again made the and why it's what
it's called Golden Haze
um because there was other things and it
was chemo and
um uh uh skunk in it
um
and uh we crossed it with the golden boy
because I wanted to speed it up but my
my
um what I was looking for was a fast
growing short fat sativa yeah right so
the um the haze it was a uh uh
Early Skunk
uh chemo
crossed with the haze and then we
crossed it with the Golden Boy to speed
it up
yeah you know see all over the place I
just I found one that seemed to fit the
uh the mold I was looking for
and uh I just caught I didn't have a
seat of it I just had a uh a cutting of
it yeah and then we did breed it with
some other strains my buddy skifa
um who unfortunately has passed away but
he uh
he crossed it with something blue string
maybe it was even like blue sky got to
look it up I might still have some of
those seeds too but I just wanted to
find the lineage of that Golden Boy
because
um I was told it came from the triple s
c boys early 90s maybe mid 90s so they
were done by then yeah they were done
that's what I mean yeah yeah they were
long gone by then um I'm thinking if it
was Offspring from them yes and even
being off literally Offspring for kids
of theirs or something like that moved
to Ontario
yeah I wonder I wonder if his son moved
out there because his son took over the
company eventually yeah he's the one who
runs it now yeah yeah and then again
this wasn't anybody that um
I knew it was yeah sure that was a story
that was brought to me and like I said
the strain was a really unique stream
but it was super fast and I was like
[ __ ] we need it was going to be a
breeding staple for us until we grew it
out and we're just like yeah this plant
is [ __ ] up look any kind of [ __ ] did
you really weird [ __ ] did you like c99
at all since you were looking for plants
that were fast hazy uh I'm growing I
haven't seen 99 right now
uh came from this guy tank out of
Toronto area
um I
did grow I'd have to look at my notes
um
it just tends to be one of those ones
that speaks super fast it didn't stand
out as the you know 45 day okay it might
have been like a 55 day a lot of the
stuff we do was like 56 day kind of
stuff because we had 50 lights and I
needed to produce I needed things to
grow
and finish all around the same time yeah
kind of name for the summer and uh we
did we did do the Cindy 99 it did have a
um uh
uh a following yeah we wanted it we did
uh we did want to bring it in
Incorporated that photographer that you
couldn't remember
yeah Andre Grossman yeah somebody
commented yeah I thought it was gonna be
male frame I think did I
did I send you a notes I was like oh
yeah
but uh yeah Audrey Grossman [ __ ] I love
that guy he was a phenomenal [ __ ]
phenomenal him and there was another
photographer at Amsterdam called himself
Yap he he did like the first really
micro trichrome photography oh okay and
uh he yeah he shot through a microphone
a microscope and uh he did some pretty
interesting uh photography he was like
one of the he was the first I think that
did micro photography on cannabis but uh
Grossman uh
really nice guy uh super talented he's
the one that shot uh Kyle's Special
Blend poster yeah you know
um and uh I lost track of him
um I should try to find him I know I'd
like to talk to him last time I spoke to
him I believe was right after 9 11
and I called him I was trying to find
him in more of a panic because being a
photographer myself if he was in the
city he would be the type of guy that's
running towards the [ __ ] buildings
yeah photos before they came down kind
of thing so I was kind of concerned
about uh about that but yeah anyways
yeah we did a few uh I would say shoots
together because he was well well more
established than I was
um but he did help me because I would I
would find out through him what he was
getting paid and I said well like if
you're going to use the centerfold for
me I want to get paid the same or so
close kind of [ __ ] right yeah well back
then like you did did you do school for
photography yeah yeah I started uh
I did a three-year program here in
London okay so like but you were like
early early cannabis photographer right
how many photographers were around back
then
yeah there wasn't very many of us like
um
I was Andre and I both were listed as
contributing photographers uh in the
um inside cover
right but he ended up getting lots of a
lot more Centerfolds uh covers and stuff
like that
um
and uh
and yeah I don't I think he might have
went to school I'm actually I just met
with fanchon we're gonna I'm gonna put
together a scholarship in my name
ironically for uh the program because I
want to um
uh
uh I want you know kids to know that you
don't have to be a [ __ ] portrait [ __ ]
photographer you know you can be a pot
photographer and still make good and
kind of you know even though I went to
jail for it and [ __ ] like that I think
make a story for a scholarship but uh
well like yeah cool in the last episode
you mentioned like when you were at the
border you had 10 000 negatives like ten
thousand that's a lot of photos man oh
dude I had boxes and bought and I just
found uh
um
I'd love to have you scan some of these
like that did you have you ever thought
about doing a book
no no
did you keep track of the strains in
these pictures like did you write on it
what strength what I used to do
um is I would take a picture
um of the plant and then I take a a
piece of paper and I'd write what the
strain was and put it in the picture and
then I would do a shoot of that train
yeah most Ops and and uh full plant
shots and stuff like that and then um if
I if I liked it enough for and I thought
High Times would like it I would shoot
it on a positive on a slide yeah because
we had better uh color saturation and it
was better for them to uh and then uh a
lot of the times I would bring out my
old Super 8 video camera and videotape
what I was doing in the garden just so I
would have reference uh because I was
doing it for information for myself on
different genetics as well as for for
High Times and for future you know
I mean that's going to be super
important like I don't know if you
understand that but because it because
so much has changed and so many things
have been renamed over the years it was
a really prime time during those years
to get Point like when you say like
point of origin for like land race stuff
this is like point of origin for a lot
of these strains like in their natural
habitat like getting pictures of let's
say Romulan in Canada during this era
that's very special we don't have a lot
of pictures and things like that anymore
when I was up there's a string called
Biker Bob which was a big yeah I've
heard of that out in California in BC
for a while there
um who has set up that I know I I did
this shoot
um
with High Times in mind I think red set
it up
well maybe Mark uh no I don't think Mark
said it somebody set it up but like it
was up in north of Whistler and
um I used to blindfold myself on all
these photo shoots I wouldn't go to a
photo shoot especially if I didn't know
the people yeah when blindfolded I was
not smart you'd never be blamed or
anything yeah I would just wear
sunglasses and I would tape the inside
of sunglasses even if they said I didn't
have to do that they're like dude we
know who you don't want to pop up on
that radar ever somewhere it's just like
you know what dude you have a list of
and on that list is everybody that knows
about your garden yep I don't want to be
on that [ __ ] list if something goes
south I don't want to be on that list
kind of that's smart yeah and uh we
ended up in some really [ __ ] up
back [ __ ] area countries you know good
old boys million dollar [ __ ] grows
I'm sure
um when I was working in the interior we
ended up going to wine and definitely ha
or something like that but super nice
[ __ ] guy and uh ironically his he
blew his [ __ ] Transformer on the pole
when I was there
sparks flying everywhere [ __ ] like
all the lights going off his entire
[ __ ] cruise I met this guy this day
uh it's when I was working on that uh
greenhouse and um his entire [ __ ]
crew [ __ ] bailed everybody [ __ ]
ran because they knew [ __ ] Hydra was
coming right like oh yeah
you know it's on fire kind of [ __ ] and
I'm so used to being the guy that you
know back in the nation days I'm the one
that had the pickup truck with the
topper on it that could fit all the pot
plants and everything in the back yeah
yeah you know I'm not scared of the
[ __ ] cops I mean I think I can outrun
a lot of the cops especially back yeah
so I was just like [ __ ] what are we
doing what are you like how yeah what do
you need to grab let's go you know and
use those things but we need to take
this down we need to shut this door we
need to screw this we need to do this
and I was just like [ __ ] right we
were there for
couple hours maybe before the hydro
people showed up you know because it was
all I think I think he put up his own
[ __ ] Transformer on a pole or
something and and it blew their
Transformer or something so he was
definitely like [ __ ] he's fine but
you know we were just like
we're here to [ __ ] hell I was like I
don't want to know what your [ __ ]
Garden is I you know so I'm blindfolded
when I get here I'm blindfolded when I
leave but while I'm here I'm your
[ __ ] best friend kind of yeah I'll do
whatever it [ __ ] takes but
um yeah I ended up
um I ended up always you know even at
that Garden I don't remember what the
strains were because I think
um one I was a little worried because I
didn't know what I was walking into on
this one it was a friend of a friend
kind of thing and when I got there you
could tell it was definitely organized
guys on two wheels yeah
I don't want and but the Biker Bob you
know most of the guys down riding the
bike of Bob's road bikes yeah yeah it
makes sense I'm just gonna turn on the
light so you can see me better but yeah
yeah did you bring your seed case with
you
I want to start going through it I
didn't start going through it like
sitting on my desk downstairs
because I actually want to go through it
all
um I want to I want to go through it on
the the video with you so we could just
uh so it'd be easier I guess you should
just do a whole session on that yeah I
mean yeah we have to find like because a
lot of the seeds I have are just like
seeds that came to me with a story
that's the but that's the best part
right like that's what people want to
hear is the story so that's these these
seeds can evoke a lot of these stories
that you probably didn't even remember
that you had about certain strains yeah
but again like the Elmwood I normally
didn't know what the [ __ ] the Elmwood is
right like the Elmwood is a a strain
that was
super popular in
certain circles in uh
Southwestern Ontario for outdoor right
but after this people gonna be chasing
it guaranteed people going to be trying
to find it I have a shitload of OCS I'll
send and that's something else like I
was saying is
um yeah but see that's the same thing
like now you know would would uh I'm
gonna call him Double D because I don't
know that's in Canada I used to work for
him
um he's out on the East Coast obviously
um but um if he would know about that
box story yeah I mean Ed would know
about it but um I don't know too many
people that want to talk to Ed yeah but
oh you're referring to to Rosenthal
right yeah yeah someone in the thing was
like no he's referred to Ed Borg I was
like no he's referring to Rosenthal nose
board yeah yeah so yeah just because
um again that's what he told uh
Miss for Hampton Steve when uh when he
was working in Switzerland with those
guys
yeah I think so you know again
everything that we talk about
is and I was just reading something
today about uh the natives a native
saying where you know people like you we
wanna
remember
a purpose on this planet is to uh uh
remember our Legacy or something and it
should be to continue our story kind of
thing and everything that we you know
like we're discussing here as we said
earlier was this is what I was told and
yeah a lot of this shit's just not
written down it's not good and it's not
going to be written down for obvious
reasons so that's why you know when I
get to meet guys like you I'm saying
well if you know somebody that knows
somebody this is what I heard yeah and
they might say yeah there's no way that
happened and then say okay well at least
I know now yeah well that's kind of the
purpose of this podcast is that a lot of
the history is oral like a lot of
history is like verbally passed on you
know and it always was the native yeah
[ __ ] down you know we had some carvings
in the in the uh in the um uh on the
walls in the caves you know and on
stretched out leather but no we have a
uh everything is you know it's around
the campfire and tell stories and yeah
hate that to the young ones and you know
when I was at rainbow gatherings you
know the granola Funk with the uh camp
that we were uh staying with and their
contribution was uh building a stage
luckily the one I went to I was able to
help uh build a stage so the elders
could come and tell stories about
earlier years of the rainbow gathering
and the history of jingle Gathering and
I was like well [ __ ] you know we need
that and that's what this uh what I feel
this is is for the uh for the canvas
industry for the for the seeds is you
know a lot of the [ __ ] this is uh this
is what I've been told is what I hear
and if we can find people to like I say
with the triple s c Golden Boy story you
know is that you know was somebody
pulling my leg with somebody that told
me this did believe it because somebody
told them that yeah I'm still tempted to
go he's like the one person that I knew
that was worked with Neville will help
them
I wasn't sure about using names yeah
yeah indeed okay yeah I think that
I think he'd be that would he would at
least know something I would think yeah
so and like I said what the story was is
you know there was uh uh somebody never
was supposed to sell a uh a bunch of
genetics to somebody never came through
he threw him in the back of a freezer
when he was pulling out of I believe
Amsterdam
um he came across them he passed him on
to Ed
supposedly for like an outstanding debt
or something like that or maybe just
because he had them and they ended up
um with Steve in Switzerland yeah and
whatever happened to the fast beer and
and all that stuff yeah the fast few the
fast Patty the night Queens are they
still alive
no
yeah but the Ortega which was one of
them is in the Louie yeah um
I don't they didn't really like it like
I said before they didn't like any of
the strains that I liked like the the
fast Spear and the night night night
Queen uh because they were um sativas
yeah uh Steven and red and those guys
were all big Indica fans so they love
the Ortega you know
um I wish I could remember some of the
other streams I'll have to kind of go
through I have a thank you for joining
us on this journey we are forever
thankful that enough people watch us to
keep us going with that in mind you can
show your support for the show by liking
subscribing and sharing the show we
don't advertise so we need you also hit
righteats.com and syndicatecare.com to
show more support for the show
kick over the statues and bring it back
to the farmers
[Music]