all right I'm gonna do the punk records
again
um a lot was missed last time it was in
other rows and I'm doing this to
document it for myself as much as anyone
else so
the one-on-ones which is Joe strummer's
first band that one has crayon on it but
there's another copy right here an older
copy of the original sticker Joe
strummer's first band keys to your heart
one of my favorite songs
um
45 Grave
this one is the sleep in safety LP about
45 Grays schools out
she's so badass
another 45 Grave this one is the I think
it's an EP you're single foreskin it's
good the bad the four skins
seven seconds walk together Rock
together one of my favorites uh LPS from
seven seconds almost a lot of them are
really good but that's so good
uh 999
separates uh what do we got here action
TVs on the blink
Downtown Boy
we have it's the addicts The Sound of
Music
adolescence original press
uh adrenaline OD
Agent Orange
uh anti-nor League
so what
spizz energy
Athletico space but they change their
name a bunch Avengers
this will be 52s it's rock lobster and
uh my favorite 52 girls some old stiff
baiters
Battalion of saints
right that's a good shot
uh big boys
more big boys
you know what they don't get covered
nearly enough
um yeah I love the big boys one of my
favorites this is Blitz now it's not the
voice for Generations or second album
Second Empire Justice I love it one of
my favorite albums of all time the boys
alternative shirt but I'm a big boys fan
and the Hollywood brats some of some of
my favorite music when I was uh
in the black jerks I was writing
um a lot like boys style team generate
mixed uh to hell with the boys I had
someone from Australia send me that one
um I'm nice to help otherwise which one
says this is uh which one is this
there's a self-titled here yeah that's
the self-titled original really sorry
this is the one that came from Australia
to hell with the boys
um
some broken bones
Chesterfield Kings I used to have a
really cool Christmas card from them I
sold one of them records back in the day
and they sent the Christmas card and I
cherished it and lost it
one of my heroes of punk rock will
always be Billy childish The Man Behind
the milkshake the mighty Caesars the
head coach even the head Cody's
um really childish
more here's uh poems of laughter and
violence it's a spoken word Billy
childish Elfie
um this is the 1982 cassettes this is
released on his own label
uh where is it oh no it's not I thought
this was on his own little this is on
the ladies
huh his own label is
let's see
his own label is what am I forgetting
why are these stupid together
here you go hangman records God that's
stupid why did I remember that hangman
records okay we got China White danger
zone
original press
um
Clash
combat Rock
combat Rock again because you can't have
too much combat Rock right combat 84 one
of the best oy bands ever
uh Comsat Angels the most underrated LP
I own
they're so good so good the whole LP
this whole LP waiting for a miracle if
you've never heard them and you like
like the Cure or Depeche Mode or gang of
four specifically check it out one of my
all-time favorites
um and more CS Angels come to Angels
it's not as good as that wing for
miracle LP James whiten the contortions
some of the best of no wave uh more
contortions all original uh James White
and the blacks same guy
Prime this is a lighter LP
not that great uh daggerman on hangman
records this is one that Billy childish
put out and it's like uh
it's more like uh like like skinheads
playing punk rock it's pretty good it's
like oh wait not it's hard to explain
garage anyway the Damned and Tesla
Gloria
uh we have White Rabbit oh uh I'm sorry
single
uh damn more dead that's original press
um got the kill sessions I have a big
damn fan always day glow abortions
um Dead Boys I do have a lot of Dead
Boys
uh there's a Sonic Reducer
it's a good one uh young loud and snotty
anyway I think there's one more yeah I
gotta Living Dead Boys
is that it on Dead Boys no oh yeah dead
candies and God We Trust
um
it's a little hard to do a Franken
Christ
death the punk band death
is degenerates this is not this is a
later release on Rave up records I had
the seven ink sets original but they're
a great Texas Fan if you haven't heard
of them check them out
um the diodes
Eddie and the hot rods teenage
depression
we got uh what's this enemies
of Detroit it's been a while since I
looked at it
Fang Where the Wild Things Are I keep
hearing Fang reference lately it's weird
like I nobody talks about him this last
week I've heard about it like three
times uh fire engines this is like
um like a weird
Jazz Butchery type LP I got it because
it was on
why it got this they had a seven inch it
was worth a bunch of money on a certain
label
and I got it real cheap so I checked it
out and loved it anyway game Gang Green
we've got Generation X
germs now this isn't repress obviously
uh the germs first seven inch farming
um Hayden Nation GG
the Hammersmith gorillas these guys had
such a major uh influence on my writing
and dressing and everything like
yeah Jesse Hector the singer of the band
pretty much brought I will make the
claim that he really brought a lot of
rockabilly to England a good portion
that was inspired by Jesse Hector and um
if you can there's a Jesse Hector CD
there we go this is like a early like
Teddy boy Jesse Hector running wild with
a message to the World DVD and in there
hopefully it's still in here and I
didn't lose it oh it's not in here
oh there's just two who I don't know one
of the discs is missing and there's a
DVD of Jesse
um I thought I might have to buy it
again because I don't think it's in here
but yeah he's on there and it's a
documentary about Jesse Hector and it's
really freaking good if you don't know
about him go check him out every punk
rocker should know about Jesse Hector
and his major contributions to punk rock
and Pub rocks
government issue Joyride I would rather
have like this bull here's the head
Cody's
have level travel covering the sonics
um Holier now it's like weird like
hardcore skatepunk
infantry this is one of the dudes bands
from the dragons that passed away San
Diego's dragons
um
is the dude in the far left he passed
away and yeah he was in a punk band
called the dragons went to see um the
dragons play right after his funeral and
a Ace Frehley showed up from kiss and
played the zero and the zero showed up
and they played Dragon songs with the
dragons it was it was insane
the Jazz butcher uh this isn't really
Punk but it's in here just because more
Jazz butcher conspiracy
you guys put your five
Jody Foster's [ __ ] Army
this one's a little tighter I need to do
some records over uh the last I didn't
have a bunch more jfa it's on my jfay at
least it got mixed in here's a last
so the last or another one of my
favorite oh here's that some more jfa it
got hidden no the same one
the last or one of my favorite bands
from LA
um they were also big Inspirations on
The Descendants a lot of people don't
know that
um they're La explosion is amazing
get some more GFA yeah without order
boom we got Public Image Limited shirt
those guys are show punk rock
jfa if you ever watch this any of you
guys you want to go party let me know
let me know I want to party with jfa all
right and then we have uh
mad Garden EP
back in the right spot
I'm sucking a cat sorry about the view
here all right all right and we got two
uh Joy Division
this shouldn't be in Punk but I don't
have a metal section I don't own metal
records I don't really like metal but
Juggernaut I bought this at a thrift
store as a kid and it was so funny like
just speed metal yeah so I kept it
here's a repressed it's the kleenex Lily
put LP that one's an actual repress
which I don't have a lot of so I'm kind
of calling them out when I see him
um
more last oh you've got a lot of order
again okay when it happens more last
this one is the
um
objections or something a better song on
this side this kind of feeling
um
the last Drive where's the LA explosion
all this stuff's out of order
earned it
you're driving me nuts when it's out of
order
okay
I see what's going on here
okay here's more last I know you're I'm
trying to last
um more or less that's enough troll last
objections
there it is the LA explosion this one is
what started my last craze
I can't remember where I found that but
it was fairly cheap and it was so
life-changing good life-changing good
the last ones
I saw the last drive already The
Laughing dogs with their maker
the layers Liars l-y-r-e-s Menace uh
there's another Menace but it's the
single
or not the lp the other one was the
minute single
rest in peace GLC uh method actors
what else we got
the mighty seeds there's more Billy
childish but this is all pretty rare
old stuff the mighty serious users of
trash
how cool is that you can't out cool
Billy childish ever can't be done show
me someone other than Jason Jesse who
can out cool really childish Mighty
Caesars again
I've got the milkshakes the milkshakes
another really childish band
a little bit obsessed just a little
yep that's that's what it's about and
some more just because why not
they used to be so hard to find in the
US back when I was collecting you had
the important for the UK if you wanted
them and I don't know what the status of
all that is now but yeah maybe some Sex
Pistols uh Punk prayer Ronnie Biggs I
can't what the other side is uh great
rock and roll Swindle it's the biggest
blow and something else I don't know
uh repressed Misfits these are friends
Misfits
Misfits uh the nipple Erectors the knit
nips with Shane McGowan from The Pogues
one of my favorite like Powerpuff LPS
um I know everything's my [ __ ]
favorite whatever uh Peter and the test
tube babies
pear brown eyes
rum sodomy in the Lash
that's like pre-spider Stacy Pogues
though I want I really want um Pokemon
that's one of my favorites and that's
what spider Stacy sings pointed sticks
famous Canadian band
ignore the Laughing
um
pop rivets uh I believe this is a let's
see this might be a later press
but I do have an original pop rivets
empty sounds from Anarchy Ranch this
took so many years to find it I first
heard them when I was like 16. uh no
probably 18 19. um but this is mod comps
and I chased it ever since and it took I
mean I had eBay searches going for years
and stuff to find this pop rivets LP was
insane I don't know if it's still that
hard but I mean back then things were
really hard to find I mean we had eBay
but it was just it was just barely
starting uh Park Dukes whatever I never
liked that man
um it's this one Pretty Boy Floyd in the
gems I think it's the same uh label as
the action
see
yeah protects this is a later press
I don't think this was ever a LP for us
but protects are badass so I bought it
uh pure hell
pure hell and this is a later press too
it comes with the poster
the radiators from space really good
early Chiswick stuff
radio Bird Man
that was hiding up back in there
um we got what's this
the raunchettes
you've got
Reagan years
uh
very very responsible for like most of
my political white deals this in a lot
of Bad Religion maybe some lagwagon
honestly totally honest yeah
but Reagan youth hardcore
influenced me politically they were so
smart man
um Red Alert
yeah
uh residence
I mean I they're not my favorite they're
kind of noise
Rose Tattoo we've got some Sharpies
Angry Anderson in the Sharpies from
Melbourne
uh some more rose tattoo I believe this
one is the one that has nice Boys on it
yeah
one of the best songs ever
um
sacred order e-ticket old Escape hunt
got the Saints I'm stranded I think it's
a French press
I love the Saints big time uh more
Saints
lips lipstick on Your Collar my favorite
eternally yours
um
scream this is an early press but not
original original this word repressed
things a lot the sect it's actually
really really really good Punk
on a razor razor I had a lot of mod Punk
and ska on it so if you see those don't
don't ignore the razor seizure
it's your money God
punk as [ __ ] take your money and shove
it all right uh Sex Pistols flogging a
dead horse uh it's kind of a off-brand
to help you most people have never seen
sham 69. if you're a punk rocker and you
don't know sham 69 shame on you
and because Sid Vicious single come on
everybody my way and something else
which like out of all the great rock and
roll swindles songs those are my
favorite
um didn't like a lot from it the slits
cut right before Ariana passed I got to
see the slits in San Diego and they were
absolutely amazing it was an honor to
meet her so she'll be Mommy's little
monster
tattooed on my back Soldiers of Fortune
no wimps or posers the American way all
right
um we got the sub-humans Canada
great band often kind of confused for
other subhumans but way different music
Suburban stud slam another LP it's
totally overlooked never talked about
super good we got Talking Heads
um
tsol beneath the Shadows
only one one of the only ones worth
owning from tar babies a kind of like
funky Punk
toy dolls Nelly the elephant
V2
also got
I thought the vandals this is the
original press yellow labels Woodland
Hills address
sorry vanilla muffin sugar oi we got to
play with them it was a wild night all
night that night
uh the Venom punk rock that's a late
press
vice squad this is actually
an interesting one my squad is an old
boy band and uh
oh
we played with him one night and um four
of my three or four of my bands played
with them so they signed it um
yeah well they were so [ __ ] cool to
the peanut butters they called us the
peanut butters because it rhymed with
Nutters and like our senior was cutting
himself up and bleeding so they thought
we were [ __ ] nuts I thought it was
nuts that I played three shows with
bands in the same night
um Warsaw later press
this is a really old press of Warsaw
um
Wasted Years
ah Wayne County and electric chairs
we've got white cross
see that one wasn't there last time
um X
and
youth Defense League early oi
so that's probably what I'll stop it
today there's tons of um compilations in
here that I'll go through another time
like
like old chisholit compilations with
[ __ ] screwdriver and Motorhead on it
to
like oddsbods mods and sods old mod
compilations you know I've got tons of
really amazing old compilations
um
there's other cool ones that have like
cat and jazz on them and like Makara
shaharazad weird little splits from
later on but yeah we'll go through that
some other time
anyway thanks for showing up and looking
at some punk rock cheers