what's up Syndicate crowd here we have
the original Haze poster trying to keep
myself out of reflection but this is
behind archival glass sealed and it's a
reason I haven't made reproduction
posters it's going to cost a lot to uh
get it yanked out of this scanned and
all that so my reflection is going to be
a part of it I apologize I don't want it
there but you're going to have to see
the shape of my ugly head behind it what
we have here is the original Haze Cosmic
Boogie poster this one was sourced bya
granddaddy mic um I believe this was
given out at the Hempfest 2013 as an
award and then I purchased it from
someone who won the won the uh
contest Mike owns the Lion Share of
these posters and for a while he was
selling reproductions no longer is um on
that page for the reproductions he broke
down what some of the meanings were
behind some of this stuff or at least
gave some insight to it and I found some
of it Illuminating so I'm going to go
through even though I've done a video on
the The Cosmic Boogie poster before I'm
going to go through and kind of
highlight some of this stuff because
it's one of the rarest items in cannabis
I mean uh if I remember correctly the
last one sold for upwards of five grand
probably a little more um yeah so if
you're hunting for these things be
prepared to wait a long time and uh to
spend spend a lot you know to spend a
lot so with that we'll start at the top
we we have the silver haze
bud with trademark underneath it it's
really hard to see it's really
light then we have connoisseur's Choice
cultivated California
Cannabis down here it says
Americana 19 I can't really tell what
some of these things say cuz my vision's
so bad
now but yeah that's some of the inner
writing that's really tiny people have
asked to see on the podcast cast when I
get a chance and then we
have warning in some states cannabis is
illegal
enjoy another cool thing are the signs
of the
zodiac because as Farmers we
rely on the
seasons and you know back then the
Farmers Almanac was really big and uh
this kind of represents that the growing
Seasons as you can see there's weed
leaves under
each little horse scope
sign it's all beautifully done I I would
love to know who did the art for this
there's not a lot of info out there
about it um what else do we have we
have organically grown acclimatized
what's that mean it's grown
organic and it's acclimatized to North
America's outdoor I mean realistically
Santa Cru outdoor but they're kind of
putting it out there that it's grown and
acclimatized that they have Haze a
sativa over here that is growing right
it's finishing proper all that um see
where is it no chemicals yeah organic No
Seeds they obviously don't want you
getting their seeds um let's see is and
then there's somewhere it says in nature
we trust but I can't remember where
that's exactly
at anyway um then we have my favorite
part the scale the Triple Beam scale
what that signifies is Honest Weight and
the triple beam balance represents
ethical business practices integrity and
Trust according to granddaddy Mike so
that's what that means and if you see it
says weight there on that side and can't
honest on that side so honest weight God
some of this is
so
light and um the enjoy
and it says enjoy celebrates the spirit
of the Cannabis
cultivation at work in the haze and
there's a quick side note that
granddaddy Mike put on the on the thing
on the poster page and it says it is
interesting to sometime God it's so hard
to read this it is interesting
to remember that in 1975 to 1976
topshelf cannabis was $50 to $60 an
ounce and that silver Hayes was
introduced at $250 an oun
the entire Harvest sold in 90
days wow can you imagine selling outdoor
everything gone in 90 days you know for
that price it's crazy and real quick
I'll read right here what uh the poster
says in clandestine location sparsely
scattered throughout California a few
dedicated Farmers cultivate the herb
cannabis as a way of life anyone can
grow weeds and see the Virgin green but
to cultivate the Exotic Queens beyond
your dreams you should have dedication
sensitivity to plant life consistency a
little basic knowledge Good Karma and a
great desire to find harmony with Mama
nature the basis for any strong healthy
plant is the soil it grows in resin
producing herbs grow best in soil that
is neutral to semisweet the larger the
bush or tree whatever it may be the
larger the root structure needed to
support it Roots develop most freely in
a loose rich soil
mix one yard of soil composed of 30%
mushroom compost 30% Redwood sawdust 40%
Sandy LOM top soil mix organic nutrients
3 lb of hoof and Horn meal 5 lb of rock
phosphate 4 lb of kelp 1 lb of natural
compost 1 lb of Iron 5 lb of gypsum and
5 lb of
dolomite mix soil and minerals
thoroughly and let it sit for at least
one week then check the the soil with a
soil testing kit for pH and add
agricultural lime to bring pH to 7.5 to
8.5 range semi for the connoisseur's
treat spring arrives and with it comes
New Life fresh spirit and a great hope
for the new crop plant your favorite
seeds on the 6th or 7th of April the
Moon is in cancer best sign for planting
above ground herbs in May the third
fourth and fifth are good if you're
still not together try June 8th and 9th
while the Moon is in scorp iio when you
irrigate make sure that the Moon is in
one of those signs when POS when
possible cancer is the most excellent
time to irrigate Taurus Scorpio and
Pisces are also good for irrigation
pruning should be done only in the third
quarter patience is the real secret and
true Tre test try to make it until
December 10th or 11th when the moon is
in Leo and harvest conditions are
perfect so if you can dig
it in nature We Trust Spirit of 7
shout out to the haze crew the Santa
Cruz hay crew um not A lot's known about
them uh the Hayes Brothers story is very
mysterious I've heard uh several
iterations of it um some from granddaddy
Mike himself that involves an actual
female is one of the main Growers um
yeah it's fascinating fascinating
there's always RL um I hope he's still
alive if he is I hope he contacts me cuz
I'd love to talk to him um but yeah I'm
not going to talk a dude or anything but
yeah anyways uh thanks for coming on
this Cosmic Boogie Haze Journey with me
I know I probably talk about this poster
too much but it's maybe one of the uh
most special things and the longest
chases I've had in cannabis so thanks
for showing up