welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate and we're here this week with
part two of our outdoor Extravaganza
talking about some of the new strains
that were harvested this year with uh
peaches Kush of the Giants little Hill
and of course thousandfold is the host I
won't be here this week again but I'm
back the next week um one thing I did
want to tell you about about was that
we're having a contest right now uh for
hitting 10K Subs we finally made it
we've been talking about it for a while
so go check out the contest video it'll
be up when this hits um and you'll be
able to see all the Deets on it lasts
about a week it's available for the
Instagram account breeders.
syndicate.net on the show on I believe
April
1st and all going to have a separate
contest for the patreon members as well
all the details will be in that video go
check it out for now let's start the
show uh all right there was one more
strain I wanted to talk about that kind
of caught my attention from last year
and it was um something I got from my
buddy from anaku genetics up in Seattle
he sent me something called Isn't She
Lovely and it's um it's a purple
Pineapple Express to a gorilla glue
number four and it was the first time I
had seen uh a heavy purple plant that
smelled like pure pining so it I I I
smelled pining and and gotten really
nice Pine smells out of out of a lot of
strains but never a dark purple strain
um and there's there's hint of like a
little carolene or a little pepper in
there but it's mostly dominated by
pining and so that that's another one
that struck me as interesting and struck
other people when I'm sharing or when
when I'm cracking jars somebody will
will grab the grab that jar and you know
they'll be surprised just as much as I
am to get that kind of smell out of
Purple weed it's uh it was another one
of the highlights of of last year's grow
for
me nice that nice have you ever like
been to a party or a contest or maybe
just
like a group of friends together that
they all bring their jars and like you
look everybody's opening and and and
smelling and like you look like over the
course of the night or the day or
whatever and seeing like certain jars
will just be rans sacked and other ones
are still sitting there full have you
guys ever noticed that it's like a table
test it's like you're not really
watching but like that like it tells you
what other people are liking you know
what I mean yeah that was that's what
happened at the party last year is there
were lots of jars that were emptied
quickly and there were lots of jars that
were still Plum full left on the table
that's always fun to see honestly you
know yeah had it happen yeah kind of it
tells the story itself you know you
don't it talks for itself it's like an
unofficial little judge judgment and
it's like oh okay it's a poll right it's
like a everyone's voting basically right
maybe you know what I'm just thinking
about it right to make it as objective
as possible people shouldn't see how
much is left in each jar because that
might in of itself encourage more people
to like take from the same jar so I feel
like the jars should like be opaque or
something for it to be like a good test
because otherwise people are just going
to notice which jar is already
empty yeah anyway
sorry um yeah I think uh I think that
covers it mostly for for stuff well we
we could
want to have a second did peaches want
to have a second round of
highlights um you know the only I would
say the other one that I really enjoyed
in the uh Garden this year was Riot's
bubbleberry
V2 um it really did well there was some
blueberry T TPS and a few of them that
were just you know really nice and it it
was one of the best growing ones as far
as structure wise the way it grew it
didn't hardly need any kind of staking
or anything um I was really happy with
that one so nice seems to be
consistently one of the easiest you know
best growing things around um because
like everyone says that and I I saw that
too myself yeah I got a pack of the
bubbleberry that I'm waiting to go for
next year I wanted to do it this year
but I decided to do the the blue garig
and the uh the uh the the Kush Bonnet um
whatever the blue resin cush this is
just some arm armchair breeder
theorizing for me but I I wonder if it's
like one step away from becoming
something like quite amazing in terms of
like it's got such a strong base I feel
like or is such a good base for
something and I feel
like it's perfectly gray as it is but I
wonder if something could kind of like
take it take it a little bit further I
just don't know what that this is
specifically the bubbleberry V2 your the
bubbleberry yeah okay I'd like to cross
it with the barber
bud that's what I'd like to do with it
cuz I
wash um I went up and I washed what 3.6
lbs of
bubbleberry um and unfortunately she's
not a washer at least not the fenos I
had um but I have a feeling that in her
is some potential and then I think if it
gets crossed you know cuz the barber bud
is shishkaberry by Afghani one and I
just think if we took that
the bubbleberry V2 and put them together
that you could get some really good
crosses and then increase the potential
for washing a little bit
better hell yeah
interesting all right yeah so I think
that does a a pretty good job of just
going over what what we grew last year
and what we were what we're really
elated with and for the next little
segment I think it would be fun to talk
about um and this doesn't have to be a
long segment we can't there's not a lot
of juice to squeeze out of here but just
talking about postseason cleanup um
preparations for next year do you guys
do everything after fall and it's all
prepped for when spring comes around or
do you let the winter happen and then
prep in Spring and uh you know what kind
of entails prepping for for your
Following season um it'll be the next
little topic that we go over uh little
Hill you want you want to start us off
here and tell us what your postseason
operations is like well I I do the least
amount possible I I'm usually pretty
burnt out and and ready to call it a
season by the end yeah and um I mean I
planted a cover crop in September while
there were still plants in the ground um
it it still hasn't really taken yet and
I don't know why I've always had issues
with with cover crops there and they've
always been very hard to to get going
before before winter um so I'll Reed
again this spring and and see what I can
get going the cover crop was a mix of
everything Clover
legumes um
grasses everything okay um just because
I don't know what's really gonna perform
for me um and I've tried this over the
years so much and the the weeds seem to
do fine so those will get tilled back in
but um coover besides cover cropping
like I roll up my trellises to reuse the
the trellis netting because my beds are
long and linear
um I'm I'm I'm actually glad that works
out well because I I can use that
trellis for years and uh that stuff's
expensive so um but as far as like yeah
not not much else in the order of
cleanup um you know besides like
disconnecting irrigation and stuff like
that my stems are still in the ground
um there's no sense in wrestling them
out at the end of the season because if
you just let them rot they will pull out
with no effort in the springtime yeah so
that's that's what I let them do and
then you leave most of that roof ball in
the soil which is good to break down in
there and you're really just pulling out
the stem which uh makes life a lot
easier if you you can spend you can
spend days pulling out root balls and
it's just there's just no point Y they
come out so easy after they brought and
you know I don't have to like I don't
have to remove all trace of of evidence
of a grow so I I don't have to worry
about that but if you you know that's if
you have to do that that's that's
different but I don't so I definitely
like Lum
Rod yeah oh one other thing sorry
uh for the greenh houses I I have to
take my skins off um in the winter
because they'll just collapse under snow
load
oh yeah rather than taking them off and
pulling them back on which is such a
task um we just roll them up to the
center of the greenhouse um because they
have roll up sides anyway so we just
keep rolling them all the way up to the
very peak of the greenhouse and then tie
them off up
there
and there's not enough room for snow to
really
collect and uh and that that makes
putting them on in the spring a heck of
a lot easier just have to untie and let
let gravity do the rest and right right
so it's so much nicer than wrestling
with those things in the spring and the
wind and all that stuff you guys they're
big green houses they're 108 feet long
some of them and um it it's a
task so that's my that's my into of
season
breakdown yeah I'm in I'm in the same uh
I'm in the same boat as you by the end
of the season I'm just and I'm in trim
jail
my I'm not I'm not too worried about
cleaning up everything down there at the
at the end of the plot and it like you
said like I've there are years where at
the end of the at the end of the year I
I tried uprooting everything and trying
to knock that dirt out of those root
balls you know just sitting there just
beating the hell out of it trying to get
all the dirt out of it yeah that's
that's no fun after after a couple of
season that I just I wait wait until the
the Winter's over wait till that snow's
gone wait for that defrost to come
through and uh and then I start working
my pots and and pulling that stuff out
of there um last year I had a little bit
of a scare is my pots were
frozen H like up into to March almost
yeah yeah I was going to say up into
March I I still had my pots that were
just sitting outside frozen solid I was
trying to get my shovel into them and
not getting anywhere because the the
soil was frozen solid in those
pots yeah we had a win last
year yeah yeah it was it was some heavy
late winter heavy late winners last year
yeah there was there was some moments
there where I was wondering if I'm going
to be able to get out on June 1st
wondering about the the late night temps
that I'm looking
at um yeah like uh it it depends varies
varies from year to year there are some
years while I'll go down there and I'll
cut stocks and I'll make uh I'll make
like walking sticks or I'll use the
bigger stem the the bigger stalks on the
bigger plants for some sort of art or
craft or some sort of hanging bar that
that'll go up in one of the sheds or
something um but other than that yeah
it's you know once Harvest is done I I
leave most of that stuff down there and
and a lot of that work gets done uh
before the before the spring season
before I'm thinking about transplanting
plants
Outdoors
cool what about you
peaches well
um there's been a couple years where I
haven't been able to pull off getting
anything done after harvest because
things have been too much and too crazy
but um this year um I actually managed
to do everything I wanted which was I
went back through and turned all the
pots I added compost and biochar and
then planted a winter cover crop that
has like 12 different things in it and
uh started watering it and they got them
I got them to sprout and they're now all
full so um that's what I try to do
sometimes I don't get to it I got to
pull down all the bamboo pick up all the
uh you know twine I we use hemp twine to
go between the bamboo for all our
trellising and stuff uh
and so we take all that down make sure
there's nothing left up there no trash
no twine put all the bamboo away and
then let it go till
Springtime yeah seems to be a pretty
concise uh agreement amongst a lot of
outdoor guys is by the end of that
season we're you know we're we're hands
are full and and we're pretty exhausted
from doing stuff since Mother's Day
right it is yeah speaking of speaking of
a heavy winter last year I had something
happen to me for the first time and in
this little Valley um I so for my water
source I'm
about where I actually grow my outdoor
plants I'm about 200 225 yards away from
a creek a natural Creek Inlet and so I
have
120 I think 120 gallon tote that I fill
with the creek water water and then spig
it and tap off of that just to hand
water my plants with a with a normal
hose off of that um but I use a little a
little pump to pump uh Creek Water that
225 feet over to my tote so uh and for
the past 11 or 12 years now in this
specific spot I've always left my pump
outdoors and I've never drained it and
never had an issue with the with the
water freezing inside and destroying the
pump
well last year our winter was bad enough
that it uh it split the bell housing the
pump housing it liter it basically
cracked the thing straight in half and I
was like whoa that's the first time I've
seen that happen it was it got pretty
cold down in that Valley last year for
it to to finally freeze the water in
that pump and cause it to expand like
that that's the the first encounter I've
had with a pump freezing over like
that
yeah ice will ice will break
metal if you let it yeah for sure it
looked like it it did it pretty easily
too it didn't look like it had that hard
of a time doing
it yeah I definitely had a lot of damage
over winter mostly fences but uh I've
definitely had some pipes break not
metal but it was it was a bad winter
knock on wood this winter doesn't seem
as bad we have a big storm coming right
now but it looks mostly it looks like
mostly rain with with snow on the back
end but not much but right hopefully
that holds
up yep so for postseason cleanup I think
that pretty much covers that topic I
mean you know we all we all kind of do
the same thing we do what we can when we
can and uh so to to round off this
discussion and finish the last little
portion um uh let's just talk about what
we're excited about for the following
year or for for the upcoming year and
this could include strains this could
include new uh new additions to the farm
um new plans you have uh you know uh new
equipment that you plan on using just
anything for this following up for this
coming up year that that you're excited
to to grow or excited to use in the
garden
um uh peaches let's let's start with you
what what's what's got you excited for
for this upcoming
year um well uh I actually have my Barb
that I'm going to get to put out as
clones um and my keeper feno so I'm
excited about that cuz usually we do
everything from seed and so um I'm
looking forward to not having to you
know kick out males and know what I have
and then
um yeah that's always fun and then I I
also have some seeds uh they were
calling it
Barbarella um and and it's a Barbara Bud
cross with Renee uh but recently they
renamed it sweet peach because it is
supposed to be peachier than the barber
bud and I happened when I bought the
barber Bud to get a free pack of that so
um I'm really really excited about that
one because I'm hoping for even more
Peach chirps that wait but are you mad
that they called it sweet peach well no
I
mean everybody like there's now a sour
Peach there's all kinds of stuff so you
know it is what it is um it would have
been nice cuz I would have probably
planned on naming my feno and something
I make that but it's okay um it is what
it is I'm just happy to find Peach TPS
so um that's what I'm just really
looking forward to that barbar Bella and
then like I said having some clones
already to go and not having to do the
whole seed thing this time um I'm kind
of looking for forward to that
part it's good to hear it's good to hear
it's always nice to have something
you're excited for and especially you're
looking forward to grow for the
following
year yeah it's a little different cuz
normally I'm I mean I'm excited but I'm
not sure what we're going to get and
have because we you know choose seeds
and we've been searching through this
and that and so this year the main focus
is going to be on just a couple of
strains that we've already grown and we
know what to expect from them so right
that's been something that's kind of
addictive for me the more that I pop the
The Wider spectrum of these seeds and go
further into these genetics is not
knowing what you're going to get is as
equal or almost more exciting to me than
like unnown cut that I know is going to
perform well like that they they hold
the same equal value in my brain they
both scratch the same itch you
know
um what about you Hill what what are you
super excited about growing for next
year um I'm I'm I'm excited about
growing less strains honestly I I grew
such a variety this year just to see
what was going to work for me in my
expansion um I'm I'm I'm looking forward
to having that narrowed down to to four
main strains in the outdoor the Phoenix
papaya bomb Mochi runs and ice cream
cake and then in the uh in the depths
it's going to be a whole lot of ice
cream cake and a little Mochi runs and
then uh couple other green houses will
have long finishers like sour diesel and
blue dream but uh there might be some
cat piss in there as well on the early
early light dep because it does well in
the cold but other than that um my uh my
little side side seed Garden where I get
to like grow some stuff and and hunt
through some stuff that I
like either for personal or just to
maybe work some breeding projects and
and just and just be a just be a hobby
grower in a little small space um I'm
I've got a collection of maybe six
poodle nuts crosses that I'm going to
grow out along with clones from those
two s1s I like um okay so I'm excited to
look through those it's a pretty wide
variety um I got Bubba cook to to poodle
nuts from Caleb those are old seed that
he used to give away his freebies um
like oh man that sounds great though
yeah the first bubak cush was the first
thingy reversed to start his seed
company so it's from that it's from that
lot um so that's that's going back quite
some time who knows how many will
germinate um I've got can I ask uh just
quickly the the URL itself is it is it
quite a slow viure oh yeah big time
get Bubba as well um Bubba does a little
bit better um also a very squat very
slow lots of nodes um short internal
length just like just like Urkel but
Bubba's still it's still grows faster
than Urkel
Urkel's Urkel's just one of the slowest
and then and then when you flip it it it
doesn't stretch that much so you really
got to veg it to
size
right yeah um so most URL phenotypes
like the poodle nuts is a URL phenotype
of its cross just like t1000s URL pheno
type of vcross they're definitely on the
shorter end of plants
um what other crosses oh uh I got one
from Matt uh which is uh one of his
blueberry crosses cross to uh poodle
nuts or blue bonnet cross to poodle nuts
I got a pood nuts backat cross from high
and Lonesome I've
got a pood nuts to Kim 91 from uh goat
and monkey
seeds um and I've also got some poodle
nuts to Triangle Kush from goat and
monkey and I bet I'm forgetting one I
can't remember so you like Pol nuts I
love it I love it and it crosses the
smells the smells really translate well
they're dominant in the crosses which is
oh been surprising to me but it just it
crosses well to Sour Diesel and honestly
that's why I want to get poodle nuts
back so I can cross it to Sour Diesel
and grow those out that's really what I
want to do and uh okay but you know if I
can't get the cut back I'm growing out
these other varieties and I'm going to
see what's what um possibly do some
crosses but we'll see and then uh sorry
you did say this earlier but one thing
is poodle
nuts urle to kimd
sorry remind me yeah not kimd but it's a
kimd uh 3x three
3bx so it's sort of kimy um it's called
Trace dog that uh do I got it yeah JJ
did a long time ago and then made the
cross to URL um yeah so it is it is it
is very much kimd cross um and then I'm
going to grow out a bunch of old heart
attack cush seeds looking for some early
finishing plants that I know are in that
genetic line which is cush cleaner to
sfv or sfv to Kush
cleaner and uh there's these are some
f2s I made from that
cross
um and uh hopefully gonna find some
early finishers that's definitely on the
terpinolene scale I've always I've I've
kind of like steered clear of too much
terpinolene in my garden over the years
just because buyers kind of thumb their
noses at it but I feel
like it's a it's a t because it's so
dominant in everything it's cross to
like it's very easy for everything to
end up smelling like Jack Jacker or
trinoline or Jack TPS as people call it
or pine or or whatever you want to call
it um I I feel like the
the the the Next Generation hasn't been
exposed to it like we
have and and
so as long as it checks all the other
boxes and for me it needs to be early
because I want something to finish early
and to get my outdoor Harvest started
early um I mean it seems to me to
function really well as a Counterpoint
to something else if you can get it to
work with something else right like
alongside another nice
trip to me it's just it just overpowers
everything it's crossed to
so you you might find something that has
a little bit of both but for the most
part you're just going to get hit in the
face with a pine tree well maybe this is
why the Santa Cruz Ricks are interesting
to me because it does seem like there's
an actual shot of getting like a
blueberry terpinolene like a decent
balance uh I but I could be wrong that's
what I I me if if that's the case that's
great um or maybe you got lucky but
um the high like having Tor pinolene in
there I think is good regardless just
because I think it adds to a more
euphoric sort of energetic High which
you know most of us are looking for it's
it's easy to find the lethargic high but
if you can find that high that makes you
clean your house and get motivated to do
stuff that's that's always a fun tool in
the toolbox you know for for certain
occasions and I've always found that in
in the terpinolene strains um the you
know they're typically they're more
narrow Leaf
cultivars um uh Hayes has a lot of it uh
deran poison has a lot of it train wreck
um so some of the super silver hazes
that have gone around have been tpine
dominant I've heard that too yes
and I mean all those Colombian Panama
high they could they all have that in
there big time so um and we know what
kind of high those things have so I I I
I I'll like having it in my garden as
long as it sells I don't know if it will
or not but for me having an earlier
finisher and this is just a genetic line
I happen to have in my fridge and I know
it's there because I've grown a lot of
it over the years
um it's just kind of like hey let's
let's bring back some old stuff and see
how it works and maybe maybe it doesn't
you know but like I've got a little bit
of space so where I can experiment and
and do things like that just in in hopes
of finding something new that that
really works for me as a as a
grower very
[Music]
nice and that's yeah that's about that's
about what I have cooking for next
year sweet
sweet I'm uh I'm super I'm super
interested to see um especially with
Bubba kind of making a little bit of
that Resurgence and and uh you know um
CSI starting to starting to do a little
more work with it I'm curious to see how
more prevalent it it start if it's
cyclical and starts coming back around
more because Bubba was one of the first
like uh one of the first ones that
really stood out to me in my my younger
and earlier days of smoking it was the
first one that really floored
me who was
that uh it was me thousand oh that was
thousand okay yeah pubba Kush was one of
the first ones that really floored you
yeah yeah so with with csi's upcoming
work I'm I'm kind of curious to see if
if we see a Resurgence in the community
where a lot more people are playing
around with it now that would make me
really happy um and that's that's one of
the things that I mixed personally that
I'm excited for to try next year um I
plan
on looking through csi's catalog and
there's two things that that I want to
pick up to to try for next year one of
them um would be I want to try the
humble uppercut by itself um I believe
Hill you were saying that you guys also
got cantaloupe or like sweet honeydew
melon out of the The Humble dupper cuts
that you were growing and the the the
sweet 16 humble derer cut that I grew
was a dead ringer for cantaloupe like
smelling the plant I I couldn't believe
how closely related to to cantaloupe it
was and that just made me want to want
to go back to the root of the humble
duber cut and and pop some of those and
see what's hanging out there um that was
you right little Hill that was talking
about the humble Tupper cut no no I I
didn't grow that one okay I must I can't
remember who I was talking to but they
they they had a friend that and a family
member who also grew them and they were
mentioning cantaloupe turps and and I
just I liked that line through and it
made me want to go back to the to the
original to see where it's coming from
um that and
also buying some of the some of the new
Bubba cush stuff that that he's got out
so I'll probably be running some humbled
uppercut and some Bubba cush stuff for
uh for next year's outdoor um one of the
sweet 16 hybrids that I was given but
didn't get a chance to pop was the
bubble gum um I'm really curious to see
if the sweet 16 bubble gum cross keeps
it uh you know if it comes across with
bubblegum turps but still has the
potency and the the pungent you know
fermenting smells that come from the
sweet 16 it could really bolster those
bubble gum turps that seem to fall off
in every bubble gum strain that I've
grown so far I haven't had anything that
smells like bubble gum in flour and
I harvest it get it in jars and the
bubble gum transfers over it it almost
always
dissipates that sounds exciting that
that cross just because bubble gum bu
bubblegum does so well outdoors and has
good finishing times and it it's such a
sweet Frosty bud but yeah if you if it
could do something to help it retain
that smell and flavor that that would be
that would be absolutely killer and it's
been it's been a great hybrid for
outdoor grow ERS as well anything
crossed to Bubblegum has been has done
well for people and same with Bubba I
haven't grown the Bubba the bubblegum
crosses but I've grown a lot of Bubba
cush crosses uh Outdoors like fullterm
back back when we were growing big
plants and I was super surprised not
being a huge bub cush fan I was so
surprised how big these plants got they
still had those big broad leaves that
Bubba Kush has but they were [__]
enormous and you know there most of them
were OG
crosses um they they got
absolutely huge um that is surprising to
me for sure yeah they loved the NorCal
sun and some of the biggest biggest
outdoor plants I've ever had all the
biggest plants outdoor plants I've ever
had have been from seed but these were
especially just girthy because of the
size of their leaves and the thickness
of their stems um I even had a huge
Windstorm where the top of the plant
actually blew off the plant so like the
top maybe two and a half feet so that
top Cola they weren't topped or anything
actually it looked like a grenade went
off in the plant and there were trell
and everything but the that that stem
just blew straight off the plant and
this was in September and it was it was
a loss on on that part that blew off but
um yeah like a grenade went off so I I
would have thought that a Bubba type
would be quite mold prone as
well yeah you would think that I mean
that makes sense big thick indicia buds
um I didn't have any
issues I typically didn't have mold
issues back in the day growing big
outdoor plants um I was selecting
strains that wouldn't mold on me but
like stuff that molds on other people
didn't mold for me but I didn't I didn't
have any issues CSI might say different
where he was because I know he always
had more mold problems than I did yeah
but uh it's I don't know maybe it's just
part of the Vigor but like the buds were
dense and like all the all the
parameters were there for bad mold uh I
just I just never had that
issue has anyone done a bubblegum Bubba
cross I
haven't interesting it's it's one of the
reasons that has me so interested well
it's not it's a keystone factor into why
I'm curious about trying The Sweet 16
bubble gum is it's notorious mold
resistance and and Bud rot resistance um
uh you I I don't have any uh fears of
running that sweet 16 bubble gum
Outdoors as long as it can go full term
um the two other examples of the bubble
gum cut that CS I use that I grew in my
garden they were grown Outdoors endured
multiple rainstorms that were over an
inch and even the the Albert Walker
bubblegum survived ice like there were
there was snow that landed on it and
then froze and it was like actual I I
had to like thump the nugs to get ice
sheets of ice to fall off the buds and
there was not a trace of mildew not a
trace of mold not a trace of Bud rot I
was really impressed with the impervious
qualities to mold that his bubble gum
cut had and that Albert Walker bubble
gum plant that I had it had every chance
to to create mold it had it had exposed
uh Branch exposed stems and branches
that were rubbed and had uh had dead
cell material on it it had uh Decay fan
leafes there was all and it had plenty
of moisture all of the the right um
qualifiers to create a moldy mess were
there and it just didn't happen so yeah
I'm I'm really curious to see what the
sweet 16 bubble gum does next year um I
I might end up doing probably two maybe
three plants or I I could go with the uh
the method that I did with the sweet 16
Kim D's and grow three of them in one
pot and kind of let them VI for control
and fight for each other for some five
six foot tall plants instead of some 10
foot tall
monsters um yeah so next year I'm I'm
excited about the bubak cush stuff I'm
excited about more sweet 16 stuff um I'm
going to I'm going to go back and I'm
going to run some more Appalachia stuff
but this time I'm probably going to run
the Appalachia f3s just to get a sense
of the green crack and the trest dog
mixed together
um I like those now oh nice nice I I
liked everything that I saw out of the
Appalachia hybrids mostly the outdoor
Vigor literally just growing giant
Butterball bushes so I want to go back
to the the core Appalachia and see
what's there um I'll probably run the
loomus headband APPA appy um because I
was so impressed with the plant that my
brother grew last year um I'm also super
excited to jump back on the humble's
Most Wanted which I grew two years ago
didn't grow last year and I'm jonesen
for it this year um it was a one of my
favorite plants grew itself another Girl
Scout cookie hybrid from CSI that is
just does its own thing and provides
really great smoke for me and in my
perfect it it perfectly works for my
climate um what else am I excited for
next year um yeah the Santa Cru wreck
mixing the the Blue Dream um with the
atws I I'll probably run Category 5
again because uh I liked it a little
more than the Mojo rising and my brother
liked the Mojo Rising more than the Cat
5 so I'll probably run a couple cat
fives um I definitely am interested in
trying to get the blooper skunk uh up
and running the Gil Blue Bonnet I had
two of them last year but uh both of
them turned out being males super
unfortunate they were both really big
healthy bushy plant and I was looking at
them I was like oh man these end up
being female these are going to be great
but a loss both of them were were males
um the blueberry n the riot Berry the
blue garri those are all Riot stuff that
really intrigue me and um yeah so the on
top of of trying some more riot gear
some more goat farm gear some more CSI
gear um I'm also going to return back to
some of the stuff that I've created um
in 2021 I created a series of pine
tarush hybrids and I've played around
with them here and there but friends and
and close relatives have grown them more
than I have and I've seen some really
really good success in the Living Dead
Girl pine tar Kush crosses and the um
the lemon party pine tar Kush so next
this coming year I'm going to be playing
around with some of my own seeds a
little more I'm going to get back into
the the kotg f1s the uh black cherry
soda hybrids that I crossed to the sour
diesel white widows um in 2018 I grew a
handful of those and I was just really
happy with everything that came out of
them and I just haven't Revisited it yet
because I've been so happy exploring
this this plethora of genetics that I've
been thankfully given access to so I'll
do a little little return to Cinder and
come back home and pop some of my own
stuff and you know get back into my own
my own genetics which I'm also just as
excited
about hell yeah um I did I did think of
one prompt I had or question I had for
for peaches um I don't know if she wants
to speak to it though but I wondered if
you might tell us a bit about the early
Pearl stuff I know it's kind of like
more on Buck side of the story and we we
even have maybe talked about doing h
episode on that but I wonder if you give
us like a little you know update on on
that on what the story is
there um well
uh the early Pearl has been his definite
uh he's been on the search for a while
um last year his white whale yeah yeah
it has been ever since ever since I've
met him actually which you know we met
at 18 so it's been a long time and uh
last year man we had the early Pearl out
there we had the silver Pearl um S1 we
had Pips perfect Pearl and then we had
the Lost Pearl and we also had the hunza
valley uh 91 by early Pearl that we had
made the year before um cuz you know
he's searching for that that one
phenotype and uh this year actually he
tracked down some uh
20-year-old pear uh early Pearl clone
strain and so that's one of the one
that's going to go out on the hill too
um he's really excited about that one
cuz he said from what he talked to the
guy about it has the smell and the looks
of what he's been searching for um so
you know uh it's gotten to the point
like we've done this so much last year I
told him he couldn't have any of the
pots on the hill for early Pearl that I
was doing my peach hunt so there is like
I don't even know 20 some plants down
here in one gallon pots that he was
searching through last year um we found
one male that we kept it's in the uh
room back there uh that we're going to
use for breeding and then uh you know
it's just it's he's still on that search
we quite haven't found the one
yet so I don't know if that covered what
you're asking about or if there's yeah
know super cool yeah I think the fact
that like he has such such a strong you
know affiliation with the that
particular plant in his mind and you
know searching for it it's like it's
kind of an epic story it is it's a real
epic story because that you know
he's uh the short little story is you
know when he he lost his dad when he was
young and then this guy who mentored him
was really like a father figure to him
and probably one of the only men in his
life that was actually like a decent man
to him and wasn't you know an ass and uh
he showed Cass you know all about this
growing and I mean Cass had been growing
before but when he went there this guy
was his mentor and he was a good person
and as well as a good grower and uh it
was the early Pearl was the strain that
he went and helped him with you know his
wife had cancer at the time and that's
why he went over there to help him grow
so he could be um you know taking care
of it way took her to chemo and did that
stuff and um
so that strain was what uh him and his
his uh his name was Stan Harden and his
whole thing about this is trying to get
his story told because he was one of
those old guys who you know ended up
going to jail and he they let him out to
die basically um and it's just one of
those stories of you know so many that
of us have of our uncles or grandpas
that the you know the War on Drugs took
people from us that should have never
been taken and so that strain means a
lot to him and that's why we've done a
lot to try to bring it back and try to
find you know that exact one it's just
been really
hard these uh stories like that are like
Keystone like moments for a lot of the
Cannabis Community it's some of my
favorite um uh some of my favorite stuff
in the community is hearing people who
have been chasing this strain for x
amount of years or they they're trying
to get back to it because it meant so
much to them it's it's really cool to
see people in the community that that
have that gumption to to chase after
something like
that yeah I mean it's it's taken you
know well you guys know like seed pack
we've probably gone through I don't know
20 plus seed packs over the last few
years um just trying to find that one
and we still haven't found it so now
we're switching to the trying to you
know breed with it and you know got the
mail and try to you know bring it back
and bring some bger back to it he right
you know feels like it's really kind of
lost what it had back then and you know
there's a whole really neat story to it
all I don't want to tell it all right
now cuz I know uh he wants to do an
episode on it but like it it did that
strain specifically well that pheno of
the early Pearl I should say it was a
pheno um did make it out to like the
Great Grateful Dead um Cypress Hill
digital peoples I mean there was a whole
little thing that happened with that
strain
um that that would just be neat to have
that story told and it would be really
neat for him to actually find it so
hopefully one day we can get
there yeah it's epic and yes we will
hopefully have uh an actual show on
this maybe actually it's like a maybe
it'll be a good time to do it like
either before the next season starts or
a partway through or something yeah
we'll see yeah but thanks for sharing
that really cool yeah of
course kush yeah what what else we um uh
other than that yeah I think I think
that wraps up most of what we were
talking about um I know that we could we
could talk a little bit about um the
future of the outdoor round table and
where it's going to go for 2024 tell us
yeah tell us about your ideas so mostly
my idea is basically a framework replica
of what we did last year we're going to
check in every month or every couple of
months about what we're doing in the
garden if anything's new updating with
our outdoor grows but also sprinkled in
I'm going to start to try and do some
interviews um I over the years through
Instagram through IC mag forums through
people I've met and in the valley um all
over Northern California uh I'm I plan
on doing interviews uh with with these
select people and and just sitting down
and having a a onetoone conversation and
and getting to know some of these
outdoor Growers much like myself a lot
of us are recluse uh and and we don't we
wouldn't without being prodded or poked
we wouldn't have jumped into the
community and started talking and and
making ourselves more known and I I know
tons of cats like this um um I got five
or six guys off the top of my head uh
and women both guys and girls that that
I I want to interview and I want to have
discussions with and they're all uh
they're all great outdoor Growers and
great minds for for what they're doing
in their own respective rights and I
think that more more people should have
discussions with them uh a lot of these
people I've spent a lot of time uh
sending paragraphs back and forth
talking about weed and talking about
life but haven't sat down and done a an
actual voice conversation like this and
I think I think uh I think people need
to need to be exposed to to the
different shades of of Growers that we
have out there um almost no two outdoor
Growers are alike it's it's a very
unique community that I I've ran into so
far and I'm I'm excited to to talk to
him and sprinkle in some of those
interviews throughout the year um on top
of just the norm noral outdoor Round
Table
stuff honestly sounds great man and um I
think we already have quite a good
foundation to build on um and very you
know very appreciative of uh your
efforts cushion but also you know Peters
and little Hill for helping us out so
much over the last six months or
whatever absolutely yeah I appreciate
you guys coming and providing your your
thoughts and your Insight and and
sitting down and chatting with us I I
really enjoy it
I really appreciate the invite and
getting to sit and chat with you guys
thank
you yeah I'm I'm happy to be a part of
it and I love talking about weed so it
it works out well for me um and hearing
other people's
experiences with uh some of these
strains I don't get a chance to
grow um yeah I'm I'm happy to chat as as
the season moves forward to to uh talk
about what's going on and and what
issues are arising and and uh kind of
The Season's a marathon so it's funny to
check it's it's fun to check in right
and see how everybody's doing and how
they're dealing with with different
things so right on guys I think to me
that is a really nice thing about
outdoor at least you know living in this
in a similar region anyway where you
guys are actually in Pace with each
other sort of um and kind of check in
whereas you know if you're indoor grower
like it doesn't really matter you don't
have that kind of um seasonal
progression I guess
um yeah yeah there's there's a couple
major keystones is like you know going
Outdoors when everybody and then when it
flips into flower we're all not on the
exact same schedule but we're all tuned
into the same you know we're we're we're
right on par with each other I never
thought about it that way compared to to
indoor you know guys who are modulating
their own
schedules no I love it it's like a set
of um rituals or something right well
yeah I feel like my outdoor Garden the
more I do it it turns into a ritual it's
it's become a meditative process for me
it's like uh it's like unconscious
meditation just going down hanging out
with the plants you know cutting a few
fan leavs here and there talking to the
plants I've done it for so long now that
it's it's basically a part of my life
and it's it's like like you know
meditation to me
now that's your second
nature right mhm that's
right all right guys well I think I can
probably um wrap us up I'll do the shout
outs um any shout outs from you
guys I got one
um uh you guys can hit me up on
Instagram little Hill cultivators um I'm
still selling uh Farm swag all organic
cotton americanmade Farm swag if you
guys want to represent yeah it's pretty
low-key way to do it there's nothing
that says cannabis on it so uh I I
appreciate the
support um and uh I gotta actually get
some breeder Syndicate swag to wear um
just because I like the design and want
to sort of low-key support the support
the
channel yeah I need to get Matt to get
get on the snapbacks get some
hats
yeah I'm not sure what's going on with
the riot merch at the moment I think
it's going but not not 100%
um any shout outs from
peaches or Kush at this point um no I
mean just you know come to the Discord
and ask questions uh you know come talk
to me about Edibles and hash and I'll
answer your questions
so yeah same same mirrored sentiment uh
just a shout out to the community um I
wouldn't be here if you guys didn't want
me here and uh I'm always open for
questions and you know so feel free to
hit me up Discord Instagram shoot me a
message uh let's talk I'm always open to
talk about
plants I was going to say as well uh
going back to an earlier point you made
Kush about seeing who you could get on
if between you and little Hill you can
actually get Caleb on again
you you guys would deserve a medal get a
trophy you can get again same I'll get
in his ear for sure um because I always
those are my favorite episodes when he's
talking or a couple other folks uh but
uh cause man yeah he talks to Matt quite
a bit and Matt says that you know he he
tries to be like polite because he's a
friend and he doesn't want to pressure
him too much but I'm like why don't you
just pressure him oh I'll pressure him
he'll just say no but I don't
care
yeah yeah would love to have that Denali
denali's definitely planned for a return
Caleb I'm not we'll have to do some
sweet
talking yeah yeah maybe across you two
and Matt maybe we'll get
somewhere yeah we'll Wrangle them in we
see okay well uh I'll try to do the the
shout outs that Matt normally does um
you guys already mentioned uh come check
out our Discord um
patreon uh we have Riot SEO Europe for
seeds in Europe we have gir by seeds
covering Australia and New Zealand um of
course Riot seeds.com and lifted
genetics for those of you in North
America um have I forgotten anyone
else I think those are the main seed
banks um
otherwise want to thank the guests again
kusher the Giants Peach's little Hill so
great to have you guys back on in the
new year and yeah look forward to more
outdoor stuff this
year thank you otherwise thanks everyone
for your time this Friday evening and we
will catch you all soon right on guys
see you later peace take it out take it
easy thanks for tuning in everyone um
see you next week you know uh I'm pretty
stoked about this next show we're going
to be covering some old bases but much
better better detail more accurate info
which is most important uh I just wanted
to make sure and thank again Kush of the
Giants peaches little Hill for coming on
covering this thousand for organizing it
and and always being there when I can't
be um it there's never enough ways to
thank my dude um don't forget we have
gir by seeds Australia for people in
Australia we have righto Europe for our
people in Central Europe and all around
Europe and we have lifted seeds for the
US people who only use credit cards
stuff like that great guy he carries our
homies and he's all about delivering
quality over quantity of breeders
breeders you know what I mean um that's
important to me don't forget the gel
drops up super limited when it's gone
it's gone I keep saying that people
don't get that and they always get sad
when they miss it um we also have the
sub Rob seeds out right now under seed
trip on our website right seeds.com uh
seed trip is his business name and we've
got some Sour dub reversals cross to the
98 Super Silver Haze and the skunk dog
S1 so go check those out super super
dank going to cuss super
Dink and then uh yeah check out the
contest video too don't forget about
that and we have a new drop coming from
uh pack from goat farm killer Blue Dream
stuff that has yet to be released some
of it people have been really looking
forward to like the uh Santa Cruz Rec
2.0 stuff like that so go check it out
and I'll see you next week thanks
everyone want to sit at the table with
The Syndicate check out our patreon and
our link tree or description below our
merch site is officially live we have
all sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies
to sort you out and shipping is super
fast and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it
out