welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey in defining my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
[Music]
welcome to reader Syndicate I'm Matthew
with my co-host thousand fold and today
we are honored to welcome not just my
friend Chris the Giants from the
canaluma naughty but the dawn of the can
Illuminati Mr Denali and it's probably
one of our most requested ever episodes
believe it or not the
um so I'm really stoked to uh get into
this with you guys and without further
Ado thousand you want to take it away
yeah we get we even get Denali on the
camera that's amazing I know okay
um you all have no idea how lucky you
are
um yeah so as Matt mentioned you know
today we have a little round table on
outdoor growing and we
met and also I think typically have not
uh covered growing that much and so we
thought we would
ease our way there uh talking to a good
friend's Denali and Kush of the Giants
what was that what's the Missoula ease
it in
it's called denali's joke
um and yeah I guess we start at the
start a little bit of an interest
introduction from both of you perhaps
um where you know where have you been
growing if you can disclose that or in
as much detail as you'd like to disclose
and how long have you been growing
Outdoors for
uh go ahead D I'll let you take the
first one uh I figure you might ah geez
first down girl was 1980 uh yeah in a
little creek bed that uh I just dug up
the soil and removed some big rocks out
of the pop the hole and uh
planted a few seeds one came up
so uh and I use Miracle Grow you know
that's a huge back there I think a lot
of people did yeah not a lot of options
right no no not a lot of options
um I think like 1985 or uh some
somewhere right right about there that
uh we started adding amendments and
things like that to a blood meal and
bone meal and stuff like that
but uh still never got into uh what what
they do nowadays we worked well those do
it you you kind of skipped over
something so your your first indoor
grows or outdoor grows you saw or what
year uh 1980 oh that I saw that you saw
I didn't move up till uh up here uh
until uh 79. okay and I did put a couple
seeds just like a half an inch in the
ground super hard soil they didn't grow
yeah and at that time I wasn't uh
connected with anybody it was uh it was
uh very low-key yeah it would be hard to
connect right in that era yeah it was it
was hard to get weed when I first got
here you know because people just don't
trust you [ __ ] yeah it was it was a bad
scene back there getting caught but uh
how'd you get into smoking during
your era I mean because you're you're
probably I would say two generations of
Growers aside away from me
um
I was back in
1975. I uh uh girlfriend broke up with
me and I was uh bummed and I can't
buddies came by uh
and I remember Mikey had a 1969 Camaro
when we were going to Cruz and I was
sitting in the back seat and Pat
uh he said hey we're gonna fire up a
joint and I said I never smoked it
before
and uh he said well you're gonna take a
hit and I said uh sure I'll try it and
he said well just go ahead and solo it
so I sat back there and I smoked half
that joint and I never got high yeah
but that was uh very first time I smoked
weed uh and the third time I smelled
weed that I did get high and uh for me I
I was I lived in sheltered life you know
my dad he wrote his Congressman about
Playboy
they were totally against drugs oh yeah
all right mom got upset when I named my
little hamster Hashimoto at her no
because it had hashes
who's dark and yeah but uh that that's
how I started but like the third time I
got stoned man I could talk to the girls
and stuff like that that that was it for
me you know I started smoking all the
time regularly after that parties things
like that
that's funny never dated in high school
anything like that you know yeah just
knowing you like it's funny because I
can't I can probably count the number of
times like I've been like hey you know
you want to try this and you're like
[ __ ] yeah let's do it like you're always
the first one that's down to just try
whatever I love it yeah so the fact that
you ever had a time period where you
hadn't smoked weed and were just like
maybe you know it's fun I was 19. that's
so funny never in high school you know
I got a couple of uh questions here for
Denali so you started going in 1980 uh
did you take have you taken in many
breaks between then and now
oh yeah yeah I would get transferred
with the company I was working with and
um I wouldn't grow and uh we moved to uh
uh Association uh HOA and uh you
couldn't put up fences and things like
that and uh there was years I didn't
grow you know but I knew people that
were growing so it wasn't hard getting
weed yeah you're always kind of stayed
in the scene yeah yeah and that first
time getting high it's it's been forever
and that's why he's the done right there
right what kind of um when you were
first starting growing what kind of
information did you have access to about
the plant zero
yeah Henry books or anything like that I
didn't talk to anybody I just uh did
what I thought yeah and so you just
figured it out as you went on I guess oh
yeah and uh uh I've learned so much more
since being in this group than I have in
all those years prior
so you felt your way through it like
making love to a man like your first
time you just kind of feel your way
through it yeah yeah it happened that's
what Amazon is for
yeah I mean that's right right not bad
um did I miss this Denali did you tell
us you know roughly where you were based
I mean you don't have to but uh
yeah it's no big deal I think a lot of
my ID pictures show where I'm at I'm in
Lake County in North California Nor Cal
baby yeah yeah I'm saying 79.
all right how about you because you're
the Giants when did you start and where
are you growing at the moment so I
started in 2008
um when I turned 18.
um but since I was about 14 or 15 I was
always in my brother's Garden he's the
one who introduced me to the plant and
when he was watering or taking care of
his stuff I was always out there helping
him and bullshitting with them
um and I'm about
180 miles north of Denali in between
Shasta and Lassen County in the in the
Foothills the lesson
for those of us who are like not super
familiar with the geography there how
similar would you say the conditions are
between where you two are growing living
he's uh he's in the valley and he gets
uh he gets a higher heat index than I do
and I live on the side of a mountain so
we we share a lot of the same
similarities and our heat but when it
comes to like things dealing with like
the cooling off at Night My I think my
temperatures drop off a lot more than
people down in the valley at sea level
Doom
yeah
yeah nice
um Asian are you good
I'm at 3 400. yeah I'm like 13.
yeah
yeah well Lake County also has an
interesting like aspect to it with the
like living next to the water like
that's kind of my aspect
sorry I have to do it every time someone
says that like I was wondering where
that came from I didn't realize I was
like what
caught me off guard first I was like
wait it's not so listening
yeah no he's on demand's table
I think uh I think living right on the
Lake Edge and growing right on the in
that area has has a huge effect on on
your plants um I think I think it's a
totally different environment than what
I'm dealing with
yeah I mean I guess we should say right
off the bat that one obviously one of
the biggest differences between going
outdoors and indoors is that you are
very much constrained by your immediate
environment and in some ways that's
going to be a running theme through this
talk
um
actually on that note I did want to ask
you to as well as part of this like
intro
um have you two grown indoors much
I I haven't first indoor grow I had was
1988.
and uh that was underneath the house
and a buddy had a
couple clones
that uh there's a story about and uh
I grew them one year
and uh uh went to a rehab
so I uh
didn't grow any for another probably two
years after that uh but I never really
got into indoor grown because uh the
climate's so good up here and that uh I
could grow outside
did you wanna
do you want to dip into that little
story that you just mentioned yeah
you know some people say it's [ __ ]
you know but that's okay
the way it is
1985 I met a guy uh we started fishing
together
and he had uh he took me over to his
house and walked me out to a barn and
went in the barn and here's all these
pot plants growing this little bitty top
tiny pot plants maybe a foot tall
and uh had them under lights
and he was using CO2 he was taking his
own clones he was uh
uh the lights he was using metal halide
and high pressure sodium so he was
Advanced for that year like doing CO2
everything yeah yeah
high pressure sodium lights were on a
track and they wow and um
uh he had this whole operation going on
and uh he told me the story of where he
got these two cuts
and uh
uh a friend of his with an electrician
I'll work up in uh the Northwest and uh
uh University up there
and when he came back
his buddy started growing these well
they those two were friends because uh
their two uh ladies they were with went
to high school together and they were
best friends in high school so that's
how uh Tom and I'm calling Carlos Carlos
met and uh
Tom turned him on to these cuts that he
brought back from the northwest
and one was green one with a little bit
purple
and he said that that's where they came
from in 1985 was the University up in
Northwest
and uh he was uh growing in uh
vermiculite and paralyte and I believe
it was about age 70 30 something like
that
and two gallon pots and he would uh veg
for 10 days
and he would take them at eight weeks
and just like clockwork and that [ __ ]
was so Stony the green one would stick
to the bag and the purple one wasn't as
high
you can get the same high out of it but
uh it was still primo weed at the time
so I I buddied up with him uh real quick
and to the to this day we're still
friends
1985 with the early afghanis that's
that's pretty impressive you know like
it's an early time you know like the
fact that you mentioned they stick to
the bag stuff like that that's a common
thing that I've heard about how like
people are so used to certain types of
Bud that when they found something that
was like physically sticky they would
stick to things that really really like
freaked him out it was a trip
and if anybody could tell me
how he knew the story about these two
one green one purple
from the University up in the northwest
how did you know that story in 1985.
yeah I'm gay if somebody can tell me
that then
what he had was the UW so what do you
think um you've had time with the the
pnw hash plant now yeah
yeah a little bit what did you think
compared to comparatively
yeah pucky
uh
I would say more like it yeah
um it it not full of resin at least not
the way I grow it but I'm not doing what
he did you know I've always wanted to
take both those cuts and run them just
like he did and see what they would do
it sounds like he was using like an
early form of the hempy bucket system
which is just you know perlite and
nutrients just constantly feeding
it used a uh I remember when I first met
him he was using uh
Violet food because no really uh
variegated
violet plant is variegated like a
cannabis plant then he switched it over
to Jacks 20 oh Jacks yeah 2020. and I
think it was like 5 50 18 or something
like that Jesus that's funny yeah Jax
makes sense a lot of people use that too
during that time
yeah I've used it a few years ago it
still works that's some great insight
into the to the possible UW uh Origins
and it's it's one of the better ones
that we've seen where there's pictures
and you know uh testimony about it that
far back
well you know I just I know what he told
me yeah you know that's it that's all I
know and he couldn't have known that
story without it happening yeah and this
dude's still around
oh yeah oh yeah he's the most arrogant
piece of [ __ ]
I would get him on a show but he would
tell you how great he is
he sounds like he's pretty great though
you know he still swears he grows best
we in the world
does he
uh yeah it's pretty good
[Laughter]
85 years running like light lights on
Rails and [ __ ] that's that's so Advanced
that's so Advanced that's really cool
yeah he was taking it down to L.A
getting ready about like four thousand a
pound yeah oh my God whoa just murdering
it
yeah some guys I'm just gonna button and
say that uh even though this is a bit of
a tangent I think we want to get a few
stories out of Denali because obviously
he's witnessed a lot yeah absolutely
yeah just a bit
it's been a fun ride
fun ride all right well cush with the
Giants like have you had much experience
growing indoors and why I'm asking you
both this is just so we can later on
kind of I want to get to teasing out you
know some of the like
uh differences
yeah so I play around a little bit
indoors but it's usually after my
outdoor season is done and in my section
of the mountain pretty much for about
four months out of the year we have a
foot of snow on the ground or more and
so when that happens and I'm done with
Harvest and everything's taken care of
that's when I swap into indoor mode and
um my indoor stuff is always playing
around trying new stuff trying mediums
like trying pure cocoa or trying some
dwc buckets it's always been just just
something new and fresh to just play
around and give something new a try
yeah so for you you're indoors you're
kind of like yearly Focus I mean sorry
your outdoor is like your main focus and
your indoor is a bit of a like play
around experiment right yes and and
another reason why that is is uh due to
power outages I live in such a rural
area that I'm used to losing like 17 18
days of power throughout my four month
five month winter so a lot of my yeah
dude I've had a lot of runs where it's
like okay well today's day five without
any lights so I'm I'll just runs over so
you know wow uh do you have like
generator backups yeah I have
I have backups and stuff but
like I said the grow is always like
secondary it's not my main focus so I've
never had the the that uh specific
breaker panel set up on the automatic
generator it's it's in the garage not on
the main house so
yeah I get you yeah okay uh I plan on
eventually upgrading to where when we
lose power I can still have the tents
running but it's just not a main major
priority for me right now
no that would be a huge project in and
of itself I imagine
yeah I looked at getting the generator
the uh the generators installed for auto
swap over and yeah it's it's a little
expensive but but definitely worth it
for for the projects that I plan on
doing in the future
I get you
okay yeah well thank you both for
telling us a bit about you know how long
you've been growing for you know your
relative experience
um I think one important thing that I've
talked to
I think cush and maybe Matt as well you
know in starting to approach growing
information I think we want to be quite
careful about how we frame this
information like we're we're definitely
not trying to tell people that like this
is your you know quote-unquote ultimate
guide you know insert YouTube clickbait
Title Here to Growing or anything like
that I think for me
um my idea is that we just try to uh
share and be explicit about the
diversity of environments and conditions
that people different people are growing
in
um because
uh
different people have just very
different growing situations
um okay well we can actually get into
a bit more of the uh core growing issues
and the first thing that stands out when
we talk about outdoor growing is
obviously going to be climate I think
for a lot of people
um you two did touch on climate a little
bit but can you tell us again you know
how would you describe the climate in
your where you're growing
so yeah yeah it's it's Aaron hot and
arid for like most of all of July all of
August most of September and then right
around the end of September and the
start of October we get some pretty
heavy showers
how okay maybe because you start how how
have you had to adapt to that or like
um how do you see your grow kind of
being
um
I don't know yeah having having evolved
to deal with that so my challenges with
the climate have changed as my goals
have changed with my garden
um for instance back when I was mono
cropping a single strain and trying to
get as much weight as possible I worried
quite a bit about the climate and making
sure that I harvest before a heavy rain
comes you know I'm more worried about pm
and Bud rot and these things because
because weight is my main goal but in
the last three or four years those goals
have shifted because nobody's buying
that weight anymore and so now I I don't
worry about the climate as much if a
plant is expressing some PM or
expressing some mold I'm not going to
cut it down right away I'm trying to see
what this plant is natural resistances
are like I'm going to harvest enough out
of it to where I'm not worried about
getting every ounce and every gram off
of it so I get to see some more
Expressions rather than worry about my
making sure I harvest every plant at its
maximum weight potential
nice
how about you Denali
I don't remember what the question was
so I guess it was yeah first a little
bit about the climate that you're
growing in and secondarily how have you
like dealt with that
well
uh
I've been trying to pick strains that uh
big Kush and man
um
someone's picking up a lot of background
so you can tell her we love her right
back yeah yeah love you
go what I mean I mean yeah she wanted to
show me show you what she made
um
she made replicated the jalapeno poppers
they looked exactly the same too bro I
ate so many of those and like you know
my diet I wasn't supposed to be eating
that [ __ ] that was so good right bro I'm
those are those are coming again those
are absolutely being made again big you
know it's it's uh like Kush this it's
dry and hotter than hell here and uh it
rained earlier today here
and so that was just a freak thing but
uh in September it starts to cool down
we get a little more rain and uh if it
gets bad enough you got to worry about
the mold and things like that
uh for me uh where I live
um it's like every year I get a
different kind of critter you know it
might be like one year it might be trips
when you're might be white lighted one
year and um
yeah you have to deal with them
and uh
do you have any good stories about this
yeah God I remember plants just covered
yeah just covered uh
not all of them some of them but
semi bug resistant you know you just
don't get on them I've only had a
uh no bad ones uh
russets oh God yeah one time and I just
any plant that had them I cut it down
and put them in my green barrel and got
rid of them
and uh just didn't have that much that
year
jeez but uh I I think it's damn near the
perfect uh environment here for cannabis
for certain times you know there's those
uh 19 weakers Jamba yeah yeah
January there's no way
I mean on on that topic of pest Denali
uh is there anything you do to try to
mitigate
against this I used a three-in-one stuff
you know I don't I don't want free
anything in flour but yeah spring in one
is uh that and depending on the bug
there's white fly stuff and
I'll use neem I don't like name
personally I can't stand the smell of it
anymore I can't stand the smell I'm
traumatized by it either it's so
effective other than as a leaf shine you
know it's good for shining your leaves
and that's about it in my opinion and we
have a lot of them uh cabbage Moss here
and they they had a little bit
absolutely the caterpillar goes in and
uh caterpillar caterpillar killer it
works good
you know and it's been a sad it's pretty
much for that that uh uh that bug is
that are you talking about spinosad or
BT no no BT BT yeah yeah
um what do you have to do with any like
mammals
uh like gophers
yeah I guess or yeah whatever else
that's out Gophers are a big one like if
you plant straight in the ground right
like that's a real issue yep where I'm
living uh they brought this dirt in and
packed it in and made canals in here and
I haven't seen it over here in 40 years
oh my God we've been dealing with them
all like the last two years at this
place it's been nightmare anytime we
plant something in the ground whether
it's a fig tree cannabis anything it's
just ravaged instantly
I I don't know what it is raccoons mess
with plants no
yeah the red Terrors they're evil if do
you guys have raccoons in New Zealand
no we have like uh what's the closest
things that we've got to that we've got
kind of like stoked or weasel type
things okay
yeah raccoons are they're a nightmare
trash pandas they're the worst they're
like they're mean too they're vicious
little shits they don't [ __ ] around
yeah there's a herd of them around here
but now we don't have any uh gophers or
molds or anything like that I know guys
uh uh in the valley where they have
garden and right in the soil they have
just hundreds of them
cheese
coach might have ground squirrels up
there I don't know if they have that yep
yeah every once in a while so I've only
had it happen once out of all the the
cultivars that I've grown I had a train
wreck across to a Salmon Creek big bug
and for some reason the gray squirrels
literally ate the nugs off of the plant
at about week four or five and that's
the only plant they touched it was
really weird
there was something about the turp
profile or that specific plant that they
liked enough to just literally gnaw on
the tops of the plants like that it was
it was incredible
what about um pests in general for you
Kush what other things have you
encountered bugs other mammals rodents
um so in my area there's tons and tons
of mule deer and black tails and uh on
my Ig on my photos every plant you'll
see will have an internal cage with
about a three foot diameter and that
cage not only provides structure for the
plant but it protects from deer that
want to come and Chomp uh the plant down
to the stock and if I didn't have those
internal cages protecting them then all
of those plants would get chomped down
by deer
and uh as far as mammal goes that's
that's the most mammals that I have to
deal with
um and then pests actual bugs thankfully
I've never had to deal with mites and
I've never had to deal with caterpillars
but I do have to deal with aphids and my
first year dealing with aphids was 2019.
and I attacked the aphids instead of
attacking the ants which the ants are
symbiotic they carry the aphids onto the
plant aphids drink the suck the life out
of the plant they poop out this honeydew
the ants harvest the Honeydew it's a
whole symbiotic relationship and the
second I started attacking the ants the
aphids no longer became a problem and
the best thing that I found is food
grade Diatomaceous earth I sprinkle it
in a heavy ring around the base of my
pot and it acts as a barrier that they
will not cross through
yes sir you have uh wood rats up there
no no no issues with wood rats yeah
because they have them here and what
they'll do is they'll just eat eat uh
outside of your plan away just round in
a circle at the base
I think that when they girdle it and
that it'll kill him what a lot of guys
do is they just put out bowls of water
for them
right right yeah that's smart yeah
what do they do with the water
why they're that's why they're yeah
that's why they're at the plants I
always wondered like because I've had
rats like paratroop and indoor grows and
like garages like we're you know 14 feet
up and there's no way for them to get in
I've got chicken wire everywhere I think
um and they would come in through the
tops and every time all they would do is
like girdle like at the bottom base of
the plant and not nothing else and that
was it like it would be done one bite on
[ __ ] and be done yeah it was so
painful just put them out some water
that's wild I had no clue I was like
tripping on my own glue traps and [ __ ]
you got to be kind to your guests you
know you gotta give them Provisions yeah
and [ __ ] with your [ __ ] you know like
the Santa Claus Harmony uh
other thing I'd like to add with pests
is there's a really cool insect called a
Green Lace wing and introducing those to
my garden has been one of the coolest
symbiotic like things I've ever seen in
my garden their their life cycle is to
literally kill aphids and reproduce into
these really cool flying insects that
are that are really quite beautiful and
for people who don't have ants but have
aphids they usually resort to ladybugs
and if if you're buying ladybugs to
protect your plants I highly suggest
buying Green Lace wings as well either
in their larva form or in the egg form
and then getting them on your plants
yeah it's it's really cool to study the
life cycle and understand how they work
and it's really one of the most brutal
like aspects of nature I've ever seen
because the The larva form of this
insect it's literally a miniature grub
with a giant uh Spike on its head and it
Rams the a holds it above its head and
it drinks the fluid as it's draining the
blood out of it yeah with from a spike
on its head yeah and then it throws the
corpse on its back and uses it as a
disguise so that other aphids don't know
that it's a predator it literally
disguises itself
they're called aphid Lions when they're
in that stage and if you look up some
YouTube videos on them it's it's one of
the coolest things in nature one of the
most brutal things in nature I've ever
seen
Wow nature is metal it really is
that's amazing I'm actually going and
buying these right now because you know
I've had problems um also because I
don't do a lot of outdoor I haven't done
like even even when I was doing outdoor
like it was usually greenhouse and then
it was like because something messed up
with a greenhouse we ended up on the
back of the hillside you know so trying
to do outdoors been really really like
butting my head against the wall when it
comes to to pests be it frips or aphids
do you guys have any tips for thrips
so I ever since I've been in the same
Valley within the same like three 400
yards in this little Valley growing for
the past since 2008 and every year on
like one percent of my fan leaves I see
thrip damage but it's it's so minuscule
that I've never seen it as an issue
where I have to tackle it I've never had
such a thrip infestation that it becomes
a huge problem
especially when I'm looking at a very
small amount of fan Leafs that have the
little bit of damage sure yeah it's not
as big of a deal at that point right I
had trips one year and in flower latent
flower and you do a [ __ ] and thing about
them
nothing about them you know all I can
just spray my buds or anything right
yeah yeah they've been brutal here
I think that's one thing with outdoor
growing is you're never gonna have a
plant that's like at least in my
subjective experience I've never had a
plant that's uh like
yeah not what's word I'm looking for
um impervious to to pests when you're
growing outdoor in that environment your
plants are going to have something on
them at some point
yeah it's been it's been hard trying to
explain this to my chick because she's
seen my indoor Grows Right and she's
used to seeing like no pests and
Outdoors she's like what is going on
like why can't it look like that why
isn't it it's it's try to explain like
how much you have to stay on top of
spraying how much you have to stay on
top of all this just to have those kind
of perfect leaves and everything it's
just it's hard to stay on top of it's
it's hard
what's funny is uh way back in the 80s I
don't remember bug
I do not have bugs wow
you know they they introduce a lot of
bugs in the states like I know here they
put spider mites on the uh edges of
freeways
like in the in the garden area there to
take care of whatever bugs they have
there but of course these all end up in
in North Rose here it's just
it's really hard everywhere depending on
what your city uses for its own Pest
Management or if like you're in an
agricultural Valley like us where you
have all these big crops of grapes
almonds all this other stuff around
bringing in all these other types of
bugs too it's it's wild to try to deal
with we have wineries here yeah yeah
they bring in all kinds of crap right I
bet
one other thing that I'd like to talk
about is with pests I've noticed that um
some cultivars have a natural pest
resistance not a complete resistance but
where you know I've had plants side by
side where one was covered in aphids and
one wasn't and they're literally three
feet away from each other where you know
they should have and uh a collective
like
um a collective comparison that I've
noticed between them is a lot of them
have peppery cushy like uh carphenoline
they have that that potent pepper kind
of smell to them and that those plants
like the the living dead girl that has
the pck in it
um it was very peppery and those plants
had little to no pest intrusion on them
whatsoever that's interesting
do you think that you can only know
which plants will do well by actually
trying them out
in your in your particular environment
I think you think you get a good
baseline from seeing other people's
outdoor grow but it the Expressions will
be the Expressions will vary depending
on your specific environment
this is I put up a picture of the Green
Lace Wing just so people can see and
it's a larval form I think it's on Rice
halls or something yeah what great color
yeah
[Music]
um just randomlying because Matt you
asked me about land mammals in New
Zealand so just a bit of trivia uh New
Zealand uh historically actually has no
native land mammals
um what apart from bats so
um humans introduced the first land
mammals to the country I think maybe
seven eight hundred years ago and those
are rats and then later on we got
um pasta weasel Stokes
I believe you guys got access steer and
some sort of goat as well yeah we've got
goat India now as well yeah so but
before before humans uh they were only
nice Birds
um
so yeah it makes sense that rats would
have been one of the first because of
the ships and the cargo ships and in
different pests and mammals that got
aboard that way
yeah yeah and uh you know unfortunately
I cannot speak to Growing Outdoors here
so uh maybe in the future someone could
but yeah that's not me for now I mean we
could basically ask in Australian same
[ __ ] right they have oh man no they're
creatures
they're a different vibe I just we need
to get you telling you you're an Aussie
yeah I know it's easy right um we need
to get booze on we need to get booze on
at some point
um right
right okay
um is there anything else that y'all
wanted to say about piss in your outdoor
gross
what I will say
yes not so
um
no there's not much more that I mean
most of the pests that we encounter
Outdoors we we kind of went over so I
got a question in this in this room real
quick if you could pick maybe two things
from your toolbox that you think that
are just essential for outdoor growing
for pests for IPM what are the two
things that you would
um advise people to at least take a look
at
uh to cushion the Giants first
um the the two things that I mentioned
the diatomaceous earth the food grade
specifically so you're not causing any
issues with your plant consumption and
um the other one is using natural
methods ladybugs Green Lace Wings using
uh nematodes using natural Predators
because they're essentially going to do
more work than you can with your hands
and they're better at it so yeah yeah
excellent how about you Dee uh two two
things I'm not without is uh Avid and
forbid
hey you can't forget equal 20 too
that's the third most data uh BT yeah
green one and the caterpillar yeah that
handles most of my problems yeah leaving
your bowls of water so they're
comfortable bowls of water yes those
water for the wood rats
you know um those cabbage Loopers too
out here are just nightmarish there's no
time I can get away with the grow
without seeing those they're always the
first thing to attack my plants Savage
Loopers
and it gets hot down by you
111 something today
okay right well I wanted to move on to I
don't know just for fun a bit of drama
like what about human piss
tweakers
Denali we have to deal with many human
pests Tweakers tweakers do you have any
good stories yeah I do I have one for
Denali that you can mention there was a
tweaker that got him to take oh never
mind take care of his veg Garden for a
while but nevermind
hey yo he over watered
zing
but uh
[Music]
no I I I was I was ripped off my first
year I grew
and I think I went Maybe
38 39 years and never got ripped off and
uh
somebody came in and ripped my one plan
off I remember that p91 yeah and it was
coming down that night uh but I believe
that was my neighbor across the street
as uh normally he'd get something from
me at Christmas and that Christmas he
didn't oh you bastard yeah so I I truly
believe it was his kids they've shot me
and he went for the p91 bro yeah oh yeah
yeah
so look
good that year too I bet very proud of
it yeah that's a good one Could you um
look him in the eye after that uh yeah
yeah I had no problem yeah but he uh he
he got a little fidgety
yeah they probably moved uh three months
later yeah
yeah yeah nobody is
yeah we'll get to him later John does
not allow this yeah the bad thing is is
uh the house straight across street
two-story it's a rental as far as
weekends so they're like everybody knew
all the time coming in there yeah yeah
but nobody mess with me nobody in there
it's not do you I mean despite not
having too many experiences in that
context do you take any precautions
about those things I I highly recommend
bungee sticks and Claymores yep online
and then like those those things where
you you you know you dig a hole in the
ground you put spikes in them then cover
pitfall trap yeah those are really
really really effective smear poop on
the spikes yeah absolutely yeah
absolutely watch a home alone for more
inspiration I was thinking more Yellow
Jackets those little girls got wild with
the spikes oh yeah I'll let them grow if
they start in a plant I'll let them make
their little Hive in there and
everything else
not to stick my hand in there I saw that
picture yesterday of the yellow jackets
up in there yeah
yeah okay so now he's talking about
literal Yellow Jackets yes Matt's
talking about the TV show yes little
girls but yeah I saw that picture
yesterday of wasps in his garden but I
touched him
yeah they're uh I'm not sure if they're
yellow jackets or Hornets I know I got
hit eight times one year oh my God yeah
oh God I remember Andrea he told me I
needed to hang uh fish hooks right at
eye level treble
I like that I like that idea Andrew's
brutal
oh God it would be shout out to Indra we
miss him yeah we do we do I definitely
miss you
how about you Kush human piss
um so the spot that I'm at it's pretty
rural
um The Little Valley that it's in so if
a person's trespassing they know they're
on private property and thankfully I
haven't had any issues with people
um you know rando's showing up looking
through the garden
but um we I still take precautions I
have trail cameras set up I uh I check
the dirt to and from the grow every day
for Footprints if you know well I'm also
checking for game sign but you know
you're always taking precautions to make
sure you're the only one in and out of
there
um and other than that the really the
only people that we're worried about up
here is helicopters looking for your
grow
um something on the mountain that we've
kind of noticed is they'll check out
everybody's Grove from the helicopter
but they only bust people who have like
a hundred plants or more or if you have
the type of property that looks like
they can make some money from the Civil
forfeiture
um
we've seen the helicopters fly through
and then the next day the bus go off and
it's generally only the people who have
like 300 400 500 plants it's so and it's
weird with our County too they flip-flop
voting every year one year it's legal to
grow outdoors one year it's not legal
and everybody on the mountain who's
doing like me 10 12 plants we just grow
it anyways and you know expect the worst
or best to happen
I use baby monitors
and uh um
anybody who's used trellis knows how bad
that is if you get it in your feet
and I'll put a bunch of that out on my
back deck with some Coke cans tied to it
and uh yeah you can't walk through that
trellis and not get your foot hung in
that [ __ ] at night dark you're not gonna
be having no damn flashlight going yeah
so yeah there's little things you can do
and one thing I know since we're all in
California none of us would ever own a
weapon to protect ourselves that's for
sure
I've never heard of one nope nope
is that a paintball gun would be good
yeah I bet it would but we would never
even own one because it looks too close
too what about a Super Soaker too close
to a real one probably get us killed
it's just one of those things in in
California where actually the United
States where they make it kind of extra
charges if you get caught with any kind
of weapon despite the fact that they
know that like indoor Growers are
targets for being robbed
um probably needing you know outdoor
indoor doesn't really matter yeah you
know um uh and they need to be able to
protect themselves probably more than
most other home businesses being with
their businesses and they actually make
it illegal for you to do so
at least in California you have to sign
paperwork saying that you do not grow
yeah when purchasing a firearm
I see
okay
well
if you all are happy to move on from
this topic I thought another one that's
like really fundamental probably you you
two take it for granted more or less by
now but I do want to ask about uh like
your vidging window your flowering
window how you strategize around that
um Denali do you want to start
well I pretty much let the sun do all
the work
you know and uh them plants are going to
flower when they want to flower and
you just run them out till they start
but generally that's in uh August
you know you might get a few that uh
earning flowers in July
but uh then it depends on the plant
you know some you take that 10 weeks and
if you if you get that window of
opportunity with the weather
some of them you that are shorter they
get taken in September but I would say
the majority uh in October
yeah a kind of a general rule of thumb
that my brother taught me and pretty
much what I noticed a lot of The Growers
go by is outdoors by Mother's Day get
your plants Outdoors by Mother's Day if
you want to get like a six or an eight
foot tall plant and generally August 1st
is when we would expect stretch and and
the initial signs of flower to come and
that's kind of for pretty much everybody
that I talked to in Northern California
that's a pretty Baseline statement that
I hear from most people
um I personally don't do Mother's Day
anymore I do June 1st because I've had
days before where snow dropped and I had
plants outdoors and I was like well [ __ ]
you know I don't I got little seedlings
getting drowned out by snow in late
spring snowstorms that hit randomly so
now I wait a little bit later and I go
Outdoors on June 1st
and I usually put 12 to 14 inch tall
seedlings out expecting something
between the six and the eight or nine
foot range which is about the size of
plant that I prefer working on I don't
like when they get much bigger than that
yeah I go in much later than you
um
with Tweakers and things like that you
you can't grow an eight foot nine foot
plant here you have to have it below the
fence right and I've tied them down
and um
attempt below the fence but I generally
don't go in until July
just so they don't get so big and I
personally think a smaller plant
might be better I hate to say that but I
I do than them giant plans
right some of my dwarf plants some years
where I grow and a plant will dwarf out
and it'll only go for it but like the
snow S1 from last year one of my
smallest plants one of the most potent
hardest hitting longest lasting smokes
out of the 14 13 cultivars that I grew
and it was a little dwarf thing that was
no different than the other plants that
were all 12 to 14 inches when they went
Outdoors
yeah I don't I know there's talk about
how smaller plants will produce more
resin the energy is all focused on a
much smaller structure so it gives it
more more benefits but I've never done
the test personally myself I'd love to
take a cutting of the same plant and
grow a big one on a small one and side
by side and test them that'd be a really
fun project yeah
yeah cool I mean anything else on like
plant size that you guys wanted to throw
in there since that's like an
interesting little topic
this uh you know plant size is
interesting sometimes like some some
plants that I think will not have a long
stretch phase end up stretching like
crazy
um you know you never really know with
some of these plants
um and something else that I think we
kind of touched on earlier is like
selecting the specific cultivars for
your environment over the years I've
unconsciously lean towards Afghani
genetics and I realized that where I'm
growing is very similar to high altitude
Afghanistan if you look at photos and
videos it's High Desert Pine with red
clay soil and that's exactly where I
live and I noticed a relationship
between the Afghani cultivars that just
basically grew themselves in my
environment and I kept leaning towards
them naturally because they they perform
the best in my area
yeah so often you know it's about
finding good fit right that's like a
general principle I imagine of growing
Outdoors finding the right plants to fit
your environment as well right
absolutely
I think two better plants I ever grew it
was in 82 and I was uh living in the
fifth wheel and in a trailer park and I
put up a eight by ten little uh you know
those Sears storage sheds you know with
the metal doors and uh put up the
fiberglass Roofing on it
and uh buddy and I uh started these nine
plants in there and uh
uh they grew and it was one that just
stayed super short it didn't probably
get three feet tall but these other ones
you know hell they're up against the top
of the roof and you can perfectly see a
cannabis leaf and uh so that wasn't
gonna work so I went to the uh
Sporting Goods store and bought all
these you know one two
ounce lead sinkers and uh Bishops uh
snelled Bishops and I put these weights
on them and that's how I kept all these
plants in that eight by ten storage shed
bent over and not touching the top was
with weights and sinkers and then after
they butted and that God what a mess it
was with all that weights and sinkers
banging into your hooking and stuff like
this oh my God two glands that came out
of there no and one of them is super
short didn't grow very big bushy uh but
it smelled just like seven up and it
tasted just like seven of them
and uh then there was this one that grew
and it grew really weird it grew like a
rose you know with the leaves there
wasn't a lot of hairs on it do you
remember what it was no no these are all
seeds that would just get out of bags
gotcha you know and uh yeah but I've
seen it grown I've seen that rose petal
like what I call it uh one time in
Spring Valley and I was probably five
years ago and I didn't see it till it
was damn near ready to cut and I
probably should have took it cutting and
just you know we vegged it something to
try uh to uh get it to grow when they
say Rose are you talking about Bud
formation or Leaf formation uh yeah it's
Leaf it's actually Leaf formation okay
the leaf comes around interesting the
way that's it I think Urkel can do that
sometimes poodle nuts has some look like
that too yeah it can Rose top or flower
top almost
yeah it was raining it was weird very
weird but it was strong and it was uh
super crystally and sticky
nice
yeah well this is actually touching on
the question no one could get to anyway
which is about what have some of uh your
favorite plants been to grow outdoors
denial you can you can keep going for
sure of orange
yeah what what what about it
what about it do you like uh
it's got a crazy difference amount at
least uh one I have
um got a crazy difference now it's um
got a great high as far for me you know
and
weeds of you know subjectable I guess it
would be you know might not get you as
high as it doesn't mean
but um I don't know man that's the one
that like I think everybody like pretty
much agrees that it's as strong as chemd
or close to it like no ceiling type eye
that's OD too I bet you do that's just
tasty
so both of those plans do well Outdoors
for you Denali yeah they do they do yes
um is there anything about them you
think that lends them to that is it the
structure is it you know what is it uh I
might give more loving
that's true uh so it's because you like
them more that like you pamper them more
of course yeah of course yeah there's
always some in the garden that that are
that way for sure for me at least I
gotta say I I think nacho very much for
uh sharing that with me yeah for
slipping you the D yeah yeah
you're what one of two people in our
group he's ever passed something to you
are the Don Don uh d-a-w-n
yeah how about you
dinner so
yeah over the years
um it's definitely a personal taste and
I think it's from like a nostalgic
purpose too because the first weed that
I smoked that got me really really
really high was my brother's Bubba Kush
and
from then on out it just set kind of
like a precedent and I I noticed in my
outdoor Gardens continually the first
bag to go or the first jar to go is
something that leans OG like I would
grow a plethora of stuff and over the
years
um just the the White Fire OG Fire OG
Tahoe Skywalker
candy cush Larry OG the orange kush the
Obama kush the dosey doe like all of
this stuff for me personally just it
hits my favorite stuff and a big part of
that is
um just just nice pain relief
um I think there's something in the OG
that has great
um
inflammation it helps with inflammation
I think it has a great amount of
anti-inflammatory to it it just it helps
me with
everything when I smoke in OG so one
thing with OG that I've noticed like
looking at test results
um and it has the same effect for me too
even with anti-anxiety I don't normally
get anxiety with ogs despite the high
potency
um is that they're both super high in
mercine like really high even though
it's totally different smells
um and I know there's more components
obviously in OG than just nursing but
they both like blueberry immersing or
blueberry and OG test super high for
Mercy right I always thought that was
interesting for the pain relief and
positive aspects yeah
yeah
no you go sorry I was I was just gonna
say like the pain relief is probably one
of my main uh one of my main goals that
I'm looking for in some of the cultivars
um I do a lot of outdoor activities and
I'm a bit overweight so it doesn't wear
and tear on my body so at the end of the
day I'm looking to smoke something that
[ __ ] that takes away all the pain that
that I accumulated throughout the day
doing [ __ ] I probably shouldn't have
yeah for sure
growing was a resin's uh gut yeah the
kush yeah I really like growing that one
too yeah that you that that does really
well outdoor with you like the Terps
everything it's just loud yeah the first
only plant I uh uh reversed wow yeah it
was your uh with your spray that's right
reversed it got balls and then they were
getting real close and I cut the
branches down
yeah you were just test traversing it
right
I just wanted to see if I could do it if
I can do it is do it
right there that's it you definitely can
yeah
um I just want to ask of course so you
mentioned that you like those plants for
you know various reasons uh pain relief
one of them
um are there any features of those
plants you think that lend themselves to
Growing Outdoors well
here
um yeah stocky structure
um uh they hold up their own weight I
don't have to tie up many branches
um they don't
they don't have a structure where I'm
worried about
um their weight causing issues with them
which is a lot of the issues in late
season with my with my setup and how big
my plants are is how I'm going to
support
um weak armed or weak branched plants
and with those ogs and those hybrids
they gen they basically grow themselves
I don't have to do a whole lot of
external work to them
that's cool
um because my segue was actually going
to be into plant training and with their
e like either of you have to do much
training on your outdoor Appliance
very very subjective between the
cultivars some you have to tie up every
Branch some I don't have to tie up a
branch at all some plants like last year
I had the Albert Walker to the bubble
gum she was so heavily weighted down and
had such spindly branches that I did a
secondary outer cage and tied them to
that cage as well without that support
every Branch would have literally just
snapped at the first inch or two of snow
um yeah it's very very subjective
between cultivars um
yeah I would agree with that
yeah there's some you don't need to some
years they get really involved and I'll
pound stakes in and I'll run trellis two
links you know yeah two things to Trail
us through it and trellis is such a pain
in the ass when you go to take it off
one thing you didn't mention was using
um trellis for caterpillars
oh oh the bird netting that's what it is
yeah yeah talk about that real quick
yeah uh
which is uh one year I happen to have
put it over my vegetable garden and I've
seen uh one of them cabbage Moss bounce
off of it and I said well [ __ ]
a pain in the ass but I'll put that bird
ending over my plants and
as long as you keep it where there's no
holes you're great if one gets in there
he can't get out yeah it just bounces
around but uh no it works it's Flawless
they don't get through that is amazing
that's such good Tech it really is
caterpillars then you don't have to
worry about any spraying or anything
else yeah
please
yeah that was good that was good then
with uh that trellis yeah I I had never
seen that before but that that really
really uh shocked me that the the
caterpillars actually or the the moths
bounce off or whatever's going on yeah
like are the holes just too small for
them to enter and then I think they're
like five eighths gotcha I think they're
yeah they're pretty small and you know
with those wings out yeah they're not
right but the biggest pieces I've found
you know locally was uh like 28 by 28 so
I'd have to put a couple of them
together yeah
yeah they seemed to work well though
yeah it does if you can do that yeah
and like you said it's a pain in the ass
to get the trellis out once you're
harvesting sometimes right oh yeah
everything going through it
you know we generally all uh lollipop
everything yeah they were nothing on the
bottom just tops coming up yeah
I want to loop back for a sec onto back
to your favorite plants for just for a
moment because I remembered one more
thing I want to uh switches
um have you two gotten the chance to try
the same
you know clones cultivars
um
both the in like indoor grown versus
outdoor grown
sorry those are quite a garbled question
but I think yeah a couple of the stuff
that I've played around with indoors we
ran Outdoors
um I did a Cindy 99 cut that leaned
pineapple and it performed really great
indoors and and tasted really amazing
but when we grew it Outdoors she lost a
lot of her pineapple turbs and she she
didn't hold up structure very well for
out for a big outdoor plant
um same thing with the ATF but
um the Alaskan Thunder [ __ ] performed
better Outdoors than it did indoors in
my opinion it uh yeah I think it did a
lot better Outdoors than it did on the
indoors what was your um I always ask
people this and they mentioned Alaskan
butterfly or matineeska Valley Thunder
[ __ ] in your experience what did it
taste and smell like
um a unique
unique blend of anise like this weird
yeah this it's like anus is a part of it
but the other part of it is almost a
chemically something that's hard like I
don't have the palette or the exact uh
impact smell to to describe it perfectly
but it was memory doesn't exist for it
right right yeah but I would I would say
it somewhere in between like chemical
and and some one of the volatiles um
like a stringent aprid ooh Akron akron's
perfect there you go I would say
accurate yeah
perfect yeah that's interesting because
I re even with uh old dudes from Alaska
rarely do I ever see two people describe
uh Alaskan [ __ ] the same way so I
always ask when I hear it yeah I just I
just got it from a dispensary in like
2012. I have no clue about the I just
remember the brightest orangest hairs
I've ever seen on a green bud with like
perfect triangular buds like when you
would trim them up you could just roll
the bud in your hand and hold it and
just cut with the scissors perfectly
this is oh that's nice perfect
triangular bug formation
I love that makes it easy especially
when it's uniform from the top to the
bottom I love those cush genetics where
it's like golf ball nugs from the top to
the bottom yeah yeah it's my favorite
structure
I think that's one of the only things I
like about cookies is how easy it is to
trim yeah
I uh uh senior thinking you know about
the question of uh
uh my favorite plant and I just started
thinking of one after another after
another but uh as far as lay them out
right yeah let's hear them
God it was the chamba back in 80. I
remember just you know although done
growing plants right yeah Thai stick
that was if I if I could go back and
have one thing it would be one of them
Killer's Thai sticks
um
yeah that was actually we use a one-hit
Bowl
that was it and that's all just a little
Snapper and it would be enough huh oh
yeah
yeah I mean we may as well you may as
well tell us uh about the chamber since
we're here
that was uh uh I got transferred and I
have to be in Bakersfield working at
Bakersfield substation uh right next to
the old ice plant yeah the ice house
yeah the ice house and uh that was 19.
this before Matt was born
oh yeah
what year was it 1980 yeah I wouldn't
have been born yet yeah I was 81.
but uh the
guy lived in uh you know the place where
we work everybody's being transferred
from different places and uh there was a
few guys that lived over Santa Cruz area
and he brought this stuff over before
Christmas
and that's what he called it Jamba and
man it was just beautiful bud
55.8 and back then was like screaming
like you know Robin yeah yeah
but uh oh yeah I was at like 150 today
something like that an eighth oh God
yeah for an eight yeah is that what you
were getting an eight through fifty five
an eight for a 55 bucks yeah that would
be about I think 130 155 today I mean
yeah
but uh
they would just kill her butt and it was
uh
triangular it looked like Christmas tree
it's exactly with about that green color
and uh they weren't stiff and hard buds
but they were just nice compact buds
yeah and uh uh that's it you don't
remember anything about this I know it's
so long to ask about smell or any of
that stuff any of that stick it had a
sweet smell okay it wouldn't uh you know
a harsh smell at all I remember that but
uh yeah just take a small hit and it
would expand it would blow your lungs up
yeah yeah my older brother uh uh that
was the last time he ever smoked weed is
when he smoked Chama oh yeah the older
brother got some oh uh yeah I went down
for Christmas and uh uh smoked with some
friends and my brother happened to be
there and he wasn't a big smoker yeah
but he got this super panic attack
thought he was gonna die and everything
else
they scared himself so bad he hadn't
smoked since
that happens a lot with people uh one
negative experience if it's if it's bad
enough like a serious panic attack can
really turn people off from weed for
good right good we can do that but uh
plants that I really like that I grew
indoors and Outdoors was uh and they
have to both be Mass my Clockwork Orange
I found that indoor run and uh Riot very
hashplan an indoor run that's right
that's right that one gave me a [ __ ]
panic attack too and blueberry never
does that but the it was Riot Berry
Bubba G13 hash plant that's what the
whole thing was yeah
you know while I have you here do you
want to tell the story or you want me to
tell the story about how we met and you
bought those [ __ ] Clockwork seats
oh no I'll be glad to tell it yeah
please do okay well uh it was at uh the
Sonoma County uh Cannabis Cup Emerald
cup
and uh
I knew you were gonna be there we had
talked over the you know because you had
started doing your uh podcast or you
know yeah your life feed yeah and uh
so I knew you were going to be there and
I was really excited to meet you and I
wanted to meet you what a plumber huh
yeah
I've seen you sitting there and uh
that's why I got in line there would be
lying waiting to see you in that uh
for you and uh I think they were getting
clones there also yeah but um
uh so I got in line and it came with a
buddy
um we'll just call him the Butcher and I
was standing in line I got this great
idea
for what I wanted to do and yeah told my
buddy what I'm gonna do and uh he said
uh I'm out of here
I'm not going to be around if you're
going to do that well I'm going to do it
I'll wait in the line I got up there and
I I you know probably wrong but I acted
like a deaf mute
[Laughter]
and uh I had a pad of paper with me I
added my little uh there's no way
add a paper out and damn it I didn't
have been
so I went and pretended like riding on
this you know and back the guy he didn't
hand me a pen and I wrote there I was uh
interested in the uh
uh what were they maybe uh
banana uh Riot Berry crops maybe yeah I
don't know what it would have been that
time and uh uh so uh you know wrote out
you know I was interested in that and he
uh he said uh you know held up five
fingers and uh oh no
I said it again
and he said okay
uh 450.
so I gave him the 450. he gave me the
chain I stuck my hand out I said pleased
to meet you Mr Ryan my name
oh
and then he walked off and just like I
was like
uh yeah that's how we met yeah
that's an amazing the last part was that
he came up to me and was like okay so
the extra 50 bucks you want me to put it
in the fire finder do you want it yeah
he was gonna pay it yeah I get an option
to uh take his fifth back or put it in
the fireplace
I could never forget that dude like this
dude I mean I was sold on it that he was
this deaf mute and I was like oh yeah oh
okay yeah you know just okay nice to
meet you I'm Denali just bounces off
talk about a first impression might have
abandoned
it yeah and uh ended up best friends
after that as well yeah
that's a beautiful story
and who didn't know that he was the one
that impregnated my mom it's so weird
yeah
yeah the world Works small company yep
small company it was it was indeed
you know in thinking about these plants
that you grew both indoor and outdoor uh
what were some of the main differences
that you saw in the indoor Expressions
versus The Outdoor ones uh Clockwork I
don't get as much uh uh resin in that as
I did indoors
um
a ripe area lost so uh that's not around
but uh both of them were uh they grew
different they look different
than the ones that I had indoors I've
grown one of the one of the guys plants
it was uh q36 yeah and uh I grew you
know put it outside
and when I send him a picture he said
what's that
and I said that's your q36 he said
you're kidding it doesn't look anything
like it
and it just didn't how did it do outdoor
what's that how did q36 fare outdoor
uh it was good it was it was it was I I
thought it was fruity myself or tropical
did it mold a lot uh no it did not wow
yeah because it is a dense plant I have
a uh a picture with the
q36 and the D
and uh beautiful picture again both of
them look great
but uh these you've done indoor and out
yeah by now
no
I uh uh you know since uh our friend was
around and had departed that's right
I've just been uh I haven't uh really
floured anything I tried to do uh
done I forget some some local uh
some local would grow what is that Zohar
or something like that
yeah something like apple fritter or
something like that Apple [ __ ] yeah
yeah and uh I did it in indoors in a tan
and uh air conditioning went out in the
house and it just cooked it yeah I bet
it really booked it
that plant does not have a lot of
resistance we're learning a lot about it
uh I haven't flowered anything I plan on
it uh
coming up you're gonna have to do chompa
indoor yeah I'm gonna have to bring
zombie indoors yeah is probably what I'm
gonna have to do that's a long flower is
it the one from pack yeah yeah that's a
long flowering [ __ ] yeah it's 19 weeks
you're wild yeah yeah it probably will
it probably will reverse uh see if I
just get some mail pollen and maybe hit
it with something a little shorter
that's smart hit some of those afghanis
stuff like that short squats
but uh very cool
that's in the works but no I I want to
uh run indoors although I suck running
indoors I'd much rather run Outdoors
myself
um
uh it's pretty cool to be able to walk
in and have that you know when they're
flowering and the smell in there and
that yeah it is a beautiful smell yeah
well I got a couple more practical
questions for you too
um one I actually got to talk to Kush of
the Giants a little bit about beforehand
but I wanted to hear uh again the story
so
um what are your considerations well
okay sorry first of all do you all grow
in containers or like bags or are you
going in the ground and what are your
considerations slash experiences around
you know growing in the ground versus
growing in containers or bags Outdoors
Kush do you want to start first yeah
um so I currently grow mostly in 65
gallon fabric pots and it's uh generally
for ease of access uh if I had my
preference they would all be in the
ground but the the property is
continually being worked on
um cleared for fire danger and I've had
to move my little man's Anita patch
three times now so
um
yeah it's um
what was the question again
um
containers versus being in the ground
what are your considerations yeah so
um and and in previous years I would
take the containers and bring them all
up to the top of the plot and mix my
soil up there and and so it was easier
to keep things contained in the soil uh
in these fabric pots
um this year I experimented and dug a
hole in the ground where I found an old
petrified stump and um the the new spot
that I cut out of the patch this year
I'm feeling is more permanent um and I'm
probably going to be doing a lot more
holes in the ground rather than the 65
gallon fabric pots the the 65 gallons
are kind of restraining and constricting
some of the plants natural want to to to
grow a bigger root system
so I I do like the pots for their
accessibility the being able to move
them
um is really nice especially when you're
not in growing in the same exact area
every year
but uh I would much rather prefer the
ground
fascinating thank you how about you
Denali I uh I I use used to grow in uh
100 gallon pot then I personally thought
that wasn't uh I didn't need to use that
much soil and all that other stuff that
I could still grow plenty big enough
plant
and then I dropped to 65s and right now
I'm at 30s and with me planting late
um
um like I said my plants just don't get
that big but I've always used uh
fabric pots were at least now and what
the last eight ten years and uh
hey I find them uh better much better
than plastic
uh plastic you hit the Sun hits it and
it just it cooks that side of it
I leave my train of thought you'll
always win from one of these days you
guys all do this
dude it just happened to me five minutes
ago I think I'm the youngest person here
you know it happens to everyone it's
normal
right now um what about growing in the
grounds I would much rather grow in the
ground
yeah absolutely yeah some of the best
plants I Grew From my uncles uh in early
2000 and we had dug right in the ground
where his dad had his own worm beds and
uh out on an acre of land and uh that
was just Prime soil and they grew so
nice I bet you know there's one thing
that I do know the only thing I know
about outdoor that I've learned from
other people that that I didn't know
because I you know growing indoor and
pots you don't really learn this is that
cannabis plants like to grow about what
two what a foot and a half two feet deep
and then go outwards yeah is that
correct yeah they prefer yeah they
prefer the the horizontal growth yeah
as wide as they are going to be as Bush
wise is that correct too
roughly it it changes for some like last
year that Puro G Kush Kim dog Irene
hybrid was like 400 500 wider than the
65 gallon pot
wow the yeah the logistics behind it
when I look at the photo I'm like I
don't understand how that big of a plant
came out of a 65 gallon pot but in
general most most plants like to stay
within the curbed area that their their
Roots unless you train them or purposely
pull them out but a general rule of
thumb is yeah they like to stay around
the diameter of the pot yeah because I
always wondered
deeper like what if you dug six feet
deep and and I think the CSI was telling
me no they they like it's kind of
pointless at that point because they
like spread outwards so going super deep
doesn't do as well yeah yeah there's a
there's some dudes like uh Nuggie Nick
and there's a couple other IG cats they
have just two by fours it's not even two
feet tall and it's it's like a a 10 by
10 box with less than a foot and a half
of soil and they're growing 20 foot tall
plants yeah the plants are
super healthy super happy
I just wanted to ask Denali
um because he mentioned that he would he
would prefer to grow in the ground so
are your considerations growing in pots
the same as Kush of the Giants like are
you doing it because it's just more
convenient more accessible security
reasons yeah
um
yeah the fact that I actually thought
about having come in somebody come in
and trench it you know just long strips
yeah uh but uh it's just so easy with
those uh fabric plots you know and if
you need to you can move them you know
that's a consideration you know because
we red flagged here you know you got
five days to get your [ __ ] out yeah
you're in the ground you just might as
well cut them
yeah you're not gonna get them
at least in pots you might have a chance
yeah
yeah that's another big consideration
why I'm not in the ground completely my
substrate is lithothide clay and
volcanic rock it takes me an hour or two
to get an inch down like it and it's not
shoveling it's pickaxe work it's I might
pickaxe it apart and then shovel out the
rubble so you live in concrete basically
yeah and the only this is why you didn't
want to play Minecraft with us right
yeah play Minecraft in real life play
Minecraft at home yeah you'd rather play
The Quarry anyways super meta
that's really cool okay no thanks you
know that was a good Insight on both of
you thank you
um
there's a lot this is kind of like the
last prac like quite practical question
that I've got before it opens up a bit
so
um how do y'all feed slash amend
Janelle you want to go first girl I have
a big old big old Barrel
on what I'm using you know some years
I've gone and done bottles and liquid
formula and then pH it and all that
other stuff and I have to be open barrel
and put a pump down in it and I'll rub
water out to the plants or the garden
hose uh
they haven't just used it to dry
Amendment and Nature's Pride and they
have a grow and they have a bloom and
it's real easy and it doesn't Clump up
and stuff
um
as far as amendments
I've used uh
Happy Frog and Seed green I believe it
is and mix them too and then I'll add
other stuff to it Vu Blends and uh
just other nutrients a bunch of stuff
insect grass and all that kind of stuff
I watched Caleb enough and seen he'll
put out what he puts in his stuff you
know you just have to catch the post
uh Matthew muted
okay I have two different mute buttons
so I have to check yeah no he's very
transparent about that it's uh it's very
nice it's helped me a lot too when I'm
learning about organic growing um
because I've never grown that way in my
life I've always been a bottle person
and you know it's nice to be able to
brush up on that stuff when someone
actually knows it real well
yeah he's honest you know yeah he just
didn't realize man he's a good dude he's
like you man you know he's just a good
dude well like a lot of people don't
know you're one of the reasons me and
Caleb ever even became friends like
Denali was the the link between that him
and Resident along both
um kind of pushed us together to to be
more collaborative
yeah I appreciate that I don't take no
credit for nothing
[Laughter]
um how about you because of the Giants
feeding
um
yeah so for me personally what works
really well for me
um
my when I when I pile all my soil up
together it's around 650 or 700 gallons
of soil and every three or four years I
refresh it with
um slow slow breakdown amendments I do
uh 50 pound bag of blood meal bone meal
kelp meal alfalfa meal crab meal and a
30 pound bag of humic acid
and then all through veg I'm essentially
just adding water and uh if the plants
are showing that they want more nitrogen
or if there's not enough readily
available nutrients then I will Brew
some activated aerated compost teas to
to spike to spike some nitrogen and get
things uh heated back up in the soil and
with the size of plants that I grow I
noticed that yeah about every two or
three years they they suck those pots
dry and and deplete pretty much
everything out of them the the ladies
fade pretty hard in a lot of my photos
and if I need more than that if I need
more than the activated aerated compost
teas on top of the the pre-amendments in
the soil sometimes I will Top dress with
a pellet a chicken [ __ ] pellet I use
only one type it's from Nutra Rich
um it's like a four two two chicken
pellets a really hard pellet and when
you scatter it across the top of your
soil and water it down it breaks down in
tight of a muddy slur
um and beyond that
um in flower if I notice some liming up
a little bit or asking for some more
nutrients I'll go to something like uh
the Gaia Green Earth
um the flowering stuff some Maxi or some
Earth Juice and I'll I'll do very little
amounts of that if the plants are asking
for it but generally most the mostly
just having the soil pre-amended and
doing the activated compost teas does
does plenty of work on these plants
nice
okay
um anything anyone else wanted to say
about feeding amending foliage anyone
yeah I I like you know from Kush
how often do you look down on the tops
of your plants
well right around August uh I'm stopped
being able to look over them they're the
ones looking over me right now
especially Matt's blue resin Kush oh my
God man how big is she now
yeah I want to say 10 but I could be
wrong
um maybe the top top spear is ten yeah
like I'm gonna have to get on a ladder
to get I'm gonna have to get on a ladder
do they make ladders bigger than you
yeah yeah
there's some contractor ladders that
I'll have to [ __ ] bring down there
yeah dude that that lady man the she's
she's just doing all sorts of things
that I like and I did not expect her to
express in in the way that she did
that's awesome but uh I'm happy that
she's she's going for the sky right now
I think she's the tallest out of
everybody right now that's so wild
Afghani blueberry right right with the
with the fan leaves I think you saw the
post I did just the other day that those
two families those things the Legacy fan
Leafs on the second and third node yeah
insane how big those are yeah that's
wild it reminds me of the balochis or
whatever it was it had the big [ __ ]
yeah right prehistoric some yeah
Jurassic Fern style stuff yeah yeah the
Kush used in that was the one that
Denali was referring to earlier it came
from our buddy resin lung and it was the
one that his crew had held since they
were running the old you know Mansions
back in the day in La pushing OG cush
out of the Mansions so that's where that
came from and um everything in that blue
resin Kush is testing super high like
three percent Plus in in Terps but up to
like seven you know like crazy numbers
so I'm really really interested to see
what she does outdoor yeah she smells
wonderful right now just like sweet
sweet Citrus blueberry oh that's nice
yeah
okay
so if nothing else I have a couple of
like more open-ended questions to round
out uh our conversation today
um Matt also wants to leave a bit of
time for a little review at the end that
you you too can join us
um witnessing
um so okay the first open question is I
wanted to hear about uh your kind of
worst experiences Outdoors partly
because it's entertaining partly because
it's also informative for other people
um Denali do you I mean we mentioned
pests earlier and some stories around
that um do you have anything comes to
mind when I say worst experiences
Outdoors
ah
I guess when I found out uh
uh across the street uh her uh son was a
sheriff
and uh this is uh this is a no Grow Zone
and so yeah so he's a uh Sheriff here in
the county
and I met him and I was really worried
he was going to tell me you know yeah I
can't do this you can't do every year I
was worried about he was going to change
because he kept going up in the ranks
yeah uh he never bothered me but I
worried about that
worry about that a lot I bet yeah yeah
yeah that sucks yeah you never know like
which way cops are gonna go especially
with their neighbors you just don't know
some of them will be growing right next
to you and you know arresting people
during their day job it's wild up there
yeah there's a guy that had one of these
dispensaries that they deliver in that
and he he was the ex head monkey mug of
the Department of fishing game Jesus
busting busting outdoor illegal grows
and [ __ ] yeah his guys who go out and
cut down uh plants and things like that
but you know
he's funding it yeah and he did it for
one of the senators or something that uh
had the money but he could get the
license of course he could that's why I
[ __ ] hate politicians that's
disgusting yeah it's super disgusting
and it's abundant
okay
how about you Chris worst experiences
um fail stories worst experiences man
um
honestly the the real big one comes to
mind is uh
topping some cultivars that should not
have been topped and what it does to
them
uh I had it happen twice and it happened
with the Deep chunk yeah
yeah I topped it outdoors and then I
also did it with the Salmon Creek big
bud and oh interesting it it created
such a short stocky jungly bushy plant
that it became a chore to every day go
in and clean out the inner growth make
sure she could breathe make sure she's
literally not choking herself out
because she's like intertwined in the
cage and intertwined in herself yeah
like some of my biggest fail stories
would be like just you know treating a
plant not letting it naturally grow and
learning which cultivars um will do that
and looking for the telltale signs
um good example of that was this year I
popped some cream bag seed from my old
super cropping it's a black cherry soda
hybrid that I'm very very ensconced with
and
um as it's growing and as it's as it's
stock is shooting up and I'm looking at
this thing that's like like four inches
in diameter I'm like I can't top this if
I top this the same exact thing is going
to happen that happened to the Jeep
chunk and so I just let it naturally
Christmas tree profile out and it's it's
performing much better than if I had
topped it so it was a fail but it was a
lesson that later taught me to pay
attention to these things for these
outdoor plants that hey man don't don't
top that that's going to be a problem
yeah that's a good point it does release
certain hormones into the plant when you
top that you know some plants will react
well to you some won't you know and you
just never know till you do it but yeah
one of the key things like if you know
like indoor if if you want to know if a
plant outdoor will react bad if you top
it and it goes straight up with two
poles like straight up next to each
other it's going to be one of the ones
that probably does not do well outdoor
problems yep I had the uh what is that
big sir holy weed triangle Kush last
year yeah I topped it and it bifurcated
the stock and went straight up in the
air I call Twin Towers it literally was
funny just identical branches all the
way up yep exactly yeah another fail was
like uh one year I think it was 2018
when I was growing some uh
lemon party or maybe in 2019 I was
growing lemon party s ones and it was
like week two of flower week three of
flower and I was like man I want to hit
these with some kelp I just thought that
they could use the the the Boost and I
hit them with too much kelp and they got
burnt and they never really recovered
from that so that's that's another thing
that I've learned is like if they're
happy and they look okay you don't have
to you don't have to force feed them you
know sometimes yes
sometimes with the outdoor grow just
letting the plants be helps in a lot of
situations rather than trying to over
meticulously worry about every little
thing with them
yeah I mean that's kind of a perfect
segue because the next question was
going to be about
um how have you both know like observed
your approach to have changed over the
years and obviously in talking about
fails and all that sometimes these are
going to be the turning points or the
major learning points um that allow you
to progress
um Denali you know you've been going
what like that's like four you know 40
years or so like how how do you see your
progress or Journey as a grower and how
how has your approach changed over the
years
uh
I still don't think I grow very good
weed now
that I don't think I get like 75 I think
it's always got something more to give
that plant
I don't know that I've ever seen a
perfect grow
um and I don't know where I'm going with
this
like like how what how does your journey
changed I mean like in the past even
five years it was well uh god well it
changed immensely with the computer yeah
okay you know there was an information
back then it was a few books in that but
uh
yeah it wasn't readily talked about
there was nothing like this you know I
didn't even when the forums came out I
didn't get involved with them because I
just thought these guys are crazy for
talking about this stuff over this thing
that somebody has to be listening or
being able to you know what's going
where and who's doing what and I just
stayed away from it a couple times I
logged on to him and I just was like nah
no way but um uh so much has changed in
all them years you know from Miracle
Grow job all this stuff they have
nowadays and that you know you go into
one of them nurseries and you better be
smart you better mean what you want
because he used cars she was a shoe
store yeah there's some for everything
and multiple of it yeah no
um
I still think you can grow good weed
just with basic amendments I really do
yeah um
I I think a lot of people overthink it
you know and uh yeah looking for that uh
perfect
and uh
I don't know if it's attainable I think
this plant uh uh always has something
more to give always a curveball
yeah
I mean there's some they're pretty damn
good now yeah you know but uh uh I don't
know I just uh so Denalis yeah denali's
staying humble you know after 40 years
he's still learning and yeah
yeah I uh I forgot a lot of stuff you
know but I have this place here to come
to and uh questions and I still ask some
basic questions yeah because these guys
know these guys are good Growers they
really are and uh uh anybody can't learn
from them well you know I don't know uh
I learn every day from and I really I
really you know thank Matt for starting
this and getting this going and
introducing me to these guys
um yeah
I love you big change big change
all right very nice how about you Kush
um just essentially a wholehearted
agreement
um just like stay humble and like over
the years I've I've always said that
like cannabis next to bass fishing and
deer hunting are three of the most
subjective topics that I've ever
encountered and everybody thinks that
their way is the right way to do it and
that's an empirical fact and I've found
my success by taking the subjectivity
out of it and and looking at people who
are successful
seeing that they're doing something
different than me trying that method and
if it works for my garden then I
continue to apply it if it doesn't then
I don't apply it to my garden and I've
been doing that since day one with an
open mind and I feel like that's
probably the best way to tackle it is
just always always think that you know
you're probably there's something more
that you could be doing because it is so
in depth and it is so subjective I feel
personally I could spend lifetimes
studying and learning about this plant
and still come up short in considering
myself an expert and sure I think as
long as we keep that attitude like and
keep our minds open to the possibilities
it's it's the best position that you
could be especially for
an outdoor grower with the X Factor of
your environment or the the multiple X
factors of your environment
yeah
yeah and and that you know comes back to
my earlier disclaimer about
grow information and how it's often
framed on the internet
um
people like to pretend that they have
the authoritative or you know Ultimate
Guide to whatever
videos on YouTube I'm not an expert I am
not a [ __ ] expert I am a I'm a Noob
at this dude I've been growing since
2008 like I I don't know [ __ ] compared
to a lot there's a lot of people who
could be sitting here instead of me
well I think what's important you know
and what we covered today is again just
exposing how diverse the approaches can
be how diverse the environments can be
and the challenges that come with them
um and there's never going to be you
know like Matt and I have been saying
even throughout the breeding episodes
like there's no Silver Bullet
um you just have to
um like Christian Denali have both Sid
you know essentially try stuff out learn
iterate again and keep iterating like
forever because that's your dick in it
dial it in yeah just every year dial it
in it'll get better every year if you
pay attention
nice
yeah well I mean anytime
you just get a hold of me all right
how can this fall me and you we got to
do a double date we'll hit your Lake and
then we'll hit my Lake okay and then we
can hit the Kern River
oh yeah
all right yeah
that's a bad
bad it is man people people swim in that
all the time still despite all the signs
everywhere stay the [ __ ] out yeah at the
beginning of the uh uh Canyon Road
there's a sign there with how many
deaths there are each year yeah yeah I
remember when I believe it was in the
30s and it's in the 200 and something is
now oh yeah have died in that River yeah
um we we have our our scooter rallies
out right next to the river at a French
Gulch Campground out there I know where
it is yeah and each year we go out there
and this year it was the first time
we've seen that River above like almost
hitting the the banks it was it was
insane people were worried about the
damn flooding and stuff so yeah Rivers
flooded oh yeah that's bad River yeah
nice tangent huh you know um one of the
things that I really want to talk about
before we are done with Kush of the
Giants
um
[Laughter]
is uh the cream you mentioned it very
briefly uh right this is the breeder
Syndicate let's just give a brief brief
or not even brief let's just talk about
um your your fascination with the strain
called black cherry soda and the cream
absolutely yeah um so uh sometime around
2010 uh I had a friend from the Bay Area
she was a breeder and she offered me
some of her clones to try outdoors and I
I got to try the black cherry soda and I
got to try this hybrid that she just
called cream and it was black cherry
soda crossed to Triple Threat and as far
as I can research it's um sour grapes to
Afghani to unknown
um and the the cream really just kind of
it was one of those things that just
fell into your lap and you don't know
what you have and how good it is until
you lose it yeah
it's literally a plant that grew itself
it had no external needs it just it just
did its thing in my environment very
easily and I would have buyers that
would buy every crumb of it it um
they've flowered out really fast early
in flower you'd get this beautiful like
vanilla like strong vanilla extract
smell and then week four or five this
Citrus orange would come in Mandarin
orange where you'd get the uh you know
the old 50 50 ice cream bars oh yeah
that's the exact smell you would get out
of this
yeah just just one of my favorite
profiles and and I think I super cropped
that or mono cropped that from
2000 10 to about
2019. it was nine years where wow I grew
14 of those outdoor every year trying to
get two pounds off at each plant and the
buyer would literally buy every crumb
off of it it was yeah and
I didn't realize because and that's the
other thing that's funny too is I smoked
mostly cream during that session too not
really I I I try stuff here and there
and try a single out offshoot plant in
the garden but I was mainly smoking that
cream just being super complacent not
realizing that I had such a fantastic
plant that I could smoke it for so long
and not get tired of it yeah yeah and
then the second I lost it it became
super apparent to me how much how how
fantastic she was and
yeah so so in in losing her you started
your journey into trying to recapture
that in seed form yeah it got me into it
put literally put my nose right into the
to the reader Syndicate episodes about
reversal sprays and and taking your
lines and and you know making the the
the generations last I I at the time
that I had the cream I was very
complacent just cloning re-mothering and
just super cropping this plant in the
back of my mind I was never thinking
about propagating this plant and I did I
didn't think that
um recloning it and remothering it so
much would cause genetic issues later
down the line I I just it just wasn't in
my mind it wasn't something I was paying
attention to
and um yeah so it got me into uh got me
looking into what I should be doing as
far as is breeding and and in case I run
into something like that again in the
future and and luckily uh I found some
old trim I got some Bag seed of the old
cream from 2016. and I got uh had a male
and a female come up this year I took
out the mail but took clones of it all
the Clones are rooted they're waiting I
took clones to the female so I got this
this bag seed representation and yeah
she's she's a little chunkier than what
I'm used to and that that would you know
that she's she's got a different
phenotypical expression a little bit but
she has that vanilla where we're in week
two almost you know two and a half weeks
of flower and that vanilla it's
literally emanating vanilla smells so
I'm I'm in Nostalgia heaven right now
with this plant
you know two strains that I immediately
think of when you talk about it are West
Coast dog Which is popular up in your
area very very much like vanilla bean
smelling uh I believe someone renamed it
Madagascar vanilla bean for a while and
um agent orange Agent Orange Is Right a
few times I've seen a seed line that
produced 50 50 bar terms that's a name I
haven't heard in a while yeah yeah a PGA
agent orange it was one of the people
often confused my Clockwork Orange with
it so people would be like oh you're the
dudamate agent orange and I'd have to
disappoint them be like no no I made the
clock and they're like oh I don't know
what that is [ __ ] that you know right
right yeah but no it had a beautiful 50
50 bar uh taste and smell and that's
something that's always stood out to me
because in the world of oranges I'm not
a huge fan unless it is that 50 50 bar
sweet orange green yeah it's beautiful
yeah most of the Citrus that I run into
it's not my favorite I don't find a lot
of pure orange Citrus strong
um as compared to Lemon Citrus or or
lime Citrus much much different
different than the orange Citrus sure
absolutely I like Cali orange you like
the Calio I like the Calio
my first time I smell the guy came in
and it just reeked and I just thought
that was some of the best stuff
I have an old pack that I found from
Dutch Passion at California Orange you
should pop it see if you like them
that's old like that I haven't had that
in years and years and years
any glass orange I had was your orange
cookies
oh yeah yeah that's right but that was
mostly cookies dominant yeah
that was good though that was good good
you did good with that one
my uh my buddy did the California Gold
Rush from Caleb last year the Calio to
train wreck oh how was that it was a
monster it was an amalgamation of really
large Buds and just terpenolene and
citrus orange like yeah it it was it was
a heady plant big buds but Airy but you
know not not real dense
he he made a lemon party Calio too which
I was like oh my God that's gonna be
almost offensively Citrus to the point
like lemon orange to the point where it
might not even be smokable because it's
so oily anybody who's after lemon Terps
go to the lemon party
um s1s everything that I popped just
Starburst yellow
um uh not Bubba head the uh lemon head
candy uh Terps were there uh and my
favorite was one that leaned a little
sativa and it was like black tea and
lemon it was like a hashy hazy
um tea black tea mixed in with a lemon
like I thought like lemon black tea
every time I smelled this plant that's
beautiful yeah
all righty I mean is that
is that us before the review man
uh yeah I guess we could do the review
since we're talking about Lenin right
and recently we had it we had a person
join our our uh
server briefly very briefly that talked
about a cut called Lemon Cherry gelato
and he was talking about how this cut
just one cups it's the bomb you know the
the another gelato So lately I've been
on my quest to
update my my knowledge of current
availability of flower strains and
flower form
um in the hype Market you know strains
that I normally wouldn't pay attention
to or smoke I've been trying to force
myself into learning about maybe opening
my eyes broadening my horizons as it
were to see what some of the kids were
smoking these days so I decided Lemon
Cherry gelato uh would be the the next
choice
and I wrote down some notes real quick
when I was smoking it on not first the
scent you know the flavor profile the
high any anything like that
um when I get a strain called Lemon
Cherry that's going to be the first
thing that I'm looking for when I smoke
it or even smell the bud right what does
it smell like does Mike lemon or cherry
does the name infer anything
um smelling it
it wasn't I mean it had a decent scent
it wasn't like unscented it was um
I could tell that it had some kind of OG
in it but the dominant scent was mostly
gelato not really sweet
um as as I in first I I smoked it with a
lighter
and I was getting from the flavors
earthy chocolate for a second
um some floor cleaner like OG
hopsy not unpleasant interesting for a
gelato but it tasted exactly like a
well-grown OG Kush which from the smell
I knew that would be in there I did not
think that would be the dominant flavor
when combusted was just like smoking a
really good OG Kush
um with that said there was no lemon or
cherry of any sort combusting it for me
personally in this grow of it obviously
depends who grows it how they grow it
Etc
um it did have a unique almost woodsy
smell with a sweet earthy chocolate
almost like Bubba um in the background
like how Bubba can be kind of chocolatey
um but yeah it tasted like OG Kush
all the way and the the most important
part of it would be the high which
lasted a total of 13 minutes it may be
the
um the least
length of a high because I could feel I
was high at first it wasn't like it
didn't hit at all it wasn't like a
Blackberry Kush it was non-existent but
it was third I counted it like okay I
marked it down okay I smoked right now
within 13 minutes it was totally gone
and I had to smoke again so that was a
problem that's a problem
um so I've been sitting here with the uh
rip you know sitting here with uh the
rip
um vapiness throughout the episode
because ripping it gives you a whole
different flavor profile all of it it
you're getting a lot of the volatiles
that that burn up immediately when you
combust it you'll never taste you taste
them this way
um so what I wrote down during this is
while we were doing this let's write it
down the loudest flavor by far is the
Lemon so whereas combusting I tasted no
lemon nothing this tasted completely
like lemon like all up front lemon
um floor cleaner like like OG Kush would
um but Extreme lemon extreme lemon so
the lemon name is accurate per vaping to
be honest um The Hive is much brighter
clearer and more energetic I actually
really liked the high from it
but it lasted like 10 13 minutes
I'm just curious at this point and uh
with Denali and kush here uh do you two
what are your primary modes of like
interesting like
joints glass do you do either of you
vape as well
I like uh I like balls I like water
filtered
yeah yeah I got a prototype shower head
glass piece that I really enjoyed i've
smoked out of a lot of pieces but
nothing beats the shower head Park
system
nice
I was just saying I was just gonna say
that like um it is interesting what
Matt's pointing out right that vaping
obviously can be quite a different
experience especially when it comes to
the
yeah smell and flavor and high high is
so different I can't even explain to you
how different the high is from um from
using the rip versus combustion
um you know some people say that vaping
doesn't get them high at all whereas I
think it gets me so much more
um
so much more high it's it's
way more complex way more complex of a
High
um like I said the incombusting this in
a decent high but it wasn't like um it
wasn't anything better than a normal
gelato like as far as high vaping it was
much more energetic it was clear-headed
but it was obviously there and it was
pleasant kind of giggly
um it's a totally different experience
and I highly recommend everybody give
both a try
yeah fascinating I don't know do we have
a rating system yet uh do we want stars
do we want buds do we want and how many
four or five where are we going guys
I need to start a rating system guys
help me out
five stars five buds five stars yeah
five stars you know we can think of what
else it can be I will give this a three
out of five because it got me high it
was a decent High
but it loses two stars for lasting 10 to
15 minutes like I already want to dab
some diamonds or something
you know what I mean like yeah so that's
my review on Lemon Cherry gelato the the
best strain ever
According to some
yeah
uh that's cool I mean thank you both so
much uh for coming on the show
um it was a really cool conversation and
I think we covered a lot of territory
um shout out to Rings poor guy he was
meant to join us I think
we'll take that L uh we messed up a bit
with the coordination
um yeah but we hope to have him on again
I think it was clear from just talking
to you both today that you know there's
so much that we could say on our door
right this may not be the last time we
have this conversation so hopefully we
can get rings back but otherwise yeah
again great to have Denali on finally
finally
um
and yeah great to hear from Christian of
the Giants as well like fantastic
information from both of you
Denali do you want to give any shout
outs to anyone in The Syndicate on The
Syndicate discourse I know that there
are people there who absolutely love you
is there anyone you want to shout out uh
our whole crew
yeah everybody in it
um
and uh
I don't know
I kind of got a liking for this Carlos
guy oh yeah yeah Carla Charles isn't bad
he's not a bad guy I like that guy a lot
actually
so he's
okay
but they're all good over there man yeah
a lot of knowledgeable people over there
you know uh sheets but uh you cannot
love the sheets
but uh yeah there's a lot of good people
you put together yeah and meet and Kush
at the party uh he's a giant but he's
literal sweetheart
like I'm already short and and he really
oh yeah
[ __ ]
[Music]
okay
all right because of the Giants you got
anything you want to shout out
um just uh just a big thank you to
everybody in The Syndicate and
especially to you Matt for for bringing
me into the fold and you know just treat
me like family it it's been a huge
reminder uh and I said this before but
it's it's a huge reminder of how
important Community is
um I was very complacent
in past years and now that I'm brushing
shoulders with with some of these guys
it's like hey you need to step your game
up you could be doing better and I like
I like when I get motivated to do more
because the people around me are just as
excited and endeavored into this this
thing that we all love it's uh it's iron
sharpening iron for me and I and I love
it
yeah everybody in that group does make
me want to be a better person that's for
sure like it makes me want to be a
better human being for everyone around
me right that's something special
absolutely
all right with that thank you bastards
thank you so much for taking your time
and uh both of you it's been an absolute
pleasure and uh yeah you got anything
thousand do you want to say
no I think I I think I've said
everything I wanted to say
um maybe we'll see you two back at some
point yeah for sure
yeah anytime you need both back in
okay all right save some diamonds for me
hey you got oh yeah we got I stocked up
I stocked up I stocked up so you better
get here
um with that be sure to join our patreon
Discord go check it out on patreon.com
forward slash breeders Syndicate
um what else we have riotsseeds.com to
get the spray that we've been talking
about this episode and some of the seeds
that we've been talking about this
episode and a Siege from some of the
other can Illuminati members we're about
to add Ms Jill's year to the site which
I'm sure a lot of people that know me
think that is the most ironic weird
thing that Miss Jill and me have been
very good friends for for many years now
and uh very very privileged and proud to
add her to the team that's it oh yeah
all right next week thank you everyone
same [ __ ]
you want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out