welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate hey everyone welcome to
breeder Syndicate I'm Matthew I'm not
going to be on this show this week uh we
kind of are trying to experiment a
little bit with other people running it
uh but when I'm down or I have to get
other stuff done I mean that's always
been kind of the goal and thousands
helped a bunch with that so this week
it's going to be run by thousand and
Kush of the Giants but we're also going
to have um uh well Kush of the Giants
little Hill and Peach and it's going to
be talking about like the outdoor
results strain specific type stuff what
does well outdoor it's a really
interesting episode you guys know me I
really don't like outdoor stuff but I'm
pretty impressed with how well they did
real proud of it so I'm stoked to put it
out
there and with that we'll kick it off I
just didn't want to just crash into it
so see you
two weeks thanks all right good evening
everyone and welcome to the breeda
Syndicate uh tonight I will be your host
thousandfold and uh we are without Matt
um some context uh he's having a little
bit of uh tooth trouble but also we were
eventually hoping that kush could
actually Host this himself so we we're
sort of on the way to that too um but uh
I am here for tonight uh but I'm going
to let Kush run the show so uh we are
joined tonight by little Hill peaches
chis of the Giants all uh All crew
members that uh some of you would have
met before on on the show uh and yeah
without F further further Ado I'll hand
it over to
Kush well first of all I wanted to thank
little Hill and peaches for tagging
along and and doing this conversation
with me um and essentially tonight uh
we're just going to do a small outdoor
recap of the uh the season that we had
for outdoor last year um the cleanup and
the prep that we we have for for next
season um we're going to be talking
about what strains we liked last fall
and uh you know what worked well what
didn't and then we're going to wrap it
all up by talking about what we're
excited to grow for this upcoming season
um it's not going to be a super long
episode it's uh you know it's going to
be short and sweet and
just kind of recap the season and have a
discussion about everything that we
[Music]
did um yeah so we we'll start it off
with just what what did you grow this
last outdoor season that really worked
well with you what what what were the
ones that stood out to you and um to in
in your in your mind what was your
favorite um for me personally the
highlight of last year's outdoor grow
were the sweet 16 hybrids that CSI sent
my way and and I I played with them and
I I I follow my nose a lot when it comes
to cannabis um especially for selecting
stuff that I like my nose is usually one
of my my main things that I aim after
and all of these sweet 16 hybrids were
just incredibly strong
pungent um I was just at a party a
couple weekends ago and I brought some
of the sweet 16 pineapple and every time
I crack the jar or people across the
room would go geez man what is in that
and it's just the the floral notes that
come off of it stand out to me out of
out of a lot of the stuff that I grew um
from this last year the uh and I got to
see its expression across um multiple
hybrids I tried sweet 16 to Pineapple
sweet 16 to Humble duer cut and I tried
four different sweet 16 to Kim d
and they all expressed that um wine
fermenting fruit just really strong odor
every time you crack a jar it it hits
you like a like like something that
that's almost offensive to the nose it's
uh it's so strong in its odor um so yeah
I this year for me the the sweet 16
hybrids I wasn't expecting um much out
of them but man they blew my socks off
I'm super happy that I so got to try
those just wanted to needle you a bit
about this cuz you're talking about uh
how is how are the effects are you
implying that the effects they're not
quite as strong as some of the other
plants um so the sweet 16 pineapple was
uh sativa leiner wasn't as strong as the
other two hybrids but um they were all
when I'm talking about pungent I'm I'm
talking about the smell specifically on
the nose um they were all great smoke
the sativa leaner not being as um heavy
but they they were all very potent very
resinous strain completely completely
covered in resin I was impressed with uh
I was impressed with what I saw through
through it the uh sweet 16 that he used
has a has a strong gentic backbone
because you could see the similarities
across the the multiple cultivar as he
crossed it
too so yeah that I mean one of of the
other big ones this year that I really
enjoyed from CSI was the Triangle cush
Girl Scout cookies um it's another one
of his Girl Scout cookie hybrids that I
grew that kind of just grows itself I
don't have to I don't have to baby it
and it just really flourishes in my
environment comes
out per like it comes out almost perfect
to what I prefer smoking out of cannabis
is just a really good pain relief uh has
great uh Citrus great great cushy smells
and and it looks really good in the bag
so once again continually this is the
fourth year in a row that I've tried a
couple of different Girl Scout cookie
hybrids from csi's library and they all
continually provide this really great
smoke for me um yeah I got some more
that I want to talk about from last year
but I'm going to go ahead and ask little
Hill you know what were some of the
standouts from your garden last year
what were some things that that really
stood out to you um I grew I grew a lot
of new stuff this year um I had a little
extra space to work with and I wanted to
figure out what was going to work for me
Outdoors um with I haven't grown
strictly outdoors in quite some time
it's probably been I don't know six
years or so or seven years and uh so
like you know with new strains and
what's what's popular I I am a
commercial guy
um I just had to figure out what was
going to work in my environment finish
and and do well for my grow style which
is pretty hands-off organic
um I the the standouts that I that I
that I that I'm going to run again next
year were Mochi runts and I don't know
who that strain came from it was a clone
from a commercial Nursery um it's a runs
plant but but much more vigor ous and
really high testing in THC and the candy
flavor came through and the color came
through and really a really a vigorous
plant so I was I was a little hesitant
to run anything runs because I generally
don't like it but uh that one definitely
won me over another one was papaya bomb
which is a papaya to THC bomb cross also
from a commercial Nur
Nursery um huge flowers and just a old
like late '90s early 2000s type of smell
of just like strong tropical fruit hence
it's name papaya um you don't see a
whole lot like that anymore um and it
really kind of takes me back to like
sweet tooth number three and and some of
the stuff I grew when I first started
growing so I was really happy with that
one um funny you should mention those
sweet 16 crosses in this little side
Garden I I had where I grew a bunch of
seed and uh some random clones I I
acquired I I did grow the sweet 16
clone and I I liked it a lot not for
commercial production but as far as
flavor and having something
unique um I love it I enjoy the smoke
it's really tasty it's not super potent
no but uh it's it's a fun plant and I
still I still held on to the Clone just
to figuring out if I might do something
with it in the future or not I'm not
sure
but um I I really did enjoy that clone
and I know the guys that uh Caleb got
those genetics from um one of them's a
very good friend the other one's a good
friend but he's he's since moved away um
so I kind of I knew those those the
precursors to that to those to those
genetics uh you know so which clone are
we talking about right now I forgot uh
sweet 16 um got it it's a mindo perks to
a a killer queen cross and uh
uh all all those guys are meno guys that
that I knew pretty well that we were all
doing it back in back in the the
greenrush Heyday uh so it's kind of cool
to see that those genetics still sort of
mixed up and and and
thriving because they are unique and and
it was really a time when you could you
could grow stuff that just like the
smell jumped out of the bag unlike now
where it really seems like smell and
flavors have all kind of gotten BL land
and right you know the same so it's it's
that's a fun one to grow
um that was my biggest uh that was my
biggest and like reason for liking that
strain was the uniqueness of it um I
tried the sweet 16 from Caleb and the
first time he cracked the jar and I put
my nose in there I was like I've never
smell anything like this in cannabis
before the fermenting wine you know the
the blackberry wine 69
huh yeah this was at the party yeah and
he also had the blackberry wine um the
69 and both of them were like these are
unique turp profiles that I've never
smelled in a plant before and then those
same TPS seeing them in the uh the three
different hybrids that I got to try last
year I was like oh yeah there's shades
of it here but just you know little
influences from the kimd or little
influences from The Humble duer cut it
it really Shone through and basically
covered everything Frost and gave it a a
good nose I can imagine the the cross to
Pineapple was great for the nose
pineapple was another cut sort of from
that same era that all these same people
were growing in some form or fashion
because it's the nose jumped out of the
bag and and and that's really what sold
pot for us back then and and honestly
that clone the pineapple clone was
always a farm favorite for everybody so
and that's the stinkiest one that's the
sweet 16 pineapple man I cracked that
and it's like rotten pineapples and
people are looking at me like what is
that I believe it I also grew a clone in
my little side Garden uh from Caleb uh I
he he gave his brother a bunch of uh
selections from Girl Scout cookies runs
T1000 okay and so I I kind of I looked
at some of the plants he had flowered
out and I and I and I picked the one I
like the most um and I grew those out
and uh you know just kind of
like it's kind of like what the market
seems to want or what they think they
want just like per purple Frosty weed uh
DSE um not really my I been wanting to
ask you one thing little Hill like on
the T1000 like do you see it as a kind
of um cookies alternate or something a
way no I see it more as an Urkle
alternate yeah yeah that makes sense
yeah it because it is a URL leaning
phenotype of the
Cross and so it's got some of it's like
heavily
like favors the Urkel flavor and and it
is a little squat um compared to some of
the other phenotypes you get out of that
c
cross um but it's just it just got added
potency um added added Vigor from a
triangle Kush um yeah and uh so yeah so
what else did I grow the dog Waltz
s1s um I had three of those from some
really old seed yeah um that that was
fun it was I only got three to pop out
of 30 it was it was really really old
seed 15 years old give or take um but
uh one of them was pretty bland the
other two had that smell one of them was
green the other one was purple it was
funny to see that variation I I kept
cuts of both of the ones I
liked um what else did I grow this year
oh I grew s for the first
time I was G to say before you go into
the sour um I just want to add that I
don't know if I'm allowed to leak this
but there may
be uh that that
um the poodle nuts cut um has been found
maybe I can say that I don't know I'm G
to note that and just in case until it
hasn't been I don't think we've gotten
it yet from the person who said they had
it no though it's supposed to be on the
way but it's been a minute we'll see
what happens uh I know how it goes
everybody gets busy so we will we'll see
if it actually if we can actually get
our hands on it and if it's actually the
real one um I would love I it's my
favorite weed all time so I'm I'm really
looking forward to getting my hands back
on it and and introducing it to sort of
this modern Market um it's it's a
stinker it has a great high and uh it's
it's just my favorite weed um
so yeah those s1s uh were fun fun to
smoke again um it's funny how and I
think this is this is a good segue into
sour diesels I I grew Sour Diesel for
the first time in a long time and I grew
a lot of it back in the day because
there was strong still is strong demand
for it but um it's funny how like your
memory things are always better in your
memory um than than than what they what
they really were so I feel like that's
going on right now with sour diesel
where whether you have the the real cut
or not I feel like there's a lot of cuts
that are so similar they're tough to
tell
apart
um the sour diesel I grew is exactly
what I remember so so there's that but
the the purple Kim dog or or or the the
dog Waltz um sometimes I call it purple
Kim dog um the poodle nuts it's got a
lot of names uh I like I was smelling
these these two fenos I got and I was
like man is this it it's not as gassy as
I remember the grapes there but is the
gas there you know is the flavor there
doesn't really burn my nostrils and I
remember it burning my nostrils or is
this just in my head that it'll never be
as good as my memories of it just
because I've I've built up this these
thoughts in my head about how great it
was because it's my favorite of all time
and I think a little bit that of that's
going on with Sour Diesel and
everybody's saying like this isn't the
same one it's not as this it's not like
that and I'm
like well you know a lot of people don't
want to admit that like maybe you're
holding it on a pedestal in your mind
and it it's never gonna it's you're
never going to be able to find the right
one or grow it to what you thought it
was in your mind right and yeah all they
know they could have had it and it
thinking it wasn't and then exactly and
then add on like everybody's growing
under LEDs now everything's different
about how we grow and and in CO2 and so
it's like they're not being grown in
these like I mean Grow rooms in 2005
were were so like Stone aged compared to
where they're at now yeah you know with
high press sodium and carbon filters and
most people weren't running CO2 and and
and and who knows what temperature and
humidity fluctuations you were having at
night and right you know nobody was as
dialed in as they are now so I don't I
don't know like all those little things
affect the plant so dramatically um on
how it expresses itself especially Sour
Diesel you know um so I don't know just
just my thoughts on that um so that's
yeah that's that's that's about that's
about where I'm at with with what I like
from last
year it's funny you mention that with
sour d because cuz um I think it it also
kind of lends Credence into volatile TPS
um I grew a Kim 991 S1 and uh a snitch
free sour d last year that both
exhibited the volatile chem strong
traits that you get on the nose but the
resin um after harvest and after sitting
in their jars they they morphed quite a
bit and that that um you know that Sour
Diesel that um used to smelling or that
that chem dog that I'm used to smelling
it it like you said it changes or my
perception of it has changed a little
bit um it's it's not it's not exactly
what I thought it was every you know now
that I've I've gotten a chance to to
throw it in the
garden yeah yeah it's uh I don't
everything everything makes a difference
you're Cur you're curing process
you're I mean yeah it's it it is a
finicky plant and those things are
volatile and and everything makes a
difference and also a lot of us were
probably growing at smaller scale 20
years ago or 15 years ago than we are
now or or vice versa and like all those
things just make a difference regardless
of whether you think they are or not
it's just every little thing is
different
now peaches you you and buck also have a
sour correct maybe not a bad segue for
for you yeah we did uh four of them
outside this year um just in 10 gallon
pots on the back of the Hill cuz all the
big pots were filled but uh she did
really good outside she was a heavy
feeder um definite heavy feeder I could
give her as much in her T gallon as the
45s were getting and uh it kept her
happy wow um so but she did good and
honestly it's it was it's one of my
favorite smokes right now um when it
finally got dried and cured
uh it tasted just like it used to taste
back in the day like I remember getting
it from up in the bay in like
2000 and uh it was one of the first weed
I ever tried that actually tasted good
like it it coated your mouth I never
forgot that weed and um to smoke it
again it it's it's there that's what it
is like the chps are there um and it was
it was a good plant I'm really happy
with it I'm planning on putting it back
out next year um a few more of them a
little
bigger um but I was happy with it it did
good and then um so it was one of my
favorites uh she went the sour went 11
weeks um all the way into
November um but luckily she was smaller
and no mold no nothing like she was a
champ they got rained on um and
everything and no mold she purpled up
really good was a beautiful fall
colors yeah she uh she was always mold
resistant at my place she could get
rained on quite a bit and hold up yep
she got ran on I want to say like three
or four times and then you know towards
the end letting her finish up she was
getting the de in the mornings and I was
a little worried but nothing no powdery
mildew no btis just a real champ of a
plant yeah big flowers but
flowers definitely allow air
flow yeah and then I squashed some of
the flower uh just recently into flower
rosin and um I haven't got to smoke it
yet but man was it it was so turpy it
wouldn't come off the paper it was so
oily it was one of those types that you
know that just so gassy smelling and
stuff that it just that that rosin's not
going to set
up how was the yield on
it um I honestly I haven't waited yet to
see what it yielded I literally pressed
it on the last day and threw it in the
freezer and came home with it and it's
still in the freezer so it was it always
did really well for for yield and
quality on the bubble hash this was this
was before rosin was even a thing but uh
yeah it was always the first stuff we
washed and it was the main stuff we
wanted for bubble hash because it it it
just quantity and quality is always
topnotch on it oh see you should have
never told me that cuz now I'm going to
put more out on the hill next year
a as as long as you got the climate for
them to finish they they really do like
that post Halloween finish yeah as long
as you got that climate I say go for
it sometimes we do sometimes we don't
you know it just it all depends um this
year was a good year though it it rained
a little bit but nothing major um so it
wasn't too bad cuz we don't have a
greenhouse so everything's just out
there so it's got to stand up to what
Mother Nature brings to
it
cool other than the uh sour d what what
else in the garden did you grow last
year that really stood out to you uh the
Barbara Bud by uh House of the great
Gardener um I've been searching for
peach church now for like five years and
uh it's the first one that had Peach
chirps um several different fenos had it
in it but there was one that she had it
from start to finish and then um I just
made flow rosin with her and it tastes
like peaches huh like artificial or like
candy no like a peach cup you know like
the little Peach cups you used to get as
a kid right and it's like sweet peach
smelling wow it smells like that huh
that's interesting I've never
encountered that before it's the first
time I've ever smelled peach in a strain
like and then I I only had one feno I
kept because she smelled all the way
through the other ones kind of changed
but uh I saved the two that changed and
I did fresh Frozen with them and when I
washed them and squashed them that live
rosin when you Stir It Up it smells like
peaches wow and they weren't even the
feno
kept so yeah she's she's got those TPS
in there and she was another one she did
great in the rain no mold um now I had I
only had five feminized seeds that I had
put out and every one was a different
pheno and one of those fenos didn't grow
past 2 feet tall was a mad bush like she
reminded me of how Bubba used to grow um
or like the banana cush or LA
Confidential just not tall totally all
Leaf horrible to prune um that feno I
would never keep and then there was
another one that was a sativa feno that
got you know 9 ft tall had open buds
that one I washed um along with another
one that was similar to that one but my
keeper feno had the nice thick dense
buds it had good coverage Sandy tric
Combs and that peach smell so um I'm
going to do her again next year CU I was
so
impressed um and then I have to say my
one other standout on the hill that um I
wasn't too happy with the tur profiles
cuz I got a lot of Mandarin cookie
leaning ones was the peach
Crescendo um cuz she's got some Frost
like you go to trim her up and you're
what an eighth in and you've already got
to clean your scissors yeah yeah so and
then a couple times I've smoked her in
the last few days and I've caught a
little hint of peach like a fresh peach
but then it kind of changes almost into
like a banana and then it kind of
changes from there so and there's some
potential in that one but those were
probably the ones I was the most
happiest
with yeah whenever I'm trimming and I'm
I like you said your scissors get gunked
up way too fast my mind always who I
wonder how this would wash you know I'm
always always thinking about the
concentrates on that strain
yep um
exactly something else I I wanted to
talk about before I uh before I go on a
couple other strains that I grew last
year um the papaya little Hill that you
grew did do you see any pink pistols uh
when you grew it
Outdoors no I didn't um I don't know if
the originala did that or not but uh
um this cross none of that know a lot of
the modern people are talking about the
pink pistols in it oh wow no I didn't I
I didn't see anything remotely close
most of the pink pistol stuff is either
camera OG lineage yeah or uh there there
is some other stuff my buddy down in
Hopland used to have uh some guava Kush
that he made that had some God Bud from
Hawaii in it and there were phenotypes
that would push out those hot pink
pistols but that's interesting yeah
that's that's that's about it as far as
I've seen from that okay yeah both the
chem 91 and the sweet 16 chem 91s pushed
Pink Pistols this
year they they stayed pretty true to
that yeah there was a Kim 91 or Kim D
not 91
sorry yeah it was sweet 16 to Kim D not
Kim 91 that sounds
interesting very chemically very salty
but also still like still mostly
overpowered by that fermenting wine
fermenting fruit
smell um something else I wanted to talk
about was the Appalachia crosses from
high and Lonesome um I got to try a
plethora of them between my garden and
my two my best friend and my brother's
Garden um I popped a bunch of Appalachia
stuff kept a kept three or four for
myself and gave them three or four each
to to grow out and what I was really
Blown Away with was the Appalachia old
Betsy um I mean it was like a dead
ringer for old piny
Afghanistan just cushy old gen genetics
you know bright green dense buds with
with fire red orange hairs it was it was
uh it was like being transported back to
the early 2000s when I was you know
first first messing around with buying
weed and and before I started growing in
like 2007 2008 and the before that I was
picking up stuff that reminded me of
that like uh it it was I was really
impressed with what the Appalachia did
Outdoors across all the Hybrids really
big really vigorous really healthy
plants and um that funky Orange orang
there's this mango Funk that
accommodates all of them and it was uh
it was most it shown through mostly in
the shore in the shoreline Appalachia
the shoreline Appalachia started off
smelling like um just orange and vanilla
or like those candied orange slices and
then after harvest and after it spent
some time in the jar it's just
skunky volatile smells that are dominate
acrid acrid would be a great way to to
describe how uh how funky the skunk
smell is coming out of the shoreline
Appalachia and then um another one that
I was really impressed by in the
Appalachia line was the Appalachia to
the loomus headband it was um some of
the best lemon turps that I've had in
recent memories um not the strongest
lemon turps like lemon party still holds
the crown for me for lemon turps but it
it was just
a a really good blend of cushy Full
Assault um instant onset heavy
medication with a with a nice like lemon
drop flavor in it I was really impressed
with the Appalachia loomus headband um
my my brother got a chance to grow that
one and I didn't and I liked it so much
that I'm absolutely G to try it um I'm
probably going to try two or three plans
of it next year it was it was it was
really impressive to me
and then um what else did I grow last
year that I really like um yeah the the
atw hybrids um the Arcada train wreck
hybrids from pack some of the most
unique takes I've ever smelled on um Tor
pentalene like I got to grow a cat five
and a Mojo rizon my brother grew a cat
five and a Mojo rizon and then my best
friend grew Mojo 5 in a crosses people
know those are dosidos the category five
is dosidos slurricane to Artic Arcada
train wreck and then the Mojo rizon is
blue garlic to Arcada train wreck um and
the category fives were like mixed berry
on top of trolene um kind of like a
mixed berry Crunch and still dominated
by the by the tealing but hints of berry
mixed in there and then the Mojo RIS
were um super unique uh definitely
tentene but more of a menthol I called
it blueberry Menthol when I would rub
the the stock or the stems I'd get like
a blueberry Menthol turpentine but
there's also this background layer of
mushroom compost um I smelled it in the
blue garlics at the party when I first
smelled it I was like whoa It's like
composting mushroom and then as I grew
the Mojo rizons that blue G
mushroom Funk came through and it was it
was very prevalent across the all three
plants in three different Gardens do we
know what's in the blue garlic um I
believe the blue garlic
is um I'm not sure right off the top of
my head honestly I think
it's I feel like there's a
GMO I think it's GMO to the blue cookies
but I could be wrong I I think it's yeah
I think it's blue cookies to
GMO look it up really
quick um yeah Circle to yeah yeah look
it up when we get chatting about
something else um yeah so so the stuff
from pack from from goat farm I was I
really liked those atw hybrids it made
me want to do the blue dream atw knowing
the knowing what's there
potential oh yeah what are you I'm
already
seeing uh they're not far they're
probably about 20 days in um but okay
the balance of to pinolene and blueberry
is quite uh already quite apparent I
mean obviously it's going to change over
over the firing uh period but already I
can kind of see like the different
balances that each individual's you know
um showing me which is really cool I've
never I'll be honest this whole time you
know I know that the Syndicate crew
generally are big fans of tending but
this is maybe the first time I've
actually confirmed myself what
terpinolene actually is because it's so
obvious you know with these that I'm
like okay I know what I know what that
is I know what that is now cool right
right I bet those have a potential to be
huge yielders um yes train R crosses do
do great
um it just train wreck is good in itself
but it needs a boost from something else
usually a squat indicia but a blue dream
is also a commercial yielder um yeah
dude like you have potential for for
having really really good weight on
those the Vigor on these uh was alarming
to me as someone who grows in like these
basically micr spaces this has been
probably the most challenging um line
yeah Blue Dream is a is a real narrow
leaf and it's going to stretch and and
train wreck is like this weird mix of
you know equatorial genetics and indicia
genetics where it also has a stretch but
it has like a very odd Leaf shape so it
might look like an Inda or or pretend to
be one for a while and then it hits its
stride and and just start stretching and
and uh I can tell you that oh sorry you
go you finished oh I was just going to
say the the stems on train wreck will
stretch a lot and they won't break they
they're very
rubbery yeah they'll Bend they will bend
all the way over back onto the ground
and not break I'll say that I can
definitely uh at least you know
anecdotally corroborate what you're
saying like the the train wreck leaners
are giving me trouble because they want
to spay out you know they just want to
flop over and take over like all the
horizontal space and then the Blue Dream
leaners just want to go straight up so
having to do like very different
constraints for both of them that's
exactly what I would expect
yeah cool yeah those late season train
wreck plants tying them up and they're
just all floppy all over the place no
matter what the weight the weight on
those thin branches is insane for train
wreck all right that's where I think it
gets its name from is because it looks
like a train if you don't support it
properly it's just this this whole Maze
of branches just flopped over laying on
the
ground um I think that's where it gets
its name honestly and and and I I mean
I've seen it in my own garden of of
plants just completely falling over and
pulling bamboo staks out of the ground
falling like towards the South where the
weight is and I just take those bamboo
staks pull them back and the whole plant
just pops right back up and not a single
broken Branch it's just it's just what
it what it does right um I
I wanted to ask little Hill about um his
Phoenix um stuff and how how he how how
he thought it went oh I know that's like
T1000 adjacent but you know right uh
Phoenix is a T1000 to to back to
Triangle so it's a triangle back cross I
selected this pheno four years ago I
think or five five seasons ago um 2019
and just I've kind of had it on the back
burner just growing it a little bit here
in there but I really rolled out with it
this year and I I knew the quality was
there I I I knew I like the smoke I knew
it was going to do okay um what actually
added bonus it yielded really really
well in the outdoor beds so so that was
cool and I'm
definitely gonna roll out with it again
next year and grow more of it
um I passed it to a few other people
including uh csi's brother in Trinity
and uh it's been good enough to stick in
their Gardens and and and and take up
you know some real estate in their
Gardens as well um so I've I've been
I've been absolutely ha so happy with it
as far as just like the quality of the
smoke and the flavor I I wanted to get
as well as the
potency and then on the the test results
I've gotten back have both been I think
I've gotten three test results back and
they've all been through the roof uh
high turpine levels over one of them was
over 3%
Tarpin which is really good
um uh and then just the added bonus was
the yield I didn't expect it to do quite
as well as it did but but it did and and
so that's you know I'm a commercial
cultivator but like I selected this
based off of vigor not yield it it it
had all the properties I wanted as far
as flavor and structure and
then if you vigor was a big part of that
um if you grow a big enough population I
grew 111 females out to pick this one
and it was unique out of all of them
sheesh if you you can really see a
difference in Vigor Vigor from seed um I
mean all seed has its Vigor for the you
know for the most part but there's these
sports that stand out that just you
can't hold them back from growing and
they outgrow their sisters and and this
was in that group of maybe the top 10 %
uh vigorous plants which was just also
again an added bonus to I'm selecting
for quality of flower for the most part
um and just to have it be in that top 10
Perc I think that's really what makes a
commercially viable cut blue dreams in
that same category where it just you
can't hold it back from growing it's G
to grow and that's that's that's part of
what makes it such a good commercial cut
um so just to have that added bonus like
it's going to be a quarter in my out
outdoor Garden next year um and I'll
probably grow it in some green houses as
well Phoenix is an awesome name for a
backat cross train like
that yeah yeah I called it because it it
survived was the only mother I kept
through the fire in 2020 and I kind of
just like all right it needed a name we
were calling it back to the triangle for
a while and I really like that name but
but I I don't know I just I just felt
like Phoenix was was what we should
could the whole the cross should be
called back to the triangle I don't
think I don't think Caleb ever named the
back cross but um it's a good it's just
a good it's a good name I gotta giggle
out of it yeah like back to the triangle
too that one's got to get used yeah all
right everyone that's the end of the
episode um again I'd like to thank uh CH
the Giants little Hill and peaches for
showing up and hanging out and thousand
for running it
um don't forget we have the new sub Rob
drop coming out with some skunk dog S1
cross to sour dub as well as the 98
Super Silver Haze cut that people call
the cup winning Shanti cut which we
don't really know but we know it's a
great cut of super silver haze cross to
sour dub F that's going to be on the
right site um we're going to be doing
another drop of Blue Dream soon with
goat farm brand new releases we haven't
done yet with it or shown um they've
been done we just haven't shown them and
they've been run um also keep your ear
and eyes pilled for the TGA work
because as odd as it is to hear me
announcing any new TGA stuff it's
happening um space dude met a lot of
other things that he probably should
have met back in the day in in my
opinion and other people's opinions so
I'm really stoked about that I'm
I'm it's it's conflicting because it's
TGA you know but I uh we love Miss Jill
always love Miss Jill and uh man I'm
really stoked about it I I believe s had
a legacy with some cool stuff um he made
his name doing cool stuff and regardless
of how our relationship was I think that
no matter what I can put my biases aside
with that to make sure that Legacy
survives with extra cool [__] still
around you know with something he
brought to the table really well in
selecting the space dud um with that
said we have seeds that Girt by seeds in
Australia we have right Co Europe we
have lifted seeds in the US who can also
take Card directly and soon maybe maybe
maybe South America and Brazil um we'll
see how it pans out I think it's going
well so if it does I'll definitely keep
you guys posted in the future and yeah
with that I'll probably see you guys in
a few weeks um until then stay nice to
each other as nice as you can be or only
be mean to the ones who deserve it
peace want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
my G and it's an amazing resource for
old cataloges and knowledge we hope you
join our Union of readers and Growers
come check it
out