welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
you'll notice with a lot of our
interviews it kind of just jumps into a
conversation and this will be no
different and the ending will probably
be no different as well so
um apologies in advance a lot of our
conversations are all over the place
it's a bunch of us with ADHD so uh yeah
just wanted to put that in there cheers
okay welcome to breeder Syndicate
everyone I'm Matthew I'm here with my
friend Shawnee kids and not so dog and
we are here with New York Pete
um was the I guess you would say owner
Runner of compassion clubs in the um in
the 90s in Canada correct yeah and we're
still going so I I started the uh
originally it was called the London
Compassion Club uh back in 95.
um and then
um we went public in with Allen Rock so
that would have been like
97 or so and that's um that's when I uh
split off from hemp nation and did the
organic traveler which was my retail but
they call me NYPD just because my name
is
Petey Pete and I'm from New York kind of
thing so that's uh they don't call me
New York Pete but they call me NYPD NYPD
yeah I'm always scared to lead with that
because I remember when the first time I
heard I was like NYPD yeah
a whole bunch of [ __ ] NYPD uh
paraphernalia like the shirt and the hat
and all that yeah but where we're from
you know it's like everyone had a
nickname like my name is Johnny kids
like Pete has only really known me as
Shawnee kids going back to the 90s right
yeah that's funny yeah yeah and all of
our friends had nicknames everyone had a
nickname you kind of had to in this
industry though right sure back in the
day I didn't want to say hey [ __ ]
Sean [ __ ] you know or Chris Clay or
[ __ ] anybody's real name
you're the king of shortening words too
oh I [ __ ] mixed up everybody and I
and there's evolutions of people's
nicknamese I know has a [ __ ] nickname
and if something like bomb boy worked
for me for years no idea what his
[ __ ] real name was
I'll admit that on my birth certificate
it does not say not so dog yeah
[Music]
um but it's like it's the same thing
it's tour names it's it's it's a
different nickname it's a different way
you know
in a semi-shady you know quasi what you
know anywhere from completely illegal to
quasi-legal to to gray area to maybe you
know yeah and I always said you know we
have uh we I've always lived in the gray
area of the world and sometimes it's
really dark gray and sometimes it's
really light gray right like you know
I've uh I've had a deal in the black
market because I needed to to suffice or
to satisfy the need of the medical
community that I was part of and I
couldn't grow enough for everybody so
um and that's really really why I
started growing pot I started growing
pot you know one not to sell it I just
wanted to save money and when I started
organic traveler uh in a you know
University Town I had the uh grow your
tuition Campaign which was uh I would
sell you seeds and give you information
sell your grow guides come back come in
on any Sunday and we would have grow
chats and
um
walk you through how to do cuttings or
start seeds or or stuff like that
um because money in your pocket whether
you save it or make it it's still money
in your pocket right yeah no don't get
into this industry and I [ __ ]
honestly you know I I won't work with
anybody
back in the day especially when cannabis
was illegal if your sole income was
strictly on growing pot
good on you you you're not going to be
in my circle because I think you know if
you're doing that's kind of prostituting
the uh the plant and I've always been a
good big advocate
about you know not prostituting this
plant like use it for what it's meant
for right like it was put forth for us
to enjoy not to you know uh pasteurize
and and prostitute kind of thing so I've
made my entire living off of cannabis
yes but I also had organic traveler
which was a head shop that was legal if
I got busted which I have and end up in
jail which I have and they take
everything that I own which they did
my rent was still paid and there was
still food on my table so before I had
hem Nation or sorry organic traveler or
before him Nation well ham Nation I was
uh delivering meat I'm a vegetarian I
was [ __ ] delivering meat every
morning from nine or eight in the
morning till four in the afternoon come
home to my garden and that was my gravy
my [ __ ] shitty [ __ ] day job put
food on my table paid my rent and then
all the gravy in life my two thousand
dollar
um bike hanging on the wall my trips to
[ __ ] Amsterdam or California or
wherever the [ __ ] I want to go that was
great that was all from the Cannabis I
was you know and it's not from being you
know a dick about it I was uh I grew pot
I would have a harvest party and I'd
bring all the staff in from uh hemp
nation and I'd be like what do you guys
want right I'm gonna I'm honest with you
I'm charging you double what I charge
Medical
so I can sell it cheaper to the Met for
people that need it over the people that
want it yeah and uh and you tell me what
you want you don't have to pay for it
you will pay for it in time but if you
want two ounces or three ounces or QP
that's fine you I'm gonna take the pie
I'm gonna put in one of those containers
I'm gonna stick it in my deep freezer
and you come to me when you want a
quarter ounce
50 bucks bring it you know but that pot
is there it's for you I'm not selling it
to anybody else right that could be a
generational thing too because like when
I I felt like where I you know where I
grew up at least it was really important
to have some kind of
um verifiable income yeah right because
you had to have some reason of existing
you had to have some way to make it you
didn't want to go to court and they're
like how do you support yourself and
you're like uh right and you know it
comes from an era where like you it had
to be a side gig because you know you
needed even if it was just a even if it
was just a front like you said like you
had no like organic traveler was all a
front like I mean I [ __ ] never made
money do at organic travel I lost it
when it got to a point of losing about
40 Grand a year I said okay we're
pulling the plug and now by that time
you know I was doing the compassion
Society for
like 20 years
the cops knew what I was doing you know
and then you know in Diva came into play
and Diva came in into play
as I was close and organic like I I same
thing CRA I had to read
and you you kind of need to have
um a reason for like you said what
people see but for me it's for what I
see and what I know
and I I cut ties with some really
[ __ ] great Growers and uh and I cut
ties with people that were just [ __ ]
[ __ ] you know and it was just
um their focus was money money money and
when you chase it
you know you're opening yourself up to
the you are more vulnerable to be taken
advantage of or get busted or you know
get Shady deal with Shady people [ __ ]
like that I've been pretty lucky I mean
what I've been in this industry
um [ __ ] long time 30 how old am I 30 40.
40 almost about 35 years you know that I
put my name out there and said hey I'm a
[ __ ] pot guy kind of thing yeah and
London London is a pretty conservative
place like it was completely different
than like that's why most people went to
BC because everybody left BC and that's
why I say like they'd be like oh BC
grows the best part of course they do
they're from Ontario like [ __ ] you know
like I went out to BC I lived out there
and I didn't meet anybody from [ __ ]
BC kind of thing right I've been out
there on grow contracts but you know it
was um
what we have here I mean it seems like
it it kind of
I think the marijuana movement started
around here and we are in a very uh
conservative uh town and back when I
started we had a very conservative uh
religious mayor and uh you know I wanted
to make a point I put up big banners
that said the Lord believes in marijuana
do you believe in the Lord you know and
it was not something that she took
kindly but would not you know
um
make us think about it because she would
be giving me AirPlay but yeah more clock
in the morning the [ __ ] Paddy Wagon
showed up and took down my [ __ ]
Banner
you know and that's the thing like
you've been doing this a long time and
and all of that but like the one thing
you've been doing also is like fighting
the law openly right like since what
since 93 you've been constantly more
like I think is when the Constitutional
challenge yeah yeah
like I still talk with Alan Young uh on
a regular basis right like he's uh that
poor man's been beat the [ __ ] up in this
[ __ ] industry too who is he uh Alan
Young is the uh I say the Cannabis
lawyer in Canada so
um
um and so he's the one that handled uh
Chris's case uh his partner Paul
Bernstein he handled like Ross roll a
big doobie whatever the [ __ ] his name is
if you go to the West Coast you have
John Conroy when you hear constitutional
lawyers uh you're dealing with Alan
Young
do you want to explain the the whole uh
Chris Clay arrest
uh sure yeah so uh I was part of NPC but
in the shadows uh luckily so the first
time he got raided
um
yeah it was uh yeah so with with Chris
very educated well read polite kid who
didn't start smoking pot till just a few
years prior
um read the law and the law
the way that the law was read is it
wasn't cannabis that was illegal it was
THC yeah so THC is not in the seeds
that's correct we started selling seeds
and that's how I met him because I was
going back and forth from New York to
Saint Thomas or London because I was in
college and I was bringing seeds back
and forth Just trading for genetics for
genetics yeah
and so I was helping him with the the
little uh Great Canadian Emporium seed
[ __ ] company and then he realized
well cuttings don't have [ __ ] THC in
them either so he took out a [ __ ]
full page ad in the uh see I think we've
seen magazine that said uh overgrow your
government and I I'm pretty sure that
Chris well it would have been Andrew who
was the artist coined that phrase the
overgrow overgrow your government right
that's overgrow the government and it
was like it was literally a cartoon of a
seed marching with a helmet on with the
hemp Nation flag on it holding a bong at
like it's a gun and you know and we said
we're gonna sell 30 skunk one cuttings
for 30 bucks or 25 for 25 bucks or
something like that and um I think by
the seventh cutting or something along
that line uh Jordan who's the
little person I think is a proper name
Howard the Duck yeah he was Howard oh
that guy okay you're talking about yeah
so he uh I just reconnected with him too
he's back in Toronto and um so they read
he was the one that actually sold the
cutting to an undercover cop
they must have brought or the duck sold
the cutting to an undercover cop yeah
yeah that's why he was arrested right so
Prince was arrested because he was the
owner with his name on the lease yeah
and uh Jordan got arrested because he
was the actual one that did the um the
sale
and um
and uh they must have bought the cutting
and then brought it down because they
didn't buy it and then bust them they
bought it and then came back a little
bit later I mean Chris would be the
better about this I mean I was smoking a
lot of pot back then Chris was spoken up
yeah dreadlock actually back then too
and um they all did Jordan had Jordan
was like a little person but he had
dreads down to his ass he had like a lip
piercing you know he was yeah he was uh
he was uh that still trips me out Howard
the Duck bro he was only Howard for like
a very split yes they tried to remove a
lot of it because he was underage I
watched the documentary on it the other
day on the making of Howard the Duck it
was probably awesome yeah did they don't
mention him do they yeah oh yeah yeah
they talked about how like they had
hired him and he was a little kid and
yeah like they initially shot a bunch of
it with him but the movements from the
dummy they had to move it remove them
yeah yeah and but he's in hell if it was
him or not because as you know if you
can you actually email me that uh oh
yeah yeah definitely kind of it's way
worth watching he was in something
modern too with like Colin Farrell yeah
I'm Irish oh and Bruce is a great movie
I didn't know his name yeah that's him
that's Jordan French yeah and I I hate
to say but I and I joke with him too I
was like listen you know what you kind
of all look alike kind of thing because
there's so many people that times I'm
like [ __ ] I'm pretty sure that's Jordan
like I don't know if it's not I have to
go look at the [ __ ] credits they say
oh it's not him you know you know it's
just um
and then Prozac back in the day uh which
was another one of the kind of
um I wouldn't call him a Klingon because
he was part of the he was hemp Nation
family right like and uh you know
obviously Pete rocks was and Pete Miller
and [ __ ]
um
uh there's all and there's a whole bunch
of a whole bunch of us but anyways
getting back to the bus
they they must have took the plant out
brought it they couldn't have analyzed
it they just maybe confirmed that it was
Cannabis and came back later that uh
afternoon and raided the place yeah we
didn't take any of the seeds didn't say
anything about the seeds busted them for
uh paraphernalia paraphernalia to 262.2
yeah and the um and for the uh
distribution
of uh controlled substance or back to
econ it would be called something
different back then I don't know if it
was a PPT like the uh possession for the
purpose but um anyways they you know
cleared out the store [ __ ] made a
mess of it basically tried to shut them
down and
um maybe they didn't realize Chris had
really supportive parents that had money
and believed their son not to be a
[ __ ] criminal like he was treated and
um
and
the Elmwood house we had a grow house on
Elmwood that everybody lived in except
for me because I actually I was
delivering meat at the time and
um
and you know they went there that's
where they busted Prozac and uh his
girlfriend at the time
and uh that was [ __ ] a [ __ ] show of
craziness because as soon as the cops
busted us the phone calls started going
everybody that it was at the house was
literally like running to the basement
grabbing pots running out the backyard
throwing them Over The Back Fence into
an empty lot so by the time the police
got there there was literally a trail of
dirt up the stairs through the kitchen
out the back door and dirt still on the
top of the fence I bet yeah throwing it
over and they were just like they were
like yeah not on the property not our
problems you know so um so that that was
the first bust
and then since they didn't say anything
about the the seeds Chris and Chris and
I Chris and I got a little bit more
serious about it and started to um
um
get a little bit more into the breeding
buying like you say showing those some
of these early uh scent to see packs and
stuff like that anybody that was going
over there mail us seeds right when did
we start buying seeds like you did you
tell me that you were the first in in
Canada so I think I think Chris was the
first
uh Seed Company in Canada because I
didn't know of anybody else that was
publicly
selling seeds right uh way before dark
enemy uh Mar uh Mike up north
yeah Mark Henry sorry Dark Energy same
thing dark enemy yeah he yeah they
removed the whole chapter from my book
because I was so scared that he was
gonna sue me yeah he was kind of thing
but he's a [ __ ] douchebag
um and then
um
Mike up north at Crosstown he was early
in it
um I don't think Dom ever no Dom never
got into the seat thing
um out west there was nobody really
out west that we knew of
uh NPC wasn't even around at this point
in time so as far as I knew
yeah Chris Chris was the first one to
stick his [ __ ] Little Neck out there
to um
to to spread the word right like to
overgrow the government so you know and
when they busted him the first time
they uh
they didn't do anything about the seeds
so we figured [ __ ] you know we we know
where the limits are so [ __ ] yeah the
ball to the wall let's get into the seed
[ __ ] business Let's Start Spreading
the seeds [ __ ] everywhere you know
and we started that's when I was hired
to work in the store
um and every Sunday I would do
um cultivation uh counseling whatever
the [ __ ] they wanted to call it with
NYPD yeah and uh and um
it was a uh
it was the point that you know we
started getting noticed and we would
start getting people traveling to us and
then Chris
got on the internet and everything back
then was raw code and started producing
the uh seed menu online
yeah and it was [ __ ] it we were getting
more hits at one point if I remember
correctly he said we were getting more
hits than University of Western Ontario
that's funny I believe it right because
we had so many [ __ ] people that just
heard what you can buy cannabis seeds
and then you know because we were in the
newspaper sure they're gonna put that in
it so it gives us credibility of who we
are and what we're doing yep and then uh
when they came back the second time they
offered Chris a uh
a
a way out an option is yeah to to
um plead guilty to lesser charges and
drop the Constitutional Challenge and
um and basically sell the seed sell the
pipes sell the bongs we don't care about
that you know and Chris came to us and
said it's up to you guys that I mean
we're we're a nation at this point in
time we were true we were treating
ourselves as a nation so we we had
Minister as minister of Agriculture and
then we had a minister of Labor which
was Bill that took care of all the
retail store and all the um uh all the
staff and then we had minister of uh
education which was Sarah and she took
care of the library and the museum and
uh and stuff like that and Andrew was
the Minister of Defense he was our
artist but he was the angriest
he was he just had he was he's a
brilliant he's a school teacher Iran
which scares to share with me now and
his wife owns from Mars which is another
Staple in this town and um
you know so we were set up as a nation
kind of thing we were ready like they
call it as War on Drugs we were going to
take it as a War on Drugs so we formed
our nation and we were ready and uh and
this is like with our early 20s kids
right like you're all like in your early
20s this was in the 90s still this would
be late 90s okay yeah so we were uh
um
yeah it would have been like mid 90s
actually second time yeah because I
opened up organic in 97.
and um
and we were all and Chris was already
banished from Ontario by that time
and the thing was is after the first
raid
like I said we went balls of all to the
with the seed and the seed uh business
and that's when we started again if
you're going through Amsterdam sell it
send a seed so I can breed them and I
was doing what um what the [ __ ] a big
douchebag and uh Amsterdam are you on no
no he's he's a nice douchebag okay
douchebag uh so many no yeah but he's
the this is the most famous he
threatened to sue us as Legends for when
we were entering the cup with the uh he
thought
Neville fast no no no that never was
always uh good people but we were using
Neville seeds yeah
hey Hank oh yeah so
Hank is the type of [ __ ] guy that
started doing what we were doing but but
being a dick about it I would I would
openly say Hey listen we got in 20 seeds
of skunk one from uh from the dronkers
and
I'm open breeding those and in the same
room we had an original Haze we had a
black dominant we had all these other
strains so they're f1s this is what
you're gonna get when there's no
guarantees here but
you got your grown pot you know now
you're officially a pot grower and uh
they're they're good genetics they're
not you know from where I started my
genetic uh selection was from bags of
weed yeah you'd get [ __ ] and New York
we're not getting the [ __ ] best weed
we're getting [ __ ] Jamaican brick
like when I first started
we were buying nickel bags in East
Rockaway on B15 which I think is
actually in a Beastie Boys song but um
for five bucks for a nickel bag and 10
bucks for a dime bag and we would get
you know a third of it with seed it was
back when it was after people were
saying uh buying it by the lid right
there's like four fingers in a [ __ ]
in a sandwich bag yeah but we were
basically going and buying nickel bags
for
five bucks and you would get
a shitload of seeds in it and if it was
good pot
I would save the seeds right and I
didn't know what the [ __ ] it was I
didn't know what sativa was or indica
was I mean it's all [ __ ] Jamaican
[ __ ] [ __ ] weed or Colombian or or
whatever so when we got certain things
and people like oh it's gold
okay well I'm Gonna Keep the [ __ ]
seeds because I've heard that back in
the high reading in High Times magazines
so I started collecting those genetics
and I would bring them up to Canada and
I would trade with uh with Chris right
and he would have his seeds from here
London is a [ __ ]
phenomenal place for cannabis for
multiple reasons one because we did have
the Perth County conspiracy that was a
lot of the draft Dodgers that came to
Canada
um
didn't want to go too far north and
we're right between Buffalo and Detroit
and if you look at the uh Geographic we
are surrounded by great lakes so we are
a glacial runoff that all the minerals
and everything got deposited so our soil
here that's why we're such a large
farming Community our soil is [ __ ]
awesome was awesome
right so since we were getting all that
uh and we're all grown pot in the fields
in the [ __ ] uh in the corn you know
we were growing some great [ __ ] pot
and if you got seeds in it which you
would inevitably uh get something I was
happy as [ __ ] [ __ ] people like pissed
off like oh man it's got season I was
like [ __ ] give me this no that's a
score bro
you smell the pot is it worth keeping
you know yeah give me some descriptions
grow it out see see if I could grow it
indoors you know
um if it came from around here I knew I
can grow it most likely Grow It Outdoors
because there wasn't very many people
growing back then if they were they were
using phototrons and uh yeah fluorescent
lightings and [ __ ] like that
the hid Community really wasn't taking
off uh it was in the
90s
in the early 90s I was having some
local kids go and steal [ __ ] lights
from in front of buildings yeah because
there were street lights or something
there were metal halides and HPS and
they were either 400s most likely all
400 there wasn't too many thousand Watts
back then yeah I think 250s and 400s yes
we were trying to
um
we were growing pot like I said we were
[ __ ] cockroach we didn't know what we
were growing how we were growing it but
[ __ ] man it's it's a weed they call it
weed for a reason the more you do to it
the more you can [ __ ] it up so let it do
its thing give it food give it water
give it air
she's gonna give you back so
um by by bringing some of these Jamaican
strains from New York
and which I'm saying Jamaican which I
think it's going to be it was it was
brickweed so I knew most likely I should
say I didn't know back then but I
learned quickly that you can't grow any
of course here right just but we can
grow it indoors uh people didn't like it
because it was too big too scraggly too
long you know if anything they're
growing up here especially all the pot
that came from the the
60s and the 70s or 60s when the draft
Dodgers were coming and then the 70s
when their kids were getting you know
old enough or or something that they
were growing dad's strains and I just
saw
one yeah so it's called Elmwood and it's
supposed to be this ancient genetic that
is supposed to be fire for outdoor
around here so I get a lot of
um
uh seeds do you know any more history on
Elmwood or is that just basically no all
I know is I wanted the seed forever
because I heard of it yeah all I knew
was like when you get to Northern
London North London Lucan Exeter you
know a little bit further north maybe
not as far as
um not as far as own sound but maybe
kind of in that direction south of
Collingwood Owen Sound this was the
plant that everybody grew because it was
massive interesting uh was it the the
the best don't know but you know we
would have people that grew like this
this strain is called berry berry
actually you know what this is berry
berry it's a uh and it was my first
centerfold in High Times oh what's in it
it was just a [ __ ] seed that a guy
came in and says this is the [ __ ]
bomb
wow all right let's let's try it out we
grew it out it was had to be like an F1
uh because it was all over the place but
it would [ __ ] turn into something
like this I was just like
this is [ __ ] awesome and uh they
didn't have a [ __ ] name for it they
was like us taste smells like it might
be a blueberry salad I'm not calling it
blueberry yeah
all right it gets the uh gets the idea
you know what happens oh good
like I was curious when did you first
start uh or when did you first make
contact with high times and start
working with High Times uh
Kyle found me
um
Cushman yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah right I
like to put that out I actually sent him
an email because he's out in [ __ ] the
oakster damn [ __ ]
spreading the uh
the what does he call it now the plant
Chiropractics or something like that
it's super cropping right yeah and it's
an article that's was the first article
and it was like a Grower's interview or
whatever on me yeah and I didn't make it
up I was shown by some growers in uh in
this area and I made sure it was in the
article saying you know it's [ __ ]
phenomenal technique for people that are
growing indoors that want to grow
certain trains certain ways sure and
don't want to have [ __ ] 50 plants you
can have
two plants three plants and still get
two pounds yeah you know not it's gonna
take a little bit longer but you know
certain strains obviously work better
for it but it's manipulating and
training plants uh to grow in a in a
certain way and um
and so when Kyle came through
so short long story short the other
thing with him teaching this is like how
did you learn this like I want I want I
don't want him to acknowledge me but I
want him to acknowledge the lineage of
the history yeah this technique sure
because people deserve
yeah yeah right especially because I
don't talk to either of them anymore and
the one guy's the biggest dick in this
[ __ ] town when it comes to anything
in general but he showed me this
technique that [ __ ] got me recognized
that's what they flew me to high to uh
the Cannabis Cup to talk about it says
talk about Canadian cultivation
techniques and it was super crappy yeah
and then they did the same thing with
Soma five years later or something but
so anyways
um Kyle was living in Detroit
at the time and
um
he was coming from maybe Toronto or
something
and I he must have heard about uh either
the seeds
or me or
um something can you hear that beeping
curiosity yes what is it like diabetic
thing I don't know oh it's okay and
um
and uh he just popped in the shop one
day at Organics and struck up the
conversation and we hit it off and then
um
he would come back and I would uh him
and his boys we called the Detroit
danksters uh great Growers back there uh
Sally is still there Big John I think is
gone but
um that was that was his crew his voice
super super good super talented growers
in in Detroit
and um but they like the [ __ ]
Canadian pot like the they were coming
through London and I would invite them
basically who I was saying before the
hemp Nation family yeah so I was like
listen if you guys want
you're paying 200 bucks an ounce but
you're paying U.S not Canadian you know
and um I was happy with that they were
[ __ ] stoked because you know they're
paying three 400 an ounce in Detroit at
the time sure yeah and I just said you
know I'm selling to you you do what the
[ __ ] you want with it yeah we didn't
have vac sealers back then we were just
[ __ ] I was taking you know freezer
bags so taking Ziploc bags throwing them
in freezer bags and then another freezer
bag and then baking soda or dryer sheets
and then another [ __ ] Ziploc
and the way that we got it across was
they would have a a friend
come across go to Windsor to the casino
and the boys were like a guy would bring
his girlfriend not tell her what was
happening and they would go over the
night for the casinos the boys the
dancers were paying for all of it yeah
dinner [ __ ] if you know the if they
stay the night do whatever and uh the
boys would go there
with a key to the uh to the guy's trunk
didn't even [ __ ] hide it like just
[ __ ] duffel bag in the [ __ ] back
yeah
um and then would drive across the board
with nothing
and then the uh the next day they would
the buddy would wake up drive across got
all the paraphernalia from the focus
Casino spent the night had dinner you
know that's it didn't buy anything
didn't do anything to the casino [ __ ]
go through no problem yeah right we did
that for [ __ ] years
and then I found out just a few years
ago that uh when they were uh went
across to come by come back here they
were asked if they were coming to see me
by name oh quarter oh and they were just
like okay like yeah he's incredible to
like turn around you know like the the
winds were crossing in Detroit yeah
coming from Windsor
um and now I had a uh a run-in
with the Windsor border coming back from
a photo shoot
uh four High Times where I met with Kyle
um and the gangsters
and oh God another photographer [ __ ]
most I think the most famous uh
photographer back in the 90s to early
2000s
God damn it he was there doing he was
shooting also but anyways
I was meeting with Kyle so I brought
all my photos it was right after I got
back from Switzerland so I had all my
Swiss photos I had my Amsterdam photos
um and I got
I got this in the early 2000s then
because you said yeah because I was in
Switzerland in 2000
so Switzerland didn't really get going I
don't think I was at the cup and I think
I did the cup in
no I did the cup
quit smoking pot two yeah it would be
two thousand we've been two thousand and
um
so when I that's what I was meeting I
would imagine that's what I was meeting
Kyle for because I brought all my photos
uh which always meant pictures which I
just basically use as proofs and then
slides because that's what the magazine
wanted and then video because I wanted
to uh document
the shoots yeah so when they pulled me
and I was driving my girlfriend at the
time had a
1969 Volkswagen bus
and I had
crazy dreads that were probably just
about my shoulder length but they were
still just finishing developing so they
were all over the [ __ ] place I was
like you know what I'm not Crossing with
anything definitely would never cross
with any [ __ ] pot or anything like
that and um got pulled over
and they said you know we were searching
the vehicle sure I guess I got a pot
leaf on my [ __ ] shirt and they said
do you have any drugs on you I was like
listen this I tell you my name's Pete
young I'm from London Ontario I own
organic traveler which is a marijuana
[ __ ] uh paraphernal shop
and I can't make it any easier than that
like no I'm dumb not stupid nothing yeah
illegal kind of thing and uh they said
okay well we're gonna search the vehicle
and make you stand out stand in front
and I watched the guy go around to the
back and he's a younger custom agent and
he holds up the first slide and you just
see his eyes go [ __ ] this big oh I
bet he thought he found the mother lode
yeah I was like ah [ __ ] so I walk around
and I approach him and said Hey listen
you know
not sure how the law is here I kind of
have an idea that you're allowed to look
through anything but there's people's
likeness in these photos that I do not
have model releases for so legally I
can't show them to anybody right and he
explained yes you're right you have
absolutely no [ __ ] rights here uh
we're allowed to look at every [ __ ]
photo every negative for pornographic
material
and he's like do you have any
pornographic material it's like [ __ ] no
I was like you it's all pot it's like
it's me pot my dog and pot me my dog and
pot as like there might be a couple
titties yeah maybe models that are
holding cannabis and stuff like that but
nothing pornographic and he's like okay
I had
[ __ ] not hundreds but thousands if not
maybe 10 000 photos negatives in that
van
because I brought everything yeah
because that was a money cow for me for
High Times they loved it they and I
didn't get paid for all the pictures a
lot of it came into the grow America
because Kyle needed photos to put in to
grow America and I say okay I'm gonna
donate this many but you're paying me
for this many right like if I got a
centerfold I got 600 bucks if they got a
full page I got 300 bucks [ __ ] so it uh
it made sense for me to do this so
anyways maybe that's you know he opened
up another box and literally thousands
of photos and he's looking at him and
it's like pot and I was like oh you want
to see some really nice ones I start
pulling out pictures from from uh
Switzerland which is Fields yeah yeah
not just like a backyard full but a
[ __ ] hectares or yeah yeah and I was
like oh and he's like where's that I
said well that's Switzerland somewhere
in Amsterdam I was like summer here some
are there kind of thing yeah never said
they're from Canada never said they're
from the states kind kind of thing and
he just opened up another box and he's
like is it all part it's like every
single pitcher and here's pie he's like
why do you have all this and luckily at
the same weekend they were having the
one of their uh
big Rave convention party kind of thing
I forget what they called it they had a
specific name and I was like oh I was
coming back from there and we set up a
booth to show people to use cannabis
because you don't have to have it tested
for [ __ ] you know bad drugs right and
they had them at these at these concerts
or at these parties where if you got a
pill they would go and they'd scratch
off a little bit of it and they would
test it and say yeah it is MDMA or it's
you know some at some speed or whatever
they would be able to tell you
um maybe not what's exactly in it but
they could more or less tell you what's
not in it right so I just made up that
[ __ ] literally on the whim that I
was coming from that and I had all the
pictures that's just put out on display
to show the show kids not the you know
smoke pot don't [ __ ] do drugs don't
do hard drugs
they bought it they liked it I'd [ __ ]
gave him one of my [ __ ] credit card
said Hey listen I offer uh 25 off any
officer so if you want everyone or you
want to pipe a bong anything like that
you know just show them your badge you
get [ __ ] you get discounts so that
was one of the Techno festivals in
Detroit yeah yeah and it was they were
big back then
I mean I wasn't trying to interrupt or
anything like that but one of the one of
the ways that we used to regularly go
into into Canada
um that um
was we used to go like in especially in
the Detroit scene with Windsor being
right there there was parties that were
thrown in Canada yeah right and there
was a lot of border crossings well they
learned like what hippies and ravers
looked like and they didn't like them so
we used to drive across the border there
wearing like Dockers and polo shirts and
all normal and all of our like real
clothes were like stuffed in the trunk
yeah of what we normally looked like
because we were trying to go back and
forth and look like the biggest nerds
ever yeah right because if you you know
if you looked a certain way yeah you're
gonna get you're gonna get checked out
on a certain level and I just didn't
have that option I had [ __ ] dreads
and you know like I I did the opposite I
was just like I'm driving a Volkswagen
bus okay I got a pot leaf on my shirt
and I got [ __ ] dreads now I'm born in
New York
and I live in Canada so I have a
passport for both
they can't deny me wherever I go if I'm
going to the states no matter what I
look like they can't deny me because I'm
only using my Canadian my U.S passport
I'm gonna come back to Canada I'm not
telling them that I have a passport for
the states or vice versa I show them the
[ __ ] Canadian passport right right
can't deny me I know I look like
somebody that you don't want to let in
your country but I'm a citizen [ __ ] off
you don't have a choice so it makes a
big difference I like that how do you
know you're in the States now
yeah okay all right I mean I uh you know
it um you know I have uh I I have I have
an uncle that does the same thing he has
Brazilian citizenship because and he's
he's American as well and so he uh he
when he goes into Brazil he uses the
Brazilian when he comes back into the
U.S he uses America so it looks like he
never goes anywhere but he's yeah
constantly you know and he just uses you
know and so but yeah I just I just
remember especially in the Windsor area
because Detroit was right there
um as as the years in the 90s went on
they definitely started
um you know I don't know if you want to
like what what you know profiling if you
will no you know he had an image of like
what hippies looked like or what herbs
Smugglers look like or what ravers
looked like or you know what each one of
these groups was likely to have on them
or whatever you know so well I always I
always tell people that you know I I
kind of followed a certain
mathematical equation for lack of better
terms right the police know that what to
look for right if
um if you're in this industry
so there's going to be uh 90 of our
community
is susceptible to getting busted because
of the way they look the way they smell
the way they walk or talk right sure
it's five percent on either side the
five percent of the people in this in
the movement or industry that never
leave their house they don't go to the
grow shop themselves they send somebody
to send somebody to go buy the
fertilizer go buy their seeds go buy
what they want and then that person
whoever purchases has no idea what who
the person is that place the order kind
of thing that person is never going to
get busted they I mean it's going to be
very unlikely that they get busted and
then the other five percent is where I
fall in I stand on the street corner
with a [ __ ] six foot pot leaf with my
dreads out in my Volkswagen going I'm a
[ __ ] pot guy like they don't want
that they they know who I am they know
what I'm doing
there's ninety percent of the other
people are out there are susceptible to
fill their quota
why the [ __ ] do we want to drag in the
dreadlock who's going to have the
newspapers there
so they're like we'll leave him alone so
I'm in that five percent on the opposite
side because I literally had a six foot
pot leaf in my front window I literally
did have pot plants growing in my front
window and for a certain time my whole
front window was full of [ __ ] peyote
and San pedross and didn't you also do
stuff like call the newspaper and they
would run an article where you take them
to like a corn field oh no that was a
that was uh like CBC and [ __ ] I brought
news agencies to my my field my crops
let me throw in a question before I lose
the threat of it when you met Kyle did
he have a strawberry cough then did you
ever hear anything yeah strawberry the
cough came out of Connecticut right yeah
so those boys do you know who those guys
are uh I know of them I don't know okay
no but I know basically you know this is
another thing with Hank douchebag
um the uh the cough they named it them
like Kyle [ __ ] said you know it's
makes them cough it smells like
strawberries whatever the [ __ ] deal
was so uh Kyle was with uh HT at the
time
um
and
uh he met the cough guys when I was
still hanging around with him
okay um never got to meet him they were
different direct I was actually I'd have
worn out from my arrest in Connecticut
so I wasn't going to go to Connecticut
yeah there's no reason to be hanging out
in Connecticut no there's no reason
doing [ __ ] Connecticut
it was a speeding ticket so yeah it was
145 mile per hour speeding ticket so I
never I never went back and I was like
you know whatever but no reason told me
about it and it seemed like a great
strain now I had strawberry Diesel and I
was like what what strawberry are they
using kind of thing like you know is is
did you give them my strawberry by
chance like you know what what you know
and I never really got down that uh I
never went down that rabbit hole to
figure out what it was but from what I
understand from what Kyle told me he's
just like they hit the money shot with a
[ __ ] uh with a plant that produced
this [ __ ] fire pot it was [ __ ]
phenomenal and um
and
[ __ ] do you know what was in the
strawberry diesel you were running at
the time
no no no just because it was that was it
was brought to me as yeah because the
the cough itself did start in
Connecticut and I got introduced to it
it made its way out to Colorado through
people who went from Connecticut to
Colorado yeah um Kyle has always been a
little bit [ __ ] uh you know he dances
around origin stories because it's like
one of the things that because he worked
for High Times he got pretty well known
for you know yeah and so as he's tried
to become like a can of celebrity some
of the origin stories of the things that
he's known for he's gotten pretty uh you
know pretty vague well I mean because
the [ __ ] douchebag he sold the cough
to [ __ ] Hank
right that's why he's the Strawberry
Cough seed was produced yeah it's
because [ __ ] and I don't know if the
Connecticut boys got even a piece of it
right it probably didn't
um because and like when when Kyle and I
when I dissolve my friendship with him
was we were in Amsterdam
in the middle of one of these squares me
[ __ ] screaming at him about uh him
backstabbing me kind of thing over the
common story yeah and I was just like
what the [ __ ] is wrong with you like uh
you know he's a [ __ ] skinny little
Jewish kid from New York he's from New
York right yeah yeah
and uh and
eyes like I I know you did it to the
cough boys but you didn't know them
right they were just some [ __ ] kids
that you [ __ ] met that called you
because they have some [ __ ] great
[ __ ] pot he got
um
Kyle got famous because of the Kyle's
Special Blend [ __ ] pitcher I remember
yeah the hell's the name of the
photographer
I don't remember the names of the
photographers
for a bit I use a super [ __ ] nice guy
super great guy
um
and that pissed me off and then uh he
tried to
um
he tried to put like I was finished my
first tour in in Switzerland and I was
contemplating if I should go back or not
because Steve is a hard person to
[ __ ] work with they want red from
this town right okay so
um
he I didn't know him when he lived here
but I met him through Steve
before Legends yeah
um
Matt I don't know who I met first
actually I think I don't know if I met I
don't know who I met them all around the
same time I think
right and they were all out in Vancouver
um red and jair he called himself Kermit
for a while
um were Brokers uh Growers not not
breeding yeah Legends started in
Switzerland right like yeah it started
with the uh the Louie and
um and that was just a you know a freak
um
thing that happened with the Ortega
that's what he said yeah yeah and uh but
so anyways yeah so
I know them is Steve
Steve's [ __ ] Wick is [ __ ] this
[ __ ] long yeah and if he if you if
he's pissed off like
when we were in Amsterdam and um
what [ __ ] out to start work sorry my
memory is [ __ ] now but um is this the
fast spear story no fast fear is my
[ __ ] story the [ __ ] he took my
medal because of my fast fast fatty was
a strain that Hank threatened to sue us
over yeah right because he went back
Hank came through Switzerland saw heard
that we were going to enter all these
strains and he's like well I worked on
these strains so they're mine he went
back to [ __ ] Amsterdam and registered
all the [ __ ] names and when we showed
up he at the dinner
right before uh High Times because all
the with all the people yeah he came up
to our table said Hey listen if you're
thinking about entering these strains
uh I'm going to sue you unless you get
and so red had to go up make a side deal
like okay we're going to give you a
percentage but the [ __ ] douchebag
Heath wrote down fast fatty
I brought fast fear those guys hated
fast beer [ __ ] didn't want anything
to do they were all Ortega they were all
big [ __ ] uh Indica freaks yeah yeah
because they didn't [ __ ] work in the
field you know red did a little bit but
I was there for [ __ ] months you know
Papa Bear came out there sat in the
[ __ ] hammock smoke joints and [ __ ]
with you know waited and thought he was
the [ __ ] the king we uh we bred sweet
tooth yes um strawberry blonde
um the Louie
I figured also we just basically we had
a uh we had
30 maybe 600 watts in a room
mainly we're just doing cuttings because
the company is called Mr hemp that Steve
was working with and it was just it was
right after they got busted for the
selling pot to a minor but we still had
the uh we sailed the facility in lagano
and um we ended up uh just taking a mail
and smacking it against the fan in the
corner yeah it pollinated the whole like
he couldn't barely see through the
[ __ ] room and um so some of my seeds
here someplace called the blonde bastard
and the blonde bastard was uh
was a strawberry blonde crossed
um
and they didn't want to do anything with
it so I ended up uh keeping it
let's see what was the uh strawberry
blonde do you remember what was in there
see this is
what I remember
with Steve is he he had a whole bunch of
strains that were were good and I like
um this here is uh uh big funk
which was one of his screens and then uh
the strawberry uh sorry the Sweet Tooth
number four gotcha
I'm pretty sure again Steve would be
better
to understand it and I think part of
this is
um correct and part of it might be
just my interpretation of it yeah I
believe that he had a bunch of strains
that were
uh or he had he had one strain or he had
a few strains that he thought were
[ __ ] great okay and he found that
[ __ ] resinous blueberry male he
crossed everything with it now
it was my understanding is when he got
the um the the sweet pink grapefruit
cutting yeah in California two cuttings
came up to Vancouver Vic who I'm pretty
sure that's the guy's name not sure what
he was didn't get the best reputation
with the boys yeah
um one cut and Steve got one cut are you
talking about Vic High yes yeah okay
yeah so but I don't know who he is like
yeah he's no longer with us okay well
you're good really clear yeah right but
uh I have a feeling
um
Steve took that blueberry mail and the
sweet and the the sweet pink grapefruit
and
crossed him
and then grew out a bunch of this
different seeds and
one became Sweet Tooth one became big
big treat one became you know this one's
called Big Funk but that's not his
original Siege so big treat was one of
them
um
uh something bud I'm I know I haven't
seen someplace I just don't know where
the [ __ ] they are
um
but uh I have a feeling that Steve ended
up with
um
a bunch of different phenos of that
those two strains and that's what he
started building his catalog off of yeah
and then you know the Sweet Tooth which
was one of his more favorite I know he
wanted to back cross it
um maybe to that same blueberry
or to the grapefruit and that kind of
took different lines
and stuff like that yeah so he had the
uh he had two different shishka berries
yeah the red line
[Music]
um
yellow the yellow yeah and uh you know
so I don't know
you know did that come from a dip
because that you know he was pretty
famous for growing these big huge long
[ __ ] Spears of berry right there's a
picture of his wife holding him and
they're like [ __ ] three feet long of
just straight colas kind of yeah you
know and um I think you know so I have a
feeling that maybe
the um
the seeds were all from
the same
uh same crosses but just different
phenotypes yeah that he
started
creating new lines and uh I think the
sweet tooth and the shishka berry were
the ones that really stood out
um
the strawberry blonde the big tree the
plum bud
Plum Bud that I just saw that it was uh
yeah that was uh and I know I have that
too okay okay I'm sure I have all these
[ __ ] seeds someplace man I'm blind as
[ __ ] though Plum I see Plum crossed a
mighty might that was West Coast Seeds
but yeah there's the plum bud
it described it a little bit saying that
it smelled very fruity but it didn't go
into detail
no because what the hell is this
Gabriella Island I got yeah
I wouldn't be able to see that
collection I bet you have some cool
stuff in there that I have no idea like
it because I I keep track of everything
but I just write it down and not think
about it anymore
you know like this pungent skunk from
Legends right like
what is that I don't even [ __ ] think
we even sold that strain right you
didn't no no and it was just one of the
genetics that you know we grew out that
we liked
um this is from Khmer
what the hell is this [ __ ] stream
calz calzar
colors are so that's a C4 it's like a
Cali or calories I like to C4 it didn't
produce worth of [ __ ] but it [ __ ] was a
good train so like Calio shiske Berry or
something like that yeah
yeah so again you can't if I even bring
up that name with Papa Bear forget about
it like a [ __ ] it's like with red and
Steve you just can't mention and those
guys were
Brothers like [ __ ] maybe back here
you know and I don't know how did you
meet Steve like did you know him before
you got invited to go to the Alps no I
didn't um I knew him before then
um
first time I did opium I was in his
[ __ ] at one of these places [ __ ]
freaking out in his hot tub
um
I didn't know how the [ __ ] I met him I
mean I was a pot guy here he was from
here he it probably got out there
through Hillary
um
and he how did you get the invitation to
to go to Switzerland
yeah Steve's a picky guy I mean you had
to have done something to leave an
impression
I remember you told me that [ __ ] guy
paid me 2100 a week to [ __ ] go there
Jesus yeah and I was like not bad and
then it dropped down to and then [ __ ]
that's Steve right I didn't get paid
that much yeah I paid a [ __ ] pot in
Switzerland as a Canadian they're like
you know oh [ __ ] the industry is not
what it was and you know if I can I'm I
brought all the [ __ ] uh pot to
Amsterdam from Switzerland that's for
the for the cop right yeah and what kind
of you know I'm a little Bent by it now
I guess I always have been but they were
all Ortega they were not one and they
didn't want anything to do with the
[ __ ] uh
um
um fast fear yeah right I was all fast
fear because I was in the field every
day working I couldn't smoke Ortega I
[ __ ] it would puddle me yeah well I
would uh I was all about the [ __ ]
night queen and the fast beer and now
these strains are all strains from uh
Neville yeah these three seeds came from
uh little Eddie douchebag sorry I don't
like a lot of people which one Eddie
Eddie which one uh my Dutchman no oh oh
oh nobody likes him yeah but um so the
deal was he was hired by Mr hemp at the
same time that Steve was and he brought
all these seeds that Neville owed him
the story was Neville old him owed him a
bunch of money
and instead of paying him he found a
[ __ ]
box of seeds in the back of a freezer
when he had to jump ship
and gave him to Ed as payment partial
payment whatever so those seeds ended up
in Switzerland they ended up in the
field and we had that's where the
Neville that's where the uh the night
Queen the fast fatty fast beer or take
Devil's Haze probably goes from there I
don't think I don't think we had
Neville's Haze in our field we had
strains I never heard of right these are
all strains no one's ever heard of
gotcha because they were they were back
in the freezer they were they were a box
that Neville sold to somebody I meant to
talk to Neville about this before he
passed that and it was like
five years ago six years ago I had
another a new contact
UM through the Mr hemp seed thing
and uh I never got a chance to talk to
him about it what do you want to ask him
uh it was more about the history of this
box of seats okay and what year was a
box of seeds that's why I'm not sure but
I could tell you that they were still
viable in
in
um
2000 yeah 99 probably uh the story was
that
um somebody ordered these seeds
never picked them up
so they got forgotten about in the back
of the freezer when
when time came for him to thaw out the
freezer for whatever reason he passed
them on to Ed
for again what I was told for an
outstanding debt
and uh Ed broaden Switzerland and Steve
plant him and Steve planted them and
then Ed had a falling out with Peter
with Miss with with Mr hemp and he was
gone and I was brought in to replace him
and I they actually even gave me his
phone I still had his phone
when I got there which I think is one of
the reasons why because it was still in
his name and I was calling Canada and
all over the [ __ ] I was sitting in a
field in the middle of the hotel yeah
why not I was like [ __ ] it like I don't
particularly care for the guy anyways
yeah and um so that's why that's what I
heard did you uh did you have any old
um early Pearl Early Girl silver Pearl
stuff yo yeah back in the back in the
early days of Scentsy yeah
um and then see this is the other thing
that again you know we hear so many
stories and you know regardless of who
the stories are from you know we went
out to dinner with the drunkers a few
times
um
uh
uh sativa sisters
um
God Jesus beautiful girl the hell she's
out of the business no she's still in
the business a little bit
um the Amsterdam Seed Company
uh okay
they were out of Canada though right
yeah out of BC uh yeah I have their
catalogs Karen Karen okay Karen was a
blonde and then big tit with the black
gray hair that
sold everybody out
um I forget her name she's kind of still
in this did you say big tit yeah she's
got big titties
she was uh Karen's partner in the
Amsterdam she's Infamous out in the in
the in the uh uh seed industry what were
you gonna say about the Pearl and the
okay so back back then
um
when it wasn't the Scentsy seed bank it
was just the seed bank yeah yeah right
so that was before Neville sold this
stuff to Scentsy it was just yeah yeah
so it would have been Neville now I
thought it was a partnership between
Neville
and Ben that was uh that was at First
Bank
I thought that was that's what brought
the end of the seed bank I thought it
was that when Scentsy seed started
I don't what was it the bus that that uh
made Neville sell to us to drunkers I
don't know I don't know I just know that
basically
the story almost basically the story was
told that Neville was the breeder for
Santi seed bank he did breed for them
for a little bit so but you know it was
all of his genetics yes that he was
breeding yeah so when when the first
um
catalogs were coming out of the sentency
bank you had early Pearl you had silver
Pearl in them
we loved it because again we were
dealing with genetics that were
um
from Neville like these were these are
the original [ __ ] strains like I mean
other than like the skunk and the
Northern Lights yeah you know we were um
oh I just had the name too
uh uh [ __ ] that's
damn it
there was a coffee shop who's who
entered the sweet tooth
um before Steve was that gray area or
someone no it wasn't great blue bird
Blue Bird Cafe yeah who owned that do
you know katsu Bluebird I don't know who
owned that
I think it was bluebird
I should look it up but anyways that's
the one that Steve tried it was gonna
Fireball because uh we're talking about
like Steve's [ __ ] temper yeah like it
was Ariane and
um and Luke and everybody else that was
trying to and the drunkers are trying to
calm him down because
they and it wasn't blooper
they entered the can they entered Sweet
Tooth in the Cannabis Cup
and without Steve's knowledge or
permission
oh man
it was it was a coffee shop though it
was no it was a city it was both they
had a coffee shop see but they were also
a seed company Barney Electronics
Barney's Farm Barney's because Barney
made it Barney's sold they still sell
Sweet Tooth yeah so it was funny but see
the the [ __ ] had done it the uh that
guy's like [ __ ] from what we were
told again from the other guys
big [ __ ]
um Netherlands Mafia yeah yeah yeah Gary
yeah and they were like I was telling
Steve you can't do it if you go there
you know it's he's gonna kill you it's
going to be [ __ ] you [ __ ] because
Steve
is a big guy yeah I've never seen him
fight but I wouldn't want to see him
fight because he would fight in a
[ __ ] heartbeat yeah and um you know
so
um
but yeah fighting fighting the mob is
not like no it's just something
he was going to go in there and
literally Fire Bomb the [ __ ] place
like he was like [ __ ] [ __ ] Gary sucks
[ __ ] right so so anyways um so again
this is again where you know we're we're
like [ __ ] the elders uh sitting in a
teepee trying to regurgitate stories and
we kind of go by what we're what we hear
and what we're told kind of thing some
of us get to witness it firsthand some
of us hear it regurgitated once or twice
and we never know so that's why like
with like I say with those seeds from
you know the this fast beer this night
Queen you know this fast fatty these and
there's a whole bunch of other [ __ ]
strains in there
that you know I was I was told this
story and it it anybody that I reach out
to and and hear pieces from they kind of
connect a little bit they kind of sound
similar so about them being seeds from
Neville and stuff like that yeah it
makes sense for the time most times it
was based on his his one of the things
that Neville mentions a bunch is that it
seems like 90 of what he made he never
released
in the sense that he had strains that he
liked that got put on the catalogs but
he'd make hybrids of all kinds of things
right and only a tiny percentage of
those things ever got offered up an
actual sale
we wouldn't
um
we wouldn't uh breed I wouldn't breed
anything without somebody else's
permission
unless it was a publicly you know
um uh available anybody can buy seeds
from like sexy Bank you know I would
breed and not think about now with Luke
I wouldn't do that because because you
know he's very particular well and he's
he's small and same as uh
um you know so the small one same as
Soma yeah
I wouldn't uh I wouldn't read any of his
stuff unless I would you know I kind of
asked him kind of thing and even with
this like with all my genetics my my uh
B-93
I don't want to I can't sell that strain
like people I was offered a lot of money
for it I'm working out a deal right now
to trade somebody for it but it's gonna
be and it's just because I want uh Sam
skunk
um
um I have an opportunity to get the one
of the original skunk one Cuts back oh
nice when we were and Sean you I think
you in town with uh [ __ ] that
epileptic [ __ ] kid yeah yeah which
one tell you so this is just this kid
that um Frills was yeah so he was
brought to me by the TCC the Toronto
Compassion Center uh said listen we have
this kid
uh he's uh he's a good grower
um but he's mixed up with the wrong
people we need to get him out of this
town can you take them brought him and
his mom and his sister to London set him
up in an apartment set up a garden the
whole bit turned out to be a great
Gardener
um
but it went to his head and then of
course yeah that that that original
story never
finished I think he's still dwelling in
that reality where
he was always a go super big kind of guy
and then getting in in business with
really bad people and it would always go
very very very bad out west like as soon
as he left here because it happened over
and over and over you know and like he
would always be like like when when he
would get [ __ ] destroyed she'd be
like I'm never growing again I'm never
growing again and then he's like buying
or he's involved in these like giant
farm chicken coops filled you know like
it's you know when I when I met him we
he was
because of his and his mom I loved his
mom and his sister
um but they had no control so they would
uh we would grow he would grow a bunch
of pot for the center I would give them
a receipt and then I would give them a
certain amount every week or every month
because if I gave all the money to Tilly
which I did in a few times he went out
and literally bought 200 worth of candy
he's like I was like where's the money
you were supposed to pay your hydro bill
oh [ __ ] man he's like he literally had
bags of [ __ ] candy and his mom you
know well not just that but I remember
the dude would be like stretches long
stretches of time where all he would eat
is like lobster dipped in butter or
something like that you know like he was
just that type
it was always extreme like bending like
like uh crazy that was after me because
I didn't allow that then he he started
hanging out with uh egg boy yeah yeah
right they got [ __ ] busted in my
truck yeah with 480 plants or something
and I get sucked into it my dad got
sucked into it because it was his truck
you know and I was just like and then
they drop off a vehicle because
we switch vehicles turns out to be
stolen right so I'm driving around in a
stolen [ __ ] Jeep Cherokee oh that's
uh really you [ __ ] douchebags but
that skunk one that's the whole reason
of story he had
we had him growing the black domino and
the skunk one and this skunk one I had
again it just landed in my lap through
all these connections I would imagine it
would have came from the early Scentsy
days yeah but it was that [ __ ] real
skunk and it was a fine Dutchman I think
it was
is his name Scott does that mean
Dutchman's Eddie Eddie right yeah and it
was a common name so he was supposed to
be one of the original skunk
uh sellers of the seasons yeah yeah and
so he had like some of the more pure uh
his were called the pure yeah you know
what I just saw that here too yeah you
have an old Sensei skunk one pack in
there you go no I have the old cure oh
yeah the pure I still have an old pack
of pure myself yeah I mean not as old as
yours though
um
not so missed out on some of the seed
pack showing you missed out bro I did
yeah there's some cool stuff can I just
lose you I just hit a button on my
[ __ ] feet no you're good black
actually black domino was out of
anything that I personally popped from
Amsterdam as far as seeds that were
available to the public that was the
nicest thing I I personally found do you
remember the uh the description they
were like it would leave a man feeling
whipped and something like the
description that the that the boys put
in there uh yeah full-blooded Indica
with large bracks we'll soon have you on
your knees and begging for more yes
harsh overpowering lady simply gushes
sticky resin to which most men seem to
have a Fatal Attraction a word of
warning this powerful compact Indica has
had devastating effect on many a man
leaving them apparently beaten and
whipped with a strange smile on their
faces not so usually looks like this
after he gets done with the
conversations with me though yeah yeah I
love that kind of stuff and uh me too
when we uh when Ron was doing the uh
Canadian cannabis cups here in town and
we had the Red Devil I kind of stole
that kind of Mantra from from that to
describe the Red Devil yes making up a
bunch it was a [ __ ] fire strange it
was great strain was a bunch of [ __ ]
that I was saying but um I love that
that's the first time I saw a red devil
I believe it was Greenhouse
that came out with that or at least they
were the first people to sell public
seeds of it yeah
I ended up getting was from a alcoholic
guy that was a good grower from around
here
um
but uh
um what the [ __ ] is this
Red Devil yeah Greenhouse it's in your
catalog and uh yeah Afghani Afghanistan
and I've always wondered if if like
Shanti doesn't still we've I've never
known it but like if if you know if he
tries to sell a version of that based on
you know because he sells devil but
they've never explained what the [ __ ] it
is right yeah I heard that too I heard
about the devil but I don't know if it's
uh and again the Red Devil was it
cutting brought to me sure and
um
it we just had a [ __ ] great funeral
of it and
I was friends with [ __ ] crazy Ron
that uh hidden Jungle which was a seed
company in uh one of the original seed
companies actually it was before iron
iron seeds
but uh but uh yeah we entered the Red
Devil in his Cannabis Cup and right won
first place
you know I fixed it but did you keep
much Willy Jack stuff around
no yeah he was one that was doing like a
lot of early girl and black dollar
Repros black white
um
he was from around here too right but he
did his breeding in he was from Ontario
but he is breeding in Montreal is that
no it's Willie Jack yeah that's what
we're talking about okay Willie Jack
yeah did you ever see Willie Jack how he
did his [ __ ] breeding I've known
nothing about Willie Jack again a lot of
questions about him yeah I don't want to
like literally I did a lot with the
Quebec Seed Company yeah that was his
[ __ ] guy
um I know again I can't remember his
name but he did a Cannabis Cup there as
well
and uh Willie would basically in his
backyard along his fence line again this
is what I was called he would grow a
male and a female and then five feet ten
feet apart another a different male and
different female sounds about right yeah
so if you were buying a seed and his
seed was 30 bucks for yeah
right yeah but he was saying oh this is
Northern Lights oh this is this strain
this is this train it's like no it's not
he has no [ __ ] clue it might have
some of that in it be honest with the
people you only charged you thirty
dollars a [ __ ] 10 pack yeah you don't
need to make [ __ ] up yeah you know
[ __ ]
tell people that this is what I did to
start reading I'm only charging you 30
bucks you know
but I didn't I didn't like him I didn't
think I thought he was kind of dishonest
well yeah I mean if if that's if that's
how he was doing his [ __ ] it's obvious
that like you know the cross-pollination
is gonna occur you know
um that's that's not cool
so
um what's up what are some of the
posters behind you before I forget
um
oh this is a chemo I've never seen
before that the uh the one chemo and now
I think
it's the
[ __ ] I don't even remember I know one of
them went pink and I'm pretty sure it
was the Ottawa
cut that went pink could be the UBC one
but basically the auto one one is
probably just a UBC
uh that was pollinated this is a spice
of life
strain tube I don't know who the [ __ ]
Eric is
here
um so this is uh so let me just let me
get the C pack back in there
uh and I don't mind sending a bunch of
these seeds if you want to [ __ ] try
yeah me and a me and a good friend will
try reproducing any of the pop happily
it's so [ __ ] cool UBC chemo all right
chemo poster yeah it was a [ __ ]
centerfold in High Time
I'm just gonna pick this up so this here
is
where's the camera there we go there we
go so this here is the berry berry oh
nice uh so and it actually says it in
the upper corner yeah yeah and then uh
sorry I have to try to get the so this
here is the chemo that it might be the
Ottawa because it's pink pistol yeah I
think I think it is and I can you know
this is what I've been told but it's
super nice because it's super pink yeah
it's beautiful
um I I have tons of [ __ ] photos of it
dude I see you know I told people for
years like chemo sounded cool but like
and everybody always said they liked it
but the name always turned me off yeah
well again the theory the the history
was like the G13 yeah that it came out
of California and it was used uh for
medical patients that were called chemo
right and then
um maybe the cut came out a piece out of
um California might have been called
something else yeah got to UBC they were
using it maybe for medical uh for chemo
patients that's how it got its name but
I was just told that uh yeah it got its
name from uh
complete so this also this was another
centerfold it's [ __ ] it's hard to see
because of the uh yeah what is this one
that's also berry berry
um yeah so you can't really see it it
may be better that way but
um it was like it was a go-to strain for
me for a long time yeah because it was
just uh it was so
interested
about this chat is because it we wildly
bounce around there's like all kinds of
of things that I think of that I want to
chat about and then by the time that I
wanted to merged on to some different
year totally different people whatever
it's amazing in that regard because
we're covering so much ground but uh
yeah yeah you said you're friends with
red right yeah yeah
that's awesome and that's with the fast
spear that's in uh with his no shirt on
this [ __ ] guy he showed up to the
field I'll see if I can find a picture
can you take a picture of that later and
send it to me yeah send it to him so
there was Matt there was this uh we I
used to go to these Harvest festivals in
the early 2000s yeah and there was this
guy Matt knows who he is there was this
guy chip
um that started Royal gold Matt and he
had just been out to Switzerland I think
it was in 01 maybe or something and so I
remember the first time I saw pictures
like you were mentioning of those fields
and hectors and huge greenhouses and all
that he came back with all these photos
on his computer
of all these people in Switzerland that
were just starting to blow it up and at
the time it was the largest yeah
they were doing it under aromathery so
we had this is one of a this is a field
here one of the fields with me let's see
oh yeah Jesus yeah and uh it was for uh
aromatherapy
that's kind of a that's us harvesting
some of them kind of I remember way back
then when you were out there somebody
showed me a picture because you weren't
around and it was you sitting in an
armchair oh and you had flower up to
your knees yeah all you've seen in the
frame was like flour up to your knees
yeah it was so funny and for the young
people watching now that are like in
their in their 20s looking at this and
they're thinking yeah that's it right
there we did we had terracotta floors
and we didn't have enough place to hang
it so if you the funniest thing is on
the on the table there there's only uh
two sets of scissors
we didn't know it we we had to harvest
all the tops so we went through the
field harvested all the tops brought
them back and we're like we can't even
hang them there's not enough to say so
we just laid them all terracotta and we
just went in and rotated them every day
and that's uh me sitting in the chair I
can I mean for people like Matt was
saying for people that are younger I
think Switzerland for the most part was
the first time that it was like us
seeing like non-land race type pictures
of you know people actually growing on
that large of a scale yeah
grows so bad like people are used to
seeing big CBD grows here is what I'm
saying like people our age are used to
seeing these massive hemp grows and
stuff but people during that era you
would never [ __ ] see this so it was
really it was a really unique time it
was a very special time and for that era
like people in the U.S seeing stuff like
this was mind-blowing at the time yeah
see this year that's we had a company in
town called novaks and you're supposed
to take your bag into different parts of
the world and uh enter it in a contest
right yeah and I basically got the most
votes but they can't they because it
wasn't legal I got [ __ ] uh there was
a do you know Felix
um oh yeah
yeah owls yeah yeah so uh this is his
field in in Switzerland wow
he had such shooting plans but I mean
yeah yeah his uh like his this is his
his what his field looked like
you know do you have any of his stuff
saved
I think so he used to supply so
impossible to get it's so impossible to
get in the U.S because he just never
shipped here so it was like and then the
distributors
the uh oh so this is the Sweet Tooth
Garden
um oh very cool that's what we we
um sorry for the [ __ ] no I've seen
yeah I've seen that picture before I
think that's a great picture yeah and um
on your Instagram
I think that one is there's there's a
few of the Switzerland that's activity
that's the skunk one on this side oh wow
yeah so that's the blind story it's a
dark picture yeah he has the black
domino yeah yeah and yeah before you
offload that let us know so we can make
sure that thing stays alive forever oh
no I have it I'm sending it right now to
um the guy for the skunk one cut so I'm
giving him the uh the the b-98 the Widow
95 and the um B93 anything would be nice
because it was our Northern Lights so
yeah so this was my version of Northern
Lights And if you look at the size
that's a four inch Cube oh wow yeah and
they were just following Hunters like
when you see the the size of the nugs
looking like it was like it was the best
sea of green plant and it was and it was
an l like was it a pure NL I don't know
but it looks a lot like what I would
picture the nl5 cut looking like yeah
yeah exactly and I thought it was just
you know
um it was yeah it was just a phenomenal
cut kind of thing so there's another one
over at [ __ ] about to lose that's
funny dude yeah he's [ __ ]
that's in fact we would we had such this
is in Switzerland too so we had such a
[ __ ] good time
that's when everybody loved everybody
yeah and uh when he when that guy first
showed up the [ __ ] Switzerland
[ __ ] guy sees the field he gets all
excited he goes home and he shaves from
his like shoulder down to his wrist back
shaved his entire arms both sides I'm
like what the [ __ ] are you doing he's
like dude I'm running through the field
with my arms out and I'm gonna make hash
if you wanted finger rub he made it like
[ __ ] 10 feet 20 feet lost his breath
couldn't get a [ __ ] quarter of a
[ __ ] gram off of them but his arms
are shaved and he was done I was like
you got to be fine like it was a good
thought good effort he literally did
shave his [ __ ] arms
but I don't think he got a single
[ __ ] gram of hash kind of thing so so
we made it about two hours in right now
there I know there's so much more we can
cover oh yes um but we could do a part
two yeah I was hoping actually that we
could have you back and we could we
could see if we could get kicked back
yeah yeah or or maybe even Chris Clay
also has an option because I know that
like I mentioned before there was about
I don't even know how many questions or
how many follow-ups I could think of
while you were talking about stuff but
then we just tangented it off onto
something totally different which is
amazing no you don't have to apologize I
have ADHD too so it's okay
if you read my book like I can eat a
send you a copy if you need or I need a
signed copy right very stream of
Consciousness which I liked you know
yeah it was my book is written that way
because I wrote it as if I'm having a
conversation and I had to hire somebody
to
listen to me take notes and then try to
put it in [ __ ] order that's the way I
talk it's not in perfect order and I'm
looking at it going because I smoked a
lot of pop back then I was like that and
I remember it happening this way and
then another story that crosses with it
doesn't line up perfectly [ __ ] I don't
know but I did make a huge mistake in my
book
um and it wasn't my mistake it was a
misprint where it says that I grew a
Cannabis Cup winning strain which I did
it was a fast beer it was my [ __ ] not
my strain yeah but I grew it I'm I was
the one that chose to enter it in the
cup those guys didn't want anything to
do with it yeah I knew it was going to
win because the it was honor the goddess
which was all the female judges
I got hired by sativa sisters Karen she
flew me to Amsterdam just to be a
[ __ ] Gigolo guy [ __ ]
because I [ __ ] have a good time and I
like [ __ ] females and flamboyant and
I got laid a lot
um it's why
um that's why we relate so well we're
not we're now we're now speaking Sean's
language he's just smiling
well [ __ ] it's because of that you
know all the all the Growers out there
now know that you can get laid and be a
grower it is possible
I don't know
um I saw he brought this beautiful hot
[ __ ] yoga girl from Texas to work his
booth and he was all stoked you know
he's gonna get some that chick I took
her home I took her back to my hotel and
then I was like I don't want to leave
yet I was like I got no place to stay I
never made it I never made made my
return flights so she's like oh you can
just stay with me I was like were you
saying she's like oh one of Tony's
places and I was like uh do you think
this guy who flew you there paid for all
your [ __ ] is gonna be okay with me
coming to [ __ ] you in his place yeah
right right yeah Tony Tony you know
Tony's a rocket fight yeah right Tony is
a [ __ ] well I'm the coolest cutest
[ __ ] Sebastian Bach wannabe yeah he
had like long hair very good beautiful
Mane yeah yeah it's like I was like and
here comes this [ __ ] you know uh
Ready New York dread and I had [ __ ]
you saw the pictures my dreads were not
[ __ ] anything uh to write home about
at that point I was sleeping in a field
for the last [ __ ] two months I was
like I was eating off of a dirt floor
like you know and I was [ __ ] the
hottest chicks kind of thing just a
simple farm hand
yeah so but
um yeah so yeah sorry about that like I
do when I do talk I I got engaged down
different veins and oh no I wasn't
telling I wasn't criticizing I was just
simply saying that like as you've got to
take on a bunch of different stuff
there's like different things I wanted
to go off on and then yeah something
totally else interesting and so yeah
wait wait wait wait wait wait wait wait
a second yeah you gotta take you gotta
take notes as we're talking yeah
this is what I want to talk because I'm
the same way I'm just like I want to
talk about that it's [ __ ] awesome
thanks for joining us on this Canada
Journey if you're ready to start a
Canada journey of your own check out
riotsseeds.com for your seeds and
feminized seed spray be sure to like
share subscribe and join us on our
patreon Discord
welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
cannabis strain history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground