welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to Breer Syndicate I'm
Matthew here with our co-host
thousandfold and today we're going to be
talking to Patrick Pico and uh he's been
a good friend of mine since I think we
first met at Emerald cup 2017 in person
and ever since we've stayed in contact
and yeah he's got a fascinating tale
through the uh the seed world and a lot
of experience uh in the seed world
making seeds at scale and more thousand
you want to kick it
off yeah I guess first I wanted to ask
everyone how their week has been
fantastic how's the new year new year
was great family man so super mellow
which I'm grateful for because otherwise
I'd be feeling like [ __ ] right now and
every day since the first so um we did
absolutely nothing yeah I like the
slower Pace these days it's um it's
really gratifying so it's been a great
week do they do they celebrate New Year
in Kenya where you're from
thousand yeah it's traditional to just
like stay up late and watch cartoons and
watch the balls
drop yeah it sounded like cha like
straight up Vietnam where I'm at like
yeah our city is very conservative so
fireworks have always been really big
here and like there's never really been
any push back on fireworks despite it
being desert and like lots of brush and
things catching on fire every year but
yeah it was they were they were lighting
off boom booms loud I don't want to say
that word boom booms loud enough to uh
Shake Windows like a mile around setting
off all the car it was wild so big old
Anatolian Shepherd was on my lap the
whole time but yeah it's usually never
fun what happens we to get old I guess I
don't know we did have a whole bunch of
fireworks out here um they allow those
there
they do yeah wow that does surprise me a
little bit it's a bit of a Wisher
climate I guess it's probably not as
risky as it is for you guys but still
you know do they allow like bottle
rockets and like firecrackers or is it
just like the safe ones it's the safe
ones I think relatively yeah yeah it's
weird where we're at in California too
because like they import like you just
go over the Border over to Nevada and
people bring back like m80s and like big
old monster things and like there's no
way to really rationalize like that that
legality because it especially with
online now anybody can get anything
anytime anywhere it's really opened up
that market you know yeah I mean like
you guys were talking about earlier
before we said a recording I mostly feel
sorry for all the
animals they have to put up with it or
or even even veterans with PTSD or yeah
dude yeah you know that that was
something I hadn't really considered
until later in life and it's just like
especially after the Iraq War and the
Afghanistan war and the guys come back
like that stuff isn't a joke to some of
them really affects them so yeah people
need to take more consideration to that
if they really do care about the troops
and you know all
that okay well I thought maybe we could
just ask uh Pico Patrick here a little
bit about what he's been doing um
obviously that's the whole point of the
the entire conversation but maybe just a
little brief thing on what he's been up
to just recently and maybe touch a
little bit on the bank seat hub okay
yeah so my most recent um job is in
Arizona I left California last year I
got laid it off at the end of the season
which I'm sure we'll get into a little
bit just prices plummeting unfortunately
we had a great year but it is what it is
um and through luckily some good
networking um I was able to find a job
relatively quickly it was something I
had kind of passed on earlier because I
didn't want to give up I was running an
outdoor operation um and didn't want to
kind of give up in the middle of the
season and go take a job somewhere so
circled back on that and uh and
currently doing that which is in Arizona
it's a 100,000 foot facility we're doing
indoor which is a back to indoor for me
I hadn't been in that in a couple years
um so it's fun it's extremely
challenging and like any other aspect of
working with the plant I just learn new
things every single day and that really
drives me to just continue on this
journey and keep going so that's been
the most recent
iteration
very nice and yeah you like you you've
told me and I've read I read your
interview in Skunk mag that you've
obviously been working at scale for
quite a while right so that's gonna be
quite cool for us to get into later on
yeah I we can we can talk about the bank
if you want to that was that was a
really cool project it's a good thing to
segue into so um initially when I got
the job at the bank I was kind of doing
the same thing I was out there looking
for work I had gotten a license in
somoma County had Fallout with a partner
had to sell out of the building that we
owned at the time and the license and U
made a partnership with an extract
company to do that that partnership just
just fell fell apart really really
quickly and ended up leaving that
position and then was pretty much
freelancing for a little while doing
some sales and some other things in in
the industry um and then was looking for
work so an an outfit that I had
interviewed with prior um due to some
other some good networking and try to
get in with um as far as just a grower
any job working in their Nursery ended
up circling back on me and interviewing
me for what they were looking for at the
time which was just someone who could
come in make seeds grow seeds at scale
they were doing 32 Acres the first year
I was with them and they wanted to plant
all of it from seed so there was a
series of dep crops that were getting
planted and there was AO also a lot of
autof flowers and we're talking like you
know one farm would have 170,000 seeds
twice a year so massive massive amounts
so the first part of the job was making
all the seed um which I was tasked with
and in the interview I I told them you
know I haven't done this at scale I had
only done one reversal prior and they
wanted all them um and so it was like I
I was very honest with them and telling
them like I'm I know how to do this but
I've never done it at scale and I was
lacking a lot of confidence to say the
least um but they basically were very
supportive and told me look if you will
come in and take this job and try it
we'll learn together you know and fair
enough luckily um it all worked out
really well the reversals were extremely
successful and we made three million
seeds in the first year so at the rate
at the rate of you know growing a couple
hundred thousand a year and making
millions in the first year I had
essentially somewhat worked myself out
of that job because we made so many
seeds can I ask you um just can I just
interrupt you and ask what did you what
do you feel like you learned from this
one oh my God from that job
yeah I mean the entire reversal process
I'm very analytical I keep a lot of
notes I I use a lot of data so you know
for what we were doing with STS
reversals just the proper amount
tracking it per strain tracking it per
specific varieties and looking at
lineages to see if there were going to
be correlations with other strains I
wanted to reverse and how successful or
nonsuccessful they would be how many
plants per seed you're going to get per
square foot you know how big the
receiver should be those timelines of
Staggering the donors and the receivers
what the ideal timeline is depending on
those genetics and their finishing times
and um you know there's also there's a
graph as far as for seed maturation how
long you want the seed to actually
continue to mature and there's four I
believe there's four car like four um
data sets that they're looking for that
all hit their Peak at a different time
it's like the germination rate um the
storage rate and there's two others
one's Vigor and one's one another one so
ideal timelines to where you hit all of
those at their Peak before you start to
basically get diminishing returns or if
you overdo the seeds they'll have the
crack shells um which obviously nobody
wants to buy you can still grow them
they germinate just fine but nobody
wants to buy those so isn't that wild
like that they still grow like I
remember um what line was the first time
I saw that bod did it with it was one of
the G13 hash plant lines uh chem 91 G13
hash plant was the first time I saw it
and like he sent me a bunch and they
were kind of cracked like I think they
still grow and they they did which blew
my mind you know considering I thought
air was getting in going to dry it out
but it they did uh crack pretty well but
nobody wants to buy them yeah nobody
wants to buy them I mean honestly they
they they crack a little bit easier
because you there's yeah the water will
penetrate you know into the yeah embryo
right away right and then they don't
have to actually break through the shell
to get up above the surface depending
upon what substrate you're using if
you're using like you know little Excel
plugs or something or rock those things
can be challenging so it can make it
easier but yeah nobody wants to buy
those and they look like [ __ ] so there's
certain strains that just that happens
and even when you take it to the number
of days that you would want to go to for
all of the other things that you're
looking for in a great seed um you know
some strange just got to take them a
week earlier two weeks earlier so that
crack doesn't actually happen it doesn't
open so learning things like that um I
was doing crop registration on all this
acreage so with that came a lot of other
plant diagn nois that was happening
first time I saw beat curly top virus
and last one thank God that was a tough
one you know um be able to identify that
in cannabis I've never seen that before
it was it's very wild luckily it runs
its course Fair fairly quickly like 30
35 days and it's out of the plant and it
goes from wherever the bite sight is up
the plant is affected everything below
and on any other branch is good it
doesn't affect it so how many times it
got bit by the leaf Hoppers that carry
it will affect how terrible the plant is
in yield and everything else but I mean
it'll take a plant that's about to be 10
feet tall and you know seven feet around
and turn it into a tiny little squat
Bush that is like two feet by two feet
oh no yield impacts are tremendous and
you have it you have it you can't
there's you know what I mean it's going
to run its course but you're not going
to get good viable butt off those
branches and it hurt that one hurt so
that was a great learning experience
experience um just everything at scale I
I ended up running the farm Ops on that
you know with that outfit the prior or
the next year rather because I'd made
all the seed and we didn't really need
that as much anymore so now it was just
about growing the seed and um running
the farm Ops they liked what I did from
a plant diagnosis standpoint I took a
lot of videos again shared a lot of
information would give reports back on
all the crops and where we were at with
the acreage and then would try to map
out the Harvest plan which was insane
because you know if you're running that
many acres it's all ready at the same
time yeah and you so and you need a
place big enough to dry it all like
you're talking about another episode
that people really don't take that to
consideration especially when they're
new and like that is a major major
consideration where do you dry it all
and if you're making seeds how do you
store it dry it and when the seeds start
falling out bit by bit like how do you
catch them identify with what plant yeah
there's so much that goes into that well
the seeds were made and kept in a
totally different area like I had a I
had a 10 acre Nursery that would be all
seed production Nursery operations
cloning seed making everything was just
in that in that Nursery so that was like
independent and then all of the growing
acreage was elsewhere and it was acoss
it was across multiple counties so it
was like I was putting a lot of miles on
the car and doing a lot of driving which
was also awesome I mean it was it was
like the ideal job the fact that I had a
job just to make seed was the coolest
thing in the world to me and it was like
I'll do whatever it takes to keep this
job you know it's a seed Maker's dream
to be able to grow it scale pop a bunch
of stuff that you want to see and get
paid to do it like I've never found that
you know and I've been doing this a long
time and that that that is something
special it's not something for those
listening that aren't really that Keen
on what goes on in the seed business
it's not a common thing to be offered
that kind of job so it is special
definitely yeah I don't know anyone else
had it before or since nope nope so I
was super lucky um super lucky to be in
that position and right place right time
networking has been so important and
everything that I've been able to do I
mean just with you you know like even
being in this chat right now is because
of good networking and keeping
relationships um so with so with that
with that job with its unique challenges
and with what we basically want I had to
put any of my ego and any of my prior
work kind of to the side you know I was
working for someone else I had to
fulfill what they wanted um what would
sell for them wasn't necessarily the
stuff that I was making and so for those
years that I was with them I was really
doing a lot of opw which is other
people's work yeah you know which I was
fine with because again I had the my
dream job so who
cares I'll go do CR rge and I'm still
doing the work so it was all good for my
perspective so with that the challenge
that we had um was genetics sourcing
genetics always having good genetics and
always having the next thing the way I
was doing it the way I was being asked
to do it was using other people's work
from the previous season or the previous
C that had come in and mixing and
matching and doing all that kind of [ __ ]
and it was always catering to a very
fickle Market that wants something new
all the time yep so with that there's no
like actual line breeding or learning
you're not really getting heritability
of traits and the things that are really
interesting except for the Autoflower
work which was probably one of the
greatest learning experiences because of
oh yeah yeah definitely so with that I
started the bank seed Hub with the
partner who was the owner of the company
um which the idea of that was so many
great breeders who had amazing Brands
already had been left out of
legalization for one reason or another
um you know whether it was they were in
a garage and they were never going to
get the zoning correct to be able to
have their seeds enter the market this
is before the 2018 farm bill so there
was still a lot of like very very gray
area as far as how anybody would get
seeds anywhere on this scale and two
facilities that were being opened up
across the country that were totally
legal and you know um compliant so to
speak so um with that I started the bank
seed Hub and the idea of that was to
basically be a conduit or a bridge to
all these other amazing breeders who are
out there to come to this 10 acre
facility make your seeds here or give us
the plans tell us what you want us to do
I'll make the seeds for you we will sell
them back to you at a certain price if
you like if you want to go hit the
market with them we'll grow out a
shitload of them as many as you possibly
want us to grow out so that we can do
the crop registration pheno hunts and
keep building for the next season and um
basically just offer the resources that
we had to all the amazing breeders who
are already out there so that was the
whole idea with the bank seed Hub um it
worked for what it was designed for but
as you guys know many of these breeders
are very hard to kind of get in with um
they're very guarded if I come with an
opportunity like that from someone that
they don't know and haven't done
business with before it's going to be
that very skeptically and which it was
had to develop relationships first with
the people that I knew and had
relationships with that I thought would
be a good you know jumping off point and
from that I knew that in the short term
it would quickly kind of start to
snowball and grow and I think if we had
another year or two we would have seen
that really starts to become a round
table kind of Coalition of breeders um
what I what I envisioned and I called it
was the Sunday mass which was the mutual
admiration Society of seed makers and we
would all someday we would come together
and we would be able to form this group
where everybody is gaining in the same
amount you know we take away the
competitive element a little bit even
the playing field and then we could have
a very real brick-and mortar or some
type of actual bank where all the brands
represented all the Breeders are there
it's all 100% legal and compliant we can
do business with anyone we want to do
business with and you know that that was
the whole
idea I just wanted to say that uh we've
heard different uh heard of different
people's attempts or initiatives to
collectivize in different ways like so
we've heard from Little Hill um Matt
obviously with the breed of syndic and
now you with this and it's interesting
like each of you has a slightly
different take on collectivization but
it's super cool to see and hear
about not common again it's not common
for um breeders to even get along to
accomplish a goal like that so it is
something that takes years and years and
years to build with with trust and and
yeah you well on your way everybody's
got a little like bone to pick with
everybody else it seems so yeah and
that's myself included yeah right I mean
some others with you as well and back
and forth and you know it it is what it
is but things change quite a bit when
you all are in the same room together
when you're all physically talking and
have the same mind or the same thing to
gain um a lot of that ego gets Stripped
Away and Things become what they should
be about which was about the plant about
about sharing about the community you
know and just about weed that's that's
what it should be about so the last the
last thing that we did with the bank
seed Hub um in the last year things were
pulled back quite a bit we did a lot
more from colone and we're running less
and less of the seed and so I did an
acre hunt and I got like five or six
friends that all had fem seeds to throw
in with me and we did an acre that was
just going to be all of us together it
didn't really work out the way I wanted
with being able to produce some content
get ready on everybody has different
schedules people had moved it was harder
for them to get back to California to
kind of see the work um so I was
documenting it all and trying to share
it as much as possible but that was like
the beginning of the fruition of all the
goals to have even half a dozen breeders
that would throw their work in together
and then if I could have gotten them all
together to that site you know then
we're viewing each other's work and like
making selections together and and
picking out the little nuances what we
liked about this Cross or that cross or
you know whatever that was that was
really what I envisioned and we we
almost got there at the end um but like
I said California ended up you know
prices of outdoor went down to like sub
500 and it was a total [ __ ] show and
when you got to pay excise tax and you
got to pay all these other insane bills
I mean the county of Sonoma was like
just trying to really Bend us over and
just hit us for these ridiculous fines
all the time and just crazy [ __ ]
constantly crazy [ __ ] from them so um I
unfortunately was let go from that
position and had to you know do the new
thing so it was great while it lasted
and the idea is still there the dream is
still there I hope that I can continue
to kind of see that mission through and
um exciting that where I'm at in Arizona
they're giving me pretty much cart
blanch to do any genetics I want um
we're doing massive seed hunts there so
I just filled the room with
2500 um plants all from seed there's six
different varieties so we got a couple
hundred of each one going um that's
going to be the first like big pheno
hunt project on that site and then I am
doing a reversal in the greenhouse right
now which should net quite a few seeds
so really exciting projects and then I
hope to kind of be able to bring other
folks back into that fold and continue
the same idea and offer that space like
now I have indoor space which is one of
the biggest complaints about the bank
seub was we were doing all outdoor
nobody wanted to take pictures and
content of their outdoor flower because
for whatever reason they think it's bad
or they can't sell seeds with it but um
now I have the basically the same idea
that I think I can replicate bring it
inside and hopefully make a you know a
mutual admiration and a mutually
beneficial group of people that would
want to take place and take part in that
and for the company I'm working for it's
all good for them too because they're
getting access to all these genetics and
all these different things for their
sales that you know they wouldn't
otherwise have or they'd have to pay for
or whatever
absolutely yeah you let us know if we
can help in any way you know obviously
we have a platform of sorts and have a
certain kind of reach so you you should
just hit us up if you can think of
anything that we can help with yeah I
definitely like to deliver completed
ideas so um it's it's in the works let
me continue to work on the mission right
now and make sure that you want it now
bro yeah yeah I have to make sure that I
can execute and be successful um for
everyone else you know before I can
before I can really just open up the
floodgates but that is the long-term
goal so you know if anybody's interested
in having those conversations I
certainly am very nice I'm sure you're
working you know your previous uh gig uh
working on that scale probably force you
to systematize a lot right oh yeah I
always have though I'm operations are a
big um just part of my flow with
anything with the plan so I very yes
yeah okay well I thought we could kind
of go backwards in time a bit
and maybe you could talk to us about
what the early period for you was like
uh making seeds and growing um you know
what Drew you to those things how did
you get into it to begin with and how
did you learn about those things well so
I'm from Ohio originally and in Ohio the
first grow kind of group that I was a
part of um they were growing all from
seed so there was no clones none of that
was even happening and it was all um DJ
Short
sensey just a bunch of old school stuff
White Widow blueberry super silver Hayes
um and and with that with that early
sort of introduction like seeds were
were the first thing for me you know so
when I ended up returning back to them
around like 2010 or so it was like a it
was like a homecoming it was like oh
this is the way we were always supposed
to do it you know we like kind of lost
sight for a while so those early days
back in Ohio all from seed everything
was selected inhouse and it was just
because it was a very closed group and
didn't want anybody to know what the
hell we were doing didn't have friends
that had clones and probably would have
you know what I mean like was parked the
car like two miles away and carrying
grow equipment down the street yeah
seemed like a better idea than parking
your car after green Merchant right so I
was like I'll carry this [ __ ] light
and these ballots and everything else
and try to make it in one trip which was
ridiculous um just to not have my
license playing in front of that store
so that was kind of the absolutely you
know that was kind of the Viewpoint and
um it was very it was very stigmatized
in Ohio in my area even from my close
friends who now are totally cool that it
was it was still like I was kind of off
to the side and on my own a little bit
um so anyways from there um I ended up
one of the guys who was part of that
group who was really just more of a he
was more of a scammer kind of he was
more like just in it for the money part
he didn't kind of guy yeah he didn't
even really smoke weed I mean he you
know he did eventually but he's he's
like the reason that people shouldn't
smoke weed in my opinion he just got too
like out of pocket and was doing stupid
[ __ ] and acting a fool you couldn't have
him around anybody so but but that was
his whole thing was just sort of like
I'm just trying to make money you know
which was fine too because it gave me a
job so um I ended up moving out to the
Bay Area to do some trim work for him
and just help out because it was
exploding and at the time the OG pounds
were 58 57 down in La so it was like
[ __ ] yeah I was getting paid a shitload
just to come and trim just because he
didn't want to have to hire some randos
to come trim and needed reliable people
so relocated from Ohio out to California
to do that and everything was from clone
so from there it's we're growing OG snow
cap blue dream blackberry kush um
Nightshade you know some other random
stuff and eventually that whittel down
to like you know maybe 10% anything but
OG you know and everything is OG all
from clone and that was the flow for a
long time you know and everything was
going to La and what year was this this
or this was um I moved out to California
2007 so right around there 2007 through
200 12 or so we that's pretty much what
we were doing and then what became
pretty apparent like you know right away
was if we it was always like oh we need
the next OG cut you know now we need
Skywalker now we need King Loui now we
need this now we need that and it was
like well we can just get this from like
we can just go backwards
buy the Seed make selections and have
something totally unique that nobody
else has yep and that's and that's where
I was starting to look in other lines
because OG was really boring at that
point because it was like that's all we
[ __ ] grew that's all splitting hairs
between the cuts and a lot of people
don't realize like some of them they
could be the same cut with just two
different names so get real boring 90%
90% of them were the same cuts and it
was just little conditional differences
from environment that would really
change you know the appearance or what
was expressing in the plant was more so
based on the environmental changes based
on these people's Grow rooms and how
they built them um which is kind of an
interesting thing like your signature is
kind of in your growroom it's kind of an
interesting concept yeah but but yeah it
was it was just really boring so I was
like [ __ ] I need these flavors like I
was in love with the banana flavor I had
banana OG I wanted to find that in a
seed form I wanted I couldn't get a cut
anywhere so I went to seeds and I think
some of the first seeds that I bought
when I was in California were off of
seedbay um you know started with some of
that Dutch growing stuff like the o99
that we talk about and that's the that's
the pre-roll that I gave you that was
that
super um so I still talk about that I
still talk about it when people ask
about banana stuff like and I did a lot
of banana work myself so I I I've got a
pretty good working knowledge of that
line and how it breeds but that was
exceptional and like when people ask me
about banana flavors I'm like well there
was one very specific one that was the
most extreme banana bread turps that it
was just unmistakable like anybody who
smelled that would smell that and that
was like a seven weer it was like so and
the and the oer 99 was made probably
years prior and probably not kept in
great condition so yeah by the time I
even got those seeds it was like they
were probably I don't know five years
old six years old I don't know when she
made them but they were old and two only
two germinated so the one was a female
one was a male 2011 that one female was
what I called the banana 999 cut that
was just the most phenomenal banana
seven weaker yielded [ __ ] beautiful
plant perfect doesn't have love the odds
on that yeah I know I know not only that
but then I use the mail because I'm like
well [ __ ] there might be some banana in
this guy too so I use the mail in my
earliest breeding work just to try to
continue that and um and he put out
amazing work I mean that's still the
backbone of what I grow today and what I
breed today and those lines is still
rooted in that o99 cut and the maale
from that pack those are still like the
bases and then I had some uh what was
the other um Sweet Tooth number three
from I think Deluxe had done a remake or
something I got that because I was just
[ __ ] head over heels for the
Tangerine Haze that came from the
devil's Harvest crew oh yeah that oh my
God that plant was so amazing it was
like no nobody the flavor was just
unbelievable with the Tangerine nycd G13
Haze yep exactly yep and it was like the
flavor was so [ __ ] good and the high was
extremely up extremely Zippy and up and
everybody who smoked it who was looking
for like a downer couch locky weed hated
it because it didn't do that but I had a
very specific experience where I was
down in La vending I would always go to
Malibu to first point to go surfing I
had smoked some OG with my buddy he had
come down there with me and we were just
like [ __ ] floored you know after a
day of surfing in the ocean you're just
like already kind of drained and then we
smoked this OG and it was like I was
like oh my God I'm so [ __ ] lethargic
and then I remember smoking the
Tangerine Haze after that and being like
whoop right back to like just you know
cognitive Lucid everything was [ __ ]
good again and I was like this is the
[ __ ] like this is more powerful than
that OG it's just a completely different
effect that you're not feeling from like
a sober to high state but it's like if I
was already high and too low man that
thing brought me right back I'm like
this is [ __ ] amazing so that was that
was a magical one but I used the Sweet
Tooth to try to like preserve that
flavor as much as possible
so those were the two earliest breeding
projects I did really was using the
banana o99 male and I made f2s but I did
all sorts of other work with him and
then trying to preserve the Tangerine
Haze as much as possible by using the
Sweet Tooth F2 the Sweet Tooth number
three F2 which I don't know how many
times that's incrossed but um that was
pretty much the earliest stuff and the
results were fantastic so be it be it
luck be it whatever like we got [ __ ]
great plans from every single thing that
got touched by the pollen and nobody was
really complaining at that time until I
accidentally seated an entire room and
then and then I then I got a little push
back on that's when they stopped liking
seeds as much as when you see the entire
room that's exactly when they stopped
liking seeds so much at that point they
got referred to as art projects and I
was no
longer which is honestly what ended up
being the impetus for me leaving that
outfit and starting my own thing was
based 100% on that I was like well this
is the ticket like we got to keep doing
this and there like no we got to do none
of that just go back to Growing blue
dream and I was like all right this I
have a different Vision I have a
different Vision than what I think do so
um that's when I kind of broke off on my
own and left you know the safe haven of
a very tight-knit friends group that I
had and had moved across the country for
and everybody that was working with us
at the time was from Ohio for the most
part um so that was sort of the impetus
for leaving that group was the souring
of popping seeds um for them you know
not for me collateral damage man we just
ended up with more seeds yeah I mean
should even complain that's that's a
plus right right um I wanted to take a
little tangent here uh and want to throw
this bone to mat as well which is the
fors you mentioned I think in one of in
in that interview in Skunk mag um that
the forums play quite a big part in your
early stages definitely and and a great
great point to to mention or place to
mention that so that was really I was on
IC mag um the guy that I had initially
learned from whose nickname is cool
white by the way which I [ __ ] love
because he he burned down a house by not
uh putting an anchor in a light and
putting it up in drywall and burn oh my
God so when he went to jail all the all
the guys in jail called him cool white
because of the
lights I like that so anyway he'll
probably love that shout out cool white
super ego maniacal guy so he'll
definitely enjoy that but oh yeah here's
his name for sure yeah yeah but um so he
was on overgrow he was big on overgrow
I'm sure he was an [ __ ] because he
was an [ __ ] in real life so I can
only imagine how bad he was on overgrow
but but I was on IC mag mostly because
of the seed Bay linkage and that's just
where I was buying seeds so I was super
paranoid still you know the same
mentality had followed me through and
was a lurker I would like put my [ __ ]
laptop on private mode and maybe go
somewhere else that wasn't my regular IP
address go even surf it and look around
mag but but yeah watching um some of the
threads on ICM especially the Jack
mayhoffer stuff um which which is I
think is Ivan right and and it was like
the early cocoa beds that they were
doing I just real quick you're referring
to Jungle boys Ian for the people who
don't know right yeah Jack mayher Jack
mayhoffer so Jack mayhoffer threads were
epic as far as just like scale growing
and and what they were doing now I'm
sure or what they were doing then they
don't do it all now but my my idea and
sort of what I was following was fully
soil organic growing living soil and so
his idea of these giant beds um in your
room was just like right in tune with
what I was trying to do so I used the
tech that he was kind of providing on
icmag and all the other information
about nutrition and living soil and all
the other stuff that was available on
there and really just just ran with it
but it gave me a lot of confidence to
kind of know what to try and learn from
other people failures especially um and
uh and that was that was quintessential
and then so much strain knowledge and
and now I I really I haven't gone on
there in so long but um just so much
information and the thing was that all
the bullshitters got called out that was
the great thing we don't have that
anymore like Instagram is such a step
backwards from the the sharing of
information because agreed and I don't
think Twitter does it either I'm not on
Twitter but I would imagine that doesn't
do it either but the power is in the
words the words are the knowledge the
pictures support the words but the words
are where it's at on Instagram it's
totally different it's just the facade
here's what it looks like the words are
almost meaningless you throw a couple
emojis up there and then you know C
conversations that are also meaningless
which is usually just a circle jerk yeah
so Instagram for me is kind of just such
a huge step back it's a necessary
platform I think because it's the only
one that we really have but sure it's
just such a step backwards as far as
like sharing information and sharing
reality because none of it is steeped in
reality
whatsoever I think I think that's a
common sentiment too among people who've
been around and made it through the
Forum era and stuff being able to have
that in that kind of community and then
going to Instagram it it's just totally
it's a night and day difference and it's
actually pretty
depressing yeah it is I mean I I just
appreciate it it was policed a lot
better yeah you know and um I don't know
it was just it was just it was generally
really solid information you can kind of
tell what wasn't and what was but
generally really solid and if you needed
verification of a cut or something you
could get it pretty easily and or people
would just call you out and tell you how
fake your [ __ ] is which also can be
valuable just to know yeah right so
there IC mag was really really awesome I
really enjoyed it and the first kind of
the first few people that I met up with
and um you know became like in in real
life friends with were from IC mag to um
and that was cool because that sort of
opened up more of the networking gateway
to like sharing information getting
stuff you know sharing weed sharing
concentrates sharing Tech um sharing
opportunities you know that all of those
things really came along with IC mag so
I'm super grateful for that forum and
all the forums that preceded it as
well yeah are you gonna jump on to canak
Cabana now that it's all opened up I
will yes unfortunately time is so
restrictive for me right now between the
job and the kids that it's just I just
don't have the time yeah I mean I don't
have the time to do I don't even have
time to smoke as much as I'd like
honestly hly or a place to do it um I'm
in my kids' room right now I was telling
thousandfold before it's like the only
place I can get away that's like quiet
and not in the garage looking depressing
yeah so I just don't have the time for
it right now I wish I did but I'm so I
mean I'm in my own Forum world so to
speak in the in what we're doing because
the 100,000 square foot is Perpetual
I've got nine different Grow rooms that
are all going at the same time um and
all a week apart so I can see very much
the entire like week one through nine of
what's happening in a room at all times
which is really cool to just track
progress and and kind of make minute
changes and see the results of those
types of things um so I just get so much
value out of that that I don't really go
to the forums quite as much anymore it
was really a little bit of a crutch a
lot of information and and now it's
because it's there's so little activity
there um it just wouldn't be as valuable
for the things I would probably use it
for today which would be more like
verification of cuts and you know
Providence and things like that and we
have our Discord too where we can all
jam on that which is really nice I mean
that's been that's been a great thing
honestly the discord's been awesome and
I've and that's been the main type of
forum thing that I've interacted with in
the last six years I think I've been on
that thing now with yeah yeah it's been
a long time bro it's been a long ride I
remember messaging messaging Denali the
night I was in the hospital first kid
and he just turned five so that's wild
wow yeah wait so did you two cross over
on forms or no no we met an emerald cup
2017 yeah so I remember exactly how we
started
talking you had said something on a post
I posted something at the time I had my
company was called vudi and I was
running that Instagram and um your bio
had a stone roses um lo oh yeah and I
[ __ ] love the stone roses and so few
people know about the stone roses that I
was like he's already in me I [ __ ]
love that dude it's the first time I
sent you something I sent it to Cinnamon
Girl oh that's right so wild yeah dude
yeah so nobody even listens to them
anymore D they're the best man music and
weed those are the unifiers those are
the things for me that have always like
brought people and made friends has been
like if there's two ice breakers for me
it's music and weed and those have
always been true even to this day yeah
for
sure sure I still use that quote I think
it's in my profile still to this day I
figured you were cool when I saw that
man I was WR it creeps people out though
like because they don't get that it's a
quote from Stone Rose's song it just
sounds like I'm a evil Satanist even
though I can I can hang with
it anything else on the
forums uh no I enjoy I wish I would have
done more honestly I was more of a
lurker I wish I would have interacted
more with people and
um I wish they were still as used as
they are today yeah yeah I mean going
back to what you guys are talking about
between say the forums and Instagram or
Twitter the architecture you know
obviously lends itself to different
things so on Instagram and Twitter it's
very hard to sustain a conversation for
more than a few days right because it
just disappears into the timeline the
abyss of noise and you're so limited on
what you can say it's not like you could
really express yourself very well kind
of like Twitter you know you're limited
to a certain amount of character sets
and people don't want to read long
sentences so you'll find that most
people just respond to the first few
things you say or the image and not read
what you wrote so there's a lot of
miscommunication that goes on yeah and
it feels like also people are encouraged
to like spit out zingers like you know
witty on liners and stuff rather than
actually a thoughtful you know
articulation of anything yeah it's just
about like your reflexive knee-jerk
reaction
of the time I defin I agree with you I
definitely enjoyed the linear nature of
the forums because I would wake up in
the morning go back to wherever I left
off catch up on all the you know the
chitchat whatever was going on and um
just follow along with the conversations
so I I enjoyed once it got it got
ridiculous to a point I remember the
slow nickel Lounge had like 800 Pages or
something and it was like holy [ __ ] I
went to bed and we were at like 528 I
wake up we're at like 600 and something
I'm like holy [ __ ] I can't even catch up
so I guess there's a downside to it too
when it gets that much
use but yeah I missed the forms man I
really like that that was a good that
was a good time San Diego's finest got
so big they had to blow it up into like
a second and third I think now might
just still be on second but yeah that
was one of my
favorites yeah when threads become their
own
forums yeah right and they lock it at a
point
yep well I thought we could could kind
of segue to Pico's I mean obviously Pico
you've talked about some of the work
that you have done yourself uh you
talked about the banana stuff um can you
tell us a bit more about some of your
own recent work uh you know night cap um
hazes yeah so um so from that initial
project with the ojra 99 I cross out to
blackberry kush which was a staple for
us at the time and um from those found
some really cool plants I called it
Gargamel um it was an interesting plant
nothing like too crazy but it had a very
very good look got great color had good
flavor it was kind of like pretzel dough
with like a hint of licorice on the back
end which I really really liked and then
um I ended up getting a cut from a buddy
that was supposed to be Gorilla Glue 4 I
checked it on the forums you know I hit
up uh that that group and I think Marlo
was the dude's name who called me out
and told me that's [ __ ] that's not
Gorilla Glue 4 and I was like well
whatever it is it's [ __ ] awesome and
it might be better than gorilla go 4
because like I never even experienced
anything like this that one we ended up
taking it to Market before I knew it was
not Gill GL for we took it to Market and
you know taking it to like Oakland and
they were like n this this ain't it and
and their best guess at what it was was
um Grease Monkey which was gly glue 4
and something else I forget what the
cross was on it yeah I think it was a
exotic D yeah that that one I remember
that one it was exotic yeah yeah it was
exotic genetics and and regrettably we
ended up taking that name and calling it
gree monkey 2.0 we didn't we couldn't
confirm it was or wasn't sure the guy
who uh but but if that was what they
wanted to call it and that was one it
was you know we could sell to the club
because it was super dank then I was
fine with it you know so we end up
calling that grease monkey 2.0 for a
minute um I ended up making some s1s of
that which may have been an S1 already
because it was the fake gorilla glutes I
don't know what the hell it was um but
the S1 of that that I popped I popped
one seed every time I'd make something I
just throw one or two you know in in
just to kind of see and get a look under
the hood and this plant popped and it
was like the the first set of true
leaves after Calen was like covered in
tricomes like covered in the the cesal
type you know the type without the
glandular stock and and it was
glistening and it was like amazing and I
could smell it right out of there it was
like fresh pine and coriander it was
unbelievable the plant continued to grow
up in veg and it just kept having these
tricomes on every single leaf like the
fan Leaf is covered in trikes
I'd never seen that before it was so
fragrant I knew it was going to be like
[ __ ] amazing it was just meant to be
um so that's what ended up becoming boss
Frost for us boss Frost boss Frost like
ruled the day for us for a minute we
went to the 2016 High Times cup and that
was the only thing I've ever entered
into a cup it hit 6.6 on the turps and
33 on the total can it blew everything
else out of the water the the NorCal cup
was um the lab was Steep Hill that did
the NorCal cup and they were they were
very very rigid um and so they had to
test it multiple times even to to to
confirm that that's what it had tested
at but that's what they ended up finally
releasing for the test results um so
that thing that I entered didn't Place
didn't do [ __ ] I was very disappointed I
thought for sure because of just the
test results and everything else that it
was going to kill it didn't really
matter um but that crossed into the
Gargamel ended up being nightcap and
again I just did a small seed run um you
know like one plant couple hundred seeds
nothing big threw two of them into pots
just to see what was up right away and
one of those two became nightcap I never
even went back to the seeds again night
cap was better than boss Frost somehow
it was like Daner more
earthy heavier you know it boss Frost
was like very um ground coriander really
bright like really bright flavors and
the night cap was just way way Daner and
um that one we ended up hitting 8.1%
turs on super high in Alpha pining but
does have a backbone and mirene too it's
like kind of one to or two to one alpha
Piney deine in that and um was the TP
Cham for SC labs for a couple years till
I think um those guys up at the ridge
ridge Farm Ridge something they um they
ended up usurping me with a couple like
ten of a point you know on that and at
the time we were putting out in the
living soil we were putting out amazing
stuff our own genetics I guess my own
genetics although I had some help
um and everything was killing it in the
turps from SE Labs like boss Frost I
never saw it Go below four and a half
and that was on like the shittiest
shittiest grow and nightcap was always
just killing it too so the cool thing
about nightcap is that um the turpine
profile this is where I started really
getting into tpine profiles like around
2014 2015 when I started my own outfit
was doing this living soil and
everything else I opted into lab testing
immediately because I wanted the data
right so I had to pick the best Labs I
would use Ste pillar SC and I just
wanted to keep one you know I keep it as
simple as possible so that I would get
as true a data set as possible um
through all the different things we were
doing in the grow trying out different
things and running different strains and
whatever so at the time I mean the boss
Frost and The nightcap were super high
in Alpha pining and were the highest
things they would ever see it would take
me weeks to get my tur test back because
they kept having to retest it to confirm
that these numbers were accurate enough
for them to put out and at the time SE
Labs was was um making public all their
test results if you didn't ask for it to
be private they would make it public and
you could go and you could scrape all
the data off of their website and you
could pull tens of thousands of tests so
after that and I had a pretty decent
relationship um as like a client to Alec
Dixon one of the founders of SE labs and
he would shout us out all the time and
we had a lot of conversations because my
test would take so long to get back I
would always be calling them like what
the hell's going on
and we would have a lot of conversations
and he was just like you know really
impressed with the amount of turps we
were getting off all the strains that we
were growing especially these unique
lines and um and what he shared with me
and we could see from the data was that
all of the Cannabis that was tested was
falling into these like seven categories
you know now that's what the emerald cup
is using as their groupings for um to
get away from this sativa Indica uh
designation and they're using these you
know I forget what the words are dessert
something whatever the words are kind of
tacky but the IDE exotic dessert dreams
sweets and Dreams yeah right so the I
mean they're trying to simplify it and
that's a corporate move I'm sure but oh
yeah regardless of that the idea that we
now had we take this vast super plastic
genome plant that can do so many
different things and we make it finite
right and we have seven categories now
that like almost all the weed fits into
these seven categories that became super
interesting and my idea was that if I
play Within These categories then I will
be able to breed homogeneous strains
much much quicker because I'm going to
be replicating this chemotype over and
over and over again and so at least the
expression of the chemotype is going to
be the same now there was a lot of
misinformation about the um like
integral part of tpin on flavors you
know which I kind of could tell right
away because of that banana 99 cut I was
searching like okay what's the tpine
that's giving us this banana flavor
right and it's not a tpine at all it's
not it's it's am Amal
acetate it's an ester you know same
thing you see in alcohol production when
you
drink and you get that banana that's a
molese and I had a background in brewing
beer as well um just for fun but that's
how I knew about that Esther and so
other light bulbs starting to go off but
the idea was the same that I follow
Within These tpine categories and do my
breeding work within those to add or
take away certain traits that I wanted
and keeping other ones intact mainly the
flavor and what I knew for the TP
profiles is that they would have a
similar effect for me anyway um so I
would what was interesting about the
night cap is that it's the same flavor
as all the non trinoline hazes or the
piff yeah piff was something I was
searching after you know as much as I
possibly could at that time and again
this is like 2015 nobody was circulating
Cuts you couldn't nobody had the CU
black it was like a total Legend you
know lost to the times or whatever you
couldn't find the [ __ ] there was some
work here or there um but I ended up
going to JJ I got a bunch of his stuff
at one of the emerald cups or one of the
high time shows and started running
through all his stuff that was supposed
to be you know as close to that as
possible he got a mango cut that was
super insensi from somebody else on an
IC Forum I forget the dude's name and
made a bunch of stuff I ended up finding
some really nice very insensi non-
terpinolene Haze expressions from his
stuff used that bred it down a couple
generations to get what I wanted out of
it and then I paired that to the night
cap because it had the same tur in
profile I was able to basically take the
flowering time and reduce it
tremendously increase the bag appeal and
the actual like density of the Bud from
what the haze that I was growing at the
time was and um and increase the
increase the um Tarpin and the
cannaboids by like a shitload so it was
basically allowing me to have sort of a
secret weapon in night cap to breed
hazes and shorten their flowering time
and do everything but it did affect the
high you know the effect was affected
the flavor profile stay the same but the
effect was a was affected so um nightcap
was super influential in with my work
and from that line breeding with JJs
into the night cap I made night piff
which is like a true eight-week
flowering you know Haze type the effect
is a little stronger but it's still very
heady it's very up um and it's incense
as hell when it when it burns in the
room and it it just hit all the trades
that I wanted right away um so that was
kind of some of the idea of
well one that was the night cap and like
what the night cap has become now I've
worked that down several Generations
since then I have a night cap Exotica
line where I added an exotic in um at
the time that I made it I didn't want to
sort of piggyback off of the success of
cookies and what they had done but now
with the cats out of the bag because
other people had already leaked the
lineage so it is nightcap Gary Payton
and then from there I bred that into
another exotic which I will not actually
well that one was a purple Cass which
nobody can get anyway because that was
cadero strain um that I was gifted by
like a family that wouldn't let anybody
else have it so that's the IAP Exotica
season two I continue to do to do that
line it's really high pining um it's ex
the pining the other thing that's
interesting about the pining is that the
effect for me for high pining strains is
very um it's very lucid I don't get I
don't get the inner monologue I don't
get the backseat driver where like I'm
behind myself kind of observing and like
commenting on myself or what I'm doing
or whatever you know that's why I call
the dumb mouth the dumb mouth yeah well
I don't get the dumb mouth from it and
and it's also extremely potent and um
the reason I call night cab night cab is
because that turpine profile for me with
the potency with the high THC allows me
to drift off to sleep without any inner
monologue or like my voice inside going
which is one of the things that gives me
paranoia and stops me from falling
asleep so for me it was super easy on
the night cap to fall asleep because
that turpine profile it allows a very
smooth transition from so sober to high
or you know whatever you want to call
that yeah it's like it's not as
noticeable that you do get the head
effect you get the rush but it's not
like holy [ __ ] I overdid it I'm too high
you know it's it's like I I can maintain
the same train of thought um and so at
the time this was 2016 I think that that
one popped and we were doing a lot of
work still with medical patients and
they were giving me the best feedback
that they were able to sleep through the
night didn't have to get up and go to
the bathroom getting restful sleep which
if you're ailing from anything like
getting restful sleep is like one of the
two best things you can possibly do
regardless of anything else that you're
taking or doing so um talking to cancer
patients and talking to people with true
medical need who were impacted by that
plant was uh and still is like a
highlight for me super amazing so map's
been on its journey I continue to use
her today I continue to breed her today
and she's a magnificent plant again it
was two seeds so recently on my own
Discord I auctioned off the the half of
the remainder of those seeds that were
left and um some lucky gentleman picked
them up that's cool yeah that's really
cool I kept half I need that but you
know I just with her in the stable it's
like there's almost no need to go back
in and the and there was quite a bit of
variance even in the two that I popped
it was like one was super Squat and the
one that I kept was really tall and
lanky and had more of what I was looking
for um so yeah I'm happy to let some of
those things go and I have so many sees
now it's like what's the you know if I'm
not going to get around to it let's let
somebody else grow it out that's about
where I've gotten with a lot of my
collection too after a while you just
start to realize like man these things
do have a time limit and and I want to
see them grown out it's it's you know
what I mean like it's either you get
greedy about it and let him die with you
or you get them out there and be able to
get data points at least very least yeah
I mean it shouldn't really be a
collection honestly it's a perishable
good it's like right right wa always bug
the [ __ ] out of me when I see people
with these M like flexing with their
massive collection it's like grow them
what are you doing yeah you know what I
also learned too on the forums the
people who had post their massive
collections were always the first to get
shook down and like scammed and it was
just setting yourself up so bad so bad
to do stuff like that yeah it's very
fomo driven yeah which I'm guilty of it
too I mean I did the same thing like I
had yeah early on I think L that's what
we saw was cool you know like the cooler
guys were showing off their killer you
know whatever they had their big seed
collection so of course we'd follow suit
as younger guys you know yeah well
endorphin the Endorphin experience is
like in the purchase and then receiving
the package absolutely and then after
that it's over so it's like I got to do
it again I need more seeds yeah yeah I
have these now I don't need these
anymore and the flex I honestly the
psychology of it is really interesting
to me because seeds themselves are
obviously not plants and they're not
flower they're not end products they're
kind of promises of of something else
and then when you even even the purchase
of a seed is like a promise of a promise
and it's like these little gambles that
you're kind of getting high on really
yep yeah that's great when we do these
massive hunts now and and I'm talking to
like the crew that's working under me
that's I I never have used the term
promise but I'm going to now but I
always say if if you let one of these
seeds not if you let it dampen off or
you don't you know what I mean it's
you're not like growing the seed
properly or doing Justice if you lose
seeds in a germination run it's like
might have just lost Michael Jordan yep
none of his brothers did [ __ ] you know
what I'm say you can't lose Michael
Jordan man you got to see all those to
their true potential to know and that's
the fomo for me now is like if I lose a
plant or a plant is I'm like it's not
doing as well as it should I'm not going
to see its true potential that's like
where the fomo hits for me now and I'm
just like ah I need they have to be
perfect yeah for sure you could be
missing that blue that beautiful blue
it's funny because I found I found
really great things in really small runs
I found really really amazing things in
massive runs and you know the potential
is there and that's that's the thing I
don't want to lose is the potential I
was just trolling my buddy here who is
popping some blue ex
seeds and didn't get them all I was
gonna mention it I was gonna mention
it all right and that's going to be our
show for today I wanted to thank Pico
for coming on thousand of of course for
always helping setting things up being
there with me to ask some of the harder
questions that I'm not really that good
at I'm only good at asking bringing
stuff um also want you to go check out
our patreon that's how you get access to
our Discord that's where we hang out all
the time we've been doing more live
chats actually I'm going to go run one
today um it's really nice we get to
interact with the whole Community
everybody gets to put their input on on
what they want to see in shows um gives
us ideas for different topics because
there's you know I'm running out of
ideas over time you know what I mean um
but I am trying to take it back to more
breeding Centric type show so expect
that definitely expect that um we have
Riot seeds.com with our seeds and spray
we have the gel drop the jel hybrids we
have um the Blue Dream Drop from goat
farm um we're going to have some new a
new influx of stuff from high and Lum I
believe some mango Haze hybrids coming
up shortly um going through testing
right now uh you can also find our seeds
at Riot Seed Co Europe for European
people in Central Europe we have gir by
seeds for our people in the southern
hemisphere of Australia and New Zealand
and then we have lifted seeds also here
in the US but they can take um like
direct credit card payment stuff and
they're awesome people um they're doing
a great job of carrying extremely good
breeders not every seed bank cares about
that even if they say they do I don't
know any other ones I really truly don't
so uh with that just thanks for showing
up thanks for caring um it means a lot
to us that we can keep doing this show
that enough people give a [ __ ] about
this topic to keep it going um there's
been a lot of times where it's almost
ended so thousand deserves a lot more
credit than I think a lot of people have
been giving him in the comments because
without him the show would have been
dead after the whole uh explosion you
know what I mean um not everybody knows
about it uh I don't want to go into too
much detail but um we talked about it in
the patreon crowd with everyone as it
was going down you know there's a reason
that co-hosts change um it was necessary
you know we hold each other to high
standards we absolutely do and sometimes
life gets hard people slip up things
change morals change uh moral fluidity
as we talk about it none of this [ __ ] is
easy choices and um just know that like
it's a good group of dudes all holding
each other to really high standards and
if someone falls back we put them aside
for a while you know so with that we'll
see you next week for some more breeding
chat with breeder syndicate
want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it
out