foreign
[Music]
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
it started to hit me
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
what's up everyone welcome to breeder
Syndicate I'm Matt my co-host and friend
natto that's me
and we are here with pipsweed from
souvenir seeds our very good friend
how's it going guys this is an episode
we've been putting together for a long
long like four years into making
something like that we've been wanting
to do something and uh finally we're
getting to do it it's one of our most
requested shows so I'm stoked to finally
have you sitting here with this pip and
uh have you interacting with me and not
so and everybody can uh share some
insight into the Ohio strains and what
you're currently doing with your your
career
um so let's start at the beginning let's
start talking about one of the
one of the Clones they held your
interest the most uh when you first
started growing what was circulating at
the time
um I mean when I first started growing
it was just I I had gotten random clones
from a few different people uh they
weren't really anything special it was
something orange really low yielding uh
that's what I ran for my first several
grows and it was kind of depressing but
it was better than nothing because it
had a good smell and it was you know
decent smoke at least for me at the time
but uh the main ones uh you know I would
say probably with when the lemon G and
the Death Star came into my light was
like really when I saw like the full
potential of like good quality cannabis
and
um and it's it really fascinated me so
that kind of like gave me the oomph to
take it to the next level and take
things seriously and uh and I did and I
you know grew those for a long time for
over a decade straight and uh made a lot
off of them how early into your like
smoking like from the age of where you
started smoking to where you started
growing like how long did it take until
you started getting like death star
quality type weed okay so when I first
started smoking I was probably around 13
and uh I was just get I got weed from
this kid at school and he stole it from
his dad and sold it to me for you know
twenty dollars I paid him in rolls of
quarters I stole from my my parents
closet or something like that you know
um and smoked it and I didn't get high
yeah so the first time I really ever
smoked weed I never really got a buzz
and then um
later on you know I would you know High
School came around you know we had
access to the swag basically the seated
pressed Mexican stuff right yeah um
there's different varying levels of that
uh some were actually surprisingly good
except it wasn't really compressed and
had the nice mature seeds in it uh a lot
of lime green stuff like that too we
call it the Christmas trees but uh there
was good stuff as well but um
I don't know I would say probably my
sophomore year of high school was when I
discovered what we called at the time
kind bud KB
um and it was in Akron at a college
party and one of my smoking buddies and
good friends I've known for a long time
came downstairs and showed me this I was
out on the porch and he showed me this
Bud he's like look at this KB bro and
I'm like what the hell is KB like
I'm looking at it I'm like what the hell
is this he's like it's weed and I I
looked at it and smelled it I was like
you gotta be kidding me dude
oh that's confusing going from
compressed to seeing like your first
actual dance Bud like well-grown
manicured [ __ ] personally Bud yeah
yeah so at that point I had already been
uh selling stuff for a while I did
through high school and stuff just to
make extra money we you know I didn't
come from the wealthiest family in the
world by any means so uh it's kind of in
a you know growing up situation was kind
of every kid fend for himself after a
certain point so
I did what I had to do to survive and
make money
so that's how uh that's what I did for a
while and then eventually you know after
I mean senior year I grew some plants I
grew my first plants yeah uh outside my
parents backyard way in the back and I
planted them late and they weren't going
to finish in time and I knew it so I dug
them out of the ground and put them in
pots and brought them inside and put
them in my closet to finish out like the
last you know three weeks or whatever
they needed yeah I line the whole closet
with tinfoil black light black lights in
there like you know what I mean yeah
yeah totally it was it was looking back
it's just hilarious but um I was worried
I was going to get caught my mom wasn't
super mean but she would uh she would
whip my ass probably I thought yeah
and uh I had harvested it eventually and
then like months later maybe a year
later she told me that uh while I was at
school she was watering it because it
was about to die that whole time but she
never told me and my mom was a gardener
too I grew up growing flowers all kinds
of flowers and planting gardens at our
house and other people's houses so
that's kind of like you know we're I got
a little bit of a green thumb before the
whole cannabis thing so I understood how
things work and yeah and you know how to
water and how to feed and you know what
a healthy plant looks like and what a
sick plant looks like and all that kind
of stuff how to prune them
um and then I never heard that story
about your mom that's funny
she's a sweet lady she's been put
through hell over her lifetime but mad I
can't even picture my grandma being like
Oh I'll just take care of the thing like
you know what I mean that's pretty cool
that's pretty rad
yeah so um I would say uh what was it
probably right after right after high
school is really when I started you know
growing pretty good and I you know
probably three four years after that I
uh I'd say
2005 six seven ish right around those
years I started getting a lot of really
good genetics I moved up to Akron
and uh I met a friend of mine who is
still a really good friend of mine we
know each other for a really long time
he's a good guy his name's Jay and he
shared a lot of really nice clothes with
me he shared the um the Bubba Kush
he shared the lemon tree The Afghani
mango the Death Star the sour diesel
those were like the main ones you know
we've had different things over the
years and stuff this is very early at
that time to be getting clones like that
too for people listening that aren't
aware this is actually pretty early to
be uh having access to stuff like that
in in random circles so it's pretty cool
that's a good connect
I had the Indiana bubble gum research
was around at that time
um one of the very first ones I ever got
is one that 99.9 of the you know percent
of the people listening aren't gonna
know what it is unless you're local but
it was called um wanaki some people say
hunaki and it was pretty frequent early
2000s around this area being sold
and a lot of people around here remember
it uh so that's one I've had in my
collection you know since probably 2000
and what's happening like
it's a it's kind of like Jack oh really
yeah um I've done a lot of research it
might I don't know what it is I feel
like it could be like J1 maybe or I
don't know it came from it was a big uh
a lot of the big Asian crews around this
area uh ran that it was a it was a big
one uh and it was everywhere but this
was back in the day it was for a short
period of like two or three years that I
remember our group getting it
consistently
yeah yeah that was one of the first ones
I got was that a TV
yeah it was it was pretty yeah it's like
it's it's tea lean but it's got like
that funkiness that fun yeah kind of
like thing in it well that's interesting
yeah that's cool it's a beautiful it's a
beautiful plant uh I I don't it's those
kind of plants aren't my favorite to
smoke I don't like the turquently and
stuff yeah uh but I keep it because I've
had it for so long and I do enjoy the
Aromas uh that come from those plants
and I do I mean I enjoy the looking at
them and growing them and seeing the
different colors and you know yeah
so I keep it around I throw it in the
flower room once every couple years and
do a nice one of it
hand it out to friends or something you
know
but if you're a sativa person you know
you like that kind of stuff that's uh
you know it's a good plant it's just
super nostalgic yeah it's great if
you're from around here and you're
around in those times
so we have that we have the one would
you wanaki
we called it the knock the knock okay
that's easier the wanaki the the we we
didn't want to mess around with the
pronunciation so we just we just called
it The Knack
that wasn't like that was just our
friend group that wasn't like everybody
you know that was just us we referred to
it as the knock so that's one of the
really interesting things about weed
that I like a bunch is that how like
especially it seems much more so in
America than other places
every crew is insistent on giving all
these different strains they get little
nicknames and then amongst that little
crew it becomes like just what it's
known by you know and so these different
strains at different times can take on
different lives
and you only know what your friend gives
it to you as
well
you know it could start off as that and
then it turns into the knock and then it
turns into this and then you know and uh
it's it's interesting because sometimes
you don't make those connections unless
you know someone that knew it by both
names right
yeah you know it can happen you know
um I mean we definitely have seen
strains that like we think it's one
thing and we'll probably talk about that
a little later but we we think it's one
thing and then lo and behold it turns
out to be another
you know we think it's another and you
know I'm I'm originally from the Midwest
too although I've been in California a
long time now
um and it's kind of interesting how the
Midwest works in the sense that it was
much less like trendy it was basically
like as as pip was saying it's like if
you got something better than Mexican it
was better than Mexican
and it wasn't there wasn't competition
for it the the desire for something
better than Mexican was huge so any kind
of kind bud you had went any kind of
right we called it dank you know we used
to call it nuggets and the reason why we
called it nuggets is because only
nuggets were uncompressed
you know like you had the shape of the
bud the Nugget itself you know and so it
looked like nuggets where it's like most
other stuff was compressed and even if
it was lightly compressed it still
changed it but if I can stop yeah so you
know it we had some nice stuff every
once in a while you run around nice
stuff but a lot of the Homegrown stuff
back then was a little bit creamy a
little bit moist still you know
um and then we have my town anything
better than Mexican was kind bud right
right same here like if it was messed up
if it wasn't dried the right way or
cured the right way if it was preemie
there wasn't competition for it there
was still more people that wanted it
than there was it
so it just went
beasters I mean beasters was kind bud
this was kind bud some of you guys
remember that that stuff went for the
same ticket it went for 50 and eight you
know some people probably charging more
I mean if you had if you knew a guy who
knew a guy you'd get the 40 deal but you
know straight up it was 50 bucks an
eighth when it first hit the funny thing
about about beasters in Canada is like
the really bad beasters they sent to the
parts of America that they thought had
no competition
and then the parts of America they
thought had a little bit more
competition from outdoor or indoor they
would send like a different grade
so depending on what part of the country
you're in sometimes there was some stuff
that was actually pretty damn good
for the time and then there was some
stuff that you were like oh
now I will say our Canadian Watchers
have wanted me to to say remember they
only sent their crap down here right
yeah
they're like just remember we had good
[ __ ] we just didn't share with y'all we
could chat about we could chat about
that later too but pip and I have had
some long combos about there's certain
strains he has that he even likes them
sort of fermented
oh and you know and what I mean by that
is that a lot of times beasters because
I mean think of it it's like it wasn't
cured that great it was still had some
moisture in it and then they'd seal it
in a freezer in a freeze and freezer you
know sealer meals and ship it and it
would get no air exchange for a couple
of weeks until somebody cracked it and
some of that beasters would firm it and
I remember having conversations with Pip
about that and he was like man you know
there's a couple strains that I actually
do that intentionally to
because I like the fermentation process
which is almost like that African cob
work yeah in a way right yeah the
fermentation stuff uh you know it seems
to me like a lot of the gassier stuff
that I run it does it really well like
the Death Star uh you know you cure that
at super high humidity uh I had my notes
somewhere I forget it's like I put it
keep it in like a five gallon bucket
with a screw top lid for 75 humidity or
something like that for a while and and
not a cold area though you want that
warm air to kind of like get that
process going I feel like it takes a
little bit longer if you keep it in a
cold area but it does good with a lot of
the gassy stuff the death star dust RS
ones I did it with it was really good
um I think star dog I think I've done it
with before lemon G it is I love the
lemon G when it's done like that when
it's like slightly fermented like that
it's uh I like it fresh too I like it
both ways it's just you know what's your
preference it's different you know just
slightly different but yeah
just so people know too like when we
talk about fermentation if they're
unfamiliar with it a lot of times curing
happens on the stem and if you trim
stuff up kind of quick and it still has
some moisture content going on and you
start to some people call it burping you
know all that that's basically like
light fermentation if you're if you've
got fully trimmed work in a bag or in a
in a five gallon bucket like he's
talking about and it's not ready to
smoke yet you're kind of fermenting it
in a way in my opinion at least yeah and
you definitely got to burp it too you
can't just throw a bunch of wet weed in
a bucket and no it's called molding yeah
yeah yeah you don't want to do that
there's a fine line there's a fine line
it takes you a while to figure it out
for each strain and like all that but in
the time frame and all that but you know
I just keep it in room temp and and it's
done pretty good versus like in a colder
area stuff like that
yeah that's a that's a complex process
and I'd imagine a lot of failure uh on
the way to figuring it out well honestly
it was it was by accident really you
know in my earlier years yeah I just you
know left some stuff it just it did the
process by itself I guess I just left it
in a bag or I left it somewhere and I
would notice every time I did that that
stuff that was a little bit more moist
and sat upstairs in a bag after a couple
months or whatever it taste it was like
it was a little bit darker like it was
like like degrading you know but and it
wasn't as loud but it wasn't like with
the Death Star it was like sweet it like
loses its gas a little bit and becomes
like sweet
and uh
and it's just I mean it's super smooth
smoke it's way smoother than like
smoking a fresh Bud out off of a plant
or something I remember the smoke was
super rich it was Thick Smoke
yeah I mean fermented stuff super thick
cloudy smoke oh nice thing I sent you
left about it oh okay I didn't know I
got the flower yeah it's uh dude it's
it's awesome I enjoy it it's not
something I'm going to smoke all the
time but like you know it's like a fine
wine it's just it's cool smoking and
getting that sweet flavor and like I
don't know it's just you gotta you gotta
try it to understand it and that that's
also something that's interesting I
think too about like the era we're
talking about where information didn't
exchange as fast and a lot of times like
when I learned like how I cure and stuff
it was kind of like you dry things and
sometimes it goes well and sometimes it
doesn't and then sometimes you learn
things good and bad by accident on right
how you treated it you know and that's
kind of what it sounds like you know all
you you put it up there you put it in a
bag and all of a sudden it did this
thing you weren't expecting and then
you're like oh well how did I do that
and you start playing with like what you
did to make it do that right you know oh
does it work with this other strain nope
this strain doesn't like it at all but
this strain boy do I like what it does
when it does that and I think that's
kind of cool because you know a lot of
times one of the cool things about
growing in the midwest is that because
change was slower back home people grew
the same strains for longer
there was there was less turnover where
like all of a sudden your customers are
like oh this is bunk I need something
new
yeah that doesn't happen
yeah they were just stoked you get
what's there that's that's what it is
and so as a result of that sometimes
Midwestern Growers really got to dial in
certain strains because they had a long
relationship of success by being able to
grow them right um and it's also we'll
talk about that soon
um some of the some of the stuff that
you know that uh pip has in his
collection is pretty rare Nationwide
because there wasn't pressure to move on
to a new thing
you know there was various clones and
cuts getting passed around locally and
they did well locally so they had their
own they had a life of their own almost
um we're in California you know populate
you know popularity changes and all of a
sudden everyone dumped something and
just moves on to the next new thing
right
you're exactly right you were able to I
mean you were you were telling us
you know death star and lemon G like
we're the better part of a seven eight
year run for you in terms of success
right I mean yeah man I mean I've I ran
them hard hard for you know at least
eight years you know and then I kind of
brought new other strains in and I was
still running lemon G and death star so
so over that over that time you know you
know especially with indoor where you
get to do a number of rips a year you
really get to learn how the plant likes
to grow how big to get it what size pots
how to feed all that type of stuff you
know really like you really get it's
like a long-term relationship you really
get to know your partner
you're right you're so right man it's uh
you know it took me uh I'd say it
probably to fully Master Lemon G
consistently uh especially on a bigger
scale you know took me probably a solid
four or five years uh you know and that
was at the beginning when I started
growing too so nowadays it probably it's
not as difficult but
uh it's a finicky plan it's not
something that you can throw in with a
bunch of other plants and expect it to
you know do well you got to kind of like
give it its own environment its own
everything like lemon G doesn't like a
lot of light it doesn't like a lot of
heat like cannabis plants in general
don't but lemon G especially
um I raise my lights up to do crops and
it flourishes under you know 25 watts
per square foot like really really low
lighting
um that's half of what suggested I
believe they suggest what 50 60 watts
per square foot yeah so and that's what
I've been running for most of my life
honestly
um it's it's I I like that I get good
quality off of it and it keeps the heat
down because I don't have to have a
bunch of Lights packed in somewhere you
know
but I also think it keeps the Terps
um a lot of times one you know you you
do two hotter lights on the top foot
foot and a half of your plant might look
gorgeous but it might have some of the
Terps burned out by the intensity and
like actually the bottoms tend to smell
and taste better so you can get away
with less light more of the plant brings
out some of that subtlety I guess
and in my area we've always I should
mention we've always had low ceilings
the houses at low basement ceilings in
the houses around so uh you've actually
seen before so uh I was kind of a lot of
people around here use 600 Waters and
that's what I've used pretty much since
I started I've used thousands before but
ninety percent of what I've done is all
been 600 watt lights so
yeah well Amsterdam had the same thing
when I first started going there they
were all four and six hundreds they
thought a thousand Watts were crazy
American stuff yeah
so now that we're on to Lemon G let's
talk a little bit one about the genetics
of lemon G
um the history of lemon G and the
terpene profile limited because that's
really like I think I mean what most
people find really exceptional about
lemon juice that flavor smell all that
goodness
um my first introduction to it was uh on
the forums you know there was there was
some speculation about it being skunk
Misty something you know there's some
speculation G13 hash plant you know
expression what have you found out
well there yeah there's you know I've
been told a lot of things over the years
I've been married to a lot of theories
different theories over the years a
couple at least yeah
um
and you know
a lot of a lot of what you read is not
the case uh some people are close you
know
um but I was able to get the story from
a friend of mine who worked for the lady
who made it I'm not going to mention her
name sure
um but she is local to you know the
state that I'm in and uh and she told
him that it was uh then it was I'm sorry
skunk Misty uh crossed with uh some g13.
now the June the G13 this this lady got
as seeds from I believe from a friend I
don't think she ordered them yeah uh I
don't know what they are I have no idea
um G13 skunk G13 hash plant G13 nl2 how
many G13 crosses was there you know yeah
yeah who knows uh but that's uh you know
and this is a good buddy this is uh my
my my really good buddy who
he wouldn't [ __ ] me or anything like
that so uh that's what she says that's
from her mouth that's I guess what she's
always said so just to kind of clear
that up that's where the stories add on
the lemon Chi as far as what it is
um
I don't know exactly what year uh it was
made I would assume it was probably
somewhere in like the early 2000s yeah
uh that's kind of like what I feel but
I've never really gotten an exact date
on it so and the terp profile how would
you best describe the flavor of G3 or
lemon G sorry
lemon juice lemon G lemon G is very very
lemony
um yeah not hardly I mean no no Turf in
a lean or anything like that really do
you notice any Matt no okay because I
can't pick it up if there is any uh
lemon
and uh lemon rind and lemon
it leans lemon astringent yes you know
like it doesn't have a lot of sweetness
on the back end it has like a very
pungent lemon
let me stop let me stop you sir when you
grow it like crap it gets that very it's
that very like Randy bitter almost smell
but if you if you grow that plant good
it comes out it's like sweet sugar candy
lemon G ooh I'm telling you there's it's
a finicky plant and most people get rid
of it because they can't they can't get
it to perform right they just get that
like basic version of it like Frank like
uh he was just yeah yeah so yeah just
get that basic version
and um and they have a hard time with it
but like I said it took me several of
your faces as we both realized oh we
only ever grew it like [ __ ] no but I
mean
I I have a thing with Citrus where like
you know there's there's a range there
from like spraying mouth like cleaner
into your mouth to like a little like I
tend to like the sweet back end because
it balances the astringent you know
um and it's one of those things where
for me like I love Citrus but I have to
have other things need other things I
can't have citrus be my only weed yeah
you know when I described lemon G I
always tell people it's like a lemon
came into a being formed like a human
form and then pissed lemon into your
mouth
that's about how I can describe lemon G
it's just so lemon I it's it's very
unique to me uh I've I've seen a lot of
plants and I was lucky to get that
planter I was so lucky to get that plant
earlier yeah I mean that I can't believe
it but it's so it's still to this day
it's so unique there's nothing that I've
ever seen really that smells like lemon
G like lemon G does that didn't come
from lemon juice
like when you pull lemon G out and you
give it to somebody that's never smelled
it before I don't care who you are your
eyes are lighting up like you're like
what is this you know
um it just blows you away and it's a
good Buzz uh indoor it's it's decent
outdoor that plant is magical I love the
buzz of that stuff outside and I will
only smoke lemon G if it's grown outside
oh wow um it's just so much better in my
opinion um but I I grew it indoor most
of my life and it's still good don't get
me wrong it's still good it's a it's a
light Buzz it's happy yeah it's 100
percent it's all my female customers
over the years require it's the number
one requested for some reason the ladies
absolutely love it it keeps it gives
them energy they clean on it you know
and all that stuff
so um
so yeah it's been it's been pretty you
know pretty popular with the females as
well have you um have you tried lemon
tree or lemonade yet
uh I haven't I've heard lemon tree
smells a lot like lemon G but I tend to
think that they're related some ways to
me it's it has to be a lemon tree it has
to be yeah in my opinion
yeah uh another thing I wanted to
mention is my buddy mentioned that he
had smoked uh my same good buddy again
he smoked um uh the G13 what was it it
was a G13 skunk uh back in the day and
he said that's the closest thing he's
ever spelled to Lemon G it was like very
spot on but it was just kind of mild so
I thought that was a kind of interesting
you know thing and then I know a lot of
people are going to ask about what's the
skunk Misty as well yeah and honestly
um I haven't I I wish I could tell you
it's probably uh they had a string
called Misty back in the day it didn't
they Nirvana or something Nirvana
Nirvana seeds not to be confused with
your people always confused Nirvana with
Gypsy Nirvana whenever I say oh yeah so
no Nirvana seats had a Misti and I can't
remember off the top of my head I can't
remember what it was NL something
and so basically everything in Amsterdam
then that wasn't from Neville or a few
other breeders almost everything was was
something by Skunk one
pretty much you know so having something
that was Misty by Skunk one in the 90s
that was the most common hybrid in
Amsterdam was something by Skunk one
right because skunk one was just
consistent you know and I actually can
kind of like that the G13 straight cut
that you had pip
um I can kind of see skunk and G13 in
that lemon G
yeah oh yeah
um I mean lemon G is kind of like it's
kind of got that uh this is this is like
people don't take this the wrong way but
it kind of has that like ugliness to it
you know there was an ERA where like we
didn't have to be pretty
you know and lemon G definitely has kind
of that like G13 like weird Bud
formation Leaf formation especially look
you know and then you know from skunk
one some kind of citrus coming through
is pretty common
so I can see you know it's it probably
the skunk one probably took the G13 from
being leafy in a mess and made it gave
it that nice running Cola that probably
made it such a good Cropper for you for
a long time right you know
and uh
yeah I I saw you know the lemon G for
the longest time or let me start by
saying actually first uh there's a G13
clone that's gone around this area for a
long time since I was in school still my
parents my friend's parents grew it and
my other friend's parents grew it and um
eventually I got it and that thing is I
thought for sure that is what was used
for lemon G because you could smell
that in the lemon G like it's obvious
you could smell that plant and the lemon
G it's like okay these both came from
the same state you know they smell
related they're probably related so I
just always figured that's kind of what
it was
but um and I don't know what that it's a
what that G13 plant I don't know if it's
an Airborne G13 cut from the forums or
whatever I'm not sure it's just a short
little stubby Afghan
um
it's not really like it's nothing really
a lot of people would prefer to smoke or
grow these days I feel yeah it's more
like your head stash unique old-school
Afghani type of type of stuff but like a
little soapy a little like it's been a
while since I smelled it I lost it you
know when I went through that whole
dudding scenario unfortunately
um I
it's just one I've never been able to
get back I've been looking several times
right like people have given you stuff
back and it turned out not to be it
uh I mean I think maybe once with the G
but okay the G is pretty easy to spot
like if you get a clone of that and it
veggies up a little even a little bit
you know you might even be able to tell
from clone like it's a really unique
plant oh wow um short squat little
Afghani but we can talk about that in a
little bit if you want yeah okay I used
to talk about it and when we were
looking he would send me pics and we
would always kind of like Wonder is it
like is it Airborne is it Pacific is it
something more ancient than that that
like survived where he's at and I will
say that like if you look at some of the
Neville's few picks that he put up of
the classic G13 clone
it kind of had that like gnarly ancient
Afghani ugly look to it I thought it
looked very similar for lack of a better
turn that's not distant you know there's
plenty of weed that I think is kind of
ugly that I actually love to smoke chem
91 the ugliest plant ever it's not the
ugliest plant ever but on Earth
no there is definitely some Haze that I
find that I find attractive that is way
more hideous
you know you're like oh this thing
doesn't have any Crystal it doesn't have
any sugar Leaf it's loose it's calyx's
it's [ __ ] you know and then
uh yeah I curse but we're in the middle
of it
all right you're good we're after a
minute in
but maybe so that we we chatted about
the lemon G for a second why don't we
chat yeah the other thing you got early
that you really love which is the Death
Star oh yeah which is a classic it has a
great name and it's been consistently
one of your favorites basically from now
to then it really hasn't shifted
yeah
yeah the Death Star is my All-Star I've
loved that plant since the day I got it
the day I smoked it I was so happy the
day I got it
um you know I only had probably at that
point like 10 or 12 plants in my
collection and it just completely
kicked them all out of the water you
know I I like that that hardcore like
potency like knock you down put you into
the couch type of stuff and uh and
that's the effects you get off the Death
Star but you know you also get the super
crazy like oniony tennis ball like
rubber gas like skunk like nastiness
everything's there and you grow a killer
people don't understand like I've had
shitty Death Star like where it's grown
to where there's not very much burnt
rubber at all where it's more of that
oniony spicy back end and it's not very
good but then I've had your death star
where it just kicks its ass so when he's
describing this if if if it smells
different than what he's describing it
because he's grown it very very very
well for a very long time so go ahead
continue please on the history of Death
Star okay
um I I guess where do I start I guess
I'll start at uh Team Death Star right
yeah yeah
um they're from Ohio Columbus area
and they are the people that created the
Death Star the Death Star is a cross of
uh Scentsy star and
um Sour Diesel
and they it was an accidental
pollination I guess
um and they had a couple seeds and they
sprouted them and they picked the Death
Star and one of those few seeds that
they sprouted
was this amazing plant
um
and I was so lucky I was so lucky to get
it in the mid-2000s at the time when I
had you know only been growing for for
five years or something like that and I
was just so
intrigued by this plant and how potent
it was and how much yield it put out so
I just started putting it in all my
rooms basically that I had that I had
flowering and I just started growing and
growing it growing it and it I mean
there's people at my door with
pitchforks you know three weeks before
Harvest like where's it we need it we
need it it was it was scary it just it
just it flew off the shelves yeah
um and I enjoyed I was smoking it all
the time
I bet uh but yeah so that it came from
uh from them they got uh
the the sour diesel cut they got I think
came from fish show in Vermont
back in like uh I forget the date it was
like 2004 I think fish did like a
farewell show at a airport in Vermont
and um and they picked up I don't know
if they picked it up in Vermont or if
they picked it up back along the way
from Vermont to Ohio but along that trip
is when they acquired that and then um
from what I've heard of another friend
of theirs went to Amsterdam and got
seeds and came back and um I guess they
were grown and a selection was made and
that was given to team death star by a
friend of theirs and then that's how the
cross got the Death Star got made okay
one of the things maybe I should mention
because it's like a long-term running
joke but it ties into what Matt and pip
were just discussing is that um
you know it it takes probably a good 84
days right uh you know I mean that's
that's about that's that's what I push
it to like you can pull it at 77 days I
mean a lot of people told it 70 days
that's where a lot a lot of people make
that's the point I'm gonna make is that
one of the differences and one of the
reasons why it might be so good from pip
versus other people is that you know he
was willing to actually see like how
long does this thing need to go before
it hits Perfection and what happens like
and this used to happen with sour diesel
a lot in California is that there's
people that would grow it until it hit
the sweet spot and there's people that
would grow it until it hit good enough
for Market
and there's a vast difference that like
say you might be able to cut off like he
was just saying if you cut that star at
70 it might fly out the door but not be
as nice
and pip would take it an extra two weeks
and it would reach this extra level
and I think the same thing would happen
with sour out west it would happen with
some other Cuts where it was like there
was croppers where like as soon as it
had the nose and was good enough to go
it's time to cut it yeah because there's
a lot of people that don't like taking
anything over nine or ten weeks
you know and sometimes not with
everything sometimes you go downhill but
with some things if you give it that
extra week or two
um it makes a huge difference
you know it lets the potency and the
flavor and some of the depth come out
um and uh you know so I think when Matt
was talking about all this Death Star
sucks there was probably a lot of death
star that was cut at 10 that needed to
go 12. I'm sure there was a lot cut at
seven and it needed to go 12 too earlier
you cut it you know the the less nuance
and depth it'll have
so yeah
uh one thing else I wanted to add too is
when this accidental cross happened I
believe it actually pollinated some
other plants as well they had uh the
Indiana bubble gum which was a clone I
had at this time as well it was popular
around here uh and they had the dumpster
which is a popular one from you know
back in the day around here and I think
those were both pollinated uh because
when I was at you know the Festival
Nelson Ledges in you know the mid-2000s
I was seeing these strains called Bubble
star and dump star yeah I think there
was maybe one or two more that I can't
recall right now but I definitely
remember seeing a lot of the bubble star
um I remember the Death Star was a
little bit difficult to get and I think
the Scentsy star was a little bit
difficult to get as well I don't think
it was just like lots of it you know
yeah kind of like
you mentioned dumpster Yeah you
mentioned dumpster Ohioans are going to
want to hear about dumpster can you rep
Ohio's dumpster for us what the hell is
dumpster does it smell like a dumpster
was it really found in a dumpster
what's the story bro oh that's
I haven't heard it from the horse's
mouth I've heard a lot of things over
the year and it's it's all generally
lines up you know things get left out
over the years things get added I guess
so take it whatever I say as is but
supposedly it was uh there was a couple
of guys growing together one of them was
known as the professor okay and I was
told that they basically had a falling
out and they were they were growing this
plant and then they had a falling out
and they threw this whole room away into
a chat the one guy threw the whole room
away into a trash can or something and
then the other guy went back and got the
cut that they were growing out of the
dumpster and called it dumpster all
right yeah so I mean that's that's just
what I've heard I'm not 100 yeah I know
there's more details um I do have some
connections I can get more details on
that from but uh you know I think
what did I what did I say it it kind of
It kind of reminds me of like the
there's a garlic Bud pick and have you
ever seen that what is it 1989 yep yeah
it's the seed bank right it kind of
reminds me a lot of dumpster it's really
it's it's almost dead on that leaf and
everything it just looks you know just
like it yeah uh so I've heard people say
it's you know Shiva skunk you know nl5
skunk one
um I mean there was a lot of that sold
so yeah I mean definitely possible I
mean the other interesting part just
real quick before we get up on that
tangent is that at the seed bank Neville
called this line garlic bud and then
when it and then when Scentsy seeds sold
the same line when they bought his
company they called it Shiva Shanti
right you know
um and so there could be some truth to
both it could you know pip and I have
chatted about it does very much look
like sort of an old NL skunk type hybrid
of some kind
you know what does it smell like what's
the chirp profile uh I I classify it as
like it's like a a sweet pineapple with
like that toe jam Funk there's like a
funk in it too you know uh that's kind
of that's kind of like where I lie with
it it's it's uh it's good smoke it's
decent it's it's I mean to be honest
it's just average smoke it's a
commercial just typical like a
commercial type variety a lot of people
did a lot of grows of dumpster in Ohio
over the years and oh yeah because it
yields like crazy but um it does get big
buds it's a little bit prone to mold you
gotta watch out
um
but overall it's I mean it's a staple in
Ohio it's been around for 20 years or
whatever now so
there was a there was a fake one that
went around Ohio I think Jason mentioned
it in his books it was called chumster
with a CA with a CH trumpster yeah uh I
personally never saw that one but I just
figured I would mention it
uh and it was mostly run in Toledo back
in the day I believe at first and that's
like we're like the professor and all
that stuff was but I've also heard
people say that there was a guy in
Columbus uh and that's where this whole
situation happened as well so I'm just
not 100 sure but that's kind of where
I'm at uh with the dumpster cool yep how
about the um Afghani mango I know that's
another older classic
oh man The Afghani mango Afghan Diego
yep I got that uh I got that around
again around mid-2000s uh from my buddy
uh it was one of his favorite ones and I
remember going over to his house one day
he was living up in Akron
and I walk in and I smell the smell I'm
like man that smells I mean that is
really unique what are you smoking he's
like I'm smoking Afghan mango and he was
smoking it out of his Volcano Vaporizer
oh nice so he gave me some Puffs and I
smoked it and the flavor was
unbelievable it was just like this like
soft mango a little bit of a sweet for
sure a little bit of like metallic smell
in there as well I feel like yeah it was
just super interesting and then he you
know brought me upstairs and showed me
like two or three lights in an upstairs
bedroom
a little window AC or something and a
fan
and he had uh he had it growing up there
and it was just such a unique looking
plant I I mean I'd really never seen
anything like it up until this point I
was growing a lot of like kind of more
like Indica dominant stuff whereas The
Afghani mango is definitely a little bit
more sativa it makes these long Spears
that kind of like aren't thick but they
fill in they're just like long Spears
and uh and I ran it for ran it for quite
a while but it could be finicky uh it
does this weird thing it'll stunt out
sometimes uh like kind of like fail to
start
um
and then it also if if the conditions
aren't perfect it can tend to like harm
a lot or like if one plant in the room
is like buy the fan constantly getting
beat up the whole time like it can hurt
so I never really did large runs of it
it's been a commercial Ohio strain for a
long time lots of people have done big
big runs of uh Afghan mango and pass it
around the state over the years and
stuff but it's just a it's a super
unique one
um I don't know exactly what it is I've
I've you know I've seen uh Angel's
breath and like I've told you before
Matt by Mr Nice and Angel heart and that
and it kind of looks very similar to
that but um I know you've mentioned to
me that those are relatively recent
releases within the past 10 11 years
yeah and I've had the Afghan mango for
you know for longer than that obviously
so yeah yeah I guess that would you know
that would kind of nullify it but I
don't know 100 super unique plant it's
been around Ohio for a long time
KC 33 maybe always an option
um KC mango I'm not sure oh yeah the the
Casey brains stuff yeah you know that's
older and I mean it was it was grown a
lot because it was one of the more
affordable lines but there was great
great stuff in it like amazing stuff in
it a lot of breeders ended up knocking
it off later on too uh BC's BC mangoes
based on that one I'll have to take a
look into that yeah yeah it might be
another Direction yeah I thought I've
talked to a lot of people you know a lot
of local people people in the Wii game
over the years and I always ask about
Afghan mango because it's one of the
ones that I have the least information
about yeah I don't know who made it I
don't know if they made it if they
bought seeds of it from a company when
it came around
um it's definitely you know early to mid
2000s areas where I would put it put
that one we've got to ask Konza where he
sourced his seeds
see if he has any kind of
anything on it
you're here to talk to him about it
no yeah I haven't either ask him no
okay so we go from
we haven't done four-way have we
uh I don't believe we have let's hit
four-way all right
the uh the four-way
I had I had originally gotten a plant
back in before I don't know the exact
date 2014 15 16 somewhere around there
probably
uh I had gotten a plant from
a friend of a friend and it was called
uh Scentsy star
and I grew it and I realized I had
smoked this before you know but I
couldn't it's been so long I couldn't
tell you know like is this a Scentsy
star I smoked or you know so so I had
grown it for years and I had liked it
and I after growing it a couple times I
really noticed a lot of similarities to
the Death Star because I think they're
on Death Star forever yeah uh it kind of
has that like little zigzag uh structure
it does and some of the Aromas in it as
well kind of uh kind of are very similar
so you know I actually thought for a
long time that it actually was the the
plant that was used uh to make dust on
our pot sure absolutely
but uh recently I found you know I was
wrong
um Death Star I've grown test RS ones
and I've definitely seen the S1 tragedy
and it's pretty pretty clear now that
they are uh you know Scentsy stardom in
it uh
so
um I feel like it's related the the
four-way my cut what you know is related
somehow whether it's part of Scentsy
star or a component of it was used to
make Sensei star or something like that
you know yeah uh so that's kind of like
that's kind of where I
where I'm at now with with that I I grew
that Scentsy star for years and then
eventually along the way I had gotten
plants under different names
um such as it's if they were the same
plant as my Scentsy star I got it under
the name of death star from some people
I got it under the name of four-way from
the guy I got it under the name of you
know all this different stuff and every
time over the years I throw it out I'm
like oh my gosh it's the same plan again
like why this is the one that you kept
getting back it's different oh my gosh
it was it was crazy
so you know fast forward several years
after that a couple years ago I I was
looking I reached out to a friend of her
of a friend who had a friend
um who said that they had the Ohio
four-way clone that used to go around
so I I get in contact with him I go over
to his house and he's a super cool guy a
little bit older and he shows me a jar
of the flower and
and I kind of like you know saw the
resemblance I was like almost like this
is that same plan again but I wasn't
sure and then he took me downstairs into
his little Hut and he had like a light
with like you know three or four plants
and they weren't in the best shape they
had some thrips on them and stuff uh but
it just wasn't the best representation
so I wasn't 100 sure yet yeah so um so
anyway he you know he gave me the cut
and I brought him some stuff too because
he's from a small circle he doesn't have
access to a bunch of stuff so sure I
gave him some cool stuff to grow and I
went and you know grew this thing out
and uh when we were talking and smoking
is flour when I met up with him he told
me that he's had it for 20 years and
that one of his buddies was the guy that
bought the seeds and made the selection
back in the day wow yeah and he
originally said uh you know the guy that
I met uh that I got the cut from said
that it was from Scentsy seeds but I had
him actually contact his buddy the guy
who you know and he confirmed that he
said he got him from Nirvana oh
interesting yeah so yeah
um so you know
Nirvana's description is slightly
different from Scentsy seeds but you
know they did a lot of work with other
people's lines back in the day so it
wouldn't be surprising to me if it was
more than likely to sensei's work that
they were using that's probably the most
you know
you know and Nirvana was probably I
probably would have bought Nirvana's
over scentsies during you know during
those Early Air that early era because
Nirvana's was always like 90 whereas
since these was like 240 you know is it
right yeah
Nirvana verifiably took various lines
from Scentsy
um and reprode them and made and gave
them their own names I mean they
famously took Neville's nl2 and called
it Oasis that's the fashion oh that's
Dutch Passion yeah I mean it was it was
very common yeah
um and all that and then one thing we
probably should mention about the about
the Scentsy star itself is that even
though it came out in 1995
uh we still don't know what the heck it
is
right yeah
he's he's been extremely uh reluctant to
mention any parentage uh as far as uh
the guy who owns paradise and you know
what else I found interesting was in 95
Scentsy seeds um re-released the
four-way uh I don't know what they mean
by that uh but in 1995 they did and then
a year after in 96 I believe was when
Paradise started and released the
Scentsy Star right yeah I believe so
that's what was actually released pretty
pretty close together so yeah I don't
know I mean can't prove anything but you
know it's just uh like I said it's
possible that uh that four-way was used
or that one of the components that make
up four-way was possibly used you know
and that's coming through expressing
yeah was was Afghan T in four way it
took a long time for us to figure out
and then it was one of those things that
was hiding in plain sight where uh
Neville wrote in his 87 update to his
catalog that he was about to release
this strain called four-way and it was
Big Bud nl1 by early Pearl skunk one
that's right it was original yeah and um
and so it was another one of those
things that like pip and I and others we
hunted and hunted and hunted forever
looking for any information on what what
actually the makeup was
um and then it was one of those things
that was just like hiding in plain sight
if you knew where to look
um and so it was honestly one of those
like the 90s was a lot of f1s but that
was an early poly hybrid
um you know because I believe
uh I believe Neville released both of
those plants that made up four-way as
separate strains big bud nl1 just became
the big bud line and early Pearl skunk
one I believe got released as Early
Skunk
you know so it was already lined he was
playing with separately to begin with
and then he took two of them and
combined them together yeah and there
you go and so obviously as a four-way
hybrid
um it could lean in different directions
um and especially amongst the progeny
and stuff like that but
um yeah so I wanted to clarify uh today
if you go on their website Cincy seeds
labels it as Indian by Afghanistan by
Pakistan by Skunk one I don't know I
don't I don't know when this was
released it's not in any of their 90s
catalogs
um but they did use in 1987 Neville did
the up Senate update for his 87 catalog
right and he said he was gonna you know
have a four-way hybrid the next year he
comes out with four and more and that's
the only year it comes out and then two
years go by 89 and 90 and it's not in
the catalog and then in 91 since he sees
comes along and releases four-way and
they use the same exact description that
Neville used for his foreign
finish time same verbiage in the
description
all that type of stuff so yeah Clues
like that you know um and you know I
mean we don't know like you know there's
all there's some other famous cuts out
there there's the Fairfax four-way that
supposedly was from the same line
um but you know obviously like if you
get a four-way hybrid
um it could lean in a number of
different directions you know right one
thing I wanted to pull on real quick
because I wasn't clear on it when you
were talking about the the the the
bubble Style are and some of that stuff
yeah um was that made with Death Star
pollen or was that made with pollen from
maybe like the East Coast Sour Diesel
that threw on some of those other plants
it was the Scentsy star that threw it
was the Sensei so the Scentsy star was
the was the the dad if you will yes the
Scentsy the Scentsy star threw the
Scentsy star through okay so that's
where that's where bubbles star and some
of those other hybrids you were talking
about that you would see floating around
came from
uh yeah it definitely I feel like it
definitely came from that same
accidental pollination or I don't say
accidental I've heard that they saw that
the Scentsy star was kind of making
pollen and they kind of used it and
sprinkled it is what I've heard as well
who knows what happened but um but yeah
early feminized seed used to be like you
know uh you know you know plant gets
stressed accidental pollen flies and
then all of a sudden you have some
feminized backseat right long before we
figured out STS or any of these other
methods that modern where you're using
in modern times
you know
I don't know Matt's smiling over there
or whatever but
but yeah I mean you know for old people
like me we used to think that that
accidental pollination like if you use
that you were cheating and it would
probably ruin the line because it was
made not the natural way that was a big
belief back in the day it was a big
belief you're like oh you're going to
use some herb accident stuff you're
gonna probably like imprint that into
your seed line and you'll never get it
out and it'll be worse
um so that just goes to show how
ignorant we were at the time we were
convinced that you know that huh yeah
the other day Caleb made a post and I
it drives me nuts absolutely nuts when I
see this but it's the typical what I
call the typical hippie response to like
a feminized seed post is like ha see
like it was it was CSI posting about a a
reversal failure right huh because
because you were you were messing with
nature is what what happened there and
then I had to point out you know the
nature wants these plants intersex it's
because man's intervened that they're
regular seeds so actually actually if
you really want to get technical they're
taking it back and it's just like this
really bad logical argument that they
seem to have in their heads that herming
is us being bad
weed used to be very Bro Science
yeah
there used to be a lot of Bro Science
and what I mean by that is just stuff
that gets passed around in smoking
circles and stuff like that and I mean
I've talked about it on previous shows
where we used to put our best Mexican
butt in the resin chamber so it would
gain equality
Mexican butt in your resin chamber and
you don't smoke that one till the end
and then this butt out and you thought
that was an improvement so there was a
lot of of misinformation in the 90s and
early 2000s when the internet and and
sort of like you know facts it was
basically just a bunch of kids spreading
what they heard from older people maybe
or reading in High Times you know we
used to think High Times was sort of the
Bible
they are now and uh then you get older
and you're like oh man who takes that
advice
but it was a real era in that regard so
you know
um yeah so I mean four-way uh you know
it it ended up being one of your
favorite plants
it did man it's uh it's just you know
super unique super old school you can
tell if you've been growing grown a lot
of plants you can grow it and look at it
and be like yeah that's definitely
not from around this time period you
know
um definitely some like 90s weeds
something like that I wasn't really
growing or smoking in the 80s so I
didn't see a lot of that stuff
but I've seen enough stuff from you know
back in the day to know when something's
a little bit older and you know
different than
would you say that the the four-way the
Ohio four-way is skunky at all yes
that's interesting because that that
Fairfax four-way like the one time when
I got to because it was super dudded
when I got it but um
the one time I got to like get any hint
of smell out of it you could smell like
what direction it was going it's like oh
wow this does have potential to be as
skunky as they've talked about it really
does so I was wondering if the other
it's cut does it's the I don't know the
the four-way that I have is it's not as
skunky as like the Death Star you know
it doesn't it's not like that uh it's
it's milder than the Death Star yeah but
it's got more like other stuff in it you
know it's like that like
I don't know how to that old world likes
those old world smells you know like
kind of stuff like that hashy spicy uh
you know skunky
stuff going on in there yeah definitely
the one the other one was like um had
oniony in it too that was the other
smell that could really smell yeah
definitely but there's some stuff about
that four-way certain things about it
that remind me of stuff you'd see from
afghanista so I always found that
interesting based on what's in it
I don't really see Afghan t in it unless
Afghan teas and skunk wand or something
like that which is something that I'd
always like to dig further into
yeah I mean it it uh it was it was one
of those confusing things for a really
long time because Neville was one of the
only guys that just sort of laid out
what was in his stuff all that second
wave of breeders pretty much
intentionally obscured
uh genetics which for like his people
like us who are a little younger younger
than that and historians trying to
figure out what they used
um even 25 30 years later some of those
people don't want to just come off it
like what would it what would it matter
if Luke came out and you know and said
this is what I used to make Scentsy star
in 1995. yeah I don't know you know like
big secret oh can't let that out you
know like and but to this day it's still
kind of like ah what's it what is it you
know as of this year as recent as this
year he will not say unfortunately I I'd
love to have him on to to talk about it
but yeah we've been getting declined
that's that's been around Robin and you
know it's one of those things where for
a lot of people it's like if it doesn't
benefit me why would I say it and it's
like do I want to say that I like ripped
it off from Neville or I got it from
this other person that I never gave
credit to or whatever the story may or
may not be they'd prefer it to remain a
mystery
because it's not like anyone's going to
go and like find the parents 25 years
later 30 years later and like recreate
it
I mean that ship has sailed while we're
in this territory let's hit my personal
favorite the one like the the the bud
that made me fall in love with pips
grows the silver Pearl let's talk about
that girl where did she come from
um
uh the silver Pearl uh came from a local
guy that actually got a hold of me on IG
I think I met him I think we have a
mutual friend as well
um at the time
and uh I'm not going to say either their
names but sure yeah that's that's who I
received it from uh
preface of saying like our group has had
this clone for a long time back in the
day and I never grew it because I was so
busy tied up with lemon G and death star
like that was my yeah my show that was
my Mo so like I didn't have time for
anything else I already had 10 or 12
plants that was more than enough for me
being a Cropper yeah
uh so I kind of always passed on it I
would smoke it you know my friends would
have it they'd bring it over and they'd
bring it to our little you know cannabis
cups that we had and stuff back in the
day yeah up here in Akron
um but I never really grew it and then
as we got older you know how things go
stuff gets lost it's not in the circle
anymore and uh and I wanted to give it a
riff so you know I was able to get in
touch with this guy and he uh he had
gotten it from an older gentleman who
lived down Southern Ohio I believe
and had it for quite a while and then uh
you know I eventually acquired it from
him you know gave him some stuff some
seeds and I forget what else but uh it
was it and a funny story is like a week
later I got another plant uh that I was
looking for I was looking for that G13
you were talking about earlier and
someone gave it to me and I grew it up
and I knew before I even flowered it it
was silver Pearl so I got silver Pearl
twice in the same week from or basically
different people from different people
yeah
one thing I'll say that's interesting
about that cut is that and not
everything does this but that cut grown
out looks amazingly like some of the
oldest pictures of silver Pearl that you
can find I mean you know you don't want
to use the word dead ringer too much or
anything like that but boy uh visually
does it look like it's it's just you
know just walked out of the catalog and
into your collection it really does it
looks like if you were to look at at
hips silver Pearl cut and you were to
look at some of those old pictures of
silver Pearl and you didn't know which
was which you'd have a hard time telling
the difference in some ways uh it really
looks it really it really does resemble
so that's not proof or anything like
that but it certainly helps right right
uh you know silver Pearl is just such a
special plant
um it's not like a narcotic hitter like
I I prefer uh I respect all cannabis
regardless of whether I enjoy it or not
you know I gave it all a chance I enjoy
all the different different aspects of
it even if I'm not smoke again you know
yeah but but the silver Pearl really
grew on me uh when I first smoked it I
was kind of I don't know off put by it
because I wanted something you know hard
hitting but after after smoking it for a
while I'm giving it a chance and seeing
what it's really about
uh you know smoking it fresh when you
wake up in the morning uh you know
nothing in your system you're fresh uh
it's just I mean it's amazing it's
really just really uplifting motivating
happy you know bright Buzz uh on a you
know it's very more like a city it's
almost like what you think of like a
sativa right but on a plant with this
short and squat and finishes in you know
50 days yeah yeah so it's I call the
high electric maybe not not in the sense
that it's um like giving you a rush but
it's bright and happy to me very bright
and happy is the best way I could
describe it in the in the the scent
profile like me and not so describe it
completely opposite and and it's really
just two different takes on it but it's
because of how complex it is how would
you describe it
oh uh I have a description I wrote of it
somewhere I'll try to remember some but
it's the basic smells are it's it's like
a uh it's kind of like a sweet melon
it's got a little bit of baby poo in
there like that funk it's got the like
the funky Funk flip funk I guess a
little bit type thing it's got uh some
like anise like almost like a black
licorice type you know thing
[Laughter]
yeah I know like yeah I see for me when
I smell it I smell like
pink bubble gum is the first smell I
smell and oh yeah D just grew it outdoor
and I smelled it and I smelled it again
and the first smell I smell is pink
bubble gum but then there's like funky
skunk background but not white it's just
yeah it's got so much going on Matt that
confuses a lot of people a lot of people
have a hard time really like nailing it
uh because there's just so much there's
so much to it it's not like some of
these there's just so many different I
mean you can sit there and smell it for
10 minutes straight and and pick out all
the different it's uh it's just really
really unique really awesome you know
short flowering Indica like I said 50
days not the biggest yield or in the
world uh you gotta defoliate it it's a
little bit you know like leafy throws
fan leaves everywhere big fat indica and
but it's gotta be great yeah got a great
structure and you don't even have to I
don't think I've ever netted or staked a
silver Pearl plant in my life regardless
of how big it's been I mean I grew up
into like five gallons I don't go bigger
than that but you know they it just so
they support themselves like you don't
even have to mess with them at all so
good outdoor stuff uh one of the things
that's interesting about it is that
because pip mentioned it is that when he
says baby poo I also get a strong baby
poo smell off it but just to clarify
like it smells to me like infant baby
poo like when all their all they're on
is Mother's Milk like they haven't
gotten any kind of real food like
because I I have a number of kids or
whatever so like you know you familiar
with that Raider but there's a very
different smell to baby poo when they're
one two three four months old whatever
and all they're eating is Mommy's milk
right then when they get actual real
food so it doesn't smell like some kind
of like gnarly kid poop it smells like
this weird it's almost like one of those
things to me where like if it wasn't in
cannabis you would guarantee say it
doesn't smell good
but there's like smells in cannabis that
smell weird but you like them but
they're in weed and it's kind of caught
that skunky sweet sickly baby poo and it
doesn't sound maybe that doesn't sound
too appetizing but it really is
no I think it's a beautiful smell there
is in the progeny
um there is a little bit of mint and I
can smell a slight hint of it in the mom
but I got some nice uh nice selections I
made that are like extremely like super
minty you know wow it was uh it really
you know threw me off guard surprised me
I also think it smells like a little bit
some of them like like a Melanie a melon
kind of you know uh it's just I mean
it's got a lot going on man so what
silver Pro is supposed to be according
to Neville is nl5 uh female the famous
clone crossed with uh early Pearl skunk
one male right and that is silver Pearl
I mean I go ahead go ahead and one of
the things since we were just talking
about four-way I don't have any proof
um I don't know how many different males
Neville decided to use of early Pearl
skunk one
but it's somewhat possible that it could
have the same dad as four-way it I mean
anything's possible man you know because
it's like it it's the same mix from the
same guy yeah it's you know the dad is
early Pearl skunk one in both the
hybrids is it a different male but it's
definitely the same line you know
and that early Pearl is uh Early Girl
across with Pollyanna yeah um
and that that's you know that's what you
know they used to cross I thought it was
the nl5 nl5 skunk one male I had it
written down like that because I wasn't
able to find exactly
what it is yeah but it's the same we
have it's the same kind of strain base
coming out
yeah specifically it's the nl5 by by
early Pearl skunk one
you know so it's a three-way hybrid uh
silver Pearl and what's interesting is
since Matt and I have been kind of doing
a deep dive on some of the Early Girl
early Pearl stuff is you don't really
realize it but secretly it was one of
the most common things Neville used
throughout his lines
he loved it he loved that early Pearl he
loved he loved mixing it into different
stuff and so it's it doesn't really get
talked about that much but it was one of
his favorites
and where did the early girl come from
Northern California Northern California
yeah and Pollyanna was huh we just
recently found out
um that one of them one of them I can't
remember if it's early girl or Pollyanna
I think it was Pollyanna
maybe it was early girl one of them is
not from Rob or Sam and I always thought
both were from Rob Rob yeah no that's
the there's a lot of assumptions so
early girl I believe is a is an Afghan
Mexican
and then they took that and they crossed
that to Pollyanna which is an early
Colombian by Mexican and that's early
Pearl
um and we also learned that that
sweetness uh is very was very prevalent
in the early Pearl and it was one of
Neville's favorite things and he wanted
to recreate it really badly later in his
life because he
really enjoyed sort of that double
Mexican Afghan blend that was early
Pearl and that's why it showed up in so
many different hybrids he had
and later in the night later in life he
was working a specific oaxacan line I
don't remember where he sourced it from
specifically it was later but um he felt
that that was very similar to what he
saw in the early Pearl if I remember
correctly and this is there's a there's
a gentleman that that Matt and I chat
with on IG
um and he his family used to grow early
Pearl in the 90s for about five years uh
up in my neck of the woods and he's been
kind of on the hunt to find he got lost
in a bus sadly but he did say pip he he
sent me not knowing that we're buddies
he sent me this pic you had posted a
number of years ago of an early of a
silver Pearl S1
and he goes man does this look like my
parents plant
oh boy he did he did you know so uh take
that for what it's worth but he go but
there was uh yeah he showed me this
picture and it's from you you know and
he's like this one really looks like my
parents old cut of early Pearl so who
knows you know yeah you never know I
mean it's it's it's it's pretty unique
plant once you've been around it and
you've seen some privacy you could kind
of tell
um you know what's related if it's
related or not so I have no doubt that
you know that's what he had and he
thought that mine looked like his
and it's also one of the rare things
that pip doesn't take 84 days it doesn't
take 84 days it's done before most of my
plants are even halfway done flowering
yeah it's so 50 55 or something like
that it's like I mean you could pull it
before 50 if you wanted to it's just uh
it's it's so quick I feel like I throw
it in the flower room and feed it for
two weeks and then you know so it's like
it's basically like a true seven weeker
yeah oh man it's super quick yeah super
quick
I mean some of them go into the 50s you
know 55 days or whatever but some of the
progeny was done in 46 47 days you could
probably pull it 45 if you lived in 1990
like they always like yeah yeah you know
you see these seed descriptions and
flowering times and you're like oh it's
done in you know 60 days and really
Freedom 35 bro
what was the flowering time on Super
Skunk I remember being a kid 49 49 you
know just getting started on indoor and
seeing those 50-day strains and being
like I could get eight crops a year yeah
yeah
it was super enticing you know you're
just thinking oh my gosh
uh I didn't realize that it was a bit it
was a bit of marketing back then
claiming everything took six or seven
weeks but
um you know it was and then I realized
how rare it was to find something that
developed that quickly that I actually
liked right so um so we got through uh
the
Ode to Neville let's get to q36
oh boy excuse me
q36 is a wild one
um again I don't have an exact date but
it's somewhere like 2010 11. ish 2009 to
2011. somewhere in there I would
probably put it uh so it's relatively
kind of like new kid on the block out
here uh for Ohio
and it's uh when I first got it it was
in like 28
2013 14. I don't know I'd have to look
but
it uh it when I first got that thing I
couldn't believe it I was looking at the
leaves on the thing it looked like it
was like came out of the Jurassic period
or something you know dinosaurs walking
around so I mean super weird uh super
dark Afghani like super unique Leaf
shape and um so I've you know vegged it
up and I flowered it out and it's
definitely I could tell immediately it
was definitely related to Bubba but it's
not like anything that I've seen crossed
with Bubba before I don't they say the
lineage is it's basically Bubba Kush
cross with Hawaiian indica and there was
there was some work done
um in that line they they had spread
that line together a second time the f2s
or the bx2s or whatever they did uh they
had a plant called the nuke that went
around for a while
and it was decent
um but eventually that kind of got
thrown to the side once they used the
nuke to make the Next Generation that
you know
the q36 came from ultimately yeah and
that thing just blew everything out of
the water so that nuke everybody kind of
like threw that to the Wayside and just
focused on the q36 so it's like a Bubba
like a Bubba Kush but it's like cream
like super creamy Bubba yeah it doesn't
it doesn't have like typical Bubba
leaves it's got these short little like
like uh uh almost like uh like Clover or
I don't know how to describe it they're
they're very they're just very unique I
have pictures on my Instagram page if
you want to look
um the the resident put it just pumps
out resin it I mean almost looks like a
like a like one of these hype strains
that you see now it's just so Caked Up
in resin yeah um the smaller plants
don't tend to yield too well but when I
put them in like three gallons or five
gallons and got them nice and vegged up
they do pretty good yielding it smells
like creamy Bubba and anise like that uh
again like a black licorice type like
thing in there as well yeah and it's uh
it's a low it's a low tester it tests at
like 15 I think my buddies some people
have had it tested a little bit higher
but generally test below 20 but it is
very just like Bubba very medical very
good a good effect it's definitely
smokes like it's over 20 percent uh the
flavor is phenomenal like I said creamy
Bubba
um like if you're a Bubba lover like
this one is the this is the ultimate
it's like Primo Bubba yeah oh dude I
mean it is
pip has shared it in our little tight
circle of friends and I would say almost
universally
um everyone regards it almost as an
improved Bubba yeah you know like better
maybe even maybe even better than Bubba
would be a way to describe it like you
know like everything they like about
Bubba and more right that's exactly yeah
that's how I would say and more
um
Bubba kinda if you don't hit it right it
doesn't really turn out well it doesn't
yield well it's a little bit leafy and
it can come out a little bit like soapy
sometimes I feel like so
uh this plant there's none of that you
don't I mean even if you run it bad it's
not coming out soapy it's not coming out
crappy like it's still gonna do good so
it's definitely like an improvement I
mean I wouldn't call it above like above
a cut right but it's uh it's definitely
like a newer age version of like Bubba
Kush that's the fire yeah uh improved
improved version of the Bubba so
the only reason why I say that is
because most people that really love to
grow Bubba for their head end up growing
q36 for their head
and being totally happy with that plant
and not having to grow Bubba for their
head because they get everything they
like about Bubba right and and a little
bit more from it so it's just pretty
High Praise really and just to clarify a
lot of people get confused the uh the
eludium is the q36 it's this it's the Q3
eludium q36 space modulator it's the
mark the gun or the Marvin the Martian
used to use on the cartoon
so that's the full name is you know
eludium Q3 36 space modulator there you
go there you go um and what was it um
there was a weird breeding trait that I
had where uh something about seed making
how it makes seeds yeah it doesn't make
seeds I've tried to seed the thing
numerous times and the same thing
happens I get you know 20 maybe if I'm
lucky 30 40 seeds out of each pound uh
30 of them are premature fully like big
seeds but just white and Hollow and um
and then the other ones some are made
mutated and then you sprout what you
have left from that you know whatever 10
or 12 seeds you get out of that
15 maybe and you sprout them and then
summer are are
like mutant like super mutant there's
like maybe 25 30 of them from what I've
seen yeah have been like mutant or runty
or slow you know and then a small
percentage of them though are
are really nice I bet so it's been it's
it's a lot it's a tough pill to swallow
when you try to pollinate a plant and
you gotta rip apart a pound of weed to
get you know 10 or 15 seeds that you can
grow and then only a quarter of those
are going to be something decent and
only a percentage of those are going to
be something amazing yeah by the time
you were done slicing and dicing how
much came out I was thinking to myself
so it gets five seeds he likes I did
cross it to the silver Pearl
and I grew those seeds and I did find an
awesome selection a really really
awesome selection and it kind of made it
worth it for me I posted it on my
Instagram page it says it make seeds
extremely resonance
um yeah
yeah it does so
um it's extremely resinous uh maybe even
more so than the q36 it's just
absolutely caked on there I'll get that
picture over to you as well now yeah
yeah
um
but I I made two selections they're both
very nice one is just super unique it
kind of has the uh I like that that like
black licorice like like anise or I
don't know how you pronounce it but I
like that and stuff and I like it in the
q36 and the the so one of the selections
I made has it's kind of like a lot of
that and less of like the other aspects
it's kind of like focused in onto it and
it's not like the most ideal plant it's
not a huge yield or it's kind of wiry
but it's got good flower and it's got
that flavor and that smell and that
taste that I like so I keep it around
I don't think a lot of people understand
that too when it comes to reversals
um is that uh because there's other
things you've done too like with your
East Coast Sour Diesel cut reversing it
where like it works but it doesn't
really give you enough seed that you can
like even share it with friends it's
almost like you it it gives you 15 or 30
or 40 seeds or something so you can't
even make it happen yeah you can't make
packs of it it's like even difficult to
share with homies because you get so few
and it took so much effort to do
um so there's just certain varieties out
there that for whatever reason don't
don't reverse well or don't take seed
don't take pollination well and it makes
it really hard to make hybrids with them
you know now speaking of hybrid making
let's get into where you're at now where
where you're at currently as of the time
this podcast is gonna air
where I'm at in my seed making yeah
uh well
I am at a uh the point where I've
already made the Rubber City and I did a
rigorous selection process trying to
narrow down what I feel like we're the
best plants out of that run yeah and uh
and I've grown them and cropped them and
just done everything I could to really
like make sure that what I want what I
want to use and uh and then I have uh I
I the one is the Ten the Rubber City
number 10 and the other one is the River
City number four but maybe before you go
any further just talk for a second about
what made the Rubber City okay yeah yeah
that sounds good and we'll go forward
from there yeah the the Rubber City was
the uh Sour Diesel reversed onto the um
Scentsy star at the time but the
four-way yeah now
and that's what uh what I created the
original River City with
so that's then you hunted that a bunch
so I grew out probably
um
right around 50 seeds I can't remember
the exact number I grew out about 50
seeds of it and these are all females
that you're growing female all females
yeah all females so big and they are
they it was just absolutely beautiful I
couldn't have I couldn't have asked for
a better results
um I ended up cloning about half the Run
uh for backups just because everything
was looking so good uh halfway through I
usually take my clones off the flowering
plants you know a small Branch or
something like that just so that they
aren't constantly growing they're just
re-veging in a stasis mode for a while
until everything's finished yeah
um when you keep a lot of moms you kind
of have to right you have to figure out
these little tactics to oh yeah have
things outgrow each other and keep
things in a stasis while being healthy
at the same time yeah right so I um so I
I definitely selected about half of them
and then I did another run immediately
after the sea drone was done just to
double check because uh some people may
not notice this but uh seed plants seed
plants versus clone plants of the same
exact copy of the genetic is can
drastically differ oh yeah you know yeah
um I mean maybe not drastically but they
can differ they're good amount you know
like uh seed plants usually tend to be
more vigorous and yield more and you
know do you guys agree with that oh yeah
and Hermes right right yeah right they
got yeah
uh so I grew out a bunch of those I made
selections of half of them and then I
did about uh probably four maybe five
rounds over the course of like a year
and a half of narrowing it down I would
just grow you know each grow I would
narrow it down from like you know half
of them to 20 to 15 to 10. and like once
I got to like I remember getting to like
eight of them that I had to choose
between it was just like I they were all
so good that they all would have been
good you know I had to like nitpick like
this one this one structures a little
bit floppier than this one but they're
all still still fire you know yeah it's
super good so I just kind of splitting
hairs there you go yep I was splitting
hairs so uh but eventually I had uh I
had narrowed it down after several
different runs to uh the Rubber City
number 10 and the Rubber City number
four go figure I would find two of my
best selections in the first 10 seats
huh yeah right right out of the first I
bought 15 and the number 20 was banging
so everybody knows he resisted the urge
to name it Rubber City 189. he did yeah
his effort to make it seem like that you
know so uh problems on that one yeah I
mean it is what it is I mean I'm not
concerned with the numbers you know I
post pictures people know what I do
people know what I run like and we
actually I remember when you were doing
those selections and like the first
round you're like oh my God guys I don't
even know how I'm gonna cut through
these let alone pick one or two you know
yeah I remember I mean the other part of
it that was funny too was he would pip
would call me and be like so I smoked
two or three examples and I'm now ruined
and I don't think I can judge anymore
for a while because I'm already so baked
I kind of have to chill out before I can
try anymore yeah you know because that's
what happens too like testing a large
number of things sometimes it's like you
can only test two or three a day you
know because you wake up and you try a
few and then all of a sudden your days
changed yeah
yeah it's hard to keep a fresh palette
and a fresh head you know
it's a slow process to do it the right
way you got to do it over the course of
days weeks you know months if you got
enough stuff I guess right so I'll say
one thing and then I'll shut up and let
pip talk but one of the things I think
that's cool that not very many people
out here in breeding do anymore
um but we have some friends that do is
that they make a hybrid like Rubber City
and then they hunt the hybrid and then
they select uh favorites from that and
then they do further work
right a lot of breeding today is sort of
one step one-off one and done you make
it you release it it's there till it's
gone
um and you know uh what we're about to
talk about right now is PIP you know he
made his some of his favorite selections
and then he he you know he used those to
make more things
so let's start off with
um rubber band
the rubber band yeah okay rubber band is
the Rubber City number 10. so all this
stuff on the on the Rubber City drop is
my Rubber City 10 selection uh that I
reversed uh so that would be the Rubber
City 10 cross to uh triangle Kush okay
so I did that I named it rubber band as
it's supposed to be said all is one word
kind of like headband rubber band
headband that's kind of my take on it
you know um Sour Diesel OG Kush the
Rubber City 10 is a is definitely more
of a sour diesel leaning looking type of
plant
um even though I consider it
multiple times better than Sour Diesel
I'll smoke it over Sour Diesel any day
of the week yeah oh yeah
yeah
um so that's that's what the that's what
the rubber band is
um I did a uh I did a couple other ones
um I did the the through chemd in there
everybody loves the chemd and it's
already got those those funky dirty like
you know yeah really really gassy and
skunky type of like smells to it so I
figured that would be a good one to
throw against it and and just produce
some nice yielders and that's called
Dirty Rubber and that's going to be your
that's going to be the dirty rubber yep
I like that name great name yep
[Laughter]
yeah and um we have the the star dog you
use the Corey Haim cut for better than
rubber I did yeah um like I said in the
description it the I've always liked the
star dog that star dog cut it's a high
yielder uh I pulled off some nice runs
with it before it makes big flowers uh
super gassy
um you know JJ did some good work with
really good work with that line I
enjoyed that plant it's a great Cropper
and it's still got gas and uh and it
shares a lot of similar traits with my
Rubber City 10s you know they're not the
same plant by any means uh but they both
are very vigorous growing big they're
that commercial style growth structure
and stretch and Bud that you want you
know like the colas and uh so I just I
figured you know it'd be fun to cross
them together and uh and and see what
kind of craziness comes out of those
things you know yeah and I see you have
um some Rubber City back cross one and
Rubber City back cross yeah let's talk
about those yeah two different versions
of the back crosses I uh I crossed the
uh sour back or the Rubber City 10 to
the uh sour and I also crossed it to the
four-way so you kind of have a choice
you can kind of pick something that
you're gonna want to want to see a
little bit more four-way or you're gonna
see you want something that you're gonna
see a little bit more
um uh sour you know yeah the Gold Coast
hash plant all right Gold Coast hash
plant let's go yeah so the Gold Coast
hash plant
uh is my Rubber City 10 selection across
to death Coast sister so some of you
people are familiar with my death Coast
it makes a lot of really good extracts
uh especially solventless it's popular
artists popular
it's really it's it's really the loudest
[ __ ] I've ever had and there's it
produces Bunches of it so I run it over
my t-shirt screens and save jars of it
and send it to friends for a while
Factor yeah and so that their wives can
scream at them and why the house house
smells like a skunk yep yep
that's for real that's just for Real uh
so uh yeah but anyway the the death
Coast was um out of the um the the BC
one generation I did I crossed um
uh Sour Diesel and death star
and made a selection and uh that was the
popular one at the time but a lot of
people don't know that I made a
secondary selection as well uh which was
definitely a more sour type of uh
looking plant
um and uh you know I enjoyed it it was a
little bit different than death coast
and I've been smoking it for a long time
and uh eventually I started um I was
making death Coast hash and I said oh
I'll make hash with the death Coast
sister too this time and see how it does
because every time I break it up you
know something's hashy when you break it
up for a joint and you see you can just
see it all fall onto the table you've
moved it yeah you move the pile of weed
a little bit and there's there's a line
of hash left you know yeah
just dumps so uh and I've always liked
the plant so anyway it just you know I
broke that thing up and it was it was
dumping big time Big Big Time and I was
just I just the smoke was phenomenal I
was like I gotta do something with this
thing this is this is too good
so I cross it to my River City 10 and uh
when it was seated up
um breaking it up when it was even
because seated plants are you know
notoriously thought to not produce as
much resin right
um
you there yeah yeah okay yeah seated
plants are thought to not really produce
as much resin right well this thing
dumped just as good if not better
seated yeah because it does unseated and
it just I've got the pictures on my Ig
you can see the gloves it's just after
every couple ounces two three ounces
breaking it up with your hands the
gloves are just so caked that they're
falling apart and ripping like you have
to switch your gloves and
it's pretty wild it's pretty wild
stuffed I mean is that what is the death
Coast sister is that what we would call
like internally the SD uh bx7 yes yes
that's Yeah in our group that's the
first the first name on the label the
sour diesel DX number seven plant yeah
yeah not not bx7 but yeah it's number
seven yeah yeah yes yes
yep uh so I've had that one for a while
it's you know probably my pride enjoys
um I only I I the flower is nice a lot
of people request the flower I
personally prefer to smoke the hash over
the flour same with the death Coast
um they're like it's just it just the
flower is good but I love I love my hash
and when I got a plant that dumps like
this you know that's what yeah that's
what I'm using it for and that's kind of
what I created it for is for uh to to be
like a hash plant you know I'm shocked
that this I I don't know why I mean
because you're you're this is one of the
cuts you were real open with about
sharing yeah I don't know why that this
didn't hit the like boom past the hype
market and just shoot to the top because
it jumps like uh for resin production
extracts how loud it is like some people
will smell this as a straight up skunk I
think so people like I smell more burnt
rubber with that back end but to a lot
of people this is going to be one of the
skunkiest things they've ever smelled
and actually I think the skunk comes out
stronger in the hash
definitely yeah that's for sure you know
and I think that happens with the
numbers Amplified yeah uh the skunkiness
is Amplified in hashish yeah it really
it really is it's uh
I love my hash man yeah I'm making cash
too uh what else we got let's see uh
talk about the
um premium rubber yes premium rubber is
one of my pride and joy Creations uh
that is both of my Rubber City
selections
crossed together
um
you still there yeah okay so that's
where so the four and the ten yeah the
four and the ten uh cross together and
those are my two favorite plants that's
all I smoke really uh I I you know I
smoke silver Pearl I smoke I throw a mix
other stuff in but my daily smoke for
the past
four years has been pretty much the
Rubber City 10 or the River City four
the Rubber City number 10 is more of a
high yield like higher yielder than the
four like as far as like bigger buds I
shouldn't say I mean slightly higher
higher yielder but it's bigger buds it's
more along the sour side of the spectrum
but it's still got all the gas and skunk
and onion and rubber it's got all that
stuff in it but um and it's like the
high yield or so it's kind of like the
All-Star so I look at that as like my
commercial the commercial All-Star and
then I have the number four which is
like my head stash All-Star even though
I smoke I'm both the same but the the
head stash one is a little bit less sour
diesel more like uh uh it's got the sour
diesel it's got all the gassiness all
the skunkiness all the everything but
it's got a lot of uh Aromas and potency
from um the four-way cut
so it's got It's very very hashy like it
burns um it when you take a hit off a
bowl and you set the bowl down that bowl
just keeps burning a little trail of
smoke off of it like when you're smoking
hash out of a bowl right yeah uh but
with just the weed it like that's you
know and it tastes like hash and it is
just one of the most potent plants I put
it right there next to the Death Star
you know it's it's it's just uh you know
it might surpass it I I I really it's so
I don't know man it's my favorite plant
that that I've ever made and I've ever
selected and I'll probably have it with
me till I go to my grave yeah yeah I'm
still partial to the Pearl but this
stuff for people looking for like those
volatile sulfur compounds right this is
such a special plant
such a special plant but don't forget
about his pearles ones that he's got
because those are pretty pretty
phenomenal too so I have no doubt uh
people are gonna find some extremely
nice plants and uh not all of this of
course but especially the premium rubber
uh with that four being crossed in there
um you know the sky's the limit I mean
there could be some some serious
unicorns pulled out of that thing yeah I
think uh and um so that's kind of one
that I that I really I really take a lot
of pride in I like that one and then I
have the the last one would be the
Goodyear which is the Rubber City number
10 s ones as well
uh cross to cross to itself and um and
those will be those will be extremely
high yielding they will be more along
the lines of sour but a lot of them are
more uh the Rubber City 10 is more it's
more dense than this hour but it's not
like dense like Indica dense it's just
yeah not as Loose as like sour is and um
and it's easier to grow sour is a
finicky plant uh definitely I mean you
can grow it and get it to come out okay
but to get it to come out 110 like you
really got it you know it's really easy
it's really easy to make Buffy sour too
oh yeah oh yeah I've seen a lot of bad
sour that that was actually sour but
just bad it's easy to screw it up I'm
guilty I've done it before you know
definitely have myself
um but it's just sour is just such a
tough plant and that's kind of one of
the reasons I wanted to do this uh is
just because it's these plants are I
feel like better than sour and and they
are easier to grow than sour they're not
as finicky and sensitive and all that
kinds of stuff and yeah I feel like you
know people say clones lose Vigor over
the years and stuff like that I didn't
have sour diesel in the 90s so I don't
know what it was like back then but uh
today it's still a nice plant and
vigorous and it makes a good yield but
it's got nothing on the on the River
City tent like it's just this the
rubbers like we were talking about how
eludium is like the new Bubba like this
the Rubber City number 10 is basically
like how I look at it it's the new
upgraded version of Sour Diesel I know
the guys in our group are running it
like that too oh yeah they're using it
and working it into lines is their new
sour of bitter and cry baby and those
guys yeah one thing maybe that I thought
we should we could mention real quick uh
before we run out of time here is that
the when Pip was just talking about uh
you know some of these hybrids he
actually did something that I think is
really cool and it's kind of it's
actually super rare which is most times
when people make feminized hybrids
they're either outcrossing it to a
totally different line or they are s
wanting it and one of the rarest things
is to make feminized seed from two
different examples from the same line
yeah right so making something like the
rc10 by the rc4 is actually something
that's super rare it's actually a
feminized Rubber City Line
right yeah it's for it's further work
and it's one of the rarest things that
you'll see on the market because almost
all feminized reversals like I said are
either s1s or outcrosses to something
different
it not Line work there's very little
feminized Line work in a way so I don't
know exactly know what you'd call rc10
by rc4 like how you do exactly f1r
you know that's how we call it
what f1r F1 reversal just F2
yeah I mean it can't it's the second
generation of Representative yeah I mean
it's a it's a reversal it's in the same
line so it's it's in Crossing it in a
sense too
it's just it's a pure Rubber City Line
F1 it's not it's not an F1 right it
would be an F2 yeah because it is
totally different clone yeah f2r yeah
you're right but I just wanted to point
out that in in in feminized seed it's
that that line is one of the rarest
things which it's Line work but made
femini style it's not an outcross and
it's not uh an S1 it's not inbred it's
you know it's uh two full sisters
crossed to each other which doesn't
happen that often yeah I've seen it
happen quite a bit lately I think people
are finally starting to catch on to
stuff like that
um and if if my theory is correct about
uh the super skunk trait the Afghan tea
trait being a a what is it double
recessive then every time you
cross to the Afghan T types together
you're reinforcing that trait and you're
getting those volatile sulfur compounds
like just stacking and stacking that's
what I think is going on and like this
is that ultimate example of that I mean
if you want some of its parents or some
of it's some of its rarer stuff that
could be in the line to pop up that
would probably be the line to look
through yeah oh yeah then like I said
man there is going to be I mean I
haven't done a ton of that line yet I've
just done small populations but the uh
you know eventually I would like to
throw down a couple hundred seeds of of
Premium Rubber and the Goodyear and uh
even some of the the BC work you know
yeah
um and just really go through them like
the right way unfortunately like I in my
position you know up until this point
I've only been able to test like 50
plants around 50 plants of each line
that I make yeah and you know that's
done me pretty good that's given me some
really nice selections uh oh yeah
surprisingly uh you know I really really
didn't think it was at first when I
first started all this I didn't think it
was going to be that easy I figured I'd
have to look through a thousand seeds to
to find that one you know and sometimes
you do I feel like you know you probably
do but if you're popping Haze maybe
right so I had to troll time I mean
sometimes you get lucky and you find it
in five sometimes you find it in fifty
sometimes it takes multiple rounds
because you can find exactly what you
were hunting for so it just is you know
it's it's a love it's a roll the dice
and a law of averages yeah 50 has been
good for me like I said I have found
some amazing seeds and our amazing
plants and and 50 seed populations
um you know uh you know you do 50 seeds
of Premium rubber or the Goodyear or
something like that and I mean we're
talking you're going to be seeing
everything those lines have to offer
that's I mean you're going to find
you're going to find some really really
really nice stuff you don't need to pop
100 seeds you don't even really need to
pop 50 you know like you just you know
get a few packs and that's another thing
I'd suggest if anybody's interested in
like figure out what line you want and
um and buy multiple packs
yeah
that's a mistake I made early on in my
in breeding
is uh I would go to Amsterdam and I
would buy like 20 different things
instead of buying a bunch of packs of a
few different things yeah and having
more to look through because I got
excited
um so sometimes having more seeds of one
line is better than having you know one
pack of eight different things also from
a Breeder's perspective when I get
orders in and since I'm the one filling
orders and I think you know Pip's going
to be too when we see someone old order
multiple packs of one line
like 99 of the time I'm going to hook
them up with like multiple packs of
other lines too because I know they're
doing serious stuff I know they're being
serious about what they're doing so I'm
more likely to do stuff like that even
but every step and you know surprisingly
it's it's kind of rare not very many
people do that would you agree yeah no
it is
huh yeah it's definitely that rare and
that's why when I see it I'm like yes
I'm gonna hook this dude up they're
serious yeah people know what they're
doing people are on a mission they know
the strain they want they know they want
to find the one so they drop the money
on it they make the investment and you
know it doesn't matter what it costs as
long as you get the plant that plant you
can make the sky's the limit whatever
however much money you want because you
have that plant for the rest of your
life you know it doesn't matter if that
seed costs twenty dollars or thirty
dollars whatever you know hell that the
plan will pay itself back when you grow
it from seed
and then you have it forever so
it's always nice to find that special
one so anyway if you if you're gonna if
you're looking at the menu you know just
uh just pick a line or two or whatever
that you're interested in and uh and get
a few packs of it you know two-pack I
mean you're gonna you're gonna be happy
with all the plants obviously but it's a
lottery it's a numbers game when you
grow seeds as everybody knows um like I
said I got lucky with my number 10 and
number four they were in the first ten
seeds of uh of a larger progeny you know
yeah it's just the roll of the dice
sometimes uh but um but you're going to
be happy I mean you're going to be happy
with anything you get that's crossed to
the River City 10 they're all going to
be really nice plants of course there's
always some better than others
um but like I said it's just a numbers
game grab you know two three packs uh
that should that should be enough for
most people if you're like extremely
serious you know um and you really just
want to guarantee you're gonna find like
just you know one two or three or more
awesome like insane blow your mind stuff
then uh you know make the investment and
get you get you at least like yeah 30
seeds 40 something like that if you can
afford it but it's not for everybody
um what now that's my advice if they
want to get any of these how do they get
a hold of you
um they I will be uh doing the release
this Tuesday
at uh what time did I say it was let me
check my notes here real quick uh yeah
Tuesday January 31st 6 p.m Pacific and 9
p.m eastern time all right Tuesday
January 31st
yep okay I put the wrong date on the
back bumper but thankfully we're
covering it up so you can't
I was like okay yep good job Stoner and
they will be able to get those
um you can go to the link in my bio on
on either on my souvenir seaco page or
my Pips weed page and there's a link
there to take you to a URL where you can
view the menu and everything and read
all the instructions and then once you
made your uh your choice then you'll
just email
um I believe it was
if you have any questions for me but the
people running the the sale and
everything is not me so oh that's only
order related questions on there and
that email or uh yeah that that email
will be the Rubber City drop at
protonmail.com
so Rubber City drop at protonmail.com
once you're uh once you've looked at the
menu and you have your order ready then
all the instructions are out that URL
and you can get a hold of us and uh and
we'll get you set up nice and good
all right
that's awesome so yeah
you also have your Instagram your
Instagram page where you can find all
these pictures of all these amazing
plants uh what's your Instagram uh my
Instagram personal Instagram is uh pip
Swede all one word and then my other C
company Instagram is souvenir Seed Co
okay and yeah um
thanks for coming on and talking about
all these old strains and and what you
got going on now we'll have to have you
come back on sometime soon you know I
look forward to it to to talk about some
of the shenanigans we've all gotten up
to this went so fast so I figured it did
you know there's so much more we could
talk about I just want to say one more
thing um talk to all my supporters out
there and everybody who supported me
through this Venture and everything I
really do appreciate it I put a lot of
care and passion and love into what I do
and it brings me a lot of joy to see
other people be happy from you know
growing my work and uh and and my
strains and to hear all the stories and
it just it just brings me a lot of Joy
so I love doing what I'm going to do
what I do I'm going to be taking a break
for a while I don't have any plans in
the near future but I will be back at
some point I promise
and uh you know one love to you guys
thanks for all the support yeah man
thanks for coming on and uh letting
everybody hear from you it's a it's an
honor
yeah thanks for having me on the show
Matt one of the things I'll say to that
is that in addition to the History part
that Matt and I did uh one of the one of
the main reasons why we did this podcast
was to give people a chance to listen to
How like we nerds like like to chit chat
about various different things and so
pip is a is a very good friend uh who
we've been chatting for a long time uh
in private years and years uh chatting
about different stuff and so
um it's it's cool to bring uh personal
friends on who have get a chance to talk
about their passion their work what
they're interested in
um and I think that like the way he
breeds is pretty neat because he doesn't
really do any hype stuff too much he
kind of like if you listen to this
podcast he kind of like collected
strains over the years and he picked
favorites and then he decided what
happens if I mix these favorites
and that is sort of like the basis for
what he's been doing so it's a very
personal approach in my opinion
um he bred things he liked which is
something I always tell people to do
pick things you like and try to find
things you like
you know and don't care about what the
rest of the world thinks find things
that you think are interesting and I
think that this list uh definitely
represents that in a big way
yeah that's a big positive and it
doesn't matter if your family gets upset
that you hang out at rest stops and with
that this will be the end of the show
thanks
[Music]
foreign
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
started to hit me
and I'm like wow
[Music]
I got high
foreign
[Music]