welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar that corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate the videos on this channel the
Breeders Syndicate 3.0 are compliant
with YouTube policies and does not
depict or promote any sales or
distribution of any substances these
videos do not violate any YouTube
Community guidelines and is intended to
educate the public about historical and
scientific aspects of hemp plants this
video does not promote idolize nor
glorify any illegal activities or unsafe
consumption of regulated substances we
are not doctors or lawyers this should
be super obvious with that said some
people need to be reminded about this do
not take anything we say as medical or
legal advice of any sort we are just the
best at what we do live with it all
content is copyright of the breeder
Syndicate 3.0 2024 section 107 of the
fair use act thank you for your support
all right welcome to reader Syndicate
I'm Matthew and today I'm here with Yoni
the CEO of plant cell technology if that
is that correct that's correct all right
and um the other day I I kind of
stumbled on to you through a mutual
friend and they were showing that you're
doing a embryonic rescue on seeds which
fascinates me all the Breeders out there
um people that are just genuinely
interested in seed collecting and so I
went in and look like you guys were
competently doing embryonic rescue which
is something I've not seen yet displayed
shown really like like you guys did um
so it fascinated me and I wanted to
reach out so here we are um tell me a
little bit about your and how it got
started tell me about yourself yeah so
so plant cell technology first off Matt
it's great to be here and uh I love that
you stumbled on our our our video you
know being confident is uh is is the
Baseline for what we
expect we it's it's important to be
professional and and more importantly to
to give people the resources and the
opportunity to watch right a lot of
science is hidden behind closed doors
and uh I think part of our mission is to
democratize tissue culture and make this
more accessible to the world so um on
that point you know plant cell
technology started about 30 years ago
okay and the the origin story that a lot
of people don't know is we actually
started as a toy company and the whole
idea yeah it's called pet plant so the
whole idea was you could get you know
three different test tubes filled with
gel and you'd get different seeds you
would have a corn seed you would have a
CA seed and you would have a tomato seed
and kids would be able to watch the
plants grow in in the test tube for
example um in the gel and you know it's
fun fun toy this is like around the time
pet rock was a thing you know pet
everything uh Space Monkeys or water
monkeys whatever you would call them um
there was one problem with this toy is
that the gel kept getting contaminated
yeah so we developed plant preservative
mixture which is the only EPA approved
solution that you know protects the
plants doesn't hurt the plants but keeps
bacteria and fungus outside of your
outside of your cultures um and that's
really where that's really what got us
our foot in the door into the industry
so fast forward 30 years later PPM is is
widely used across the industry it's an
industry standard for for most labs and
internationally
especially but what we wanted to do is
is figure out a way to bridge the gap
between your bioengineers you know your
your highly educ ated scientists and
people that wanted to get into the space
but might not have access so we started
developing a series of videos education
classes to show people what we did in
the lab you know what's the R&amp;D that
we're doing behind those doors what are
the products that we're using to be
successful and not only are we going to
provide you with those products but
we're going to teach you how to use them
and you know while we do service the
largest commercial tissue culture labs
in the world they know exactly what
there buying we thought that it's
important to create more education in
the space um more videos more content
and also break it down for people that
weren't
necessarily um learning from the
scientific journals and papers that they
either might not have access to or might
not understand um and I very much
believe that plant tissue culture is a
trade skill right being able to work in
a lab being able to be successful and
and mitigate contamination uh being
successful lab technician is something
that we should be training more people
in and giving more people the
opportunity because this is a very
important skill and and as I like to
tell people at least with with cannabis
hemp specifically we're only in the
second or third inning of the ball game
right now and the research is flooding
in the opportunities are expanding and
and we're just we're seeing an exciting
wave now of energy that people aren't
just questioning whether or not TC is
good for them but they're now trying to
figure out how to do it for themselves
that was a little long monologue of how
we got started but we really you know
started from just a product company and
now I I try to think of us as a a
collective or an all-in-one shop for
plant tissue culture with education
Consulting products and support and and
we have this community that we've built
and hopefully continue to build that now
you're a part of so thanks for thanks
for joining our video and hopefully it's
many yeah it was it was smart and and I
don't usually get like motivated to hit
people up YouTube I I really don't it it
it was awesome and it was well done
first of many yeah first of many and
it's all free that's the that's the
beautiful part right people there's a
lot of pay walls behind this information
or people just don't want to talk about
it but yeah we're here to tell you as
much as we can right yeah some things
are proprietary obviously but obviously
um something like when it comes to
embryo rescue uh that's a skill that I
think Growers especially will be excited
to learn about because I mean how many
seeds have you thrown out in your
lifetime my God so many there's so we
like between me and a few other breeders
we have a large stock of some of the
oldest seeds in in cannabis history just
sitting and waiting not doing anything
in fridges just waiting for people that
have the skill to do this and just just
and so many people have pretended to we
give them to him and nothing comes from
it ever so yeah yeah it's
exciting yeah so I mean what we can do
with embrya rescue while while we're not
guaranteeing 100% results you know no
nothing in science is ever 100% um but
if you do have old seeds I mean we we've
worked with seeds that are 30 40 years
old and we've been able to germinate
them um so yeah I can I can just Dive
Right into embryo rescue if you want
please do you know at its core um you
know majority of Growers like to pop
seeds uh feno hunt look for new strains
one of the big and common issues with
popping seeds was some of them just
won't work right yeah they're not going
to germinate and people throw them out
fortunately uh due to plant tissue
culture and some of the skills uh
developed in embryo rescue this is
actually I want to give credit to to
Bill Graham the very first yeah yeah uh
you know plant tissue culture in your
kitchen you know he's been the god I
like to call him the Godfather of DC
yeah uh but he's he's really perfected
this skill and and taught us and now
we're trying to teach the world as well
but what we're doing is we're removing
the outer coat of the seed
sometimes a 20 30 40y Old seed doesn't
have enough energy to germinate outside
his coat um so you what we do is we make
a slight incision um after soaking it in
like a hydrogen peroxide solution for
anybody that has you know questions on
the actual details of or the actual
protocols on how to do it we're we're
happy to share those no problem just you
know feel free to reach out to Matt feel
free to reach out to us
someo yeah we we'll share the actual
videos that we did um but I'm I'm you
know giving you the broad Strokes here
so we're we're cting out the the the
seed embryo and inducing it in a
nutrient-rich medium so what we have
here for example this is a gel um it's
augur based so this is completely vegan
made out of seaweed and this this gel is
mixed with a variety of macro and
micronutrients it's actually a
proprietary formula that we'll be
launching soon fun fact and it it works
amazing I mean you can see this little
guy this is from L 1121 guava Tarts yeah
one of the uh seeds we actually popped
on the video but you know it's rooting
it's looking beautiful it's looking
great um you know this nutrient media is
about three times as rich in the macro
micronutrients that plants desire as
like traditional soil yeah so the seeds
have not only the you know the energy to
be able to germinate but they're
actually able to flourish you know both
root develop shoots quite vigorously I
mean this is uh maybe 10 days yeah after
the seed just wouldn't move if we if we
planted it in the ground so what what
we've tried to share with Growers is
that tissue culture is a new is is
actually not a new tool it's been around
since the 60s and earlier it really
started in the Orchid industry um every
Orchid that you buy in your Trader Joe's
or Walmart or grocery store is likely a
clone and likely started in tissue
culture right orchids are very hard to
germinate from seeds
tissue culture asexual propagation has
been the the go-to mechanism so now at
least within the the hemp and cannabis
space we're trying to tell Growers you
can adopt these same technologies that
have benefited some of the largest
pharmaceutical companies in the world
the largest agricultural companies in
the world flower companies we can apply
that same technology and it's it's
really right now being led by a lot of
the private sector I'd say there are a
few universities that can legally work
with it um but because of all the red
tape and bureaucracy it's taking a lot
more time than it should so something
like embryo rescue is one of the easiest
I'd say steps um in the tissue culture
process and when I say easy it's it's
not that the skill itself is easy but
the mechanism and once you learn how to
do it you ride a bike you yeah you're
gonna you're gonna Excel um but yeah
this at its very simplest form is I'd
say step one um if you're a grower if
you're breeder and you want to work with
old seeds that you're scared won't
germinate this is one of the best shots
you have um you're cutting out that
outer shell and you're exposing it to
that nutrient-rich media that needs and
then the rest is uh just watching it
grow and putting it under light um and
then when you look at other kind of
techniques that you'll learn along the
way so this is from noo culture um what
that means is we're taking Noto
propagation so we're taking the cutting
from a mother plant okay and and we're
using that nutrient-rich media and we're
letting it flourish and then from here I
would take this and I'd acclimate it
either in rock wool cubes or I would
yeah probably rock wool um the the
biggest thing that I would tell Growers
or the biggest challenge they have is
acclimating these plants I mean just
yeah most plants need a hardening period
yeah so 10 to 12 days you're you're you
know right now this is close to 100%
humidity because there's a a little vent
right here it's allowed to breathe which
means humidity is slightly less however
you still want to adjust it right if I
was to take this out and try to plant it
in soil it's not GNA live go yeah yeah
so there is an acclamation period And
what I what I like to tell Growers is
all these skills can be obtained you
know you don't need a master's degree or
a PhD to do this uh but you do need a
will to uh to fail and and try again so
yeah a lot of people will fail fail when
you first start because contamination is
a problem right learning atic technique
learning how to work in the uh under
under a Flo hood and and how to avoid
contamination risks is one of the
biggest challenges but again um we've
had classes where people watch us do uh
meristem dissection for example they
tell themselves you know they're scared
they're never going to be able to do it
and after three or four tries they did
it perfectly yeah once they did it once
they do it five six seven times and
nothing's scary anymore yeah so we you
know we've seen people from all age
groups all skill levels succeed in this
and it's it's really just about
commitment to pushing through some of
those challenges and also just asking
questions right if something doesn't
work why didn't it work was it the
lighting was it the media was it the was
there ventilation or no ventilation so I
think a lot of people want kind of
instant answers and the good news is you
know we're releasing a all-in-one media
so all you have to do is add water and
and uh solidify
however um if you want to do the
research and want to work through it you
can do that too and that's that's where
we can provide a guide for you we have
all the lists of pgrs that you can
access all the um different components
that you would need to run your own
experiments but it's uh I don't I don't
need to sell the specific products here
but that that's exciting kind of stuff
and and when you're talking about it one
of the first things you mentioned early
on was PPM
talk about what that means so people
understand what that means because most
people growing would think that means
parts per million like measuring stuff
out you know yep PPM if you use
fertilizers you refer to parts per
million so plant preservative mixture at
its at its simplest is a preservative
that keeps out any bacteria or fungus
from growing in this test tube without
damaging the plant itself you know
pesticides and herbicides and certain
fertilizers are sprayed on Plants yeah
this is a way that we can avoid that all
together um
and it's mixed in with the media it's
autoclaved so you would mix in the
powder You' mix in the water you'd add
PPM and then you'd autoclave it and
you're good to go and what PPM does is
if you make a mistake if you uh
accidentally breathe or you might have
touched your scalp before you cut the
plant I mean it's giving you an extra
layer of insurance right these medias as
I mentioned earlier three times as
nutrient rich as traditional soils you
can imagine as much as the plant loves
it bugs love it bacteria love itely Fung
fungus loves it
so PPM is like PPM is insurance right
you're you're operating in a tissue
culture lab you're inevitably GNA get
contamination there are very few I would
say I don't I don't even know if there
are any labs that never experienced
contamination across the board humans
are imperfect right you're bound to make
mistakes um and especially if you're
doing thousands of cultures a day you're
mistakes are going to be made so PPM is
that extra layer of security no bacteria
or fungus is going to be able to grow in
there and then you can transfer that
plant so it's no longer exposed to those
contaminants in that small space so the
the biggest challenge when a plant is
exposed to fungus or bacteria in tissue
culture versus in the field is you're
competing for limited nutrients here um
versus a larger space and you know at
its core it's it's enabled labs around
the world whether they're in Pakistan or
Benin or South Africa or Chile to be
able to operate at the same level as
some of the highest tech labs because
you know you can work there's a company
called viscon and I think they build out
Labs that are 10 152 million doar right
these are state-ofthe-art cream of the
crop best you can get of everything
fully automated beautiful labs and then
you have a lot of universities and
research centers and companies in
developing countries that might not be
able to afford that that likely can
afford that and that's where PPM can add
a little bit more support to their
facility to their protocols and to their
workflow so that if their you know
workers inevitably do make a mistake
it's not going to cost them however much
each test tube is worth um so you know
that that's really what got us the foot
in the door and so companies knew yeah
it's our creation it was
patented um it was a game it was a major
game changer for for tissue culture yeah
the the the original claim was you could
do tissue culture without a lamin or Flo
hood and people went crazy uh oh I mean
that's oh yeah no it's that's that
wasn't uh you know we posted that in a
Minnesota University of Minnesota list
serve I think in the 90s and people just
people are I
rate I bet try being an outsider coming
into the industry and saying actually
guys you can do this differently um and
while we've had some success with that I
wouldn't recommend it yeah yeah I do
recommend using a Flo Hood I do
recommend practicing aseptic technique
because all those skills that you're
going to learn and you're going to
practice it's the right way to do it
right you can shoot a basketball
different ways but learning the right
shot I'd say is recommended for most
players sure and I'd say the same goes
for tissue culture um but you know PPM
is that revolutionary product that put
us that put our foot in the door and I I
I can tell you it's over the last five
six years um if it weren't for a lot of
our marketing and sales efforts it's
been hard um some of our competitors are
signing you know non-exclusive contracts
with Distributors so you know they can
only distribute products that our
competitors don't carry so it really
forces us outside of our box to develop
new products yeah so PPM was the first
um we have two patent pending products
now one is called the bio coupler and
the bioil and tell me a little bit about
the bio couler because I know that's a
lot absolutely so I think the 70s or 80s
there's been research in the plant
tissue culture and and agricultural
technology space about temporary
immersion and temporary immersion is
essentially your in in traditional
semisolid media you have one contact
point where the the root of the plant or
the the base of the plant contacts the
media and that's where it absorbs
nutrients with temporary immersion
you're actually soaking the whole plant
in nutrients temporarily and then you're
letting it dry out so mechanism and that
360 contact Point uh with the plant not
only increases the speed at which that
plant grows but increases the actual
quantity of plants that you're getting
yeah so this technology has been
revolutionary for almost 50 60 years but
the the systems and Contraptions and
pipes and tubes for temporary immersion
bioreactors are just not feasible uh if
you look at temporary immersion
bioreactors today a lot of them have you
know two three four four filters per
bioreactor they have these long air
tubes that connect to those filters and
then connect to oxygen tanks those tubes
are bound to get contaminated clogged
filters are are you know you need to
replace them maybe every six to 12
months those filters aren't cheap yeah
right and the risk of losing maybe five
liters worth of plants is high so while
the technology has been there there
hasn't been an application that's been
feasible for the commercial ation of it
at scale um and there are companies that
use temporary immersion bioreactors
there are a few out there that are very
good I mean they're amazing at what they
do pumping in air works very well um but
not necessarily as commercially feasible
in the long run so what we did is uh you
know at its simplest it's it's keep it
simple stupid right yeah the most
complex system sometimes are the
simplest so the bio coupler connects two
glass devices and every time you wrote
that device there's an air exchange so
instead of using a a tube and instead of
pumping in oxygen the plants that every
time the the bio coupler rotates oxygen
is pumped through the little air patch
filter that we have and the process is
quite simple I mean you screw out the
bottom you screw a new media all you
have to do is change out the media and
it's I mean it'll take you less than 30
seconds versus the old bioreactors might
take you an hour 20 minutes 30 minutes
uh so what we've done is we've
simplified
the bioreactor model uh by creating a
more commercially viable option and it's
it's incredible what it can do um some
plants like orchids we're seeing 30 40
50 times multiplication rates versus
traditional semisolid media you're
getting three or four three or four
plants you know we're getting 40 we're
getting 50 um we see this application
being useful for all types of crops
bananas pineapples orchids cannabis you
name it and so what we've done the bio
coupler is is the base device the bio
tilt is our Automated machine so instead
of you flipping the device every single
day we have a device that does that
automatically you can program it you can
set your own timing on it you know I
want to flip it once every three hours I
want to flip it for I want it to soak
for two minutes I want it to soak for
three minutes we've really created a
tool that people can master and create
their own research with uh by making
slight modifications to the programming
and that enables people to with any
species have accessibility to a a
technology that's going to be a game
changer that eventually will disrupt and
I think maybe replace the tissue culture
space Oh wow
and this is hopefully the you know 1.0
right this is the bio tilt 1.0 we're
gonna keep developing it keep improving
it and the hope is that this will help
Growers mass-produced plants that are
clean yeah more consistently and at a
cheaper price than if they were using
tissue culture because at the end of the
day the giling agent that you're buying
might cost you $90 to $100 a kilogram
with temporary immersion you don't even
need it wow you just cut that from your
budget
altoe so yeah and it's it's been and the
funny part is it's not new right we
didn't invent we didn't invent the wheel
here we just made a better wheel that
fits the car yeah um more efficient
wheel yeah doesn't break down as easy
the rubber Treads last long ER easier to
change the tires right we're trying to
make tissue culture more accessible to
people and and that's through education
but also through R&amp;D and I'll tell you
it's uh you know developing the stuff is
not cheap and it takes a lot of time so
we're we're doing our best and we are a
fairly small company so I think a lot of
people look at our website or look at
our history and they think we're this
huge corporation but we're not um we're
I think four or five fulltime people I
mean we have a lot of contractors and we
do contract manufacturing but yeah it's
family business we we're we're expanding
very fast and you know anybody who's
listening that made an order and that's
still waiting on it you know thank you
for your patience we apologize I mean
Black Friday was kind of insane for us
we're
uh we're so grateful I mean look these
are all blessings I I just want to be
able to keep up with the demand and I I
just want people to to know that we're
here for them because yeah it's it's a
daunting industry it's you know you you
look on Google or Wikipedia and you just
there's all these journals and papers
and if you're not from that world it's
intimidating and uh hopefully we can be
that bridge for for The Growers and
especially in the Cannabis space like
we're here to help you know we're here
to answer your questions we want you to
use this tool because um Hops and vroid
fusarium uh spidermites powdery Milo I
mean these are big problems and they're
costing Growers money I mean I think I
like to quaint um maybe maybe this is
controversial but I like to call hops
Lon vroid the AIDS of of yeah it is it
is and people don't realize it like
unless you're heavily into genetics
collecting and like I we have ears all
over the the world and now we're hearing
about labs in Spain going down like that
have the major collections that have
been over in Amsterdam stuff that
haven't made it over here like it's bad
it's it's it's scary and everybody has
it or you know 70 80% of Growers have it
and so the good news
to that problem is there is a cure yeah
there is there is a protocol and a
mechanism of remediating those plants
and that's where we come in that's where
plant tissue culture thrives yeah so the
for for surface pathogens when you're
talking about some of your your common
pests right your powdery mildew your
spidermites those are more easily
curable with um surface sterilization
and noal culture right we're we're
taking parts of the plant that might not
yet be infected or if they are infected
Ed they're they're less there's a lower
uh bug count than other parts of the
leaf we're yeah killing it we're you
know surfest sterilizing that leaf and
then we're inducing it in media that's
clean and then keeping it in this clean
container away from your mother room
away from potential contaminantes so if
your HVAC technician comes in the room
he's not going to be able to infect this
little guy because it's sealed yeah as
opposed to your mother room good luck
you know if uh if he brings in something
from another facility or if if forget to
clean your your shears or if somebody
brings in cuting and they don't
quarantine it adequately it will spread
oh yeah um when it comes to ferium
and you know cops lat and broid the
worst of them all that's where we really
focus on the apical marem dissection so
what we're doing we have tons of videos
on this if you're if your users are
interested is we're isolating the apical
meristem which if you think about it is
the primordial tissue not connected to
the rest of the plant with scientific
terms it's it's disconnected from the
vascul of the plant tissue so that cell
cluster is not yet exposed to whatever
viroid or virus or fungus has infected
the rest of the plant I mean you're
literally going down to Mill millimeters
going very very small I mean it's you
won't be able to see it with the naked
eye we use a hypodermic needle to
isolate it and then we put it in this
grow medium and you know in in three
months it'll grow it'll grow up to be a
normal plant but it's small it's tiny
but that's the mechanism at least our
best plan of action right uh if a plant
is highly infected you might have to do
it a couple times yeah which means you
take the marem you let it grow out then
you take a marem again you let it grow
out it really depends on the viral load
but right now that is our best mechanism
that is our best tool that we can use
and we're not using pesticides we're not
using herbicides we're not soaking it in
anything that's gonna you know affect
the actual outcome of the plant down the
line when it's eventually consumed uh
but this mechanism is highly highly
beneficial um and I'd say it's it's
probably the hardest skill to learn in
tissue culture yeah um so luckily noal
culture is fairly basic and and
something most people can learn but
merism takes a little bit of practice
but what I can tell you is a $100
microscope you can do it hypodermic
needle you can buy it on Amazon yeah um
you know you can really practice and get
better at the skill or you just have one
guy you know Joey's the the guy and he
can do 20 30 an hour right um but what
we tell Growers especially when it comes
to viroids and you know P serium
specifically is take as many meristems
as you can right because you don't you
don't want to use your
meristem we we like to be preventative
instead of reactive um so the proactive
measure is you know keeping your spaces
clean uh bleaching the floors you know
following propter Pro proper um
sterile conditions and and keeping your
overall facility clean right not
everybody does that but Mar steming and
learning that skill is I'd say the last
resort uh the first Resort is using
tissue culture using noal culture
testing your plants keeping them backed
up so that inevitably if and when
something does get infected great I have
10 of these or 50 of these so I can time
it out in two to three weeks they'll be
in the vegro and ready to go but you
have backups and we have the mechanism
to back up our genetics now so we we
shouldn't be hearing about cannabis
strains going extinct we shouldn't be
hear about you know oh I can't I can't
get guava Tarts anymore because it's all
it's gone right every grower that's had
a heal C
fortunately till we [__] stop can't
stop vomiting because it's exactly yeah
just hypothetical there is you know God
forbid you know God forbid especially
with some of the more medicinal strains
right the lower THC but more unique
canabo profiles that actually really
help people that are you know dealing
with a wide variety of health issues God
forbid one of those strains goes extinct
because uh a pesky vroid wiped it out
yeah so what I'd like to you know tell
Growers and tell you specifically is
please please please even if you're not
going to invest in a lab open your mind
to tissue culture right yeah this is a
tool that you will be using in the next
five to 10 years it's not an if it's a
when yeah and start practicing uh
because your genetics are your business
right if you're if you're an operator
that owns properties you have property
insurance you have flood insurance you
likely have fire insurance if you live
in California yeah as a cannabis grower
you should have insurance for the number
one product that you're selling which is
your PL which is your flowers right so
that's what tissue culture does is we're
backing up your genetics we're
protecting those genetics and and we're
keeping them contained so that when you
need them when when the disaster strikes
that's okay we have 50 backups ready to
go yeah um and then secondly I'd say the
main benefit of tissue culture for
Growers that aren is familiar is what if
you could shrink your mother room by
three fors I mean the whole concept of
the mother room is going to become
extinct the idea of keeping these huge
trees alive attracts pests attracts bugs
takes up energy takes up space now
imagine if you know your mother room was
100 square feet instead of 12200 and
imagine if you could have two more
bedrooms in there or you could dedicate
that space for a lab a mother room and
something else so Growers are obviously
dealing with a wide variety of issues
whether it's high taxation whether it's
you know High cap X labor costs this is
another mechanism where a tissue culture
can be a tool to actually reduce and
lower your costs in the long run by
better optimizing the way that you grow
and optimizing the way that you use your
space to effectively produce plants that
flower um so yeah that's I I I could
talk about TC and its applications and
its its use cases all day I think it's
it's Paramount for tissue for cannabis
to
survive um and yeah man we're we're just
excited this this media is g to be
launched soon um we have all these new
products that Growers can use and
experiment with specifically with uh the
hemp cannabis space and um our classes
of course you know we have classes
online we have classes in person we have
pre-recorded classes like there's
there's a million resources so I don't
want to hear somebody say there's
there's not enough information out there
we have 800 videos for free on YouTube
on how to do this uh and that's just
scratching the surface so you know our
our dedication to the community is that
we we want this this skill this this
scientific practice to thrive in the
Canabis space because it's important
it's important for people it helps
people and uh this is just one way that
we can do it more efficiently yeah you
know preaching the gospel no I mean a
lot of the moms in um the canidate space
are kept in i' would say traditional
Market is as opposed to Legal Market um
or
or commercial Market I guess because the
commercial Market is would be the legal
market now yeah um they're kept in more
shoddy like homes and stuff like a lot
of the really old rare stuff by people
who don't trust anyone so it's really
nice to see you know you guys coming out
putting all the stuff out there uh
showing can be used but yeah it'll be
interesting to see that that that space
adapt start installing Lamer Flo hoods
and and houses that are blowing up I
think it's important I think it's
awesome but it's it's going to be the
turning point because the commercial
Market doesn't have access to most of
what needs to be saved in the first
place yeah yeah second inning man second
inning we're that that's what's so
exciting about this is we we haven't
even scratched the surface of what we
can do with this technology I mean soon
we we already have this the the
technology to extract secondary
metabolites so imagine growing THC or
CBD or turpins just on in gel without
the actual plant right extracting
extracting those chemicals directly
right so there we're we're gonna
continue to develop more efficient
mechanisms that's not to say we're GNA
make growing flower Obsolete and growing
plants obsolete absolutely not but as
the industry develops and as hopefully
research opens up on the medicinal side
we'll be able to better identify canono
profiles and Turpin that actually help
people and then grow those specific
profiles yeah without you know it's huge
being able to reproduce something
exactly without worrying about the
environment like that would be a massive
step in reproduction and medical
qualities of everything I think so and
think about it if you're taking an Advil
if I'm if I'm taking uh you know Advil I
want 10 milligram every time I don't
want 10 9.7 and 8.9 it's not a medicine
at that point you're just guessing so
this this tissue culture specifically is
is one of the I'd say most important
steps that will marry the industry as a
transitions from you know Black Market
gray Market to fully white Market
corporatized commercialized at a large
scale and it's happening it's it's you
know you're seeing your largest
producers your segas you have conception
and node Labs I mean you have a lot of
companies in the space
however and we were talking about this a
little earlier backstage but there are
also a lot of people that love the word
tissue culture and they oh yeah use that
buzzword to claim what they're doing is
tissue culture when in reality it might
not be tissue culture it might be
something else that they're calling
tissue culture or they might just be
doing tissue culture incorrectly and
charging somebody a arm and a leg for it
so what I tell people is be weary right
do your due diligence who are these
companies that are popping out of
nowhere that are claiming to you know
have the prot calls and the knowledge
and the skills to do it it's very likely
that they do have them right but at the
same time any industry that starts to
blow up or or starts to get popular
attracts people that like to take
advantage of others especially one with
the gray Market where that you can't get
so easily yeah noticed so you know you
don't have to work with us I just want
you to you know your hard-earned money
should go to somebody that can actually
help you and not somebody that's gonna
use a buzzword uh claim to claim to do
it charge you and then you know you're
left with a plant that's still infected
dead
or you know or Worse yeah seed companies
are is the same thing it's it's the same
Cesspool of uh of people there's
breeders and then there's seed makers in
my in my mind there's people that breed
and then there's people that can make
seeds which is everyone that has a male
and a female and trying to for people
coming in trying to guess who is who is
the is the worst game ever and like
marketing doesn't quite relay who is
what and does what yeah tissue for me
for me going from seed to tissue culture
and trying to navigate that sphere it's
a completely still like foreign sphere
to me even though I should be massively
invested in it it's been so tenuous and
yeah I mean we we'll send you some stuff
you can play around I mean happily do it
yeah yeah you don't you don't need a a
500 square foot lab to do this I need a
laminer Flowood because every time I've
tried it I've massively failed massively
but it's it's been because of small
little and you
know infections whatever it's infections
or or contaminant so no we'll get you
some PPM we'll get you some test tubes
and then hopefully depending on how good
the instructions were in that video you
can start practicing on some seeds I
mean I I'd recommend some seeds that
aren't valuable to you first just so you
the protocol but you know getting the
getting the skills of grabbing the
scalpel putting the seed in without
touching the surfaces you know being
careful with your hands it's it's the
first step man and imagine just pH
hunting in this way you can just put
them on a shelf and you can have 10,000
of these little guys that take up you
know maybe a library shelf instead of a
whole farm right your your your space
efficiency is increased by a magnitude
of 10 to 15 times so you know you can
really store them keep them safe and
secure in these test tubes eventually
you know there is there is some
maintenance with this right so you're
not just going to put this at a test
tube it'll eventually outgrow to test
oh yeah yeah you know that that's what
you want that'll grow fast that looks
like it'll grow fast it'll grow fast so
there is a there is a maintenance uh
maintenance involved with this and
whether it's every two to three four
weeks you're G to change that plant to
New Media uh but that plant itself can
survive in that media for you
exstensively
forever um no scientific report will
ever say forever 100% with anything but
a long time probably outlive you and
me right and you we're I like to think
of ourselves as conservationists right
we're we're caretakers for these plants
for these genetics that hopefully
Generations will experience will consume
we'll uh will get to take care of or or
be exposed to so yeah I mean it all
comes back to tissue culture is
necessary I've said it a million times I
feel bad but you guys are just you you
need it it's
very you know like one of the few things
that I've seen and and I'd like to ask
you how you would mitigate something
like this early on when tis culture
became like a buzzword uh maybe 10 years
ago like in cannabis when people really
started pushing it hard they were um
selling Whole nurseries were selling
like tissue culture and saying like yes
we we'll we'll give you a thousand
plants you can run them right now start
it and then they'd run them and
everything would have interex issues
right away or or some kind of hormonal
issues coming out of just tissue culture
running the plantlets straight in um how
do you m stuff like that how do you
mitigate that from happening that's a
great question so first and foremost
testing right at its at its finest we're
using the same testing devices that they
use to test for covid yeah that we're
using to test for hops L vroid
thermocyclers PCR machines uh
fortunately as the the need for these
devices has increased the price has gone
down so Supply demand you know it might
it might have cost you 10 15,00
to get access to a a proper PCR machine
that could run for hops slate and bywood
um now you might be able to get one for
cheaper maybe not 15,000 maybe five six
7,000 but yeah I think when tissue
culture first started becoming a
buzzword people well I can't speak for
everyone but a small percentage of that
industry use that buzzword to sell and
make quick money as we know this
industry is actually a lot smaller than
people give it credit for and you know
your reputation is everything so uh
hurting people and and taking advantage
of them is is an easy way to go bankrupt
quick as a business um so testing
products I I would say is is the easiest
way to avoid any of these issues right
you can do gender screening and gender
testing uh mini PCR is a great company I
think their device is like $1,500
there's only six Wells so yeah it'll
take you a little while but you can you
can run gender screening on that device
um for hops late and vroid there's some
great companies Tumi genomics has a
you've interviewed Tumi they're great
yeah Tumi has a great device um that's
it's awesome yeah you can test for hops
slate and vroid I'd say the only
challenge with the device as of now is
it doesn't tell you viral load it'll
just tell you positive or negative so
major factor yeah it can be especially
if you're you're trying to determine how
bad the plan is affected how many how
many remediation Cycles do we need to go
through that's a good thing to know but
again again Tumi also has a lab you can
send them plants directly and they can
run tests in lab AGD is another great
one they have their device I think I
don't think it also tells viral load but
it will tell you a positive or negative
I have to confirm so don't hold me to it
sorry AGD if I got that wrong uh but
they're great you know they lent us a
device that we were using for our master
classes for a good year actually and
that thing was probably 10
12,000 we ran a number of hops slate and
viroid tests fortunately none of the
cuting and plants we brought in had it
uh fortunately or unfortunately because
I think it's also good to experiment
with it but we also just popsa and vroid
is a vroid that can transfer not only
from Cannabis to to other crops so we
gotta be careful um especially in our
lab but yeah we we luckily didn't bring
anything home so the simple answer to
your question is making sure you're
checking all the boxes right they're
doing tissue culture okay what does that
mean
are they doing not culture are they
rooting in vitro or X vitro so in the
test tube or out of the test tube what's
What stages are they running through in
tissue culture versus out of tissue
culture are they actually running
testing or are they just taking plants
putting in tissue culture and hoping for
the best I think a lot of people are
doing the ladder
because because test cost money and yeah
test cost money it's like $40 $50 a test
it's not cheap yeah however
as a commercial business if that is your
if if that's your business if that's
your welfare I highly recommend
investing in those tests I recommend
absolutely allocating part of your
budget towards the due diligence
required to keep your actual product
clean yeah and uh that's the missing
link so the testing companies combining
with the tissue culture knowledge gives
us that full 360 perspective of are my
plants male or female what are the tpine
profiles THC profiles everything else
when it comes to testing for heavy
metals testing for preservatives and
then also does this plant have hops does
this plant have ferium does this plant
have any of the other pathogens viroids
and viruses that plague this industry
and so we have the knowledge we have the
machinery and the skills to do it it's
just about I guess helping people and
teaching them so in our class we we do
spend at least half a day to a day on
testing because testing is not easy
um it's not as simple as you know
putting a plant in a test tube and you
know there there are steps and it's it's
kind of like cooking but I'd say it's
more like baking where you got to use
the exact amount of flour and you got to
use the exact amount of eggs otherwise
it's gonna overcook or undercook so same
goes with using a qpcr machine using a
thermocycler using some of those devices
uh but with anything practice makes
perfect and so the education the
opportunity to learn it's all there um
but
I think as a grower as a breeder as
somebody that's working in the
commercial side of the space you have to
make that decision right from a budget
standpoint does it make more sense to do
this in house does it make more sense to
send it out and and send it out to Labs
that do testing uh that really comes
down to your budget your patience your
um commitment to investing in the
equipment and the protocols and the
people right the labor to be able to do
it that's that's just a whole another
component right everybody you hire in
the in the facility likely already has a
job so who who's going to take over uh
for who's going to do testing so that's
that's a that's a question that really
comes down to your business plan your
needs and your budget um so something I
I do recommend Growers take seriously
and and consider but um still it's it's
very important because again tissue
culture needs to be coupled with the
testing otherwise you're really kind of
shooting in the dark here yeah yeah that
makes sense I mean it's that way with
breeding
even I believe it yeah uh if you don't
if you don't eventually test in some way
have someone even even if it's down to
having someone smoke it and having a
group of people smoking it you're not
getting any kind of feedback and it's
all shooting in the dark I mean yeah or
or you're just losing time right yes yes
and if you're doing real breeding it's
time and time is money time is money
time is money and it's all we have
exactly something you don't get back so
if we can cut that cycle in half right
you don't have to grow it out to a
certain point or you already know what
the problem is and you can mitigate that
problem that saves you money a lot of
money um especially in the long run I
think people are thinking very short
term when it comes to these businesses
and I get it right cannabis is
incredibly competitive very Cutthroat
very hard to succeed I think people
outside the industry think it's like
this you know everybody's making cash
hand overhand notm no the margins are
tight I know I get it I've spoken to
hundreds of Growers and I I empathize
with you guys guys and girls it's it's
it's hard and We Know It And so we're
just trying to find ways through the
technology that we're you know applying
to every other plant species alive how
can we also use this or cannabis how can
we also optimize this process and give
you more time back or give you more
space back or you know save a little bit
of room in your budget
for you know keeping your genetics alive
for another couple years or yeah forever
right um
yeah it's it's it is funny how it really
started with orchids though yeah it
doesn't surprise me like I I used to
collect orchids quite a bit yeah it's
like a three billion dollar industry
it's huge yeah I just thought they were
beautiful and as I was learning I was
like well you know what's a kiki what's
that you know and then starting to learn
how people how people you know you can't
just pop seeds of orchids it's not like
cannabis and yeah it blew my mind that
you just couldn't go pop seeds of this
stuff why can't I just go get seeds yeah
they're dust the seeds are literally
dust
and you have to spread them out in Jael
media for them to actually start to
germinate but um what's cool about the
Cannabis space is I I
think because of the passion and love
and variety that exists and just
biodiversity within the Cannabis plan
itself this is I mean this this could be
one of the best mechanisms of getting
people into genetics right oh human
genetics can benefit from this
inevitably if we train hundreds of
thousands of tech technicians that know
how to isolate a merem that know how to
work with cell culture whether you know
working with certain hormones whether
you're telling a plant to to produce
chotes or roots or callus I mean all
these skills will eventually be
translated or translatable into animal
culture into cell culture into human
cell culture
so you know we're just we're just
scratching the surface with plants and
the beauty is cannabis is a mechanism
for this industry to grow because people
love that plant more than anything else
can imagine I mean orchids are probably
the second most popular or second or
first most popular you know maybe
irrational love um even though they're
incredible plants I love orchids nothing
against orchids but because of the
biodiversity and the genetic you know
the uniqueness of genetics with cannabis
people are going to be diving into this
and I think this industry and this this
science is only going to grow from here
I think so yeah it's similar I like to
say it's how the adult entertainment
industry develop the internet right
really started off with you know webcam
girls and chats and and really footage
but that you know created this explosion
with programmers and people that were so
interested in this space so you know
sometimes devices lead us into uh the
bigger picture but
um you know it's there's a there's a
long way to go uh there's still a lot of
applications that we need to find out
and Growers need to take the time to
figure out how it works for them right
I'm not going to tell you that tissue
culture can replace the way that you
grow today it's not gonna replace the
way you grow today we're not trying to
get rid of
your um I mean we are trying to get rid
of your mother room but we're not we're
not trying to get rid of everything
right what we're trying to do is say hey
here's a new tool that you can use yeah
right you've been trying to use a
screwdriver but it's not exact it's not
you know the grooves aren't aligning
quite right so this this is a a new tool
that you can add that can help you with
XYZ um and yeah it's it's all it's all
part of the process and I have a
question for you is is is pheno hunting
like as a as somebody that's into seeds
and breeding is is pheno hunting
expensive it right to do it right to do
it correctly I mean when you're talking
about feno hunting like is it are you
going and getting something from another
country and are you trying to have it
express the same way it Expresses in
that country at that point it's it's
it's a crapshoot like trying to get it
done and to do it very expensive popping
thousands trying to replicate the soil
density paracity what's what's what's
its makeup is you know um but when it
comes down to like let's say I want to
select blueberry from something um it's
a lot easier because there's so much
work that's been laid out before it just
having enough experience to know what
direction and why but feno hunting is is
everything if you're a breeder um seed
make if you're just a seed maker I'd say
it's more of a
marketing thing like hey you can get all
these fenos from this plant when ideally
when you're breeding you don't want to
have a bunch of Expressions a wide swap
of Expressions you would more likely
want a minimal amount of Expressions so
people can get a proven plant from a set
of seeds ideally and and for for you or
for some Growers obviously you know I'm
sure the timeline varies but what what
would you say is the average time from a
grower to feno hunt find traits and
expressions that they like and then
actually produce that plant at scale
three years I'd say would years three
years yeah to do it correctly to to pop
seeds do proper feno hunts run it once
run it twice run it three times to make
sure that it's going to be replicating
the same Expressions you saw the first
time and then yeah then if you want to
take it and breed it I would say like
you would feminize the seed to to speed
up the process selfit and go from there
maybe self it a few times yeah in that
case it would be seven eight years I
would hate to lose three to 10 years
worth of work yeah because some some
technician brought in a bug and killed
my my
plants that's just it's insane yeah to
think and yeah I mean people that do
spend the time and have the skills to do
that I mean I can imagine you get tired
after you lose a certain amount of
genetics and so we we need these guys to
keep going uh guys and girls you know
whoever however they identify to keep
going going because yeah no it's a lot
of work it's time intensive and so use
tissue cure please back up your genetics
please please you know help us help us
help you I've lost whole collections at
certain points and then eventually like
three years ago I was like [__] this no
more mom room nothing gave all of my
moms to everyone else and just started
working on my stuff from seed but now
that I'm getting back to um because I I
I literally stuck my head in the
blueberry genetics and until I have was
prod proding a perfect blueberry
smelling tasting plant reliably ined but
now I've got like oh man I need to go
get my mom's again [__] yeah you know
and now I'm I'm like man do I really
want to like 18 years of a mom room
sucks like running a big math I mean we
were we were running between 100 I don't
know at some points 180 moms to down to
30 to 40 but when people don't realize
like that's a lot of of moms you're
constantly cycling clone cycling clone
we weren't doing tissue culture so
you've got seven or eight clones of one
thing just to hope you don't miss you
know and and there's only a few of us
still doing that in the world and
they're not in major corporations they
don't even interact with them because
they won't you know and and what what
part of our job like I feel like or or
what we're doing with the breeder
Syndicate is trying to in trying to
break the the mold between what's going
on with the legal Market what's going on
with the traditional Market which is
where we're at and talking to people in
Academia and in science and trying to
link all those because like a lot of
people in Academia don't understand that
there's only a few historians in
cannabis that understand how everything
came to be and could put that together
because it's a really closed circuit of
people and everybody really deeply knows
each other and then getting those people
to talk to those people and linking it
all around so nobody ends up getting
screwed by the marketers in between it's
hard inevitably yeah yeah like I said I
still got screwed it going to the the
tissue culture market like and I thought
I I thought I thought I could be totally
competent I know cannabis blah blah blah
and still got worked so you know it's
it's it's slightly different and and you
know cannabis expresses itself a little
differently and in tissue culture you're
you're inducing stress this plant is
under stress this is not its normal
growth environment right so it will have
interesting Expressions right if you use
too many hormones it won't grow well
yeah there is a right and wrong way of
doing it and
um with people what I like to say is
just start basic don't don't play around
too much with hormones and this and that
just just be simple try it at its
simplest and uh we we do have like some
base protocols to use but um really
start there uh and then eventually you
can run your R&amp;D and of course strains
will respond differently that's the
that's the craziest part is the genetic
diversity will cause you know whether
it's due to the Turpin or the THC or the
CBD or you know a variety of other
factors one plant might not grow as well
in the same media as another plant
absolutely so this is this is why we're
still very much in that development
phase in figuring out how Growers can
commercialize this and with our formula
we've seen I mean the formula works for
I don't know maybe 90 95% of strains but
there are some outliers right and that's
that's where continued R&amp;D comes in so
we're never we're never done researching
we're never fully satisfied with our
products maybe PPM is the one product
that we really can't improve because it
it it works um but with Medias and
protocol there's always going to be new
things to improve on and so I know we're
we're coming close on the hour here but
one thing I wanted to mention that we
didn't talk about briefly is synthetic
seeds yeah are you familiar with
synthetic seeds oh yeah yeah um Dutch
Passion uh uh one of the uh Dutch
companies I think 15 years ago did a
small release of them and realized that
most people didn't know what to do with
them once they got them but it was a
great it was cool to see it but yeah
that's it that was the first time I'd
seen it brought to the Cannabis Market
on any scale and it was small it was
small scale that that's where the biocup
comes in so we found that there's really
two ways of germinating synthetic seeds
one is temporary immersion which is very
effective and then the second is
actually breaking that you know seed
coat like the the little gel coat and
placing that plant in media in Rich
culture media um but the implications of
this this are huge because not only are
transporting
plants problematic because they die or
they get contaminated but um now you can
get you can probably fit two
300 little plantlets we call them
synthetic seeds but they're actually
just they're they're little nodes from
the plant that'll eventually grow to be
big um you can fit two 300 in one test
tube and you can travel with it
everywhere I mean because they're not
seeds amazing encapsulated little
tapioca balls if you know if you look at
it but how does that work legally like
since they aren't quite seeds and they
aren't quite well I plead the fifth yeah
I like it's one of those things like I
just don't know that yeah I don't yeah I
don't I won't speak on the legal
implication not a lawyer and I won't
recommend one thing or another because
again not a lawyer uh we just we just we
just know the technology and how it's
used for different plants different
flowers spicy Tomatoes if you will um
but the the the biggest thing that your
Customs officers are looking for is soil
yeah right dirt brings bugs dirt brings
fungus dirt brings contaminants that are
foreign to wherever you're going so
that's the big problem but with a
phytosanitary certificate this is
certified sterile yeah this has been
fully sterilized you know this one isn't
but usually you know wrapped covered
sealed so so there is no risk of this
specific test tube infecting our our
food system or or animals or yeah so
this this eliminates one of the biggest
risks within transporting um and then
secondly just the mode of transporting I
mean it's so much easier imagine if
you're a grower instead of having to buy
a truck and you know putting these
mothers in a huge truck you can put
little pest tubes in a vial and send
them or drive them over I mean it it's
in the game changer with how much space
you can you can save and how much
efficiency you can take advantage of um
and it's just yeah it's just it's
another toolkit that people can use that
we're working on developing further so
first how long can these synthetic seeds
survive um so we're doing research on
that second is what are the best
mechanisms of germinating the synthetic
seeds and then third what are the best
formulas for those synthetic seeds right
to keep them alive to keep them
contamination free and to keep them
sterile so all of these points in
research are you know in progress are
being developed and you know stuff that
we will share with the community of
course uh whether it's via products via
protocols or just via training in our in
our classes but we want Growers to to
use all these tools accessible to them
to improve their operations right how
can you save money here how can you save
time here how can you create more space
efficiency here um at the end of the day
that's that's what this is it's it's
we're
optimizing the way that we grow yeah
whether it's cannabis whether it's
orchids whether it's pineapples um
they're all plants and they all require
the same thing light nutrients water
oxygen um and that's what we're doing
and it's it's a beautiful thing and like
I said second inning man still a ball
game we have a lot to learn and a lot to
do and you know we haven't even
scratched the surface at what point in
your life did you get into the Cannabis
sphere of this uh business you said it
was a family business right yeah so I
would say right around the time the
hempa was passed is when we started
really trying to better understand the
Cannabis space um because like I said
earlier you know Bill Graham is probably
the first and only Public public person
yeah he's amazing to really work with
cannabis and to publicize it right there
were you know University of Miss
Missippi has been I guess they had some
some
deal yeah
yeah University of gu I mean there are
these large institutions amazing
institutions with unbelievable you know
s zabya droya and people who've been in
this space who know the plant left and
right um but it was really hidden for 15
years 20 years maybe so I think people
really we we started getting into it
2018 um and connecting within our
network of customers because we we do
sell products you know a lot of these
universities University of goare these
these large companies already use our
products they already know us um so it's
just about you know sharing data or
sharing research we want to better
understand what you're working on why is
it important what are the implications
and then going to conferences like we
went to canmed and I learned a lot about
you know how to test for some of these
virus viruses and viroids how to um use
testing technology to better understand
understand uh or to better integrate uh
tissue culture and Commercial operations
with testing so there are more and more
resources now than there ever were
before what I tell you is five six years
ago I guess before we started on YouTube
you might have found somebody with an
accent on a w on a whiteboard or a
chalkboard yeah drawing you know stage
one tissue culture stage two tissue
culture writing out scientific terms
trying to explain it
but you know I appreciate the effort but
it didn't do it yeah right so we started
making videos so that I I myself could
better understand the process you know
I'm a visual learner I want to see it I
want
to um as I'm reading see what they're
actually doing um and so there are a few
amazing books like one's called uh
plants from test tubes brid and a few
other
authors amazing book very just
insightful easy way to learn but yeah I
mean hannabis Kemp
Canabis Camp cannabis had really I think
started seven six five six years ago and
now it's really kind of grown to his
life to a life of its own and really
helping support us and some of the R&amp;D
that we're doing or answering questions
and you know we're getting questions
that we never thought of that we can now
pursue because people want to figure out
how they can utilize this or or how this
can be efficient for the way that they
grow so it's it's really something a
gift that keeps on giving right because
Growers have
non-stop questions unlimited curiosity
and desire to see their plants healthy
desire to see their plants grow and and
and Thrive so um we're learning as much
as they are along the way and it's it's
it's beautiful right we're and and all
that information or a lot of that
information is public yeah i' love take
you to one of our parties where a bunch
of these old yeah old reclusive breeders
go and meet up and hang out could you
could talk to the to the guys that were
involved in doing this from the
beginning and
getting I mean we went to MJ last year
and MJ biscon and we set up at Flo Hood
just in the middle of a party I mean
there was so much smoke you could barely
see but we showed people what we were
doing right this is tissue culture this
you know big buzzword that you know you
thought would cost you $50,000 or $2
million no it's just a Flo Hood some
equipment and a protocol right yeah and
showing people getting them under the
hood giving them the tools like once
they
really simplify it and you know see it
for themselves it's not as scary as as
it sounds right yeah it is it is
something to learn but it's not as
complicated as uh requiring a PhD for
the very Basics right obviously you want
to run research you want to run the lab
sure you should have the the education
and we we recommend that but again if
you want to work in that lab if you want
to have the skills to to work under
somebody that has knowledge they can
share with you you know we can teach you
and there's resources online to to learn
and we classes are are a decent price
too like they're they're not super
expensive or unaffordable at all I
thought that was really awesome like
yeah
Ian pack of seeds though like so like
you know $400 on a on a basic you know
entrance thing is isn't bad at all
that's two packs of seeds for most
people a fish right you you can spend
four or $500 every couple months or
couple years on seeds or spend your time
and money on feno hunting or spend the
time and effort of cleaning up a problem
or you can invest in the knowledge and
let that knowledge pay for itself
knowledge is the most valuable thing and
especially with tissue culture knowledge
the companies that employ it have a
cutting edge now yeah they have the
first movers Advantage because they're
optimizing the way they grow which is
enabling them to invest more in better
equipment better processes better
products um so use it as an advantage
take advantage of the fact that the
information is out there now there's no
excuse whether it's our classes videos
online tons of Education there's blogs
there's there's an unlimited wealth of
resources and yeah start looking right
start reading start asking questions you
can reach out to us come to one of our
classes uh hopefully we'll do some more
shows in the next couple months or years
we're not going to MJS this year but um
I'd say we we'll probably end up at
spannabis I Lov spannabis oh yeah
yeah yeah there it sounds like a blast
out there I mean we set up the flo Hood
we were doing synthetic seeds we were
doing demos people were doing it
themselves I mean they loved it people
ate it up and then we also go to Orchid
shows we go to flower shows we're we're
involved in you know other Industries as
well of course um so yeah don't be shy
to to reach out and if we can help you
we're here to do it that's our goal you
know what's funny is like most of our
audience probably would never go to MJ
biscon or or I mean because the the the
corporate Market kind of shook out all
of the traditional Market already
they've already run through the guys and
used them got the whatever they needed
whether it was you know learning how to
do this and that or using them for their
connections or whatever so most people
don't even go to that anymore we used to
all go to um the emerald cup each year
yeah I've heard a lot about the emerald
cup it used to be the wild west where
like you know like we'd go and make a
Year's worth of sales in a night or a
weekend you know it was wild it was
awesome and then eventually they're like
all of you need licenses and then all of
us were like ah crap and so then there
was like one seed bank there that was
borrowing someone's license that sold
one year and then after that it was just
done like it's a shame because there's
not there's nothing else
commercialization yeah it's it's a
realist thing that's gonna happen we
always knew it was G to happen but um
watching watching how it's changed and
and who the big players are and the
passion that they didn't come with for
the most part I mean I'm sure there are
is one or two but like I don't know like
not without naming anyone there's a lot
of major the the major cannabis
corporations and it's like just been one
major push back like you're killing all
of the genetics and every everyone's
passion for breeding by constantly
letting the the the market forc cookies
down our throat under a thousand
different names and that's what that's
kind of where I'm at with it like when I
see anything runch gelato cookies sherb
it's all like the same expressions of
everything melded with different names
and and that's kind of where breeding's
gone so yeah a lot of our our mission
has been to get people interested in
other stuff that isn't like talked about
by rappers per se you know or like yeah
but it's hard it's hard it's it's it's
hard because we don't have the U the
marketing expense that like hey give
this rapper $75,000 to rap about this
this strain you know yeah and that's the
real way to do it but yeah it's it's
it's marrying a lot of different worlds
that probably never would have
originally met and nobody expected to
meet you know I mean what I'd say to
that too though is what sets you apart
from those big commercial grows it's
it's your genetics right yeah you you
have Budweiser but you still have micro
breweries yeah micr breweries anything
have continued to grow and I think
eventually maybe not but my hunch is
that you'll have these big Growers that
sell kind of dirt weed and you know
lowquality product and then you'll have
you know very Niche and unique strains
that can only be obtained from some of
the best breeders so to those breeders
and and to the world that is getting
pushed out via commercialization those
genetics that's that's your that's your
ticket yeah and you know your library
your your passion for finding the you
know unique Expressions I think that's
how you can differentiate because a lot
of these guys that are entering the
space that are large commercial they're
buying out they don't they don't know
what they're talking about no and is a
quick turnover for money usually in most
of these things they want to get in get
out make money get out so protect your
genetics is is is the is the moral of
the story is the moral of interiew
exactly please please please make sure
your genetics stay alive because you
spent time you spent money you spent
years or months
um investing in in identifying them and
growing them so keep them safe and use
tissue culture to keep them safe you
know after this interview um SS I'm sure
I'm gonna have a lot more questions I
have some here butt they would they
would run us into like two hours so uh
sure I'll probably bother you again for
some more time so we can run through
this and like yeah because there's
questions about Floy and all all this
other stuff that people want to know
using and assessing it absolutely let's
do it yeah yeah dude uh this has been an
absolute pleasure and and it's it's data
heavy but that's what I wanted so that's
what that's what people need and I think
that's want and they'll be able to watch
this over and over and over that's the
hope and we're just gonna continue the
conversation so questions are are
encouraged um as I said there's plenty
of resources too like if you have basic
questions or more advanced questions we
either have it already answered you can
just literally search on our blog for it
or um we can touch base and I can you
know I can share some answers as well so
like please you know we that's what
we're here for we're happy to talk I I
want to appreciate say I appreciate you
guys for for making yourself so
available like we had to resched this
like two or three times I was busy
knocking myself out spinning around my
house yeah so I appreciate and I'm glad
we got to turn it out yeah no you asked
some great questions I mean I love that
you came to one of our webinars and here
we are so that's the beauty of this
community and uh hopefully we can just
keep it going and and teach teach and
share this knowledge with as many people
as possible I'm the type of person like
if I go and I see someone like someone
doing a webinar on embryonic rescue I
know enough that I'm going to be like
are they doing it right or not and then
I'll say it exactly like stop it
[__] and and there's no [__] and
it just wasn't it was great it was great
so I app the idea no [__] here
that's right well I appreciate you and
uh yeah thanks and this will probably
air Friday so you know and I'll I'll let
you know when and where awesome man to
continued and uh looking forward to
talking to you again thank you so much y
I'll talk to you
soon want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate disc where
we get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out