[Music]
welcome to breeders syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
lived it i'm matthew owner of riot seeds
i'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
hopefully more people show up so we can
actually give a nice
treatise on the past present
um
future maybe i don't know if we can talk
about the future of clone trading clone
collecting i've talked about it a little
bit recently
uh um
about
a little bit of where people are that
have a lot of these strains archived
that are
rare and old and
special
but um
i don't think i've really given a full
long tail of how it kind of how it
developed over time
how it was when we were breaking into
the scene like how one would even go
about
collecting clones in the first place
because obviously you know a lot of it's
trading
and not everybody has something to trade
at the beginning
uh we'll talk about clone circles
yeah i got to give myself the own crouch
here
but until we start that anybody have any
questions yet
anything you want me to touch on so i
don't forget
anything
clown hoarding
i could talk about clown hoarding
there's plenty of clowns hoarding in the
seed industry oh my god there it is
yeah clown whoring
you could do that too
clown whoring
those bastards clowns are always whoring
around
clone people
well this is about clone people
i mean really it's but going to the
theory of it should
ben sherman fool you know
you know how i roll clay um
yeah i mean
it's all the same theory right like you
can you can take a theory and apply it
to
folds
it's very easy to do so hopefully you
guys can use some critical thinking and
apply it so i don't have to go and go
and go over every single [ __ ] that's
pretending to be in circles you know
it's it's a lot easier just to explain
it
before you know what it is or on a reveg
oh i'm not doing cloning um
tips and tricks but i mean just for that
quick one sometimes it's better to take
it on a re-veg sometimes it's better to
take it beforehand sometimes things root
easier after a revenge so yeah
this is george
george from walmart
okay
i think at 80 we can be close enough to
start this [ __ ] all right so back in
the day
clones weren't really a big thing a lot
of a lot of a lot of people were using
seeds when i say back in the day i'm
talking you know 70s 60s
on through the 80s up until the 90s
clones weren't the the primary source
for people to be passing genetics most
of it was done in seed form that's how a
lot of this started
on in through when you get up into
maybe like the northern lightsair would
be a good example
of
how of how people started getting in
these circles that had certain genetics
and were keeping them very tight and
only passing it to people in their
circles and trusted people and that all
kind of started because you know there
are different people in each market and
giving someone a special clone that was
considered elite at the time and the
definition of elite back then is a lot
different than now that is definitely
morphed but you didn't want to give
someone in the same
area as you the same exact clone
if it was super special
because they'd be knocking into your
market and and you guys would end up
competing with each other so you
basically set yourself up to be competed
against so a lot of times when clones
were shared they were they were shared
in different markets but they were also
clone crews that were pushing out tons
of weight and all pushing each other to
to brand a particular line kind of like
the northern lights stuff
um as you got into online
uh when overgrow was popping up and all
that you had a lot of people
that had amassed these small
little collections of clones during that
time some bigger than others but a lot
of them would amass these small clone
collections and um
provenance wasn't as much as a serious
thing back then
i see you saying clone hoarding over and
over and that's i'll get to it dude i'll
get to it for you um
but you see these people messy small
collections and as they would speak they
would learn to trust who was going to
keep their word on not passing said
clones and making it back into their
market and some people would just take
the clones and run and and do their own
thing rename it pretend like it's a new
thing and that's how we get to today
so as i entered
i wasn't i didn't have special stuff but
i was in california and unfortunately
there were a few places uh
what's
the best one i found was pnc it was a
dude named ape and i would say at least
80 plus of his of his things were legit
sourced he was a stray nerd like a lot
of us are still today and he did some
pretty good sourcing of a lot of og cuts
pure cushes
purples back then he did a really good
job sourcing i was just fortunate to be
in that area i also had a clone crew
that we were part of with the hogs
breath crew and in that circle people
were allowed to have the cut we weren't
allowed to compete we weren't allowed to
share and that was
that was super important we weren't
allowed to share with people outside the
group and that's how you ended up with
people like
you know the p91 crew the hogs breath
crew the bull rider crew
you ended up with all these different
crews with their one specific cut and
this is kind of before the og kush craze
when all that was going on once og kush
hit it was
it was a lot of fronting
a lot of pretending
a lot of fake sourcing
and it got really bad and and as the
online market
the online forums kind of blew up it
started to get more and more permeated
and a lot harder to verify sources
now most of the people that take this
seriously
take
provenance seriously in the first place
and when i say provenance i don't mean
anything more than
like like the term applies to art if you
if you have a painting that you have and
is signed by someone if you can't prove
where you got it from back to the artist
you've lost the provenance and therefore
it loses value
right
so
with clones it's very much the same
thing you could say i got this clone
from xyz but nobody knows how xyz got
that clone at that point it's broken and
people who are super serious about it
don't really want to trade with you and
they don't want to get in on it you know
um
so now we go to today
the trust in the market
is is all but gone
uh
people today tend to have popped up in
the last few years that are big in the
uh clone
trading scene that i'm noticing that
keep having the same mistakes
and it's because they're trading with
people that are new to the scene too but
have them convinced that they are legit
and connected to this guy or this guy or
this guy or this guy when it comes to me
and my friends we all know who we've
given clones to and who those people
have given clones to for the most part
there's always going to be exceptions to
the rule but for the most part we know
who has what clone of old [ __ ] who has
given it who had permission to get it
who didn't
all of the above and this still exists
this is still a [ __ ] thing
and people around
selling clones online
aren't a part of that those circles
they're not
they never they never were any of those
people selling clones online like that
with their big ass list like hey i got
all these [ __ ] clones [ __ ] source
from the breeder cut lovely these guys
are not people that would ever be
trusted with clones in the first place
from any of our circles not my circle
not the other circles that are old that
i'm not even a part of
no one's going to trust these dudes with
[ __ ] um
and that's where i'm seeing a lot of the
problems arise
check out your only radio ridge does
have a great only fans he's got this
great picture of his testicle amazing do
you know any verified cuts that look
distinctly different than in his picture
so
we get to the next topic verifying cuts
through pictures
there are a million reasons why this
can't and shouldn't be done and why you
don't see guys like me and inspector and
everyone trying to verify clones through
pictures
expressions and micro like in
microclimates and expressions things can
look totally different totally [ __ ]
different however there are a few cuts
that have certain traits that we know
always occur no matter what the uh
what the what the
expression is there are certain traits
that always pop out of certain clones um
the point being
you guys the best advice i could ever
give anyone is if you want to buy spend
money on a clone from someone chase that
[ __ ] all the way back to the breeder
they should be able to do that if they
can't do that then there's an issue
don't just take their word for it
because i've seen people saying some
wild [ __ ] [ __ ] that they're getting
past
chem 91 directly from a certain source
that didn't happen couldn't happen it
doesn't happen
um
and and it's it's sometimes it's hard to
get those answers but if you can't get
the answer then it's not worth getting
because every time i'm seeing people get
screwed
every time they go buy clones from these
doofuses they get screwed
so if they cannot trace the provenance
back to the original breeder there's a
problem and you probably
i mean you can always take the risk and
try but here's the thing if you're
taking a risk and trying but you've
never had the original clone how are you
ever gonna [ __ ] verify it and and
people with the chem 91 cut wouldn't be
selling it
not like that that's not how that works
so
uh yeah archive portland's a great place
to get clones archives as big a nerd as
anyone when it comes to provenance he
doesn't [ __ ] around so if you're getting
stuff from archive portland that's a
great source
um
but yeah i mean most of these kids are
just trading
clones
just trading with people who have no
access to anything and shouldn't have
access to anything and then some of
these dudes are cool and like they don't
understand this has gone on and they
repeat it and they repeat the story and
now someone else has that story and they
say but this guy is trustworthy yeah who
was the guy that you got it from was
that dude trustworthy probably not you
know
um
that is that is
the best advice i could ever give you
chase that [ __ ] up the chain
do not see places like harborside they
have people that they randomly get so
back in the day at least i don't know i
don't want to speak to now but back in
the day they would have random people
bring in clays or trays of clones or
they'd have their in-house cloner but
often they'd have people bringing trays
of clones you're trusting some random
ass that a bud tender trusted to bring
in clones and vet them
why why have you guys ever talked to bud
tenders
you know they know less than probably
you do even if you're a new person but
tenders don't get into provenance
sourcing any of that stuff if you want
to source something do it right
take the time meet people be friendly be
trustworthy don't be a snake and and
you'd be surprised how quickly things
open up i've told that to people from
day one and everybody wants to work it
around the around the back end i i can't
comment on finest because i don't i
i don't know who they source stuff from
etc but they've they've been very nice
and they've done great um tissue culture
work
but as far as
like
yeah i know yeah uh let's see
pre 90 379 500 a pop that blah blah that
pre-79 bubba
but yeah i mean
if you don't care
then you're adding to the problem
frankly that's that's really what it
what it comes down to if you don't care
and you're
passing these stories on without doing
the work then you're adding to the
problem
and that that's where i have a problem
and that's why you see all this
confusion in the market people throwing
up pictures of a chem 91 that don't look
like chem 91 you know maybe it's just a
really weird grow maybe they over blew
it but i see people commenting
in these in these [ __ ] threads let me
see for example let me see if i can find
it real quick
let me see
a good example
of someone oh you can't really see it
commenting in a thread that has no
[ __ ] clue what they're talking about
there's two currents guy he's new
he's probably newer than most of you
but he's telling acting like he has a
way that he can oh that might be a
[ __ ] hybrid i don't know
[ __ ] where did you source your
cam 91 to be making these judgments and
claims oh oh you didn't
oh you didn't oh did you say you sourced
it from one of my best friends
you're lying so it it's how it goes it
how it goes you know but then other
people don't know they see this dude
speaking in there they don't know that
he's a noob they don't know any of that
[ __ ] and they're like oh well if he says
it might be real then it might
that's how it goes
this is how the [ __ ] just spins on and
on and on and on how people set them up
up sell themselves up to be
a verifier of cuts when they have no
place verifying anything
um
and you like i said you'll be
hard-pressed to find someone that will
verify or shoot something down um i
could give you actually with with chem
91 i could give you a few pointers and i
know i've mentioned a few before
but um a few pointers leaf
cannibalization
that's nutrient burn that's not the
leafs cannibalizing themselves the one
trade it does seem to have is the never
ending white pistols but it looks like
someone just burned the [ __ ] out of uh
s1 or hybrid of chem 91
but in certain micro climates maybe
maybe it's hard to say
but i would feel much more confident
not even commenting on this thing
because there's no way there's no way to
know for sure unless it's got a lot of
the traits and it's missing one so what
can you do
anyway yeah i just wanted to give a
quick example um you know someone was
claiming to have a cut of archives
moonbow
oh cancel i didn't want to do that
someone was claiming to have a cut of
archives moonbow
well arc i've called him out on it and
then the guy's like oh no no no no i
mean i mean i had the breeder cut of uh
something else rainbow belts or
something it's another one that archives
not gonna pass cuts out his breeder cuts
out of
so be careful be careful who you trust
run these [ __ ] down
see what they know about
about sourcing cuts see who they're
dialed into circle wise
ask them
then glass some dudes in the circle
likely people will be honest with you
and tell you if they're in their circle
or not it's very easy to do
very [ __ ] easy to do
anyway
that's that's about what i wanted to run
down on that i think i think that it
used to be more common knowledge how you
did it you make friends
you get into circles
you don't get [ __ ] immediately because
everybody's been ripped off to [ __ ] you
know some people get mad that they can't
just get that clone immediately because
clone hoarders it's not fair you know
why it's not fair it's because [ __ ]
scammers rip everyone off
and it's been been that way since day
one been that way since day one so
people people that do have cuts are not
like super open to just some random new
guy who says hey i'm cool give it to me
i promise like that's been done for
years and years and years and years and
been heard for years and years and years
and it's a major trigger for a lot of
people um
people in these circles love to share
their clones
do i look way more serious
people in those in those circles love to
share their clones because they love
sharing dank with people
they don't necessarily like to openly
share clones with random people to
bastardize the clone
another good example of this had been
when everyone was trying to chase
joint breath for chems
you know i could i could go way further
into that but i'm not going to for the
sake of my buddy matt elite
not gonna
i'm not gonna talk about old p blood but
needless to say blind leading the blind
in that situation and people were still
paying joint breath for clones because
they really had that hope it's that fear
of missing out uh logical fallacy and
it's also the appeal to authority
logical fallacy both of those are there
the authority being oh well this guy's a
breeder he says he's a breeder and
and peat bud says he's legit
well that must mean these are legit
well how much do you know about how much
experience peabod's had with the actual
clones
uh
have you ever heard the story about him
bringing kim for as chem d to a cup and
entering it exactly
so
yeah
i shouldn't have probably gone that far
in but there's a point to it you can't
just trust everyone just because
someone's name is even linked with the
clone it's not necessarily a good reason
to
necessarily take their word on on clone
provenance
so yeah
anybody got any questions about that
the dog bud male exactly and people had
put his name behind a dog bud mill does
that make any sense [ __ ] no and
everybody else around him was telling
don't do that that dude's a liar that's
gonna be a problem and come back to
haunt you but sometimes money is just
too much of a
uh
yank i mean i really really liked bee
bud i did but i mean you know he was
backing someone who said they were gonna
murder me and someone who would say the
n word over and over and over you know i
can't deal with that i can't handle that
hopefully he's he's figured life out a
little better and who to run with and
who not to run with
oh i gotta go be going to church
just because i'm wearing a
long sleeve
mask g said he got a male knows that and
he's also said he didn't so
you know that comes back to it
i have a question where is the start of
the line to get my money back
you know
problem is many don't care
about history or the provenance that
make loot exactly and and a lot of
people in here are in here because they
do care about that and that's a point we
want to get everybody educated on the
same page
that oh no this is a
key lime lacroix
yeah these are the bomb that's pretty
much what i always drink
i haven't tried a fire sample of apple
fritter yeah i'm not a apple fritter guy
i've never
really
run that stuff so i can't comment on
apple fritter lumpy's giving me some
good cuts though before and they were
legit so
there is that
lumpy was a good source for the the
cookies and cherry pie early on
i brought as usual i brought out another
guitar by the way to show you guys just
because i can
i brought out the black beauty today
now this is just an epiphone black
beauty but
you know it's still very beautiful
all gold hardware i'm actually going to
change out these um
these pickups i have some um
toaster
uh hand wound pickups that are going in
it look a little more gretchy sound a
little more gretchy
um
yeah this is one of the babies though
all bound it's the old epiphone
headstock which i wish it would have
been one of the new ones that look more
gibsony but it is so pretty
isn't it
just beautiful
i don't remember why i got it if i was
thinking i was going to play some mike
nest style stuff or what but
yeah i'm not usually i'm the less
pickups the better but this case i went
for all three
shit's
pretty it's in this case
anyway yeah
leave it up if you can um this is going
to be posted on patreon after this so if
you guys are on a re-watch
run it through the patreon stuff
yeah this isn't a gibson case too i
don't remember where i got the gibson
case at for that one
are you a neck or bridge pickup kind of
guy
neck mostly neck i like the neck sounds
for punk rock and garage
years from now i bet you're glad the
headstock is og yeah probably huh i just
think it's so much prettier the other
headstocks are so much prettier
but yeah i mean
i wanted a gibson one
but in the end after owning a bunch of
gibsons and a bunch of um epiphones
i've determined i like the necks better
on on um epiphone les pauls i don't know
why like they they have something closer
to a gibson sg type neck
from my experience and i like that nice
thin neck because i've got
little lady hands you know
the the i'm not familiar with the
what is the story around the two tim
there's way more way more way more cuts
of chem d than just two going around
yeah there's way more there's the sham
deed the chem d
the dirty d
the dead ringer the bundy sis and some
of these are the same cuts just renamed
100 times
so yeah i mean there's tons tons tons
tons
even bodhi said his chem 3 wasn't real
yeah
that chem 3 came from a person that we
know past fake cuts the incognito
dude but
yeah
i really tried with incognito he has an
amazing seed collection by the way like
it's not just [ __ ] on the dude but
he did in interject a lot of bad cuts
um yeah
just grab some super
chem d from [ __ ] joe
you just got screwed black metal he's
one of the reasons we had this uh
little conversation sorry to hear that
but
[Music]
you know it is what it is
uh let's see one strain you recommend
from some
recommend from you someone that's never
got your gear before i think about right
berry v3
right now like with what's available i'd
say like bubble berry cherry berry any
of those just because they're so easy to
grow
um
yeah yeah black metal i mean we talked
about this a thousand times on this show
yeah
so for the people new to it tent flow
actually has screenshots if you need to
see them
um
so yeah that dude is not cool at all
not cool he's also he docks me so i mean
he's a
dry snitch
i don't know why anybody's [ __ ] with
that dude i made it real clear real
[ __ ] clear about old [ __ ] joe
no i don't an sd cat
that would be a surprise to me never
heard of the dude when i was down there
yeah
in the j crew
to [ __ ] a bad sherman man
sherman
but yeah i mean you know buddy's one of
the archivists that i take very
seriously i love bodhi um
radio ridge has been doing an amazing
job of sourcing legit genetics for a
long time and even before they even talk
about them they run them through a lot
of people to make sure that they have a
legit cut before they declare having any
kind of cut which
uh
yeah no it's the same guy black metal
you're definitely talking about the same
idiot
um
another dude let me give you another
example today and this is one that i
probably should have [ __ ] slapped
down much harder earlier on where is it
where's the fake bull rider well maybe i
don't have a picture of it ready
um
this one dude was showing fake pictures
of bull rider is this it
that
this dude
is dude nobody no no san diego
old-schoolers respect this dude have
ever heard of this dude before that um
he's a complete [ __ ] he had made
claims that he and his partner made
afghani bull rider and he didn't know
that there was a difference between
afghani bull rider and original bull
rider so now since he's been made aware
of that he's now claiming he has
original bull rider which is dead
um
yeah there is that there is that little
situation that is not alive anymore
never mind that though that's just
details details details
um
yeah that if anybody wants a real bull
rider cut the closest you're gonna get
is old betsy and old betsy hybrids right
now um
and there's plenty of those available so
there's no reason to
uh even even [ __ ] with someone that
stupid heard of pnw strain hunter i have
not
i have not
where did skunk one originate from
uh
that's probably the most
known story in the history of cannabis
and most documented uh sam the skunk man
what is a true dg two blueberry people
say dj shorts i went through 23
blueberry cuts to find the one that
smells like sour milk and muffins
dj
was the one who popularized
the
line called blueberry but there have
been other cuts called blueberry that
didn't come from his stuff from around
the same time
so hopefully that helps
um
what else we got
writer is correct
yeah the rx farmer that was the afghani
bull rider i was referring to not the
old bull rider that i had in my backpack
back then it was called bulgani
yeah black metal i'm guarantee it's the
same dude same dude we've all been
talking about there's people in here
have been ripped off by that dude that
can tell you just as much it's not on my
word
anyway
what are some
old clones that are still around that
you would like to get your hands on
old clones that are still around i'd
like to get my hands on purple indica
but it's not even you know what like
even stuff like that
by uh via uh archive to csi csi is super
honest with clones and sharing and it
was asked not to share so i've still
never grown purple indica pure
so like a clone like that i'd be very
interested in
trying to think of some other one oh the
corn the corns another one i'd be really
interested in
um
let's see what is the relation of old
betsy and bull rider sister stock
the the the cuts came from the same
person so yeah
and guys like brandon rust wouldn't know
that [ __ ] so
but i bet after this he'll be repeating
it like it's [ __ ] some [ __ ] he always
knew
see that's a problem there are
double-edged swords to
uh
putting info out there like this
yeah i i ran some metal haze back in the
day from um dutch flowers we did some
metal haze crosses it's it's a very
interesting
uh line pretty sure it's positronics
haze 19 crossed a skunk one that
uh positronic sold for a long time and
it was renamed
baby yoda i've never even heard of baby
yoda to be selling it for a thousand
i mean
you know
again
it's possible to buy clones that are
legit
but know your sourcing always ask
questions don't just assume
like and i get it's very like you want
to be that one dude who can
source something
and and be like oh i'm the
be like i'm the one who got it yes i'm
one of the very few rare
people that have this rare cut but
nine times out of ten that's not going
to happen it just isn't
so tom hill hayes skunk one no
tom hill's haze was a selection from
positronics haze 19 but it probably was
nothing like the same pheno because
there were so many different phenos
so but similar yes
uh have you run much of the legends your
primary stuff firstly yeah that was some
of my favorite stuff back in the day i
ran um
let's see from chimera sassy frass
mental floss mental floss was my
favorite out of the chimera stuff um
let's see what else from legends johnny
blaze
legends ultimate indica
there's another one
but yeah those are the the top ones from
both of them that i really really dug
how about that archive post dude selling
one yeah we talked about that a little
bit ago yeah it's it is what it is
that's what what kind of is is helping
foster these situations is is people
like that you know
but did el jefe verified cuts of his
elites so jeffe what jfe did was he made
it into our circle and i remember i was
talking about
uh people that get into circles and rip
people off and get booted out that's
exactly what he did um everybody in the
circle was very open with each other and
with clones
and
jefe got a lot of clones from everyone
in the group and ripped everyone off and
immediately started selling them against
everybody's wishes
um
he's one of the reasons
a perfect example of someone who's a
[ __ ] piece of [ __ ] that does that
luckily he lost most of them
and um
and some of them he was handed were fake
so we can be thankful for that
but um
yeah
it's a shame it's a shame
what's a one cut that you haven't worked
with that you would grab if you could
i'll go with corn on that one just
because
yeah
if it was hilarious until he wasn't i
agree
um
he he damaged and burned every bridge he
possibly could have [ __ ] had
which made a lot of sense because he
when he came to our crew he didn't
really have any friends
porn is an old cut for uh that archive
has
you'd have to ask him what what it
actually is and the story behind it i
don't remember
what was purple pain there were a few
different purple pains but purple
champagne was supposed to be the the
derb the f1 dirt it's been called a
thousand different things so
stay trippy uh who is who is he
with the fake death star
i don't know
how big a fairy phenom variation would
you see in chem 91 s ones i haven't run
them but um just from observing people
pop them online and talking to csi it
sounds like it has a fairly good amount
of variation stuff that looks like sour
all the way to stuff looks like pure
afghani
i don't know what copy genetics is
double purple doja um
i don't
that was that's always been pretty rare
so if people pop up at the day i'm
always skeptical but um
fairfax selection according to icy mag
forums but there's more than one corn on
there a fair fact selection i'm not sure
it might be four-way selection
it could be could be did jeff take make
afghani bull rider i don't know i mean i
i i smoked it sold it after any bull
rider bud but i never really cared
because it like who did what because it
wasn't bull rider
didn't have anything to do with it i
don't think
how's the nl preservation project going
great going great
uh
death star i didn't know el jefe used a
death star
so i wouldn't know
um
i wouldn't know
that [ __ ] from woodshed was ridiculous
he brought that to a party uh i was the
first canned illuminati party and he was
just invited in to come to the party and
he showed up with his death star he'd
been [ __ ] banging on about how dank
it was and i took one look and one
smells like
[ __ ] you got skunk one you got
skunk one bro and if you can't tell that
you shouldn't be trading cuts
but yeah i don't know this is [ __ ]
funny
yeah that [ __ ] was garb though
i mean it was okay for skunk one but you
know it wasn't death star that's for
damn sure
didn't j i don't wanna i'm not gonna get
sit here talking about some [ __ ]
nobody the whole time
uh i'm looking forward to that project
too across the nl5 to one of those p91s
that's not a bad idea i think that could
be very nice like a
older afghani base
yeah that'd be really cool
i've already talked about that like i
said i'm not going to keep bringing up
or spending time on a [ __ ] nobody but
yeah
death star og is great too i'm not sure
which one you're referring to or what
that is
um
yeah so that's that's a rough treatise
on
how you should verify cuts how you go
get these cuts
um
yeah it's really there's not a great
shortcut i'm sorry
it's not a great shortcut
sometimes it takes years to get a cut
and sometimes you'll never get it
just is what it is you can't
people calling things elites
has caused
a lot of
different ideas about what these cuts
are and how good they are everything is
subjective so
what i consider elite may not be what
you consider elite but back in the day
it was a consensus value given to stuff
if something kept getting passed because
there wasn't the online hype system and
instagram for pictures and what's what
not if things kept getting passed it was
because they were naturally hyping
themselves because they were dank and
after a certain point enough people
agreed that this clone is dank that's
how you got in a league cut nowadays
it's anything that gets thrown on
instagram that some hype schmuck wants
you to think you know is legit
okay what do you think the relationship
between super skunk and chem is if any i
think chem 91 is a pure super skunk
um that's just my best guess but pretty
pretty sure on that one
first class genetics is the number one
in legit cuts i'm glad you know that
because i i don't i don't i don't know
that i'm sure the guy's nice but i i
just he's not in our circle so i don't
know
um anything about what he has
[Music]
what's up fatty gainesville green's
still going around i've never seen a
real cut of gainesville green in my life
uh i've seen a lot of fake cuts of it
anything about fire alien ramen that was
og rascal and it was a seed line
oh you have cuban black haze cool that's
what i was talking about like that
incognito guy that's one of the ones he
brought to the table along with ken
three and fake mass super skunk so
yeah
y'all getting y'all getting skunked
y'all getting skunked
um we got some stuff first class i can
fit you in definitely not unhappy that's
good see that's a that's a good good
call
as long as this stuff you know what it
is in the first place before you get it
otherwise i mean
things can be
this is where some confusion also comes
in because things can be dank right you
can get a fake clone that's super dank
probably even better
than the than the clone only however
does that make it legit
you know you have to know the
you have to be able to identify
something in the first place before you
can uh
verify it
yeah you just gotta know you have to
know it in advance
what's the difference in amherst sour
aj salary csd
amherst sour
new to me i mean like i get like people
were saying it was from amherst so
someone smacked amherst on the front of
a sauerkraut i don't know anything about
that sauerkraut i only know ecsd the
choco same thing
the aj sour was very dank but what aj uh
considers his sour
now was nothing like the old aj sour cut
so yeah
salt and lime never heard of that no
see like the cuban black case a lot of
people like it
but is that what it is
i don't know
don't know i know where it came from and
i know that
it
i know the provenance on it and that
that guy passed two other fake cuts when
he passed that cut
so yeah
yeah the archive cut of sour would be
the same thing as the choco the ecst et
cetera
so those are the same exact cuts
if you're comparing archives versus
choco they're the same cuts who was the
original train wreck so the original
train wreck
supposedly was nothing like the train
wreck that got pushed by ae
in the arcade train wreck it was much
different before that but the one that
gets passed the most is like that lemony
torpedoing one
and that's what most people
yeah
mandel crotch put the amherst on the
name again no surprise
do i think the aj sour i used was the
original sour no i think the choco ecst
is the original sour i do
but i mean
who knows again that's not one we can
take back to the total beginning because
there's no
true
there's no true like agreement between
the original guys that had this hour
on what that sour is now
i don't think any of them could identify
it today by any stretch of imagination
and we tried we tried to get him to do
it so
yeah
found an incredible train wreck fino in
bubble gum breath crosses
that me
why is there a train wreck fino's in
bubble gum breath crosses that's weird
i i maybe i don't know what bubbling
breath is
little timers in amherst that said it
was the original sour originally from
new york upstate it is from new york
upstate but it was not called
uh
amherst sour no one's ever called it
amherst sour back then uh
as far as i know it was called our
diesel and that's the original name
so yeah i mean people can call whatever
they want but they shouldn't if they're
talking about original sour
it's not super debatable
possibly a couple sours at first though
yes
yeah
yeah and the other original name for it
was the manny from those guys so
there is also that
i don't know what mendo breath is
basically mendo perps and train wreck
men of breath is not
mendo perps and train wreck bro it's og
kush breath
and uh
probably a
mental purpose train wreck but og kush
breath being the main part of it
cam dog had fake chem 91 in high times
why would you trust any what any of them
say
that's hard
hard to argue with
are there land races that get as
commonly knocked off as ties
i don't know on that one
i mean i don't i don't know
in your opinion what breeders are
killing it right now and why um a few
episodes ago i did a long list of
breeders that are are people that i
trust and that are doing some cool [ __ ]
so yeah that you hit back a few episodes
and you could probably find that
moon tide that's a good
that's
another fair statement like like those
those smells don't necessitate a lot
more than
most of the things associated with like
the skunk files and stuff like that
skunky dials are hermaphroditic
tendencies and low potency and that's
for for real
but people want what they don't know and
can't have
so many old elites look like ugly ass
plants i guess terps and highs were a
bit more important for a lot of them
um
i think in modern times people equate
looking good with dankness
um that would be the instagram era of
growers and i don't agree with that at
all not even a little bit some of the
most beautiful [ __ ] like blackberry kush
is some of the
worst
potency
on earth like you know mental purpose is
[ __ ] beautiful
not super potent you know but it has
great terps
um
yeah
there's any name any cookies hybrid i
don't think it's that [ __ ] great but
it's pretty so it sells yeah
um i'm not sure yet pyramid i haven't
run any yet
that's right gene geno's what's up
can't smoke with your [ __ ] eyes boys
yeah it's uh
it's like the people that that run tests
and think that's a great example of
uh
how to pick your weed and what to sell
by thc volume but you know they did
people haven't even looked at the
entourage effect at all
um
hog's breath is a beautiful example
isn't it yeah it's not it wasn't the
most gorgeous but it was one of those
ones that hyped itself because it was
[ __ ] dang
that's absolutely true
mean [ __ ] a gene
we're gonna get jean on here eventually
eventually he will do it he will do it
and come hang out and shoot the [ __ ]
do you think microbes and fungi and soil
contribute to the flavor of weed i think
uh the root zone is where
it does all that that exchanging of
stuff so sure i think sulfur
um
added sulfur helps with with terps and
stuff like that um
yeah favorite came to smoke
i liked chem one because it was so
different than the other chems and i
like uh diesel other than that if we're
just saying like just cam chems
well
i guess that would depend on what chem
is right uh chem 91 no 5 haze chem 4
is one of my other phase
what's a strain that subverted your
expectations because of how ugly it was
colombian black
it was beautiful to me because i knew
its potential but it was just an airy
mess of tiny little
um
tiny little
bubbles of bud everywhere
but it was it was amazing smoke
yeah the lot has a lot of that same look
that like the colombian black did just
stringy
you know
um a lot like uh
what people called grinspoon that was
originally quays
what happened a good widow
probably the same thing that happened
with everything else from the 90s people
just overdid it got sick of it lots of
renames
um
lots of bad impressions of weed that was
not widow
stuff like that
how do you feel now that tissue culture
has really started to gain momentum and
become more available with honest people
ask fatty i haven't ever since i got
screwed by by mooney moon dog on on
tissue culturing i've stayed so far away
from it and don't care
because it's just a bad experience but i
know my boy fatty's been doing some some
cool [ __ ] with it
uh dog walker og is kind of ugly but
smokes fantastic i i think he's kind of
pretty it smokes great though
he got he did not get the cut from grace
goal
brandon did not get the cut from
grayskull because grayskull doesn't have
the [ __ ] cut grayscale will tell you
he doesn't have the cut i had the last
of grayscale's bull rider seeds and they
weren't going to pop so they had to take
him to a
tissue culture guy not sure what's up
with that since then but brandon did not
get [ __ ] from
[ __ ]
grayskull grace wouldn't
never [ __ ] with that kid god wouldn't
say but i mean and again brandon rust is
a noob but people just think for some
reason because he says he's not that he
isn't
people are liars you gotta ask the
people themselves
why don't you ever smoke weed during la
is one i don't want to get them shut
down too i can't answer fast if i'm
stoned
just can't i've tried a few live and uh
stoned and that just doesn't work out
well
so
either you want info or you want me
stoned one of the two
but you can't have both
yeah i don't know that gray ever had
bull rider um he had the seeds that we
had here and that's the bag seed and
that was that
as far as i know
so yeah
know what you're talking about don't
just trust people because they say
they're legit and old school and they
show a picture of a plant and veg saying
it's something
don't
don't just accept that is as true please
i beg of you guys
don't because it all it does is is [ __ ]
everything up
where can i get some cuts of steve
murphy afghani i'm sure you can find
someone that'll sell you some steve
murphy afghani if you keep asking around
i'm sure brandon russ will sell you some
of steve murphy's afghani
yeah
um i don't know anybody currently
keeping cuts of steve murphy's afghani
how is the csi nl project going it's
going great going great they overgrew
everything really fast it's obviously
some kind of afghani hybrid which is
what we want from uh uh nl5
um
that
gives more truth to what it's supposed
to be because we are always going to
keep making sure that it is what we
think it is
do you know what steve murphy afghani is
yeah afghani or actually that as it was
told to me it could be a pakistani or
afghani they weren't sure it was a girl
who went over and brought them back to
steve murphy so it could be pakistani
afghani but she was so it was picked up
somewhere along that line
weasel with the diesel say sour d came
from his headband siege which is chem 91
northern lights
so weasel with the diesel has told so
many different stories
respect to him nice dude but i
i've heard too many different stories
coming out of dude's mouth to be very
reliable but we do know vondo and vondo
has been the most reliable and
consistent when it comes to stories
about the sour
and um
and yeah weasel with the diesel knows
vondo too and they were roommates but
he's been the most consistent and out of
the spotlight wants nothing to do with
any fame
glory from northern or from sour so yeah
how was golden coast vintage afghani it
was a short squat
little creamy
hashy afghani
nothing great
but uh it was
pretty anything about cause i don't even
know who cosmic wisdom is sorry
um
uh would we get a shawnee kid he just
did an episode with me
how would you describe the nose on
instructure on pakistani to troll kush
depending on
uh
depending on the phenotype you can get
like blackberry the green fino showed a
lot of lemon and there's a lot of
terpenoline mixed in but there's other
notes too
um
yeah caleb would be the person i mean
csi would be the person to talk about
that anywhere vondo's story can be found
we brought vondo into our circle and
interviewed him extensively and i just
told it to you so
that's about the best place you're going
to get unless you're friends with them
so do you believe that sour cake from
head sour came from headband
those guys can't even agree on who
named headband let alone um
any of it i've watched
several people from that group including
ajj and and maybe one of them did name
it but
jj says he's named it aj said he's named
it and i believe klopp said he's named
it uh
weasel so
who knows who knows maybe one of them
did maybe one of them didn't
but sour was before that so it would
make it very hard for sauer to come from
headband how do you pick a name for a
strain
don't ask me i come up with dumb ass
names
if you're if you have autism and you're
trying to make friends and be social for
cuts that's gonna be pretty hard um find
a group that understands that i mean
we're all
i would be hard-pressed to find a group
of
seed makers that are real serious into
this and real serious into collecting
that aren't on the spectrum in some way
shape or form
um
most of my best friends have some
level of
autism spectrum
blackberry was a backseat by soma blaze
correct probably mendo perps
um all of it's probably meadow perks you
can find everything that they described
as blackberry and mendo perps so
i'm guessing it's meadowpurp's bag seed
that they didn't want to
admit favorite terpenoline dominant
clone um i really like the amnesia haze
uh
um the colombian black that's another
one
fly deport and ship yourself some yeah
there you go
that's there you go
thoughts on breeder love in her eyes i
don't know anything about them they're
very new to me
i don't know if they're new to the scene
in general but they're very new to me
some pretty pictures though
uh no
nebulous black bear was from sonny's
black russian you're backwards uh black
russian was cherry ak-47 new blues
blackberry and anima's blackberry was
probably from mendo perps
what makes an og and ogn are there so
many cuts out there is it
just about there being similar traits
and a bad seed story yes
roughly yes know anything about the
blood durbin csis i do not
there were a lot of different blackberry
cushions out there
uh sonny's black russian it wasn't
sunny's it was um
the black russian was me boos
hebrews
so you try to like the chem one yes it's
very different from um
the other cans it's not super what
people would associate with kenny
however
i think it would be great in a cross
with dog [ __ ] because they are both nl5
haze dominant probably some skunk one in
there too
um
it i think you'll get more of a
traditional dutch
um
nl5 haze type by running across the two
then
most of what i what
other stuff you could buy right now
what are you growing now uh
i'll put that on a back burner for now
talking about it just because i don't
want people
saying that they've made what i just
made so yeah i watched the original
diesel episode the other day have you
ever ever seen the forum thread of when
cam dog visited sub cool at his house
yes headband was one of the strains kim
dog had yes and kem kem dog himself has
told me he's never had headband
you know i guess it just depends on what
day you ask
i like i like chem dog greg he's a
friend i really do but um you know
unless you have
copious notes it's been [ __ ] x amount
of years he was really young when all
that was going on it's very hard to keep
track of any of that
urinal cake
that sounds lovely
come come smoke some urinal cake with me
hockey puck urinal cake
but yeah
um
cook hits that was a good name i agree
i think you would really like this
super glue cut
afghani northern lights yeah i mean when
i see stuff like northern lights in a in
a um
in a lineage like that where there's no
number to it no nothing and knowing
which northern lights were over here and
which ones weren't
it are already i mean it could be super
dank but i couldn't never use it in
anything because i just wouldn't can't
chase the provenance on it and i can't
say what it is unless it was super
exceptional you know
i'd be surprised if anyone remembered
anything after hitting circle that's
true
that's true
have you ever seen any ethiopian strains
making its way up yeah there's people
that uh people
people have sold ethiopian strains
before i don't know much about it in
that can you talk about true csr
well i can't i didn't understand what
you're asking
have you smoked the metal haze buddy is
about to release i've smoked metal haze
plenty and bread with it but i don't
know about the one that he's using
uh anything about dr atomic been trying
to get him on the the show we'll see how
it goes
uh did you get your f1 dirt back nope
not yet any idea what the harsh chemical
spray paint permanent marker fumes type
smells could come from
different terpenes combinations of
thiols terpenes
esters etc
who is real humboldt seed company
hso hsc csi well
csi is a humboldt original
hsc was the first person to have
humboldt seed co but i have no respect
for them for many other reasons and hso
split off i thought i think i may be
wrong but as i've heard it's one of the
people split off from humbled seedco and
started humboldt seeds org
where does the african haze come from
which african haze there's like senegal
haze that was a combination of two
african land races with no haze in it
um
yeah i don't know
yeah i've been trying i've been working
on dr atomic but he's not he's not a big
internet dude so it's been a little um
hard but i think it would be i think
he'd be a great person to interview he's
been around a long time he's you know
made some cool [ __ ]
bubble man mentioned the clones dog game
we're covered in p.m
those were the days
yeah i'm not sure on um
i'm not sure on the african haze from
i just
i haven't kept up on what he's been
working with
any other questions about provenance
clones
genetics in general
anything that i might know about
have you tried any transki south african
strains i have tried transki tried swazi
early in the early on durbin um i wasn't
a big fan of south africans if i'm being
honest like they tended to be
high
high yielding commercial grade for
africa
which is
you know
i dressed up for this i dressed up for i
dressed up for you
let's see
thoughts on reversal sometimes plants
don't sack up they're more look like
bananas normal
yeah um different reversals go different
ways did st george make girl scout
cookies absolutely not that's a [ __ ]
story
um but it is a story that keeps being
spread nonetheless i've actually tried
to get a hold of him to put his story on
the record and they will not do it
will not put it on the record but it
would be easily trounced
um i did ask the original cookies dudes
to
uh
talk about it and we'll see hopefully
they will hopefully they'll be
interested in it what terpene or combo
of terpenes make blueberry smell
mercene and then different
ever run out any of skunk man's gear
back in the icy mag days yes the um ty
hey skunk one
um
what else did i run a [ __ ]
there were a bunch of freebies that were
given out by sam the skunk man back in
the day i did run some of the uh the
stuff that they sold through dna is the
skunk train that salmon made too
who is on shingolos
talking about it st george or maybe he
was just [ __ ] being a dick to me
either way he's not the dude um
that's that's it's pretty well
documented uh where cookies came from
pretty well documented does the trinity
cut you are all using a berry terps no
um
i think that the people who made cookies
know what it is but don't really
don't really want to put the full recipe
out there
i it's very easy to remake cookies
so
um
yeah i've heard what st george says it
is
but
yeah i don't know it's one of those
things where
uh so many people want to take credit
for it that there's so much [ __ ] out
there
what is up with seed stunky that dude's
a [ __ ] lop
he chose to go with corporate [ __ ]
and
uh got booted from our scene
of friends because he just chose to work
with snitches that's what happens
cherry pie pakistani to trolley no way
in hell no way in hell or you'd find
constant terpenoline digging all that up
um there's no urkel or og kush
in
that combination so yeah
no plants tell the truth people tell
stories
i always go back to that
cookies was life changing oh lord
any backstory in starfighter no
that was already when i stopped when
that plot came out i had already stopped
paying attention to everything like the
new people were doing
any work with you in small boat on the
back burner no i smell boat's been doing
his own thing he's you know he's got
he's a daddy he's got life so he hasn't
really been um
he hasn't really been doing much but
yeah he's a good dude
one of the friends i hope it'd be nice
to see him get back to it also because
he grew really dank we need always bring
it to me
you think cookie's og i think there's a
little bit more to it but i think most
of these expressions that you see in
cookies is an og oracle combination
yeah you know um eddie leapfrog was
responsible for a grain sherb
uh that is different than the cookie fam
shirt
um
one is more responsible for skittles one
is just not
that's why there's a lot of confusion
around that i've heard m39 yes skunk one
uh and then another skunk one
northern light five haze or just skunk
one and all five i can't remember um i
think it's skunk one in all five haze
some combo thereof
the male pakistani chatrol was an urkel
morph get out of here with that [ __ ]
yeah out of that yeah that's [ __ ]
silly that is silly
basic five is the nl5 version
that ssc was using in
m39
yeah
nl5
skunk haze
i think what's the optimal thc cbd
church percentage it depends on what you
want out of it for your body chemistry
any thoughts on dick horse genetics
never heard of him never heard of her
never heard of her
ask the same question over and over even
though he keeps passing it
uh
i don't know what you're referring to
i'm trying to catch everything
how much about the hardcore og clone
from west coast cuts no i don't know
anything about that [ __ ]
ever try malawi gold and i'll fly face i
have not yet not yet
what can i expect to find in your cherry
gmo skittles
some cherry jim some cherry pies some
gmo and some skittles and everything in
between
uh that's the most honest answer i can
get because there's tons of phenos it's
a poly hybrid
what regs you got for something you'd
recommend any of the blue bonnet stuff
i'm happy with all of it it just depends
on what you like out of weed that's the
the most honest answer i can give you
know
best way to stabilize a home that's a
winner it just depends on the actual
clone
um it depends on what you want to get
out of it if you want an uh something
that is as close to that clone as
possible it's going to take lots of
breeding
what out of your current line what's
your current go to when you smoke who i
really like the cherry berry a lot um
um
the blue resin cush's [ __ ] bomb um
i'm a big fan of blue like berry ogs and
stuff i think they combine really well
especially if you get that like
fruit loopsy fino out of the og pushing
some berry that's that's some beautiful
[ __ ]
how do you stabilize a herm it depends
on the line
it's not there's no just one
method for stabilizing all herms terms
things hurt for different reasons and
different lines and different
combinations
the blabba kush i too loved blue bubba
too how did bodhi make appalachia he did
not
uh hai and lonesome made the appalachia
and that was
green crap crossed a tree dog
nobody knows the true origin of the
skittles gene would know he's up there
with those dudes
it's up for debates apparently
i know some people are more confident
confident about it than others can you
talk about bubble gum and how it got to
holland
um
victor if i remember correctly victor
was the dude that brought it over the
seeds you can find it on adam dunn's
25th anniversary of bubblegum i think
that's when they had victor and
um
two trees on and that was the most
legitimate as far as i know the most
legitimate story that has been given
about that
would you say seedfinder.you has legit
info
sometimes i mean anybody could add any
info i've never added a single strange
seed fighter and all my shit's up there
and a lot of it's wrong
so anybody could add info up there and
if anybody could add info up there then
there's bound to be right and wrong
yeah i don't that illinois
bubble gum story is kind of suspect i
don't that was not a victor story that
was an adam dunn story so i don't i
don't buy that so is there an
appalachian male
appalachia was a seed line so yeah there
were males females there was all kinds
of stuff
uh
i think it's a f4 f f4 last by high and
lonesome
who's dick do i gotta suck for some
legit green crack s ones i i made some
back in the day if you could find
someone with those they're legit um
i don't know i might make some more soon
we'll see
but uh green crack is much harder to
source than it was at one time i have
seen so much green crack and so much
fake green crack since
jean's 100 confident that nobody knows
well then you're
gene knows he's there
he's in that friend circle of everyone
that was [ __ ] around with uh the
trays and
and the green sherb and all that [ __ ]
uh
what strains are great for headaches any
it just depends on your brain chemistry
uh i'd love to give people answers like
that but i just wouldn't be honest to
just be like yeah this will work for it
you know are you gonna bring back the
purple drink back wasn't it gsc it was
gsc
cross 2 let's see
you know i don't remember them all in it
but i know it was during the suge night
og
cross to the west coast dog
uh trying to remember the moment it's
been a long time
what is fake green crack usually not
real green crack
it's a green crack's pretty easily easy
to identify visually or smoking wise
is green sherb also called key lime pie
some people call it that some people say
they're the same thing i've only ever
had key lime pie i've never had anything
in my hands called green sherb so i
don't know
uh not sure
jean might know that one better
butterscotch g13 g13 wasn't around when
the butterscotch wine was passed around
but there was a g13 hash plant that was
as anyone yes dukey bros kettes gills
yes that's the one that csi uses
that is the skittles cut that i know
that i've used it's uh not a very
healthy looking plant
it's a little
wiry and wrangly i don't know
what do you think gene on the on the
dookie brothers i'd refer to guys like
gene and and and csi that are up in that
area
because they're actually interacting
with those folks down on the ground
there and seeing things like down on the
ground
and they'd be much better to answer
those questions specifically than myself
that skittles cut sucks i'm not gonna
lie that thing's a piece of [ __ ] um
i get why people like it because it is
terpy but
it just structure wise it's a piece of
[ __ ]
who's got skywalker og uh who knows now
i've seen a million different skywalker
ogs
isn't key lime pie sister to thin mint
yes it depends who you ask
uh vs cheat wizard any inside of the
green curry cut it sounds like whatever
he had as the green curry cut was the
same thing that we had as diablo og down
in san diego
um it was like a
spicy black peppery
with og terps it was very specific
i tried the original chili verde that
actually smelled like chili verde back
in the day from hbk it was bomb it was
unique very very [ __ ] unique
um there's other chili type plants in
the gmo cherry skittles
but yeah that was cool
yeah that chili verde was was tight
old school spice live blockhead no
lineage was it project 19
what was that
african something project 19
it's been a long time since i've been
asked that
what's up with hbk i haven't talked to
him um a lot in a while but i need to
get back a hold of him i should probably
give him a call
we live close together and we've been
friends for quite a while um
i guess burning bush nursery said key
lime came from them and it's a gsc fino
hash plant looking thing
huh i don't know i released s1s of the
the the key lime pie cut they were very
very frosty but they did look i they
looked very skittles-y and the skittles
looked very similar to that
that
the cut that
came from jodry i will say that
he's been bumming oh that sucks man yeah
i'll give him a call
males and world filo taxi what gives i
see it often on males in some lines
specifically chem 91 pck f2 it's
interesting
it's not like necessarily a male trait
but maybe it's something from those
specific genetics being
combined favorite shitty strain there
you go ortega's sweet
i take a sweet tooth but what's the
where's the project 19 in it in
blockhead
is it project 19 or take a sweet tooth
that might be what it is
that might be what it is but i remember
ortega sweet tooth you are correct about
that being in it wasn't that louie
so is it p19 louis
louis being legends ultimate indica
since that's what ortega's sweet tooth
is
i can't remember
i can't remember at all
or is it just p19 sweet tooth
is giddle skunk one dominant no not
structure at all
um
terps i could see some skunk one in it
but i wouldn't say it's skunk one
dominant as far as like the expression
the structure or any of that
cream sodica
cream sodica was from
that's a spice of life one too no no
that's right fatty you guys did grow a
bunch of the blockhead they had um
who was it was chrome's cut chrome
chrome
from swamp boys had an amazing cut of
blockhead amazing i think that's one
that was down there with um tiara rojo's
crew
it was cool i like that that kind of
blockhead
nigerian silk i'm not i never tried
nigerian silk or any of it so i couldn't
comment
did burning bush i have no clue on that
when it comes to the
the progenitors of like key lime pie and
that stuff i have no clue
have you ever had any mango cuts yeah i
had a bc mango cut
mango haze oh betsy's kind of mango-ish
uh green crack is very mango
yeah a bunch of different kinds of mango
what was the highway man
i can't remember that one
what's that district uh homegrown best
guess on closest relative to which
tk star dog oh that's interesting
blue dot that was an old uh
collective clone for a certain place and
i remember there was a second blue dot
that came out i don't know what was used
in the um
dutch flowers
uh blue dot stuff that was made to make
used to make blowfish
not so headband l.a kush let's see
you know if you have any other questions
i'm happy to answer them
um this will be up on patreon after
this when you plant scenes you remember
them seed one through three hundred or
one through twenty right one through
eighty well we did about i think only
like fifteen
strains i was fifteen seeds on this
female one and the number twenty was
just popping and you plant seeds you
number them seed one through 300 or 1
through 20 right 1 through 80. well we
did about i think only like 15
strains i was 15 seeds on this female 1
and the number 20 was just popping you
plant seeds
want more breeder syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsheets.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
you