welcome to breeder Syndicate this is
Matthew I wanted to do a quick talk
about our Punchy booster drop now it's
not a normal drop like most of our drops
and I tried to think of a way to
kind of walk everyone down this journey
with us
um while we're doing it we I've been
doing projects since the the initial and
second blue bonnet drop which was almost
I think three years ago now and I've
I've continued doing the work and
working through the lines
um we did some work with the the
blueberry McMuffins because I wanted to
see how that crossed
um what was in that line what was in the
the F gens of that and I was interested
in working that into other Bonnet lines
and and so forth so
um there's been projects going on in the
background people always ask what am I
up to and I don't really ever have great
answers because it just is
what it is like I you know like am I
gonna share that I'm doing boring stuff
right like going through lines is kind
of boring so I thought of a way to be
able to open this up to some of our our
our like patreon members and stuff that
want to go through some of this stuff
with me and it makes it I mean you don't
usually use testers and it makes it so
like
I can see the wider pool and all that
like you know I've always been one of
the people who pushes back on using any
sort of testing because I'd like to see
all the results myself but at this point
it's more of a fun journey through a
line I truly I I feel like I understand
it and
um yeah so I have some stuff written out
um hopefully it'll help illustrate some
of the the drop how it worked what we're
seeing what you can expect so you can
you can get an idea if you even want to
go on this journey and if this is
something you'd be into and if it is
which one of these lines would be
um suitable for you so during my journey
through the the several blueberry hunts
over 17 years of operating I've come to
some deep realizations
at some point when you've worked with
enough a line enough specifically the
blue bonnet line and how how it breeds
so to so many different clones that I've
worked with for just as long that it's a
completely predictable breeder for me
now I I it's rare
I don't think I've experienced even
superstar that I've worked with a ton
and understand and understand traits I
don't I can't read what it's going to
breed like like I can with blueberry
specifically
um if that explains that a little more
so I wanted to take the work further
into double and tripled up Bonnet
hybrids in a way ensuring constant steps
to work away from inbreeding which is
the blueberry breeding trap but because
it's so predictable I can cross it to
several known cuts and know how they
will cross this is a peek at some of
that work I've been doing with my
breeding Apprentice here locally space
invader he was one of the guys locally
that I met some years back that happened
to watch the show and be local and was
just super passionate about taking his
whole grow game to the next level by
learning breeding Hands-On and he's been
an excellent student we did a few
different crosses however we were
focusing on five main hybrids letting
people see the work that's been going on
over the last you know three years as we
dive deeper into these lines
uh
tester name number one these are all the
tester names nothing is um
solid just because like they weren't
ever meant to be released these are just
tag names [ __ ] like that
um creamy punch so this is the cream
cross to plunge Punchy blue stir the
cream's original name tester name was
Silverberry so a lot of people knew it
as that it would never had a big release
because uh and I'll explain uh when
doing the initial crosses of the blue
bonnet I wasn't giving the silver Pearl
mom at the at this point when I was
doing that even at this stage of
friendships we don't ask each other for
cuts it's gifted when people feel like
it and it's done out of respect on both
ends so it's not like a stingy type
thing it's just how it works
um I was given a few silver Pearl s1s a
bit before the drop was done by souvenir
seeds I found one of those that was a
taller version of the mother similar
nose in resin production just a bigger
apical Cola and not a squat so you're
about five and a half feet tall and was
so much faster than the mom uh but she
had beautiful resin production and
beautiful tert profile and most
importantly the high
she was put in the room as filler space
because I wanted to know what Bonnet
crossed to with one of the pearls
because it's one of my favorite shirt
profiles and bonnet inherently like I
was doing the bubbleberry and to me it
was a bubble gummy type
smell and um not like pink bubble gum
but a different type of gummy type smell
um
anyway yeah I I wanted to get it crossed
in some sort before catastrophe happened
I work I work on Murphy's Law we call it
riots law around here because it is so
constant the worst [ __ ] that can go
wrong well so I try to operate with that
in mind uh so I made these seeds but it
was asked not to let anyone grow them or
sell them at the original perfect Pearl
Blue Bonnet cross
um
let's see I waited a few years and
eventually was given permission to let
them out and sub Rob did a beautiful
grow of some Stellar individuals that
were right in the middle silver Pearl
and bought it just extreme resin
production and a berry take on the
beautiful bubble gummy baby boo I've
never smelled the baby poo but everyone
else does so I'm just gonna say it's
there for most people right it's it I
just don't smell it
um with a stellar Buzz that calls back
to the Mexicans of old I definitely see
why neb spent uh and Neville spent his
later years searching for Hawkins that
reminded him of the early Pro work it's
absolutely my favorite work with Nevin
Rob and it stood the test of time we
took the best selection from the cream
and I believe there were four females
that hovered right around the similar
expression that we liked
um they should read similar but only one
way to find out
now this Punchy mail that we used for
all the all the Hybrids was selected
using trait selection method visual
trait ID I did When selecting the blue
bonnet mail the vegetative material
smelled like blueberry way more than any
of the other bonnets or the countless
other blueberry iterations that run
um
he simply has all of his family sticking
up at 75 80 degree angles from top to
bottom looking like he's raising his
hands
and I've now selected that trait in the
white monit Punchy bubble Berry the
right Berry V2 and every single time
when I use a mail from any of those
lines that had any had that trait he
passes every single visual trait that
that Bonnet does
um that Bonnet male did I should say
even in his Punchy hybrids in these he
lets the banana punch offer in some
beautiful and much needed yield for some
super commercial viability because
Bonnet on its own is a delicate cushy
smaller yielding girl and these are
serious chonkers coming out of The
Punchy lines inspect a lot of grape and
blueberry with this really wild infusion
of bubble gum but not pink bubble gum
bubble gum and sickly sweetness that is
just coated in resin that's perfect for
bubble hash and washing The Punchy and
Bonnet lines are specifically bred to be
washed and The Punchy brought a level of
resin production to some of these lines
that's staggering even in the realm of
deep chunk standards for this hybrid
some of these clock in between seven to
nine weeks blueberry is fast as is
silver Pearl if you want to if you want
speed and flour and turnaround time with
insane quality this is the one this is
my Riot pick for all the Hybrids as
being the one most people will be
receptive to
all right The Punchy booster f2s tester
name Punchy twister
this one has been a journey well it
originally made The Punchy line I was a
bit dismissive of people's reception to
me using a clone like banana punch I'm
not adverse to using modern lines
however during the time I was more
focused on old stuff so it was a a bit
of a range you know a bit off the range
I love skunk tax cut he brought to me of
his selection of symbiotics banana punch
uh shout out to the homie who made the
punch Supernova Gardens too like he
doesn't get nearly enough credit and
he's just a wonderful Dude and despite
people hating on punch for its potency
they don't have a [ __ ] clue on this
and and what this can do for breeding
there's cuts that you grow to crop and
some of those are crappy breeders gelato
three or sorry gelato 33 best example uh
good for cropping But Trash for breeding
in my opinion it's fully inbred
commercial cookies at its worst and it
just evolves
um I've tried with it so I'm speaking
from experience as the first dummy to
make the s1s of those cuts and then
sometimes there's cuts that have more
value inside of them than can be seen
with the naked eye or observed by
smoking it sometimes it's the actual
genetic data inside that needs unlocking
with the perfect partner I find Grape
smells and blueberry jam smells to be
ideal Partners in a lot of cases with
this being the prime example I did
30-something Bonnet crosses overall in
the initial runs and um just to take a
few forward and it was a hard Choice The
Punchy f1s were given away as a
promotion to help start a seed bank for
a friend that no one has ever heard of
you know like you know how you do for
friends well that was one of these uh
that was how we got to see a bunch of
these dried out really fast and people's
minds were blown my mind was blown uh
the breeding potential of that banana
punch cut was unlocked and Game Genie I
I'm old that dates me I know but you
know game G by the Bonnet male and that
Bonnet mail is special and unique enough
to pass that linked visual trait with
raisleys Punchy booster f2s while
inherently being more diverse than the
original release will still hold very
true to the original looks and smells on
it is uniform and true breeding and for
several traits that and that really
tightens up the generations as a whole
so expect way more uniformity than
you're used to seeing in f2s we have
great Kool-Aid great fun dip blueberry
jam blueberry grape explosion double
grape Berry cheesecake all caked in
resin and beautiful shades of purple
like the folks love and demand at
seriously potent High delivers the THC
percent that all the uninformed custis
demand to have and the two percent for
bonnetwork is crushing the game right
now and regularly over three percent
total Terps and in some crosses over
seven and a half which is not an
exaggeration it's it's it's something
special about this line uh we're here to
break every tradition and idea of what
blueberry is and how it should have
always been
um flowering time with this one is going
to be eight to nine weeks the occasional
seven fast lady really proud of this
line and the work that every that's been
done by everyone leading up to it it's a
labor of love and one I'm very proud to
put my name on
um the another one we did was the the la
Kush Headband of nachos across the chem
dog d by CSI Humboldt
um and we crossed that to Punchy
blooster the tester name is not so
Punchy
um so the homie space invader was
already running and doing selections of
his own uh
when we were talking about starting
projects together and his growth of it
sold me on his capability the selection
of it is strong strong super strong it's
how a double up of Super Skunk goes
right and it happens often when you
introduce the LA Kush and not a Kush but
a super skunky sour diesel type that
natso dog calls headband and kebdog D we
are pretty sure it's chem 91 Super Skunk
however you know people have stories or
reputations to protect so we can pretend
I didn't say those parts out loud for
the sensitive folks over there and that
corner
um so right away I was like this makes
sense for the project both not so and
CSI are some of my closest friends on
Earth and we can make a line where we
could see all kinds represented
um if I could have found a way to
smuggle and pack in h l it would have
been perfect but obviously less uniform
uh we'll get there one day so what we
get here is a different take on the
Super Skunk double up great berry
explosion what occurs is usually a
middle ground of berry grape with booty
font mostly popping up with a lower
percent of bland diesel types with
pretty banging highs and not much Berry
and a small percent that are this
beautiful tiny little acrid Berry type
that are hardly yielding but you know 10
grams of plant but like this is this is
in small pots and stuff like that but
they're tiny little yielders
um given a proper veg time and root
space this expression pops up regularly
in lines like this the skunk spray can
Blue Bonnet sour Bonnet and a ton in the
day record diesel Blue Bonnets so if
you're a hunter and want to find
extremely triple dank head stash that
will like white out your friends check
out this line uh of or any of the others
above like a lot of times would be 8 11
weeks because a diesel type is involved
you will see the 11 weekers push their
way through from time to time
number four the GMO root beer Funk bag
seed
um not really bag seed but it's it's
it's an unknown I guess
um Across The Punchy booster we call
this what the [ __ ] bro WTF bruh because
like it's it was confusing right
um it took me a minute to remember
exactly what these seeds were that me
and skunk Tech had run through my seed
blowers of the house
you have one line of a hybrid
um with Mean Gene that I enjoyed called
GMO root beer funk
I'm a super black licorice and just
really Stony and strong
so a few years later I was cleaning out
old stuff and found the bag with a few
creamy seeds and said screw it let's
toss those in and see what comes of them
so they're amazing plants but the smells
were not in the direction I would have
anticipated and to be honest it reminds
me of a bland old Afghani line
at first I was disappointed because it
wasn't like anything turquoise I wanted
or was expecting
and I didn't want to sell this as a
blueberry root beer because honestly
that's not the the chirps that I'm
seeing you know in in the Expressions
we're using and that wouldn't be fair to
anyone involved right like anyway
um the customers Gene skunk techno so I
wanted to State here what we have is a
super potent blank canvas to apply
crunchy booster to and there's genetics
for the black licorice smells from the
root mirror reap boat
root beer GMO Funk are there
um it just takes a little dig and
there's extreme black licorice goodness
in those those mother plants
um
overall we decided it was a really good
and worth releasing despite the name
confusion and really felt like it
deserved a real transparent explanation
on the chirps and because one of my
favorite things in life is getting
emails from people telling me that
they're the first time Growers of my
stuff and for the first time they got a
plant that looks and smells like that
breeder said I love that and I'll live
for it because the first and foremost
I'm a grower and know how rare of an
experience that's become especially for
folks using cookies and gelato because
it all looks like Gelato at some point
to pop a pack of seeds and have potent
high in terms exactly as described since
I'm new to these lines combined on the
mother's side the prediction scale is
completely unknown however I expect
purple is grape and Berry and tons of
resin to sneak in at any moment
flowering time would be somewhere
between eight to nine weeks um
it's super potent and worth exploring
it's just like I I
am very hesitant to not give full
transparency on it because of what it is
how it you know how it came to be and
that the name doesn't quite match
the genetics of the names don't quite
match what we saw but that's not a
representation on gene or anyone else
that was just a small pop of what was in
the bags anyways
um number five
so we call this one Friendly Fire for
now
um this is the first Bonnet triple
Extravaganza loose gittles crossed a
blue bonnet across the blueberry
McMuffins which is the Mac one blue
bonnet Across The Punchy booster banana
punch Blue Bonnet so three-way injection
this is the first time I brought three
of the Bonnet lines together one I love
the resin production on and ease of
growth on the Mac one I also like the
challenge of teaching people how to get
that clone to make Siege reliably for
them during the blueberry McMuffin F2
round I had popped in some of the very
few Skittles clone only crossed the
Bonnet seeds that looked viable enough
to pop I never popped that line or sold
it because so few seeds made it to
maturity because of the chaos and moving
grows Etc so I was stoked to see how it
combined with the Bonnet later on and in
a 10c pop for females were all Z
dominant in Terps the looks were clearly
so much better cell growth structure
stem wise with Skittles as well as
budget structure overall Beauty potency
but I couldn't bury that Skittles chirp
in one move with the bonnet so I figured
let's toss it into the Mac one Bonnet
Repro room when the Mac one took it back
seat to the Bonnet
um the hybrids of this are insanely
gorgeous looking like more compact cushy
versions of back one the chirps combined
with more Berry coming through but still
extremely Z dominant so the last fix in
my opinion would instead be to try The
Punchy round
um a line that is terp dominant to most
Turk donut to most with heavy grape and
Berry this project was done to not stack
height bees necessarily it was done with
the intention and goal in mind of
combining the winning looks of the Mach
1 cut some of the z-turp with the very
more of a dominant feature I stacked the
deck in my favor based on what I've seen
in my experience and using Bonnet and
blueberry to try to pull this one off
if you'd like
you could be one of the very few that go
on on this journey with us to see if we
met this goal or others in this project
I'm stoked to finally have a solid crew
of Good Growers to put all this stuff
out there to test and really give
unbiased opinions with this line expect
seven to nine weeks flowering time lots
of sea of green types more squat Afghani
looking things with beautiful colors and
just built for smooth washing
extractions and that pretty much covers
the um I don't want to say it's a drop
because like we're only letting some out
like we have a bunch of seeds we're
going through them ourselves and we're
letting just a few packs out while we're
going through them
um
people are interested so here's your
chance uh yeah um I want to thank
everyone you know this is a wild Journey
we've been on trying to reinstill like
interest in in genetics period like I
really feel like that was an art of
reading that's been lost interest in
breeding in general so people have a
better understanding of what they're
reading when when the seed makers say
they're doing certain moves or genetic
moves and and all the stuff so yeah I
hope I hope all this has been helpful I
hope uh anybody who runs these lines
finds it helpful feel free to send me
any questions hit up me anytime on the
Discord
um and and the Discord has a section
that's open for free to everyone now so
no one has any excuse not to join
click the link Tree in any of my BIOS or
any of the YouTube videos or any of the
Instagram bios and you'll make it there
um thanks for showing up