welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
what the plan is today
is to
to get a review down
on
the three different Punchy selections
so I'm gonna smell and smoke some of
this fine Punchy friend grew
and uh like try to get a review down
of the different expressions and it's
kind of cool because these ones have
cured all out a little differently so
what's cool about these punches is that
they have uh like most Berry stuff like
most blueberry stuff
um it can be really strong on the plant
but once it's
once you get a chop it can go earthy
right
but a lot of stuff can especially the
blueberry stuff can cure extremely Berry
it can cure extremely chocolate it can
cure extremely what else is in here
um
there's like blueberry candy blueberry
cream blueberry there's this one's like
raspberry chocolate right now like in
Scent anyways but I want to see how it
passes to taste one of the other things
I noticed the other day was the one that
smelled completely berries tasted
completely black licorice which is
something new to me I've never had a
black licorice tasting strong Bonnet
um expression and this is Punchy so
maybe that's why like it was modified so
hard but it's impressive it's pretty
cool so I'm going to start with uh let
me see if this is hot enough first let
me see if my anal ones first
so I'm gonna use the rip for this
because obviously that makes
for the most accurate of flavors
and I'll start with number two I believe
number two
was the keeper that he ended up my buddy
who grew this ended up keeping but
um yeah I'll see if it's my favorite he
likes to hide the best from it he likes
the potency the best from it and I think
he liked the Terps the best from it but
he still wants to pop more because he
wants to find one that he's specifically
looking for however like like with me
like the number three to me so far has
been one of my favorites my personal
favorites but a lot of stuff is down to
preference how we smell things how we
taste things differently
so it's always cool to get different
perspectives on
the same Bud from people who have
experience with it
all right so this is The Punchy Blue
Shield number two for those who don't
know Punchy booster is a purple punch
banana OG on it
so this is the uh number two hopefully
this is hot enough we'll find out right
now
it looks like I'm going down on
something sorry guys I might be
ah there is a soft Berry in there
that's nice there was a soft Berry in
there
okay okay buddy I see why you get this
one this one's nice
all right
now I'm gonna load up another Bowl here
I wish that
uh how good is a blue sour seed I mean
you know it's all perspective but I know
that uh
I know that people love it and like if
you love sour there's everything from
Pure blueberry jam to full on burnt
rubber sour in and everywhere in between
okay
oh wait I'm simple that was blue three
no wonder that's the one that I tended
to like the most so far so let's see
what this one this is the Bluetooth so
this is his keeper
I was like yeah let's just keeping the
wonder why it's the one that I like most
so
yeah it's just strong strong deep
blueberry scent which I love
and like I said even after a few weeks
of curing they're just killing it right
now on the blue Terps
all right see how this one uh differs in
flavor since the scent is very similar
very very similar to that to the three
gotta wait a second while it warms up
oh and the other thing with the rip I
noticed is you gotta suck it slowly like
it's your dad
um
or I don't know it just it's pointless
to 30 seconds super hard because this
the air goes down so it's slow I don't
know that's how I felt it worked best
though
yeah
okay so this is the one that has a
full-on black licorice taste to me
so this is the key for his keeper is the
one that has the [ __ ] black and I
just think that's interesting
do we have the number eight just
raspberry chocolate like when you get
those uh chocolate res raspberry filled
chocolates from the store
that smell and taste is what this smells
like
is raspberry chocolate which
um I've seen blueberry chocolate and
stuff cure but I've never had this hard
raspberry tone with the chocolate in the
Cure
and I love it
absolutely love it
there's a whole lot to love about
um DJ's blueberry line uh you know I
mean like
he gets cracked on for how it was made
you know Crossing
sisters that were
narrow Leaf to broadleaf repeatedly in
multiple Generations it's definitely an
artistic take on breeding not a
scientific take
um by any stretch but what it did allow
for was a lot of really beautiful
Expressions to come through things like
raspberry chocolate and whatnot so
um that's special but I don't know what
this one tastes like under this and
we're gonna find out
we will find out
see if it has any of the
raspberry chocolate
all right you're
so totally Berry on the front
it's got great flavor
I know I don't taste a lot of the
chocolate it just tastes like blueberry
the scent is all raspberry
chocolate
that's a lovely taste though
that may be one of my favorite tastes
out of all three as far as the berry
goes the eight
ooh there's a lot going on there
huh
very interesting I like what I'm getting
from all these a lot
my buddy did a killer job on the grow
which of course is to me is everything a
lot of people say ah without shitty
genetics blah blah blah but without a
good grower what good are the genetics
you know like
it's the way I look at it
super Berry super super Berry
it goes to show you not everything
tastes like it smells right
you just want to edit and post on
YouTube's review I think people love to
hear your reviews from your own lines
yeah like I said yesterday yeah I'm like
with the reviews on the YouTube channel
it um
man it's hard to
it's hard to review my own [ __ ] because
I just don't want people to think oh
this is so self-serving who gives a [ __ ]
with mad stuff's like I want to hear
about other stuff so
you know there is always that um
divide there and I try to keep that in
consideration but at the same time like
yeah I'll probably that's a good idea I
think I'm gonna take that advice Jab
I'm already doing it right might as well
put it up and edit it and put it out so
real quickly I wanted to apologize for
the audio and the review uh of The
Punchy stuff I did it on Instagram live
and it was done with the uh iPhone mic
and is what it is so apologies there
um but I also wanted to end the review
by thanking the person who sent this in
um he likes your main nameless in our
crew but he's one of our crew members
and he's just a really really talented
sweet sweet dude and
um his grows are exceptional exceptional
and I I have really really thoroughly
enjoyed
um waking up
the past month and being able to smoke a
bunch of blueberry because some of my uh
some of my boys are pushing it really
hard on my stuff so props to them shout
out to them and uh yeah I'm really
really proud of these lines there's some
cool stuff coming out of it so uh
definitely go check it out righteats.com
all that stuff you'll hear the
advertisement like it doesn't even
matter so yeah go check it out just
wanted to shout out to my boy say thank
you
killer job
doing great work great grows
um
yeah not much more I can say about that
I'm I'm really happy with how these
turned out and uh if you dig blue
um it's a great place to look there's
also a lot of grapes in it
um but a lot of this stuff is cured up
more blue than anything to me but it's
also like Impressions like one of my
other buddies got one he thinks it
smells more purple Punchy so
I spent a lot of time in the Blue Zone
so I can get those fine nuances out and
maybe maybe I tune out some of that
stuff but yeah like that's the whole
thing about multiple people doing these
reviews multiple perspectives on
everything and that's what's most
important because we don't all smell or
taste the same
with that
see you next Friday
our show tomorrow
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out