your purple Mr Nice I know that went up
in your area did you did you grow any of
that yeah purple Mr Nice is a little
weird
um in the sense that uh
it
it's got G3 it's supposedly got G13 in
it yeah you know and it's one of those
things that when when Neville lost women
never went to jail for 11 months and
then Scentsy got him out of spent since
he gave him a bunch of money and got him
out of jail and bought his Seed Company
um some of the things that were common
in Neville Seed Catalog didn't Port over
yeah to Scentsy like any of the G13
hybrids any of the hash plant hybrids
um the maple leaf all disappeared yeah
and then in the late 90s after Neville
left the maple leaf the G13 The Afghani
one all those things started popping
back up yeah and I don't know if they
pulled them from seed but I think that's
where it came from yeah is Mr