welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate so tonight's show this is
going to be the second week in a row
that we have to do some stupid dance
where like we air it live and then well
I'm going to intentionally take it down
after um just so the crybaby scammers
don't report it that we talk about
tonight so um we'll have the Vio Vimeo
whatever it's called links up the audio
podcast forms will of course be up um
but yeah you need video for
context and um yeah other than that like
it was kind of funny to watch and and
you'll see um phos pop up like a turn to
punch B hiding behind other scammer
websites um I'm just gonna keep playing
whack-a-mole with them I don't give a
[ __ ] so anyway yeah I hope you guys
enjoy the show this is just kind of like
a little pre-announcement so like if you
want to watch it watch it live with all
of us you can hear the commentary or
whatever in chat as uh or see the
commentary in chat as we discuss some of
the um goings on during it and probably
have a Discord chat after I don't know
we'll see how it goes um but yeah I'll
put up the video link
in um the description for the audio
version I guess so that you'll still
have the ability to watch the full thing
because they have a lot more trouble
reporting it
there
[ __ ] want to sit at the table with
The Syndicate check out our patreon in
our link tree or description below our
merch site is officially live we have
all sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies
to sort you out and shipping is super
fast and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together together and solve
old strain history together daily it's
an amazing community of learning away
from IG and it's an amazing resource for
old cataloges and knowledge we hope you
join our Union of breeders and Growers
come check it out