now this is one of the hardest parts of
seat cracking and you have an old seed
that is really expensive and really rare
and you want to give it the best shot at
life I don't recommend this unless
you're really good at hand control and
you've had a lot of practice as you can
see the seed is sitting here between the
scissors
normally this would not be ideal but if
you know what you're doing you can just
slightly crack the shell without
damaging the embryo the idea here is to
get water into the seed shell that's how
seedling embryos form when you put them
in to germinate is when the water enters
the shell it begins the process however
some seed shells are just too thick for
water to get in and a lot of people
think this is like a dud seed that's not
necessarily the case it may just have a
thick shell in the case of that this is
what you need to do so you just gently
take it you hold it with your hand you
put it at the very top top top part as
far as it'll sit in there of the seed
because that's where you have the best
control over the scissors and gently
you'll hear that sound
and that means the seed has been cracked
now there's nothing coming out of the
seed I don't know if I can get this
thing to [ __ ] assume in a little bit
whatever there's nothing nothing coming
out of the seed you don't see any juice
or any [ __ ] coming out of seed or
anything just the lightest crap of the
shell that's what you're trying to get
to here and from there you just put it
back into your wet paper towel treated
with three drops of hydrogen peroxide
for every 2000 ml of water put that
[ __ ] right there oh my god there we go
right there right there and she's ready
to go label her up and put her back
in this case this really isn't an
expensive seat but it is a seed with
hard shell it was a can of copious BC
roadkill I want to see how how wrote
killing this each chunk cross is going
to be a lot of resin which is awesome
but let's see if the roadkill is the
true really kill skunk or not yeah
there's so many claims to that I've
never seen one in my life
well not since I first started smoking
anyways during my breeding life never
seen one and there we are that's how you
do this part of the seat tutorial