this is the riot seeds Advanced
germination tutorial um I used to have a
pictorial up a long time ago the
pictures disappeared off the site so I
decided to do a video and keep it
updated um first part here I'm showing
you all the components you'll need from
beginning to finish over there
antibacterial soap hydrogen
peroxide this isn't necessary but I like
to use green soap to keep my hands super
clean andure that everything in the
environment is is pretty spotless um
something you're not seeing I clean the
counters with green soap um just so
there's no potential contamination
that's what we're trying to avoid here
um over there that is 200 mL of
distilled water okay there's a pair of
scissors you may or may not need
depending on what you're going for um if
it's a hard seed to crack uh and it
won't crack on its own it won't let
water in on its own we're going to use
the scissors but if not let it be uh you
have a Ziploc baggie a dropper a Sharpie
a paper towel and some tape tape will be
at the end anyway so let's start uh
let's see let me get a new piece of
paper towel there cuz I like to have a
piece of paper towel on the counter just
in case anything goes wrong um in case
any little bit of contamination is still
there it's just that one extra
barrier so what I do is I fold the paper
towel into I think eth is what it is one
two that's in a quarter quarter size
right now and then one more time the
eight now this is the most important
part this is a part nobody ever [ __ ]
talks about um the biggest reason seeds
don't quote unquote germinate and and
they actually do germinate but what's
happening is a bacterial process is
stopping it from completing
germination um oh [ __ ] first before all
that before all that
wash your [ __ ] hands I already did
this so I'm not going to show that on
it'd be too hard to show it anyways but
wash your [ __ ] hands wash it with
antibacterial soap right away make sure
everything's clean like I said I use
green soap right after that to make sure
that my hands are completely [ __ ]
spotless again you don't want bacteria
getting to the the tap r um but yeah
with the germination process a lot of
people think seeds don't germinate if
they come out a little bit and get mushy
no they're germinating bacteria is
getting to the Tap Room
that means you were almost there but
some kind of contamination happened
that's what we want to avoid so we use
uh 3% hydrogen peroxide this is hydrogen
peroxide you can get any this is
Walgreens I think um and we have a
dropper here now there's 2,000 ml give
or take 100 or 200 mL in this pitch this
pitch has been thoroughly clean with
green soap too it's a little old so it
looks beat up but trust me it's clean
all right so we
get our dropper let me see if I can um
let's see do this so you can see it get
our
dropper put a little bit of hydrogen
peroxide in it I don't know if that got
any yeah it did okay so you
see hydrogen peroxide right there we put
three drops in this whole thing one 2 3
good um just dump out the remaining
[ __ ] take this little wand just so you
don't have to have an extra tool
available and stir that [ __ ] make sure
the hydrogen peroxide is in there very
well good also this goes in the water
everything needs to be washed what I do
is I just spray everything with green
soap at the beginning everything and
then wipe it down um okay now we can
take
the paper towel put it in there put it
in the water you want to ring it out cuz
this is this is too much that will that
will cause problems
but that is just enough not soing wet
still pretty moist so the water has
enough water to get in not excessively
dripping that's
perfect see here one second I have to
put you down while I grab the
seeds and in this case we're going to be
using Williams
Wonder these are the last few seeds I
have of it so uh there's only going to
be a few seeds in here
guys the Williams W
seeds and we Pat that down okay so you
take the seeds in my hand there are
three and you place
them evenly across the top so they have
room with you fold this paper towel over
on itself to have the tap r
grow right there like so you take
this fold it over the top to right
there Pat it down and you get your
Ziploc baggie label
it um normally I would just put ww but
my brain might force me to think that's
white widow and I would not be cracking
some White Widow
I'm trying to write this while looking
through the phone so I'm writing like a
half [ __ ] there we
go you put that
[ __ ] you guys like this all onehanded
[ __ ] did any seats fall out see trying
to [ __ ] around and that's what happens
all right put the seed back
in take this
and we put it in the baggie I'm going to
have to put it down to put it in the
baggie I'll bring you back and show you
what I
did now some people question this
part but there's a good explanation for
it next I will take
tape and like
so stick it to the top of that and then
I like to put it in a dark place where
it can be suspended one
[Music]
sec right
here the reason I do that that didn't
work out so
well the reason I do that is so gravity
can act on the seedlings and the tap
route will grow downwards instead if you
leave it flat on its back like if I
replace it right here downwards the tap
rot sometimes grows in a circle you know
trying to grow downwards it's always
going to try to grow down with gravity
so in this case you won't have curly q
ceilings that are really hard to plant
and I just shut the
cabinet vo [ __ ] law that's how it
works
folks be sure to visit www. rot seeds.
NL for the most dank rare genetics on
Earth [ __ ] everyone else