[Music]
good afternoon
hi hope they that woke you up our next
speaker sam moronto is the state
director for mufon illinois
early this year the ufological community
if that's even a word was rocked by a
headline about a ufo sighting over
chicago the o'hare airport
what made this so interesting was the
amount of traffic that this one
particular story
attracted from the internet i believe
that the stats were well over a million
hits and
in the history of chicagotribune.com no
story had ever pulled that traffic so if
anybody tells you there's no interest in
ufos i think that's proof enough
san maranto has is an investigative
researcher who goes out into the field
researches not only the o'hare sighting
but many sightings even outside of
illinois so let me welcome to the stage
mr sam moronto and for the first time
i've ever said maestro hit it and move
on maestro hit it
snappy little ditty isn't that
well i figure if michael shermer could
bring his toys to the larry king show i
could bring a little music to the mufon
symposium
that's some serious lights wow
what am i talking about today is the
o'hare incident
i'm going to cover a little bit of that
and then i'm going to be covering a
little about
an incident in my backyard which is the
area
known as tinley park
and we had a series of sightings out
there mass sightings back in 2004
i'm also going to jump into the
correlation with other sightings in and
about those times in other states
also going to show you some footage
that i think is some of the most
remarkable footage
from each of these events
what i'd like to do is first give you a
little bit of information about the oh
oh here incident first of all anybody
here
never hear of the o'hare incident
anybody
never heard about it
you've been in papua new guinea recently
okay because this went viral i mean
within a short period of time after this
story broke january 1st by john
hilkovich and the chicago tribune
that story went on the wires before he
was able to pop the cork on his
champagne
that
new year's eve
or new year's new year's
eve by the second of january it was
literally all over the world
it was an international press he was
doing
interviews in fact
on the first
for
for stations down in australia
now we're going to show you some footage
from
uh actually youtube and a few other
things uh from cltv where the story
actually was aired for the first time he
actually talked about it
the friday before the first
and uh the the interview is pretty
interesting we're also going to show you
some footage of the interview on cnn of
an actual
individual that was there at the ramp
one of these ramp rats uh or else was it
the ramp one of them or else the pilot
then we're going to see a little fox
piece that i was involved with and show
you the quality difference
in some of these so if we can run the
first
video dvd
and hopefully we can
oh hey
hey john hey jim how are you well fine
thanks how are you he's preening busy
with this oh my god did you see it hit
the fox crawl on monday night did it
it's just been everywhere i mean i've
been on cnn
uh
my fourth appearance today really every
msnbc every network oh my goodness and
just worldwide i mean yeah australia
everywhere
that's what we're going to start off i'm
going to say
saying john the response has been well
out of this world hasn't it
congratulations that's so where's the
latest on the investigation the effort
this is going on well actually uh
so they've done that flip-flop and i'm
trying to locate photos of this i'm told
there may be photos really
wow sweats like a bear that would be
cool
um i'm told that the
story on on ct right
has almost a million hits
yeah it's it's the most read story in
the history of ct.com
i got an email yesterday from uh billa d
for one million hits on their website
and this was the history of the website
of the first
incredible
incredible so is the possible does the
possibility exist you might get the
pictures and get them in for tomorrow
actually oh no
the actual craft no i mean i i'm told
the pilots on that plane that was being
pushed back
you know i said in the story that they
opened the windscreen and stuck their
head out
now i'm being told that one of them had
a digital camera and snapped some
pictures wow so united is not playing
ball with me and
faa i've expanded my foia to include the
flight plan which might include the
pilots names
and i'm trying to work with the union as
well are they still going by weather
phenomenon
faa you know pretty much because of the
federal holiday i
haven't talked to them that much but
yeah they haven't changed their story
and it's i've just
heard from other people you know since
then that you know that that's that
explanation just doesn't wash and they
haven't gone out of their way to
to say anything otherwise so far
no i mean they say you know it was it
was november 7th they're they're moving
on they're just doing their daily thing
well i tell you what the uh all the
people who saw it must be
feeling a little validated right about
now huh oh yeah and i'm getting tons of
emails from other people who outside the
airport as well as ed o'hare who also
either cited that
same object or saw to go to the sauna
after that just to clear the rest of
those pours out okay so what did it look
like again to the folks who saw it it
was a saucer-like yeah it was hovering
with this
yeah right over directly over gate c-17
that was stationary in the sky
uh dark gray metallic uh you know like i
say saucer shaped no lights
and it was there for some minutes and
then when it
disappeared it just streaked through the
clouds with such energy
that it broke a big a blue hole in the
overcast
and the hole remained there for several
minutes until the wind uh drifted and
pushed the clouds back together we'll
cover a little information on that
yeah the blue was the sky but but
otherwise the entire skyline was uh was
cloudy totally overcast huh oh i forgot
that spot over here it's nothing an
airplane just doesn't react like that it
slices through
and it doesn't disturb the atmosphere
there you go
at this point for his next interview
yeah and going back on
a radio station a couple of radio
stations this afternoon and
then headline news has a show i'm doing
it
three o'clock
okay
ooh i'll have to watch if i'm
yeah i'll be opposite by them um
okay australia what other international
oh my god i mean i mean all over europe
oh my gosh i'm you know hearing from
even ireland they say you know we heard
about what's happening at o'hara
[Laughter]
i mean just
as well as serious you know uh
researchers at major u.s universities
who've attempted to do their own
investigations and when they go to the
government to try to get information uh
they get stolen
so there really is this universal
feeling that the government knows a lot
more than it's willing to tell man okay
what i find interesting is would they
say that otherwise if it wasn't so
candidly you know
okay done here i don't know
i'm just going to say
what i found interesting is john
hilkovich i am so this is i see how he
presents this right here i was the first
one to get to talk about it that's right
friday
okay the ufo hair story the chicago
tribune exclusively broke on new year's
day is garnering attention
around the world joining us now to talk
about it once again is trivial
transportation writer john hilkovich who
broke the story and john the response
has been well
out of this world hasn't it yes it has
been an astronomical gym
every major country it seems people have
written in
both those who claim they've spotted
ufos during their life as well as
serious researchers i mean just the last
two days this is my email and these are
the serious emails you know the ones
from kooks who said they were brought
aboard alien spacecraft i put in a
circular file so it's just a story that
has legs and people are fascinated by
the thought and i think there's some
belief that there are advanced life
forms that are visiting us here on a
regular basis you've been contacted now
in the last few days by several
countries but that also includes serious
university researchers here in the u.s
you know i've got to tell you too i got
a call from my dad in california monday
night and he's like what is up with the
o'hare ufos or i'm like where did you
see that where did you read that well
it's on fox network's crawl
at the bottom it's just amazing how much
this is garnering yeah it really is and
worldwide attention as you say
and uh from people who have observed
made observations themselves including
on november 7th the date of this
incident uh
additional people both at o'hare and
outside the airport who have either seen
this gray disc shaped metallic object
themselves or they saw that huge hole in
the sky that the object created when it
vanished let's go over that one more
time what did people see when it all of
a sudden vanished
right through the clouds over the united
terminal and then how's the faa been
reacting uh the past few days too any
any new ground on that okay well the
object was hovering in a stationary
position about 1500 feet above the
united terminal for some minutes and
then when it left it just burst through
this thick cloud layer
creating a large open space of a blue
sky on an otherwise overcast day
it took some minutes for that opening to
close up when the clouds drifted back
together and it's just extremely unusual
according to the witnesses i mean
airplanes just don't react like this
they slice through clouds and they
really don't disturb the atmosphere that
much except for the wing tips and such
uh the faa is still
you know pinning this to a uh some kind
of weather phenomenon that some lights
from the airport or the over casca
somehow got together and created this
image but uh weather experts uh
astronomy experts others that i've
talked to said that that's uh that's
bunk uh that's the explanation just
doesn't wash united on the other hand
after first denying that they got any
reports from employees about this
sighting is now saying yes indeed their
employees did approach them immediately
because of concerns about safety and to
reiterate john the witnesses who
originally came to you are all seasoned
professional credible professionals like
pilots who saw this they're pilots
they're senior managers they're
mechanics and others so uh you know
they're they're very truthful about what
they're saying and we're trying to
locate photographs if they do exist of
this incident john we know you have
plenty of other interviews to do today
with other countries so we'll let you go
and we'll keep our eyes to the sky
thanks thank you jim
and the conversation still rolls as it
rolls to black
it's isn't it amazing what what really
garners people's yeah for for various
reasons i suppose you know
how cool yeah no it's i can't wait to
see in a week where this stand you know
yeah
i'm just amazed i'm still getting
requests for interviews because uh yeah
that wasn't that insightful
cool thanks ron thanks jim
can we run the second part please
come to chicago's this is from cnn over
the world but do they come from other
worlds you don't believe this was
possibly your imagination it was
definitely not my imagination joe was a
mechanic for united airlines while
taxing a jumbo jet to the hangar he and
another mechanic looked out the window
in the general direction and noticed an
object up in the sky
dark gray object sitting above the
terminal complex joe which is not his
real name is one of several airport
workers some of whom have talked to the
chicago tribune who say they saw a
saucer-shaped ufo hovering just beneath
the clouds at the airport he's the first
to go on camera to talk about it since
this happened several weeks ago he wants
to remain anonymous but you're sure it
was some kind of object that normally
would not be above o'hare airport i've
been at o'hare for
quite some time and let's just say that
i've never seen an object in my time
there that looked like this
and i'll tell you definitely it was not
an airplane as we know it but it could
be an airplane as another world knows it
possibly we brought in one of chicago's
top sketch artists followed the contours
of of the object to listen to joe and
draw a picture of what he says he saw
more like an oval dark gray oval because
no photos have surfaced and joe doesn't
know of any now it didn't say good year
on it did it no good year no that's a
really good drawing is that what it
looks like very much so yeah other
witnesses told an organization called
now there is the object
that most people
who have seen this footage say
was the object this was a cell
picture
i don't know how much darker they can
get that it's up in let me point it out
it's right up there
see it
that's the object
and this was actually sent anonymously
to above top secret which is a very good
website and blog
the thread on this was i don't know how
many pages and in fact my witness that
came forward that is also you'll see
included in the narcap report and
narcrap was actually field this case
the reason why of course is richard
haynes
uh
is known for dealing with aviation
personnel so this was really important
uh that this was feel to him i was able
to do some work interview this
individual and strangely enough my
format has changed because i was
actually supposed to come here today
with two sets of footage that never
materialized up until the last moment i
was guaranteed i was going to have them
i'd like to progress now if we can to
a
um
interview that we did with fox in and
about this time that i think took on an
entirely different tone from these and
i'd like your interpretation of it or
your opinion thereafter can we move to
the next segment on this
is it possible
i'm crossing my fingers
i'm getting nowheres okay
there is another segment of fox peace
but
evidently we have some technical
difficulties is this right somebody tap
me in the back of that or send me a
pigeon with a letter
okay
anyways we'll
give you some information about the
o'hare case and where it finally end up
the final report which is 155 pages you
can actually see that and download it
at narcap.org
narcap.org and when you go there go to
the left hand side of the page and it'll
say the ohio report it was posted august
27th
in there you'll see the compiled
information from foia
requests which actually were fulfilled
but not they did not come in
simultaneously but trinkled in
trickled in a little bit at a time
interesting in that request was also
some footage that some radar footage
about 14 minutes that are missing and
would have been pretty
important but didn't happen and here we
go back to
this piece
to the west off i-88 this man snapped a
photo of it as he drove to his home in
westmont it kind of looked like it took
a building and knocked it over and it
was flying around
and to the south in tinley park i got it
on tape i got it it has perplexed tj
japcon and so i turned around and i
looked up and i'm like no way
no way for nearly six years they're back
but never fear inside this orland park
apartment san maranto he's on the case
did you see that right here there all
right
illinois director i look like a troll
they put this thing right next to my
head it doesn't take much i can't fit my
hand the day before they're showing the
holes in my hand like i'm some sort of
drug addict or something
especially busy ever since a ufo was
spotted over o'hare last november he's
been interviewing reluctant witnesses
who won't go public with their accounts
these are not crackpots still he admits
most if not all of the photos of the ufo
that have since surfaced on the internet
probably aren't legitimate absolutely
insane but back to this i've gone
through this probably about 10 times
hours of home video from various south
suburbanites there's airplanes along
with them look at that all shooting the
same hovering light configuration as tj
japcon back in 2001. perfect 2004 he
goofed us when you're like wow what is
this thing ken and sherry ganaka saw it
in
not a single sound no noise at all is it
above top secret reverse engineered
technology
possibly
that's a hoax it's a hoax being
perpetrated on people astronomer mark
hammergren believes these lights are
nothing more than flares suspended below
weather blends nobody wants to be to say
to people that there's no santa claus
emergent also has bad news for linda von
henke and her family waiting for it to
either come on down or
or take me on up or whatever it wants to
do i'm
it's breathtaking this is the planet
venus then there's this guy they told me
i'm nuts asking to remain anonymous even
though he too insists what he saw was a
ufo do you any know any big giant square
rectangular looking blimps that move
like with the speed of a fighter plane
humans make extraordinarily poor
witnesses
they misperceive to hear this
but some people like chicago and mike
ernst refuse to back down here is this
this craft this this ufo his sighting
was at o'hare as well six years ago when
he was working the graveyard shift
cleaning airplanes it was just like a
metallic silver
it's about 80 to 100 feet long
70 feet off the ground you had these
real bright lights
coming from within it it was so close
that i could have grabbed the rock
and i could have hit the darn thing and
all of a sudden it just accelerated gone
it went there's cameras everywhere
the faa has to have pictures i'm not
making it up
there has not been
one piece of physical evidence
that has passed the scientific test
but they still believe i saw what i saw
period if you can't control it kill it
or conceal it
okay entirely you have to deny it in the
end does it really matter whether or not
these ufo sightings can be explained
away
after all wouldn't that take away all
the mystery the intrigue
and the fun of it
mark saxonmeyer
fox news
chicago
i wish that would have happened earlier
actually
well that was an interesting piece he's
led the piece with this lady obviously
looking at venus and everybody in this
room knew that yeah i don't know who
this person was never talked to her uh
second person i talked to actually saw
an advertising banner that's usually
seen and just downtown chicago along the
way
stop the video dvd looks like he's
getting eaten by something
i don't know what happened there that
was actually the the full
interview
um of uh
by mark saxomer from fox
of the witnesses those two witnesses but
what happened was um the piece was
supposed to play out differently as i
was told we planned for this three about
uh three or four weeks in advance we
spent a couple weeks getting everybody
lined up and not all the witnesses
showed up for the shoot the tone of that
shoot for fox was supposed to be very
serious it was not supposed to be
like this
the one individual you've seen
that
was talking about the o'hare incident of
of uh 2001 in april
was very convincing i met his family i
believe this gentleman to be very
earnest and funny thing is his last name
is ernst
and uh a hell of a guy too and he knows
he remembers this entire sighting very
vividly because as he says it was
up close and personally could have
thrown a rock at it maybe 60 feet a week
away there were four other people with
them but that wasn't everybody that
witnessed it he knew there were other
people and other hangars looking at it
and just didn't talk to him afterwards
so sightings around o'hare are really
not something
unique or new i believe our first
sighting in o'hare was in the 50s and it
was part of blue book that at least
recorded
the other thing about this sighting at
o'hare and i'm trying to cover a lot of
material mind you now this condensed
version is 155 pages long if you get a
chance please read it
and i'm going to give you the bottom
lines and everything
first of all we're looking at
is something truly original truly
unusual truly anomalous
secondly
many people seen it and it was
photographed it was photographed
and
some photographs i believe that did come
forward at least one of them may very
well be a legitimate photograph but
since we don't have anybody tied to it
coming forward we don't accept that as
evidence as you know that we at mufon
take a very rigid stance on what is
evidence and same thing at narcap
but one individual one witness that we
spoke to or i spoke to
i think she gave some very good insight
and if you don't mind listen to some
audio
uh from my interview with this person
i think it's very interesting can we
start the audio please
[Applause]
you know adjusting our arms and looking
at it through that
and uh
it's really
i think you knew when you were looking
at it even with the naked eye that you
knew it was something that was kind of
oval
just shaped
not as hard-edged as the stereotypical
tips
it seemed to have a spotlight
[Music]
what she's saying is we're looking at an
object with softer edges not quite the
same as the hard edge ufo that we're
usually depicted and everything spinning
counterclockwise
and
the other thing about it she mentions
earlier in the interview it had some
unique qualities to its of
its reflectivity
that made her consider other
types of components other than metal
even possibly some type of ceramic which
was very interesting this lady has a
background in
um
journalism she was reporter she was a tv
anchor person in the uh washington area
she has a
an interest in the military and military
aviation
and she has a background in it because
she is a military as referred to as a
military brat
her father was a
retired or is a retired
commander of a navy air wing
and she knows what flies how it flies
and what should be up there and not be
up there and she's also seen some highly
sophisticated stealth
technology she was absolutely certain
that what she saw that day
was not of this world maybe a little bit
more of that foot of that audio please
maybe that's what was causing that fuzzy
quality so the fuzziness would be like a
distortion around the edge
well
there was a distortion in the immediate
sky area
very close up to it but a visible
distortion
which i can see when i looked at it
through the reading class
um when you came upon it
uh
and you pulled over any idea like from
the time you actually saw it now you've
seen the whole event though
you know i must have because really it
was probably 13 or 14 minutes altogether
see now this is a long sighting this
wasn't something and and at that point
are you moving about where you're able
to get different perspectives or keep
from the road well when i first got from
the road
um
then we did move off um to get over to
the international terminal area and pull
over so i did get to see it
basically from two different places
which would have put it up
in the area of
the runways that are to the farthest
south
okay so here um there's the longest
runway that had to run from southwest to
slightly northeast
and it would put it kind of down in the
neighborhood of not quite
uh
not quite the end of that maybe up the
concourse is a little from that so that
area of gate seats uh concourse seat
which is that does
it totally make sense that's pretty good
right there we'll stop that
and that's pretty much uh enough audio
right now people are falling asleep so
what we'll do is i'm going to show you
some footage to keep you really awake
how's that
now we're going to talk about the tinley
park sightings obviously what came down
with the o'hare sighting is
everything conclusive and definitive so
far is at narcap and that's all i can do
is direct you because there's so much
material there
you'd really have to read it i have the
books in front of me but i cannot see a
thing
so i can't read the details
what i'd like to do instead show you
some footage from tinley park that i
think you'll find rather impressive
but before we show the tinley park
footage i'm going to show you some
footage from arizona
and this i'm going to give you some
insight august
the month of august in 2004 started with
a bang i could tell you that a lot of
things happened in 2004 as you can
remember august was the month of those
major hurricanes do you remember that
our first of the series of a five
category came on shore the 13th
of august well on the 19th of august we
had a craft or an object hovering over
minneapolis saint paul for six hours in
a 30 knot wind does everybody remember
that one or did you ever hear about that
it's sad up there did you remember
hearing about it in the news
of course not right even down in papua
new guinea and you didn't hear it there
okay
so
the problem was it wasn't really covered
very well narcap
uh i mean not in our cap but a new fork
uh received a lot of reports there was
footage of this
and there was also event that night in
let's say north west
or yeah northwest uh arizona and i'd
like to show you the object that was
seen there in a 30 mile an hour wind can
we show that which would be rob's
footage
and this is from arizona research group
1a
okay where's that pigeon
this is now see if i was on the radio
this is what's known as radio hell
okay
there we go
now
the vantage point this individual was
looking at this thing in the air in a 30
mile an hour when
he described it as being
not aerodynamic by any stretch of the
imagination
pay attention now to these illuminations
around the side and i refer to them as
illuminations not lights for the purpose
of illuminating
but illuminations the result of energy
and you see this one just go on well
it's all around it
it's very un-aerodynamic
and he first described it as being a
huge battleship in the sky
what you're looking at here
uh received ufo
footage of the year or photograph of the
year from jerry pippen's site
and knowing the individual for four
years
i can assure you this is a genuine
photograph
and it is something
out of this world or at least
an earthly technology
how do you like that
[Applause]
the research coming from this area has
got to be one of the some of the best
scientific actual scientific research
this and a few other events that
happened to this individual really
propelled him to look into things
that really
really made him
let's say question his reality
and
when you look at stuff like this and i
don't know if anybody out here i'm sure
there has quite a few who've had a ufo
sighting once you have one it's hard to
go back to just
your normal realm you know
things change
well for this man things really changed
and
also in tinley park
the next set of footage i'm going to
show you
i think things really changed
south side of chicago we have all these
border towns
and we kill it we kill that footage
there's actually quite a bit of footage
but i don't have permission to show a
lot of things i had permission to show
that
you kill that footage if you don't mind
stop that footage please
thank you um
tinley park
anybody know the area of any chance
tinley park illinois there we go
and it's a very populated area to give
you some idea it is a good demographic
it's a good cross-section of people
and it's highly populated
as you know it's south of chicago and
which is just basically an extension of
population it is also the most
illuminated area south of the loop it is
really an illuminated area
also in that area there's a very strange
subdivision that looks like a cyclotron
even as high as 36 miles up in the air
and yes i've looked at it through google
36 miles up in the air there's also a
auditorium a music center out there that
looks like a huge monolith it's really
bizarre the way it looks from space now
under the assumption that what you're
about to see is of an extraterrestrial
origin and i have no clue i didn't check
anybody's license and pull them out of
this thing i didn't even you know no
vehicle id i didn't see anything but
either way
the technology is definitely unearthly
and if we can run tj's footage
and tj's been lucky enough to actually
see this twice we had mass sightings out
there in tinley park and three events
this event took place two days after
that other object you saw
in phoenix that was the 19th this is the
21st could kick the audio up on this
that's him breathing and the crickets in
the background
they were having a party outside 40
people
ozzy osbourne just got done with a
concert people were heading off on i-80
about two miles away from there
and the air and water show was earlier
that day
and i think my friend here gets i got it
he gets a little excited huh
i got it i got it on tape
now what you're looking at here
i'm going to have you speed that up
please to get an idea of
what we're looking at
when i seen this the first time
i wanted to put it in
faster motion to get an idea if there's
if there's any
uh pattern to this or if they stay in
any pattern possibly being attached to
something and that's what we basically
came up with
this from what you will see in the next
sequence of the other sighting which was
the october 31st sighting
if we could forward to that
which will show up on them on the screen
as being 8
50 something
you will see a plane so the next set of
footage you will see here we go here's a
plane going in front of you two
batteries i got 20 minutes left in
battery
the object's about a mile or more
further away from this this gentleman
a plane cuts in front of it watch and
see this
there you go
october 31st 2004.
what is it
he had some kind of light no it's not no
no no no
that's them right yeah that's the
same red cherry lights as we had before
what they see is red red is the
wavelength that you would see because
it's the longest wavelength but actually
if you were very close to it you would
see a composite of the full
spectrum of the of our light range
now where's that plane
we back up i think we missed the plane
going through there
yep there it was
for a fourth one to come yeah this is
the end of the 21st of august uh
and actually another craft actually
shows up afterwards in each occasion we
need to go a little bit ahead now it's
starting to fade the plane's in the air
planes in the air
i don't know
i'm tired i'm running out of breath
i'm zooming a little bit more
they're back again
there's airplanes there's airplanes
along with them look at that
stop that for a second right there
that object is at from from the from the
airplane more than half a mile away
compare the illuminations now you heard
that astronomers say that what this was
was flares on a balloon
a flare
is a rating loom of about 60. the
illuminations on those crafts on on the
on the airplanes are substantially more
than 60 okay they could be 300 or more
depending on which lights are blinking
now when you look back there this object
being a half a mile away and we're
looking at an airplane there when you
know the difference of size and
calculating the distance those
illuminations those illuminations are
about three times the size of that
airplane
okay now you get an idea how big this
object could be
the other thing is
these are at the end of a large v
or a
v
triangular isosceles type
craft
very large
on the
21st we actually have footage of objects
coming in and out of this
object
the object you're looking back you're
looking at in in the background is over
three thousand feet long i wanna know
where on earth we build things like this
okay
you can run that a little bit more
please look at that those airplanes with
them
yeah
they're you've we don't know they're
ufos
they came back on august 21st now
there's more
because mortar is just now what happens
is he thinks it cut between
the two
the two on the bottom therefore making
the assumption that i was wrong that
this is not one object he didn't know
how far the two objects were away from
each other this very event we have
on videotape vhs
that is on a 90 degree angle confirming
my
hypothesis myself on the back
there we are now what's interesting when
he gets close to some of these you can
see some
some of the colors that are
really interesting
no it's not okay no no no right in here
right
yeah that's them it's the same red
cherry lights as we had before
look at them turning like that
oh my god
there seems to be a pattern too when you
analyze at 1 30th of a uh
a second to see the patterns they also
go on and off the two will illuminate
and fade and one will get brighter and
there seems to be a pattern also when
you look very close at the craft itself
there's arcing blue like um
electrical arcing underneath it
and i have a still photographs last
thing we don't know ufos
pretty interesting how do you like that
[Applause]
now we're going to show you some footage
from phoenix that i think
is also truly remarkable
again from arizona research our
gentleman out there who has
done some magnificent footage i think he
has up to 60 hours of footage now
uh of some things now this is what we
are able to show hopefully sometime in
the future we'll be able to show more
uh this is rob's last one
i believe
and if we could see that i'm gonna tell
you what it is this happened on
uh
9 11 of all days
2005. the funny thing about it is you
noted in phoenix like when we had the
phoenix lights all of a sudden they're
saying you know two hours afterwards and
they dropped the uh the flares they're
saying that prior event was actually the
event well the funny thing about this
they dropped flares in the same area
where this
very huge and unusual
uh
array of lights let's say and possible
object was actually located at and the
funny thing about it they did that a
couple days afterwards and yet the news
agencies picked it up as that being the
event now mind you we had two hours
before the phoenix late this was
actually days later and yet they said
this was the event amazing isn't it they
did time travel in the media did you
know that
let's see if we could have that last
piece that last uh
there we go now please watch this
now you see those three
these three here pay no attention to
that that's actually a result or a um
unusual
artifact that shows up on his camera i
want you to know he went through nine
cameras doing this research so if you
want to be a field investigator around
these types of anomalous events and
phenomena you better be able to replace
your equipment because they beat the
heck out of it
please pay attention down here you see
this
line
and if you can speed it up please
pay attention to this and we're looking
towards south
towards south mountain about 20 plus
miles away in this direction would be
sky harbor anybody here know the arizona
area
okay so you have an idea where we're at
north by glendale up that way now see
what's going on here you will see things
shoot out and up along this
object here this illumination these
illuminated this luminated field
now i made the assumption to him i
brought the
assumption to him let's make the
assumption this was one
huge object i says would you able to
give me an estimation on its size
knowing where it would be located and
the estimation came back to
eight miles long
i find this to be well back that up
please
back that
up i can't show this other footage
is that rather impressive or not
now you will see a plane there it is
okay let's back it up and run that slow
because the plane is coming and an
airplane's coming in
just a little bit back it up
and you'll see an airplane to the right
come in through here
going to sky harbor and all i could say
is can you imagine being the pilot
saying this
i'd take a week's vacation at a minimum
we'll come across here
now this was a 9 11 2005. the funny
thing is 9 11 2005 we also had events in
tinley park
the tinley park sighting there was
correlations with multiple events around
the world the first sighting day we
actually had sightings around the world
as far as even the aegean sea on the the
the very next morning we had sightings
down in houston texas on channel 11 they
actually showed some footage supposedly
i was never able to get it uh the 24th
or the 23rd depending on what time zone
you live in in australia there was the
very same craft as seen in
tinley park the same illuminated field
and isosceles layout of illuminations
actually photographed in melbourne
australia
okay thank you very much with that did
you how's that pretty good
[Applause]
time is getting close and i'd like to
cover a few things i'd like to cover at
this point if you don't mind
communication communication you know
regardless of how much technology and
whatever we have today we could you know
you could we got cell phones heck you
could call somebody all anywheres around
the world again papua new guinea
and you could be out in the forest or
whatever and you have a cell phone or a
satellite phone you can still
communicate cell phone probably not
satellite phone yes right
um communication is a funny thing though
how we communicate is even funnier yet
now for the past 60 years and we're
celebrating 60 years of roswell correct
we're also celebrating 60 years of
modern ufology
we've communicated to the scientific
community
through this period of time and
basically
presenting them with what we feel to be
rather
substantial bits of information
quality evidence to some degree
and if you talk to ted phillips
very hard evidence
unfortunately
the community at large at least the
scientific community at large hasn't
been let's say dented as of yet
though i think the general public is
finally getting the idea that there's
something more than this now you can
look at all different types of polls and
they vary between certain amounts
and if you talk to a skeptic it's 40
percent that think that something's here
they like to use the term believe i
would like to turn the term belief
thrown in the garbage
believe is actually a leap of faith it's
to take something on faith without
evidence
anybody here
walking through those corridors looking
at the material and talking or listening
to any of the speakers and seeing the
data
and footage
or any witnesses if you could walk away
and say that i can believe because again
it's a leap of faith then i'd say you're
not listening very well or reading very
well
you should know by now that something
truly unusual is going on if we're being
visited i would say yes
by what from where i have no conclusion
but i think we should leave all those
options open at the very least we
shouldn't make any quick decisions but
in the same token we should allow
ourselves to at least consider the
possibilities and this is something we
should really prod
science with because it's to the point
now
that we really have to go beyond that so
for the next 60 years like something
else would be something else may take
place at least we hope something else
will take place
one thing to do is to bypass science
altogether let's just talk to one
another
isn't it funny we don't talk to another
one another anymore we're not on
at the meetings and we're not
congregating at things like this that
much let's do that the other thing is to
make use of other ways and means to
communicate one way is the abstract form
intelligence is true intelligence is the
use of abstract abilities
use of the abstract art and science have
more similarities
than one can imagine and with that in
mind i'd like to show you a very nice
music video
by seth john stevens is the music
musician the artwork by jim davis who is
art director on the east coast at one of
universities and i when the first time i
saw this he actually brought me to tears
it has nothing to do
with the actual event
of a sighting in
in illinois on january 5th
but it made a good tile title and it
strum the court of imagination for this
gentleman these two artists on that note
i'd like to please show this video
and i say please again
the dvd
thank you
you