welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to breeder Syndicate
I'm Matthew here today with seed trip
Rob AKA sub Rob as I knew him when I
first started talking to him um we're
GNA cover some stuff that we didn't
cover last time maybe expand on a few
things that we we kind of felt like we
should go more in depth on and uh I
think we're gonna start it off today
talking about San Diego's finest Cuts I
mean we we briefly mentioned how
influential it it was at the time and
and still is today but that was more as
a from the uh purview of my own but as
the scene as a whole that thing took on
a life of its own so let's start off
start off with what year did that kind
of start forming um why was there three
Etc let's start there I got I mean it
would be easy to look up but I want to
say around
2008 couple years after I signed up on
the
mag maybe 2009 n it was it had to be
2008 yeah yeah and uh it was it was
formed to Showcase and inform on the
cuts that g was bringing into the eight
was bringing into San Diego and pretty
much the rest of California running back
and forth North and South uh it was
started by dragor
and and uh a lot of the San Diego cats
saw the title and signed right up y or
her buddy of theirs and signed up on IC
mag just to keep an eye on
thread uh because like I said you know
we had a running list of what G was was
vending at the time
it was a badass threat right from the
start and it it evolved from there into
uh into General all
around everything threat but the theme
was mostly Cuts we were running in San
Diego and we were all on that trip you
know free the genetics at the time so
you know people were always bringing new
stuff
in and it just became inevitable that
people people would start spreading the
jeans and it didn't hurt G's business at
all nah no he he he actually sold clones
fairly affordably even back then like
you you weren't having the $500 cut for
this and 800 for that ridiculous yeah
the Raiders
won how how did the draft go by the
way I went well uh it was unexpected but
uh the Raiders got a lot of the depth
they needed to be able to compete and uh
it's going to be it's going to be a fun
season if nothing else AP is a coach
[ __ ] Max get the [ __ ] out of here now we
got well I won't go into it that's not
to
show one thing I could talk as much
about as cannabis it's the raid yeah
it's like me with the MMA and and [ __ ]
like that that's
an I guess I could talk about just about
yeah anything where man men get a hold
of each other and and and hold each
other exactly dude so yeah again I wanna
I want to stress that like you know I
don't think ape gets brought up a lot
but he was such a major influence on
even [ __ ] that I did [ __ ] that you
did how the scene blew up the entire
State you know even the big guys in and
up
north in the triangle they had access to
all kinds of stuff that other people
didn't of course but sometimes they
wanted something that they saw and and
able to give it to them yeah it it was a
lot there was a lot of difference
between what was going on up there
versus down in SoCal despite you know
like some of the the stuff that was sold
at Harborside would come down here but
there was still quite a big divide
between what we were growing you weren't
seeing a lot of like bull rider and Hogs
breath way up North being blown up in
Mass you know it was quite different in
Southern California I mean it was it was
big but they didn't it's not part of the
family tree of the Southern California
right growing was Northern especially
the bay like everybody knows the bay was
was purple crazy oh yeah back
25 I mean we could start with one of
those Granddaddy Purple when did you
first see it when did it hit the scene
down there you know I might have gotten
that from from a
um I don't remember maybe Sean or one of
the other guys might remember but it
wasn't the it wasn't one of the two main
GDP Cuts yeah uh son of bog later known
as great punched uh let me know that he
thought that the cut that I had cuz it
was small man it grew like freaking
Bubba it grew Bubba with slightly
smaller nuts I'm talking about that kind
of Bubba the one that just
stay uh it took forever to get there uh
was not a yielder but uh I guess it
resembled a cut that was known to some
people as the Royale cut
interesting uh and that information came
from I guess Colorado wherever wherever
great punch was based that was the first
I'd ever heard of the Royale cut yeah I
I had never heard of it but yeah it it
was different though for sure I remember
seeing pictures of like Ken's GDP being
all like pered out like like me like
magenta purple and the one down in San
Diego didn't look anything like that I
do remember the slow growth a
lot it was H more cushy it was more more
potent than the other two gdps that I
grew in San Diego which I was
not I was not necessarily that big of a
fan of uh GDP the purples I usually like
are those old
school purple stinky incense Afghan
Pakistani um not the fruit purple I like
that I always took you for a fruity guy
dude that surprises
me I guess that's how I come across how
how did the Grape Ape compare that went
around San Diego to the GDP the kind of
Grape Ape I had uh sucked I remember
specifically being very disappointed in
that I you
know while mislabeled Cuts weren't as
common back then yeah as they just
because sheer
volume I can't say for sure that that
was the great AP that uh
you know that made big book of buds or
or the can of Bible or whichever one it
was that had in it it was one of those
purple strains that doesn't turn all the
way purple it's got like purple streaks
through it yeah it had a very
odd this is how disappointed I was in
that I remember these details plus I've
been strumming through the forums
refreshing and I I saw a couple picks of
it and what wasn't purple almost looked
like uh it had
a goldish tint to it like when you pull
out some six or eight month cured Buds
and they kind of look to it not not to
the point of you know falling apart yet
where where you like it
yeah but it just uh it wasn't it wasn't
something that I ever grew a second time
yeah yeah makes
sense the
SR was
definitely runs on the ladder above
great I remember growing huge fan of
that either but it was it okay I
remember growing Urkel at the same time
as the SR71 and I could never tell him
AP part sometimes I would I would be
like well this one's a little more hashy
smelling or tasting as opposed to full
rape but that was like the only
difference I noticed SR71 grew a little
bit faster but not much I remember them
looking almost
identical you know well I hesitate I'm a
little more hesitant now to say I never
grew so and so because as I've gone back
to the forums to kind of get ideas for
what we should talk about I'm finding a
whole lot of stuff that I I completely
forgot I grew uh I don't believe I ever
grew early I do remember smoking uh
smoking it for a while because one of
the things we did on the thread was
after we had met you know each other got
everybody got to know each
other if one person you know was going
to
grow a couple pounds of one thing then
everybody else would focus on something
else and just get samples from the other
grows yeah getting purple arle from Sean
maybe
grotch think he grew that too so I I for
a grapy for grapy uh purple cut that was
that was Prett that one always [ __ ] me
up and made me I don't know I I never
liked the high from it but it always
smelled really good and tasted really
good so I'd always smoke it and end up
regretting it because it would spin me
out like in a real weird
Direction now I don't remember like I
said I don't remember how much we went
into to bull rider other than the um
just little bits of the story where the
dude from um I want to say
Fresno is where it came from and it came
down with old Betsy but other than that
uh trying to figure out much about the
story of bull rider was was a little
hard but there was The Afghani bull
rider that was big down in San Diego um
can you touch on that a little bit well
we have bull rider which was huge and
gerbo from [ __ ] yeah yeah gerbo recently
I saw on Instagram maybe it was an
Instagram story or maybe it was a post
and it's still there uh he he posted a a
small
short uh summation of where it came from
to the best of his knowledge and the
fact that the guy was a bull rider and
that's why there the Afghan bull rider
that was going
around uh it was popular to grow I would
assume because maybe maybe it was Elder
yeah space saber you know maybe the
Afghan shortened it down I was never as
big a
fan that was the weed that no matter
where you were drinking at in North
County somebody at the bar on to the
side of the bar always had a little bit
of Afghan bull rider yeah yeah um so
yeah it was grown it was grown by a lot
of people who probably all the people
who wanted to grow Rider couldn't get it
yeah
yeah was that bya Jeff Tech
first do you remember I know that Jeff
Tech was in that original crew
yeah or ancillary to it you know one
degree at the most separate um I don't
know if he's the one who found it I
heard that he grabbed it from somebody
else who was in the in the crew and
growing it in his
backyard Sean be a good guy to ask about
the history of that yeah yeah it
would there there was another seed that
got popped by Brandon
rust uh that's made of Afghan bull rider
in the last couple years it's made its
way out to uh a couple people in
California among them sea who's been
posting pics
recently uh and
it looks better Sean says it's better
hands down and he's still running in it
so that that whether or not it's good
smoke but you'd have to go there for
details maybe I should have hit him up
about that before I came on the show I
mean I I met that kid I want to say four
years ago now and he showed up in my
when I used to do the Instagram live
streams the rust kid and he he first he
came on claiming that he bred bull rider
and then I was like oh yeah which one
the Afghani bull rider bull rider he's
like what do you mean I said there's
there's not just one you know like he
didn't even know that there there was
something even called Afghani bull riter
at the time but later he then took
credit for breeding it so I've always
been sus as [ __ ] so anytime his name
comes up I'm like [ __ ]
clown I have to I actually I actually
well I never met the guy I don't know
the guy um and I heard when when I
started following him or I don't even
know how I can't maybe Sean pointed him
out probably some any bull riter I
noticed that sometimes you get into
arguments about stuff that is is from
the past like that yeah but he seems
like he knows what the [ __ ] he's doing
he seems like a hard
worker uh hard Hustler for sure he
hustles the [ __ ] out of people and yeah
I have no no love for that [ __ ]
yeah I I don't know one way or the other
I don't mind talk [ __ ] on people I just
I know you don't
and the only reason I know who Jeff Tech
was because I wasn't involved with the
you know with those
original transplant in
um but I know of jefftech because
when when bull rider in Canada launched
they pretty much right they were about
and I hit up Sean the local one of the
local San Diego
and uh and that's when I found out who
Jeff Tech was and how he was connected
up
north is he a Canadian Jeff Tech I don't
know he ended up there yeah that's what
I thought music producer somehow they
they were in the same Circle and MGH
bull rider back in the day that he still
still had the cut still growing it uh
and somehow turned it into a b Rider
brand the only thing I'm angry about now
because I reached out to oo and uh I
well first thing I did was reached out
to everybody I knew in San Diego and we
hit up bull rider Instagram
Pages [ __ ] hey do you even know what
you're just ripping off uh to his credit
OBO did reach out a few times and just
they never actually connected with gerbo
and him to history of the bull Rider
brand I mean if you look at the branding
it's the same brand that gerbo designed
originally for his loading and
accessories it's the same logo exact
yeah OBO did reach out so you know it's
on it's on gerbo to reach back out gerbo
is hard to get a hold of though
sometimes so I could see that what's
that jerbo has been hard to get a hold
of sometimes though so I could see that
being ask I've talked to him a number of
times and he's just one of those strange
cats you know he doesn't he doesn't
really seem that concerned so I'm not
you know going online here and Blasting
bull rider if
nobody's upset then hey man just you
know show a little something about the
history of bull rider and that it's not
a where they at Toronto it's not a
Toronto you know culture yeah it's the
San Diego thing just acknowledge it and
uh [ __ ] run with it I guess yeah I
mean as long as they don't touch p91 I'm
[Laughter]
okay yeah all right so let's get into
green crack when did you first see the
crack and when you saw it was it called
Green cush with the ca or was it called
Green Crack first you
know it was it was both when I saw it
first I can't remember where I saw it
first but I do remember smoking it and
saying wow I would have and this is not
as insulting or as negative as it sounds
it was like I would have loved this [ __ ]
in high school you know what I mean yeah
yeah the first blueberry was the first
strain I ever had that was a tone
specific could be described as c yeah
but Green Crack just had that overall
sweetness that
uh [ __ ] delicious
and that was and I was already online
and that was
when that's when people would have the
debates you know there was the the
Cannabis
grammar guys who who insisted on calling
it this or that and not weed because it
had negative so it could be versus green
crack that that never that never
bothered me yeah it never bothered me
either but I saw a lot of it
well I do understand some of that that
old school you know speak about it
correctly yeah you know I that train of
thought and where that that whole small
movement started and I appreciated it
you know if you were speaking to
somebody educating them about cannabis
or informing them about oh sure then
sure call it cannabis you know if you're
on a
[ __ ] weed forum you know
right yeah um so yeah so uh that came
around uh which you had asked if we
covered green ice enough yeah yeah Green
was C
green uh he crossed green ice to gorilla
gorilla gold from breeder Brad and on
the last cast it was gorilla gold number
four in when I was going through the
forums I found out it was gorilla gold
number two
okay uh but that just made an almost
perfect sweet cannabis strin I mean I
don't think any of us gave it the
credit when we had it well as far as I
know calii was the only one who ever
grew it because again we were in that
Rush of strains for the first time ever
where you could have 20 different cuts
delivered to your house and smoke a
joint with the dude
yeah
right
um so yeah I I didn't high and
Lonesome who who's working with green
CRA oh yeah yeah high and Lonesome with
the uh Appalachia for sure I was putting
out s1's when I was down in San Diego
and that pissed a lot of people off
because everybody thought I was going to
take their clones and S1
it oh you know everybody was worried
everybody's still worried yeah for sure
for sure
sure you know CSI gave me great advice a
long time ago and he said don't ever tie
yourself to one clone because if you do
someone's going to get it and then
you're going to be real sad about it and
you're not going to have anything left
so never worry about tie yourself to one
clone so I've always kind of gone with
that but um yeah I remember back then
getting locked out of everything because
because I was a dude making fem seeds
down there you know and s1's of [ __ ]
yeah I wish I had appreciated the the
the value of S1
seeds uh before I did because I passed a
lot of S1 seeds in the community yeah on
taking them in uh for a while I was
afraid of them you know like a lot of
old
schoolers um and then I finally started
messing with him it's like holy crap I
want to S1 every cut that I enjoy now
yeah
15 years 20 years ago yeah
one bro science damned everything
bro yeah I
still take fem seats he's like no dude
you know you know I don't mess with with
that stuff I'm like dude get off the
island once in a while
bro well it just leaves it all for us
it's all right sure
ad dub now is that is it just alien dog
as ad dub or do do we know what it is
alien dog crossed with sour d oh that
makes
sense yeah I love that [ __ ] and do we
know if that was um alien dog from obso
or from
snd
yeah yeah that would be pretty fire
great cross I'll tell you this the ad
doesn't have the Flop the flavor that
you expect from or not that you expect
but that you hope from sour double yeah
but it doesn't matter because that
high to my physiology is so unique I I
love a is that still
around yeah yeah Diego yeah people need
to cough that [ __ ] up I don't think I've
ever grown a
dub well in in the era of turps you know
I don't think think it'll ever be a huge
strain yeah but in the era of smoking
flour and getting high like
concentrate yeah not saying strength to
strength but that type of high that
encompasses you know everything
yeah again I was never the best at
descriptions but everybody who smoked a
will tell you essentially the same thing
it it's a very unique guy yeah I mean
there's a reason they've kept it around
this long you know I think last time I I
called it it's like being high in a
bubble you know yeah until you finally
get out of
it um so there was one when I was going
through the The Strain list purple Joy
did that come via
ape no that was something that uh SPI
Sean
Crum
Source I believe but he did give it to
yeah yeah yeah was that's the kind of
purple plan I'm talking about man uh
that was a heavy
smoking like you knew you smoke pot
after a joint of that like yeah you let
your lungs breathe for a while and you
just sit back and enjoy that uh that
[Music]
I wonder if he got that from um breed
Bay Sean cron I'll have to ask him
because they were selling that a strain
called that at the same time but it was
some really weird like genetics that I
had never heard of at the time it wasn't
anything I want to say it was a nepes of
some sort but I I don't know if it's
even the same [ __ ] I just remember
grabbing it from
ape you know I seem to remember from the
photos and I just saw photos last last
week when I was going
through uh it did have a Sean posted
some photos from way back in the day
when he grew it outdoor and it had
a it had a different structure it was
not you know the leaf structure was
different the the branching was a little
different and I've
seen napy plants in pictures and
pictures only always seemed to have that
leafier
that same so it wouldn't surprise me if
it was some sort of of Nepali in there I
I'm sure Sean remembers you gotta get
him yeah eventually we got to get him
on um so one one interesting part I
think that would be I know we talked a
little bit about the beginning of
Gorilla Glue but going more in depth to
it how it was hyped why it was hyped how
it became as famous as it was was it pre
planned was it uh
accidental it wasn't really pre-planned
but there were people who hit Josie up
and were like this is what you know
cookies had was already in full on hype
mode yeah I wasn't even I wasn't even
aware of Instagram at at that time yeah
that mean a lot but just to put it in
perspective um and there was a
guy Sunset limited maybe okay I believe
what his name was um before we ran his
ass
out we said don't don't ever come back
here
scumbag he I think he helped
doy a lot with advice and it was again
was all right there on the thread I'm
still I'm still catching up to that
point in my my
reading um maybe we'll talk about that
another time and I'll have more details
fresh fresh in mind yeah but it there
was in some sense a following
of the cookie blueprint for for hyping a
strain up you can see why I mean yeah it
didn't get hyped up
I mean it's still hyped up yep you know
there's got to be a
reason yeah to to there's got to be a
reason to last that long not not to get
hyped up first place yeah no for sure I
mean I I like Gorilla Glue I like
smoking it I like that one the one thing
I I noticed with it I I avoided growing
it for a long time because I was like
who the [ __ ] wants this poly hybrid mess
you know like this is where I want to
take any breeding but it actually breeds
breeds just like it looks like it it's
not all all over the place it actually
breeds like it looks and uh passes on a
lot of its best traits which which
always surprised me with with all the
crap crammed in it yeah it's uh it's
it's been on a wild drive you know it's
and there's a lot of poly hybrids with
it in it that I enjoy more than Gorilla
Glue which is the whole point of poly
hybrids you know yep did did you ever
get to try any of the uh gg1 gg5 any of
those uh you know I got to smoked some
of it
somewhere uh not enough not enough to
make any judgments versus number
four uh you know that's why when I was
getting invited to to judge in you know
certain events I always said no because
you know I don't really no string till
i've smoked like I don't know I figur I
got to smoke a half ounce
over over a month before I can even make
judgments on strin so I remember getting
high off of the I believe it was
the I think it was the number five the
yeah you know you had to sign a contract
or whatever that was that was number
yeah yeah yeah it was yeah I remember
being high but I I just I don't have
enough info to pass on any wisdom but
isn't that that is the hard part about
judging even even when we do our meetups
in the in the mountains and [ __ ] it's
like everybody dumps all this new [ __ ]
that a lot of us haven't tried like on
the table and we're trying to smoke it
all within two days and it's just not
[ __ ] happening to where you can
really pin down anything special and
there's there's people who can do it you
know there's people who can smoke in one
session four different kinds of flour
and just pop off and reel off their
comments and and you can tell they're
not faking you know yeah they work like
that I'm one of the guys I I gotta you
know I gotta know I gota know it for a
little while I yeah with me strains hit
me different at different times of the
day if I'm in a different mood like it
hits me all kinds of different ways so
for sure I I I get
that all right let's talk Master
Kush SoCal SoCal Master when did you
first see
it I've always called it dirty Bubba it
just reminded me of Bubba Kush crossed
with Master with a number of possible
Master kushes yeah you know a lot of
people still don't realize Master Kush
was a general term you know for for a
seed string or I don't even know seed
strings
yeah uh but individuals can always be
found in cush populations that just
stand out and somebody found that one
and I think somebody hit Bubba with it
because they grow very similar it's so
Bubba it's so [ __ ] Bubba yeah Bubba
with a uh just a garbage
reek you know finisher on that that
sweet rotten smell yeah of Master cush
or that can be expressed master I always
thought it was pretty good I like soal
Master I'd like to see it pop back up I
you know uh I haven't seen it in a long
time I've got some seeds on the burner
uh it's the it's when I hit SoCal Master
Kush uh with
revs I I can't remember I'll have to
look it up it's either
revs F3 bre mail of yeah or F4 pollen
which I selected myself from five
minutes yeah um and even though it's not
the ideal combination in my mind it
doesn't really matter because what I'm
looking for is is that Master cush I've
still got c99 seeds if I want c99 yeah
that's the only
seeds I
have uh left with the SoCal master I bet
it'll kick through that thing so it bred
so dominant um I know who was it it was
Jim Jimmy nits might have done some
SoCal Master Kush s1s at some
point
Zoolander no not Zoolander Jimmy nits uh
Pisces I don't know if Zoolander did or
not well um is it is that cut still
around so
I haven't seen it a long time not from
like a reliable source I've seen Cuts
where that people call Master Kush that
look just like it but I've never got my
hands on it to be sure you know but yeah
cross SoCal Master Kush and Hogs breath
yes SoCal Master OG and Hogs breath that
was the Super hog super hog yeah yeah
that was one of me and me and Jimbo's
first uh crosses in San Diego with the
hog breath crew there was a cut floating
around SoCal we gave it to G uh we call
it uh
bht's
hog yeah BHT had told Dusty you remember
Dusty Dusty oh yeah Dusty that's a
danal yeah Dan they trade and BHT went
up there and gave him what became known
as bht's Hogs
breath uh because d
was pissed and just went on the war path
online and just every chance he got was
just
smoking BHT over that he was so pissed
you know how he get oh oh yeah yeah why
why why was it called BHT what what what
cut was it PHT thought it was hog breath
oh but was it the super hog as hog
breath and it was Hog's Breath crossed
with silal
master that worked out yeah that was a
Killer cut too man that was heavy
rotation San
Diego um I'm pretty sure crch would
still chop off the fender in
exchange for that BHT hog breath if
anybody's got it I sent the last of the
seeds down to Bitter I don't remember if
they popped or not but I did find some
of the old little super hog in my
collection we don't have any proof that
I think you sent me some seeds might
have and we don't have any proof that
that was what that cut was but everybody
unanimously said that tastes like Hogs
breath and so it also had the look right
from the start purple leaves it would
get purple and if if the leaves
lay the under the the top of the leaf
that was under would not turn purple so
you ended up with all these cross
patterns on imprints yeah it was it was
another dang strain that I
wish hadn't disappeared because that was
great cut you know like when we made
those we made some like I don't know
15,000 seeds so it was going out of
unified he was selling them for like I
don't know it was like five bucks a seed
or something silly or five bucks a pack
so they should have been flying around
everywhere but who knows where where
they all ended up yeah yeah yeah that's
another one of those strands that if
there was that many seeds out there I'm
amazed there aren't more
Cuts right with with one of those two in
its name yeah and with with the way the
name game goes though you know it could
be out there under some other stupid
[ __ ]
name the super hog wasn't that creative
in the end in itself strain names are
not so easy anymore bro they're hard I
hate naming [ __ ] now
I like when uh cultural other cultural
phenomenons work their way into the
cannabis seed name game like uh I
remember when or orcut you know um I
remember when Game of Thrones was big
everything was Ki this Ki that yeah yeah
you know other [ __ ] like that that's
when you know you're running out of
names yes yes or or when you you have a
a string called Blue cocky because
you're just gross like
me
yeah all right so I didn't have this one
in the list but I remember talking to
you and you you um you had camd pretty
early on in Southern California do you
remember the sourcing on all that where
it showed up and
when uh I got that from uh from crazy it
it was something we talked about openly
online right from the I don't mind you
know saying where I got it from sure he
doesn't either uh he got from from Greg
Kim which I understand sometimes does
bring questions into it but in this case
from from
everything it was crazy got the right
Cuts he got that
got yeah which I love both matter of
fact when I I started growing those two
cets at the same time and there was a
few years there where that's what I
smoked you know two bong rips of East
Coast Sour Diesel followed by one of
kimd I mean I had it down path and
that's when I really started to notice
what I've always said about Kim D
because it's definitely in the in the
goat debate as far as I'm concerned sure
the fact that I still to this day have
not built a tolerance to it there is
weed that that I love that if I smoke so
long I just
don't it it just quits satisfying you
know whatever whatever physiology I have
uh but kimd to this day is one of the
most
potent uh CS for me out
there it's like that no seiling high
that people talk about like it's the
epitome of that I watch I've watched it
wipe people out that smoke heavy heavy
heavy yeah
yeah Sour Diesel which I guess is
related to kimd according to gab yeah
chem 91 vi vi chem 91 sure that's right
that's right
um East Coast Sour Diesel that original
East Coast Sour Diesel from the Kim
family uh was the per example of I could
smoke a lot of Esco Sour Diesel and I
did because I enjoyed the taste but yeah
at any point in smoking session I follow
up Sour Diesel with KMD it was like okay
I'm good yeah
right I love that flavor it's still the
best sour it's right there with sour d
those are the two best sour plants in my
opinion yeah I agree
lots of other good ones but I'm just
saying those two were
both you know Peak
Performance yeah we were spoiled bro we
had the we I think we had the best sour
down in San Diego personally via that
route Coast Sour Diesel that was all I
needed and then we had
sour why would you incorporate at some
point you have to draw the line and say
okay enough of this kind of plant let me
grow some of these others I want to get
too and if you've got those two you've
got both of the types of sour that there
are me you got you got both you got the
peak of both like OG there's many
different ogs
tons what's that tons of
ogs ogs that I still remember you know
to this day um s is the same way but to
me there's two basic profiles with OG
you got three or four basic profiles and
then variations on that I just smoked 92
OG for the first time how was
that it's I'm I'm blasted high right now
and I think I've taken three hits off
that bow
um the uh the New Mexico process of
drying and caring continues to fascinate
me and elude me really maxing but my
buddy here Uncle fishstick I got some of
that 92 9 to OG from I wasn't even sure
it was OG when I opened the bag and by
day three of being in the jar I was like
okay yeah there it is there it is it's
it's a dirty OG I don't know if it's a
cut or if it came from seed it there was
a collective that 92 uh came from
specifically that specific cut that they
started calling
92 okay yeah it's good it's it's what I
dirty ogs like Valley OG was it's notet
Valley OG was but it's it's that dirt
OG you were one of the few uh other
dudes that grew resin's cut of OG right
yeah it was Rascal's cut it was the same
cut that Ras same same same as far as I
could tell I mean I grew him years AP we
got the legit original Rascal cut it's
it's all on the thread cuz Rascal was
pissed we didn't know we weren't
supposed to have I remember I remember
all that [ __ ] and I remember how it came
down I remember when uh this dude Doug
had it he had it before Rascal was
really blasting it out big and there was
a whole bunch of drama on that yeah well
I guess there was a business deal or a
business venture that was going to be
formed between Rascal Wick 650 yeah and
another dude who's still around you know
W anymore um another dude who's still
around so I won't say is name but they
were going to do a business venture I
guess it fell apart and Wick and the
other dude got got pissed and Wick gave
his cutout to a few people among them
Sean yeah after some back and forth with
Rascal we just said look man we won't we
won't I won't make seeds with it we
won't sell seeds with it you know he's
like all right GL you guys got it and he
was cool about it yeah uh that was a
great cut that was a that was a hydro OG
cut you know some gr and hydro and they
are Head and Shoulders above everything
else everything else
absolutely a Hydro Cut and few years
later when I ran resin cut resin's cut
me and the guy I was growing with time
we both as soon as we could smell it you
know we're like yeah that's
yeah the last Hy I ever ran was was Maui
skunk dog and resen OG and let me tell
you that was the stinkiest table in the
dude yeah the dren's cut is definitely
meant to be run Hydro he actually gave
us the recipe that they used to use when
they do like the cholo Mansions blowing
up Hydro tables and [ __ ] and it it was
like some I want to say jacks or
something like that or some some hard
hard nutrient line
I just used R water and Canon yeah Canon
that's what that's my fall back
too right you don't have well Hydro is
still Hydro you still got to control
everything exactly
butan I don't I don't measure PPM I
don't measure PH I just same not at this
point not this far in it's so
good all right day
recer day record day recer diesel which
was never really that dies to me no to
me it was more like a chem 91 OG hybrid
somewhere right in the
middle yeah yeah something like that not
quite as sweet as OG but uh
exactly grotch and I did a project we uh
he reversed the chem 91 and
hit I gave him
k91 KMD and Rascal's cut yeah
which yeah we made seeds but we did not
sell any seeds and this wasn't this
wasn't thousands upon thousands of seeds
anyway
um matter of fact those seeds got stolen
after um he hit and the day record
diesel so kimy
Rascal and original diesel got hit with
chem 91 reverse pollen yeah
um and that chem 91 was definitely legit
that came from money yeah money M and uh
we talked about that openly on the
thread so I don't think he'll mind that
being
known um and that we called that super
record the uh the original the day recer
Cross of k91 we called super wer and
that's I've got some picks of that up on
my Instagram too that's some of the
gooiest just most frost covered flower
ever I still have some seats but I'm
zero for the last six waiting for the
next step in seed cracking science
technology because there's
some a friend of mine had an eight in a
baggie he was taking it home maybe it
was a quarter it was a quarter quarter
ounce yeah and he had to go through the
checkpoint and they they went through
every surface of his vehicle after he
showed him there's the quarter out
they're like there's no way that's all
we this vehicle there's no way and they
they tore into they didn't tear into it
but they they searched yeah every place
you could put weed without tools
and dude kept telling man this is it I
tell you you know I'm not dumb enough
yeah more than this through a through a
border checkpoint was it like Arizona
checkpoint no it was just one of the
many in North County gotcha yeah or
Southern and and they're not border
checkpoints you know we all the a
checkpoints they're what the
agricultural checkpoints oh they're drug
interdiction checkpoints that's yeah
well why are you doing immigration 880
miles north border you know it's too
late yeah that's one I would have liked
to have tried I I'm a big fan of day wer
as it is and with chem 91 on that that
would be fire that' be super fire lots
of
potential chem 91 makes some killer
crosses a lot of The Offspring I find
chem 91 to be pretty boring I mean not
the high the high is C sure you know but
I I think it's rather boring
D I think it's kind of ugly too on its
own not too pretty not too yeah but in
hybrids
awesome yeah all right sensey star
what's your first experience with Sensei
star uh you know that's one of the few
strains I've tried
from uh from a dispensary in you know
California it was one of the earliest
ones in dispensaries that I remember
like when dispensary started popping up
ceny star was one of the
first the bud being sold it was cool to
uh you know we had all seen the Cana
Bible yeah uh think I don't even think
rosenthal's books were out yet um but
we'd all seen the can Bible so it was
really cool to go to
dispensary and buy some pot that I had
never grown or or smoked and just match
it up with with what we saw or the
beginning of the online sure you
know that was pretty cool and I remember
enjoying cense star I remember it being
uh solid High you
know having that really
light
sugary sweetness you know yeah I like
the sweet cannabis tones in general I
don't know what Turk profiles those are
any of that [ __ ] but you know what I'm
talking
about sweet and I thought it matched up
pretty good with the description in
the yeah yeah yeah that was actually by
the time it got released uh and made it
over here in uh Luke had released it in
SE in fem seed form it was pretty
uniform too even from the even from the
seed pack so the the kind of centy star
they had on the East Coast would match
up a lot with what was going on on the
West Coast very very uh
consistent here's a good one for you I
know you can wax poetic about the
Shram I liked the Sham man I really did
you know I got excited when a friend of
mine got that cut back recently and I
started thinking about potential seed
making projects immediately just got
excited and uh that excitement tempered
a little bit
um as as far as the seed making goes
yeah because when I think Colombian I
believe that's
Colombian Colombian
Romulan Colombian Romulan yeah the
little bit of experience I have with
different Colombian genetics man you
never know what you're gonna get right
with
yeah and I realize that's there's
nothing scientific about that conclusion
but in my decision making process that's
concl iion I use um but as far as
smoking I really liked it that
was that's the and I know it's it's an
old stereotype that string but that is
the most nag Champa insense like string
yeah that the way it smells while it's
growing that's what it smells like
smells like that when you smoking it and
smells like that in room after you're
done sming you know and just the the
person still have it that you were
talking to they still rocking it I don't
know if theyve flowered it yet but
supposedly they have it that'd be cool
that'd be cool to see my DMs to remind
myself of which person that was yeah I
hate when that [ __ ] happens bro hate
it yeah oh I know who it was yeah um I'm
sure they'll give it a good run and test
and I don't think it's on of lock down
or anything yeah I doubt it because it's
so few people know what it is to even
know to want it
anymore well actually I remember
shy picking people when he released that
c but uh it got passed around number of
people first time I grew it I actually
killed it off at like day 25 I was like
look I'm just G start again because I
did not plan I had never grown a plant
stretch like that yeah don't never have
Dr a plant that that stretches that much
yeah and I was in a closet at the time I
didn't even have a tent other than a
yeah and she just she took off I mean
Beyond even tying over the space between
I'm like okay I know what I did wrong I
mean I flowered her at like two feet
tall in closet yeah was s feet tall in I
bet three weeks yeah
um but yeah I grew her for a while
uh the bud structure always annoyed me a
little bit you know it was not a was not
a yielder Weight Wise you have a plant d
That's I finally got it put out and it's
like jeez but since I have
acquired uh a taste for for dry sift
hash and making my own hash yeah that
that's what I'm really excited to do I
can only imagine how good that
has and we'll see we'll see if the
flowers earn and sit I'm definitely get
my hands on so real quick like kind of
as an aside when you talk about dry sift
hash do you would you prefer the profile
of the resin to be more greasy or more
like Sandy for doing dryi
hash
100% not because of the quality of hash
just for the sake of keeping your
screens [ __ ] clean man yeah
difference when you're when you're dry
siy yeah uh I've got some strains that
uh that I've sifted a few times it's
like man I just I don't want to try this
[ __ ] anymore the hash is amazing yeah
it's actually it's actually
uh trop cherries by Relentless yeah yeah
you know you don't expect the resins to
be that gooey because of the way they
grow on the plant yeah the way they even
look on the flowers and and the leaf
material uh but they are gooey when they
go through that screen man uh but the
hash is from that St is is awesome oh I
bet I know it's a big hit because of
that people love that chop Cherry hash
well I just I I was reading uh Fletcher
argued with somebody about how Tropicana
cherries was just
a a lower remake of the
Tang hit
with I don't even remember what the
argument was about but I thought he was
short
drifting Tropicana cherries a little bit
yeah I mean it it it I've always
wondered how you get cherry on top of
Orange because orange is usually so
dominant I mean it's a hard pick well
the the cut that that I have now uh I
haven't grown it yet but I've seen it
being grown yeah for the three and a
half years by my buddy here so I've been
making half that
leaf um it's more orange than than it is
Cherry is it okay that makes
sense but in the hash
once you sift it like it's almost
like it's almost like the orange turs
don't make final screen for the
hash but Cherry do and it comes out very
much smelling like Cherry pip
toac is it is it a cherry pie cross the
drop
cherries I don't think so it doesn't it
doesn't seem like uh
it doesn't seem like cherry pie to me at
all I actually like cherry pie I ran
that for for a little yeah I did
too um it's a little closer to didn't
uh didn't CSI do a cherry pie Tim D
cross I'm sure did yeah that would be a
nice combination oh yeah yeah dude I
like I've always liked cherry pie quite
a bit so I guess trop trop cherries is I
just looked at Relentless as site it's
the Tropicana cookies which was uh I
don't know Tangi cookies crossed with
cherry cookies F3 which I don't know
much about their their cherry cookies or
what made the cherry or whatever but it
it's a gorgeous cut it's a gorgeous cut
I like Relentless a lot too really cool
dudes yeah I've been rooting for him any
of the guys that came up on the forums
you know
got or even we're we already in their
early years when they were
on they tend to have a different
attitude too like I don't know why I've
always gotten along with him real well
and it just uh it's one of those things
where you know kind of get where each
other came from what kind of [ __ ]
what kind of [ __ ] each other put up
with to get here well in fishstick Uncle
fishstick from the forums he's he's here
uh he also has a cherry cookies cut that
is actually that is a pretty insane cut
like that was when when he started
growing that I got some of that that was
the first time I've
been here in Las crues and found
something that I mean oops I smoked a
little too much that time yeah kind of
surprise you know it took me off guard
I've had had a number of cookies crosses
that I like smoking you know
sure but that one he's also got a got of
what's the kimd isn't
uh what's the kimd GMO is that K yeah
yeah yeah it's like a yeah it's a camd I
don't know if it's uh Forum or camd or
some kind of cookie
camd yeah it's uh speaking of New Mexico
drying and curing you know that stuff
I've got sample of and it's about three
weeks of curing now and it I mean it
just takes yeah dude you could tell
there's KD in it just when you smell
it what's that you could tell there's
camd in it just when you smell it like
instantly I it's I kind of milked that
that jar a little bit you know yeah it's
it's
good but the the 92 OG potency wise uh
it punches the GMO in the face oh
interesting yeah I mean it's uh it's one
of those it's one of those OG cuts that
I'm not sure I would want that to be my
permanent OG cut yeah because it's a
heavy hit High yeah like I I smoke last
of that GMO now instead of 92 OG before
this show because I'm still like ready
to fall out here you
know oh speaking of OG did you ever get
to try the Tokyo OG when you're in San
Diego no I remember that dispensary
Point LMA people talking about the Toyo
OG yeah at first there was the usual you
know bitching and moan in to rename
this um and that happened with every
single OG that popped up sure you know
yeah but it was around for a while I
mean [ __ ] fire it was [ __ ] fire
yeah who know OG kush yeah who were big
on that on the Tokyo OG the first time I
smoked it I couldn't drive home bro I
couldn't drive home I had to give
someone my keys and that's when I was
like [ __ ] this is strong you know like I
I figured any other [ __ ] OG but it
was strong like something else to
it the variety that has come from the
what I assume are all S1 seeds or not
all but for the most part yeah bag seeds
I mean just the quality I've got okay so
resin lung in addition to that cut he
gave me two big vials of seeds it's got
to be I don't
know thousand OG seeds that were just
taken out his crew was moving
yeah and they were just selected he's
even got the two guys name on the bottle
Oh Yeah from I think
oh I I think it's stated 04 through 08
yeah so it's a bunch of bag seats from
the big you know because they didn't
want the seats going out they were
picking them out yeah yeah yeah and uh
I'm I'm over for probably 200 on those
ones oh brutal yeah yeah I you know I
always just occasionally get it it'll
come back to bite me though because you
know I like to pop five at a time in my
current setup yeah
five uh and I'll drop those in now like
30 or 40 of them one day you're going to
get
40 day I'm G to get like 85% germination
and how could you let any of that [ __ ]
go you know you couldn't absolutely
couldn't I've got a bunch of old scenes
that I want to pop right now the problem
is having having room having room and
viability I mean I like I told you the
story about uh great scho sent me the
last of the bull rider seeds that he had
I think they were from gerbo one of the
guys and um I had a person that I
thought was going to be able to to crack
them by a tissue culture and that dude
ended up being not able to do it and so
I sent him back to gry skull and I don't
know if he ever found anyone for it but
those would be worth it to to try to
crack you know let me some of those I
don't know if it was at the same top or
maybe it was ones you sent back to him
I'm not sure
I had zero luck I even tried the seed
cracker on a couple of
them uh I tried putting some and
straight
dirt uh and made sure that you know they
didn't get I mean like three times a day
just making sure it wasn't packed too
hard above the seeds
yeah yeah you know I always wondered if
old Betsy was selfed if you could go
through that population and find
something more similar to bull riter
than old Betsy itself if they're truly
related and you got to check out those
pictures Sean gr has a
new oh I haven't seen him look to it
it's very similar to bull rider you you
could tell just by looking at the buds
between bull rider and Afghan bull rider
you you pick each one of them out
immediately and uh from what I've seen
of the live plants Sean posted uh it
it's definitely a full Rider leaner
interesting I don't even know if he's
smoked I don't know if he's finished
harvesting I'll hit him up yeah hit him
up and find out I'm
interested all right Super Silver Haze I
know we covered some of this about um
where the cut came from the uh the
different nomenclature of it whether it
was the 98 Cup winning cut uh whether it
wasn't can you talk a little bit about
what you've seen in the breeding that
you've done with
it you know I went back because number
of people hit me up about it after last
show yeah but we did and I went back and
looked on my Instagram and my where
where I was posting about it as I was
growing it as I was curing it
and there's there's more
info in those five or six posts than
than what I even went over on the show
last time yeah comes up you look at six
of my last seven flower posts have been
uh three different types of plant that
I've
seen that a number of people have seen
you know come from those and the one
thing came up I noticed a lot was lining
I forgot how liny those things were
especially one in particular
last um on my Instagram I described it
as limey or limey Jack herrer okay yeah
it really reminded me Jack Herrera is
actually one of I think when we were
talking about Cy star I mentioned
getting a strain from the dispensary and
trusting that that was it Jack Herrera
was one of the first ones I got and I
love I for Jack rcut as much as I
enjoyed that first
uh Jack experience that I had from the
dispensary
um and the primary difference between
the classic Jack rare and the SSH to
me uh was the flavor it was a little
more uh with the
SSH uh and that comes across uh in that
last run I did a three different plants
one I described as lyine one was lemony
and then one was was the weirdo which
was just pissed off and looked unhappy
the whole
time uh you could tell you can tell that
the one of the two hazes in SSH yeah
through in
seeds uh I described it last time as
'90s Seed Catalog stock photo of a '90s
a hybrid yeah uh it was very typical
pictures from back then I guess that was
actually the the the 2000s really no
that was the '90s too
um but she's very dominant in the one
cross I've made yeah I mean if if you
like SS you'll like everything that
comes from this
plan uh from this
cross uh and that's the one we have
labeled uh sssdh on the uh on site on
riot
right yeah it's uh it's definitely the
non Haz leaners the Haz leaners are
obvious from what I've been told from
the other Growers who have grown it what
I've seen pictures of what I've grown
here myself yeah no doubt uh number one
they don't like small containers for
their Reas they a bigger container the
SSH is the SSH leaners are very much uh
classic indoor grow you can grow this
much from this much almost
Hydro properties when it comes to the pl
you're going to get I grew them in three
gallon containers they were you know
four feet tall
yeah big yielders as you would expect
because that's pure SSH right there
that's
absolutely um but The Hazing fenos which
I really got a kick out
uh they want the
bigger the bigger pots I'll let you
know comes through in the high uh much
more body in the SSH leaners yeah than I
mean they have the same look when you
look at the SSH mom you don't think pure
sativa by any stretch in the
imagination uh because it's just too
good of a the buds are thick and yeah
branches are fully loaded
uh but from The Taste and the smell you
definitely get the sativa impression
yeah uh but own you it'll it'll kick you
it'll kick you in the stomach you know
it's
yeah sounds like an ideal the ideal
hybrid using uh Super Silver Haze and
the sour dub you know you get lucky in
that way like I said on the first show
pretty much the only thing I said on the
the first show was it wasn't what I was
looking for and that's just because it
doesn't resemble anything to do with
sour double except a sweetness uh a
tightness
in
heightening and improving the sweetness
of SSH because the S has that cedar over
bite you know yeah uh little bit
accurate but the sour double smooth out
makes it a little
sweeter and it gives it a better
high or at least more balanced everybody
loved that sshi you know that hike right
between indicia and sativa for me it
just wasn't potent enough you know I
think I used of how many how much we had
to smoke to get through a Raiders
game you had to smoke a lot you know
yeah um that was the only downside but
it tastes so good that
you know like sour double or east coast
Sour Diesel you just keep smoking yeah I
can imagine that lip smacking translate
like how with the sour translating on on
top of that uh SSH would be really
freaking nice yeah and that's not to say
that won't pop up I got a 50 seed grow
going with krd yeah out where Long Beach
wherever out there in Southern
California and maybe he will find more
of that sour influence yeah but it's
definitely
something if I were to describe it I
would say you're going to get the SSH
experience you're gonna
get you know a lot of the younger
generation are not as hip to the SSH and
I'm sure a lot are interested in it so
it's a great place for them to start you
know as opposed to trying to hunt
through you know the 30 seeds of [ __ ]
Super Silver Haze to try to find one
keeper you know and if you're new you
know if you're new to smoking if you
came around after the sshs and the
Neville's
Haze this is a good plant because it's
got all the potency that any of the yeah
any new fangled stuff has I mean it's an
ass kicker for sure um so you're not
going to a pure SSH experience at all
you're going to you're still going to
get all the body that you need how long
is a flowering on average do you think
uh people going to find there all the
SSH leaners I've flowered I flowered for
6870 days
yeah uh the Haz
laners uh I took mine to 85 this last
time and it probably could another week
yeah but it was it was sadiva you know
it was
ha um it had one of the interesting
things about that plant that I forgotten
about was when I had it I had it in the
tub you know finishing up drying burping
and when I would open it the the aroma
was movie theater popcorn butter oh wow
I did not expect at all uh but when you
up an individual flower and held it to
your nose give it a little squeeze it
was it was like Sweet Tarts it was super
sharp oh wow
it's one of the weirdest is that a
dichotomy yeah yeah weirdest situations
and and post cure it lost the the movie
theater butter popcorn smell it just
sweetness but didn't taste like SSH at
all didn't look like SSH it looked like
a very dense
small uh
Haze a lot of different Haze hybrids out
there
a lot of range in that term yeah and
these smaller flowers that were
everywhere yielded huge I smoked that
cut and I cut alone for almost six
months I really went full on that was my
first real experience with the
sativa even though it's not a pure
sativa genetic by by breeding by lineage
it was was it was it was Haze man and it
was my first real experience with that
yeah I remember talking to you during it
and how you're how you're opinion
changed over time like you know I kind
of like this [ __ ] [ __ ] you know yeah
yeah I did a complete 180
uh over the course of a year you know
some yeah some work hash um and again
cure is nothing new to any of us but
it's still something that can amaze me
to this day
absolutely not care matter of fact I
still got some of that it's dry as hell
but I still have some of that you know
when when people talk about making live
resin hash and
like doing that without curing the plant
how does that how does that hit you like
does that sound advisable would you be
something like that you're hashing for
tping is that all it is I mean
when they advertise it that that's I
mean the high no way is the high going
to be better
yeah if I have the term correct any live
resin live rosin any live resin hashish
that just means they cut the plant down
trimmed it and threw it in the freezer
right and then hashed yeah um I mean I'm
not dogging it hell dude [ __ ] rosin
changed a whole lot the first time I
ever
smoked um but yeah no it's not going to
have the same properties there are so
many chemical processes that we still
that scientists still have not looked
into yeah
within uh not to mention what happens
when you completely compress and mix
those those
chemicals and then let them form into
into a third chemical compound you know
there's left but I don't personally
there is no concentrate that I don't
like you
know problem
yeah but to me the
solventless uh
cured hashish is just my personal
favorite uh I remember the first time
keeping track of curing the flowers that
I harvested and doing it and burping it
in the beginning having them in glass
jars
the first few times I mean it it it
really blows your mind the first time
you do it yeah and some are more
dependent on it than others rev Cindy 99
is probably the most cure dependent
strain I've ever seen because what goes
into those jars after harvest is so
heavy smelling it almost makes me
nauseous yeah what come four six weeks
later is that sweet light Airy that you
expect from a city 99
yeah um so yeah so I'm a big fan of
curing before
making hash she concentrates any of that
but again you're talking about cannabis
concentrates so it's still Gonna Get You
Higher six months yeah I was just I was
thinking about that because people are
asking me about doing uh concentrates
with my blueberry and realistically
blueberry the type that we've made and
worked on it takes a good month for it
to fully form back in because once you
chop it down a lot of that that super
Berry smell dissipates and as you cure
it it comes back full force like tenfold
but people were talking about making
live rosin with it I was just like I
don't I don't know how that's going to
do any fa you know favors for you if
you're chasing blueberry you know well
again that's what we say it's strain
dependent you know I would say that
there's plants that smell that the way
they smell at the end of harvest M
preferable in some you know fine points
here and there to the cured smell you
know there there's some out there when I
say they're they're pressing for turs I
mean that's what I assume because I've
never heard the argument that fresh
resin is or Bo
yeah you know what I mean so I'm
assuming that when they do the live
they're
doing particular strength yeah I
remember strawberry cream was that way
that was that was another one where it
was like instantly the way it smelled at
cure or right at dry was super
strawberry you really didn't get much
more strawberry as it cured so it
probably would be good for something
like that in that sense but I don't know
how the high would translate for sure no
and when you're pressing meaning what I
assume to be heat you know
rosin you're getting all the tpes that
are on that plant at the time
of um when you do dry shift for example
or bubble hash my two favorite ways of
of
hashing uh you've got different size
screens so in a lot of cases like bubble
people who make bubble hash they keep a
lot of different grades they keep
anywhere from two to five grades for
different reasons yeah reasons are
they're all different you know you can
go within the sizes that made it through
each screen and you can
assume uh especially as you as you get
smaller that everything going through
that screen is one kind of triome or
triome stock or
some plants have different size tricomes
you know so when you when I do dryft the
the trop cherries is a good example if
you get that as flour you're gonna
you're going to be hit with that that
Citrus orange smell right off the bat
yeah uh flour but for whatever reason I
only keep hash that's been worked on 220
lines per inch whatever's left top of
the 220 LPI which is 75 microns
approximately whatever's left on top of
that 220 LPI screen that's what my hash
is I don't even keep any of the other
ones doesn't mean they're not good
doesn't mean they're not potent it's
just
that's that's the hashes everything else
is something that great um so when I
scream the Tropic can of cherries
wherever those
whatever those orange chirping are at
wherever they're kept at it doesn't make
my 220 screen it's either the the the
pile below it or the pile that was left
on top of the 110 that I used to get
220 that's so carry pipe tobacco smell
and no Citrus at all I never even
realized or came to the conclusion that
it could do that but that makes total
sense as you explain it that's kind of
stream of Consciousness overall because
I'm still learnning how it's going but
that's that's a really good example so
for example the the blueberry nine yeah
the blueberry nine yeah might come out
uh extremely blueberry either at time of
harvest or a month down the road or
maintain it the whole time that doesn't
mean that blueberry turpine will make it
into into the hatch yeah that's
correct uh it all depends yeah that
makes sense dude yeah I never thought
about it that way well the second oldest
form of cannabis behind growing the
plant itself uh is still the most
unexplained and that's you know dry SI
hases yeah it's still unexplained form
unexplored
scientifically form
of
yeah well we're about an hour and 20 in
so I think uh let's see is there
anything else we wanted to get in in
this episode cuz we're going to do some
more uh the San Diego's Cuts I don't
know that we ever talked about J1 no no
let's hit up
J1 what's
that no we haven't touched on J1
yet you back there I had a phone call
coming in oh there you go you're
here I had a phone call coming in sorry
about that you're
good
so so we didn't we didn't touch on that
last
time that was a wicked strain uh for for
bag appeal it's one of the best I've
ever
seen uh to our knowledge it's uh Jack
rare skunk number one yeah was brought
back from
Amsterdam what my source thinks is the
the the 90 % solid story of it
yeah he brought it he gave it to me it
was interesting because the forums were
getting
going and me and this guy had already
been in touch he's a friend of he was a
friend of reps he's passed on now yeah
mountain or no from uh the Cabana or
skunk magazine
okay um Oldtimer buddies with rev he hit
me up he was one who got me all of revs
seeds uh pollen from his breeders
program yeah he was the intermediary
between me and the r
um he had this cut the forums were
getting going and he had an interesting
idea he wanted to bring J1 he was up in
Shasta he brought it down to San Diego
and he wanted to see online how fast it
would take for that cut to spread yeah
just just because the internet was new
to us old times you know what I mean
yeah like we already had the cuts thread
going I already had seeds thread going
let just see what so we gave it to G uh
I think he was working with Shan at the
time I think yeah I
think
um and he gave it out and we gave him
lots of cuts that he grew into a number
of mothers so it spread fast and you
literally could watch it in the forums
as it made its way back up north and
within the first two months there are
already two [ __ ] origin stories out
there people play yeah you but it was it
grew so Jack herrer like yeah
uh but even more coated with resin than
the best pictures of Jack rare they ever
showed I mean it was just C uh it
smelled like uh yellow Gatorade to me
like wow expressed as yellow Gatorade
yeah but the potency Factor wasn't
really keeping up with everything else
that was around I mean it's a nice it
was a nice daytime smoke but it uh it
went through the circles down there in
San Diego pretty quick
yeah
yeah watch I remember there was a
collective in um San Diego
called BCC it was downtown Broadway in
between seventh and eth on Broadway and
they would sell the the whatever the
worst Bud that they had at the time they
would label J1 and they would sell it as
J1 how [ __ ] up is
that give it a bad W you know yeah dude
it's the worst they were a bunch of
yuppies anyway so figures right yeah it
was a nice combo of those 90s
Amsterdam yeah makes
sense I crossed it to uh matter of fact
same guy got me some iron Cindy poen
yeah
rev and I hit that and made
F1 J1 cross with iron Cindy and then
some of those seats made their way to a
user his username was you are average
with a u and an
R uh average and he made both f2s and
f3s and made sure I got some of those
seats back too that's pretty cool it' be
interesting because you throw that metal
Haze I had some of the metal Haze and
some of the metal Haze hybrids rev and
and Mountain are part of a group of
growers in Northern California yeah and
fall I would get a box from Mountain and
it was like iron Cindy uh Cherry Malo V1
1948 yeah yeah yeah combinations there
in outdoor
grown by old heads just I
mean like if you were to put pot in a in
a capsule to send to aliens those are
the guys you'd want growing it in that
area of the country it was just some of
the best outdoor weed I've ever s yeah
and that pH puts puts a little o in
anything that it was cross with the iron
C I got lucky um I got I got his uh
metal Haze cut early on like the actual
cut cut and was able to grow it it was
it was definitely cool uh made a lot of
crosses with it early on rev rev he's uh
A Relic from the past and not enough of
the the younger dudes know about him but
he's very influential yeah on Instagram
because eight got some uh red is it
Russian River skunk or red red red
Russian skunk red Russian skunk yeah
picked up a pack of those and I was like
I I don't understand why this guy has
never had his time
in in the you know online world you know
there's all over the world who know who
he is with his soil and his genetics but
I don't understand everybody's always
bitching I want something that's
different yeah right using the same [ __ ]
well hit up Kingdom organic seeds
because it's all different there every
bit of it I think it's because he never
dipped into OG Kush he never dipped into
any hype strains and crossed him into
his stuff so there was like no little
middle ground for like people that
wanted OG but wanted to try something
different with OG like they just never
got introduced to him that way you had
to be from a certain era to really get
what he was doing and why he was doing
it the way he was doing it he say he has
killer [ __ ] at 70s and 80s
weed he used Madness in the cross that's
right that's right but Madness was not
like the others Madness was you know an
Oregon big bud cross it was from the era
before
p91
yeah and all that which is probably why
he liked it yeah it would make sense
yeah shout out rev he deserves
it well I guess I guess we can call this
one an episode is there anything else
you want to get in on this one we're
going to probably do a few more anyways
yeah no I made notes but they're all in
my phone
so next time we'll teach you how to hook
up your phone to your printer to print
them out what's printer yeah what's that
[ __ ] but yeah um go check out go check
out Rob seeds uh right seeds.com has
some we still have some more of this
gank dog I've got to put Bunch back in
stock that people didn't pay for we have
the uh sssd which was the S the super
silver hay sour dub that we were talking
about um anyone you want to shout
out
yeah I was supposed to wear this tonight
from my buddy
my buddy SAA but unfortunately it's
Snapback and they just don't make
snapbacks gigantic [ __ ] heads like
me he's a local artist here he's got a
shop he does some [ __ ] badass
t-shirts uh I love he does t-shirts in
the Hat Southwest like North Face go
[ __ ] yourself yeah yeah yeah I love
it definitely got some cool [ __ ] check
is check him out online at sa on
Instagram anybody
else no that's
my yeah this your first shout out huh
yeah all right well I appreciate you
taking the time to talk with me and this
is going to be the one of many I'm
sure I probably won't remember much of
it [ __ ] OG
F smash before that I probably didn't
know well it's all good we did good we
got actually got a lot more in than I
thought we would so uh you know what we
did forget so next time is we can I'd
like to get into that
Duty oh yeah because that was all
logged yeah dude literally I'm going
through the threads and I I see okay
here I made a post right here and the
post is so what's this I he
about
double half the plant is [ __ ] and the
other half is perfectly fine yeah it so
ridiculous and stupid at the
time um and and I'm still as far as I
got we're like just starting to work our
way through the through the confusion
and TMV came back up right away you know
of course uh which was a lot more
credible when plants started dutting
yeah but I assume what we were all
calling dutting it was the hlv or
hlb I talked with Tumi Organics and if I
remember correctly they did say that
patient zero was Sour dub like that's
the that's is that if you have hbd
eventually your plants are going to
start dutting correct yes yeah
correct yeah cuz it was was uh it took
over the San Diego I mean we can go into
this next time yeah yeah know it's just
a little taste of it so people know what
to expect next time there you go yeah
yeah because that wiped a lot of people
out yeah it did [ __ ] [ __ ] a lot of
us
up that's what we get for
trading yeah yeah it was it if it worked
its way through as fast as I remember it
then I find it hard to believe we're
ever going to be rid of it yeah no it's
it's it's total uh a lot of the
libraries in Spain now it got
transported over there via cookies and
all kinds of other [ __ ] so yeah it's
still working its way around the world
just taking [ __ ]
out what a
disaster all right man well I appreciate
you and uh we'll have you back very soon
all right man right
peace want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out