welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to breeder Syndicate
I'm Matthew with my co-host thousandfold
today we're here with a very good friend
of mine sub Rob from seed trip seed trip
seeds I get we say seed trip seeds trip
seeds SE trip it's just seed trip just
seed trip all right thousand take it
away yeah so the first thing I wanted to
ask is actually where does the name sub
Robb come
from I uh that came
from uh around 2000 I think uh I was
going on a road trip I'd settled in San
Diego I was going on a road trip I had
no idea how the internet worked at that
time uh and I was going on a road trip
so my girlfriend wanted me to set up uh
an
email and tried rob you know a few
variations of my name and uh then I
looked down I was eating a sub sandwich
and I'm like well how about sub
Rob from the sub sandwich yeah that's
literally where it came
from until a few years later when I
learned how to Google and I googled sub
robob and a whole different sub Rob came
up under
images uh some dude in leather who was
submissive sweet sweet submissive Rob so
the first chance I got it I changed to
seat trip yeah yeah I like I like
submissive Rob better though yeah good
for him but you know it just wasn't my
trip Daddy I didn't think about the
submissive thing at all I was thinking
like sub Rob like less than Rob which I
thought was really funny well you
know with that idea but no it was it was
literally a sub sandwich Submarina in
specific for those oh [ __ ] that's right
yeah that's good [ __ ]
too that's funny dude that's hilarious
okay
so go ahead thousand no I was gonna say
so you saying that was around 2000 um
were you growing
then yeah I started
growing fulltime in the early
mid90s uh in
Portland uh I had gone home for the
first time to Alaska to
work and uh I went ahead and grabbed old
blueberry um clone that had that's been
floating around Belta since the early
80s at least yeah down to Portland and
and started growing full-time down there
so when you start you you mentioned
Alaska let's start there if we can so in
Alaska during during your years growing
up there you know you mentioned earlier
that like it was more legal in Alaska
than it was the rest of the states what
kind of stuff were you seeing when you
first started
smoking well nothing really had names
back then at least not our Circle we had
some names just to differentiate the
Growers like Bruce's Halloween bud you
know
Mike's Mike's greenbud you know [ __ ]
like
but and of course Blueberry Blueberry
was the first one that ever had just a
specific moniker that I came across yeah
that was pretty self-evident why I mean
it's that was that that's a crazy cut
still going evidently yeah is you
referring to Old Blue old blue Alaska
blue that's right I was watching one of
the one of the podcasts last year and I
was in the live chat and somebody
hopefully F he's watching he or she is
watching
now uh mentioned they were from North
Pole which is right up the road by
Alaska standards Delta yeah and uh he
asked where I was from when I mentioned
I was from the interior and I said Delta
and the first thing he did was type in a
few blueberry emojis oh wow that's 2022
first time I smoked that cut
was probably 82 so 40 years later the
same cut is still synonymous with my
hometown so that predates DJ Short by
quite a
bit uh probably but I mean I personally
have always thought just like skunk that
you could find Blueberry in I'm sure can
Afghan seed lines yeah no it makes sense
makes sense it's just so cool to see
something like that back
then what's that it's so cool to know
that there was something like that back
then that was and called blueberry at
the time because of its sense yeah I
mean I was in high school when I first
scored blueberry it was probably
freshman or sophomore year so that would
have been that would have been 84 or
85 and the people I got it from talked
about it like it had been around for a
while so that's
wild I don't know start start his
blueberry line uh I know he he first
started selling it in mid 90s
so selling it but God knows what you
know I don't know how long ago he worked
it and let stuff out or clones out but
who knows on that to be honest yeah and
I have no doubt I don't remember
seeing when did The Seed Catalog start
showing up in High Times 85 was the
first
time I want to say that was I want to
say that was the one where um they were
putting like after 1 Afghani 2 from Sam
the skunk band that quick little list of
skunk one and stuff like that I don't
know where anybody would have gotten any
commercial seed in the interior of
Alaska in the early 80s you know what I
mean now we had lots of seeds there was
a lot Mak sense there was a lot of
Travelers in Alaska same kind of hippie
expat veteran angry crazy [ __ ]
who wanted to go visit Afghanistan
and India you know Alaska was also on
their itinerary you know I mean it's
exotic a place a good place to go get
lost not be
found no shortage of seeds uh when I was
growing up
but clones really took hold in the mid
80s yeah around where I was from
especially
blueberry
what when did you first see Matt nusa
Valley [ __ ] show
up well going back to strain names
nothing really had a strain name back
then yeah back then everything that came
from the valley and I'm sure not just
the valley being matusa Valley yeah not
matusa Valley probably Anchorage and
Palmer and was probably every everything
was called mat NSA [ __ ]
especially during the summer uh when
tourists around oh I bet I
bet but other you know other people have
commented on some of my posts and
threads that they've never smoked the
same Thunder [ __ ] Yeah have commented
that they've never smoked the same
Thunder [ __ ] twice you know yeah that
makes sense I wonder why it took cold
though any idea look man skunk when did
skunk number one become a strength uh
78 okay well that that nips that
argument in the bud right there because
I was going to say skunk was a term
before skunk number one but oh yeah yeah
know everywhere I lived whether it was
Oregon Alaska
California and this is all pre- internet
everybody use the term skunk you know
Maui wild there's there's 50 different
strains named ma
absolutely that is the real deal MTF or
the real deal Maui wow but once people
start using the name you know fast
forward 20 years later who's to say what
is what you know yeah right it's lost in
the mix people didn't trade strains a
lot back then there were certain small
groups that you were basically well in
in my situation it was it was who your
parents knew you
know out with that's where you got to
cut if you got to cut at all so I just I
I don't think MTF has been a strain
specific name since probably
the80s yeah every grower in the valley
and I used to go down I lived in
Anchorage for a couple years and which
is close to the Bley and the friends I
knew who grew down in that area were out
in matusa Valley everything was matusa
everything Mar bro don't sweat it
because if somebody gets a cut from
Alaska
that's worth you know making a hybrid
out of or a poly hybrid out of it's
pretty good it's probably a pretty damn
good cut yeah I never had bad weed until
I got to Humble for
college you leave it to California to
leave that impression right now I also
had some of the [ __ ] best pot
I'd ever smoked in my life in Humble but
I've never had bad weed last did did a
lot of Mexican brick weed make it up to
Alaska
too wow I didn't experience that till I
moved
to I might have seen some in
Humble when I moved to New Mexico was my
first real experience with Mexican brick
week so that's not even that long ago
right take back i' got
someone when we were I used to spend the
summers in California yeah um my parents
were from Humble and one of
their my paternal grandparents moved
from McKinleyville to uh s to the Bay
Area because he worked
for uh so I used to score weed with my
friend Matt in San Francisco and yeah I
remember getting brick weed then too so
in my teens were your parents Growers or
were they into that scene at all smoking
at least well my dad uh smoked whenever
his friends came over or he went over
there or they were working or there's a
lot of party in in Alaska you know
there's yeah imagine so yeah uh and they
also take work very serious because a
lot of the work you can only get done
during the summer so the
Summers uh with all of our parents were
a matter of working 16 to 18 hours a
day when you snatched a few joints from
their stash yeah right you know
yeah so you got a thousand what question
do you want to get
in I was actually more curious about um
what life was like for you back then and
like how you you know how you gravitated
towards the plant and all of
that um well it was uh I'll tell you
what really got me into weed the first
the first stuff I got into I think my
first
true love in the drug category was
probably LSD I loved acid as far back as
you know I I tripped the first I started
I don't know fifth grade sixth
grade you know by sixth grade I'd had
enough trip what I was doing and I also
grow grew up in an environment where
where we didn't have TV we didn't have
electricity for for a lot lot of it so I
read a lot and my dad had a lot of
counterculture books so I
really got into everything from the who
were the whacked out hippies on the bus
that began the whole hippie movement to
the Grateful Dead to marry pranksters
the you know and so there was a lot of
mention of
cannibis but for the most part I viewed
p as something to come down off of LSD
or mushrooms yeah
or or all those all that speed we had in
the 80s black beauties you know yeah
right whatever we used to get through
the school day um and that's what it was
for uh it didn't really become something
I was really passionate about until I
was
in either sophomore years or junior year
of high
school I was assigned to write a story
uh about the war on drugs and because
remember this mid 80s
yeah couldn't escape the War on Drugs
propaganda and I got I got assigned to
write a paper I don't know if it was
journalism or if it was just some sort
of writing class on the War on Drugs
specifically cus yeah and what I used to
do for my schoolwork is in the Library
we had these they were like
encyclopedias I think they were called
the S issues
SS
okay something along those lines and
basically what is they would address a
subject and they would present procon
proside and a conside and they would
back up each side with all the evidence
that they could find while they were
assembling the
encyclopedia and uh so I went and I
started reading you know you start with
the discovery of Delta tc9 whatever it
is yeah in Israel at a university and
then I read all the the Prides and then
I read the the consite for legalization
of
cannabis and
uh that's why I learned about the DEA
schedule you know schedule one through
four
and within 20 minutes within a half an
hour a 15-year-old kid in the mid
80s you know no internet no outside
interviews just two books figured out
that cannabis being illegal was was
[ __ ] yeah to be a schedule one
narcotic you must have no medicinal uses
well the guy who discovered
and labeled Delta 9
THC also noted like the first experiment
he did was on uh what was cataracts yeah
glaucoma or something like that yeah
swelling of the optic nerve and how
cannabis had the medicinal effect yeah
of shrinker back down not to mention all
the Bro Science from all the hippies
that you know were still in their 30s at
the time yeah and it was really shocking
to me that was my first real moment of
wow the government is pulling one over
on us and that led to you know the the
industry behind the War on Drugs you
know in hindsight it's tough to remember
when I discovered what phase of the the
industry of the war on Canabis and who
was making money off of it and where and
how much privatized you know prison
industry and on and on and on but as
hard as it is now in hindsight to
remember the exact timeline of
discovering those things I'll never
forget that day in the library when I
was 14 or 15 going wait a minute this
does not add up and at that point that's
when you know a a cannbis activist was
born in me yeah no makes sense it always
been something that you know our parents
and our parents friends and our teachers
and our future teachers and that was
something for them that was old man [ __ ]
give me a couple squares of acid a 40 of
malt liquor right Reds and a joint for
tomorrow morning and I was good you know
yeah I had you know I feel to stories
down I mean I tend to ramble especially
when I'm this side oh no that's good no
that's that I had a similar experience
uh growing up like weed was always
around but it was always like it wasn't
a drug to us like we were into drugs and
that was like okay yeah we'll smoke weed
but it was to you know come down off
this or in the meantime of getting this
or that it was always just kind of there
and it took a long time for me to find
the same passion that I have now similar
to your story yeah I probably a lot of
people you know probably came into now
once that happened and once I got a
little older and started meeting the
actual Growers instead of their
kids you know and talking about cannabis
while we sat around smoking it got more
interesting and more interesting and
then
as I was introduced to more
strings uh that that really peaked me
but even when I started in the mid 90s
when I started growing just full on
fulltime it we had one strength and that
was blueberry that was it we didn't give
it to
anybody you know uh our closest friends
the first couple years had no idea we
were the ones who were growing the
Skiller weed
yeah it was so blue I Matt I know you're
a strin nut it this is how blue old blue
is
from from from Delta uh a lot of people
would travel together during the winter
a lot of us would work up their seasonal
you know
firefighting working out in the woods
with geologists exploratory geologists
looking Gold Mine [ __ ] like that and
then go wherever we wanted in the winter
some of them
go snowboarding you know in Utah or
wherever um and so this one winter three
people from Delta came with me down to
Portland to where I had my established
circle of
friends and one of them was the guy who
gave me the blueberry cut his stepdad
was the guy who gave me the blueberry
cut so Bill knew that I had spent the
previous winter growing blueberry in
Portland went back home worked Billy
came with
us uh and and my partners already had
the blueberry going when we got back so
the first thing we did when I got there
uh we had to fix the ventilation on the
roof and I said Bill come on up with me
I just got to fix the ventilation for
the grow room yeah and we go we we
smoked a joint of
blueberry climbed up the ladder went
started fixing the ventilation from our
flower chamber and Billy looks around
and goes oo one of your neighbors is
baking blueberry
muffins how high are you you know yeah
it was crazy it it's I've seen so many
Blues
DJs you know I've seen so many Blues
from men and none of them are close to
what that blue very was which is what
old dude says about every old strain you
know yeah but absolutely true nothing
people every place that clone has been
people still tell stories about
that there is a clone that floated
around uh Oregon as well I don't I don't
I it's old and it's also called old blue
and it's also maybe not connected to DJ
Short as
well you know it could be it could be
things did not end well in Portland for
a group of us because there was other
drugs still involved back
sure um and it's
possible the one guy besides me who had
access to it could have Let It Go I mean
yeah to this day he's still on the
needle so he
hasn't so I got to judge his
trustworthiness yeah for sure you know
so I don't know it it's very possible
but uh there was there was a couple
blueberries in Oregon at the same time
yeah that makes sense bunch of
hippies yeah and I had no idea if it
would survived or not until this past
year
when uh my sister got a hold of my
childhood best
friend his mother on Facebook and they
put the two of us in touch and uh I sent
him a picture in my flower room and he
immediately sent back a picture of his
uh and it was just Captain old blue and
I'm like you're [ __ ] me dude that's
blue still growing it and he's still got
it yeah get that down this way I want to
see it I want to see it that was my
immediate plan um right now I'm [ __ ]
around with those seeds I made and that
guy from Wales sent back to me uh
the blueberry once I get those out of
the way I gotta get an OG out here in
New Mexico man it's killing it is kill
do that that's easy enough yeah well I
I've got it in works right now I I got
to get it done before summertime summer
here you can't ship clones out here yeah
it's the same here it's the same like
nightmarishly hot nothing lives in mail
yeah um so you know I I'll probably talk
to him we we he said he's willing to to
send it down so we'll see I I had some
hesitancy at first it's like
uh you know sometimes what's Hall of
Fame in your mind yeah is exagerated
over the years and I'm old enough to
know that sometimes just leave that
alone yeah but then your show last year
when that when that viewer from from
North Pole started typing in blueberries
I was like [ __ ] if if my hometown is
still known for blueberry pot then yeah
I'm pretty sure it'll hold up just fine
yeah that's pretty cool that's pretty
cool I I I love all blueberries even
though I feel like I've got the best I
still want all of them I need to
experience all of them when I hear about
especially the older ones it may not
even be related or tangentially related
or whatever the DJ's lines you know I'll
say this about DJ J's lines every blue
smell I ever smelled from them wasn't
really blue now that's not a giant pool
of DJ shorts blueberry that I'm drawing
from that's sure I don't know how many
samples from how many Growers I grew his
stuff once it was actually a cross it
was uh it was Dr Atomic from Canada yeah
yeah DJ shorts blue and somebody's
probably sense's nl5 y it actually was
not a bad
cross I remember those pretty fondly
actually there were some good blues that
circulated Canada there really were um
different selections done with DJ stuff
bigger selections done in Canada by
different dudes up there and and they
did pull out some really good Blues but
they were they were few and far between
and hard to get down
here they uh they were they always
seemed more fond of the the fruit tping
in Canada you know even before the
forums you could tell the Canadian seed
companies they were all selling berries
of various types
yep yeah so what was your first Forum
experience where did you first come into
the forums and I because I know you're
you're um technically te technologically
[ __ ] in some aspects how did you end
up on the Forum so early
uh it was that that same time period
that I did the uh the sub Rob at Hotmail
or whatever it was yeah when I came up
with that it was it was on that computer
it was really the first time I've been
on a computer they'd been out but I just
I I was busy you
know uh I started looking for pot and
the first two things I found
were who was who was it who had herana
back in the day motor Rebel and um wood
horse and yeah wood I found that was
like the first pot anything on the
internet I ever found I'm like holy [ __ ]
this guy's selling seeds yeah and then I
overgrown right after that yeah so what
was your experience like there I
never there was a point where I did
register there was I I was super
paranoid still back then sure
um there was a time period when you
didn't have to be registered to view
everything on overgrow and at some point
they made an upgrade where it was only
limited access so people all registered
as like unregistered
1701 I was one of those unregistered
guys for a
little
um but uh then
around
when did I sign up at IC
mag when did IC mag start that was in
the 2000 right
2006 I think it started in 200 2002 or
2003 even earlier yeah I registered in
okay something like that and that was
that was the coolest cannabis experience
I ever had outside of the actual growing
and smoking yeah for sure but that was
you know High Times may be a joke now
the fact that High Times was pretty much
my only source of information sure any
for a decade and a half [ __ ] I mean I
think you look back some of those old
High Times you know that
magazine was not only respectable as far
as I'm concerned they had hulix are
worthy content back then that would have
never been considered oh yeah but when
the qualifications for what it takes to
you know to qualify for awards like that
they had it they had it all I agree
early High Times was amazing some of the
best even some of the best strain
reviews you could ever find you know
back from are The Connoisseur they had
cool punk rock stuff too like they were
very punk rock oriented in the 70s which
I thought was interesting
and metal and metal yeah yeah it wasn't
just the dead you know it wasn't just
Led Zeppelin the dead and the doors bro
it was it was all all
inclusive yeah I uh I enjoyed I mean
that was like what I looked forward to
most each month was High Times mag
coming out you know and you You' catch
your dad gling through it and reading
it it was just uh it it really conveyed
that 60 and
70s Outlaw culture not just hippie
culture oh yeah
sure all the cocaine ads and [ __ ]
Bro all the cocaine ads all over the
place in the old High Times yeah and I
mean they were writing about Ricky Ross
before Ricky Ross got busted yeah they
were writing about the whole conspiracy
of behind around Ricky Ross before
before anybody else was they were a good
so yeah was I don't remember how
um were you concerned about your you
know personal safety at all in this time
like how did it feel to you I'm sure it
both felt like it must have felt
empowering but also like you know were
you
scared when I got on I when I really
started going at it in the Forum no that
point by Pro
25 you know and I didn't give a [ __ ]
it's like come come find me you're
you're seeing everything I'm doing yeah
you know pictures up every day so if you
think you're GNA come find a warehouse
behind me know I like my job too much
you know
here here's my tens you know so I I
wasn't worried at that point at all I
was like come get it I in in
California I understood exactly where
somebody with 25 or 30 flowering plants
ranked on the list of [ __ ] that the
local or feds needed to get done and get
busted yeah point in the early 2000s in
California if you were going growing 25
plants nobody gave a [ __ ] exactly that's
how I felt
too so at that point my paranoia almost
completely
disappeared so when does when does the
sub Rob's Madness cut the San Diego
Madness cut float through what year is
that I started getting that in 1999 it
wasn't a big San Diego cut one guy had
it one grower that was it and he also
bred it it was
uh it was Oregon big bud crossed with an
indicia that he
had uh I started getting it from this
kid his his girlfriend worked with mine
and uh he came
over and started selling me that he also
got bull rider
p91 Betsy Hog's Breath he got every C
every strain that came through San Diego
this 16 or 17 year old kid had access to
awesome family um I never found out who
it was I never cared you know I wasn't
trying to get a better deal just make
sure I don't run out of weed
um and then I started growing again and
this kid would always ask me about
cannabis he he was always interested in
cannabis and cannabis history so when
the guy who was selling him Madness
decided to retire and moved back to
Humble he said I ain't taking this clone
with me he was he was old he I guess he
was
like and uh he told he told my friend
hey man you know anybody who who will
take care of this clone appreciate it
and he said I got just the guy and so he
gave it to me um and that's still one of
my favorite Cuts not the most potent
yeah it was it wasn't going to knock any
of
the the really well-known San Diego
Cuts you know off the top of the
mountain except for in you I've never
had a never had a cut like that what was
the CH profile like on it like the scent
profile it was
uh leathery it was it was in that
leathery you know kind of
suede new suede new leather you know
that
smell
sweetness very hard to describe very
hard but uh it was definitely
unique um tasted just like it smelled
and it had a good solid good solid High
yeah interesting do you have any idea
what it might have been cross to like
with all your years of experience now
looking back wouldn't have a guess I've
had
other I've had other strains that that
fit into that
leathery
pleather tennis ball suede yeah I think
uh the perfect Pearl cross that you sent
me oh yeah yeah that a little bit uh but
it's not a profile that that you see a
lot you know definitely not nowadays it
had like a like an aftertaste too which
is always good with the cannabis strain
it had the not the taste but you know
how Shram immediately evokes nag Champa
oh yeah nag Champa this
invoked the texture of cologne to me
interesting he
necessarily not not NE
a specific scent but just the after
effects
of
should oh you're doing fine no this is
good um this is
great when did you first run into let's
let's go through a little list uh p91
your
experience well I moved to San Diego
moved permanently to San Diego in 99
okay so it was everywhere yeah it was
everywhere I happened to stumble into I
should say most of my friends in San
Diego that I had made prior to moving
there permanently weren't weren't really
smokers they were all
drink
um but it it isn't hard if you're out
drinking to meet
somebody in Ocean
Beach and once they get you a sack of
p91 you don't lose that number you know
right no the
relationship
yeah so how about Hog's
Breath same thing man I I got that
kid that kid who basically became my pot
dealer uh he he had access to everything
pretty much as soon as I met him that
was let's see that was Jennifer so uh
yeah so like 2000 yeah you know I mean
he just started bring every week he'd
bring me a
selection and
then you know we didn't not everybody
had the frame of reference of strain
names back then sure so it wasn't you
know your dealer didn't show up say oh I
got
p91 he showed up killer green Bud right
here and I think 91 you know um so I
don't know which was first but I
remember they all came from that one guy
and and he was only dealing for a couple
years once I met him before he moved on
to more lucrative things yeah so yeah so
I think that my experience with all
those San Diego streams pretty much
started almost immediately that's pretty
cool so I know I know we've moved on
from the p91 but I didn't want to ask
cuz it's it's a name and it's a cut that
still floats around in the group um and
I like to know like your impressions of
it from back then you know how would you
have described it well it's the S1
that's still floating around just the S1
yeah sorry that's it yeah yeah
um well you know it was I did a small
experiment I I I don't remember when I
got the
cut had to be probably I don't know 200
three or so yeah I got the cut and I
noticed something a specific effect that
I got when when I smoked it so what I
did was I had a few guys that I shared
with that I hooked up and two or three
in particular who did not know each
other you know I I gave them each a sack
yeah and them for feedback
I'm like anything specific no matter how
weird or how corny or how important
unimportant you might think it is I just
want to hear it and again they were
separate and all three of them came back
to me with the same exact thing that I
had noticed and that was when I smoked
p91 I slept better than any other time
in my life and I had the most intense
dreams when
interesting and I and I hadn't even so
much as hinted to any of the actually I
think it was two guys
uh I I never said a word about it it was
what do they call it a blind test
yeah they both back and the only thing
they had to say about it was the Sleep
effects the dream
effects and uh as far as other thoughts
so that's the first thing that always
comes to mind when I pick p91 yeah B to
me I remember the taste I remember the
feel of the flowers everything the term
Oily to me
yeah very oily now that's not always a
good you know that's not always a good
quality whether it be from a hash making
perspective to sometimes the strains
I've tried that were oily on the flowers
like that weren't that great or were
more CBD than they were THC sure but
91's case n it was everything was good
I've heard uh peanut oil or just
straight Associated yeah with with to
but uh I'd say oily
and good bed time meds man yeah it's
strong [ __ ] even the S1 kept that that
potency where like people compare it to
kimd type potency stuff like that I'm a
big fan of s1s and that that p91 S1 that
who is is it B has it bit Yeah insane
when he posts it or anybody who's dra
it yeah that's a sick
one yeah that's
cool I was gonna ask if yeah exactly
whether you whether you'd um actually
gotten to try the the S1 that floats
around or if it's just something that
you've seen from a distance I haven't
yet I think that kind of popped up in
San Diego after I'd already left I've
been out here a few years
yeah were you were you one of the people
I think no I think it was grotch and
someone else when someone claimed to
have the original p91 and had a bunch of
people show up to a collective and they
were like sorry bro sorry bro and he got
all mad at everyone that wasn't grotch I
don't think that was grotch might have
been someone else some well some it
wasn't grotch that popped up with a cut
grotch was one of the people I think
that went bitter went a few other people
I had to inform the dude he didn't have
what he thought he had
so you're talking relatively recent yeah
yeah in the past few
years I think that must have
happened again after after I left so
about two or three years two or three
years ago yeah yeah I I'm still in touch
with all those guys were on group
threads and stuff like that but I don't
I don't really know anything about that
let's talk about how you met some of
those dudes on on uh sano's finest Cuts
Like that's
probably when I think of like the most
uh seminal influential uh threads
throughout all Vice mag that of course
that one jumps out to me because I was
in San Diego for a long time and and I
was kind of partial to that and some of
the guys but for you like how did you
all kind of form into a a crew of
Swords uh yeah it uh it started with uh
a guy what was
arts dragor or something like that d r a
g o r drag over yeah he and I were
talking about it and we said we uh ape
you know ape oh yeah yeah Gale
propagation expert had just you know
started moving clones selling
clones and we had got i' had gotten some
some other people that I just talked to
through DM through DMs had gotten
some uh and we were and me and and drag
are started talking about he said hey
let's start a thread on on IC mag that's
specifically just this guy's hooking us
up man by that time we' flowered we'd
been through a couple flower Cycles with
his cuts and they were they were insane
it was some of the best legit dude
yeah so we said let's start a threat
um showcasing everything that he's got
and we'll advertise for him uh even
though it's just California you know at
least and uh it the thread started going
uh the same people started showing up
every day and at some point you know I
used to I used to get every UFC that
came on yeah house and I had at the time
what was big screen TV you know yeah
yeah CD LED and so I invited some guys
over for and my buddy who owned
Submarina uh brought us a big six foot
sub uh for everybody to just Chow Down
on uh and we started getting together to
watch every UFC fight and sample each
other's Wares which you know started the
network uh you know well you grow this
you flower this yeah and I'll flower
this so that you know you didn't have to
flower remember I'd never had access to
Cuts Like like this before this is
200 3
2004 or or no May no probably a little
later than that because we were already
on icy M so let's call it 06
yeah you know I was still popping seeds
in San Diego and growing until I got the
madness cut uh and then I met ape and
hit the bullet and said [ __ ] it I'm
going to trust this dude I'm GNA buy
cuts from somebody I'm not Rel related
to
yeah and I was blown away I mean I had I
had a at the time 4x4 flower tent and I
had probably 35 moms you know yeah yeah
I know what you mean one cut Rob to 35
cut
Rob so yes that's how it started and
then once you're sharing information
like that
anonymously you know you just start
going to the get togethers at robs watch
the fights and let me tell you everybody
was always trying to outdo everybody in
the early times we'd have the get
togethers and even Gypsy warned us
because we talked about it he's like hey
man have your G togethers but you got to
be careful you know law enforcement is
probably you know looking at the [ __ ]
that leftover paranoia from anybody over
30 at the time and we're like prop 15
prop 215 go [ __ ] yourself we suck it
we're done with that [ __ ] yeah and uh
and that's how that's how it started man
and and so everybody would come over to
my
house and everybody would bring like an
ounce of
flour big chunks of hash bubble hash you
know
Edibles and everybody would leave after
like four hours and I would stumble down
into my kitchen the next morning and on
the dining room table is like you know
five grand worth of
weed edibles I'm like what the [ __ ] and
it happened every time and the group was
slowly growing and I would tell people
hey if you see it on this table take it
on your way out you know don't be a lot
of weed but everybody was still polite
and getting to know each other so I
ended up with so much more than I could
ever
smoke so many strings so fast through
that group and that that's too I mean
we're all still friends yeah you know
nobody in that group ever got busted
nobody you know no rat no one ever
ratted that's
good still in touch people have made it
in legal weed others have made it in
Black
Market both you know yeah yeah that's
right the people who were part of that
you know that original group
krd uh he's killing it as he always has
Sean con killing
Grace
yeah yeah it turned out to be a really
great group Growers and always learning
man you went on that thread back in the
day and you started spouting some
[ __ ] you get verbally slapped down
by everybody in oh yeah yeah our we go
each other you know who started that at
was
uh sh big big herb
tree do you remember him no what was his
name big herb tree big herb tree
nuh-uh uh he's the one who started us on
that path of of br
honesty and
criticism and that's one of the
things you know yeah but we all at least
I learned I learned so much from being
on that thre you know what's funny is I
didn't really realize how how
influential ape was in the in the threat
I knew he was you know a part of it I
didn't realize how influential he was in
that group because it's funny because
like he had he was influential on me as
well like he really really hooked me up
early on with clones that you know like
I I didn't understand how how deep of
access I was given immediately as I got
into San Diego and it was just
drastically different than any other
City I've been to like that it was just
like Bam Bam everything's legit from the
get-go it was it was lucky lucky St
swerve would come down there too make
that's right yeah they were Partners
weren't
they probably at some point or were all
the [ __ ] that guy gets you know you know
what I the only thing I have the only
dealings I ever had was getting swerve
cuts and again from where came from to
where I ended up in SoCal in the early
2000s with clone Traders uh dude's okay
my book man oh man yeah he's something
else to me I have my I have my different
experiences but
yeah yeah see I've never had I never had
a bad
experience even that good of a kisser
bro with uh with the pictures of his
plants in High Times yeah yeah you know
but yeah man I love those clone vendors
Wick Wick 650 yeah Wick 650 he was a
part of C Cali Connection 2o I think or
he was involved with getting sort of his
early Cuts yeah yeah and those guys were
all involved with each other at some
point I mean it's just like uh just like
us splitting up you know flowering
duties for new clones amongst the San
Diego finest guys I'm sure those guys
were like hey man if you'll take OG you
know over to San Bernardino for me I'll
drop GDP off in the bay for you you know
I'm so I just looked at the thread in it
the first one is 2008
um I also thought
that I could ask you about some of the
other cuts that were around um sour
dub sour
du my favorite plants of all time yeah
it's a damn good cut
dude matter of fact I've got it coming
back with the OG that I've got coming
I've got uh
got OG I've got you know what I don't
even give a [ __ ]
what what label comes with an OG but
anyway I I'm wandering off your path
again thousand so sour double yes uh The
Taste
incredible uh one very fast plant to
grow only plant that I take early like I
take everything till it's done I let it
finish it's
rare doesn't go 70 days
and sour double is not done at 62 63
days but that's as far as I take her
because the the the tpping start going
like this like
yeah still great when you take 70 when
it's finished but you don't get any
higher the depth the high doesn't change
anything in two weeks like the last two
weeks or it's a great breeding stream me
yeah remind me what it lineage is guys
who was Sour dub sour dub was a uh sour
bubble from bog cross to and there's
some debate um on whether it was nycd I
don't think it was nycd because it has a
lot of sour diesel type notes in it so
I'm pretty sure it was res doog Sour
Diesel I pretty sure that's why there's
confusion because res rat had them both
yes that's right and I'll tell you I've
gone back and forth and so is gry school
and so is Sean Kon so is everybody who's
been growing her you know on and off
since she came to be yeah
U you know there are times when you
really got her dialed in that
a that a sour grapefruit like red
grapefruit
smell is in there yeah and grown nycd
that's one of the things she was known
for was red grapefruit and I've smelled
it but on the other hand the sour that
you smell is so
traditionally and and I heard there's no
sour diesel in
nycd there's not no so there's not but
in sour double there is a
sour no doubt about it that goes back
to to being from that original Sour
Diesel Jee pool
I agree yeah I mean I've got it to go
super skunky um I don't really hear
people talk about that much with it but
I've got it to go super super skunky to
where it was just like right in that
skunky Zone with sour and that you know
sour dub it was gnarly it was
gnarly yeah sour dub is is a great plant
the official story there there lots of
variations out there the story is bog
gave a handful of seeds at a NorCal
Music Festival of some point to a to a
gangster to to a to to a gang member he
did not know that some big dude at
a at a music fest and bog was feeling it
and he said right it'll be the best pot
you've ever smoked the dude grew it it
became a staple of that crew uh our our
boy grce skull knew one of the guys in
that crew
and he gave it to gry skull and saide
man you got to change the
name uh nobody can know that you have
this plant
yeah like hash plant but cash because
they were just serious money off this
plant uh
so gr school gave it to a couple of us
in you know
Circle uh whoever wasn't full at the
time of of all the strains they could
handle and we started growing it and by
the first harvest everybody was making
room for it everybody made room for sour
double in there we said we got to come
up with the name if we're going to you
know talk about this online because
that's the one stipulation that that
gray has to to stick with is not to call
it cash plan yeah so at one point Bob
was consulted and he said I'd just call
it double salad and uh I was like that's
good enough for me grce skull said
that's good enough for me and then one
of the younger dudes who was always
thinking you know he he was he was
probably 15 years my junior and he he
kind of knew what was coming up with
social media hadn't really started yet
but yeah the younger you know let's put
something more marketable than double
sour and he suggested sour
double instead of double sour because
the S came before the D and he said
it'll always be associated with San
Diego now oh that's smart and we all
took a vote and sour double won so
that's why it's called sour
double yeah that wasn't you know I
remember when I first got the cut I
dropped it immediately without flying
because I was like oh this sounds boring
it would just be like another sour
bubble you know I really regretted that
cuz I could have had it much earlier on
you know and ran through with it yeah
that was uh that's crazy weed I mean I
still grow it yeah I'm oh dude wait till
pop some of those skank dogs we'll get
into that later yeah yeah yeah let's
into it now yeah these the crosses that
you just
released um it was I I got double
specifically uh because I wanted to
reverse it specifically I wanted to
cross SSH and sour double yeah ever
since heard about SS s eh yeah yeah back
forms I just thought that would be a
great merging of of tpping of smells of
taste uh so I got the SSH back I got
this the double back from Gray let's
talk real quick let me cut you off let's
talk about the
SSH the history behind it real
quick y uh it's pretty commonly referred
to as 98 SSH now yeah I think crazy is
calling another one 97 I think SOG cut
maybe oh yeah yeah Old sogs 97 yeah so
when I'm talking about the SSH the
when that cut came to me and Sean from a
guy in Camp okay when when he gave us
the cut among other Cuts he told us it
was the one that won the cup in 98 the
High Times C
so you know that we took that at every
strain this guy gave us was exactly what
it was the guy knew people so I thought
there
was that's what it was uh the first time
I heard different was Noto pointing out
when he every time he saw pictures of it
and and heard it being harvested at day
65 Day 70 at the latest and being done
he's like you know that doesn't sense
sound like the or look like the 1998 Cup
winning cut of ss MH and from everything
that he said and he sent some pictures I
immediately stopped calling it The Cup
winning cup yeah crazy I think more
people know about that cut from crazy
composer than anyone else because he a
bunch of it yeah and uh he immediately
you know after talking to Nato I noticed
also started calling it The 98 and I I
think that's kind of
become the common monitor of that cut so
that history we got it from
Canada we were told it was shanti's
personal cut I will say this about that
cut I hit Shany up on Mr Nice
fors said hey man I just got 98
supposedly I just got the 98 Cup winning
cut from a guy in Canada
and Shanti hit me back immediately and
saidwell did it come with a number and I
said it did not he says if that CET is
given out to anybody the person giving
it to them must give them the number you
know whatever the number was maybe it
was Trey position when Shanti was
growing last you is what it was but it
did not come with the number so
I uh I read the email and I said okay
cool you know we'll see we'll see what
it's like like 15 minutes later I got a
call from the guy in Canada who said hey
man I just got a call from Scott or yeah
yeah Scott yeah I just got Scott that
I'm handing out his cut um so the guy
who gave it to me never retracted that
it was the cup when cut but it it seems
to me that there was a
breaking the communication between
Shanti and this sort yeah yeah maybe
they just had them mixed up tell you
this it's an excellent cut it is a
everything that I used to read about
super silver Hayes in Mark emer's Seed
Catalog or S catalog it fits that
description to it to you and it's fast
and it's effortless it's just it grows
itself just give it the bare minimum of
what it needs and you're going to get a
big gorgeous plant
ssh what do you about scent
profile what's that what's the scent
profile on that one got the lemon you
know it's got the lemon it's got that
cedar Haze yeah to me those would be the
three things I would describe but I've
never been very good at descriptions
I've always relied on the other guys in
SDF for that uh but Cedar hay lemon I
think is a pretty good summation yeah
that sounds right I got tired of it I
don't know if it's because I grew so
much of it there before I left I mean
you walk into a room full of that stuff
and it's drowning out
other yeah it's loud um it was either
that or you know I smoked a lot of it
and most of what me and my business
partner were smoking at the time was Kim
and OG yeah you know you got to be
pretty stout to keep up with Kim and the
ogs and it's and I've never been that
much of a sativa guy but to me it a it
definitely leans
sativa but the true sativa heads will
tell you it's too indicia you know it's
short
flowering pretty pretty thick flowers of
good yields um a nice
ay a nice indusa mix yeah like a good
like a good super silver hay should be
you know know five skunk one Haze yeah
so yeah so the way one of the ways we
judged Bud was by how much we had to
smoke to get through the Raiders game
because the ra for a few seasons were
pretty intolerable and we had to smoke a
lot of SSH to get through some of those
Raider games uh
so we pretty
much for the for the bleer of the years
there that's funny so in summation
that's that's the cut that you used in
Cross to a reversed sour dub right
revers sour dub your juice is the [ __ ]
I'll say
it I got I got I mean I'm still scraping
pollen off the surfaces in
there ironically that cross is not at
all what I want I have found nothing
that I was looking for in that
cross but what I found was if you like
super silver haze which seems everybody
besides me and my buddy you know yeah
Super Silver Haze then what you'll find
is twoth thirds of the the plants will
be super silver haze but a little bit
fatter and a little bit more body in the
stone yeah so it me it was an
improvement but but the ones that I'm
really interested in is the one out of
three that
is
uh I what I describe it as the 90s seat
catalog stock photo of hay hybrid yeah
it longer flowering 80 to 90 days big
leaves don't like small containers at
all just put them in big on
uh but the flowers that came from those
things are pretty insane I smoked
nothing but that feno of SSH for like
four months yeah I
bet find a
special cut especially when you're not
used to really good sativas which I'm
not you know physiology or what but's
different this thing blew my mind I
really enjoyed it and when I pop more of
those
seeds I'll be looking for those
fenos but the SSH fenos that came out of
it are so freaking good the hash that I
made the hash just balls off of it um
and that's why I sent those ones in you
know I
haven't years but after a year year and
a half the reports I've gotten back from
the other Growers it's like okay let's
what I'm just going to sit on these
seeds along with all the other ones in
my freezer so yeah man uh if you like
SSH if you are still in one of those
areas where you cannot get clones that's
how I would grade these seeds is you
want to try SSH for the first time these
seeds are a great way but you're not GNA
find I don't think from all the reports
I've gotten back I don't think you're
going to find any sour in ss8 sour
double so if you're looking for sour
then you look at one of the other
hybrids
all right let's talk about skank
dog that's gonna
be that that's where you're GNA find the
sour all right let's talk about the uh
is it a skunk dog S1 that you used it's
a skunk dog
S1 uh that I kept
for Rounds
um I went into this phase where I was
going to take it back to the '90s
European growing scene where everybody
just grew from seed didn't keep clones
just keep it moving exploring all the
time and so I ended up getting rid of
that S1 and I really wish I hadn't
because that is a plant that I actually
enjoyed growing more than skunk dog and
if if you followed anything I've done
online from the forums Instagram you
know I love Maui scun I think it's one
of the greatest hybrids of all time I
love the the taste it took me years
before I reached that point where I I
got sick of it and stopped smoking it
for a while because it's so specifically
stinky anyway move to the
S1 uh the the word that came to mind
especially when I grew it I grew three
of them
Outdoors um along with a couple orange
juice Bud crosses from from OB oh yeah
obso yeah five or six plants out there
and you could smell them for blocks here
in the desert in the summer it was crazy
I really expected the cops to show up
and new medic you know at the time new
new recreational grower loss um and I
hit that with sour double and everything
that I have
smelled from that has been you know
there are strains that can make your
mouth water yeah um
uh I use the term strain today after all
the Kur fluffle yesterday online about
using strain
I just somebody trying to make his bones
arguing with Chimera
or where was this
Instagram what's that was this on
Instagram where was this on
Instagram yeah and uh I don't even know
what started it because I don't follow
the dude who started it but I I'm pretty
sure it went back to the old strand
versus strain
and we know you know but everything I
just described about the last 30 years
of my growing we didn't have medical
textbooks that we were studying out of
it was 100% broscience so I'll say
strain I'll say pheno you know and all
the kids can kiss my
ass that's what's up so skunk dog yeah
what was in Skunk dog I I can't remember
off the top of my head skunk dog to the
best of my knowledge I probably text
Sean 50 times over the years asking
him and if I finally remember right I
know it's a kimd bag seed and I think
it's crossed to a skunk from the island
of molai so
molai father I believe
crossed with a Kim of some sort bag seat
gotcha the s1's that I grew uh including
the one I kept the Kim is obvious I'll
never question that it look like Kim
growing uh except for it kept if you've
ever grown skunk dog it's got some
really weird branches it uh it really
goes crazy on side branch so the the
plants and I I think I've got some picks
up on Instagram um from when I grew them
Outdoors it looks
like Kim with the exact same branching
from skunk do uh and that's that's when
I first started using the descriptor
skank because it just smelled skank and
then when you hit power double the
examples I've seen and smelled so far uh
I would say that that if if I grew some
of these hybrids some of the skank dog
out you
1990 every I would have sold it as
skunk you know I been called it would
have been referred to as skunk by
everybody who smoked it or smelled it or
was in the room with somebody who had a
bag of it in their pocket it is skunk is
the best descriptor yeah but I couldn't
call dog uh so I called it skank dog
yeah I like it I like that name
anyways really really brought out
Amplified the chem and
added that sweetness to it
uh I'm I'm getting ready to pop some
more soon as these dab me are cleared
I'm popping more of those I cannot wait
to try some of that again I found a a
tray a trim bin with probably a half
ounce you know what I might still
actually have it it's still over there
uh maybe a half half oun of seeded bud
so it was the it was the skunk dog flow
with the seeds from the sour double P
yeah yeah to of my tent for over a year
uncovered dry right now but when I found
it and I just kind of crumpled a few
seeds out of a flower the smell hit me
and I was like holy [ __ ] if I had to
pick just one strain right now to pop
seeds of out of everything in my
collection it would be it would be more
of the skin that's awesome that's sounds
really good and we we talked about on
the show um what we refer to is like the
super skunk double up like if a a camera
sour something with super skunk in it is
then crossed to something else with sour
or Cam in it they tend to align and make
skunky [ __ ] [ __ ] almost every single
time and it's it's it's gnarly it's it's
and it's
predictable another good example of that
was uh canado before he you know started
selling seeds you know he he was work
doing cross and he did a sour double
reversal and he and he hit I think every
clone that Colorado had was sure did he
collected everything and he wanted to
send gray he wanted to send gray
School uh a 10 pack of each one of those
sour double crosses to thank you him for
releasing uh sour double yeah
so so Sean told him at the time hey man
I don't mess with post office but hit up
Rob He he'll probably do it and I said
hell yeah here's my address yeah he
doubled up every pack and sent me in
grce skull a pack of everything he' done
from Durban to OG's to to all that and I
um I popped either one seed or three
seeds of KM hit with sour double uh
reverse
pollen
and there was a keeper whether it was
the one seed pop or the three seed Pop I
can't remember which one but the plan I
ended up with smelled like East Coast
Sour Diesel on steroids yeah makes sense
original cut that I got back in I think
09 it it had that kind of sour diesel
smell not not even a little bit watered
down and I was really surprised by that
smell yeah well makes sense though yeah
I remember when he did
that yeah I grew those seeds for years
I've never explored any Jean Pool uh
like I've explored the sour double Jean
Pool all because canado wanted to hook
gry skull up so that was pretty cool
yeah he's a cool dude he's always been
super cool to me too I like him a lot
the white sour dub is another cut which
Sean still grows in San Diego uh that
was the other one one of them was a one
seat pop one was three seat pop uh and I
got a keeper cut from each one of those
uh one was the white sour dub I love
that is that
wubble what's that is it called
wubble uh the cut that I kept we just
called White sour du
okay Sean could be calling it something
else especially with the whole with the
company maybe um or maybe somebody else
kept the cut too or maybe canado called
it that but uh yeah I don't
know that's like sour
du cream you know yeah I bet dude smooth
smooth tast comes around on did you get
to grow any gg4 sour doubles
no wonder how that one would
be pretty
interesting I mean bat cross if you get
a little more sour to me the one thing
that that
gg4 kind of lack was
was a distinct flavor yeah you know and
maybe that was a little bit Jaded by the
fact
that everybody who had sour double at
that time was still growing sour double
when when you know Dawn started giving
out Cuts yeah
of and it's easier to grow it yields
more than sour dub
uh but when you're comparing the two I
mean I never understood why somebody
would take gg4 over sour du and I had
that same point of view like when gg4
came out I already had sour dub so I
wasn't really interested in growing gg4
the first like decade of it being out
had no interest in it at all it ended up
being a pretty good breeder though on
its own in can you guys help me out here
what's the overlap uh in terms of their
genetics why would you compare them I
guess as
like sour Dub's a part of it gg4 came
right what's
that didn't didn't G didn't grow that
that's what it was right it was Sour
double hit with mystery Allen yeah it
was like they said sour dub chocolate
Thai chem
sis that's right yeah I don't know which
one came and hit which or reversed or
where they even found Kim sis to hit
it it was interesting and this brings it
back to the SDF threads it was
interesting watching the beginning of uh
of gorilla Gorilla Glue number
four because on the
forums you can see the blueprint for the
modern hype hyping of a strength
marketing the blueprint was burner
online with
cookies and I remember the beginning of
Gorilla Glue number
four you know Josie wasn't uh he wasn't
a marketing machine he he wasn't really
carrying that much it
was it was another one or two members
specifically who who kind of talked him
and it said hey man you got something
here in today's legal world you know you
don't just let something like this go
for nothing you can make money off of
this
yeah and I'm pretty sure those posts
would still be up on on one of the SDF
threats probably the second one uh and
it was really interesting watching
people suggestions hey you should do
this you should do that so it was It was
kind of interesting watching the
beginning
of cannabis marketing from from online
cookies and it was just it
way the way it was done prior to
burner doing his thing with cookies you
know the
guys who'd been smoking the longest
would tell the young guys this is what
you want to smoke this is the [ __ ] you
know your friends would tell you hey man
I just found this this is what you want
but that turned around with cookies
cookies the hype came before the flower
for 90% of the people who were hyping
they
did you know you're on your second grow
of all time you're in the beginnner
Forum and you're telling me the cookies
is the best pot in the history of
cannabis you know so I was always
getting a little grouchy back then
online I talked a lot of [ __ ] Don
understood especially with Gorilla Glue
number four still think it's over bright
but if people enjoy it who gives a [ __ ]
right
yeah3 but I seem like I'm the only
person I know who can't stand hash plan
133 things like that so I do miss the
back and forth I do miss people being
able to criticize each other without
130,000 people sliding into your [ __ ]
DMS telling you you don't you know what
I
mean days were good yeah they were I I
tended to get banned from every form
because my [ __ ] mouth but you know it
is what it
is editing all this
a coherent format for for your show yeah
it'll be it'll be
interesting I um I I also wanted to ask
about the
adub and whether that has any relation
or is that just a coincidence with the
name that's adub
is sour double hit with uh
alien alien do
V2 or
V1 something that OB did with alien dog
gotcha yeah it was probably the V1 then
if it was
OBS or no no you know what I think it
was grotech and
uh this other dude who who came on to
stf fairly early I'm having trouble
remembering his name and I'm kind of
embarrassed about that I think it was a
project they did and some of the people
who who got the
seeds uh krd was one of
them and krd found ad dub and he was
just listing them you know there was
like ad dub BD Dub C dub Etc and the
ones that were kept were adubb odub and
something else so it's sour double hit
with alien dog
yeah uh and that's that's a very
specific type plant also it's got a
unique High the way I interpret it
that's like uh smoking yourself into a
bubble you know can't tell you how many
days I was working in the garden and I
would smoke ad dub and and I would find
myself wandering like The Stereotype
from the 80s like what am I doing what
what was I mixing you know and
I I did halfway and hadn't finished yet
and something right beside it on the
workbench that [ __ ] just put you into a
another state of being that's like
smoking
concentrates like I don't buy into all
the 30% this 28% this 3% this but when
people were first starting to get things
tested I think that was the second cut
that I
saw come up with a 30% re
yeah which you know the reason I don't
talking to it is you know those are
adjustable it's all about where the
machine is balanced at now yeah there
are uses for it of course you know
especially in breeding and selecting
phenotypes and stuff like that but
that's another thing I remember about
aou was I think that was the second time
behind Bruce Banner that anybody dared
to say I got 30% THC yeah about getting
laughed at and it's the one that made me
believe hey I don't know if it's 30 but
it's definitely got something something
up in there yeah that was a great
strength how about okay me and you've
talked about it a bunch but I I don't
think most people outside of a few of us
really know about it the Dabney
blue Dy blue was something Sean had more
experience with
um but he brought over some some of the
Dabney uh Afghani kush yeah uh very blue
that's like that's
near I've smelled besides Old Blue from
from Alaska that was a deep blue like it
was uh it was good and that was cross so
I don't know what the original dab me
blue was like which is also from Oregon
yeah yeah it's from a remember I I got a
hold of the guy or he got a hold of me
somehow yeah he was like mini Frisbee
Golf Course name yeah
yeah never got the original back though
oh wait no I take that back it is in the
circle it is I don't know if I don't
know if I'm ever allowed to touch it yet
we'll see well one of the crosses I made
with that was uh East Coast sour DB me
yeah brought
over some
pollen he had a
male male Dabney blue Afghan Kush he
brought over some PA went up to my tent
and hit East Coast Sour Diesel with it
and I made a bunch of those seeds we use
a lot of that pollen on the East Coast s
Diesel and we hit a few other things
with the purple Joy which was a purple
plant that was I remember that kind of
purple plant that I dug I mean that deep
perfumey AF it was it was in nepes um
nepes Afghani hybrid if I remember
correctly well that makes sense too the
the nepes yeah uh but it had that purple
flavor that I like I don't really go for
the GDP so much the
graes but I like those old those old
perfumey stinky small buds but they
don't take much I like those purples so
so he brought over the pollen uh the F1
seeds I sent most of them to the server
fund auction
mag among the other other people who
bought them was uh a guy who went by
Brando
MK okay and heend being head of
something for Prime Wellness in
Pennsylvania which is a I guess a big
ass company and he happened to take the
seeds in there and pop them there they
became Prime Wellness property as far as
far as he was concerned you know as far
as
he say these are my personal stash you
know um but they to this day they still
run two fenos that they call Sweet blue
uh sour blueberry oh nice make shatter
they make all the concentrates out of it
I go through the uh matter of fact on
their website they have it listed as sub
Rob Sour
Diesel um which it wasn't sub Rob Sour
Diesel it was
diesel clone yeah but I think that had
marked on his packaging was
subro you know and then diesel cross
with dab blue so that's what I've got
going a Guy in Wales bought him in like
2010 he lives in Wales so he he told me
uh he told me he says I've got tens of
thousands of dollars of seeds in my deep
freeze that I never got to Growing he
goes some of them are yours why don't I
just send back your way and he did
that's
awesome got six going in the in the bed
tent right now in perpetuity I cracked
them like eight months ago and I've just
been recycling moms because I haven't I
haven't flowered any Myer yeah that's
been going on for a while
bro I gota do I gotta do it I got OG and
sour double coming so I need to it's
real interesting when you're running
literally just personal growth
yeah I went from having enough up room
and we weren't even big I've never at no
stage in my career would I be considered
a BigTime commercial grower by today's
standards sure and no same I've done
compares to the 100 lighters 200
lighters thousand lighters you know um
but I used to have room for stashing
anything I wanted cracking seeds and
an extra tray over there in the corner
it's different when you
are when you're just running a
little 5 by 10 by 810 you know
yeah I was going to ask you because
obviously we have we have lots of
different clones than names that we
could ask you about but I did want to
know because you were you know just
referring to your current situation like
what are you working on now and like
what what do you think the future holds
for you in terms of um the
PS um right now I'm not working on
anything man I I I've been smoking the
SSH dub for going on a total the last
Harvest of it for like six months now I
just started going over to another when
I moved down here to New Mexico there's
another oldtime icy mager that I've
known forever online who lives here and
I go buy and get samples from them and
uh it's just really slowed down the
flowering schedule plus I kind of I I
grew a little more than I needed to and
I don't I don't I don't sell weat
anymore you know yeah uh I've
been the real work I've been putting in
is judging that SSH dub lately um but I
do have plans for every three sets of
plans I make I usually carry out one and
the next thing I'm going to do is see if
this East Coast sour dab me is worth
doing a seed increase and see I got this
goes back sorry here I am derailing
conversation again when I was when I was
living in b
s around
2015 maybe my house got burgled and I
had in the freezer I had a b with every
Cross I'd ever
made um not to mention all my friends
had ever made anything I'd ever bought
traded for and in them I had a a whole
bunch of those of both F1 and F2 East
Coast sour dabing that I had always
planned uh because of the success that
Prime Wellness had with 10 of those
seats I always had plans to work that
line and maybe do some real actual
breeding work with it uh but the thief
along with a bunch of other [ __ ] got all
the seeds
so I need to find out just how
stiff these East Coast Sour Diesel
genetics come through in these seeds and
just how hardcore the the dab me Kush
does um and see if it's worth trying
to to increase and do something with
those th suck bro very
C
these always [ __ ] [ __ ]
up yeah yeah like yeah I also want I
want to do another sour dub reversal
because I missed some plants I I didn't
I didn't get the the chimd cut in time
when I made those seeds and going back
to that that plant I got from canado
hitting kimd with sourd these are
crosses these sour dub crosses are
something that I begged my friends who
make and sell seeds to do I didn't want
to do any of this stuff man I wanted to
move
on but the the Cannabis world that the
demand in the industry seems to have
moved on from some genetics
prematurely yeah I'm not I'm saying hey
you know go get the sherbets and the
biscottis and the biscuits and and the
whatever hell else pastries are out
there but don't you know down a little
bit you know
because there's a lot of
the there's a lot of the cuts that
came in the era of the forums that we
should still be concentrating on I
mean you know I
don't I don't I don't want to take the
journey away from from everybody but at
least a small percentage of people need
to go back and start working with the
sour and the m and the ogs because those
are Gene
pools and oddly enough I've talked about
it like I had people hitting me up all
the time asking for OG Cuts because
nobody kept them like not nobody but and
a lot of people enough people dropped
them that a lot of these big you know
places that these people used to run
like they don't even have ogs anymore
not pure ogs you know and that gets us
circled back to SDF which is the the the
thread I'm supposed to be staying on
sorry we all had at one point not only
did all the p91 bull rider you know all
we all had not just one but we all had
all those cuts yeah you had in your
bedroom you had p91 in your bedroom you
had madness in your bedroom you had
catpiss you had Hogs breath and they all
disappeared and you know lame eight I
really do because I wasn't one who had
never had
access to that many Cuts you know at one
time yeah and the only one who went
crazy and would just get cuts from eight
and bedge them and flower them in a tent
with 14 other kinds with single plant
each you know of 15 different guts uh
and you would just you know move on from
them and you wouldn't keep moms because
you got another 20 from eight when you
came to and and basically we all thought
that p91 would stick around we all
thought bull around and they just up and
disappeared in the matter of like a year
and a half yeah they
did damn shame we didn't know what we it
was like being cut drunk you know we all
just ate that [ __ ] up and forgot
B cyle repeats itself how it goes dude
we always thought everything was to be
around
forever yeah because maybe this is
almost more forat but when I look at you
know I went through some of the threads
and piled a whole list of of clones that
stood out to me when I look at some of
the names you know Chernobyl strawberry
cream day recer it also strikes me that
of course this is some of these are some
of the cuts that Matt worked with
earlier as
well um so yeah it's super cool to make
that connection I didn't I didn't
actually realize I don't
think I like that strawberry cream yeah
yeah you you would have run the same
exact clone that I did because mine came
via
eight yeah it was good cut yeah it was
great man if for a strawberry it was
[ __ ] Mega
strawberry I had another one I don't
know what it was a lot of times I would
get Cuts I'm sure everybody did from me
where something went wrong and the
information wasn't passed right but I
remember calling one
which stood for body odor Berry that was
a dank ass Berry cut I'm curious what
what other Cuts did you come up with
from those
threats what else you come up with let's
see so we've already mentioned p91 hugs
breath bull rider so I saw GDP grap a
cat piss Purple Kush green ice Albert
Walker Chernobyl uh strawberry cream we
mentioned OB Betsy Master Kush D Green
Crack Green Crack was a big one down
there so green ice was something that
was around for a very short period of
time that was C green uh he had gotten
some seeds from the original gg4 which
was gorilla gold 4 Yeah by Bri up in
Canada which was an awesome strain
indoor or
it was kind of on the Bland side for
indoor weed in so in Southern California
at the time
but Cali found a male and he hit Green
Crack along with a couple other cats and
so that's where green ice was born and
that is a strain that still to this day
I still whenever I talk to him I'm like
hey man dude remember green ice yeah
he's probably dude I know I fcked up I
shouldn't have lost
it but uh but yeah that was I remember
the flavor of that I haven't hit that
since probably 2007 or eight that was in
the
beginning uh and and I still remember I
remember that that plant that was
awesome I'll bet you not many people
remember it but uh I enjoyed that very
much do you remember ak-48 God's gift
they flown around
yeah I don't think I grew it but I say
that all the time and then I go through
the the forums yeah yeah did I did grow
that but I remember growing AK-47 I
remember growing Cherry I remember AK-47
When's the earliest that came
out [ __ ] I don't know probably mid 90s
yeah because when I was in Portland
growing uh blueberry there was one guy
that one one of the very few guys we let
in on our secret he was a grower also
and he was growing these these newer
seeds uh
AK-47 and white widow and he had he
selected cuts from both of those and
that was pretty awesome weed I'd never
really had
AK-47 that lived up to that AK-47 that
what's his name was grown in Portland
back in the day
yeah good sh trying to think like i'
I've had a few good AK-47s um there was
like a lemon AK there was the uh like
Cedar AK but then there's also the
Cherry AK that went around San Diego and
it was beautiful Frosty no density to it
it was Fluffy and not very potent but it
was it was really good tasting that was
about it for it it's still floating
around oh yeah yeah I'd used it in the
Cherry Berry that I not too long ago
yeah I enjoyed it yeah me too I I was
stoked to see it again even though it's
not super potent um it is a great
breeder especially for those CHS cherry
cough
drop yeah now I've already I remember a
couple of the Clones you listed thousand
uh popped off in my mind immediately but
I've already forgotten what they were
so um I think ones we haven't talked
about yet like maybe choby or dayer
Walker any of those was a seed line from
TGA so there's a lot of different cuts
of that yeah yeah that's the Deo Walker
remember that walker uh Shan I think
Shawn was the one who got that one and
it was
Albert uh
and
Fletch I think all Fletch even needed to
see was the veg picks of that plan and
he was like hey bro that ain't that's
not Albert Walker and it turned out it
wasn't of course he was he was right on
with that one yeah so we called Walker
just because we were too lazy to come we
didn't know if we were going to end up
keeping it tell you what man that plant
is a citrus
explosion yeah it was a nice plant dude
he tried taking the Citrus down or not
uh the first reversal I ever tried was
Tahoe OG Kush oh wow hard one I had room
and I was spraying it every day and it
just wasn't going well and so I said
Sean happened to come over one day and
he got in there and he found a pin prick
of pollen somewhere on that plant and he
ran upstairs and he
hit and he hit uh dega Walker yeah with
it think he got three seeds grew all
three of them out and one of them is
still around uh it's called
Cactus cool okay yeah yeah cooler cut
comes from and and we always swore we
were going to reverse Tahoe or or one of
the
ogs uh and hit it again and try to bat
that Citrus down a little bit
more full of that in a room it's it's
overwhelming it's too much like I Citrus
for it's crazy how much citrus
that yeah I was bummed when I found out
that wasn't real Albert Walker because
that was one of the ones that I [ __ ]
with too and I was like oh yeah we got
the real Albert Walker we got that down
here it turned out I've never smoked
grown knowingly smoked Albert Walker and
that's a like you said that's one I was
wanted to try yeah same I i' I've never
seen a real one or smoked it or wouldn't
even know what it smells like nothing
about it
really if that one isn't it you know
that's my only experience with
it what uh what was your favorite San
Diego cut I was so partial to to Hog's
Breath I as question I probably didn't
need to for sentimental if nothing else
you know and the Clockwork one that came
from uh Doug this dude crazy Doug down
there Doug knew everyone he was the one
who hooked me up with James in the first
place um and the whole Hogs breath crew
but he had you know like there's an
Apollo 13 cut he had down there that was
really good uh he gave me Fire OG really
early on he gave me KMD really early on
so like yeah he was that dude was
connected to
everyone sorry guys just wanted to ask
here and Matt maybe this is obvious but
I I'm just like it's not clear to me
what's the overlap between the Hogs
breath crew and San Diego's finest um in
terms of people with they lots of
crossovers
or not really it was just family like
the the Hogs family was there they ran
unified collective in San Diego and you
know people that you could go in there
and talk to him anytime the dude who who
like local groups basically local local
different groups and Hog's Breath was
just that well known in San Diego that
everybody knew it it was it was the
staple um do we want to talk about the
bull rider or we is everyone sick of
like bring it up once in a while I don't
know anything about bull rider myself
because I only ever had a fake bull
rider
uh bull rider probably overall is was
probably my favorite of the San Diego CS
yeah I love I love the smell the smell
and The Taste was just you know I barely
even remembered if I'm being honest but
I
remember you know when I first got
here I just come off smoking blueberry
for four years yeah
Straight had become a big thing for me
uh and I thought I was a snob you know
thought I knew what I was
doing uh and bull rider was the one that
took the place of the blue rider for me
because it gave me all the flavor that I
could want from from a
dank sour but not Sour Diesel
perspective it was it was really dark
dank weed to me and did old Betsy did
old Betsy cross your path down there
yeah but you know I used to get old
Betsy from the same guy who I got
everything else from but here's where
everything differs for me when I think
back to the old Betsy that he was
getting me I think of really dark purple
almost black Leaf weed oh
interesting I wasn't that big a fan of
and it wasn't just once or twice it was
a few times before he even quit bringing
it when he would bring me his little
Briefcase full of samples and [ __ ]
um because I I literally thought it was
just a man cut but I I had to wonder
since then was I getting the real but
why would he get you know all the other
legit [ __ ] and not Betsy yeah thing
turned out to when I had to start going
other places when I got pee when I got
you know Hogs when I got any of that it
was the same thing that he used to get
me uh but then I see old Betsy plants
growing that are green all the way
through and
yeah being described is not what so I
don't know maybe like he he got mad he
had more than one connect you know he
there was only one connect that he got
Madness from so maybe he had that he
went to get old Betsy
from to what genuine old Betsy was I
don't think I had the real deal um how
about blueberry Hog's Breath remember
when that came around at
all I remember the you know the the name
yeah
yeah but I don't know that I ever got
any of that once I once I see I got here
in 99 and I wasn't grown right away but
I was growing Again by 2001 2002 by
then I was no longer you know buying a
I was growing enough to keep myself
going here around yeah that makes sense
yeah that was I just remember when that
finally got released and he let it out
like you could throw a rock and hit it
like it was in every [ __ ] grow room
of every [ __ ] kid in San Diego for a
while yeah kept my grow secret from well
as best good for the first years I was
growing in San Diego I used to uh I used
to use I used to run apartments and they
had to have a walk-in closet and then I
would just basically take about 80% of
the closet then build out of Styrofoam a
wall that I can just door
into um got pretty good at that too we
ended
up it was kind of cool to build rooms
out of Styrofoam small rooms oh yeah but
we got to the point where we built it
had 12T ceilings in this
building and we built
a 16 by 12 by 12 growroom two of the
four walls were just built out of
completely out of Styrofoam duct tape
and spray epoxy yeah about four in
thick that's way to do
it you leave the ventilation system on
overnight and suck in the walls or blow
the walls out then you just call in a
coked out Russian to frame it in for you
and I appreciate the uh the tip on that
book that you told me to get too the The
Afghani one what was it called didn't it
yeah what was it called do you
remember I'd have to go into my I'll
have to look it's a really killer book
though it's really well
done Afghanistan the kingdom of cannabis
yeah something like that
yeah yeah yeah it's very similar to
chiac yeah
yeah the story as it you know as it
happened I'll tell you what yeah you
need to do people need to do more
episodes on hash on
hashish uh because it's
the there's no blueprint you know and
for a couple years I was going through
your book stash and explaining what was
looking for I wanted the basic blueprint
I wanted okay this is where you start
when you make cash and this is what you
can expect and this is what you should
do and you can do that with growing
flowers you can do that with living soil
you can get that information on any
aspect of growing but for but for making
dry sift hash it's just not out there
and I couldn't understand uh why it
wasn't out there why isn't there a look
this is how you make dry sift Dash and
now now I understand because it's it's
different every single time man it's
it's such fluid art that is done so many
different ways with the same basic
tools uh yeah I think people need to
start talking about hashish more
concentrates in general but specifically
dry
SI I
think yeah you've done some beautiful
dry SI stuff that I've seen I appreciate
that a
lot I
really don't like smoking just flow
anymore you know as obsessed as I've
been with growing for my entire adult
life back into my
teens uh it is now second seat it's just
a step to getting to making hash you
know what I mean yeah yeah it's like it
was the penultimate it was the
destination for the first 40 Years of my
experience with
cannabis uh and now it's just third to
the last
step yeah yeah well you do a damn good
job job at
it I'm really happy I I'm the [ __ ] you
I'm the hashtag you know [ __ ] your legal
weed guy yeah honestly I'm I'm happy for
everybody who's who's getting going on
I'm happy that not nearly as many people
are going to jail for it uh I think it's
[ __ ] great and if I were 25 years
younger I'd be you know I'd be all over
it but sure it's so nice to be this age
where see for example you don't always
want to see behind the curtain right
yeah you know grew up a fanatic of
Harley-Davidson motorcycles loved Harley
love the lifestyle love the
fictionalized lifestyle love true
lifestyle Lov writing all that stuff I
went to work for
Harley-Davidson and I still love it but
now I know it's it's a job it's a lots
for a lot of people to put that image
that I fell in love with that's
so that takes a lot of work to keep once
you see that it just takes makes a
little edge of the magic off you know
what I mean just a little bit it
actually opens up a whole new world you
know uh
just but with legal weed I'm actually
kind of glad that I'm kind of you know
Miss that being the focus of my
professional drive because now I get to
keep magic and I get to you know tell
people to go [ __ ] themselves and you
know know call people
sellouts happy for everybody
else just I'm not gonna take part in
anything where tax money goes to law
enforcement you know what I me I you
there that's probably a whole another
episode in and enough yeah me and you
can rant about that [ __ ] for
hours I'm happy with what's going on see
at this point I'm just talking I'm not
even thinking of the podcast I'm
yeah um now we love
that yeah here in New Mexico I don't
even know the laws I
literally made myself be ignorant of
laws I don't know if any of the tax goes
to law enforcement out here and I don't
want to [ __ ] know yeah because that
[ __ ] just ruins it for me talk about
losing the magic bro yeah yeah no I I
look they got some really cool [ __ ] in
in the legal scene out here and I'll
tell you what since it went recreational
a couple years ago the quality has
skyrocketed which doesn't take much all
you need is a Cali pipeline for cuts you
know yeah
right Skyrock but I haven't partaking at
all I've never been in a dispensary out
here in three and a half years I've
never
shopped
uh I did look into they have macro
licenses here they maxes out I think at
a few hundred plants yeah somebody who
is at least zoned right can can make an
honest Mom and Pop Shop
attempt uh here in New Mexico especially
in Southern New Mexico where everything
the focus is always on Mom and Pop you
know
small down here from food to art to you
know it's a great place they could velop
a really they could develop a really
cool cannabis scene here in Los crus
they' have to CH one thing another
another thing that just I'm Zero
Tolerance
on for personal grow I can have 12
plants here right
yeah if I have six in flour I'm limited
to six in veg
yeah you want to you want to set the
number of what I can flow at six and
charge me at tax essentially for
anything above that because you'd have
to get a macro micro license yeah I'm
fine but don't [ __ ] tell me how many
goddamn plants I can have in V you know
what I mean what's that doing the fact
that somebody has 10 plants instead of
six while they got six in flower is not
going to influence anybody who isn't
going to break your law anyway to break
that law they'll just
exactly you're not
creating criminals by letting them have
30 or 40 veg plants while they search
through a match seeds you know what I
mean yeah like this is so small town uh
do it yourself mom and pop restaurants
mom and pop everything that if they
would let people you know do those CES
find those fenos
develop the the habits you need the
experience you need to find special cuts
out of
seeds you know you let the people do
that you're going to organically grow a
nice cannabis seat oh yeah
rather than the cats who moved from Cal
I'm not talking [ __ ] but there's people
who moved from California out here to
New Mexico
absolutely you know even if New Mexico
did very well to make sure it was New
Mexico residents getting the licenses a
lot of those licenses got somebody in
the grow room
you know from Cali running the whole
[ __ ] show yep um again no not
disrespecting anybody it's a good
business move on everybody's
part uh but now you're letting those
people dictate what the local scene
grows Las Cruz kind of an island on land
you know you got El Paso over a very
unfriendly State
Line yeah
and then you got a whole lot of desert
for a whole lot of miles a whole lot of
Indian
reservation and then you got Northern
Mexico a long way away so I really wish
they would do away with the plant count
laws as far as vegetative yeah that
doesn't really make a lot of sense
especially considering like you're not
producing any drug content with the veg
plants who gives a [ __ ] about the veg
plants grow more than six without a
license are going to grow more than six
without a license absolutely yeah right
it's common
sense so if that was changed I'd be a
happy cat I was going to get a micro
license one of the things you have to do
is present them with business plan and I
you they don't give you the information
over the phone but I annoyed one of the
clerks who works there so much she says
okay pitch me your business plan and
I'll tell you what I think I said well
my business business plan she goes how
much money are you going to make in the
first year I'm like
nut she's like what do you mean I said I
just want to pop seeds man and be able
to have sort through them that's all I
want to do I don't want to sell cuts of
it I don't want to do any of that [ __ ]
and if I did I'd do it and I wouldn't
[ __ ] tell you anyway yeah
right
right but she's like you know that's
just not you know your business plan
will have to approved so you will have
to come up with something and that's
when I said okay thanks and I was like
[ __ ] it I'm not looking any further
business plan bro we're Stoners get the
[ __ ] out of here with business plan well
you know it's it's not a bad idea you
got to force people to to consider these
things there there's also we live in a
water rights state so there's you know I
don't have any water rights although I
do have a well on on my l
that's no longer in use but it qualifies
me to buy water
rights but I'm like look I'm not going
to need any water rights because I'm not
going to be growing enough where I'm
just not going to go fill my seven
gallon jugs of with RO water yeah down
at M in the grocery store parking lot it
tests less than 100 per million so yeah
she's like your business plan just
doesn't make any sense I'm like I'm
sorry I just want to pop seed man [ __ ]
yeah business plan I love that yeah you
need a business plan I want to make no
money how about
that go over well so I don't know but I
do appreciate some of the things they're
they're doing here in New Mexico and it
being a a low populated state it allows
them
to kind of uh push towards Grassroots a
little bit I think it's a good
thing but I'm sure they still fund the
pig somehow so [ __ ] uh you know they do
they always do always find a way to do
it gotta get your cut or it ain't
happening yeah who's going to protect
you bro who's G to keep you safe they
don't get their
cut yeah
right
stupid but other than that you know it'
be this be a great place especially for
Afghan for for Asian oh yeah and races
man 120
degrees but it's got plenty of humidity
in late
summer you know it's you look at
pictures in those books like that book
you just got and yeah it looks lot like
my backyard yeah it looks a lot like
Bakersfield too bro like it's very
similar
yeah High temps love it yeah also burns
up all the turps though I'd
imagine no no it uh what did I grow I
grew three skank dog or I grew
three skunk dog
s1s okay and
three uh OG of some sort hit with orange
juice Bud from OB Soul
OBS
um like I said they stun they Stu the
everybody knew somebody was growing B oh
I bet everybody within a mile
radius and I'm kind of downtown I'm Zone
commercial residential here
yeah and I've got enough room and I got
a big ass empty c one room Cita out back
so I had I had the potential to do a
cannabis business if I wanted to but
like I said you know having kind of
missed that
window uh it allows me to just enjoy
being a small small
time yeah well do you have any shout
outs you want to
do no
no Oh you mean like for like like yeah
yeah yeah any shout outs you want to do
for the closing out just say hey give a
shout out to my boy
XYZ you know everybody knows who
everybody knows gone with yeah yeah
that's right that's that's right man
want to make them feel special if
they're friends of
mine a shout
out yeah that's what's up and uh like we
said you can find your seeds at seed
trip uh seed trip seeds at riot
seeds.com in the feminize section and uh
they'll be available until they're sold
out so be sure to grab them and with
that we want to say thank you thank you
for joining the show Rob and we'll have
you back soon have
fun thanks Rob like we said your seeds
are available at uh at Riot seeds.com is
there anywhere else no no that's it
there's not enough I mean I'm keeping
what I got yeah uh people need to jump
on those I suppose we
probably I was really high when we
discuss that I hope I got
across you know I think did a good job
did we yeah yeah we did a good job on
that yeah grab
those want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out syndicate gear.com
we also have an underground Syndicate
Discord where we get together and solve
old strain history together daily it's
an amazing community of learning away
from IG and it's an amazing resource for
old cataloges and knowledge we hope you
join our Union of readers and Growers
come check it
out