welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to Breer Syndicate
everyone I'm Matthew here with my
co-host thousandfold and today we're
going to be having local botanist and
farmer Dan who is currently muted
because his kid is bashing toys around
um today we're going to be doing a recap
of season 11 and doing some uh q&amp;as for
people in the audience and ones we've
taken before the show thousand take it
away yeah uh recapping season 10
launching season yeah there you
go we've got a few questions from the
Discord but also of course we're
welcoming everyone to just you know uh
put questions in the chat um maybe to
kick us off what has everyone been
smoking for those of us who have been
smoking have you all been growing for
those of us who have been
growing go ahead guys obviously my my
sick ass wasn't
smoking Matt is straight edge right now
yeah
currently yeah right now not right now
um but talk in your
mic am I am I talking in my mic now
little hear me barely good hold on no
we're good we're good all right um yeah
no I've been smoking the sweet pee a lot
um and then yeah that stuff really good
super tasty super consistent um yeah I
love smoking
it Mr
Dan you're
muted uh I just took some rips of the
wet dream the Green Crack times blue
dream and that [ __ ] was fire so shout
out to screw for send sending that
out about you than that oh yeah um I've
been sampling my freshly Harvest Santa
Cruz RS so I've got four of them um and
two of them I mean again just visually
purely visually look a lot more Blue
Dream than the other two but you know I
think profile wise there's definitely a
quite quite the mix across them so still
getting used to them but uh one of
them's got a killer he Buzz which I love
for the daytime so I'll probably be no I
I don't know that I've ever talked about
why I'm not smoking on our show um but I
got sick with something that people have
been arguing about ever since I brought
it up cannaboid hyperemesis I think it's
s supposed to be pronounced like hyperic
right local maybe Science Guy uh I'm not
a medicine guy man I don't know
hyperic Hy emesis syndrome which makes
you uh essentially you you flood your
canabo system so much that it makes you
uh throw up non-stop until you either
die or quit smoking and it it shows up
quite a bit so I had to stop smoking and
it's supposed to be for supposedly 11
months if you're a lifetime smoker uh to
completely flush it out so you can smoke
again so that's why my Hiatus exists but
it's been fun um shucking stuff and not
being able to smoke it it's been quite a
treat uh the SHP cream pie seem very
nice I mean it like uh it's very greasy
resin and it makes a lot of greasy resin
people like opposed to the Sandy so
that's about all I got to say on the
smoke front kind of sucks
um Matt did you want to kick us off with
Al some of the Tas us some of the drops
that are happening okay so we have uh my
drop we have uh uh packs drop uh Santa
Cruz go form and we have high and
loansome drop so my drop's going to be I
call it Viva la bluevolution which is
just it's the blueberry in crosswork or
as it's written um which is a totally
madeup term for cannabis but it it fits
because you need a term for something
like Crossing in between Generations as
as opposed to going straight
generational
work so you know like there's there's a
backat cross in there at some point and
and reading back to DJ shorts blue so we
have the blueberry incross which was my
most popular from the original Blue
Bonnet release and that was DJ shorts
blue b or blueberry uh F4 from an old
pack that I selected cross to the blue
bonnet of course and what it did was
take all the looks from DJ shorts
blueberry which is probably some of its
most
awesome part of its traits is the looks
because it's beautiful purple cushy
looking stuff and cross that to the Blue
pond it so it injected heavy blueberry
TPS into it so it was kind of what I
always imagined the pictures of of like
when I was buying seeds at DJ Short
Stuff it's how I imagine those things
growing out smelling like blueberry
looking like that and that's that's what
I reimagined with this and it worked out
really well um so we we redid that and
then we crossed that to Mac Daddy which
I have no idea what mac daddy is but it
looks like a better version of Mac one
um well it smells like a bubble gummy
Mac one to be honest I don't know what's
in it um that that's like clone only
type I don't know um we have blue cocky
which is a new
name Dan came up with for the sherb
cream pie cross to uh the blueberry and
cross and I'm pretty stoked on that one
it's fat chunky sherb um a little louder
than normal
sherb um but yeah like I mean there's a
cut out there called Blue sherb that
everybody was all stoked on when it came
out I was too I was like wow this this
sounds pretty good and then tried it and
it wasn't really blue at all so kind of
wanted to reimagine that one uh blamy
which is the white runs blueberry and
cross which again smells like it's it's
a lot smaller yielding version of the
Sher cream pie and then the the trop doy
blueberry and cross which really is like
a a Tangi dominant uh cookies blueberry
and cross so basically it's um kind of
leaning into the hype crowd a little bit
to try to get some injection of Interest
into what we do in the first place and
as it were like thousand said maybe a
trojan horse style attack
on bring him into the the old by working
in the new I guess you could say I just
so I have to point out like how good
blue cocky is for SHP pie blue hybrid
it's like Dan you literally just came up
with that like five minutes ago yeah you
did
yeah that's how my [ __ ] up brain
works blue cocky so good a cream pie and
all so then we got um we have what is it
goat farms uh Blue Dream work so he
dropped let me see we got here I think
he only wrote the names on these I still
going to spread them out um no that's
not it either where is the goat farm
drop this one's a banger that dream kill
dream killer is going to be what the p91
I believe uh that's the sack one oh sack
one yeah the sack one cross that's right
so Sol assassin number one OG which is a
cut I held for years it's a really
really dank old OG cut it's probably a
hybrid it grows way better than OG you
never needed to stake it um super OG and
turps almost like Irene but it's just a
way better growing plant than any OG um
we have the the Santa Cruz dog [ __ ]
which is the dog [ __ ] cross to Electric
Baloo whatever you want to call it cross
to um blue dream and these are all FS
for him the blueberry incrosses are all
reg seeds let's see all yanking out like
a weasel here hold
on we've got Waking
Life you remember what that one is local
uh that's the TCP K blue dream so the
pure kush yeah pure kush blue dream and
then we have wet dreams which is the
Green Crack blue dream so those are
going to be dropped this weekend I've
been shuing so much I haven't really
gotten around to it I've been trying to
make the deadline for uh releasing the
blueberry incross those would already be
out except for the fact that I'm waiting
for my printer for and then we have the
the mango Haze drop from high and
Lonesome I don't have those in yet but
there's going to be I believe Green
Crack mango Haze dog [ __ ] mango Haze um
El in there you guys know camd mango
Haze mango Haze is there an mango Haze I
don't know if you did appy mango Haze I
would hope so
I I don't remember the list I need to
get it for I don't remember seeing that
one there's
a I think I want to say
eie
mango um yeah bunch of other ones that's
all regular stuff too so we've got a few
a few different regular seed drops and
one fem seed drop and uh for my next
drop it's going to be probably I think
we're going to do the blue and cross f
we're going to see we're going to see
where it takes us um that's the hopes
anyways but you can never bet the farm
on that stuff yeah
pretty there's another round of blue
drop right I mean another round of
there's another blue drop after this
right to come that we we may not leak
yet oh which which one's that I don't
know that blue oh yeah A5 A5 mango Haze
that was the other one oh yeah yeah
hopefully that one will work and come
out thank you G and then um we also have
the TGA crosses coming soon which is
like the the epitome of something that I
said I'd never do and never say
never yeah so that's going to be fun
that's going to be all the newer um bet
I think better moms that should have
been crossed to space dude personally
yeah that's gonna be coming very soon
too these are insane drops by the way
like all of them yeah they're pretty
good
stoked I don't have enough space or
money for this [ __ ] yeah me either I
know all right what's next on the agenda
well we can start off with some of the
questions so the first one um which
we've had before I think but let's go
over it again so Diggy effects asks I'd
love to hear more about mother plant
maintenance especially in Solo cups
maybe we can expand that to say mother
plants in smaller containers all right I
I could I could start with this one uh
mother plants in smaller containers the
main thing you're going to run into is
like mold
PM bugs because you have a lot more Leaf
in a smaller area because if you're
using the stuff in a smaller area you're
topping you're training you're cramming
as much as you can into a tiny scale um
so yeah IPM has to be on track uh air
movement has to be on track um a lot of
times people like to use and I know this
is like absurd nowadays but t5s lower
light if you're in a smaller environment
to to induce like slower growing as
opposed to like decreasing health for
slower growing decreased light for
slower growing if that makes sense um
that was one of our big tricks back in
the day keeping you know 100 moms in a
small space was using e5s and uh light
like light raising lights and lowering
lights as they go up and down and yeah
that was the main thing um I don't know
what else you guys
got
um I would say probably the biggest
thing is the thing that Matt mentioned
in my at least in my situation cuz that
helps like mitigate how much growth
you're going to get and like once you
start getting that many moms it just
becomes a lot to manage um but also like
me in my case I also uh do um cocoa only
uh so I have to water and feed like
every single watering and like if I do
my plants are going to fall over because
like the weight of the plant is just
like too too much for the kind of the
width of the pot
um let's see I also do uh racks racks
help me a lot um that's I mean you could
double your area with that easily um
let's see what else
um I mean yeah just keep your plant your
moms like well fed well like well
watered
um I had a question about this as well
uh is there any sense
in with mothers like do you keep the
lights as intense as you would for
plants that you're growing out to crop
no um yeah I I give them less light just
in general like less intense
light what about
feeding I feed him every time they need
a lot they need heavy food in pots yeah
I mean they're getting the same feed as
my like plants and flower um so yeah I
don't I don't really reduce diet or
change diet for them too much you got to
keep it
consistent yeah Kyle's right constantly
taking Cuts constantly taking Cuts
that's another good way to keep it lows
I mean it's essentially the same thing
as topping in many sense or many sense
the same way same achieves the same
thing as topping but it's a huge
important part of the process especially
if you're keeping a lot of moms and
you're doing like a strain library to
keep stuff alive you have to take lots
of cuts because [ __ ] dies as you keep
them smaller it's just part of the
number scale yeah and that turnover just
helps keep them small too it's like if
you're cutting it every you know four to
six weeks and restarting it then you
know you're going to constantly pretty
much have like a SE six or seven inch
clone up to like you know a foot or two
tall and then it immediately goes back
to a clone and so it's a ton of work but
that's that's how I do it or try to do
it I'm behind right now I've got some
clone trays that are like 2 feet
tall you know that that was another
trick I used to use and I don't I mean I
don't know if I recommend this or not or
don't recommend it it's something I did
um you know the 10 x 20 plastic Mii
trays or whatever like the thick ones I
put load those up with peite and I would
keep essentially like a hempy bucket for
a lack of a better term just peite and
water and keep the Clones in that or not
water but a feed and constantly water it
that way the problem with it is if it's
all different strains they overgrow each
other real fast some get like two feet
tall some stay four inches but I was
able to keep things in that for like two
months sometimes if I needed oh yeah it
would look like [ __ ] but it would it
would work it would function if you know
I mean oh I've got a tray of 50 yeah
that's like two months in the tray two
feet tall and I'm [ __ ] watering it
twice a day and I'm just like I I don't
have time to [ __ ] pot these up yet
but they're going in next I've saved
whole libraries that way just like
backing them up that way and that's like
a emergency scenario or if you're
feeling extra lazy or have very little
room it'll work um yeah it's just
essentially what it would be is uh Mii
tray peite and then one of those
skeleton trays you know you set clones
in that are open and just set the Clones
in there rock wool more perite water
that [ __ ] in and they'll go bananas in
it you know so yeah I mean I've seen sh
take off the flower in it you know well
and you can get groan of any size too so
you could like really easily just get
like the 3in cube oh yeah you know what
I mean and like they're kind of tall too
and so you could fit like 18 of those in
one of those 10 x 20s and just like keep
a little mini mom like that too you
know
underneath you're [ __ ] like the 50
even when I plugged it was just like oh
I'm gonna have to pop this down like
twice a day yeah guar it's gonna rot it
was nuts trying to do the 72 count I
mean but the tray was off at that point
but yeah I mean it was it was hell like
trying to keep used to do mini Cuts in
the you remember when uh Oasis cubes had
the the wedges and they were like the
102 count and the little plastic insert
yeah um yeah we used to cram little like
three-inch Cuts in those and like they
took an extra week to like really get
established but you know if they're all
just like stuff you would have thrown
away and you could sell clones back then
that was [ __ ] great yeah
dude I got I'm still working out a
system for my like tiny tiny shamefully
tiny space and I had like a got like a
one foot by one foot by like twoot
cabinet in which I there's like a shelf
in there and I stuffed like 25 plants in
there I can fit 72 in that
[Laughter]
spotu crazy dude yeah I mean just to
like keep my [ __ ] though like I cut two
full trays just for like the Dozen
things I'm holding on to CU I like to
take five or six of of each you know and
suddenly you have like you're just
throwing them all away you know what I
mean yeah you do throw a lot away that
way yeah it sucks but yeah it hurts
every time you're like oh this could be
you know like anything from an ounce to
a pound of weed and I'm just throwing it
away my buddy my buddy Chris assaro down
there he was um he does really nice
Living Water um it's it's I guess it
would be living water it's it's he has
worms uh he feeds water through that
through the worm castings that go
through that and I think fish [ __ ] in it
somehow right like like aquaponic thing
but like aqu ver vermiponics
he's growing some beautiful Punchy
plants that way absolutely sounds cool
yeah yeah it works really [ __ ] well
never heard living water though yeah lo
you gonna try uh you gonna try growing
plants out of your tanks
dude yeah yeah let the NES feed or the
yeah what are those little [ __ ] n
don't be a
[ __ ] be a [ __ ] you want n
water bro that's my compost te right
there there
you how well it works like with a fish
and just it's [ __ ] nuts
like locco told me that he has like a
shot of that water every
day makes it for life good for the gut
biome it was Gage green that used to
drink Willard's Water you remember
Willard's Water Dan
no area
weird [ __ ] and doubt it it was mud water
although he did say one thing that has
stuck with me for years I remember one
time that dude from Gage green was like
well I mean just think he was like
arguing in favor of veganism and he's
just like well think about it if you go
to a vegan restaurant you're probably
gonna want to [ __ ] a bunch of those
people but if you go to an Applebees how
many of those people do you really want
to [ __ ] good point I was like point
taken
bro stuck with me for like five years
now like chicks with Harry armpits we're
where you go bro see that that's what
that's what my book of poetry would be
right there yeah
right yeah yeah welcome to the live
stream
everyone I didn't say that [ __ ] I think
I think that was that was an actual
quote Yeah Jason whatever his name is
the the younger one the the older one is
the one that was a freak the Asian dude
with the super long yeah yeah yeah
that's Jason he's the younger he came
later um the old dude though he was I
think it was maybe fulvic water or
something yeah it was foul as [ __ ] it
was like kavak Cava or something you
know like mud water it was
crazy oh man only only crazy people
drink
that that's probably just as bad as like
the people who uh drink silver and turn
blue turn
blue or you could be like me and just
spill like $25 to $50 worth of silver on
your floor at a
time oh
nice yeah it didn't yeah I stained yeah
I stained the floor I was like sick I'm
glad I'm moving out in three days I
think I think to PR blue drops Matt
should turn blue just oh [ __ ] I've been
trying to get AI to make a picture of
Matt with a blueberry head and I just
can't get would be amazing I don't know
my head's pretty fat again right now I'm
all blimped up so but I've like done it
where I've like insert insert your image
into it to give it a starting point and
like it just yeah someone with more
Talent needs to do that [ __ ] I'm just
too beautiful for uh to turn blue like
that get uh is indo here Indo could
probably try it yeah Indo get to work
brother yeah do
it all right you want to hit the next
one next question was oh this is an
interesting one this came up in the
breeding series as well uh does anyone
use keep notes basically notebooks for
plants um tracking data in general any
tips in bra yeah I got mine like right
here actually yeah I'm so unorganized
I've never kept notes on anything which
is why I'm also starting to find get
yourself one of these it's just a lab
notebook you can put all your favorite
stickers on there this one's from like
10 years ago okay let's see the stickers
let's see the stickers yeah right yeah
heav 16s on there that's how you know
it's old any good bands any no there's
the trim scene that's the barber shop in
Humble that my wife used to manage we
got our general Hydro six Rivers Brewery
more General Hydro Roots organic I think
I was working at the uh the um Hydro
shop when I got yeah you got stickers
like that dude clonex baby the
one more Roots organic track seven
brewing in Sacramento that shit's fire
influence the most like dead LED company
of all
time yeah yes they made good [ __ ] though
the first gen but anyway like I have
like a little table of contents up front
like you just do this like you would a
lab notebook in school and uh like
here's some [ __ ] reading notes you
know what I mean how do I get this
centered reading
notes what else we got in
here um you could be you could be a TA
at a university Dan yeah for real look
at this one's developmental pychology of
the resin glands of hum lupus know I was
reading weird [ __ ] at point I guess yeah
not I'm dumb as [ __ ] I guarantee
you Merlin and Clark 2013 that was the
when I first read the Cannabis evolution
in
ethnobotany designs for clone racks and
[ __ ] the evolution in ethnobotany is
like a real college textbook for those
yeah that one's dank this is literally
like me designing my first tissue
culture lab you know what I mean and
like the phases and like different
equipment I need and [ __ ] how do I get
that there we go I just remembered like
that's how I do it is like the lab
notebook's gritted out it's numbered
Pages you can like here's where I
designed a quality index for grading
pounds when I worked in
La grading pounds yeah because we had to
like grade pounds and know what to sell
them for and so like it's my whole
process of like giving it a like a score
basically well that's nice just so when
buyers like try to to push back on it be
like no I actually have a system is
opposed to just like this is a cool one
a little like flood tray design for like
a rolling rack oh nice to V and so like
two little reservoirs with pumps and
like returns and [ __ ] Dan's gonna
auction off this notebook later on oh
here's all the here's the Clone list I
had in 2018 what is it what is it let's
see let's hear we got walto G strawana
Sour Patch Kids forbidden fruit cement
shoes Vienna OG this is when I first got
down to LA and so we had all this uh
weird [ __ ] purple punch Dosey Do two
different
cuts uh Ultraviolence that was all from
that cult classics dude had their kind
of like moment in the sun there in like
2018 shout out Marcus yeah what's up
Marcus super glue Crazy Glue stra sour
straw B of sherbet sherbet that was the
green shb
g44 g41 g33 Bubba G Girl Scout
cookie uh Kosher Kush Buckeye that was
actually a cool little purple plant did
you ever [ __ ] melv van yeah she was a
yeah
it it wasn't good it looks cool though
it was like a black rose hybrid of some
sort it was some yeah yeah um purple
Jack sfv Strawberry Fields Sunset sherb
golden Cobra I don't actually remember
that
one um King Lou Daisy OG Wi-Fi OG Durban
got to have Wi-Fi bro yeah this this
reminds me there was this one dude Jimmy
down in LA and he like ran a bunch of
like grow houses and stuff and he had
really good Cuts like he had this like
sour power OG no clue what the [ __ ] it
was it was fire M12 and shout out to
Local's cat yeah what up dude you got
Indo back there
yeah oh I had the trace dog at that
point that was a good one there you go
part of the silver back the silver back
was like an OG Gorilla Glue hybrid that
was super
fire
but Jesus Christ yeah Dan what about
like when you were what about notes when
you were actually tracking plants and
how they were doing I remember you
actually showed me like a spreadsheet
once as well yeah so here's an early one
um 2018 breeding notes but I just like
had the I just had the uh um the Clone
name a few little short notes I think
this was probably the first time I was
flowering this stuff I think this was a
run from bio Vortex it was his like
orang is the new banana J and I actually
found shout out Vio vortex one the you
from hso they're yeah dude he's a
[ __ ] really chill guy I met up with
him once in he's legit he's legit yeah
he's a really good and just like like
he's on it you know what I mean he takes
his time with [ __ ] you kind of have to
know him to get his seeds you know I
mean yeah that's kind of cool too though
yeah I met up with him in person and he
had this like cool chest you know what I
mean like this bag and he like pulling
out all these baggies and [ __ ] I just
like oh [ __ ] you're this is awesome this
is like visiting a seed bank in
person you know but not to be confused
with HSC who have has the best marketing
campaign on Earth what else do we got in
here I think that's it
really yeah here's me like mapping out
profits or potential profits you know
what I mean [ __ ] okay so we know Dan's
organized as [ __ ] how about you guys are
you guys organized too like this this is
insanity um honestly dude it's gotten to
the point where I just throw plants and
flower all the time that I don't know
like I just keep it track of when I
threw it into flower and that's about it
um I feel like everything I've grown I
can reference it in my
brain no I know where you're writing
know all the DMS and pictures on Discord
and stuff that those are those are kind
of notes as well I guess they are yeah
in some sense I use mine a lot actually
where I go back on like IG and I'm like
oh [ __ ] yeah okay I remember that now
and yeah pretty useful I'm at the point
where I use monkey at zoo like is my
strain index somehow he has EV he has a
list of every single strain I've ever
made from day one like that he keeps but
I have to reference that because I'm
like someone ask me something like I
don't [ __ ] know somehow he knows so
it's really cool that someone has that
because I I don't have that in my I used
to my brain isn't so good anymore though
long not a reliable tool
anymore what about
you the notes I think I yeah I also tend
to rely on IG when I first started
growing the forums were were good for
that obviously you had your own like
thread and you know you could obviously
keep a lot of notes in there yeah and IG
you know like Dan was saying it's not
bad but it's not easy to search like you
don't have to manually scroll through
everything um to find what you want so
it's not ideal either um ideally I don't
know I could probably use a spreadsheet
if I wanted to I'm just I'm still not
there yeah my memory is good for strains
and what they were like descriptions
it's pretty accurate for that my own
strain names less accurate like what I
called something at certain points but I
like if someone tells me the cross I can
tell them exactly what it was like you
know remember that much but strain names
are harder so when you're making seeds
that's probably a good thing to keep a
list of there was one for a long time um
when uh speak sleazy took over the
website they deleted all that so that
was kind of it unless someone finds a
way to go back in time like monkey did
so shout out to him for the help with
that I will say that when I first
started growing one thing that helped me
was actually recording mistakes that I
was making in the earlier run cuz then
I'd be like oh that's right this thing
happened last time and I I'll try not to
do that again um now most of that
internalized but yeah at some point I
was tracking like fuckups basically yeah
I can't imagine you not keeping notes
bro as organized as you are C you
probably I'm super into archiving [ __ ]
for sure but you are too Matt like you
you do keep a lot of stuff too maybe not
notes but you know you're into archiving
yeah yeah I keep collections of [ __ ]
look at look at that's behind that right
now I'm watching to see if my my hasola
autograph on eBay goes for more than two
down to six minutes and at 1500 it's not
mine I'm not selling it I'm watching
someone
sell yeah I guess I'm the only old man
that still does it uh IRL in the hand
you
know but uh I don't know I think it gets
you back better back into the mindset
you were when you were doing that stuff
too you know what I mean CU like
instantly that took me back you know six
years oh sure I bet where it's just like
oh I know what I was thinking about you
know what I mean and the things that I
thought were important and like what I
know better now and so I think it's a
really good like reflective tool too to
see like how far you've
come okay what do we got nice next okay
so next we have a bunch we have a couple
of questions from
scrwen uh I Know Dan has a lot of
experience reversing plants local
gaining it Matt obviously right um could
you talk about some common mistakes uh
outside of the typical trying to reverse
a single
plant go ahead Dan I'll catch up at the
end I feel like it's all either maybe
local you go first local um Local's
fresh right yeah I actually I just did
my first one not too long ago so it's
it's still pretty fresh um but the first
piece of advice is don't uh reverse a
big ass plant that's what I did
yeah um and like my sweet pee by Nature
[ __ ] just grows insane um like at in
Sint rates um and then two do more than
one plant uh you never want to put all
your eggs in one
basket um and then another thing would
be
timing uh you kind of got to know um
when it's gonna throw balls you know
like I I I didn't know about when it
would and it just kind of did around two
and a half weeks is when I started
seeing balls but then they didn't really
open till a few weeks after that so like
the the timing thing is still a bit
confusing to me um but it's all like
trial and error I feel
like yeah I feel like it's like
literally all mistakes until you do I
don't know half a dozen or so and then
you kind of get your bearings a little
better um but I agree with everything
that Lok said it's like um timing is
super important because if you spray too
much it doesn't go well if you spray too
high a concentration it doesn't go well
if you spray too low a concentration and
so like knowing what you're working with
and kind of documenting that because I
was Dick to the wind when I started my
reversal journey and someone just told
me like yeah mix a few ounces of this
liquid with a few ounces of this liquid
and do it in this order and I had no
idea the concentrations I was using and
it did not work most of the time um and
it took me like three years really
because I wasn't buying commercial
sprays to kind of like figure out where
I actually wanted to be and like some
stuff's easy too like I was doing some
hemp work and CBD work and that [ __ ]
reverses really really easily and and so
you get this false sense of confidence
same thing with autof flowers I reversed
Autos after that and did some of that
work and that [ __ ] is super easy you
know what I mean at least this the low
riter stuff that I was working with was
like just went every time and so um then
you get into doing multiple different
types of clones and you start tripping
over your dick and you're just like uh
what the [ __ ] happened this has worked
every single time that I did this why
isn't it working now and then you kind
of realize like and that happens over
and over again you're like okay well I
don't like know what I'm doing at all
actually and so for me it was once I
started documenting concentrations
blending different concentrations and
like doing kind of just like basic
trials like that where I was like okay
well this is all almost always too much
you know what I mean this is damaging
the plant it's counterproductive and I'm
like the concentration and the frequency
is too much and so yeah timing is really
important concentration is important and
then uh knowing the plant that you have
is also like obviously part of it
because it's like if you don't know it's
like General flower rate then you're
probably going to be thrown off like if
it takes a long time to initiate flower
for a normal female flowering it's
probably going to take longer during the
reversal too you know and you may be
doing extra weeks of sprays that you
don't do with an eight or nine week
common cut you know um I'll toss in one
more and this is the thing that I
probably get asked even by Pros like
that have been reversing some seeds some
femin seeds is is the most important
thing is patience because like like on
my bottle it says wait
20 4 days 20 24 days till you see any
sort of reversal going on and usually by
24th day you're like the [ __ ] it's not
going to happen and that's usually about
the time it starts to happen when you
start freaking out it's usually 24 days
before you see any initiation any of the
the common clone types out there that
aren't hemp um before you even see balls
and then from there out it's usually
like two and a half weeks two weeks till
it drops and matures if it's going to
yeah number one thing it I want to say
it took about four to five weeks to see
any sacks like wanting to open yeah um
makes sense yeah right on yeah and then
like L was saying two numbers is Big you
want multiple small plants I'd say at
least two if you're doing one variety um
and then usually I'll do a second backup
variety that I usually have some more
confidence in or have like reversed
before and kind of know it's whole
shtick and deal and so um yeah like you
having a backup plan for if that
reversal fails is pretty key because
otherwise you're like flowering stuff
you don't want flower from necessarily
youve been feeding it differently like
you're just kind of off at that point
you're like well I'm either going to
kill all these plants and start over but
if you had that backup plan then you're
like well I'm still happy with this you
know what I mean I'm happy that I made
this and I didn't waste my time in
electrical and space and all that um I
think also another thing too is like
when you're flowering males you know you
kind of see a lot of the flowers open
you know at one time I I feel like in
reversals it's very like you know
sporadic like a fuel open here there um
but granted that's you know only with
the the one plant I revers which was
sweet PE so yeah you know what what the
[ __ ] do I know yeah no it it tends to be
correct you don't see a lot of things
open all that sweet pee looked real good
though man that was a good reversal
hey maybe the next one man yeah yeah hey
but sometimes you get it to perfectly
reverse but the pollen's just like not
viable enough for whatever reason like
sometimes pollen drop doesn't mean [ __ ]
yeah exactly or like if you're trying to
do an S1 then especially not you know
like when I did that AJ sour reversal
like it barely made any seeds on itself
it made like 20 but on everything else
it was perfectly fine you know what also
is common is like getting the plant to
then take the pollen right so you see
all the pistols die off all that stuff
or whatever you call them uh stigma die
off and yeah then you see seeds forming
and then they won't mature because of
either plant health or whatever else uh
I saw that even this last time with the
the blueberry and cross some one of the
plants is in lower health so the seeds
started forming but they just ended up
in a lot of immature seeds so there is
that too like it's not always guaranteed
even if you see it have you guys [ __ ]
around with the uh BR them back under
veg light after like oh yeah set yeah it
worked pretty well for me I actually
very healthy seeds yeah I didn't I was
told like to expect a higher proportion
of like malformed and white seed but
like they all came out pretty good it
was a lighter color maybe it wasn't like
dark sometimes it could be gray modeled
but I dude I've gotten some amazing
seeds doing that like I did one round of
um I don't the the fake Irene the first
time the Bonnet and then the second time
I did that I did it with the re and made
seeds with the same bonnet mail and it
made some of the most like healthy
robust brown tiger stripe seeds I've
ever seen and being able to hold them
side by side and look at them was pretty
wild well just freeing up flower space
you know what I mean like not spending
all that time and having that dedicated
space for you know eight to 12 weeks
yeah it's just
huge there is a follow-up question from
scrwen which
is um I imine for both of you um any
common threads that you see with plants
that are difficult to
reverse I would say not always no CU
like like Girl Scout cookies reverse is
just fine and it's one of the most dense
plants there is in my opinion um not not
now anymore I mean guess there hybrids
of it but the at the time the the girl
SC cookies was super dense and I
remember thinking when I went into that
that some of the more dense plants or
some of the ones always had the hardest
time with because the flower clusters
and how the floral cluster set up for
reversals they would stack in so tight
they wouldn't mature that one reverses
really well um same with Bubba Kush it
reverses really well and has very very
dense flower stacking um I have found
that a lot of the more loose Airy types
like uh older what you would call tra
sativa dominant strains um they tend to
reverse really well but again not always
there's not um there's no hard set fast
rules yet well I've what I've I've
noticed with all the ones that I've
tried and failed to reverse multiple
times is they kind of fall into
different categories depending on like
what branch of the general family tree
they lie on like the AJ the sour stuff I
feel like it's just self-incompatible at
some genetic level you know so that's
one type versus like the Skittles just
doesn't make pollen sacks and doesn't
drop pollen you know and the pollen
super lowly like super low not very
viable like when you do and so it just
um I feel like there's different reasons
why things don't work out in reversals
and um for like the really hard to
reverse plants and like they I think
it's just different genetic like walls
that you hit and so and those will
probably lie similar with the families
of the plants they're in you know
yeah yeah
nice um anything else on
reversals yeah yeah numb I guess here's
another one that maybe some PE it might
be not common sense to some people but
like there's no need to spray the leaves
when you're doing reversal you know
um boy armpits yeah right them arm pants
yeah that's that's just like one thing I
you know again just being like a newer
person that that's what ha yeah when I
was young spray them arm pits yeah well
cuz the leaves they just end up getting
super damaged after a few sprays anyway
even if you a lightly dosed spray and so
uh like with the spray that I'm playing
with like after the third spray like
there's usually a decent amount of
damage that you'll see on the plant yeah
and that's like the higher concentration
and then the different additives and so
um you know it's just something to keep
in mind that it's like the more of the
plant you spray the more damage you're
causing to it which is going to have a
stress response that may not work in
your favor
exactly
nice okay and screw's last question was
more General um what plants are you guys
excited most excited about currently and
I guess cream pie inter whatever sh
cream pie because you get to call it
[Laughter]
[ __ ] good name I'm keeping that name
um I'll say interpret that whatever way
you want whether it's like a plant that
you're actually growing or something
that you're interested in working with
yeah any of any of those things
yeah I'm excited to get into some uh
Electric Boogaloo crosses that's
definitely first up on the the list I've
got some blueberry the blue bonnet f2s
those are going in on the next one
too um and then what
else I've got some more stuff from high
and Lanson that I need to check out but
I definitely want to get in on the mango
Haze stuff like I I have to I've never
flowered any like real types of haze
like like that I also need to hit up
Pico for some of the the night cap
wasn't it yeah I think that was his the
sandal Woody one I really want to try
that out too and so um that's like my
next venture is like getting into real
long flowering stuff that isn't just
like sour or chem mango Haze is really
good dude I that 2009 was my first grow
mango Haze and it was one of my first
real experiences with hay uh after that
I had the piff stuff but they were very
similar there there were Sim
similarities between both
I thought it was pretty oh and I'm
tossing that Jesus OG in again for
flour yeah I get my get my teal on again
it was good dude it was amazing extracts
I thought I thought it was good the
flower is not quite as nuanced like um
but the extracts are [ __ ] amazing so
I want to see if it'll dry sift too
because I feel like that would be really
amazing but I think it'll be a cool
breeding tool I'm kind of interested in
like a blueberry terpinolene combo I
think that would be really
interesting
yeah
local
um let's see uh what are you allowed to
talk
about I'm pretty [ __ ] excited for
like the dog [ __ ] like the act or the
electric boo whatever
um it's it's a probably one of my
favorite plants um you mean the Clone
itself right yeah like the Clone itself
um I got to smoke it once uh at the last
party we had uh Bittersweet SD grew it
uh super tasty Weed really great high
and uh you know the Eppy is always from
H&amp;L I'm always excited on that [ __ ] yeah
um sweet PE as always um I'm actually
growing out the uh p91 S1 for the first
time and that's really [ __ ] exciting
um I'm stoked on that for you yeah
because it's like you know I've seen in
the double digits of like sweet pea you
know so it's it's pretty [ __ ] cool to
see like the parental gen yeah um and
the cut that I have doesn't smell
exactly like the one that um bitter used
um yeah but there was a cut that I
really like that smelled exactly like
that um his is definitely more like true
to peanut smell yeah uh mine it has it
there but it has
like I guess like a soapy and sensey
weird thing I don't know it's it's like
super clean tasting I don't know how to
describe it
um and I haven't picked that smell up on
his cut yet exactly sorry this is a bit
of a random interjection but we're going
to talk to sub Rob hopefully next week
week and um I learned for the first time
looking at some of the ICM uh San Diego
finest threads that uh p91 is is po 91 I
didn't know that yeah it's one of the
stories for the poe Class of 91 is where
it comes from um as opposed to like any
Interstate or anything like that it's
it's supposed to be Poe Class of 91 but
it's not it's just one of the stories
that goes with it it's okay yeah gotcha
yeah not confirmed for
sure um
and
then I'm
also have the sorry po San Diego Powe
there you go Powe sorry my bad guys you
know you know I'm not I'm from
Scandinavia so yeah [ __ ] weird Arctic
Circle people um I was also gonna say
that 56 day headband uh OG is also
really [ __ ] nice um that [ __ ] looked
good yeah I've you mean o kush yeah yeah
I mean yeah to me it's sfv yeah okay
that's cool I think it's sfv like I
think hiill renamed sfv yeah and called
it that's a totally late term that
someone kept using on our show stupid
yeah okay that's cool but yeah no
regardless it's it smells really dank
dude I I like it a lot
yeah it's a damn good what
about are you also you you shade a pick
just just for uh Band-Aid Haze
Destroyer speaking of
hazes can we talk about that or no yeah
kind I mean it was more so like a
personal thing
what um they old sent you some of the
Destroyer uh
no that was from another buddy we cannot
talk about this and uh yeah I just don't
yeah I don't know how much yeah
okay God I mean like I haven't talked
you know but whatever it's it's just for
my Personal
Collection personal fond blings yeah
yeah I use the the long fans to tickle
my
butthole
long it does it it does it a little
better than the broad broad
leaves yeah better come on the fish trip
bro if if you get in trouble just throw
me under the bus okay uh if uh you're
mention it it's my fault no I mean I
just it was
unexpected God damn it
thousand
unrepairable hey I'm just here to like
make content you know yeah right we're
just YouTubers bro don't take us
serious yeah but no sadly that's just
for fun um nothing's coming of it uh
even breathing yet yeah don't don't even
get your hopes
up everyone just forget you know men and
black the [ __ ] memory thing just
forget we talked about this edit edit
right we're
good okay okay um Matt I mean you know
after your massive outdoor grow you know
are there any
other any excited any plants that you're
excited so I'm going to be remaking
bubbleberry this year here and and but
I'm have to do better planning um
obviously like the bug factor is insane
Outdoors like [ __ ] insane it's an a
valley so like we have white flies rips
up the wazu like it's just so you guys
have the green aphids down there too
yeah we have we have everything you
could imagine it's an ad crop problem
and the farmers all spray around here so
it gets kicked in every direction you
know um it's not their Direction so I I
don't know if I'll be doing outdoor this
year or move it back indoor finally I
just have so much stuff to move but I
need to make more bubbleberry because
it's finally gone almost gone um I don't
know like I it's hard to to keep like
being excited about working blueberry
because I know everybody's so sick of it
but I I haven't found the end of what I
love like every time I I like the
blueberry in Cross is exactly what I
wanted from the project that's a
completed completed thing I feel like um
but like there some of the hybrids are
really red so I like want to go there
there but it's like I keep breeding for
blue and all the Hybrids you know so I
don't know I it's it's hard to keep
doing that and keep a viable company
going as I've learned
but you know it's it's what I'm excited
about still I haven't I haven't moved
off from the blue breeding just because
I understand it so well and I guess the
longer I work with it the better I
understand it the more predictable the
breeding becomes and the less I want to
move away because I can predictably
breed that was the whole goal of
everything from the beginning I'll just
say I don't think there's any shortage
of excitement for blue stuff at least
not in like these circles People Are
People St to hear about it dude it's
been absent other than what blueberry
muffins has been the only blueberry in
the market that's been popular yeah yeah
and like I don't really like it like the
muffin TPS are like not like it's it's
cool it's nice for the first time but
like it's not the blueberry that I miss
and like that I used to get as a
teenager yeah yeah it's uh yeah I prefer
like the blueberry jam stuff that the
Bonnet throws yeah that's where I'm at
with it it's I don't know like there
there was a few years there where there
was a lot of downtime and nobody was
like crawling up my ass for blueberry
like a blueberry I've had that before
blah blah blah and it's like no not this
one but like how many times have people
heard that in cannabis not this one it's
just not you know so it's taken years
and years of enough people trying it for
it to build its
own now we're there and now stuff's
selling out you know so it's like I got
to go back and remake it but the time by
the point it's remade are people still
going to be interested that's always how
this game goes I think endo's right
though I think you need to do blueberry
permanent marker
blueberry I mean after someone just told
me Mac Daddy's in-house I just puked in
my mouth no I'm just
kidding it's not ouse seed yeah
maybe I mean on this note I do have a a
blueberry and cross girl that's just
started flowering so I'm excited about
that nice yeah good I'm excited how you
like it yeah did you do a blue cookies I
did yeah I've done like four or five
four or five yeah no but I mean on the
re no so the very first blue cookies cut
came out of our um what was it it was uh
uh original diesel bx1 cross to cookie
Berry which was the Forum cut Riot Berry
and that's what that blue cookies cut
that midnight Farms had came from so
that was from the like not the original
but the first Cross of the original and
it wasn't as blueberry as I wanted it
wouldn't have been my selection for it
it's the one that went around um yeah we
did a lot of cookie Berry stuff tons
ogk cookie it's like the most preferred
cut of the M of all time I'm I'm not
every time I've ever been with a group
among people like they're like trying to
get me to grow blue cookies or they like
have blue cookies they want to show you
and like I've seen some really yeah I've
actually seen some really nice ones and
like I remember some kid gave me like
eight bag seeds of a blue cookie that
was really good that I got to see the
weed of and it came in like a little
Marboro
cellophane yeah yeah but they didn't pop
and so I was pissed because that was
really good weed yeah it's strong it's
just it's just not blueberry like I
would have wanted like that's an ogkb
blueberry Blue Bonnet or blueberry ex
would be really nice the the OG KB we
did that one and then we actually I
think I have some we did a back cross to
ogkb with ogkb cross to Dan has some Dan
definitely have some yeah whatever you
whatever you made yeah I think you sent
me
some but oh yeah screw Stone's just
saying um yeah
sure there you go scu's growing some oh
okay they're gorgeous and like I said
the ogkb bx1 was awesome but it was so
blue dominant still which was when I
really that was early on so I was still
really learning like how dominant Blue
Bonnet bread at that point um so it's
not a true what I would call A bx1 like
there's no good perfect ogkb
representation sanss blue in it there's
a lot of bar in that one but it does
exist it's
nice
nice um
okay what's next uh from Pascal's Law
okay yeah that's right this is like
a very philosophical political question
what are your biggest hopes for the
future of cannabis and what are your
worst fears
I think we've realized some of my worst
fears already and yeah I don't think
it's really going to get better anytime
soon but um I'll be basic let me start
this off I want to be real basic here
and just say uh it would be nice to have
full
decriminalization uh obviously like no
regulation
um don't you know that's what drives
prices up
bro
well I mean to me that's an obvious
answer so yeah like true
decriminalization because there's been a
lot of studies that have shown that like
in certain minority youth categories
that uh arrest are up under legalization
in places like LA and yeah um they're
still getting like every day in the news
here people are getting popped where I'm
from yeah and so like it's not really
true you know and so I think a lot of
people are like yeah it sucks now but at
least nobody's going to prison for this
[ __ ] I'm like well you do if you are
like the wrong color skin and you have
more than an ounce right you know and so
like it's a do you guys know about
Germany's uh news I know that they are
doing something I can't remember if it's
like a full someone doing right they
have some weird wreck setup that they're
doing I think I think it's actually
pretty good but again yeah someone maybe
someone in the chat knows uh oh I just
have no trust anymore that's just my own
yeah that's where I'm at like any kind
of any kind of country attached the
United States in any any type S of way
is going to go our our route with the
legalization I like whether it's
Australia whether you know what I mean
like any place remotely attached to the
UN even probably will have have issues
like we did where it's just
corporatocracy um my hes for
future okay so fish F said it's legal
now yes we know it's quote unquote legal
we're just trying to figure out like
what that actually means um he says four
plants each so there's still rtion um
yeah see that's not legal to me that's
it's not legal
regulated for me to hold clones like I
can't I remember it's it's four plants
and I remember that the person was
talking about it was said four plants of
which you can only yield x amount and it
was such a low amount that it it didn't
make sense for even four plants to only
yield a certain amount if I remember
correctly like like four ounces over the
total of four plants something okay so
yeah fish farm no so what we're talking
about is having no restrictions like
like treated like a tomato plant yeah
like legal legal not not legal yeah at
the same time I don't know I don't want
to rain on Germany's parade like it's
still something I guess but like even in
a regulated system you could have
something that's like a farmers market
that kind of replicates our popup shows
and like has a structure behind it and
Licensing and fees that go to the state
and taxes collected they just know that
it would usurp their system because they
can't provide that level of quality
quity you know what I mean like right
now if you go and meet up with a bunch
of these guys running big companies they
I think that they are so delusional that
they've convinced themselves that this
shit's not mids you know they see what's
on the landscape and they see all these
other Rich Kids growing shitty weed and
they're just like oh well I'm actually
crushing it mine's better than theirs I
have the best I more than them so this
is top shelf you know what I mean and
I'm like well if the Market's Baseline
is [ __ ] then like your weed's One Step
Above [ __ ] like none of us are getting
good weed and exactly screw their taxes
and regulation like yeah I'm back to
like fully just like cowboy like just
like I don't give a [ __ ] anymore like
I'm gonna do what I'm gonna do and like
come and [ __ ] get me you know what I
mean like it's just like even put my
face out here and [ __ ] it's just like oh
well like are you you serious like you
know like how much [ __ ] I could say
about the [ __ ] that I like go happens
legally every day in the state yeah
right you know what I mean that you guys
willfully Overlook because you're
getting paid you know what I mean the
department of cannabis control
everything that California has going on
it's an absolute joke and that's what
the rest of the company country is
emulating and so and imitating and so
it's just like to me it's just a and
until I can show up with my [ __ ]
pickup truck with a couple pounds of
weed with their [ __ ] State stamp on
it and [ __ ] and I can pitch it to you
manto man you know what I mean man to
woman whatever in [ __ ] airm farmers's
market then like I can actually sell you
that weed and convince you that's it's
like this is why it costs more and this
is why it's better but they've
completely taken that out of the way you
know what I mean that's not even
possible and so to me that's like
willful deception to the larger market
that doesn't know better in part by the
state and lobbyists that do know better
that represent these companies you know
and so it's just big business Corporate
America and a nutshell and so I don't
really have much optimism but we can
still do our own thing you know what I
mean yeah like small collectives of
people that are just friends that grow
weed together like exactly like the
Discord Community is like that's what we
need more of because then you don't have
to go and buy weed from the [ __ ] shop
and get charged through the ass on taxes
and like get kind of shitty weed a very
limited scope it's almost like a union
in a sorts or Collective you know no
it's like this is our [ __ ] rights and
everything I mean that's that's what it
is about people getting together and not
being [ __ ] completely greedy bastards
you know that's that's the hardest part
with humans because it's like when when
when bad humans see good things
happening with between a group of people
where everything is all equal it looks
like something they can pre on and that
they're like always the first to wreck
it and that's the hardest part is just
knowing how to you know slit the throats
and you SL well you I've met a lot of
these rich dudes and like they tie I
don't even know if morality is a
question in what they do it's like the
moral thing to do is whichever thing
makes the most money for them yeah you
know what I mean that's almost what it
seems like to me but
um godam
it but like seriously like it's uh
anytime you get people that's that are
basically middlemen Financial middlemen
trying to squeeze dollars out of
something else that someone else is
producing and and like because you know
what I mean like we go out there the
idea is that like you go and you work
you make production you get paid for
said production but there's so many
people in our econom
that are just ringing a few pennies out
of every little thing that someone else
is doing and if you get enough of that
you can make a [ __ ] ton of money and
that's when you start making shitty
decisions where it's like I talk about
this all the time my wife hates [ __ ]
hearing about it but I'm always talking
about how like a business nowadays like
a corporation's um obligation is to the
shareholders not to the um actual
customer anymore and that's why we keep
getting things where it's like well why
is the quality of like every experience
in retail
and fast food and everything else going
down and it's like because someone else
is ringing dollars out of it and someone
else is having to make up that Gap by
like over hour like giving people too
many hours like it all ties together you
know what I mean it's our economic model
that's broken hold on I gotta show this
one I remember this guy came in last
time as my ever he's not old
enough unfortunately unfort I mean maybe
he is yeah but yeah you never
know if anything Denali is my [ __ ]
[ __ ] dad so he was in the right place
at the right time to have made that
happen I wanted n to be my dad as well
yeah I'll adopt him yeah yeah he's a
good dad he's a good daddy local uh
what's your philosophy local what's your
take on the political situation right
now um I don't know dude I'm like the
last person to ask about politics
um but I don't know I just don't want to
get in trouble for growing plants you
know that's that's really it you know
yeah um on the less political side no
[ __ ] the
man say it with me now um [ __ ] the man
um but on the less political side I
think uh like for me it's kind of seeing
where like the culture is going to go
because like I don't know I believe that
a lot of people my age are just like
lost causes dude yeah
um so yeah just kind of curious to see
where it's gonna
go yeah no [ __ ] the man yeah I agree
yeah I don't know I just it's hard to
find anything optimistic to say about it
you know this point we haven't seen
really any upswings in anything positive
in my opinion for cannabis uh the events
that we used to have were amaz not would
even say amazing they were cool like old
Emerald cup and stuff like that where
it's at Now versus
even five years ago it's a hot [ __ ] mess
um no disrespect to the emerald cup
people it's just the it's a lot of
people can't participate anymore that
were the driving force behind it and
that's why it's lost
popularity um [ __ ] I mean laws period
price of cannabis um us being able to
support our family doing what we've
always done like all of it's changed
none for the better quality so I it's
what positive is there to say more
people smoking but who gives a [ __ ] like
quality over quantity you know what I
mean like quality people over quantity
of people is a real thing um I don't
know and and it's lost the sense of
community in many ways in that respect I
mean not everybody listens to the
Grateful Dead granted you know but uh
there was some sort of community there
and I I feel like that's just all over
the place I do have to say that more and
more random people that just casually
smoke weed have been hitting me up for
seeds and clones and stuff and I've been
going out of my way to like literally
any person that's just an acquaintance
in my day-to-day life if they're like
hey man I heard you really like weed you
know it's like I'll give them like
[ __ ] 100 seeds of like you know a
couple different thing like 10 seeds of
like 10 different things or something
like that and just like try and Spark
that interest because I'm like yeah you
can just do this for yourself he's gonna
get hit so hard now after this
[Laughter]
show IRL I need some seeds I need come
meet me come meet me in real life and
then we'll talk but I've been I don't
know whenever I have like less like I'm
always like trying to do too many things
at once but like I would love to have
like a thing where once a month we all
met up at some dude's ranch or some [ __ ]
and just got high and [ __ ] drank a
few beers and talked about weed and [ __ ]
I would love to have that in my
community I just don't have the time in
my life to like structure it I'm like
trying to like be self-employed and like
[ __ ] do all a million different
things at once you know and so um you
know but anyway like maybe at one point
you know more people need to do that
kind of stuff because it's cool man it's
nice to like actually hang out with
people that like have like interest
because weed and being a weed nerd is
kind of like it's a bubble in a bubble
you know what I mean ning and ning and N
it's like a a burrito full of burritos
bro yeah like people don't get it when
they're like oh so you really like weed
and I'm just like yeah let's not talk
about it it's the waters are too deep
for a casual first
conversation I mean I think I'll would
just Echo what lots of people have said
My Hope Is that it's just currently a
very immature it's at a very immature
stage and like the you know like beer it
will get you know to a better place
that's probably as optimistic a spin as
I can put on it right now yeah the weed
swap meat [ __ ] yeah I'm
there that H right so one of the things
that um Pascal's Law I always thought it
was Pascal's laa I don't know why but
Pascal's Law makes makes I think it's I
think it's a play on both yeah okay okay
okay well one of the things that I
noticed he asked in this other one was
it says or future viral threats and that
wasn't even a part of the the process in
my brain right now as we were talking
about the future of cannabis but yeah
that's a major [ __ ] issue right local
like this is a real thing H yeah it's a
real thing um passing AIDS it's yeah
it's like the SCD
of of the weed World um yeah hlv really
does show up places people don't
understand phone trading it's abundant
it's I mean it's yeah it's it's one of
the costs you pay um sometimes [ __ ]
doesn't even look sick dude like you
wouldn't even know it exactly yeah and
then other things you're like yeah
that's 1,00% sick like I can visually
identify something's wrong but I don't
know it's just
like you know you gotta like understand
how it transmits um so like you know
exchanging a runoff you know like you
don't you want to have everybody on like
a riser or something um or on their each
individual um saucer so that the the
runoff doesn't touch the bottom of
another plant because that's how it'll
contract it um you don't want them to
exchange fluids uh you know xylem flum
yeah that that too um
but yeah it's just like I mean yeah
every every little step kind of counts
like if you know say you you forgot to
bleach a pair of scissors and you didn't
realize it you know
like you may have infected something you
may have not and I think the most
important thing to nail home is that
some plants like we're noticing like
they may not look sick at all so
visually it's not something you can
necessarily detect visually a lot of
them can carry it and don't necessarily
show any of the disease but if you have
those in your garden they can infect
other plants that really show the
disease real fast so it really is about
either being super clean only popping
from seed not taking in Clone ones and
playing that game or constantly being
able to have access to test and
test no shared root zones between
varieties either yeah that's a huge one
it's like even [ __ ] cloning trays and
[ __ ] like I don't know dude like once
you run into to a scare it's just
like exactly exactly every last thing
for over course of week um
so yeah and I mean I I work with it you
know so I I kind of see how it spreads
too so it's just like once you kind of
see it you just you would rather want to
stay like on top like be precautious you
know yeah rather than like oh [ __ ] you
know my plants are sick maybe I should
put them on their own saucers so yeah
it's a really really good point for not
using AOC cloners too like if you're
doing collecting don't use AOC cloners
oh man that's that for the disease yep
you can [ __ ] your entire collection like
that dude super fast I wish I still had
mine I used to have a couple 128 cell
ones and I kind I want a flower in one
yeah go yeah dude I have one you come
pick up bro it is ready to rock [ __ ]
yeah
dude oh we still got to go to that
underground Garden down by you I sent
you that [ __ ] right yeah yeah yeah you
did that [ __ ] looks crazy yeah it does
yeah we got a lot to do yeah um and then
I guess another thing to add uh but they
probably covered this on the Tumi uh
podcast is leaves and Roots can show
very different results that's right yeah
you get them tested yep yeah parts of
the plant being tested but again nail at
home there are carriers that don't
necessarily show it so don't assume that
you can see it like plants can stay very
healthy looking that are less
susceptible to the virus but still carry
it and transfer it to other ones that
don't don't assume any of it s I'm
laughing at
comments yeah yeah someone remembers
back in the
day back in the day in 2017 yeah we were
talking about back then it's it's been
around for a while it just took a long
time for us to understand what that
truly means yeah yeah and um I'll also
add like I've lurked on clone trading
discords and like I can guarantee those
[ __ ] Gardens aren't as clean as some
people but dude like I see some pictures
and I'm like I'd be damned you know like
what the
[ __ ] um you know I'm not a big ADV
advocate for clone sales yeah people
that don't understand what they have in
their room and that's abundant as [ __ ] I
get messages from people all day hey I
heard this clone for sale is this a good
price for it and I just smack my head
like don't even get it yeah dude don't
even get it I just can't get over how
many of these people use the the phrase
breeders cut that's when I know you're
full as [ __ ] yeah breeders cut yeah
you've got every breeder selected cut of
every single one of these varieties
exactly Cup winning breeders cut oh I
met so and so and it's like well how can
you prove that yeah how can you prove
that you got direct from this person
they're like well I know him and I'm
just like well like okay
cool okay um we have a few questions
from dubie I assume that's how you say
it right that it's not that's the point
of his name right duie anyway um taking
care of and feeding long flowering
plants uh let's say 12 weeks and
longer local you want to go I know
you've had a few recently um I mean
it's just the same process but stretch
out it is yeah I mean you're kind of
just
elongating the feed you know like
say because most schedules are designed
for like nine week crops so it's like
you're not going to feed a 14we plant in
a 9we period um but yeah I mean I kind
of just keep them fed because they go
longer they'll get hungrier whatever
um but yeah any
specifics I mean don't go maybe do you
want to help do the that translation so
for a 9we feed what are the you know
they like a few segments right how would
that translate to like a 14 beginning
flowering mid flower and flower yeah
just you just elongate each set yeah if
it's if it's a 12we plant versus a nwe
plant each set gets like one more ESS
well like a lot of the feed like if you
follow like a Bottle recipe that's like
you know like if you're running Cana
they say like oh if you have longer
flowering plants like repeat weeks like
three to four as many times as you need
to like then and then once you get to
like you know I don't know like seven or
SW call it final swelling like Growers
we should all know what final swelling
is the final swell that's when the end
stage begin yeah experience honestly but
with also with longer flowering plants
like they don't necessarily like
nitrogen is heavy other plants yeah you
don't need to to feed as heavy with them
you don't need to water as much
necessarily with narrow Leaf dominant
plants um there's little tricks like
that that you'll learn over time but
generally speaking it's just a longer
stretched out of the same
thing I do want to say though that
reminded me I was like a little
distracted at first that dude name was
dubie the first guy that I saw growing
indoor his name was dubie he passed away
recently so uh rip doobie rip
doobie just to clarify not the same
person who asked the question obviously
not no it was my homie it was my homie's
dad he passed away too young so um
anyway rest in peace
yeah shout out to
this
sweet well done dude well done was that
a salmon Pig middle [ __ ]
yeah uh okay followup from duie
experiences changing growing Styles uh
during your growing career anything from
minor tweaks to major major like style
change I guess I've done everything and
it all works yeah done everything it all
works except for me I didn't ever get um
what the [ __ ] is it called deep water
culture like circul rdwc Rec I could
never do it right I never nailed that I
don't know if it's because I didn't have
a perfect Chiller whatever it is but I
never had a chiller that's probably why
it didn't work I tried it a few times
but I think you need a major Chiller to
make it work but I don't know I couldn't
do it I my friend was working on a farm
in Oklahoma that had like a whole
Greenhouse of that [ __ ] yeah and I was
like that's too much yeah like that to
maintain that it just looked like a
nightmare yeah I was like I'd rather
have just like 20 gallon pots of soil or
I in one gon plants yeah on table if I
had my say if I had my my say and my
space perfect
at the time my brothers I would run
tables nonstop tables Coco tables yeah I
age just because like and and have it
just be you know flood and drain flood
and drain flood and drain nice and easy
I want to do that with these Blue Dream
s1's after I get the initial down oh I
know for a fact the Clone does and so
yeah three inch pots of that [ __ ] just
like single
Spears that um dude that Waking Life in
like a one gallon H absolutely like
[ __ ] slay dude oh I bet yeah I can
only imagine in like rock wool or some
[ __ ] smaller pot single
Cola I'm gonna get MD into out of
existence did you see the one he posted
after the last episode I did yeah like
he he he posted it for like a second and
deleted it and it was me over like some
shirtless model or
whatever
you to get you in some Tom of Finland
pics with like a mustache and like a hat
all naked yeah
binging yeah too good I knew it was
coming I want to reframe that question
um have any of you had to change Styles
out of necessity like out of some kind
of like situational speaking of speaking
of renting like I started off you doing
tables and I quickly found like when I
got a 24-hour notice tables [ __ ] suck
for that like yeah because all of a
sudden you're having to take plants out
of a a a system of feed that they can't
be dry like that all the time because
they're used constantly having a
flooding system um I moved them all to
single pots and that's when I realized I
have to do uh hand feed drained to waste
after that point because it just wasn't
going to work any other way like renting
kind of necessitated that change uh
having people come into your grow and
having to hide your grow necessitate
necessitated that change so you know
that's one thing to think of if you're
renting don't necessarily jump into
tables because it's a really risky
situation at that point they're harder
to take down and keep your keep small if
you do get some
2x4s right yeah they fit in the Subaru
and in a black trash bag you know yeah
like pots pots you can fit about 90 of
the three gallon into a small U-Haul if
you really stack it
hard yeah I mean was my main thing for
me I just bought my first house and so
my style changed a lot once I actually
like owned a house so I like my setup's
different now because I like framed out
a little flower room and I'm going to
frame a little bedroom too in cloning
space and so um now I can be a lot more
permanent but like the mobile setup
which I feel like a lot of people are
stuck with for me it's like yeah 2x4s
small tents uh growan because you
bringing bags of soil into your
apartment I don't how the [ __ ] do you do
that
l d I used to do it into a big apartment
complex it wasn't easy it just just
always
Asing dude people see that [ __ ] my
landlord was literally so he was floor
level with street level and I had to
park right in front of his window and
bring it downstairs right under him and
I lived under my landlord and grew above
him to to the left of him behind him
across from him and Below him and I was
different
names yeah it was it was not fun and
then disposing of all that that's what I
mean is getting rid of it like the
growan makes it easy CU you're just
taking the trash out you know I mean
that's kind of what I do you know D the
bottles all the plastic bottles all the
[ __ ] [ __ ] hiding all that
[ __ ] night it was a nightmare I have so
many like Cana DRS that I not like you
like used ones you know yeah yeah yeah
because like I'm not just gonna throw
[ __ ] away in residential you know
homeless people are going to [ __ ] go
there Oh They'll dig it out and then
like yeah leave it outside the can and
right when you go use someone you don't
likes can exactly I did I did a lot of
that and yeah whatever look we all know
you're just staying up late gaming and
you're pissing in those can of
[Laughter]
jugs the whole tub is just filled with
piss jugs of
Cana nitrogen
man nitrogen
formula oh [ __ ] yeah I know I I've
changed especially with clone when it
came to cloning I've tried every single
cloning technique from aroc cloner to
you know yeah domes to God bubble
cloners all kinds of different things um
and I always end up going back to domes
I always end up going back to does just
because I like soil man like I tried
doing the cocoa thing for the small
scale indoor and I didn't get bad
results but I was just kind of always
mad at it you know what I mean and I
felt like it was harder to dial in
certain plants and then like I just went
back to promix and like small amendments
to it like dry amendments and like
[ __ ] great love it and then I blended
all that cocoa in too so it's kind of
like a king's mix yeah um nice yeah so I
guess it's a hybrid of all now but um
good [ __ ] yeah good
[ __ ] this was an
interesting I've never really thought or
heard of something like this before have
you
guys I could see it maybe stressing it
out and showing a Herm trait that may
have already been there you know because
gg4 is super hermy
yeah it could be um I mean if it's a
seed plant doesn't it still have still
have some and km's kind of hurt me too
you know what I mean not like the worst
way
possible so this could be a stress thing
as well is that what you're saying sorry
yeah it's super stressful to graft a
plant like most of them die until you
get really dialed in like when I was
watching people do it and like got to do
a few trays all of mine died on my first
few attempts you know and then like one
dude just had the touch and so like he
was grafting all kinds of [ __ ] yeah I
had a friend who could do that I I
wasn't very good at grafting myself well
what we noticed was the root stock is
very important and you'll find a plant
that's very a very compatible root stock
compared to everything else and it's not
always what you think it was like to me
I was blown away I was like that piece
of [ __ ] plant is like the best root
stock we have like okay I mean I guess
it actually has a use in my mind now
because like I don't know why the [ __ ]
we even flower it so hold on what in
what context were you grafting to begin
with like were you trying to do like
Apple thing like the apple tree thing no
we were trying to like see if we could
improve Vigor on hard to grow plants
with shitty root systems and like just
low Vigor in general so it was like Z
stuff OG stuff um and put it on a more
vigorous root stock to see if it helped
it grow better and it what it what we
realized is that it kind of relieved
viral symptoms if you had a cut that was
just dud it out it's the only copy you
have access to and you still wanted to
use it you could get it like out of the
full dud Zone where it'll flower
normally make some seeds and move on
that way you can Trash the cut um and so
I did that with like the the Hindu
Skittles that's where those came from
Hindu Z I mean doing those yeah because
you know they it's a thing with like uh
obviously like agricultural crops right
um yeah they almost breed for root
stocks I think it' be cool be for plant
counts too you know someone should start
a company doing that and be like hey you
got three varieties just grow one
massive outdoor and you'll stay under
your plant count you know whatever
you'll get three varieties some [ __ ]
like that yeah I've seen those kind of
like Hydra you know those like on the
Forum some guy does some really cooked
like Hydra project with uh like five
different strains on one one plant kind
of thing yeah but who gives a [ __ ] about
plant counts anyway man like you're
already grown dope like
yeah about
fcking for real like just do it like
just be nice to your neighbors and they
won't rat you up
exactly that's why I'm glad I'm moving I
got this dick next door is like [ __ ]
definitely ratted me out to my landlord
why I had to like rip my [ __ ] apart
Midsummer last year just like [ __ ] you
dude because I have six outdoor plants
like I don't it wasn't even six it was
five yeah I have I have a neighbor like
that right now who's like he worked for
the county as like a a I don't know like
a tax person or something and he's
always looking over my defense
constantly so I have to move that's cool
this guy got two different two different
graphs to work
out on is Steve Murphy's purist uh I
haven't seen any pre flowers yet that's
pretty cool yeah yeah because we had
really high failure rates depending on
what the root stock was so that's cool
that it's like not you know not going to
be the same for everyone you know said
right that's right
[Laughter]
peaches like count d nuts yeah look out
for D's Nuts genetics and D's
remodels and
cocky Caleb should fix his web shop
cannot add seeds to the back I'll tell
I'll let him know it's so what try a
different browser too we had the same
web person at some point and I agree it
needs to be totally redone there's yeah
both of our sites need to be totally
redone but I I should do that I I'm
capable of it I just have so much other
[ __ ] to do yeah I'll I'll let them know
if they're not working yeah definitely
try a different browser if you haven't
yeah that can be a big issue with h kind
of archaic old websites they can be very
browser specific if you don't just a
good question for everyone here's a good
question for everyone you guys all go
ahead what was the first strain that
smoke that got you hooked blueberry
excluded there you guys uh
S1 oh yeah yeah that's a good one blue
cheese blue cheese yeah blue cheese yeah
local God
damn God damn godamn blueberry
excluded um blue
[Laughter]
cheese I'd say uh probably some of the
first good weed was from bitters like
that I've had and grown was from bitters
sweet pee for sure my first was a purple
train rack purple Urkle train rack
I had some like purple pineapple train
wreck in Humble at one time it was at
hprc and it was all seated and it was
really good but that was actually one of
the first seed runs that I like grew
plants out of it was just bag seed from
there was a killer killer purple train
wreck cut in San Diego it's supposed to
be it was supposed to be purple urle
train wack and I usually don't like
purple urle anything but I really like
train wack so I kind of leveled it out
to where it was no anxiety but just
really Stony that was the first time I
wasn't getting like weird anxiety from a
purple
so I really like that one quite a bit it
showed me that I could like that kind
[ __ ] oh yeah yeah dude the old dude next
door probably smokes dope I smell that
[ __ ] it smells dope call soft power soft
power power like that yeah my neighbor
is anidea single lonely dude who likes
to [ __ ] with my lawn and take my garage
jerk him off bro no not he's not hot
enough dude
your he's not your typ then you can't do
it obviously yeah but no this dude like
[ __ ] with my garbage cans and like
loads up all my [ __ ] and like if I like
I don't know he just pisses me off so
much and he'll like run my sprinklers
and I'm like I don't give a [ __ ] about
lawns I'm like lwn
like yeah I'm like dude like I don't
care about the lawn it's like less it's
like 100 square feet in front of my
house and like I he runs your sprinklers
oh yeah bro and like he leaves notes
like on my car like oh you need to run
this 30 minutes a day four days a week
during the summer he's a landscap archit
ho and I wanted to leave a note on his
car that just said [ __ ] you is it a
homeowners association there or
something [ __ ] no dude we're in the city
man this is an old ass neighborhood with
just this douchy old dude who has the
nicest house on the Block God I hate
those people yeah he's just a [ __ ]
dick weing about the [ __ ] lawn he
might tomato Farm he's not dude he's so
[ __ ] lame [ __ ] you Gary
[ __ ] Karen that [ __ ] dude man I'm
so glad I'm moving this weekend yeah
[ __ ]
yeah um we are kind of we're at the end
of the questions but I wanted to ask Dan
about something because we probably will
do a whole episode on this but like a
couple of weeks ago you you were really
wanting to rant about uh
polyploids oh you want to give us like a
little like uh some context for that
well it's all the rage right now like H
HSC just released like a [ __ ] hourong
video on it like two weeks ago I
couldn't even get through it yeah I was
like I love hsd yeah right unfortunately
why I'm wearing this flannel is because
I have one of their old shirts on that I
paint
in and I was like I'm covering this [ __ ]
up man nothing but love for them polys
are great talking man they're whatever
they're running a business it's it's
just a shenanigan another shenanigan to
chase for people that aren't yeah well
whole thing that people are chasing is
seedless right and like I've read all
these papers and like you don't get
seedless you just don't get fully formed
seeds and maybe it's less but you get
little white seeds you get pods man yeah
on a lot of it some of those are the
worst I doubt a lot of them's ability to
truly make them and test for them
because I don't know like they at least
hired a real geneticist you know what I
mean they had him talk in that video and
[ __ ] I'm like I haven't looked into the
guy at all he may be [ __ ] but like I
don't [ __ ] know him so of paper on
polyploids the other day that just kind
of [ __ ] blew most of it out of the
water well the only the only attribute
that I can say for sure that might be
beneficial is for Mass scale outdoor
seedless you know what I mean so you're
not worried about hemp farms and Herms
and stuff you know what I mean but guess
what like you're you're I I don't know
like I guess like it doesn't even
protect you if the crop itself Herms you
know what I mean three sets of
chromosomes on a triploid plant like
they I'm they can line up with another
triploid
I would imagine they can yeah you know
and like um there's also people doing
tetrol work and I'm like well tetr
you'll just make mixoploids and other
polyols yeah tetrol I believe can breed
with diploid because you're still gonna
have an even amount of chromosomes but
like yeah uh triploid can't make yeah
PID but that doesn't mean that there's
no seed that forms at all and so I think
it's dubious that claim in a nutshell I
haven't really [ __ ] with it in person
so I'll just leave it at that but like
the other things more in the hemp Market
that I've seen um and I won't name names
they're they know who they are but
they're um um have all these things
about increased Vigor and at least in
CBD plants there was a significantly
different increase in CBD production but
that wasn't true for the THC plants they
tested and so you get a slightly bigger
plant but even when uh they were looking
at the yields the flower yields weren't
increased the biomass yields were
everything's all about biomass for these
corporate [ __ ] so that's what I mean
yeah and so like if you're not
increasing THC and you're not increasing
Bud yield then like I don't really see
what the point is because all you're
doing is enabling people to grow more
boof and crash the market out at a
bigger scale because like biomass at
least like the way I understood it like
you know like when we were doing like
lab studies and [ __ ] it's like the
entire weight of the plant like yeah
that's stem Lea root yeah anything you
pull out of the ground that gets put
into that [ __ ] bail you know and so
um to me it just seems fruitless maybe
I'm wrong but like um nobody's actually
doing interesting breeding in the larger
market anyway so like why would adding a
new technique to a bottleneck genetic
pool like really change anything exactly
it's just
a it's a marketing yeah exactly it's a
marketing buzzword yeah it's just gonna
be I don't think anything's really G to
come of it just like we haven't really
seen anything come up mainam you know
yeah ex we've read we've read the paper
Benjamin that's that's the paper I was
referencing biomass increase what you
[ __ ] do you know yeah biomass is not
important to me you know I breed for I
turn it into tinctures and you know what
I mean like hash like it's for me to
consume and so biomass isn't really that
useful to me
I'd like this question before we're done
this is a go did Eagle 20 give a certain
[Laughter]
flavor yeah I don't I don't know uh
maybe I'm [ __ ] dude I'll tell you
what before I was educated I sprayed a
lot of Spectra side yeah SPX yeah yeah a
lot of that like the guy that taught me
how to do clones I sprayed every single
clone tray with that [ __ ] Lear I learned
on Fon 27 Fon 27 and Spector side m
together turns black we would call that
black death and then spray that oh
you're it was it was bad and I would do
it without a mask like I'm probably of
cancer as speak from it yeah yeah people
laugh at me at work because I'm like
super serious about wearing a respirator
when there's just dust in the air even
you know what I mean I'm like I'm not
breathing that [ __ ] in man you know how
much [ __ ] aminox I breathed in like
oh my God like even how
much oh yeah yeah I just don't I don't I
just don't use like n95s and dirt you
know dust masks anymore because guess
what you pull it off at the end of the
day of working and the whole inside of
the Mask is covered in dir yeah have
like actual I wear a respirator now a
painters respirator yeah with a with the
cans on the
side when I used it when I used it I
don't I didn't start using that until
way later uh fun fact is the the pink
cart it's like a pink magenta it's not
like hot pink there's like a hot pink
and then there's like a m there's like
three tiers of them yeah yeah but you
want to get like that really dark pink
for pesticide application that's rated
for it I got hot pink yeah I think
that's just like the dust and fumes one
yeah I don't probably the cheapest
one but yeah um there but it'll say on
it they I think they do call it a tiar
on there I can't remember but it it
should be
yeah okay so where we at yeah so we
don't really have uh any questions left
um anything else that we wanted to talk
about these
nuts every
time um oh by the way when I was having
that brainfire earlier when you're
talking about the drops I meant that
there might be another blue drop coming
another blueberry you know another
Bonnet drop right I don't know if oh
yeah yeah I guess there is I'm like oh
the
yeah yeah I mean I guess yeah well no I
said it within we were talking about
high and Lonesome stuff so it was
probably confusing yeah the timeline on
it I'm not sure um there is more blue
blue bonnet I guess yeah Blue Bonnet
stuff being made specifically blue
bonnet or is it blue no Blue Eye blue
and cross not blue bonnet or blue and
cross stuff being made we'll see how it
goes oh scrw says what to look forward
to in this season well I don't know we
we they things there there might be one
very big and exciting thing um but I
don't know if I don't think we can talk
about that yet we're going to be doing
more with the the can Cabana guys too
there's a few more of the dudes we want
to have on um some really important ones
yeah sub Rob interview sub I'm stoked
for sub Rob I love sub Rob sub Rob like
for you that you that aren't familiar
with him um we have his seeds on our
site under seed trip um sub Rob was one
of the dudes that helped Run San Diego's
finest onight he's probably one of the
most respected members him Sean k um
there are a few others but those those
are the ones that I'm closest with
um it was just such an influential part
of the Clone only trading scene during
the Forum eras of like 07 to
2001 um almost everything ran through
San Diego's finest and it was one of the
I think longest running most pages so
far so they I think they completely went
over page 500 and had to go to a whole
new SD fin
yeah yeah there's so many and uh yeah I
mean he was he was the boss of it he was
[ __ ] cool and he he's just very very
down toe
transparent um we've always gotten along
politically and everything so I'm stoked
to have him on he's funny as [ __ ] but
he's also very knowledgeable and very
very humble with his knowledge so stoked
on that one um yeah the the Cana Cabana
guys I'm sure there's a lot more we have
lined up that we need to go back and
touch on so yeah there's gonna be some
good stuff this mon
this season yeah and I mean just to give
some insight into our process we we're
really more than like a couple of weeks
ahead like we're not that professional
yet um so it's not like we have the
whole season M it's usually be [ __ ]
it up or we would be no that's not true
yeah I don't know but we'll see we'll
see where it
goes yeah I mean that's for me really in
terms of like talking points today yeah
um I guess uh um so yeah we have the
blueberry incross cross drop go get your
[ __ ] I'm going to be putting it on
the site probably this weekend um like I
said I'm ahead of schedule on getting
the the bean shooked and all that except
I'm waiting for a printer to print the
labels but after that they're going out
hopefully Amazon will speed their ass up
um that that the blueberry incross is up
for order right now under pre-order it's
probably going to go up in price after
they get made and packaged and sent the
first round I want everybody who's who
gets in on the early up to to have some
Advantage um if you're part of our
patreon Discord you get 30% off that
price too and that only costs $5 a month
so for $5 a month you could get I $30
off or 40 I don't remember how much it
is but it's a lot off um we also have uh
the goat farm drop that I need to get up
to in package same situation um but you
can also get 30% off on those if you're
a part of our patreon Discord so check
that out we always you know shoot the
[ __ ] on there it's it's it's a lot of
fun make friends make loved ones
permanent loved ones in your life I
don't know I I it's like a nice family
there you know sometimes we have to
whack them all but it's not too
bad um and then High lome mango Haze
drops coming up soon too so keep your
eyes peeled for that so stoked man yeah
that [ __ ] some of those photos look just
absolutely amazing like I I had to save
a few where I was just like [ __ ] I just
want to look at that for the wank Bank
yeah right
yeah like it's just really good it was
just unique too and just like different
and the resin on it I was just like
incredible yeah I can't wait to smoke
some I guess other than that I guess
this is I mean I don't know if we're get
this is gonna be the end of season 10
the start of season 11 I think they
already did the I don't know I think I
already like committed to it this being
the first episode of season 11 yeah that
makes sense season 11 episode one
[ __ ] um oh and we the the
Raffles sometimes in our um the Raffles
were those are super dope yeah yeah they
were pretty fun the one thing I don't
want to do is like make gambling
addicts I'm always concerned with that
because like you know like in a group
based on weed there come a background of
a lot of addictions and addictive
personalities so like that would be
horrible to trigger something like that
so I'm trying to be very cautious about
it but at the same time it's a way to
get we need to keep a tally of who's
playing every week and then H like three
weeks in a row you're out you're out for
like two weeks time it out yeah no I
just want to be I want to be careful and
and also say that you know that's always
in our thoughts too because they were
just super fun with the the live chat on
there too like co-current with them like
I was just listening to those and like
doing drywall work in my house and [ __ ]
and like having a blast man it made that
[ __ ] go a lot faster so I'll probably do
one this weekend so you guys know um I
don't know which one yet but we'll do
like maybe maybe a breeders pack of the
the blueall on it or something like that
or blue blue and cross yes iot resin on
your balls accidentally eyeballs and
lower balls yeah yeah never really had
just makes it can it can irritate the
skin because of sensitive skin on your
scroot sack but impromptu waxing yeah
eyeballs though that's [ __ ] man that
sucks I got been having it happen
non-stop all week while shucking I've
been in some weird trim scenes in
Humbolt
so not even an yeah that's not an
exaggeration either some weird [ __ ] used
to happen on the
hill holy I would love to hear about
that another time yeah especially some
of the other stories that I heard from
like especially female trimmers like
holy [ __ ] dude just wild [ __ ] happening
out there oh God I how do I get in on
this seriously bro you got to Spill the
Beans I know man okay part two part two
part two there you go all right I guess
uh yeah is is that going to be it any
you guys have any last words any shout
outs this week yeah shout out Papa
Dale Papa D do well love that man love
that
man um yeah oh yeah and don't forget the
the the space dude drops coming soon
from TGA don't want to forget that one
that one is gonna be a big one um yeah
we'll see how that goes got a lot of
seats to blow and a lot of seats to
shove still on that
one shuing and blowing you know that
game
all right local you got anything uh
shout out to my cats shout out to your
cats they were here the entire
live they
yeah oh hey dude shout out to the
dude right thousand you got anything
he's been he's been coming up to the
window like every 10
minutes no I don't I'm I'm like my
brain's gone yeah it's me this is a fun
show yep I guess with that we'll we'll
end it thank you everyone I'm going to
try to edit this into a real episode
because I think it sticks it into a live
portion makes it harder to find so I'll
try to it does yeah yeah have it done by
this
weekend all right and with that from us
here cheers good night everyone bye want
to sit at the table with The Syndicate
check out our patreon and our link tree
or description below our merch site is
officially live
we have all sorts of shirts hoodies and
goodies to sort you out and shipping is
super fast and most importantly the
quality is topnotch I've been saving old
designs for years for this purpose so
please check it out Syndicate gear.com
we also have an underground Syndicate
Discord where we get together and solve
old strain history together daily it's
an amazing community of learning away
from IG and it's an amazing resource for
old catalogs and knowledge we hope you
join our Union of readers and Growers
come check it out