welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
cannabis strain history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
welcome to breeder Syndicate I'm Matthew
and I'm here with my host thousand fold
and today we're going to be talking
about making seeds in small spaces and
home environments
yeah
um so in the past uh Matt you and not so
I think have tended to focus on
commercial breeding and the conditions
of the breeding industry and while
certainly tips and techniques have been
shared like you guys have pivoted them
you know amongst you anecdotes and
responses
I think it's a definitely a good time to
have an episode dedicated to
practicalities of seed making and
reading a little bit especially for the
people at home or in smaller spaces
yeah a lot of a lot of what we've done
is more specific to people that have
already like maybe memorized marijuana
botany you know like it's already
already more advanced what we talk about
in the the techniques and specifics so a
lot of people have talked about like
they would like something more basic
just a a quick intro on just seed making
in general a lot of the basics have been
totally skipped over left out and
there's not really anyone covering them
or in one spot so yeah
yeah this will be fun yeah
without further Ado I think we can jump
in
making seeds with regular plants and I
think the first distinction I wanted to
make was
you know obviously before you get into
something like this there's a little bit
of time planning involved because there
are timing constraints absolutely
so for some people
it's about lining up their males and
females so that they're both ready at
the right time like that the pollen
donors already and that the uh the
females are ready to receive at the
right time and then there's another
group of people who are interested in
collecting pollen storing it you know
what it takes to store
um and you know retain viability on the
pollen so maybe the first question is
um
how do you stagger males and females if
you're trying to line them up so one of
the questions we have is actually from
Lily from our Discord okay and Lily is
trying wanting to do an open pollination
on some of those AK packs yeah yeah
um
they do not want to collect pollen they
do not want to dust they just want to
let it rip so yeah how would they
stagger
males and females so the best way to
stagger males and females the only time
that really needs to be done or
considered is if you're Crossing like a
short flowering female to a long
flowering male say or vice versa like
that most of the time males will flower
and there's not really any staggering
needed if it's the same exact strain and
they're all flowering at about the same
exact time the only time it really needs
to happen is when you've got an Afghani
um Afghani type let's say female or and
like a haze male you know or uh vice
versa let's say a haze female in an
Afghani male The Afghani male will be
done flowering you know eight to nine
weeks whereas that Haze Mill or the haze
female might not even start flowering
until like week seven to where there's
any kind of uh stigmatic production
so that's the only time it really needs
to be taken into account staggering is
usually a feminized breeding
that that comes into play
okay well that's cool because you
answered the second question which was
from little Kevin in the hood who who is
talking about how do you deal with lung
flowering plants
is the approach to staggering still the
same yeah like I guess like if you sort
of answer that but yeah I mean it you
know I mean you have to know
it's a lot harder when you don't know
the lines that you're working with and
you're just like making crosses to see
what happens
how to stagger because you don't know
exactly at what point the the female or
male whatever it whatever case it may be
we don't know when it's going to start
flowering and when it's gonna end
flowering and producing whatever you
need it to
um yeah so it does help to have some
kind of knowledge if you know roughly
how long it flowers and trying to go off
you know seed making seed makers
descriptions on flowering can be really
hit or miss so if you're trying to cross
two totally different types and don't
really know I do recommend a run without
doing it just to see how long they
flower so that you're not wasting and
blowing the whole run on one you can't
use or you know just a whole Mist that
you have to wait till next round to
follow me to female
um no great advice
Okay so now in terms of the people who
are interested in
um perhaps collecting and then storing
pollen I guess the first question is you
know when do you collect how do you
collect
to begin with
so what I like to do is use what people
call trim bins
um they used to be called pollen
collectors I think back in the day but
essentially it's what people have or
it's a bin and then on the bottom and
then there's another bin that sits
inside it with a screen on the bottom
yeah and essentially people will trim
over it and the trichomes fall and
suppose you know you scrape up the hash
in the bottom but with males what we
like to do is let them hang over the
edge kind of roll it gently roll them
over the the screen and the reason I
like using this method is because the
Petals of the male don't fall through to
the the pollen below the the actual
powder the actual pollen and when you
collect it you're not having to scrape
out a whole lot of male parts I mean you
might see one or two that you have to
pick out because when you go to then
store this pollen you don't have male
parts with a bunch of moisture in them
damaging the pollen or molding and
essentially killing the pollen when you
store it so that's the best method I
found for collecting pollen and and
screening it all in one like in one Fell
Swoop otherwise you know you can collect
it and then you've got to sift out the
male part slowly and there's all there's
all sorts of way people have done it you
know like you know putting bags around
males once they're ready to collect you
know put a big bag around a branch and
tie it off and beat it around so they
got it you know take that dump that on
some kind of string sift it there's all
sorts of different ways people have done
it but the the best method for me is
that method
um and we're actually coming back to
some of those questions about like yeah
bagging branches and stuff and or back
you know isolating the whole plant yeah
I'm in terms of in terms of timing
um when when do you collect the pollen
it's just when the sex are open you know
yeah you want to have
so
when you flower a male you'll notice
that certain sacks will open early now
there is like breeding theory on and I
think some of it is just like based on
experience as opposed to scientific
theory on in cannabis on you know the
pollen that opens the earliest is a
different color than the pollen that
opens later you know though there's
theories that the more mature pollen is
so much better to use than the the
earlier flowering less mature pollen
um I've never noticed a major difference
in all of that usually any pollen that
starts dropping I collect into the trim
bin and slowly collect it over time and
then sift it all together that's usually
how I do it but some people are very
fastidious and say like oh no I only
collected after a certain point the
other stuff I just let draw you know
don't collect at all but I've never had
really any issues with that or seen any
notable difference
yeah okay so earlier I think you
uh you you mentioned that moisture
obviously is is one of the key things
you're trying to
um avoid and so in terms of storing
pollen for it to remain viable for as
long as possible you know what are your
suggestions some morass was asking
um
yeah how do you store it how long can
pollen remain viable for should I cut
with corn flour like some people
recommend
um
so I don't like cutting with anything
like I don't see a reason to do that
some people think that it um like weighs
down the pollen makes it all better or I
you know there's all sorts of different
reasons people cut pollen that I've
heard over the years but I've never
found a good reason for it
um with pollen storage I also don't have
a super good answer on on how long it
stays viable because I've seen it stay
viable a year without being stored and
just living in you know like air vents
in a house but I've also seen people
intentionally store it really well in a
freezer and a month later it's dead
um and that's without any kind of visual
contamination
so it's really hard to say there's no
guarantees when it comes to pollen one
on how long it'll stay viable there's
just no guarantees on that
um me and a few other breeders in our
group
um don't like to store pollen in the
first place because when we go to use it
we've had so many bad experiences over
the years with like just it not taking
or not being as consistent you know
after it sits for a month that it's not
really worth storing
over time so I don't have really great
recommendations other than to say the
way that we've tried it and that you
know making sure all of the pedals like
whether people realize it or not there
are pedals on the male flower if you
look at it real close it's a it's a male
flower you know that hangs down the
petals are put are opened up and that's
what the stuff falls out of now those
little parts that open up that's not
pollen that's a part of the petals and
we do not collect that so that's like
one of the most important things that I
see most errors made are that people let
petals in their pollen now when they
scrape it up and you could put it in
like a black film container like the old
um photography film canisters are
perfect
um anything dark you don't want any
light getting to it light destroys
pollen and moisture destroys pollen so
you you know you put it in that seal it
up put it in the freezer put it inside
of two you know freezer bag tight uh
Ziploc baggies throw that in the freezer
and um row your dice is about your best
bet when it comes to pollen storage you
know I've seen people sell it and I've
also heard nightmares about the
customers you've watched sold pollen
that's been stored x amount of months
you know and sent by a male
um if you're gonna do that just beware
Paul and you know it's it's very Hit or
Miss very Hit or Miss is that a recent
thing people selling pollen or is that
no has been going for a while Lauren
it's more recent I mean the past maybe
three or four years I started seeing it
pop up and I just because most people
know like that have been making seeds
how unviable stored pollen can be and
how unpredictable so it wasn't really
like a market but now that more people
are trying to make seeds and don't
really have any knowledge about it
they're more susceptible to buying it
you know I've seen right so yeah
yeah another kind of uh Ploy yes 100
okay
yeah 100 yeah
um I guess well just what we're talking
about uh storing pollen and all that and
you kind of mentioned obviously you've
had quite a bit of experience with this
like do you have any do you have any
funny stories about storing pollen or
like pollen fails or
um I've seen I've seen
oh [ __ ] I've seen pollen cut with
cornstarch and have weevils pop up in it
that was pretty gross
um you know I'd like I just mostly the
stories are like pollen storage it looks
fine you go to dust it and you know it's
it's something you're really relying on
like a lot of times when we would store
pollen it would be feminized pollen
reverse pollen because one it's a pain
in the ass to do two it's never assured
that it's gonna drop no matter what
spray you're using or technique you're
using it's never a shirt it's gonna drop
three it's never sure it's going to be
viable so when you get it you know it's
viable a lot of times you treat that
like gold and want to store it but the
problem is like when we've gone back and
used it we have to wait you know
four days a week to see if it took and
usually that's during Prime dusting time
and we'll get into what prime dusting
time is yes we will and
if that doesn't take then you're also
back a week on Prime dusting time and
you have to either hope that you have
other pollen somewhere another you know
a plan b or your crop is now going to be
sensimia that's been dusted by unviable
pollen you probably don't
you know it's just yeah one of those
things yeah
then again some people say they smoke
pollen so there is that too
what that's the thing yeah yeah I heard
the other day about someone saying that
they got oh I think it was the zomia guy
was talking about some guy gets the
pollen and puts it in his mouth and like
uses it like medicine like choose it
I mean I think someone was joking in the
survey the other day about getting
tricking people and doing lines a bit I
mean oh yeah
I think that was um on csi's post when I
was trying to tell people they should do
lines of it
that was me that was
yeah
I'm trying to trick people into doing
lines of pollen yeah I've seen that done
too that is the most hideous horrid like
sinus infection you can ever get is is
uh snorting pollen I would imagine yeah
don't kids at home don't do that do not
start Pawn if what there's no drugs in
it there's no it's just gonna make you
sneeze a lot and probably give you an
infection
the post was about the post in in
reference to it was um CSI asking you
know he's heard about people smoking
their males what do you people think
about this and I said everybody knows
that you snort the males and only
dummies smoke
foreign
but yeah no there were people chiming in
saying yeah I always smoke my meals yeah
they're heady and I'm like I get that
there are resin glands on some males not
in prodigious amounts some have them in
prodigious amounts and I tend to think
those are more intersex type males and
not males that you'd want to be using
anyways
um but the ones that have some resin I
guess maybe people can smoke like the
those petals but I can't imagine smoking
pollen for any reason at all
I mean yeah I know we're not really
going to talk so much about selections
today but it is interesting right the
whole process is like
because it's so opaque people have to
people come up with like all kinds of
strange like almost like divinatory yeah
that's what it is it is trying to make
these selections like I cast my rooms
and yeah I mean because you have to
start somewhere and there's no real
defined way to start because you don't
know what you have until you run the
progeny and that's really all that boils
down to so people have come up with all
these methods they think or Voodoo yeah
like you said you know like read the
bones read the Stars you know yeah
okay well okay coming back to this
process of making seeds and you already
you already gestures towards this when
do you when do you want to pollinate
your females and how Okay so this is a a
good good one to use like a rule of
thumb for all females no matter when
they're flowering
you want to pollinate them when when
their hairs are the most white right
when they have the most white hairs
everywhere is when you want to pollinate
them the second you see the hair start
to die off that is a non-receivable
point for pollen that means that hair
can no longer receive pollen and trans
you know transport the the seed into the
ovule or whatever's going on I don't
know the the technicality of it I'm
trying to make it seem more human but
that's not really what's happening
obviously but yes that's that's that's
technically what's going on the hair
receives the pollen the pollen grain
pollinates the embryo right here forums
and the bract and then you know
um so if the hair is dead it can't
receive pollen therefore that bract
cannot make seeds so you want it to be
where the ultimately where it has the
most white hairs living without any died
off that is the perfect point for
pollination at all times no matter what
sometimes that can be a 13 weeks flower
you know Malawi's hazes whatever
um sometimes it could be at 20 weeks
flour on some of that stuff and
sometimes it can be week five week six
sometimes it's week four
um it really just depends on the line
you're running but overall the rule of
thumb is the most white hair is the
least amount of brown hairs
yeah yeah that makes a lot of sense okay
so in terms of like the actual method of
pollination like I mentioned earlier I
guess we uh obviously you know you can
just have your plants in the same room
your males and females and just let them
go but I guess uh some of these
questions are more about
uh for lack of a better term like
partial or isolated pollination
techniques like so dudeness mentioned
yeah small pollen runs and applying with
brushes morass was like yeah you know
pollinate can you pollinate one branch
and let the rest of the plant flower you
know that kind of thing
um can you abuse even was like oh can
you can you brush
multiple pollen sources multiple
yeah yeah yeah
um and you know what are the risks there
so yeah variety of questions about
brushing on and so the logic of this the
logic of this is presupposing that you
have a completely opposite and distant
storage place for males
because if you're doing isolated
pollinations you do not want any chance
for any of these males to flower in the
same building as your your receivers and
I guess that also kind of um
gets down to pollen isolation I don't
know if you want to talk about that
first maybe before we discuss that well
I I thought maybe we would have a whole
section on the different isolation
techniques and so maybe here you're just
gonna broad stroke but I don't know if
that makes sense yeah I mean
pollen isolation methods there is no
good pollen isolation method in my
opinion
so that's a broad stroke of it like okay
if you're gonna try to do isolated
pollinations in
a small environment I wouldn't
if all you have is if all you have is
like a tent or maybe even two tents in
the same house even if they're across
the room
it would be very hard to pull off a
plant flowering
and I'm thinking about like a house with
central air maybe pull off a plant
flowering and and a male flowering
because pollen is so fine and so light
and travels so microscopically that it
is very very hard and I always go back
to this case in point
I did my blue bonnet pollinations at a
big at like a 5 000 square foot house
okay and in the back is where I did the
Polish the furthest back room you could
possibly do
uh in the front of this place I had a
whole nother room isolated with the big
tent and I was like okay so I did the
pollination and this is I did the Blue
Bonnet pollination a year prior a year a
whole freaking year prior and I did it
open in that back bedroom so this next
one I was going to do in a tent I wasn't
doing a pollination I was going to do a
sensimilla run and
that run inside of a tent with a carbon
scrubber on the outside
still got blue bonnet pollen from a year
prior from the uh the air vents and
ducting which I did the only place I
didn't clean was my my central air
got pollinated like it was a decent
pollination of of a tent separated with
a carbon scrubber inside the same house
in a completely separate room so for an
example that's how easy it is and it
wasn't just kind of pollinate it wasn't
just a few seeds it was enough to do
it was enough to get a look inside stuff
like you know like 500 seeds of plant
like a lot
um not a lot but I mean enough to where
it wasn't just a grain here or a grain
there it was a serious contamination and
it would ruin a sensimilla run
completely
um so when trying to do like these
isolated pollen runs it is best if you
have some way to store your mail at a
completely different location that's the
only time I would say I would attempt
any kind of isolated pollen introduction
no it's really fascinating and actually
we have a bunch of different questions
on like different possible ways of
isolating so maybe we actually will come
back to this I reckon and for now why
don't we just assume we have some pollen
we will we won't mention how but pollen
for now okay and
given and if we skip the contamination
issue yes if you have some pollen yeah
and you did want to say try to just do
one branch or like you know different
branches with different kinds of pollen
like
how well does that work in and of itself
so I mean yeah people have done it very
effectively over the years as long as
the the males were kept separate and
introduced you know one by one a lot of
times what people will do instead of
just so there's a few techniques there's
the bagging technique bagging technique
a which would be to have a bag and a lot
they make pollen bags specifically for
this that let air breathe but not
they're so tight that the pollen can't
escape that's supposedly the theory I
haven't ever used these things but
that's that's how they supposedly work
and they I've seen it work
um and you put this over the branch that
that you're wanting to pollinate so you
insert the branch into this bag you tie
it off and then you kind of agitate it
um you know you you let that sit a few
days you take it off you blow down the
plant with some water you know what I
mean you don't want to mold the plant
obviously but you want to wash it off so
the pollen isn't viable and hitting
other branches that's the theory of
washing it off and uh yeah that's one
method another method is to tie off all
branches
and then do that one branch
Undo It spray it off with water and then
undo all the other branches but that
obviously opens you up to more molding
if you're doing every single Branch even
though that there's air Exchange in
these bags there's still a chance to
bring in bold you know
uh yeah that's another method and it's
it's doable you know some people like to
introduce
um pollen via brushes but brush I mean
you've got to remember pollen's tiny
when you're using these brushes brushes
even if you don't see it some of these
bristles will click and it'll flick for
sure and if things aren't tied off
everywhere like using those bags or
other kind of bags it's going to flick
onto other branches I mean this is light
stuff so it's just a really it's just
like anything the more care you take the
more time you take the more accurate you
can be when it comes to stuff like that
as long as your male is somewhere else
if your male is in the same room again
or in the same house it's very hard to
contain and but
I mean there's ways to do everything
you know it just this time patience
money you know pot they make pollen
chambers of money you know if you have
the money for a real true isolation
chamber that would be great but I don't
know anybody who has those
yeah
so so going back to Boo's question on
like which seems now to me given what
you've said like quite ambitious which
is like you dust different branches with
different pollen
um which you can do it but I imagine
again there's like a decent risk that
your branches across yes
cross-pollinated right yeah I mean
there's a good chance that there will be
some cross-contamination like well um
yeah pretty high
um but if if you're doing that you're
only getting a small amount of seeds
anyways if you're doing Branch you know
Branch style pollinations and it's just
for most likely just for you or your
friends to look at so yeah
cross-contamination thing probably there
isn't as important because it's mostly
just for people to get a look at their
stuff if you're doing if you're if
you're like selling Branch made seeds
then you should probably start like
having a serious talk with yourself
about like
is this really what I think it is you
know do some
you know personal bias confrontation is
this really isolated as much as I think
it is and should I sell this is it a
decent representation of what I want to
sell
yeah this is where your personal ethics
and morals come into play I guess
absolutely yeah
yeah okay all right so
um was there anything else you wanted to
say on the actual Act of pollinating
um
so usually it takes anywhere from three
days to a week to watch the pollen take
so watch to know that the pollen has
taken and usually the way we know that
is that the hair dye's off yeah usually
it and and if it's not just one or two
it's several where you pollinated
then you know it's taking the pollens
viable but usually that three days to a
week is like breath holding time it's
the worst especially if you're doing
reversals you are like on pins and
needles holding your breath every time
me and inspect us yes I are like
you know like every time you know oh my
it worked you know we're bubbling
holding our breath for each other's
reversals because something this is hard
and and it's very expensive to fail and
it's very it's very expensive very
demoralizing to fail you know like to
have something look really good form
balls you know like do all that get to
the process and just and drop pollen and
then it's not viable that's
brutal
yeah because I guess it's like quite a
long gamble right you obviously you have
to grow the plants and like get the
pollen do all the stuff and it doesn't
work
and in our cases it's not just one plant
that we're reversing we're reversing
many to try to beat the odds of um of
you know sterile pollen or Paul pollen
or balls not forming you know what I
mean because that can happen too even if
it's the same clone of the same thing in
the same tray in a micro climate you can
have three not Flip or you know three
totally flip not drop pollen and seven
totally flip and drop pollen or vice any
of those numbers could switch around so
it's like we're not even doing just one
we're doing several you know so it is a
big undertaking and a big gamble for
sure
yeah and we're gonna come back to
reversal specifically
um after this okay okay so
um if you're happy we can move on to you
know when will seeds be ready and how do
you collect seeds and how do you store
seeds you know for long-term viability
so for a long time viability and storage
seeds there is a small process it's not
as simple as make the seeds pluck them
out and sell them right away
um or maybe before you get into that
like when when do you even like oh okay
uh when I see it's ready so if I'm like
explaining this to someone who has never
harvested seeds before how do they know
when their seats are ready without
chopping their whole plant I'm just
hoping
so there's always a few methods that I
use
and first you want to look at the tops
usually you can see in the tops where
the light hits the strongest you can see
if there is brown sticking out of the
tops right and then you know if you're
if you have some mature seeds at the top
usually if you're seeing Brown seeds
poking out that means that those seeds
at the top are fully mature this is
where a lot of people make the mistake
of chopping their plant and just being
done letting it you know dry out and
then finding out that most of the seeds
are immature because the the seeds at
the top with the most light tend to be
the most mature the fastest what I like
to do is go to the the bottom of the
plants and I'm not talking about the
armpits because the armpits I forgot
what they're called the primordial seeds
I believe they're called that form in
the armpit area of the seeds or of the
plants those almost always form real
healthy ripe and are done fast
interesting yeah but yeah but the the
seeds in like a bottom Bud getting the
least amount of light those are the ones
that interest me because when those are
done and if they're done in multiple
locations on the bottom of the plant
that's usually a good
uh predictor of the rest of the plant
now usually I'll do like four spots on
the bottom four spots on the middle four
spots on the top and if all of them are
coming out nice and mature then that's
when I start to harvest uh otherwise if
there's any immature in there I'll give
it another week I don't even look at it
I'll give it a whole other week and just
come back to it later but that's that's
usually the best predictor go down to
those bottom nugs and check those check
the maturity and when I'm talking about
maturity there's a few things also when
it comes to seeds
um there's there's the seed string if
you're able to uh put it in your fingers
and not crush it immediately with just a
good amount of pressure like right away
that's a good sign that there is is um
viability to the seed if you could drop
it on a hard surface and you hear a
sound like a ping like a a specific
sound that's a good sign it means that
there's weight and heft to the Sea
there's probably an embryo in there
that's viable and the look of course but
the look is is something that a lot of
people don't get like tiger stripes a
lot of us use seed blowers now and that
can blow that that thin layer that tiger
stripe layer is a thin layer and that
can be blown off just by using these
blowers and and agitating the seeds and
knocking them against each other in the
blowers the best the best predictor is
usually color look the tiger stripes but
not all seeds have tiger stripes either
a lot of Southeast Asians are pure black
a lot of Mexicans are pure black seeds
Sometimes some are just hard gray you
know like a dark gray
um but the best predictor is the heft
and the touch for me and and and knowing
that you know the rest of the seeds are
mature in the plant right like that's
important
um
yeah
oh go ahead
oh I just want to ask like uh in terms
of you know scanning the lower you know
lower branches and nodes as well as the
the higher ones closer to the light
there's I assume based on what you're
saying that there's no risk of leaving
them too long like the the ones that
mature more quickly it's okay to for
them to be left
um
as long as your humidity isn't too high
because I have seen people leave seeds
in their plants too long and have them
germinate inside the plants I've seen
that yeah it looks freaky as [ __ ] it
looks like an alien plant like with a
you know the tail sticking out of the
buds as opposed to white hairs it looks
so freaky but that's the only time that
there's ever really a big risk um seeds
store well in cannabis a lot of things
the times we found like
um if we leave seeds inside Bud even if
they're like in a hot garage it's been
you know 114 the whole summer for
whatever reason staying inside that bud
it protects it better than almost
anything else other than fridge or
freezer so that's something to keep in
mind too it's a great storage technique
so you're not really hurting your plant
by the seed staying in there longer
they don't get overly mature unless
unless your humidity is way too high and
you just need to check the humidity if
that's going on
no that's a great point and yeah great
great points also on all those different
ways of checking for maturity
um
so you did you did just mention this but
how about storage now okay so storage
um after you harvest your seeds one of
the things that we like to do like at
least in our group is to well first you
want to dry them out fully for two weeks
I set them out in like a Ramekin tray I
let them dry out for two weeks full I
want them to be totally dry no nothing
on them and then I'll take those I'll
put them in a freezer Ziploc bag I keep
specifying this because freezer are
stronger or thicker millim Mills I guess
they call it for plastic thicker Mills
the freezer bag by Ziploc or whoever as
long as it's a really thick protective
layer on the baggie I put them in those
I put them in another one just to ensure
that no moisture can get in and then I
toss them in the fridge or freezer
either one for me doesn't really matter
I like fridge
um for for the first run and I'll throw
them in the fridge for another two weeks
and that simulates the process of winter
like when seeds are dropped from the
plant naturally and they kind of bury
themselves underground they stay cold
for the whole winter when it gets hot
then they germinate that's the idea we
want these things to germinate the first
second that they are warm and in
moisture and by going by pushing it
through that fridge process it makes
them germinate very fast after like even
if it's a year after two years after it
just that process is ready for whatever
reason
yeah yeah
um again for fun storage fails ending
stories anecdotes oh my God we missed
anything weird oh my God so there are
very few breeders I know that
um initially started out by buying seeds
and storing them in a fridge most of us
learn that the hard way
and like I went through a whole summer
in San Diego that was just the most
brutal summer up to that point ever I
remember moving there from Bakersfield
and thinking why did I move here for
climate when it's just as hot as
Bakersfield and granted the temperature
wasn't the same but because it was right
on the beach downtown and all that like
right at the harbor downtown it was
insanely hot there so hot that summer
and it cooked almost my whole collection
of seeds just because I didn't have a
fridge to store them in straight fridge
storage is so important and it's like I
said some people prefer freezer I prefer
freezer for long term if I know I'm not
going to be taking seeds in and out if
it's something that I'm like like I like
to collect land races from around the
world and I put those in a bag and I
store those in the freezer and I don't
take them in and out to look at them
they're just in there you know and and
that's for a rainy day that's you know
10 20 years down the line when I have a
big climate Outdoors where I feel like
they'll be able to be grown best to
express the best so I can see what I
have
um but most of the time if I'm taking
something in and out fridge is good
fridge is good I don't like rapid
drastic temperature fluctuations from
you know below freezing to room
temperature within an hour probably
wouldn't be that good for them so I like
doing uh fridge for in and out you know
if I'm taking stuff in and out
repeatedly my fridge storage is just so
important if you can find any room in
your guys fridge for your collections or
if you can afford to run another fridge
specifically for some of the bigger
collections it'll be helping the future
you'll be helping yourself I've watched
seeds lose viability in five years
without any kind of heat damage
um I've watched them to stay viable for
15 plus years because of fridge you know
and easy to pop so I again
I can't emphasize how many of us have
lost whole collections by not fridge
storing it is so important
yeah yeah good points and I you did
mention this but I wanted to draw a bit
more attention to it if you have used
the freezer
um do you have to pay attention to um if
you're taking them out to actually
germinate
um that transition um in temperature I
Like to Move It from the freezer to the
fridge for a day the fridge yeah but you
know I know people that have taken them
out of the freezer to room temperature
and pop them just fine it's just one of
those things where I just like logically
in my head it makes sense to not push
that fluctuation a whole bunch well
you're trying to reduce as much risk as
possible yeah reduce the risk and shock
to the to the embryos because they are
small little things
yeah my little living things
yeah okay well in terms of the so we
started this section as it was about
regular seed making and we yeah I wanted
to take us through a fairly linear
sequence of steps which we did do
um so I was thinking at this point we
could kind of go parallel and and and
talk about reversals so I guess here
you've already talked about you know
when to pollinate collecting seeds all
that so we don't have to go over that
again uh maybe here we're just talking
about you know applying the reversal
chemicals or spray you know how how does
that work maybe you could talk about the
different approaches with different
chemicals a bit we don't have to go too
deep but yeah just so people have an
idea maybe we start with someone who has
your reversal spray
how's that work
one second mom decided to bug
in the moms
okay
so with reversals
um like let's say someone went to my
site purchased my spray but doesn't
really know the one thing I would say is
pay attention to what size you're buying
because we have our medium and our large
they both come in the same size bottle
16 ounces but
one the the medium is more dilute than
the large
essentially to save water weight like
we're only adding water to one to ship
it to you know to add it to large it
would have been 64 more ounces or water
or whatever it is
um so pay attention to the ratio mixing
that to water it's super important if
you get the ratio wrong it can cause a
reversal failure you need to have the
ratios correct pay attention to that
large is one to eighteen medium is one
to nine small is one to nine uh one part
of the solution the stock solution is
what what we sell to uh nine Parts water
or 18 Parts water uh when they get it
the the idea is to you know make your
spray I assume people are going to put
it in 60 16 or 32 ounce bottle you know
mix it up shake it really well my spray
is a silver nitrate sodium thiosulfate
base in their solution so you want to
mix it really well it's already been
thoroughly mixed but when you get it
it's sat for a while Shake It Up really
really well and you know on the
instructions we used to say you know
spray once a day to ensure a reversal
because if you spray daily your plant
will reverse some plants like it more
only once a week some plants you only
need to spray once every two weeks and
they'll reverse just fine some plants
need it once a day for three and a half
weeks specifically and it usually at
three and a half weeks like on the money
you will see signs of a sex reversal
some kind of sexual uh like
um usually because what people don't
realize when you're doing reversal
you're not turning a female or not
turning a female into a male you're
making a female have male parts
and by doing that it's going to maintain
that female floral structure so the male
parts won't form and hang in the armpits
like they normally would on a male it's
forming in a strong tight budge Bud
cluster and usually with failures what
happens is it clusters too tight and
they can't mature they can't like
stretch out get their anthers out and
open up and you know fully mature uh so
some of that is from probably spraying
too much as best we can tell so in cases
like those you want to turn it down to
like what spring once a week or once
every two weeks with that said when
you're doing reversals by this point you
should know the plant you're reversing
You Should Know It real well and you
should expect the first reversal to be a
learning process not a one and done I'm
going to bang this out who's successful
because you have to learn the plant and
how it's going to reverse you have to
know any number of factors and like I
said I always recommend doing like a
tray of them because one is really hard
to learn from
you know when you can learn from 12 of
the same clone and see how each of these
clones of the same clone interact with
the spray from which angles and light
sources you get a lot more data from
that than you would one plant that
either
reverses correctly or fails so yeah I
often recommend that
um yeah you know like on a successful
reversal the the the
buds of male flowers will form they'll
open up and just like a male you'll be
able to slap the side of it and pollen
will fly that's what you want in a
successful reversal there's a lot of
times where it'll form in that cluster
and you see that they're open up and you
see you know you'll pick one of those
out of that tight little cluster and
you'll put in your hand and you'll see
pollen and you know it'll flatten out
and then you realize oh God I gotta grab
tweezers and each one of these and drop
it into the trim again and no [ __ ] this
is like I would say at least half of the
reversals go this way right where it's a
tedious process of taking each of these
pedals or each of these floral
structures
or you know you drop them all in there
and slowly agitate them and knock the
pollen out over the screen but a lot of
them are like that a lot are like that
so expect to do one or the other a
successful reversal where we're who
that's when you just kind of cap it in
it and that happens
um but a lot of time expect to be doing
the tweezer method
yeah yeah so different degrees of
success I guess we could say exactly
exactly and there's nothing's
predictable no matter what like like I
said whether you're using a silver
nitrate sodium thiosulfate base whether
you're using a silver nitrate uh Cobalt
green base whether you're using just
um what else is there silver
colloidal silver whether you're using
that it's all the same process on the
same Bud trying to trying to have the
ethylene blocking action because that's
what's going on that's what we're trying
to achieve and
um produce intersex trades
okay so uh another basic question
um when do you even start applying the
spray okay oh no that's a that's a
really good question because I think
it's one of the most often asked and
I've seen people like spray you know
while the plants in veg thinking that
might help the idea with spraying is you
want to First you in your brain you you
need to make a clear division
um you need to make a clear division
between
um
the the receivers and the donors that's
super super important in your mind that
has to be made because when you're doing
a reversal let's say you have 60 plants
you're not doing a 60 plant reversal
like if some of those have to receive
the plan you know as you receive the
following so in your mind figure out
what you want to be the receivers and
what you want to be the donors and
donors are being the plants that you
will spray that's that's how we Define
so you want to you want to mentally
separate the uh the male donors from the
receivers and you want to take the male
donor the plants that will be male the
donors and you want to put them in a
separate lighting environment maybe even
a tent or another room and you want to
initiate flower whether that's putting
it into 1212 for you whether that's 11
13 whether that's 10 14 whatever flower
is to you
um you want to initiate flour and on
that first day that you initiate flour
to the plants you're spraying you want
to spray on that first day
and that's when you'll start counting
three and a half weeks from to where you
should expect to start seeing balls now
that's not always a guaranteed thing
either sometimes plants will show in two
weeks sometimes they'll show in you know
three weeks but almost always by week
three and a half they're showing no
matter how long they flower any of it
they'll always show some sort of sexual
reversal within three and a half weeks
using my spray specifically
um yeah but yeah you want to keep them
in a separate lighting source and you
initiate flower on the day and you start
spraying on the day you initiate flour
for those plants and usually when you're
doing reversals you want a
a anywhere from one week to two and a
half to three week staggering period of
introducing females into the room with
it so sometimes
um depending on when that pollen will
drop so let's say after
you've been spraying it for for 21 days
or so okay so this is three weeks in
I'll start introducing some of the
females in right now to start catching
the pollen because at about week four or
five if I'm using like an Afghani type
or a nine week flowering plant a week
four or five we want those to be
catching the pollen from this plant that
is just about to start kicking the
pollen so what about week three it takes
about three four five weeks depending on
the plant
for it to do that
and you just don't know uh exactly where
it's going to be or when it's going to
fire off so we'd like to stagger some in
a week some after two weeks some after
two and a half weeks just to
mitigate the odds everything is an odds
game when it comes to reversal that's
what you've learned it's like gambling
and it's yeah it is
yeah yeah almost feels like every stage
has a different I mean it does every
every stage has a different element of a
gamble right yeah
um and that's why it used to kill me
like for years when me and Rascal and a
few others with only Americans doing
reversals and people like the first
thing you can say is that's a shortcut
that's cheating man that's a shortcut
and that's cheap and it's like dude you
have no clue how much of a short this is
so much more labor intensive space
intensive like emotional than anything
like I would I would choose using a male
all day over reversing if I had my
druthers and the tools were correct like
the plants were correct for what I want
to achieve I would prefer to use a mill
over reversals just because of how much
easier it is
just the emotions like of loss and like
failures suck it's brutal I've seen so
many people quit so many people quit
like the whole business over over
reversal failures because it's just
devastating financially and emotionally
like it's hard for some people
it really reminds me and this is kind of
a bizarre like Assad but it I used to
enjoy watching these different shows on
like either people who were metal
detectorists or like gold hunters and
you kind of see the kind of the
psychological
um game that they have to play with
themselves where they're like okay we've
invested all this money on this patch of
grounds we've got all this equipment
here
God please I hope we find something yeah
right it costs x amount of money to rent
this equipment yeah Etc yeah the time
everything if I broke down how like yes
I does it and like
that he still pays you know certain
certain folks when rooms don't reverse
like people are still having to be paid
and whatnot like it is a huge expense it
is a massive expensive failure like it's
okay when it's just me and piddling
around in my place but if I have like
seven satellite locations that people
need to be paid at or what have you
um because they live there and it's
their electricity and whether the
reversal works or not they still have to
pay their electricity and for their time
that's when it becomes a serious uh
business choice you know because that
can add up super fast
yeah yeah yeah so I guess those of you
who are like not not doing this
commercially
um be thankful in that sense well I mean
again and it goes to to what's going on
in the community that people are seeing
with their eyeballs on you know this is
June 28 2023 when we're recording this
but um the the the climate you know
politically as far as cannabis goes like
the seed makers are dropping out real
fast a lot of people are folding up shop
and going into some other skill that
they have because weed ain't doing it
cannabis isn't doing it seed making
isn't bringing the money
um you know you're going to start seeing
a lot less Femme seed makers in America
because of how much it costs to fail and
probably seen a lot more Spanish
production of Femme seeds um being sold
by American breeders uh pretending
they're their own
essentially that's my opinion
yeah
hot take
no it's good and actually there
I don't know if we have those questions
in for this episode but maybe for
another episode there are it's not like
breeding politics it's not something you
guys have approached you guys obviously
talked about bringing politics a lot but
I think someone had a question that was
like and where I don't think we're gonna
answer right now but I was like okay so
what's the difference between like a
seed maker and a breeder and like what
are these breeders doing who are like
Outsourcing and yeah yeah um we yeah
that's a whole show in itself yeah it is
yeah okay okay so we've just covered
reversals and I'm wondering is this a
good time to kind of like gesture
towards seed making with autoflowers now
I know that you mentioned to me earlier
before this started that like
if we're going to talk breeding Autos
that's like a whole thing right yeah
because it's very heavily selection
involved all that yeah but if we were
just focusing on the C making part like
this was just a one-step thing
um what what are the differences if you
were making seeds before it is so the
biggest thing to take into consideration
with auto flowers I think a lot of
people are it's appealing to people
first that are new Growers because of
the light cycle it's one thing one
variable they can take out of the
equation
that like to people who have been
growing for a long time it seems silly
to worry about the light hours because
that's done by a timer you know but like
oh that seriously that's a major
consideration people take
um another consideration people take
with autoflowers I think is that it's
being sold to them that it's going to be
flowering faster than other plants and
that it's equally as dank to other
plants so they the only trade-off they
think in their mind is going to be the
light hours
right
uh when making seeds with other flowers
one thing you take it you have to take
into account you can't clone autoflowers
that's their biggest downside if you
find a keeper in seeds your best bet is
to have already
made be making seeds with it you know at
that point because you can't clone it
um it's not like something you can
easily Rive Edge because once it's
flowering it's flowering and that's that
so it's a major downside to autoflowers
that you can't keep a clone and breed
with it so a lot of times people are
just flowering them out and making the
seeds the first gun you know now if you
want to make seeds with autoflowers
without going into the breeding aspect
and let's just say you want to make
seeds make more seeds of autoflowers
make sure you're Crossing an Autoflower
to an Autoflower do not try to cross
like an Autoflower line to like some
photo period which only Auto Growers
call things photo periods so if you call
things photo period you're calling
yourself out also yeah but you don't
want to use like pollen from a regular
mail onto an auto female or vice versa a
regular female being pollinated by an
auto male because what you're going to
get is a pretty wild distribution of of
photo period and auto flowering mixed in
you're not going to have a fully
Autoflower line so if you're going to
make more seeds of an Autoflower cross
an Autoflower to an Autoflower so you
don't have to worry about
it I mean I remember like there's a term
that people use which is semi-auto but
is that like have you heard that I have
heard that
um there is some stuff like let me think
of a good example Oh Betsy maybe where
it tends to heavily
pre-flower in veg meaning it's always
kind of like
flowering a little bit like it's always
it like week two so yeah there's always
some kind of stigma formation a lot of
those semi-autos you can make seeds with
in veg like if you have a male that you
know flowers in veg because a lot of
them will if they're stuck in a little
Solo Cup like once their Roots hit the
side they will immediately start
flowering and if you have some of these
you know semi-auto flowers and veg you
can technically make seeds with those in
veg under 24 hours of light it's one of
the damndest things I've ever seen so
some people like those because when you
put those semi-autos into flour they're
already like two weeks in so it's it
gets like a second stacking as it were
so some people like it for that reason I
can't think of any other reason to use
those other than trying to create a new
autoflowering line through selective
breeding because it already has that
early trigger trait which kind of you
know there is debate on whether rooteros
is a whole nother uh part or section of
cannabis or whether it is like an
Afghani that is just
has this
kind of mutant triggering trait as it
were like it's a trait
it can be bread as opposed to being a
whole nother section or type of cannabis
yeah yeah because I think I've seen the
other way I've seen semi-auto is being
marketed as like Fast flowering right
yeah that just sounds now like very
euphemistic I don't know if like they're
referring to dwarfs because there used
to be a thing called autoflowering
dwarfs and I don't really see that term
as much anymore but that was a thing
where like they would supposedly they
would be flowering from
um seed to end a flower in 60 days and
that was what was promised so a lot of
people fell for that real fast because
from seed germination to flower in 60
days is extremely fast now it was more
like 75 to 80 which was still fast
considering no veg time but
you know I mean it's not is it so far
that you're going to take a dive in the
quality
that's worth that
yeah yeah I actually don't know [ __ ]
about Autos yeah yeah they're they're
gaining popularity I think they they
didn't have any popularity in the US for
a long time when I started [ __ ] with
them and then lately it seems like that
there is a group in the U.S that are
just like hardcore autoflowering
enthusiasts which is cool like they need
someone being enthused for them I guess
sure it was big it was big in the
European home grower apartment Market
that's where it really booms
yeah and and that makes sense you know
from from that perspective okay no
really interesting
well I think for us we've kind of
covered the like the more linear seat
making
um set of questions I how do you make
seeds
um
and like I mentioned earlier there is a
whole section because people have all
these different
um questions and ideas about isolation
right and like whether you're isolating
the males I sing the pollen I sling the
pollinated branches and I think the
interesting for us to go through some of
these questions because sure you already
gestured towards the fact that you're
pretty pessimistic for example about
uh isolating your males in the same
building right yeah whether that can
work so okay let's just let's just get
into it
let's dive in so okay of course the
general question and this one is raised
by dudeness ways to avoid pollen
contamination in small areas with
turbulent airflow but okay don't answer
that one because the more specific ones
are like ones from booze setting up an
isolated space for males or donors
um you kind of did talk to this speak to
this already and I assume he means in
the same building yeah I assume so it's
like do you do it can you do it uh if
you want to try to do it you know what's
the best you could do
so I don't I wouldn't
and the best you could do would be to
have enough money to be able to buy the
right filters you know what I mean like
there's ways to do it
set it up like a tissue culture lab for
each one like a mini tissue culture set
up for each one of your males and have
all the exhaust
going way out of the house at the end
point tons of filtration but I mean it's
it would be serious a serious
undertaking to build that stuff
it'd be worth it it'd be cool to see
someone do it you know for cannabis but
it would be a serious undertaking but it
could be done you know
if you can have multiple tissue culture
labs and multiple things being studied
in different places in a tissue culture
lab there's no reason that we couldn't
pull it off with cannabis
no but if you're if you're like at home
you know what what are the what are the
chances that you'll have access or you
know zero I don't recommend it I don't
like because you people argue with me on
this all day and I know it like you know
some people think that HEPA filters are
just good enough like tent next to tent
next to tent with scrubbers on them and
in my experience like I've watched that
fail epically and the pollen was in a
central air ducting it wasn't even like
it was on the tent you know it didn't
matter
um so you're talking about even
scrubbing like both the intake and and
my exhaust right and so that still is
like infallible it's very fallible yeah
yeah because Boo's next question is like
even like an amplification of that which
is like okay multiple multiple males are
donors
um keeping them
um
because that's even worse right that's
even that's compounding it even further
it's not even saying like Okay now you
might get pollination where you don't
want it now it's like you might get
pollination from God knows which donor
or man it's gonna be a who's your daddy
yeah yeah and I've you know like the one
thing that I tell people to look out for
when assessing breeders how many males
are they using and how long did it take
for them to amass these nails and make
these lines because if they've got like
a list for example 75 males and it took
them two years to do it
that's an issue like unless you know
that they've got like this massive
massive corporate production building
somewhere where this is possible if you
know they're making seeds in their house
and then they've got 75 different males
in two years you should be very
concerned you should be very concerned
it's not possible you know
okay so if I were to like reframe this
am I right in saying that
if you if you wanna
do any kind of like seed making at all
you you should be prepared for like
ah uh how do I phrase this well
you should be prepared for everything to
get to get pollinated exactly yeah and
that's why I tell people too like
um a lot of my friends when they're just
starting talking about making seeds but
they want to still run since the Mia
production or I know they're selling
flour or what have you I always tell
them there's going to be a point of
where you're going to have to make that
distinction to be I'm either gonna only
sell seeds
or I'm only gonna sell flour because at
some point you're gonna have a whole
since Amia run get pollinated if you're
playing with the male in the same house
it's gonna happen so you need to make
that decision and I swear to God
everybody I've told this too that kind
of ignored it comes back to me later and
it's like yep you're right I had to make
that decision you know like I can't
breathe or I can't gross into me and I
had to switch to all breeding and it's
it's scary it's a scary switch going
from from uh maybe something more
something that that has been
consistently more money making for
someone to support their life to jump to
that
yeah because I mean seeds are no
guarantee that they're going to sell
you never know you cannot predict what
the Market's going to buy ever
so I guess if you
um in terms of like different degrees of
mitigation I guess like
if you're if you're just making seeds
for yourself
um
maybe the main thing then is just at
least just having
the one donor if you like say you're
just a home grower and you're trying to
make seeds for yourself just having one
meal at least at least if there's
contamination you know well you're a
pretty good guess at where it's coming
from
so yeah I mean like some people would
want to like break it down to oh well
can I keep multiple Mills of one strain
sure and you'll know what line it's from
but let's say you know you pop a seed
and you're like oh my God I want to
reproduce this which male made it yeah
you know no you can't do it you know
like that's where you're stuck unless
you just clone that one plant or if you
didn't keep clones now you're really
screwed so you you take that into
account as well
yeah yeah
and what we we had the last question on
this by I think it's sort of covered
because it the the method seems
irrelevant now but scerson was saying
you know doing the bag method for pollen
donors I assume he means either bagging
the whole plan or just begging the
um the branches it's the same right same
risks it's not going to change that same
risk it's always going to be the same
kind of thing some people do it really
well but like I said it's it's a matter
of how tedious how how good you are with
like understanding pollen control all
that some people can pull it off real
well and some people can't some people
have done it for 30 years I'm just
really can't and I'm one of the people
who probably would never even attempt it
because I know I'm a [ __ ] and I
would trip or do something stupid knock
a branch
yeah yeah okay
and I think we we kind of covered the
other forms of isolation
um in terms of like we talked earlier
about isolating the pollinated branches
themselves yeah and trying to beg those
so I think we don't have to go over
those again
um that's kind of it for this like
isolation and contamination prevention
section and at least in terms of
questions okay uh was were there any
other points you wanted to make about
isolation contamination I just want to
drive home the point that you know like
it a lot of people have this idea in
their head that you always need to have
multiple males from the same line to
preserve diversity and and granted I
don't want to go too deep into breeding
theory on this but they have this idea
that they need to use multiple males to
preserve diversity
cannabis is already a very diverse plant
if you're doing it with a line that's a
polyhybrid it's going to be diverse
whether you use multiple males or not so
just I would I would always recommend
going with one male
trying it if it doesn't work out if he
doesn't make what you like select
another meal do it again it none of this
is easy there's no shortcut there's luck
luck comes into play a lot and luck can
be a great helper but there's no quick
way to to rush through this
intentionally and and
and intentionally make lines and and
learn
if you're rushing so that's that's the
only thing I'd drive home be tedious
about pollen control
um learn about pollen and and how easy
it it transports and I think it'll make
a lot of sense when people like hear the
the HEPA Theory filter because there are
a lot of people with tents that that
make seeds that swear up and down they
can have seven reversals in their house
right next to each other because they
have HEPA filters like it blows my mind
and people just kind of believe it so
hopefully this will help some of those
people understand really what's going on
there and how small pollen truly is
um as a prompt I was curious like
what if you had you know yeah one pack
of regular seeds and you're just like
I'm just gonna let I'm just gonna let
them rip yeah um I know this is now
we're kind of edging towards like more
breeding because when you think about
open pollination obviously that implies
they're going to be further stages that
will take advantage of that in some way
but
you know you just said you recommend
just using one mail what about someone
who's just like nah I just want to let
the whole pack rip and just let them do
whatever they want
um what are the trade-offs so like the
only time I would let all males in a
room is if it's a line that needs
preserving or if I I have too few seeds
to pop and I want to look for more
that's the only time I'd recommend using
a bunch of males because when we're
doing that the intention isn't a I'm
gonna find a keeper and I want to know
who made this keeper it's right I'm
going to make more seeds and that's my
only goal is seed making at this point
it's not breeding it's making more seeds
to run through and at that point whether
you use two mils or five it doesn't
matter like to me like if you're gonna
you're going to be doing this for a
potential to run through as many as you
possibly can and at that point it's the
numbers game
yep yep no good points they make a lot
of sense
well
at this stage I think we've more or less
covered the seed making side of things
okay and this is anything else you could
think of uh with regards to just seat
making
um and not you know not working
Generations or anything not at the top
of my head no
okay well here is where we have the
opportunity to
maybe gesture towards like a bit more of
the breeding strategy side of things
okay questions from Digger and Eli Eli's
actually someone who's in a another
Discord with me and booze um
but the kind of like uh I've aggregated
the questions together right and so the
scenario is this they're home Growers
and they can't keep clones so what is
the best way to capture slash isolate
slash lockdown
um either outlying traits or an outlier
plant
yeah as a whole like man not keeping
clones
and trying to lock down traits
that it would be relying on Pure Luck
right so none of the you know none of
the typical breeding strategies will
help you necessarily with that yeah like
it I can't think of anything off the top
of my head or maybe something I'm
forgetting but like
you have to revisit a male
to use him
if
he passes on the traits you like I mean
granted you can get it right the first
time like I did with blue bonnet right
with the second round
trying to get it right a second time
is very lucky and I remember when with
the second round I was super happy
because it was so lucky usually the
second time it's like gotta go back do
it again do it again
but it's always in the process of
keeping clones with that mindset if
you're doing selective breeding you
really can't do selective breeding
without keeping clones
that's kind of a key statement here and
I don't think it would that was very
clear to me either because like you know
there's obviously this common conception
that like okay say I find one one of my
plants in this you know out of one or
two packs I love yeah um I'll just self
it
but yeah
yeah because you won't know you like it
okay I wonder okay maybe maybe here we
go breathe
okay okay okay okay all right vegging
reveging is the key
so let maybe let me let's reframe this
question so that it I think it will be
more constructive let's okay let's
pretend that either you have revenged or
where you may not have Keepers per se
you you can keep something for a couple
of runs okay
um maybe you don't have like mothers
that you're keeping for years and years
but maybe you have enough space and time
that you can keep something for a like a
shorter amount of time yeah
um
I don't know if that makes the question
easier I mean yeah I mean what if you
can keep a clone then it's just down to
selective reading and just reading for
whatever traits you want and that's it
that's like it it changes everything but
like with the Revenge example you can
get you can get creative with that
um
but you have to be able to live with
your plants in 24 hours light during one
point so you can't have like you need to
have multiple
at least two multiple at least two
spaces one for flowering one for veg
if you're not keeping moms I'm assuming
that you're probably not having a
separate veg area
by that question
and that's the point like they only have
one place to flower and veg
maybe we do assume that they have
separate spaces
um for the sake of the question well
yeah and at that point it's just yeah I
mean it's just a matter of time popping
popping what you like keep a clone of
the one you like you know
um use a male keep a clone of that if
the progeny run the progeny if the
progeny is good you have your kit you
have your kept mail then you can drop
him and go on to the next lot you know
the next failure generation and then you
know select for the same traits find a
male on that use him does it if he works
great
drop him you know after the next run or
go back pop more of the F2 go through
that
another male
pollinate it run the progeny Etc repeat
yeah does it change anything
um the fact that like
uh again unlike a commercial breeder on
a larger scale you know you have a few
plants to select from it doesn't really
change the overall strategy though right
like you're still just working with the
best of what you've got the best it's
always the best of what you've got
whether it's it's two seeds pop two
females or 300 it's always going to be
that process because when it comes to
the males they don't display traits like
the female does they're not it's not a
visual trait that we can tell that it's
going to do what we want necessarily
sometimes sometimes it's not a scent
trait maybe we're using a male for high
maybe maybe this line that this male
come from has an extremely rare high and
that's why we're trying to ease it we
only have a male from that line left you
know
um
yeah it's all it's always the same
process always the same process
yeah okay so just I just want to make
the our reframing of the question clear
because the original question was about
not being able to keep clones which kind
of does make this whole thing basically
impossible yeah um so we had to reframe
it to be like well you at least need to
be able to rerun something like a few
times for this to to work out at all
aside from revege aside from revitching
yeah yeah that would be that like the
simple answer would be re-veging would
be the the key yeah to the first
question
I mean maybe just spent a few moments
talking about reverging like is is
re-veging uh
fail proof it's not right like some
plants don't re-vege properly or do
other plants I have no issues just
reveging but I've got a pretty good
process down for it
um the idea is to make sure it has
plenty of root space one because if it
doesn't then there's all other kinds of
hormones firing off if it's you know
root bound and [ __ ] so you're trying to
deal with too many variables so make
sure it has plenty of root space if I'm
going to revege something I'm not
worried about harvesting the Bud from it
like maybe maybe I'll Harvest a tiny
amount just to smoke it and then I've
decided oh [ __ ] this is great I need to
Reve this
at that point yeah because that that's
more likely the the scenario of a home
grower right yeah
yeah
so the idea behind reveging and why you
would leave most of the bud
is because when I re-vege and I leave
the bud it leaves more sites for New
Growth new vegetative growth to grow out
of out of that bud that's right and when
you harvest the bud it has a lot of less
there's a lot less places for new
vegetative growth to come from
a lot of times when people revege they
get greedy about their bud and they want
to harvest their bud to smoke and if
it's only a little bit you know like
they really want to smoke it
but you again you have to make a choice
is this thing such a good keeper that
I'm going to leave all this Bud on it
let it rot and go to waste just to get
more vegetative material or is it I'd
rather smoke the bud and not worry about
it once again it's like a numbers game
once again right the more Bud sites you
can afford to leave the higher the
chances that you have a successful
Revenge exactly and the other thing is
and this is the most important
24 hours of light and it takes about two
months for a successful revech expect it
to take about two months to where you're
seeing some kind of good vegetative
growth coming off
sometimes longer sometimes three but um
it's a long process it's a lot of
electricity in some cases then you know
but if you aren't keeping clones
and
you can't have a separate veg and flower
space then re-veging is your best bet
that's the way to work through that
okay okay so yeah the 24 hour lightning
almost always ensures it for me almost
always plenty of root space 24 hours
light and plenty of uh Bud sites you
know or Bud left on it just don't don't
strip it bare and it'll do it
um how long does it take generally quite
a bit right yeah two two to three months
for it to be complete
yeah
yeah it's a long process but granted
there's been so many times where it
saved my ass so many times like where
I'll take clones of something be flaring
something out and those last few clones
dying I'm like oh [ __ ] all I got it is
this last plant in flower that's a great
case for reveging too and I you know
like I'm a big proponent of it because
it's very effective it works great and
the thing that most people don't talk
about with reveging is that it kind of
sets the plant back to zero point like
plants are like some plants that are
more like slow not as vigorous they're
tired from whatever disease you give it
a good re-vege and that plant will be
back to vigorous and spry it's crazy
like it does reinvigorate the plant
somehow and that's just a an
experiential take not a scientific take
but it's something I've noticed enough
to where it's like okay that's something
that happens and then it does and we've
even we've even gone as far as making
seeds and then re-veging that plant see
how the seeds form during a Rive Edge
which is always interesting wow okay you
can do that
I remember from Forum you know from my
earlier days on the forums like monster
cropping yeah yeah
uh create much more
plot mess is that yeah yeah biomass yeah
it's kind of boofy to do it but yeah
that's a that is a technique for sure
but
um yeah veg seeds reveg seeds usually
come out more hearty with thicker shells
that's the one thing I've noticed and it
does hold pretty true yeah
uh this is cool this has been a this has
been a funny little uh side path to come
down I didn't think yeah it is that's
actually quite fascinating
okay well returning to this like
original scenario of like uh I'm a
homegoer and I've got a keeper that I
want to like
either try to lock in in a seed line
basically which is now more just a
general breeding question I wondered if
you wanted to cover that that old
territory again of like
um in terms of locking in expressions
and traits um the differences between
like back cross reversal uh forward
breathing outcross you know like
is it worth just broad stroking
that I know it's something that you guys
have covered a lot but yeah I mean
except we're here
let's see I can't I'm trying to think of
a best way to talk about this without
having to go into the detail of the
different generations and essentially
just be like like if someone wants to if
someone has a cologne that they like
right and they want to reproduce it the
quickest way to reproduce that clone or
to get a a version of that clone in seed
the closest version
to that because there's no way to make a
mirror image of it and see it fast
that's never going to happen that's not
what s1s are that's not what fence seeds
are they're not clone versions of
themselves in seed you know the other
day I got a question from a reader I'm
going to try to rephrase this a little
bit I got a question from a reader and
they were asking a receipt maker that
was asking
um if I make these Femme seeds are they
going to be clones of themselves like is
this going to be can I tell the
customers if you want to see a clone of
this in seed by these Femme seeds and I
I had to explain no that's not how this
works
um a lot of people do have that
expectation that a S1 or self line
uh meaning a plant pollinating itself
and making seeds of itself so there's
not any outside genetics coming in it's
just that plant's own genetics
um
it is not going to be a clonal
representation of that plane to say
you're not going to pop you know 10 of
those seeds and they're not all going to
pop and look just like that clone that
doesn't happen and that's not how
selfing works and I think that a lot of
people have that impression that that's
where they're going to find the exact
clone and it's just going to be just
like the Clone mother and even some seed
makers have this idea
um that's not really how it works but
if I were going to give someone advice
and they had a clone they didn't know
much about breeding if they had a clone
and they wanted to make a seed line that
was most representative of that clone
and try to trap it in seed I would say
go the self route as opposed to choosing
a male from a different line let's say
it's a femme line that they're running
you know instead of choosing a regular
seed or a male from a different line
bringing in outside genetics and
Crossing it and having regular seeds I
would reverse it using reversal spray
pollinate itself
and by doing so you're not bringing in
outside genetics so everything you're
going to see are what comprises let's
say if you're reversing bubble gum it's
going to be everything that comprises
the genetics of bubble gum inside that
self-line sometimes it might be all
really close surrounding that bubble gum
expression sometimes it might just be a
bunch of earthy and bubble gum was the
weird outlier and when I say outlier
means you know uh it's only one in a
thousands each you'll see this this pop
up whereas the the earthy sweet
expressions are one you know one in ten
or one and two like every two seeds
you're gonna see that for sure but one
in a thousand you might see this pink
bubble gum expression that's what an
outlier is
yeah yeah
um and uh there
if the odds are that steep what what can
you what else can you do
um
like that the best method is to use uh
selfing because you speed through the
filial generation process much faster
because you're not bringing in outside
genetic material you're not working with
new stuff that you're bringing in and
trying to select away from whatever
plant that is it's all working towards
that single tray and what you'd want to
do you'd self it you'd pop as many seeds
from that selfing as you can until you
found the one that is exactly like you
like in that generation you take that
selection you self that one and then you
do it again and each new generation
you're going to be getting much closer
and closer and closer if you're doing
good selections to that original clone
in those seed each each round is going
to be really tight and get Tighter and
Tighter and by the S4 you should be
seeing like extreme extreme uniformity
for that specific trait you're breathing
for doesn't mean that the plant's going
to look like a clone of itself if you're
breeding for the pink bubble gum tray
all of them should have the feet bubble
gum tray by about S4
yeah yeah
um what are the trade-offs here
down there are multiple self Generations
the major trade-offs going to be
inbreeding
um mutations uh because you're because
you're selfing you're going to see all
those uh those wild Expressions come out
to the Forefront
um those those recessive genetics as we
refer to them though one in the
thousands are going to pop up and a lot
of that is also going to be mutations
and inbred traits that we may not
necessarily want so the more inbred it
gets each each uh self-generation
might come with more trash involved
along with what you want
yeah that's the downside that's a
trade-off
yeah
makes sense as we say uh low floor high
ceiling
yes that's right yeah yeah yeah no that
makes sense as well okay now
can what about
um for using forward breeding to try to
do something similar like what what are
the differences here like does it take a
lot more time to achieve similar results
um so uh forward reading let's just
assume we have a regular seed line of a
single line uh yeah for just for example
my blueberry uh in Cross which is like
an inbred blueberry line and we have
males and females of that
that would be easy to do like a worked
line of regular just doing F1 F2 F3 F4
because it's a very uniform line as is
now let's say we have for example animal
cookies crust uh animal mints pie or you
know what I mean like something that has
like six strains on one side and six
strains on the other and they're not
related
you're gonna have a hell of a time
Crossing those running through all the
potential expressions from this like
12-way poly hybrid trying to pick what
you like going down the next route
trying to go through that it would take
so many generations just to try to make
anything uniform because of all the
traits that both sides bring
which is why I would highly recommend in
that case using selfie when it's a
polyhybrid clone that you found that you
like the quickest way to quickest route
is through selfing yeah if you have a
regular seed line of something that's
been were filial Generations that's the
normal breeding method is is just F1 F2
male female male female male female
um
the only time we really use back
Crossing which is to say like if I have
a blueberry bubble gum on one side and a
blueberry on another side so it would
ideally ideally be 66 percent blueberry
33 bubble gum in genetics that doesn't
mean that the expressions are going to
come out that way but genetically 66 and
33 percent
um
uh bubble gum 66 blueberry by Crossing
something that's already blueberry and
bubble gum with another blueberry that's
considered a back cross because you're
Crossing blueberry back onto something
that already had blueberry in it
um yeah the best the best times to use
that most people like you'll see people
selling bx4 bx5 bx6
with bx's the best thing that we found
that it's used for is locking down a
single trade let's say in this blueberry
bubble gum I want to find a super
blueberry type plant in this blueberry
bubble gum so by crossing the blueberry
again lock in that blueberry trait
because let's assume this this blue bit
this male is true breeding for blueberry
traits so now I've locked it in in this
hybrid now most of the time it's going
to be true breeding for this blueberry
scented tray
you only need to be X1 one time to make
that happen if you're using good
selections there's no need to take it to
a px2 from that point you should either
work at filial Generations forward
or self Generations forward you don't
want to keep working backwards using
back crosses that's not how you lock in
multiple trades you lock in multiple
traits going forward
this is now this is more you know
Advanced breeding Theory but the idea is
lock multiple traits going forward lock
a single trait going backwards you can
lock in a signal chart going backwards
then lock in multiple traits going
forwards
yeah and yeah going forwards includes
selfie
yeah
very nice that that's an excellent
summary and I I don't think that um I've
heard this account as like succinctly
um as you've presented it here in like
previous episodes so I'm really glad
that you you covered it there's a great
paper there's an amazing paper
um written by chimera and he's he's like
I've talked to him about and he said I
probably wrote that when I was drunk or
something like it was okay it's called
the the myth of cubing or like the myth
of cubing and back Crossing I believe
yeah and it was one of the smartest
papers I've ever read and he actually
wrote a an addendum to it as well and I
can't remember where it's at but try to
Google the myth of cubing and back
Crossing and if I can remember I'll put
it in the description too but it's a
great paper talking about the scientific
uh like what's going on scientifically
for back Crossing in cannabis
yeah amazing well we're kind of wrapping
up but I think we did get a related
question to this on like you know
resources and reading uh Trevor Leahy
from Brita Syndicate asked you know
other girl Bibles that people have
mentioned countless times like marijuana
botany or marijuana growers guide
uh how reliable and how accurate are
they still and what would you look to
gain from Reading those in 2023
so marijuana botany is not a grow book
by any stretch of the imagination it is
a breeding Theory Book
and I wouldn't recommend that for
someone to learn growing however if
you're going to learn breeding in
cannabis to this day it's still the
standard granted Robert Mark has come
out with a new book called marijuana
ethnobotany and evolution written with
Mark Merlin which is now the standard
but it is a heavy Collegiate textbook it
is not meant for someone trying to just
learn cannabis breeding it's not a good
introduction it is heavy so marijuana is
a more theoretical less practical is
that what you're saying No it's it's
more it's just thicker reading you have
to really understand breeding Concepts
and breeding terms to jump into the mark
Merlin buff
you have some of that um knowledge yeah
it's okay the best way to put it like if
you've been through some science in a a
junior college
that book might be more for you the the
marijuana ethnobotany and evolution if
you're comfortable reading college
textbooks that's how it's written like a
college textbook that book's for you
marijuana botany is more for someone who
doesn't read college textbooks but wants
to understand breeding Theory at its
basics
yeah as far as growing
the like the Jorge Cervantes grow book
and you know the Mel Frank one a lot of
people started out on that and it did a
lot of people a lot of good however
growing's come so far so far even in the
past 10 years it's Leaps and Bounds how
how people have been able to
um get cannabis to perform and express
is Leaps and Bounds like if you look at
the old Scentsy catalogs for seeds you
see stuff being stuffed with nitrogen to
the gills just poofy no resin nothing
today we understand how to grow plants a
lot better and I think
maybe those old books while they are
great to have in your pocket for
understanding some of cannabis and
knowing like the pest stuff and knowing
what to look for for like deficiencies
and how the leaves look
um those are great but as far as
learning how to feed there are so many
more advanced courses now from different
universities on the best way to feed
cannabis and how it likes organic
feeding there's also the revs
tree living Organics book for people
that want to get into TLO
um but yeah I mean like there's online
courses from from universities on
YouTube that are so much more advanced
on soil science and and soil biology
that could really really
like Advanced people's growing
understanding I think that was probably
where I would recommend starting as
opposed to those books but those books
are great Foundation but for modern
techniques some of the colleges and
universities are just doing the most
groundbreaking stuff with soil science
and soil biology
yeah I got you
okay well we are in this final section
of
um essentially Community questions that
didn't
necessarily fit into any of our previous
sections okay and I think one thing I
want to signpost is that some of these
are more on the breeding side and and
like meh Matt presented a couple of
really rich dense nuggets for breeding
but this episode was mostly about seed
making so I think we also want to keep
open the possibility of having a
dedicated episode on breeding uh yeah I
agree uh where we maybe talk more about
like each generation and all that but I
think it's important to to go back over
and redo that one
yeah I think so yeah so we could
definitely do that but for in in the
interest of like just answering a few
more of these questions to wrap up
um some of these are pretty interesting
um loyger from Syndicate asks what
traits do you lose When selecting from
small plants for example you can't
select for outdoor plant structure large
plant structure if you're growing in one
gallon pots but you know are there any
other traits that get lost if you uh
search hunting through smaller plants if
you're heading through smaller plants um
some pest resistance maybe might get
lost in the smaller plants or I mean
they may even get attacked more you
never know you know
um
obviously structure yield comes into
play
um seeing how far because imagine not
all plants sorry to interrupt but I
guess in terms of yield it would be that
like even though your plant yields x
amount at in a one gallon pot it doesn't
necessarily scale in a linear fashion if
you go out exactly pot size right yeah
exactly and um
I mean
there are certain things that I think
you can learn about your plant better
from smaller pot sizes versus just
blowing it out and having the biggest
yielding plant you can which is terpenes
expression you can see a finer
expression of the plant
um I believe in like a two or three
gallon pot you can see like so it's not
being pushed too hard in any One
Direction but it's enough root space for
it to perform
um but yeah you're obviously going to
lose out on structure especially if
you're going indoor versus out they're
just way too different
um like I'm not a proficient outdoor
grower at all I'm an indoor grower and
exclusively indoor my outdoor runs have
been minimal and not even that great you
know so
yeah and I did want to kind of um draw
attention to the one of those points he
made which is that um on terpenes and
maybe like
uh cannabinoid balance uh chemical
compound balance in general does change
with scale yeah absolutely I know you
all have like mentioned that what is it
like the blue dream at different
different scales performing very
differently for example UK cheese you
know you can get a thousand expressions
from that plant you know I've told
stories about how I've thrown away the
same clone several different times that
smelled different because I thought it
was a fake cut because it didn't smell
like my my first smoking of cheese and
then later on when I grew it a certain
way it's like oh this is the same Berry
plant but now it smells like cheese what
the hell you know that's you know that's
one of the most important things I've
ever learned in cannabis
um was the plasticity of cannabis and
how truly different it is and how hard
it is to identify clones and different
plants in flower through pictures
yeah you know that's very rare
it comes back to that my earlier point
that like of course you know we want to
try to seek out as many Clues as
possible
um in advance of
uh
flowering something out or breeding
something
um you know we're looking there's this
tendency to look for
um science right yeah wherever they are
and it is interesting it's an
interesting game and that leads on to
the next question
from Morris uh it's an interesting one
uh do you think that there are traits
that tend to be overlooked in selections
um so we know that the most common ones
are going to be like
um structure flavor smell potency
um mold resistance you know those are
obviously really common ones are there
ones you think
are overlooked they're maybe a bit more
minor but also quite important hi
is the most important to me and it's not
the most important to everyone but in
the during the Instagram era I really
feel like that's been the most ignored
because you can't visually see it
you can't pick it fast
you know like you can't tell which plant
has the best high really fast you know
like while it's in flour how are you
going to do that
um
that's definitely one of the main ones
because it's just not something our
senses really pick up until we smoke it
and it takes time
um to properly like test and smoke a
whole crop of like 50 selections takes
even more time
and
and how much time you wanted to vote to
that and how much space you put in
between each
sampling of each high and what you're
doing the mindset and set like all come
into play
so yeah I mean
I don't know kind of rambling but
no I get it and I think it's this is a
difficult question because like
um
I know for example I think not so has
mentioned this like an interesting one
that I don't know many people think
about is that they may be a sweet spot
for say flower density
yeah
um where it's like oh actually if it's
too dense it doesn't smoke well if it's
too loose then it's too loose right so
maybe there's something in there but I
think generally the main things that
people select for it's pretty well
covered right and well there's also
there's also selecting against and
people are selected against an intersex
trait and I think that that's also
detrimental the Cannabis because there
are things called link traits and some
of the times those linked traits might
be linked to that intersex trait and
some of those may be traits like you
know heavy volatile sulfur compounds
that smell skunky and we may have lost a
lot of that because people selected
against an intersex trait that's linked
I mean that's one Theory you know um so
there are there are many traits that we
select against that maybe maybe we are
considering it but we're selecting
against it and it may be hurting the
overall gene pool
oh that just blows open the degree of
complexity here where yeah yeah you may
be yeah implicitly in selecting for
something you may uh sorry in select
before something you maybe implicitly
say selecting against something else
that you don't even know about that's
kind of
that's kind of mind-blowing and that's
why the progeny has to be run that's why
it's so important to run the project
yeah because you just never truly know
like with the for example with the blue
bonnet male the first the first thing
that I used to select him was because
was his purple stock stripes and and
just like the overall look because I I
remember DJ's blueberry mother clone
that has somewhat of a blueberry smell
and some of the other blue selections
that I made over the years that are kind
of blueberry muffin all have this look
to it and this particular one had his
his leaves sticking 90 degrees from top
to bottom all the lesions sticking
straight up so I was like okay that's
that's like him raising his hands that's
as good as any thing using the you know
what little education I have with
blueberry those specific traits that
identified visually and then that I was
like okay well this is as good as any to
try then when I when I when I was
dusting the room when I was smacking the
mail I remember I had on this big face
mask with the canisters on it usually
you can't smell much of scent through
that thing but I was smelling nothing
but Berry coming through when he was
wafting around so at that point I knew
that he at least has oils that that have
a berry smell to them so that's a plus
but
even with all that I had no clue if he
was really going to pass that blueberry
trait until I ran the progeny there's
just no way to know because in in using
that purple stripe stock maybe even
though he smells blueberry combining it
with whatever potential females I have
that trait on that plant locks out that
Berry trait so you'll never see it you
know there's all kinds of things to take
into account when it comes
yeah yeah so I guess the upshot from
from there is we're not trying to say
that like
you can't use try to use early earlier
indicators to help you narrow your
search but just you have to know that
there's no Silver Bullet and there's no
replacement for actually running
something out or it's progeny out sorry
I should say yeah um they're no
shortcuts no Silver Bullet no shortcuts
and and there's no shortcuts better than
knowing the line and running the progeny
knowing what you're working with is
super important so even if you haven't
you know bred with it let's say you've
run you know 10 clones from that same
line per year you'll know more about
that line and its traits and its
different Expressions just from running
those 10 different plants from that line
over a year then you've realized so when
you go on on to do this the breeding
work with it you'll be like oh wait I
know that trait I saw that you know
clone number three and blah blah blah
all that comes into play and helps and
people don't really realize it until
after they're doing the progeny
selection and that's when you start
realizing
all that time you spent learning those
plants really like how important it is
When selecting traits it's so important
yep yep
yep great advice
okay well we have a final question
um also from loyger are there any
differences between breeding short and
long flowering strengths
yes
um
that's that's another multi-tiered
complex thing I mean it can go
from like you know to where Neville was
saying like don't use Hayes males only
use Haze females because the haze males
breed like trash you know that like
people have these theories like that but
overall when it gets to Basics the main
difference is going to be flower time
and when you pollinate when you
pollinate
um how long the seeds take to mature and
how long you know the the the male
flowers versus the female flowers and
when they're going to go off that's the
main considerations When taking into
account seed making specifically
nice
okay well you know I think that's that's
us we covered uh the sequence you know
the specific techniques and steps of
making seeds for regulars reversals
autos
um we covered some of the
questions around isolation contamination
prevention overall pretty you know
pretty uh pessimistic risk-averse
response which yeah makes sense I think
my responses most of my responses are
going to be like uh risk averse and with
sterility and like cleanliness in mind
when it comes to breeding I think yeah
yeah
and finally at the end we got to gesture
towards
um some actual breeding strategy and
techniques uh sorry strategy and Theory
um and maybe we will do another episode
that's dedicated to breeding yeah I
think I think um yeah I think that's a
good idea and uh yeah I'm happy with
this one so let's uh finish up I guess
do you have anything you want to applaud
specifically or say again
no I'm good
okay just happy to be invited well um go
check out our patreon Discord that's
where we all hang out and shoot the [ __ ]
like throughout the week
um we're pretty interactive like it's a
it's an interactive Discord it's not one
of the Dead ones where like people join
and be like hey you know like we're
really really active there everybody is
um so check that out we have our new
drop with reader Syndicate ucsi not so
dog go check that out it's uh his
headband stuff crossed a little F1 Derby
action there we have The Punchy crosses
drops and all that's on right seeds.com
of course we have my Bonnet stuff and we
have the reversal spray which we talked
about some today hopefully that helps
some of you on that and
um I think that's it other than that
please like share and subscribe I can't
tell you how important that is uh like
um with YouTube's algorithm they're
putting us in like a lot of the mature
categories so we don't really get
recommended so it's a Grassroots effort
to get people to see this so if you you
know your friend will dig it um please
share and and like it if you like it or
don't hit dislike if you don't and
comment and tell me why I suck that
works too I'm down for that we're also
trying to get 10 000 subscribers right
man yes yes super important Lotso does
not come out of a cage until we get 10
000 subscribers and that's just that
yeah
so yeah anyway thank you thousand for
for helping me
um outline this and and getting a real
linear fashion going for the show I
think that's that's super helpful thank
you help people listen so I appreciate
you brother and from here from us here
at breeder Syndicate thank you to all of
you
thanks everybody
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out