welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
Syndicate do you have any experience
with uh Uptown Hayes
piff uh nl5 days yeah right is they're
all Cuban black the cough the dog [ __ ]
um there there I
I strongly believe they're all just nl5
haes just reamed right there a lot sold
right and I just did work um I just made
a cross with the with one of my lemon
trees I made some fem uh fem seeds with
a lemon tree of mine and cross I'm so
glad you brought it here to lemon
trees and
U it's good that you know the the Pips
all those nlvs are [ __ ] all those nl5
hazes they're dominant when you cross
time I play around with them they've
always taken over um good good stuff you
know in the past I wasn't much of a of a
fan of of those they just kind of made
my head spin a little too much uh but
now like uh i' I've been smoking them
more and more and enjoying them more and
more you know I'm getting older so my
body's changing or whatnot for sure and
uh yeah they got you know it kind of
reminds me of catpiss a little bit thanl
five Haze it's got that fun
py especially in the air like if you're
out a concert or something and someone
lights one of those up you see heads
whipping like that that that smells
fingers right
um so I just did those uh lemon tree
pffs um and they grow they grow like
like the piff
tall um and and then the flavors have
been ranging from lemon tree to to the
piff and everything in between you know
what was your sourcing for the piff
Cuban black Haze I got the Cuban black
Haze and then my buddies said they came
from um one of the guys what do you say
not dark heart uh purple City genetics
is where my buddy got the he gave me a
couple he gave me that one and a
different one from that piif Coast guy
uh something three piif Coast Three I I
don't remember but I like the Cuban
black a little bit better so you
mentioned lemon
tree yeah go ahead go ahead what you can
say oh um so when I was growing those
two hazes out uh the the other one from
piff Coast to number three uh looked
hella looked hella good hella Frosty
finished earlier but in my in my climate
it got um powdery milde a little too
easy for me sure so I decided to say
against that you know I like
um I like easy grown
plants I like I like plant
where after I harvest it I can pick off
a bud right off the off the plant
without curing it and making my mouth
water um that that's what I that's what
I'm always going after like the stuff
that I got to cure and weight I don't
know um I want to tastes good right off
the [ __ ] bat so most of my strands
that I work with that's that's what they
are yeah so CSI specifically wanted me
to ask you about lemon tree and and uh I
I got uh
I knew this I knew one of the Lemon Tree
Brokers in the bay um young guy anyhow
uh he he he he pretty much branded lemon
tree and another
one
um and uh you know every time he'd buy
packs he would find seeds inside of them
yeah so he ended up giving me about a
100 seeds a little bit more of the uh so
they're essentially lemon tree Hermes
seeds but the the actual clone out seeds
here and there so I I grew out all the
seeds um some of them popped out looking
like sour diesel even even kind of
smelling like sour
diesel and then the rest were short
different degrees of shortness different
degrees of that that uh that that turp
the um you know everybody says lemon
tree lemony but to me it's it's uh I I
smell California Orange I don't know so
to me it's more orangey but I don't know
what you want to call those turps but uh
so yeah I picked out the best Citrus
yeah strong
Citrus um grew all the seeds out picked
out what did I ended up with seven that
I picked out and then from those seven
uh came down to three of them and then
from those three I kept the one and then
I I gave the the guy that gave me the
seeds um all the pets and then he ended
up giving them out to a couple people
like that um GL Grand Flora Mark or
whatever oh yeah Flora yeah yeah so he
used he used one of those cuts um to
make his
melonade um what did I have I had a two
four I kept a two four and a I don't
remember anyhow I gave I they all kept
the one that was the easiest to grow
that had really good turps and that's
what the grand Flo guy used um the one
that I ended up keeping was a little bit
harder it was definitely finicky with
the
overwatering um but it had more you know
it had the strong it had more chirps
than the other the other ones right it
was just a little bit more finicky to
grow so I I don't I think that's why the
other guys never really went with it but
um yeah so not not much to tell about
that Hermes seeds screw them all out and
then started back Crossing back Crossing
and back Crossing and uh you know of
course I I stress out everything um just
to make sure they don't Herm on me and
and SC over again you know until until
they're
right um with the with the uh lemon tree
have you ever tried the Oregon Lemon
Diesel prior to the lemon tree I haven't
I hadn't no I always wondered like when
when people different people tried the
lemon tree if they see any relation to
it it's interesting that you see so much
diesel in it too because that story is
always kind of stuck with it yeah yeah a
lot of people especially guys from
Oregon always say lemon tree is just
that that um Oregan Lemon Diesel renames
yeah which very very well could be you
know have you um tried lemon
G yeah yeah what you think of that
comparatively to tall easy grown
plant um I don't know I'd rather grow
Calo maybe maybe it is Calo who knows
you know you know Calo like it just
tastes good smelled good but there
wasn't you
know yeah lemon G was pretty similar to
that um the the lemon tree is by far the
best
citrusy uh ganja plant that I've come
across out of them all like it's it's
got the flavor and it's got some it's
got a good Buzz to it and I mean I mean
of course it's one of those strains if I
smoke it for two or three days it's not
getting me that high anymore but um the
first few days it's great and tastes
great is actually I'm smoking some lemon
tree g33 right now how is it decent it's
delicious uh so I made a bunch of them I
ended up growing them all out myself
this year and uh picked out a few I've
been doing the little smoke testers past
few days but uh grow grow like the
gelato look like gelato but have
straight siy
Ras yeah yeah total Improvement um on
both I think on both strains right and
and that's like the ultimate goal at the
very end you know improve something
structure-wise flavor wise potency wise
like there's always there's always a
reason why I'm doing something right
it's not like I'm going to go and just
cross this to a bunch of everything else
there's always there's always some kind
of Madness behind the thought um it's
either you know like with with the ones
that with the uh with the lemon tree
reversals that I did um I I picked out
easy tall fast growing plants to cross
to the lemon tree because the lemon tree
is short and squat right yep yep so
wanted a tall fast growing lemon tree
flavor but Stony so everything I picked
out like the blue dream or the or the
pth and
gelato um
also did a GMO but that the I've worked
at GMO a couple times um it seems like
it spits out a lot of Hermes on me with
every cost done with it um so yeah
anyhow the uh I I grew out all the
[ __ ] gelato ones so I don't have any
more of those but the uh the lemon tree
and the oh not the tree the blue dream
and the pffs I ended up releasing those
just
recently and total Improvement on both
you know blue dream I know a lot of
people hate it but it it's still like I
love it too it's still one of my love
the high of Blue Dream dude like the
high The Taste the smell all of it
yeah when it's grown out right it's
[ __ ] delicious
right AB and then some some of these
lemon tree uh Blue Dream ones like the
the ones that are right in the middle
with flavor-wise where you got a little
bit of that blue dream and a little bit
they're they're [ __ ] delicious and
the frost factor is just like increase
100 folds like they both just
complimented each other perfectly always
that's cool so a lot of people don't
know and I don't know how much you want
to talk about this in detail but a lot
of us that that uh received Chim 91
later on oh ow you a did of gratitude
for it even reaching our hands a lot of
people do that are you are you open to
talk about that about which one say that
again
sorry uh chem 91 um I got that from
Jason skunk VA uh he was at my
neighbor's house in Willets um over
there and then I just I went over there
and we started
talking and uh I know um I remember not
so dog at one of the Harvest parties
early
2000s raving about chem 91 chem 91 right
him and a couple other people of his
crew right oh you guys don't even know
and it [ __ ] you know it built up in
me I was like
[ __ ] that that you know I heard
I heard it from them for a while and
then one day yeah like I was I was at my
neighbor's house and and uh skunk F's
over there and we started yapping and
chatting he was like dude I I got the
chem 91 and then like he started talking
about uh the Hydra sore guy in Willets
who also had the [ __ ] chem 91 so I
knew he was legit because he knew all
the same people and like where he came
from and everything thing so I told him
I was like you know dude I'm you know I
just play around making seeds for myself
you kick down the cut I'm you know make
seeds and I'll give you seeds of every
direction so I ended up taking that um
chem 91 to back cross
3 uh and then what did I get I I got and
then the chem fours and all that the
chem1 two3 whatever came out and Caleb
hooked me up with all of those Specta
gave me all those and I grew all those
out and that four was just [ __ ] to me
was the best one flavor wise same uh the
the rests are they're good like the chem
91 to me is is very OG OG to me
flavor-wise
um but uh SF to me was way way way
better infinitely and easier to grow
chem 91's ugly easier to grow yeah yeah
that that chem 99 was was hant
so um anyhow uh I ended up giving uh
skunk VA seeds all you know for every
single cross that I made with his chem
91 um and then I gave him all the a
bunch of chem seeds and whatnot
to
yeah so yeah that was the uh the chem 91
came from him and then I gave it to
Caleb and um the rest is history from
that you know so Bubba Kush
Bubba buba Bubba Kush what what's what's
this the back sourcing story on that
like again a lot of us ow a dead of
gratitude for you for us even having
Bubba um Bubba I got from another glass
blower uh Bishop really talented glass
blower uh and he got
it he I remember him saying he got it
from this guy that would all I really
remember was like he would just pack fat
bowls take one hit and then spit out the
bowl I
like it could it could be organ kid is
is what it sounds like to me yeah
yeah so yeah he he gave me the cut in 99
I think it was okay he gave me the cut
of that um and uh yeah from from that it
just you know I passed it around um to
random folks here and there uh Caleb
guys on the old forums back in the day
uh Fletch you know and that's how I met
Fletch uh for the second time and became
really good friends after that
um yeah most of it most of all these
things came from back in the day with
the glass glowing Community that's cool
there were uh Trinity you know what's
that Trinity uh
TR Trinity grew um Trinity I got from
Caleb okay and and I and I and I've
grown that out a couple times and I've
made a bunch of crosses that one's that
one is is one where you need to grow a
[ __ ] ton of seeds and and root right um
it it comes out with all different kinds
of flavors and looks gross
structures um oh you know what another
uh I forgot when J gave me that uh the
clone of the CH 91 he also gave me a
[ __ ] ton of Hermes seeds from it too
that's cool yeah so so I I dug through
that and that there was some fun stuff
that chem 991 like some full-on indicia
plants popping up some uh real short
squaty like Pakistani kind of looking
leaves not not so thick and wide but
more slender and yeah
and yeah so there was some interesting
stuff in there but I I never came one
across
one that had that gas in there I
remember they were a little bit
different
um yeah you did a a his favorite run of
Sour Diesel flour and I think he said
you use power flow NES flower
power flower yeah it was it was a it was
dirt brand it was a bag of dirt and the
guy the guy that made that was up in
Trinity County um that's funny story any
the guy that made that was in Trinity
County and he had like this bog or some
[ __ ] on his property and what he did was
he just [ __ ] dug that [ __ ] up threw
it in a chipper and then bagged it up
right and it and it was it was all the
ra back in the early 2000s you know and
there was no pear anything in it so you
had to mix all that [ __ ] in
um the sour diesel though he's talking
about is I had a I had a house in the
sunset District in San Francisco and and
these houses are built to grow in um the
meter so the the garages are all tandem
style right yeah uh so you were able to
like you know build a wall uh next to
the garage door and then you had the
hole back and then some people the
meter like the uh the PG guys would have
to come in and like look through a
little window for the meter so they
weren't able actually to get to the
meter um I never did this but some
people could have tapped into that [ __ ]
hella easy too yeah right yeah right
right uh so I was growing I was growing
in this house and next
door I had a grower to the left of me to
the right of me was like uh maybe a
brothel house or something like
that yeah so some sometimes the place
will get skunky and it it's you know I'm
like two blocks from the beach so
powdery mildew is the thing so i' always
have to turn it on the sulfur burners
and when I would turn them on ID just
put it on a timer and leave and then
come back eight hours later right yeah
but every time I would come back the the
people store in wa place like they would
be all in the driveway and spitting on
my driveway and flicking their
cigarettes my
driveway it must have made the place s
pretty bad and the um one day my the
other grub neighbor came over and he was
like bro there's these things called
carbon scrubbers filters you know he's
like buy 10 of them a [ __ ] stinks um
so the sour though what I
found is you're going to lose a lot of
your yield but if if you rootbound Sour
Diesel grow in a small po the buds get
super dense on you get super dense and
crazy crazy Frosty and like all that
[ __ ] Turf just gets crazy like
concentrated for some reason but the
yields you lose a lot of yield tons of
yield yeah gets lost on that so it's
it's you know what what do you want I I
always went after the best possible
smoke right so yield was the last thing
on my mind TPS
first yeah yeah that's that's where that
sour came from Power flour and age-old
is what I used back then that's good get
good advice man so root bound power well
you can't get power flower now obviously
the end of that story do you mind
telling it what happened to the
bog to the what oh the bog guy uh so
yeah the power flower guy he ended up
getting in trouble with the
[ __ ]
environmentalists yeah uh for digging
all that [ __ ] out and ended up they
ended up shutting him out shutting him
down um yeah it was like an ancient like
Redwood forest bed wasn't it something
like that it was uh it was just like um
a pond that he [ __ ] drained out and
dug it all out that's all
and then you just throw everything
through a [ __ ] wood shipper and and
uh bag it up in these brown bags and
just say power flow and like I [ __ ]
made it killing because it it was like
it was all back then you know everybody
have if you weren't grown with it you
weren't cool yeah yeah my buddy goat
farm grew a bunch of uh train wreck in
the power flower and was talking about
it today earlier and that reminded me to
bring it
up so one of my one of the things that
I'm most fascinated with that you've
worked with that I've never I've never
even grown a cut of it I've only grown
hybrids because it's not widely passed
or you know is the purple Indica what
can you tell us about that uh another
one comes from archive uh he sourced it
up up in Seattle
area um short Stout grapy molded H
easy uh I don't know I've seen it I've
seen it floating around Northern
California but they called it purple
Kish back then yeah right um and then
what else it had another name to it
ultraviolet I think they might have
called it P was another yeah there's
been a bunch right yeah
um yeah anyhow I I got that from Fletch
and besides that I have no idea the
history behind it short little plant I
just I just remember the mold it would
mold so easy it was like the first thing
to mold on me that's gnarly beautiful
beautiful plane you know how is the
smoke from it that's the one thing I I I
don't know for you oh shoot it's been so
long grapy is uh not not like not like
Urkle grape but uh
grapy
skunky to it it's like an old school
purple ay yeah yeah exactly that's it's
exactly what it is old school purple
afghan most likely broadleaf sh
um big big uh like arm siiz buds on it
indoor indoor uh different you know
still short kind but more like a Bubba
size buds on it you know yeah outdoor
though the whole the whole plant would
turn into a bud I've always just
wondered why like what what was what was
the reason that it remained so locked
other than just mystery you know I'm
just right
always if that like Albert Walker and uh
the Malo all all those floated around
the Washington area quite a bit there
was another one like Pez pink Pez or
some [ __ ] like
yeah like their they their their jam
over there more the stas I remember back
then like a lot of the sativa
plants so region has their own time what
this Str or that Str you know La in
early 2000s was
are with
purple yeah you know about every 10
years it seems like the trend kind of
changes to something
else yeah have you noticed that most
people lost their OG Cuts do you get hit
up about that lot no I'm I'm so out of
the loop dude I um I'm getting old I
don't talk to nobody uh I don't buy weed
from anybody uh like I don't even know
how much weed goes I don't even know the
prices anymore yeah I
I have no
clue yeah um the one the one thing I've
been hearing a lot and I've get been
getting tons of DMS from other seed
makers and [ __ ] no one kept OG cuts no
one so I have a feeling your your OG
seed seed uh sales are gonna Skyrocket
soon because it's it's heavily in demand
and no one kept him right I have noticed
that they uh has been doing a little bit
better than the other strength so far um
I I I see a lot of people are going back
hours as well
yeah absolutely it seem like it's it's
making so the gas is coming back right
and as it should because uh you know
weed nowadays looks [ __ ] incredible
it I mean it's the most beautiful I've
ever seen it
absolutely there's just not much to it
you know it all looks the same now they
all they don't really have the turps
that I'm I'm looking for and and uh like
OG is still my favorite that's my go-to
uh the gas OG's hard to beat man that
that flavor the lip smacking flavor the
flavor um and the fact is just like it
just never disappoints it always uh it
always works yeah
right yeah I've I wanted to ask about
one a couple of things so one I've heard
you mention recently it's called the PC3
and it's an nl5 Haze okay yeah the
PC3 uh the PC3 three was that one from
piff Coast um like I was saying that
that's the I grew it side by side with
the Cuban black cut and uh that PC3
looked looked incredible had had the
flavor had that deep Haze
flavor uh finish finish ear than the the
Cuban black um but for me in my climate
like it just it got powdery mil do a
little um a little too easy so that's
why I didn't stick with it like I the
powdery milde is [ __ ] you up out here so
I tend to stay away from plants that get
it super easy or plants that mold hell
easy or
whatnot and there was some um Blockhead
and love candy uh what was your favorite
Expressions to come out of
that um so love C Blockhead and love
candy are the same okay um as as breeder
I was like hey man you know I've been uh
uh working the strain are you cool if I
release it and he was just like you know
as long as you don't call Blockhead I
don't give a [ __ ] about you it's like
okay cool yeah right so love candy it is
um that you that was my cash Cropper in
the late 90s early 2000s
um Kush cleaner ended up replacing that
Blockhead for me but uh back then
outdoor or it finished early and it had
the look it had that almost an indoor
look where actually a lot of people were
passing it off as
indoor like a melony like a cantaloupe
melon I don't know typical spice of life
flavors um easy to grow [ __ ] hella
easy to trim produce big and just crazy
Frosty uh so like I said it was my cash
copper for days um I I uh I work that I
work that one heavily uh I back crossed
it a couple times and then I lost the
Clone and then buddy mine Kendo on used
to go online by Kendo yeah he he still
had it and and he ended up passing it
all throughout Oregon and then he
brought it back to me um so back crossed
another
time and then I don't remember what
happened cops came or I lost C cut uh
and then from there I started um going
F1 F2 F3 with it uh but like cash
Cropper again early um all like every
seed comes out identical there's no
there's no
variation right that's that's the
ultimate right like for me anyways like
if I release something I want it to be
uniform
right right that was that was my goal
for uh outdoor is like I wanted to grow
100 seeds of of one variety and I wanted
to be able to mix everything together
and have no one know the difference yeah
right um so that that's that was always
the goal so all like my heavily worked
stuff all of that comes out you know
identical good bre eaters everything's
the same you're not gonna get crazy
variation or nothing like that you know
of course there's slight slight little
differences maybe one tastes a little
bit more than the other but they all
have the same tur profile you know but
compared to like the lines compared to
the lines even 15 20 years ago it's it
the the uniformity is vastly different
though right like that's the thing
there'd be small differences but to most
people they wouldn't even probably
notice those differences most people
aren't going to know the differences at
all but me you know since I'm attached
to them and uh you know I'm my worst
critic um I always feel like I could do
better you know I got got a fridge full
of stuff that I've never released there
are people are like dude let them out
let them out but like I'm just not 100%
with them
so they're just tucked
away I wanted to ask you sort of an open
question here so you mentioned gelato
before and obviously you someone who's
known for working with older stuff and
you know preserving some of that what's
it like to work with modern hypee stuff
what are your thoughts on
that um I haven't worked too much stuff
uh the stuff that worked with I got more
her hermaphrodites out of them the the
newer stuff all all the cookie stuff
yeah
um the gelato 33 has been my favorite
more more because of the structure of
the plant it grows big uh super easy the
buds are really big it's pretty it
smells good super easy to grab or like
the other one right super easy yeah it
it was more the structure of it so I'm
uh this year I'm starting to work with
bringing in that look but um keep
keeping my keeping my flavors like you
know I'm going to try to get mix the uh
my first is I'm I'm going to work a 707
Kush into a uh it's a it's a Oreos cross
to Lemon Cherry gelato um did a r them
and they they came from uh obsolete I
did a big run of them
um like most modern stuff not much
flavor to it uh kind of like a doll
vanilla yeah flavor not much but looks
incredible there was is your decision to
work with some of the stuff
strategic in the sense of like you know
so yeah yeah
yeah so this cut that I'm starting to
work with it finishes really really
early outside end of September um looks
like indoor but it lacks flavor it it
lacks it lacks Soul really it um has no
flavor and not much of a buz to it so my
plan is U I'm gonna incorporate the 707
Kush grow a [ __ ] ton of seeds pick out
the ones that have the look but the the
that OG can to it um smoke him if it
gets me high goes round two right uh and
these are I'm going to just do fence
right I'm going to do and then I'll make
s1's of them and then I'll also cross um
sister plants together you know and then
from that just go
forward get the potency get the flavor I
want but have this modern day look and
that that's the plan I'm going to start
doing with everything that I like
smoking so I'm G first is that the um
the 707 Kush which is Perfect Blend of
the cam and ogi um yeah and then next
plan is with the potion get get the
forbidden fruit flavor in there and
uh I didn't I should have done it but um
well actually I didn't even have the
plant when I was making the lemon tree
ones but also the lemon in there as
well
yeah you know um early on like in our
show I talk about breeding and the
difference between breeding seed making
and and when I've when I've spoken about
you before on the show I refer to you as
a breeders breeder and I just wanted to
illustrate this is why because you don't
you don't do things with with no
intention everything has a reason it's
an art piece that you're trying to
create it's not just oh [ __ ] it I'm
gonna see what happens type thing with
everything you know so I I really
appreciate that I hope everybody uh
Tunes in on that
thanks thanks man and the the other
thing with that um Oreo's Lemon Cherry
gelato it finished he early so if I can
get the look that have it finish early
but have a potency of of OG's and the
flavor of OG's or you know whatever kind
of flavor that's the ultimate goal
that's what um that's what I'm gonna try
to work on like this next year so um and
they're they're going to be fem so I
think it'll go pretty quick rather than
you know like with males like if if I
try to chase that hype strain by the
time I'm I'm done making it a thousand
other people have already made it right
absolutely by the time like I'm happy
with it release it
it's it's it's already gone done and
moved on to something else so um that's
why I see all my like the older strains
with me that's a I like what you but
outdoor production like what you
implying here as well like the sense
that like on the one hand you're being
fashion forward but you're also kind of
sticking to your guns and trying to
preserve like what you already know to
be ideal for yourself in the end I'm
really making seeds just for myself um I
I just got lucky enough to be able to
make a buck off of them now I feel
really blessed off of it but really it's
like what what what do I need and what's
going to fit my needs is uh is something
that finishes hell like outdoor
Greenhouse more outdoor I'm thinking of
usually is it I want to finish really to
have the look I want it to [ __ ] taste
good and I want it to get you really
high is is is the goal and and and to be
able to like grow out 100 seeds outside
and them all turn out exactly the
same you know and especially now with
the whole legal market and these
commercial guys like uh you can you
imagine if they were able to grow
something like that not have to worry
about Hermes or nothing like that and
all the plants turn out the
same their their yield has just you know
it'll easily go up 25% to 50% by doing
seed and less and less uh and less
problems you know insects all that stuff
you know the the seed [ __ ] does way
better than than a clone does absolutely
absolutely and now you have to worry
about hlv with clone and all sorts of
other issues too you
know oh yeah yeah I I experienced that
for the first time this year um I got
some clones and I I really don't bring
in clones too
often um we ended up getting some random
folks this year and and funky and I was
like what the [ __ ] going on with this
and started looking it up and then send
send everything to the lab and boom
there it is it's [ __ ] positive now
now I'm freaking out thinking oh my God
it spread to everything anyhow luckily
it didn't spread and I kept on retesting
and retesting you know not everything
comes back negative now but that was
kind of scary it is scary Library
right man back in the day
like we never had powdery Milo in the
90s like that that wasn't a thing at all
like I didn't even know about that until
like the early 2000s and uh it was
actually when Ed Rosenthal started
selling clones and and his uh his his
growth facilties were the ones that
[ __ ] were covered in it and he ended
up spreading power rebuild you across
the world with the [ __ ] [ __ ] yeah and
then it's just that easy what was it
like maybe 10 years ago the [ __ ]
russet mites and and Broad mites came
out that was all brand new now you got
[ __ ] hopl and whatever but that's why
you go with seeds no problems but then I
was reading that the [ __ ] hop lien
goes into the seed too so that's pretty
scary so we've talked about that a
little bit I interviewed um uh hlv
specialist um and she I was I was
getting real specific with the questions
because I wanted to know
like does this transmit in cannabis at
that 8% rate that people keep quoting
and the fact is they haven't done any
tests on cannabis and Seed Transmissions
rate they're bringing over uh rates from
Hops and just kind of assuming that it's
going to be the same but knowing exactly
who's working with Duds out there what
clones are dted and how many of the seed
makers are using them and people are
popping those seeds it can't be 8% it
just can't like it would be so massive
right now everywhere through through
seed distribution so I'm not sure but
yeah the tests were hops based the 8%
thing but it it will be interesting to
see over time how it turns out yeah
totally totally yeah no there's some
scary [ __ ] out there and um I'm I'm done
bringing in
clones I got I did get a really good
Sour Diesel this year I was pretty
stoked on and I grew uh that motor
breath 15 for the first time good one
pretty stoked on that one too
yeah it's nice it's nice division Kem
and OG is that what it is chem OG it's
it's it's cookies something cookie no it
no uh motor breaths chmd OG chem D OG
okay yeah that makes sense I get the the
chmd flavor comes through and it's
potent it's a real potent yeah it's a
good one but besides yeah I'm not
bringing in any more PLS
anymore are there are there any breeders
are there any breeders out now um or not
even now like in the past that you'd
like to highlight and say like yeah they
did some pretty cool [ __ ] and I I think
they deserve some props uh spice alive
reader Steve the the [ __ ] that he did in
Switzerland um yeah dude all all the all
the stuff that he made in Switzerland
was was uh awesome back in the day um
yeah looked good smelled good uh Bubble
Bags just came out that around that time
they all washed hella
good um and everything was
consistent you grow out a pack of seeds
and most of them all [ __ ] turned out
how they were supposed to right um his
stuff was really good and then the uh
Shanti Baba stuff back in the 90s yeah
what was really good and I'm not 100%
sure but I I I heard he was like you
know making seeds for other companies
like uh homegrown fantas seeds you know
he and he would just and
I remember those FAS seeds too they had
an Afghani that was really really good
and all of them came out pretty
consistent um I never see their stuff at
at all anymore they used to be a big
brand and had a coffee shop and
everything and now you don't see anybody
in nothing in anybody's collections from
homegrown fantasies anymore kind of
sucks yeah yeah with uh with because
I've grown out a lot of the Mr Nice it's
definitely not the same as it was in the
90s yeah right like uh so yeah who knows
but yeah those were the two guys from
back in the day that stood out and then
um I could go on forever and ever with
people that I was disappointed with but
we won't go yeah
right that's weed bro that's
weed I wanted to zoom out a bit and ask
about the other kinds of breeding that
sha has mentioned like dog chicken
rabbit breeding and like what has he
picked up from there and like what
translates to cannabis breeding um it
it's uh
man I think it's all the same it's uh
all like all life breeding it it it's
kind of all the same even with people
it's crazy but um it's it's all very
similar like you got an idea like the
rabbits um they're meat rabbits so like
let's say uh one of them's got a big big
legs the Hinds but but the backstrap is
is isn't as big as it could be so then
you know I would take a male that has a
big back strap and cross it to the ones
with the big hind legs or uh you know
with with dogs I always go for structure
I want them to look a certain way uh
bullies I don't know it's just the
ghetto of some reason I can't get rid of
them
um holy stocky look right and it's the
same thing you just got to you just got
to add or take away you know you find
um opposites I find like op Crossing
opposites are the best unless you got
something in in mind like do you want to
shrink a dog to hella small then you
just keep taking the smallest ones
reading them together or uh but it like
let's say uh for full like hybrid Vigor
uh I find Crossing opposites do the best
and I also like my myself I find uh um
like
people uh find the most attractive
people like the
opposite uh black white Chinese white
right it's so like it's all pretty much
the same doesn't matter what you're
breeding like um it's all kind of the
same
um yeah yeah yep traits y traits traits
traits traits and and the longer I've
been into this that's the one thing I've
realized like I I paid so much attention
to the stories that people would tell
about these plants and then try to match
up different things to the stories to
see if it held true and in the end I
realized [ __ ] you can just follow traits
from the beginning all the way through
these lines and see what the role story
is like you really can do that it's
possible if you have enough experience
yeah totally totally like uh I mean
let's just the the lemon tree for
example like um the Wy guy says there's
no sour diesel but inside of it but when
I was growing him out there was
definitely uh s Sour Diesel inside of it
right you can follow the the back um
same thing with dogs uh uh like you know
when you start breeding them and if you
get if you got a list of the parents and
the family tree pretty much you can
start pinpointing what what goes to
where and who does what you know that's
got to be fascinating actually never
thought about it that
way that's pretty cool I [ __ ] love
it it's
it's I don't know but interesting kind
of like psychological thing
um to kind of like deal with all these
possibilities and try to map like
possible outcomes tendencies that kind
of thing yeah absolutely um you know and
and it I would say half the time it
works out the other half like I always I
always have these things envisioned in
my head like crossing different flavors
how it's going to turn out this and the
other and rarely does it ever uh like I
would say you know 50 % of the time it
actually does maybe even less than that
but um it's all trial and error at the
end of the day it's it all comes down to
trial and error you know you mentioned
art before and I think there is a
distinct analogy there
because there's only there's only so
much you can control you know you can
only control like some portion of it and
the rest of it is just uh you know
charts various other parameters but that
whole thing is is an art you know
navigating that totally that's have I've
always felt it's it's my world um you
know even with my dogs like when like
people walking by them I want them to be
like oh that's one of [ __ ] Shaw's
dogs right like just by how they look is
is uh is the ultimate goal so do you uh
have any thoughts on how different
cannabis breeding let's see what does it
say different how different the Cannabis
breeding Market is now in 2023 compared
to when you started the the the seed
Market how different it is yeah yeah
yeah well [ __ ] anyone with a tent can be
make a seed company now right yeah right
you got Instagram
bro yeah like I I I uh like I said I'm
out of the loop um I don't I don't
really I'm just kind of focused on my in
my own head and things that I'm doing I
don't really I don't like I don't I
don't know what anybody's really doing
anymore
yeah it's probably the smartest move man
the least amount of Dramas involved when
you keep your head low and out of that
and just stick to the
art yeah exactly exactly I I hate the
drama behind it so I just don't
even I'm not in it ever
yeah I get the sense that like your life
takes you in many other directions and
you don't you don't need to spend all
your time like in this
world uh yeah you know I I did the can
the can of community thing for a long
time and and it's definitely changed um
a lot uh the past 10 15 years um you
know everybody before
like I mean now everything is Corporate
pretty much you know it's uh
yeah the handshake the handshake and
your your uh your word doesn't mean [ __ ]
anymore um where back in the day it was
like that's what [ __ ] made everything
turn was was a guy's word and their
their handshake um
I don't know the the whole the whole
thing has changed uh the seed Market you
know the seed Market actually there's a
lot more people but probably hasn't
really changed much at all I mean it's
kind of the same like you know DJ Short
Stuff let's say for example you know he
came out with blueberry and then all of
a sudden um bunch of different companies
[ __ ] rebranded his his blueberry
which I'm sure that all all that [ __ ]
still goes
on I was saying that that's never going
to change that's always going to be
there uh the shenanigans pretty
much always always it's a black market
you know so it's like even even in a
white Market though it's just like
inherently scumbags are attracted to
anything they think makes money
fast that's uh I I hate the legal Market
I hate I hate corporate and and uh how
people are like you know the I I I trust
the black market a 100 times more than I
do the Leal Market I trust people in the
black market more than I do people in
the legal Market absolutely there's no
honor and it there's no uh everything is
a dollar sign like people just look at
you with dollars in their eyes uh
there's there's no more Community
there's no more you know um helping each
other out or anything like that but it
it is what it is it is what it
is so with that said is there any other
work you'd like to highlight that we
didn't touch on that you're working on
now or in the past you'd like to bring
some attention to I'm working on uh
bringing all like my favorite smoke
stuff into fem uh like my own
work um I'm G to be digging through some
of these blueberry uh these uh um blue
nectar seeds that I got and start
working that
heavily um the potions um uh I made
those this summer which I'm going to
start digging through here soon see how
those turn out but I'm pretty excited
about those there's some flavors that
like I've never come across in cannabis
in those um like just mouthwatering
greatness fruity uh like artificial
candy fruit punch like a fruit punch
down later or something like that that's
nice so I'm excited about that what else
I got going on
um whole bunch of [ __ ] I don't know I
got my hands full so
slowly but surely
busy yeah yeah so where can people find
your work if they want to get
it um I'm about to actually launch uh uh
my websites I'm gonna start doing
[ __ ] direct
sales I love it I love hearing it man I
wish every breeder would do direct sales
I think it's it's necessary now it's
kind of a necessary
thing yeah totally um I'm working on
credit card process it it's actually up
and running right now but it's not
working um I'm just waiting for this
bank to accept my uh credit card
application so hopefully here in a week
or two that should be up and running and
then um there's a list of people on
there as well they can find there you go
what's a website see
that's 707 seed bank.com 707 Seedbank
and and then I got a bunch of like uh
bulk seeds uh that are all great but
they just didn't uh for some one reason
or another like I got a bunch of like
love candy crosses on there that uh like
the M the moms took over the structure
but it's they all have the love candy
flavor to it just this melony which they
all do great but I didn't feel like
anything was improved right so I never
like released those but I was like [ __ ]
it do bulk seeds bucket seed absolutely
see how they
do yeah bunch of other random
[ __ ] well with that I want to thank you
for uh coming and spending your time
with us dude it's been a real honor and
again like I said like my first my first
experience knowing who you were was
talking to other people that had been
around a long time and they'd be all you
know the every single story would be you
know you know Shabad right oh who is
this guy and I learn more more and more
and the more I learned the more I
respected you so I I I appreciate you
taking your time to talk to us I know a
lot of people have been waiting for this
forever so uh I definitely wanted to
thank you
cheers all right man thank you app you
so much it's been a bless any any last
words you want to get
in no thank you guys appreciate being on
here it's been a blast all right brother
well thanks for have uh thanks for
coming on and spending your time with us
and uh hopefully we'll have you again
soon you're up for it right on guys want
to sit at the table with The Syndicate
check out our patreon and our link tree
or description below our merch site is
officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is topnotch I've
been saving old designs for years for
this purpose so please check it out
Syndicate gear.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it
out