ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
how you doing
good how are you doing everybody
so-called liquid silica product is made
from potassium silicate and that's where
your ph issues come into play uh
problems with raising the ph
so uh we it
we can get it from other sources a
couple of the posters here mentioned
rice halls and that's true there's even
a powdered rice hole product that build
a soil carries i can't remember the name
but i've used it and it did well
one person asked a very legitimate
question
is it even necessary
and
um
it depends like in my worm bins i run a
lot of uh rice holes as an aeration
material
so when that deconstruct is releasing
the uh
silica oxide i believe that's the form
it's in
so would i add it to my soil no
but
you know so that question isn't
you need some silicon in your soil
and if you use it judiciously
and get like the uh egg sale product
because that's what all the other ones
like the silly one from
oh the guy advanced nutrients wet betty
or something so yeah um
even a sillier label but uh
it's made from axil i mean all those
products that you see in the grow store
or what i call the house of perdition
um
they're all made with eggs so get exile
yeah you know and then cut the chase
and it's in a powder form so you mix on
an as need basis
um and it's good for emulsifying
horticultural oils i don't want to get
into that mess uh neem or karate oils or
whatever but uh
yeah and i still use them and they're
full of crap the people you know
yeah
you gotta learn the difference between
an extract
and oppressing but you know that's like
trying to explain why is it called
unsulfured and not desulford
molasses and if you can't wrap your
brain around that one
then i don't want to talk to you about
the differences between an extraction
and using solvents
a pressing that goes back at least 3 000
years you know whatever
i'll get off myself how do you feel
about
uh how do you feel about um like like
power side the the ortho silicic acids
and and and monolithic acids stuff
that's not from potassium silicate
you know to be honest with you i'm a
real minimalist
um if you looked at my recipe
uh
the biggest criticism is well there's no
there there well it's all in the worm
castings
you know i don't
look i think everybody should
recycle their kitchen waste if you don't
do that you should have to be forced to
listen to some tv show that's really
horrible or something
but it's not going to give you a worm
casting it's too much water and as much
as those worms are they can't turn water
into castings yeah so you need bulk and
that comes from either
aged manure and by that we mean five to
six weeks
to allow the
um
vermicides that are given livestock for
like we do dogs you worm them right yeah
well those vermicides kill
the good guys in our worm bins you need
to let that sit for about five to six
weeks and they'll degrade
into a form
into its basic uh
ionic structure if that makes sense
yeah so it's no longer a verbicide it's
carbon and hydrogen and oxygen and all
those good things
so we want to use that that gives us
bulk
and that's how you make good castings
it's it's through bulking yeah without
the stuff that had there's some
i'll leave it at that yes
good good cat a good uh bedding that's
been
uh
elevated with uh nutrient dense
materials like
small amounts of alfalfa meal
uh kelp meal i like to run neem and
karanja
this might you might find interesting
karanja is actually
a legume it's it's closer to a uh
alfalfa plant than it is the neem tree
which is a mahogany
and the properties in those two
materials couldn't be more different
there's no shared
constituents as a directon comes from
neem and
hungamia oil
comes from karanja i'm not familiar with
karaja what what what is that used for
well in india it's the preferred one for
medicines for uh
uh
skin products uh
and india has some of its own race
issues the beliefs that lighter colored
citizens are more intelligent than
darkerness said to be used to lighten
the skin tone i know that it can
uh
but if you if you went into an indian
market and went to the haba section
everything would have either neem or
quarantine you know shampoo toothpaste
um but over here if you get touched with
dean you're gonna fall over dead or
something or
you know you can't go to the rose parade
or something i don't know
but um
yeah i mean
uh
means but if you looked at the ayurvedic
medical system you know you have the tcm
traditional chinese india has the
ayurvedic and 72
of the uh
bottled
compounds you know um
elixirs and stuff 72
have some part of the neem tree root
bark
leaf
oil
um
and it's behind the tulsi
basil which is a forerunner of all
basils like the
wolf is to the our canine friends
well this one okay it's the most holy
plant in india is the tulsi
and then neem is the second one
so
anyway there you go at all
look up there
research.ca
uh
is nothing to do with gardening nothing
okay it's all about human health uh
diabetes uh
uh viruses uh all kinds of things you
can rub the oil on your feet
as a
cure or a prevention of athlete's foot
if you
do a lot of uh running or you know
whatever
so yeah it's been around for 5 000 years
but suddenly 18 months ago became a
you know point of discussion at uh
canacon and uh yeah endo expo you know
it's just silly you know whatever
all this is appreciated there's people
asking all kinds of questions uh go
ahead i don't mean to dominate there but
oh no worries no worries i'm enjoying it
um let's see
why my why is my worm casting running
hot and sodium and then uh and you think
i can push out sodium with calcium
gypsum
no because uh gypsum is simply uh
oh calcium sulfate and it's calcium in
its elemental form whereas the calcium
we get in say limestone
or uh oyster shell that's calcium
calcium carbonate
so there's one
calcium ion
there's one carbon ion and then three
oxygen ions
and calcium carbonate but in this
in gypsum you're getting calcium by
itself
and then you get sulfur oxide which is
water soluble
yeah and so what and like let's say
you're using core
uh
one thing that has to be
you know acknowledged is that it's an
inert
medium that's why it's
preferred if you're going to use salts
but
in a uh
organic soil it's a nightmare
yes what you want to do the big one
that's missing is sulfur and without
sulfur
the sulfur is at the base of almost
every metabolical function on this
planet including the production of
terpenes terpenoids and ketones so it'd
be a really good idea
i'm using corn i can't get any of flavor
and i don't get any aroma
okay put a half a cup of uh gypsum
you know and say a cubic foot and there
you go you're dancing
yeah yeah that's something i had to
learn on my own too to add add sulfur
some kind of sulfur too too because i
use core that's all i use right so i
like a mix i like to add in a calcium
carbonate like limestone or oyster shell
it doesn't matter the same thing
and then a little bit of gypsum so i'm
getting my elemental calcium along with
my calcium carbonate and then i'm also
picking up
uh some gypsum
so i think that's that's a good balance
if you i don't like using this term but
a liming agent if you will
yeah for like a better one
okay we have a request here on um the
history of the strain the one which is
one i've been fascinated with for a long
time myself okay uh pretty simple um
in laguna beach in the late 60s and
early 70s before
the whole lsd thor and sunshine thing
took them apart
you know
it's one thing to taunt a dog behind the
fence with a stick but you don't want to
do that with the federal government yeah
that's especially when listening in
containers
contains like a patch
okay those are like 48 000 you know i
mean
these guys weren't just a dude
we got to see the dude and get some
stash tonight you know this is like
you know you gotta bite even then 10
kilos to even
communicate but anyway
so the seeds came a lot of the guys
because they're in the bl there was like
it had to be 13 right 13 original
founding members
yeah that was a good one okay yeah and
so seven were part of this ragtag
motorcycle club
that used to hang out this really weird
bar not far from disneyland
uh they were just you know
drinkers and you know like rowdy bikers
it was the 60s man so
there was also this group of surfers
in the mid 60s that were traveling
around the world as
it was easy to do
maybe easier than today and when surfing
in the surfing spots all had
somebody there with good wheat so they
started bringing some good weed back
because they knew how to pass their
boards
so they could make a hole in the board
and stash in a pound or two
and so that's then the two got together
and then the whole thing so
the seed that i had were from kandahar
1970. and i don't know exactly who
brought him in
the whole
story
okay so then i went off to the army and
got drafted
kicking and screaming to send the women
and children first
um but off to save the world and make it
safer democracy
so it came back and uh
in the december of 1976 the first
thai stakes came in okay and they came
in uh 10 kilo
bales 20 of those pounds were
sticks
and
since emilia was still two or three
years away
so they were seedy is all get out
and uh there was then two pounds of
loose buds that of course had to be
renamed the buddha buds
yeah yeah i've heard of that yeah okay
so those seeds became the first crop i
ever did that summer in 77
and there was no growth stores there was
no new program
i don't not even sure
i even would know what to do if i had a
bottle of maxi or miracle grow or
whatever you know
yeah but i understood that you had to
water plants and that was it for the
banking loss you could walk into a car
dealer and buy four
celicas if you want and
pay cash and it was no big deal yeah
later in the reagan administration you
know
yeah
just saying no that crowd
so uh
so that was a female and
there were 10 plants that were selected
out of this mass
i'm not a breeder so if i told you you
guys be laughing so this was like
climbed by the seat of my pants just be
reliant about it you know well that's
early on though no one was really
well there were no companies and the
guys in california were still dinking
around with goofy names you know
yeah um i had a couple but
i would have named that's another story
um
so
that one uh the way it got the name was
that
they were all against the wall and they
went from sativa over to
afghani dominant
which i had no interest in at all
so i just said okay the one over here is
mine and so oh so it's like the one huh
no it's like the one over here is mine
okay and that became a running joke you
know he still does the one yeah still
got the one
and uh
so that's just like you know it has
nothing to do with i thought it was like
oh yeah it's like the one no i've had
the one that came from sri lanka and i
didn't want to
ever smoke weed again
it was like that far out you know it was
like yeah
some hindus i mean real hindu not
you know he picked it up in new delhi i
mean like in the cush valley or
something you know from the saudis yeah
so that's all they you know no big deal
and um but ironic is
that i've given that way i've never sold
a clone in my life
the last time i sold a seed was 77
uh that's early that is early yeah i
take ty seeds you know because i had
them
yeah because
i learned early on that if i was going
to take the risk of
being a
serious consumer cannabis that you might
as well do the good stuff
so i would sell like
i know you think i'm not but say i would
get fronted like a ton or two of uh
colombia
from guys in uh
detroit with way too many vowels in
their last name
they'd give you like two months to turn
it
yes so our motto was i don't want to own
it i just want to fingerprint it meaning
you know bump it 25 30 bucks
yep and just keeps it you know so then i
would turn around and go buy like
premium mishma khan
or yahaka o'hakan spears were personal
and he went to sears got a deep freezer
so i could freeze it
you know so i could buy three or four
pounds you know that kind of stuff
that's [ __ ] awesome yeah so that was
yeah you know can i just say one thing
about skunk number one
sure i mean going back to the like
original mid 80s
yeah i don't get it
what do you mean
as far as like why it's called skunk in
the first place i
you know it's like
i just don't get the whole thing about
it
i mean why like it's that desirable
oh okay now i understand that one okay
okay i can i can understand that one
okay it's like yeah
yeah one of my favorites somebody will
give me a
bud to try what do you think
now it says
so did you clone this more than twice
why
yeah it's made it through three rounds
but yeah i mean yeah come on
uh
one nice thing about growing an old
strain
is that you really can test the soil
because you can't test this off oh this
time i'm gonna do
i don't know skittles or piddles or
whatever it's called right
um yeah yeah okay and then you over here
well i'm gonna try this syrup but i'm
gonna use
i know cookies or whatever the thing is
you know whatever the hot button is
but with me
i mean i can tell you by day 24
uh
i'm not going to finish this i
appreciate
you let me try it but you know
best wishes uh go back to the drawing
board
so
that and so in my opinion which means
nothing
is that at least if i test something for
you i can give you a an accurate
comparison analysis of one
uh that i've you know grown like forever
yeah
the main reason people don't like mine
is that if you really want to get the
full you know
twilight zone theme comes on right here
um
you got to do at least 12 if not 14
weeks
and here's the best part this is the
part i love the best
i've taken at 18 weeks just to see what
it would take to get the trikes to turn
even cloudy
it doesn't ever happen never
so you're never going to get the amber
forget that one
all right yeah
let alone cloudy
no never goes cloudy even outdoors like
seven months where you like southern
california where you can take it through
november into december
yeah it never no it never goes cloudy
that has to be the highland tie that has
to be
i would think so maybe if you tried like
way less light hours like six hours like
oh yeah oh yeah i still didn't do it
over the years i've done every
i've never when i was uh ignorant
got into that well you know you need
this bulb okay
uh
yeah right
this bulb will make it finish yeah
this bulb will make it faster yeah yeah
right there yeah you need this magic
stuff what's in i can't say it's
proprietary
excuse me you know
so
but anyway that's
that's my you know just a guy that
decided to get into soil real serious
and figure out
i have post on my uh ig feed
of a soil test that i mixed five years
ago
and it has all the npk it has all the
macro and micro nutrients
and you know we're a little weak in the
microsoft throw some kelp in there
that's why kelp is the perfect one
because it's a plant right
and it accumulates all 83 elements more
importantly in the right value if we
don't go nuts
that's adding some kelp will take care
of all our micronutrient issues
wow i see i didn't even know that
it's the only brown kill makes sense not
not blue marine algae not
red but a green i mean green red but
brown only brown is the only
organism on this planet that creates
algenic acid
and i'll just i'll leave you for
research on that but you can see why
brown kelp has algenic acid seaweed
extract is created by by law under
federal
usda regulations has to be created with
either sodium
uh hydroxide or potassium hydroxide the
stuff they use in drano to clean out
your uh
drain so they use that and they burn
everything off so what are you left with
you're left with powder
you got your elements you might as well
just do salts see what i mean
yeah all the life force is gone
yeah but it's convenient
but a convenience that
is detrimental to your soil in my
opinion
i don't want to put a fungicide
in my soil after i've spent
several months building up the nutrient
yeah and fungal profile in my compost
before i ever hit a warm bin
um can i ask you
are you self-researched and you just you
just delved into it hardcore and learned
it all on your own are you are you
oh no no no no i'm academically yeah i
was going to say this is pretty pretty
heavy academic stuff yeah but the real
stuff is that you have to do it
you have to get your hands dirty there's
no bottle solution there's hey it's it's
hard work and if you want to have
scratch in the game
you got to do it
and be consistent don't
don't be my phone because we released my
product today
oh good hey there it's patty the one
with uh how you doing malted barley
malted or heirloom corn and uh hemp
seeds and where can people get this oh
build a soil it's called don't laugh
like this i named it so i don't know i
want to sound cool uh gnarly barley
gnarly barley yes fifty percent uh
barley and it's uh thirty 30
corn that's for the cytokinins
yeah
and then the hemp
which i can spend a couple days
explaining all the enzymes and compounds
well you know from
it kind of goes like this if it works
good on a plant it's probably good for
you and vice versa
that's interesting
ouch
the benefits from the hemp seed
and all all multi means means nothing
more than this it means that you took a
seed
and you germinated it
and then you arrested it about 116
fahrenheit but that does
it leaves the uh
enzymes intact so we call that diastatic
mold
now if we take that
mold after it's dried and ready to store
you give you a shout out and we uh
caramelize it
for flavor
or aroma for ales and what have you
that's great
but it kills all the enzymes so now we
call that non-diastatic malt and if you
use non-diastatic malt in your beer
formula
then you need to add
the diastatic mold because you can't
make beer without amylase is the main
player
uh enzyme in the barley but that's not
what we benefit from
can i explain this because this is
really important
so all plants produce chitinase
and chitin
itself is an acetyl form of glucosamine
okay all seashells contain
are made up from limestone
or calcium carbonate okay okay but the
crustaceans the the crab the lobster the
shrimp
and i guess that would also include the
one in the south uh crawdads yeah have
chitin
and kyden for example you had surgery
either oral or external they probably
showed you up with kite and string
okay um that goes back to like the 1880s
this has really got an instant
connection so in 1922 this young man by
the name of albert hoffman graduates
from cologne university and his paper is
on the molecular structure of chitin
and then
21 years later he would introduce
or find lsd 25 and then 15 years after
that he was commissioned to do the
research on these
mushrooms out of uh
oaxaca
and he's the one that gave the name to
the two compounds psilocybin and silicon
so in a 15-year period here he does lsd
read his book lsd my problem child
there you go write it down right book
and then anyway so
the only thing that can deconstruct
microbially that can deconstruct
a polysaccharide uh
is fungi
bacteria in their weak attempt to try to
deconstruct it create an enzyme called
chitinase
and chitinase deconstructs eggshells in
the soil
so that's kind of cool you don't have to
get a poison yeah yeah
and then equally important
animal kingdom and plant kingdom have
immune systems
and in plants you have like har hormonal
acquired resistance and sars
systemic acquired resistance and some of
them are called pathways the most
important pathway in a plant's defense
system uh is um
the chitinaya salicylic acid pathway
okay and
every plant
produces uh
salicylic gas feeling like an
interaction some plants produce copious
amounts like the aloe vera plant
you've probably heard in your career oh
you can use willow shoots
oh yeah okay well that's salicylic acid
okay and so that's why people would use
aloe vera for that's why i know i
started that i said look man i'm not
climbing a tree
i can go to a mexican market and get a
fresh aloe vera leaf
and you just cut off the spiny stuff on
the sides and you stick your stems in
there
inside the gel let's sit overnight and
the next day
put them in how are we i don't want to
get into that one but how you do your
cuts yeah and that salicylic acid
creates a barrier uh against pathogenic
fungi your molds and all that
i average seriously over 98
success using just that and i don't
but that's actually the best one is you
can find true
like the sign on the side of the road
that says honey so it's never been
touched yeah it's just you straight
hunting
yeah
wow
i had no clue about that yeah it's
really cool but you got to get organic
because
what they do to honey from the time they
pull it from the beehive so i guess in
that jar with a little bear you know all
that stuff yeah um
it's a sad story you know it's not like
the real deal you know yeah
but anyway so that's why if we use
malted grains in our soil
the kitinis you don't have to go through
the expense of using crab meal
because what you're really after is the
chitinase not the chitin
yeah so here you get it right in the uh
malted grains along with uranus urea
protease protein
phosphatase what cannabis grower doesn't
obsess about phosphorus right
yeah uh
much of their arrow usually um yeah
right yeah but you get the idea i mean
so there's like 360
enzymes in a malted grain
so what i can do and have done is i can
document okay here are the ends
you could take something out from under
your fingernail and put it in water and
say it's got enzymes
oh yeah okay
but i can explain each one and how they
work and i'm only taking like 10 out of
the 360
that are in barley so
and then you add corn to the cytokinins
and what that does to
between the tip of the root system and
then the uh mary stem
at the end of the branches is quite a
phenomenal uh study and the first uh
cytokinin was discovered in corn in
1937 and the latin name for corn is zia
so they named this enzyme zeatin
um makes sense yeah so that's and
there's other uh there's other pgrs and
other things in the corn besides
that one enzyme excuse me hormone
yeah so anyway
i was just thinking botany 101 probably
bored your audience there but uh no no i
think everybody's [ __ ] loving it to
be honest with you um i love it
i'd love to have you on anytime you are
bored want to come on i i know it's a
real treat for me and everyone else so i
really appreciate it because i like
talking to uh gardeners
instead of a salesman you know yeah man
it's a pleasure
have you ever looked at my feed
your what my feed yeah okay you've seen
some of the plants
yes okay i wanted a ten and a half
pounder
yes yes don't you think it's a little
disingenuous to come on my feet and tell
me what i should be doing
oh my good lord yeah yeah that's
everybody's uh everybody knowing that
i'm gonna scholarly
right
yeah sometimes i wanna say is maybe like
do more reading and
not so much
editorial stuff you know until you kind
of
uh
i figured i've been involved in at least
yeah at least 300
serious gardens in my career
yeah i can imagine so dude
hey the first slice they ever bought was
some jor oh yeah he was called george
cervantes then before he became jorge
so uh yeah he had a place here in
portland it was one of three grow stores
in portland at the time that was it
and uh
we went and bought these uh dutch lights
from pl light systems
okay i mean the professional stuff i was
gonna burn down my house in orange
county california
you know trying to grow some weed so we
decided
there was you know
funding was available i'll leave it at
that so uh yeah we decided to set it up
first cabin and uh i was using uh what
do you call them oh dosatrons
30 years ago
that's funny yeah and buying like full
jugs i think they were five gallons
you have dyna girl and dinah bloom uh
we'd ride down to uh
there was some in the bay area like san
jose something like that
yeah and uh so we just put the dosatron
inside the jugs
and then i had i did the drip system i
mean
by today's standard you guys got it made
i mean it's all off the shelf and
plugging play for the most part you know
we had to kind of like huh
so how are we going to do this
one time pulling stuff out of the field
and staging it next to the pickup trucks
and uh
the guy that was like our leader i
called him op8 our personal
hero and in this case i just said some
dick have you given a thought where
you're gonna dry this
and everybody just looks down at the
ground like
oh man
and we're using bull tacos to go back
into the forest to get the
the plants where i can bring them back
and stage them you know
so
uh the horizon
i know he's friends with some of the
northern lights period did you interact
with those guys at all
no not at all because that came out of
what they called the
bcga the british columbia growers
association
and uh
the nl came out of canada
on a guy that broke you see the bcga
wasn't going to do business with any of
the two groups that came out of holland
the what is now called scentsy seeds
then it was called the sssc
and then uh neville and uh his partner
uh david yeah
so yeah
they wandered around and everybody had
cash you know
yeah a briefcase is full of cash and
they were buying seeds and cuts
so
i think northern light came out from a
grower in in canada
that
said hey man you know you
you cut hay when the sun shines you got
money i'm selling so uh
that's how the nl thing
went over to uh
uh
neville's deal the seed bank that was
the only time everybody sees in my life
i bought them one time
uh hayes northern lights
and did you find any keepers in it did
you find good stuff in it
i never bought another seat again in my
life
that i've you know
every story i hear about old older
growers that we're growing the northern
lights hays in its heyday they all have
very very fond memories and they talk
about how many keepers were found that
became like one clone only that are
still around nowadays well there is a
caveat to my comment i want to make this
is really important here's where you're
getting conflicting things
in a case that i was indirectly
i wasn't involved but
i was on the possible list of uh come
talk to us
back in boston
and
in discovery it came out that the dea
and the u.s postal service was
intercepting letters
from the seed banks to customers here
and they were switching it out with uh
ditch weed seeds
this was in discovery this is what they
came to the you know here's our evidence
evidence whatever they call it i'm not
an attorney but yeah they'll sit around
before they do lunch or something and
decide how they're going to screw you
yeah
yeah so i mean then that just like
it clicked but have you ever noticed how
many times in your life
you've been back in the forum day before
the social media okay like i see mag or
grass you know that
people go well they sure my plans sure
don't look like the pictures from the
seed bank
and i just used to think i don't even
want to open this can of worms man i
just
no i'll be i'll be hated on forever for
spilling that one oh yeah people are
going to realize their collection is
worthless and then they're going to
really dislike the messenger yeah yeah
yeah yeah exactly so but no that's uh
honest to god he's like
i just went well that party's over you
know so let's go back to square one
and this thing that we know because we
know who brought him into the united
states
and the whole history
and who who had possession of them and
everything else so
i don't have a lot of confidence
one breeder here
that a farm or whatever they call them
gave me 13 samples
in those little jars with you know uh
yeah probably hold i don't know half a
gram or half an ounce
they had them all gorilla glue
girl scout cookies this did that this
this i've had put them in a bag i
brought them home
they were going to hire me as a
consultant and uh
so my wife's in the kitchen cooking
dinner and i sat down in the living room
and i opened one up and i smelled it i
went god that's really terrible
but
yeah you never know so i
pulled out a nug
and i busted it up and i put it my pipe
and i got half a hit
and i just put it down
it's ridiculous my wife comes around the
corner and she goes what's that smell
and i said oh it's and i don't want a
name because i'll get you know yeah but
it's one that everybody has to have or
you're just a complete [ __ ] right if
you're not growing this one you're
addicted okay yeah
and i just said and so i you know i was
really polite but i said then i called
the next thing i said i just don't see
any
connection i mean
what are we gonna do like redo your soil
i mean
there's just more issues here that i can
even
yeah i need like the biggest spreadsheet
known to god to even get into the
science of why this thing's [ __ ] up so
yeah
i wish you the best and sure enough one
season was over that was the first year
went legal here there was funny money
everywhere
from uh asian banks from european banks
i mean it was insane and who did they
hire a grocery store clerk that that's
your grow guy
really
oh good well you need another cal mag
lockout and handle this one you know
yeah there's no there's no purpose in
consulting for someone that's going to
hire idiots uh all along the side of you
to perform you know complex [ __ ] yeah
and i'm and i'm enough of an egotist and
a clown
i just don't tolerate pools lightly i
mean hey go do whatever you want i wish
you the best you know uh instant karma
whatever you know you gotta have the
audit
but i'm here to grow real medicine
yeah
exactly i'm not here the whole hemp
industry is like that too the whole hemp
industry i i just made my my entrance
into the hemp industry last year and i
was shocked at how many people
are playing grower in that i really
thought i never [ __ ] with it i figured
there are people that are that are
better
than i would be at doing it because
they've been studying specifically hemp
longer working with it longer i figured
they had that [ __ ] [ __ ] dialed in and
boy was i confused when i got in there
and saw the people were just playing
constantly playing
okay i don't know
oh i know yeah why not wild world
without
you know cartwheels and
you know proprietary this and i can't
tell you that and you know i mean
you think let's think about it this way
the issues facing the human race isn't
whether johnny gets his tank on is how
are we going to feed
people
and if this crap worked they'd be
sitting in front of the u.n picking up
checks for billions of dollars
on solving
world hunger right
right
i mean to me it it's that simple
it is that simple
so
that's why like on my new product i'm
donating
of my compensation
to an agency that plants forests around
the world so um
that's beautiful
i just think you know i just think
hey i want everybody to get their dank
on it and if uh
some like newt line i want to do a line
called cooch newts
spelled
c-o-o-t-s with n-o-o-t as coots newt you
know
and i'll just look around and say look
this is what you want i'm feeding
and feeding uh your your deal man your
dharma whatever it is you think you have
to do to grow a plant
i don't know
thank you very much and goodbye
everybody
it's it's my honor to have you on and
i'd love to have you on again anytime
man pleasure
thank you very much bye-bye
thank you fred
what a treat that was [ __ ] he's so smart
i'm gonna have to go re-watch that
several times uh thanks for everyone
stopping in and thanks again to cootes
that was our first conversation that
we've had
so yeah it was a privilege and an honor
take care guys
[Music]
you