[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
live here i'm matthew owner of riot
seeds i'll occasionally be joined by my
cohost not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
[Music]
you got any new news anything good you
can
share with the public share with the
public not quite yet but
not quite yet but i mean i am i am going
on a we'll have to actually see about
next week because i'm going on that
adventure
to uh which one
i'm gonna try to find some long-lost
cutting
oh that one you're going on the
adventure i'm going on the adventure i
think next week yeah so yeah one of our
buddies gonna be super happy about that
yeah i might even be able to get lunch
with them or something that'd be cool
yeah it would be neat
yeah
i hope you get it dude i hope it works
out
so
we are gonna chat
today about a pretty wide topic but
people have been asking a lot about it
um which is sort of like the the whole
like hash plant topic
right because it's meant different
things at different times
and there's a lot of old famous hash
plants
yeah
and there's a lot of breeding that got
bred into those
and then there's a lot of new modern
ones yeah a new modern plants for hash
yeah i mean not only not and by modern i
mean like even like you know there was a
whole new round of named cuts
that oh yeah they got you know hash
plant labels or yeah
different things and now hash plan
actually means
you know something totally different
sure it does
you know um so yeah we're going to kind
of talk widely about hash plants so if
you ever have any hash blank questions
or anything along those lines today is a
great day to shoot them uh and see
what's up
i got all the i got all the catalogs
ready i've got
illustrations ready of said hash plants
most of them
and i even went back and um because
there was one hash plan i thought of
that nobody ever really mentions anymore
but for a while in the
like the 0809 era it was pretty popular
and that was the cuttlefish so i even
dug up info on the old cuttlefish plant
the old cuttlefish so yeah we're going
to go over as many as we can remember
as many of this week so yeah we're going
to talk about the history of hash plant
we're going to talk about a bunch of
specific cuts
people can ask away about specific cuts
they're interested in like like matt
just said he's got a list
um but like maybe uh
um the term hash plant
you know just to start
right is kind of a weird term
uh because uh all afghans back then
were pretty much bred and grown for hash
yes
but then some strains got called hash
plant and some strains got called other
names
and do we know that was neville the
first one to name a strain or did it
come over that way with that name and
then he used the name
i mean i don't know you know the only
thing that we know about like the g13
and the uh pnw hash plant is that
neville says he bought him an organ
through friends of jorge cervantes yeah
yeah and jorge confirmed that you know
yeah um but we don't know the origin
stories
so i assume he just called it what he
got it it was a hash plan
yeah i i assume so too i don't know
where it where the name evolved would be
nice to ask jorge but i don't know if he
would know but it's weird because it's
like essentially like hash plants
started off as basically being any
any afghan
yes because they were all that's what
that's what
you know marijuana was grown for yeah
was to make hatch
and so people started bringing over all
these afghans or hash plants or whatever
all these various different things over
to america
and you know we talked about this a
bunch but crossing them with a bunch of
different sativas yeah
right yep
is is kind of that's kind of that's kind
of the beginning of it
right
yes so here's
this is
i could probably jump the gun on showing
this one actually let's go ahead quick
i mean that's not it's not terribly
jumping the gun so what happened is is
that a bunch of people started bringing
over these afghans because they wanted
to add bigger chunkier buds to their
sativas and they wanted their sativas to
finish earlier right yeah so
um afghanistan is a super different
climate than over here so most of these
hash plants or afghans that they brought
over they just rot it
yeah
they just they just read in terrible rot
uh so the vast majority
of the seeds that people brought over
ended up being not that useful yeah like
people would go and get their sativa
seeds from before they bred that indica
into it
right and so there so early on
um
early on the big hunt for hash plants or
the big hunt for
afghans was ones that didn't rot
yeah and that's kind of why i think some
of these cuttings became so popular
like you know because most you know most
of the breeding that got done just got
done with specific mops
yeah because once you found one that did
that you traded it
right yep that's how they did over there
that's how they did it so so there's an
aspect where it's like neville went and
you know neville even said that like
because matt held up his his catalog or
whatever
all that hunting that neville did in
afghanistan he said regrettably like
those those afghans weren't as nice as
some of the clone onlys he got sent over
from america yeah whether that was big
bud or the pacific northwest hash plant
or the g13 or
you know
some of the cuttings that he got and so
these cuttings that did well you know
the nl5 all these different things start
getting passed around
yeah because they work
right and so neville probably would met
with matt just held up neville probably
made it really famous this is the hash
plant pure
by
he crossed the hash plant to like the
g13 and the and the nl1
and he and then he took a g13 nl1 and he
back crossed it to the hash plan again
and that's what matt was showing that
ugly squat thing hash plant pure yeah
this is the hashtag here which i mean
you know there is debate on whether the
pnw hash plant that exists today is
this
but looking at this and granted
you know different growing environments
everything else i i would be
hard-pressed to say this looks anything
like the the cut indoors grown here
uh of the pnw it doesn't it looks like
[Music]
that gets passed around either but boy
does it look like some ugly puck it sure
does it's bud formation and and all that
type of stuff and so what's weird maybe
i should say this before we move on
what's weird about what we did right
is
um
someone just asked so afghan is hash
plant now
the afghan people
grew
afghans to make into hashish
yes you know they that they made hash
they still make hash they don't smoke
flour so they never called it hash
plants
right like it was it was just a term
that got put on to afghans and then
people think it made it meant something
specific
but all afghan and pakistani stuff
that's what they did
with their plants yeah you make hash
you know
and so
um you know and and so there's an aspect
where we brought all these plants over
to america
okay and started [ __ ] with them
whether they're steve murphy's afghan
that started the nl thing or the you
know or the the pacific northwest hash
plan or the big bud story or whatever
but we weren't using them for hash plans
we weren't growing fields like they were
and doing anything that they were doing
yeah right so what we did we were
looking for them to blend well with our
sativas
yeah right now that's a trip right
because that means that right when they
got to america a completely different
set of selection pressures got put into
play yeah they yeah i mean they were
they were selecting and for breeding
they came over here they they had been
selected to work well in the afghanistan
environment
to make to make those people hash
and we brought it over here and tried to
blend it with our favorite weed to get
good weed to smoke
right and and to finish early indoors
sure yeah but i mean
all these different like they weren't
trying to they weren't there was no
indoor
i mean we used afghans for indoor when
they came over yeah but no they from
afghanistan or pakistan or that region
they were always growing outside oh yeah
yeah they weren't blowing up houses and
no and they didn't they came from a cold
dry environment so they weren't worried
about the mold i'm just saying that like
all of the farmers
looking for
for you know uh you know genetics you
know various aspects that um benefit an
afghanistan farmer was much different
than a washington oregon california
indoor or outdoor grower trying to [ __ ]
with some mexicans
and some colombians and some panamanians
and some thai and blend this afghan into
that and get what they want
we had a way different set of selection
pressure and we didn't really make hash
for a long time except for for private
yeah
right
yep
so
you know
but we liked they were short they were
squat um they were they had a bunch of
crystal
you know and were visual creatures too
so frosty looking nugs
work better for americans
you know and so what were the what were
the famous what are the famous earliest
hash plans
so the early ones i mean as far as the
earliest we're going to go you know like
uh
[Music]
i mean the pnw
there weren't a lot of early early hash
points but some of the the ones early in
the scene would be like you know there
was the seed bank cash plant which would
be
their hash plant pure which would be
different from
you know the g13 or the the hash plant
nl1 which was using the g13 hash plant
no one
we have the puck
of course aka skelly we have the
cuttlefish hash plant
uh bce hash plant there was also a
champagne hash plant which i'm not sure
if is different from the bc hash plant
maybe some of the canadian folks will
know uh we have hash plant 13
um yeah and some of these some of these
aren't even necessarily from the hash
plant family
of strains that came from neville you
know some of these were just called hash
plant because of whatever reason
it became a bit hash plan is a bit like
kush
in that it's a general term that applies
to a wide variety of things yeah
you know and why one thing was all
labeled kush and another thing was
labeled hash plant when the kush was
destined to be made into hash
yeah it's just one of those language
things that happened
yeah and there's there is some confusion
uh i guess we can go into individual
ones in a little bit so if you want to
continue
i don't want to jump it
no i mean so that's basically like and
then it became famous because in the 80s
as as he just showed uh neville started
calling things hash plan
and there was famous hash plant hybrids
you know and mostly americans used it
because it was a short squat decent
yielding frosty plant inside yeah we
weren't you know nobody was really
making hash in america we smoked flour
mostly
yeah okay
champagne was different from the bc very
interesting
good to know
and it's actually interesting maybe if
you were going to jump around but i'm
going to really jump around to like
today okay so
when when we first brought over all
these hash plants they were brought over
and they had been bred to be excellent
hash plants yeah right and people like
uh people in europe and and in the know
and yo sami and stuff have told me that
they feel like a lot of modern cultivars
like a really shitty hash plants yeah
that a lot of the traditional ones that
were bred for that specifically and bred
for resin
are much better plants for that
yeah because they were never bred for
anything else yeah and now with the
legalization and all that and the hash
revolution that's happened with all
these various elements and dabs and
everything we're actually like looking
people talk about dumpers
yeah right they talk about hash yield a
lot in various ways and methods and so
figuring out what plants are good hash
plants is like back in vogue yeah kind
of for the first time ever yeah
like on on any kind of like commercial
scale people have been making hash here
privately to share with their friends
forever yeah but as far as like uh like
a major thing it's probably it's pretty
recent last 20 years probably yeah
easily and now with testing and people
can be like oh this thing washes six
percent or this thing washes this people
start hunting for hash plant yields
yeah and and what is a good washer what
what keeps its flavor
but we went 40 [ __ ] years
without those pressures being applied
this is this is a good input from
archive he said dumpers are mainly just
plants with higher than average thc to
terp ratio
yeah that's good
good info so
you know so there's an aspect where it's
like for a long time from what most
people is hash plants came over here and
got mixed with other weed
you know for breeding purposes
you know because like if you look at the
puck or you look at that picture
you know some of those things were short
squat ugly
you know they weren't the most
attractive things always
yeah even even chem 91 uh you know aside
from hash plants cam 91 is another
afghani not necessarily known for its
beautiful qualities same kind of way
yeah same kind of way
yeah so but they started becoming famous
because he put him in the first
catalogue yeah and so there was hash
plants and then you know like he was
saying the skelly there's some that
survived from back then that became got
really well known yeah
um but they're not related
to enough
not a lot
just see someone's asking me to show the
uh hash plant pure again so i'm going to
show that again
there we go
so the hash plant pure
neville took the hash plant clone only
he got from oregon he crossed it to a
male nl1
and then he took a male of that hybrid
and crossed it back
to the
to the hash plant
and that was his hash plant pure yeah
and that's honestly kind of like what he
did with a number of things like when he
offered his hawaiian indica um there's a
number of things where he crossed it
once to nl1
and then crossed a male of that hybrid
back to itself and just released it as a
pure line yeah that was actually a
reasonably common tactic
it makes sense yeah
it does appear that neville got the hash
plant and the g13 on the same trip at
the same time from the same people even
how would you have liked to have been
able to grab a pack of that
the original afghan mix
neville sold uh neville sold
seeds that uh jim ortega had given him
yeah he got so many that he he offered
up the same seeds that he found all of
the maple leaf stuff in he sold for a
couple years as just 50 pack 50 pack
breeder packs and 150 bucks
yeah
unreal
neville was cool in that sense and that
he pretty much just told you what he was
crossing there was no real secrecy
behind it
you know uh but he was also first
so he didn't have to hide anything yeah
that helps
um
but yeah you know the these hash plans
some of these hash plants have gotten
famous it's very likely that the
puck
is a direct descendant of that picture
matt
you know that's the rumor at least that
it's seeds from then
and then uh
um our buddy bodhi has a pretty famous
a lot number of lines out that him and
other people have used matt got some of
those from ndn guy yeah uh the g13 hash
plant which was 1988.
the 88 g13 yeah i mean that's that's
kind of how they how they type it or
whatever but
um it's basically supposed to be from
the first year that neville released the
g13
hash plant hybrid yeah yeah
right yeah
i mean i i who knows what what they were
really from or what year or which seed
bank or any of that but that was the
story given with them
1988 cincy seeds plant was or g13 hash
plan which was what they said
so whatever it is i mean it's it it that
exists and so a lot of people have that
and people have puck hybrids and some
people still have the puck clone yeah
you know and so there's some old hash
plants that exist but
um
you can kind of cons like and then there
was kind of like another wave
where people started kept using the
nickname
yes
but they it was all grown for flower
yeah
in my in my opinion nobody was really
making
nobody was really using it the way they
used it in afghanistan
no not not in the us
not in the us so
um
but yeah there was there was something
uh puck is the hash plan
you know they they or they think it is
that's what it's always i mean it looks
like traditional hash plant
hash plant strain
um like in that picture it does have a
lot of those similar traits it does have
a lot of similar traits you know yeah um
and it's out there in the community and
stuff like that people breed with it
so
you know at the very least it ties back
to something old
yeah
but that's most basically what they were
doing is is in america we were looking
for like
um
hash plants and afghans that we could
cross to other things and would bring
the flowering time and the height
and add some crystal and some density
um but uh but teeth but keep a lot of
the other qualities from the sativa yeah
those were sort of the first blends that
people were after
structurally what the hash plant did
yeah and the flavors of the sativa and
the high and the but the flavor and the
smoke and the stretch
you know yeah
so
um you know it it's one of those it's
one of those aspects where we put a
bunch of different selection pressures
on it but kept the name
see we got here so one of the ones often
mentioned is the cuttlefish you know
like or not often mentioned i should say
um but in the in the
like late 2000s it was used a lot by
subpool's crew and um best i could tell
i remember talking to jill about about
it
came from bad boy
whoever that was one of their buddies
and it was actually a super skunk cross
to skunk
uh skunk one and it was like a fruity
they say skunky fruity i'm not sure
on all that but yeah that was what the
cuttlefish plant was it wasn't even a
scentsy hash plant or seed bank cash
plant um it was a super skunk skunked
one
so we we had a bunch of people that were
just asking about the g13
so we could focus on that for a minute
hey fletch you want to come on and talk
to your 13 you're from that area
bring it
so like i said before one part of the
story is that
neville said on one of his american
trips uh he bought the g13 and the hash
plant clone yeah uh from somebody there
he is hey what's up fletch hey what's up
guys how you doing buddy good vernon
good to see you dude good to see you yep
what's going on
just hash plan
the old northwest favorites i mean i
think something that people forget
is that um
the northwest specifically uh like
washington state
is what hid lighting company came from
it's where some of the first hydroponics
companies came from that like the early
80s this was the spot to grow weed
because
the climate
is really good for having heat inside
your house generally all year round
everybody's always like oh the humidity
is so high up there well if you know
anything about
you know relative humidity
air that's 45 degrees and 80 humidity
and you bring that into like a 75 degree
grow room and hit it with all that heat
from all your equipment
it makes a perfect climate 40 yeah
humidity so
you always hear people oh there's mold
or powdery mildew i mean i i know tons
of growers from up here and powdery
mildew never existed in anyone's garden
until clones started coming up from yeah
specifically from ed rosenthal's
um operation in the you know early late
90s early 2000s with yeah the other
lady's name that was running it but they
would like i mean they spread that [ __ ]
worldwide
[Laughter]
that's what you want to be known for
you know centralized clone selling is
really what has spread most problems
everywhere
absolutely the dutting the you know the
the viroids the powdery mildews bugs all
these various different types of things
when people were just getting clones
from their buddy or a small group of
friends it kept most problems localized
yeah and it's when people start stop
maintaining their own mothers and we'll
just like oh i'll [ __ ] buy 200 cuts
for my next run
and started getting them from
dispensaries and getting them from these
centralized places
that's kind of when all these issues
um
started spreading like crazy
was because they'd get into a a poorly
run ed rosenthal situation or they'd get
into a dark heart or whatever and then
they would just sell to thousands of
people
exactly
well let's talk to g13
so you know what you know
so he probably knows but i will i will
say one more thing and then i'll shut up
is that um you know neville says that he
got it on this trip and jorge confirmed
it when we interviewed uh bjornsson
right that was like the one tidbit that
we got
was he remember he said that the g13 was
actually called
um
the uw
yeah the uw that's what his statement
was uh that was like literally an hour
and a half of of talking that was the
one piece of weed history that he
casually mentioned that like was was
any but you know it seems like it was
one of those like like fletch was saying
it was one of those things where
they were collecting different clones
that worked good indoors and trading
them
yeah
right
even up here people were really
reserved about sharing any kind of
clones um
that was true you know probably up until
medical changed in like 2008 with uh
obama's um
whatever that that uh announcement was
where everybody basically started
growing weed because it said the feds
weren't going to [ __ ] with you anymore
yeah yeah pause
so before that getting clones was hard i
mean people you know everybody just if
you had weave you never told anybody
where it came from
so
even if it was from your garden i mean
there's plenty of people you'd buy wheat
from you never knew they grew weed um
yeah for sure they they just said their
uncle got it or whoever
yeah and um
[Music]
so but the the g so what what were we
talking about g13 or what you want g13
let's do g13 uw stuff like that
um
so uw and well g13 as far as i know
there's two there's historically only
two clones
yeah airborne which is from ohio
and then there's pacific which is from
out here like west seattle yeah
um
the pacific was named pacific because of
the user
pacific on cannabis world yeah
she he i can't remember she was she was
like in some band or and i can't she was
some kind of
you know
modern [ __ ] of some sort yeah back then
but
um
she had two different clones i think
that's how she like to be
referred to and uh it was the
u-dub purple or i think didn't she call
it u-dub purple map
yeah you dub black or purple i don't
know
people call it uw-black now he said [ __ ]
that people made up out of nowhere yeah
the
the uw purple i think was and i think
she would sometimes call it purple g13
up here but
like
having been around here for a long time
um
i never saw the the uw purple or purple
that she had
yeah
is the same as the purple indica tacoma
perp
family of plants that's well known up
here in washington which is like how me
and caleb ended up becoming friends 20
years ago is because he had the oracle i
had the pi from up here
we knew those were families of plants
that were localized to our areas
and um we were trying to figure out hey
are these things related are they
similar and me personally having now
worked with the purple indica a lot and
knowing its history up here i mean it
wasn't even called purple indica when i
got it up here it was just
an unknown clone that i received and i
was just able to identify it as a plant
from
that family of purples yeah yeah caleb
and i we got this other clone that we
call the tacoma perp that came from
user stoney puff and stuff on yeah yeah
this world
and that was a different clone but the
same family of plants i also had pop bag
seeds in like 2002 of that from those
bags of that same weed i got plants they
were all almost identical to
you could have passed any of them off as
any of the purple weed that comes around
up here
yeah and uh
that was kind of that's kind of the same
with urkel you know it's like you've got
urkel
um
great
all that [ __ ] 71 whatever yeah yeah 20
different versions of the same
essentially genotype of expression yeah
okay phenotype within a population or
whatever yeah
so um
and it's hard to say whether the chicken
or the egg came from right yeah did the
earth will come first or did the gdp
which one came from which one and unless
you have
let's have a district of it it's pretty
proud so
the g13s the airborne g13
um
that i've seen
is probably most definitely related to
the lemon
aka lemon g13 that was all as it was
also called
okay both carry this trait and it's also
a um
i think it's a virus that transfers from
it through seed from parent right
i don't have the actual data to support
exactly that
but for example the lemon peel that i
have is
crossed with iodine that has a
wrap or virus we have tested for that
right
it's had it basically
i mean like after the second run from
clone
it had it
and i've never um
i it doesn't transfer to any other
strains at all
except for
lemon g hybrids
weird p13 so that is really weird
and so does the lemon g itself
what kind of virus is it do you know rap
or virus
what is it i'm sorry raspberry dwarf
virus interesting
there you heard that
so um
anyways my point is simply that there
can even be you know stuff like that
that can show you
um
potentially a genetic relation
yeah for sure
um
but i mean we've never sold pure lemon
peel hybrids you know for this yeah
yeah
that's wild um i i think i think uh the
the airborne is the one that pip showed
us not so the one that he was keeping
his g13 that he called ohio g13
and i think he had a similar theory that
it that it was related to the lemon g
well he had the limit i mean he rocked
the lemon g like he monopropped it in
that region for years too he was really
familiar with it
um and i will say that you know one
thing about the pacific that makes me
think that it's probably old is that it
is really ugly
you know it's not a pretty plant in my
opinion which one the the pacific you
know
you know like or pips like the g like i
mean that's kind of like one of its
things right was like the g13 was like
when when neville would chat about it
like you know he said it was uh it was
kind of ugly but it had crazy
you know it had it added a bunch of
potency and a bunch of crystal
yeah but by itself it wasn't all that
good
so when i did all those high times
events and everything
you know every once in a while you'd
have someone come through
that
you and they were always old-timers you
know like
these are more
and they would just come through and
just tell you some information about a
strain that you potentially have on your
menu or have hybrids of
and this older lady kate had come to my
booth i think it was either at emerald
cup or one of the other high times
events
and she told me do you know what the
lemon g13 is and i said
well i i first had gotten it from
shroomie back in like 2005 or so
so i knew it was old i knew it was from
ohio because he was in pittsburgh so it
was from right across the border there
and um
the lemon g was like
you know
it um
it's a very distinct plant yeah
it for anything else it's smell how it
grows
it's kind of like just a really big
plant with big buds but kind of not the
most resonant thing anyways
she said that it was the um g13 right
that's from out there
with a skunk misty from scentsy seeds
that hermied onto it and that's that
story yeah
and
it makes perfect sense to me if you look
at the plants if you've ever grown it
does have skunk number one type growth
characteristics
that's where those long running colas
came from
exactly
number one from amsterdam
then
if you've grown the airborne g13 that
weird and
sour
bitter smell brian yeah hell that's from
the airborne g and so it's like you can
smell it between the airborne and it's
it's pretty obvious and then so like i
was saying between all those factors
plus the dwarf virus that's all that's
self-contained to that specific family
of plants
it's pretty
identifiable yeah i can't say for
certain whether or not it's all a
hundred percent the same family so that
kind of covers the
the airborne g13 right
most likely a clone from ohio um i don't
know any other history other than that
and most likely the parent to lemon g as
well
yeah cool that's what i know as well
about it
survived in ohio this is a little off
topic but since we touched it a little
bit what do you think on the purple
indica versus circle
i've grown enough
oh that's what i was going to say
earlier i've grown enough
pi hybrids
that i've gotten oracle phenotypes from
purple indica hybrids wow though
it wouldn't surprise me in the least
especially considering how widespread
that purple indica clone or that family
of clones was
i would bet money if you if you showed
that purple indica to greg that he would
immediately be able to identify it just
like every other guy i know that's been
up in seattle and northern oregon for
the last 30 years growing weed almost
every single one of them you can pull it
out
immediately identifiable by them
i've never tried i should i'll see what
he says
yeah what i'd like to do is go out there
and bring him a bunch of samples and see
if he can identify anything
you guys know i mean you guys are kind
of close out there yeah i mean relative
no
oh
but you know what i'm saying though is
that like who knows what kind of smells
he could potentially identify as just
being related to something just like i
was talking about the lemon g and the
g13 yeah
and then the pacific g13 i never saw
anything but a couple samples of it and
it never was very impressive yeah
the uw purple that purple family that we
were just talking about purple indica
those are definitely not related to the
pacific g13 and then uw was just a name
for
any weed that came out of the university
of washington
area of seattle which was
like kind of where you would go buy weed
off the streets you know kind of like in
park in new york kind of deal
like go down to the u district and you
could buy wheat off the streets
um
and then you had you know between that
the glass blowers which was a giant part
that is often overlooked and
glossed over as if it wasn't an
important part of it but
the glass blowing scene was a large
part of and
of the distribution network of clones
around the country
very much so you know i mean when i
first got the trinity and the and the
snow
uh and you know a bunch of those things
that was all out of eugene glassblowing
circles
exactly you know it was all that was
that was one of the ways that hippies
spread and communicated and and they
they were blowing pipes and they they
had ends
exactly the dog [ __ ] stain channels
um
try to think of other strains that were
class
seen um the super bill um i mean there's
a there's a handful of strains up here
that that
maybe haven't gotten any air time but
the cough was super um oh yeah traveled
everywhere through the through the glass
blowing scene i mean the cough was like
a
oh somebody just said the quindy
that's another one quimby
i heard of it the quimby is just another
is from oregon it's just another like
old it was one of those strains passed
around those same circles
the green
that was one two
you know they they even had their own
four-way
which wasn't like a four-way from uh was
like a four-way from organ
but they just called it the same thing
but it wasn't anything related to
neville's or anything from europe it was
like trinity by something by something i
can't remember
for sure
but
so
that was that's my knowledge of g13 you
know it's it's
somewhat anecdotal but i've seen a lot
of samples you know over the years so
hold on a second people are saying we're
not just hearing facts we're hearing
conjecture about g13 the reason for that
is because the g13 is from the 80s which
is a long [ __ ] time ago and the
memories are old and some of them are
legends
what we what we think we know for sure
is that it came out of the pacific
northwest
okay and that's when it first popped up
and friends of jorge cervantes gave it
to neville
who took it to europe and bred with it
and that's
huh
i can add to it and the name supposedly
came from the license plate uh as best
as i've dug
and yeah the license plates
license and then and so it became and it
became traded so then it was bred in the
europe and then it was traded in the
pacific northwest then it kind of became
this legendary thing
for the most part and so some of it is
conjecture because you have all these
things called g13 but what's their
origin
i mean
one thing i'd like to mention is that
when i first started growing g13 was not
a really well-known subject the only
thing was some internet
folklore about it and the fact that it
was in the catalog back in the day that
was the only knowledge about it
and no one really gave a [ __ ] at all
about it until that movie american
whatever came out american beauty yeah
yeah thousand dollar ounce of g13 on the
[ __ ] uh american beauty movie and
then everybody's like what's that g13
[ __ ] is that some [ __ ] came from the
government it's the same thing that
happened with uw is like
when i was buying weed
uw was just a str
came from an area could be multiple
different strains it was like crippy or
any of those other names it was never a
single variety
and then once you had like the medical
scene around here pop up
and you had people trying to like kind
of stake their claim in the ground but
didn't weren't really in the scene prior
to that they're like i have the original
uw like dude there never even was like
the fact that you're even trying to say
you have
the only you dub is how i know you don't
have it because
because it doesn't exist you're trying
to stake a claim about something that
was um
that was just a name that wasn't
specified to a fighting
yeah
very much kind of like thunder [ __ ] you
know all those or even or even diesel
yeah yeah i mean my my buddies who lived
in new york in that era that that was
slang for for dank weed right then
was it that diesel you got that diesel i
mean now it like means something much
more specific
but it started off as just slaying for a
good weed
exactly
exactly and no indian guy did not have
anything to do with g13
people making up stuffs
um so
while we have you here let's touch on
another hash plant i know we've done
this before but i don't think we've done
it on the syndicate show uh hp 13.
um
yeah i mean my only experience with it
is that
i went to those parties in hawaii um
back in the early 2000s and that was
that's the same the jason king can of
bible group of people
and that was the only place i ever saw
it
and it was well known amongst their
circle that it had come from new york
city or from new york somewhere right
um
it's not from hawaii it
was brought there by
from my understanding a bunch of hippies
okay
and that's that's basically yeah i mean
what'd you think about it
i always deserve the height
no well when i first saw it and it was
like jungle grown i was like oh hell no
this [ __ ]
right
yeah and i think i got the clone later
from uh from caleb
yeah
um
i grew it i like the terps on it a lot
but doesn't transfer to flavor
particularly well it itself
um it's more one of those
strains you can taste it because it
smells so strong not because it converts
to a really tasty flavor
yeah and uh it's herme prone the lower
bottoms on it always through sax if you
would have light leaks or anything like
that
and um
it's pretty hard to breed with in my
experience
but it has one of the more unique
terpene profiles out
so that's one thing jason king was
correct about is that the the profile is
unique
yeah
it's always it's always a bummer to me
when that hurt profile is so strong and
direct
and then it doesn't translate into the
smoke
like bubblegum like like that but like
yeah like the version of bubblegum you
know it smells sometimes the smell and
the
you know i mean that's the same thing
true with hash too sometimes flavors on
flour don't translate into any of the
hash you make with it
yeah right
yeah it's not that hp 13 doesn't have a
good flavor it's just like it's so
strong you expect it
it
promises to deliver more than it
actually does because the spell is so
potent on it right yeah um but what's
what it what one thing i've found with
having run through so many seed plants
over so many years
is that
there's this fine line between
um
there's like three different types of
textures of wheat in my
main textures there's really terpy stuff
that's low in thc and it kind of has
that soft silky feel to the resin it's
not sticky it's not tacky and you
can't wash with it at all right then you
have like the other end of the spectrum
which is like really high in thc
but whatever terpenes are in it
don't make it slick right it's just like
alcohol and water you add enough alcohol
to water and it won't freeze right so if
you it most terpenes and and styles and
everything else in it are like
alcohol-like compounds they have low
freeze
so when you mix that with thc
you need enough thc to stabilize the
terpenes or vice versa right so you have
really terpy low thc it kind of has that
soft feel and it sometimes the [ __ ] just
doesn't translate to flavor no matter
how terpy it is yeah they have the stuff
that's like all thc but no terps
and um
and that [ __ ] wash is like crazy but it
always lacks in flavor and then you have
stuff where it's really [ __ ] terpy
and it's really high in thc and it's
that stick to the wall type [ __ ] yeah
and that's almost always the best
flower to smoke
that's like that's like all the old
elites that ended up testing between 18
and 24 thc or something and they just
had that blend
of
terps and flavor and enough potency to
get you there
entourage effect whatever you wanted it
was interesting for me seeing a bunch of
holding a big library and then when
testing first started happening and you
started getting to see what your weed
was like
me realizing that like i mean i don't i
don't know about i don't know about you
flesh i don't really like most
30 plus
strains
i kind of find them bland like the ones
that work best for me like are somewhere
in the in the low to mid 20s most of the
time
i mean i don't
just taste really strong i don't even
care about the potency of it and at the
end of the day i mean you know i used to
have
jo i mean still have hundreds of jars
available if someone comes over and they
can smoke through whatever and that
purple indica only tests like 15 to 18
percent on a good day and for 20 years
no matter what everybody picked out of
my pile of jars to smoke they'd always
say that was the most potent strain to
them had the most narcotic effects
so obviously thc isn't the only thing
the other thing is
there's hundreds of known cannabinoids
we only test for like 10 of them maybe
in
bioassays and
um
we and we've just found like did you
guys see that italian
um research paper where they found that
thc that's 30 times more potent than thc
and they found it with power
so okay so if you have one percent of
that that's the equivalent of 30 thc so
get power that's twenty percent thc and
then have one percent of this
secondary cannabinoid that we currently
don't test for thcp if that's what it is
yeah
that [ __ ] might feel like it's 50
right because you've got 30 percent with
that extra potent stuff it's like you
know it's like heroin and fentanyl yeah
he doesn't
go fanny
yeah absolutely
and for people asking this will be up on
youtube after we're going to try to have
it up in audio as well
later on
so that's it i mean that's that's kind
of a tangent but it's basically
in my opinion
there's absolutely no way
uh you know to to tell like how well
wheat is going to work on someone
by the available testing that we
commonly do today
you can get a general sense of low or
high thc and you can get some terpenes
and you can learn some things from it
but it's not comprehensive enough by any
means
to
to tell you why why it works
the way that it does
yeah i mean you're you're talking about
we're only testing for you know
five or ten percent of the potential
cannabinoids most of which the other
cannabinoids we don't even know what
they do still
and then uh
then you're talking about we test for a
small portion of the terpenes and dials
and everything that else it produces so
it's like we're gonna start making
assumptions with
ten percent of the data we're gonna yeah
that's bad assumptions about the plants
with ten percent of the data that's
pretty useless science right there
it's almost like phyllos creating a
whole
system on it telling you you could have
genetic relation with about the same and
it's also quite possible that we put the
most importance on thc
simply because it's the oldest compound
we know of that relates to marijuana and
so we've just we've just all been
preconditioned to accept that that's the
big macro no you know why we're
pre-conditioned is because that the
compound they made illegal
yeah yeah yeah you know that's the one
that the government said was the most
important compound
and it's at the end of the day it's
probably not
that's kind of what my whole point we
could we could know 15 or 20 years from
now that this combination of
cannabinoids or whatever is actually
way more important to like this specific
feeling than any number on that level
exactly
you know so and now it had all these
people breeding for 32 thc
with no terps and still smokes like
[ __ ]
smoking gravel yeah
um
and it's all because we're using a
testing system to sell stuff to
consumers that isn't even in their best
interest
you know let you said something the
other day and i know it
it
it didn't like a lot of people found it
controversial but i thought i i could
relate to it very well and you made a
comment that you're done with regular
seeds
and it's on to femme seeds
can you can you like extrapolate on that
a little bit so people understand what
you were actually saying saying
oh i'm just making jokes most of the
time i know but i mean
but it's relevant right people take this
[ __ ] way too seriously but i mean you
know the the people that always have the
most to say are typically the people
that are offended by it the most right
and sure offended well maybe they're not
so proud of what they're doing i don't
know
i just i just related to it so much um
trying to sell regular seeds in this
market right now is is very very
difficult there's not as much of a uh
i don't even know if there is a big
market left for regular seeds at the
moment
no i mean mo people aren't particular
you know especially with the compression
and pricing people are not concerned
with doing things the right way they're
concerned with how they're going to pay
their bills and make it to the next crop
or keep the lights on at their facility
or
whatever and i mean that's why you got
people that are like
you know they got a thousand lights up
they don't know what to do with any of
the product and their choices at that
point are
i'm gonna partner with someone that's
gonna run the thing and sell it all for
me or i'm going to start hitting up
people that work at nurseries of other
businesses
tell their nursery employee hey i'll
give you 50 grand to buy a clone from
whoever right and then try and undercut
their market and it's like look you're
you're never going to create a market
for yourself by always just picking up
the scraps of somebody else's that's a
fact man it's a fact
so you know what's the point of picking
up someone else's scraps it's like you
should be working on your own stuff
because then you can then you can
then you can have enough burn rate on
whatever that product is for yourself
that you can take advantage of that and
be proud of what you're doing and you
know that [ __ ] won't offend you anymore
yeah that's a fact man one thing i've
learned too is that all these dudes that
like to knock stuff off that's what they
do for a living it's all going to come
to a screeching halt when
a lot of the people that are producing
unique [ __ ]
are no longer doing it
you know once those people are removed
from the equation then who's going to
make the unique [ __ ] no one that's cut
off they're done you know exactly it's
like what
what's the point in all just chopping
each other's legs off when we could all
just be producing something only a
generation or two removed but is now
because you did your work and found
something cool
um
now the market's bigger instead of
smaller right
well if you guys want to survive you
better work on making the market bigger
for everybody that's in it not smaller
yeah
it kind of reminds me of like the just
like the the human nature aspect
of all this [ __ ]
you know because
there's a part of it too where
you know you think about it like in
music or something like that when
there's like something you know people
come out and they just create something
and then that creates a demand for it
and then there's a whole bunch of other
musicians who follow in their footsteps
because it's easier than creating their
own thing now there's like a now there's
like a heavy metal genre there's like a
gangster rap genre there's like a
there's an era where like it's not named
people are just doing [ __ ] exactly right
and so what's happened with the with the
named with the named you know strain
game basically is that rather than
people breeding a bunch of weed that
they like and trying to get more weed
that they like
they're like oh [ __ ] this thing from
archive or mat or whoever is is blowing
up right now i'm gonna cross everything
to docido i'm gonna cross everything to
skittles i'm gonna cross everything to
cushmits i'm gonna cross everything to
because it's popular and they're trying
to put their own flavor on it but it's
not like it just happens in weed that
happens anywhere where there's
opportunity
right you know and you know the other
thing i was thinking of when you guys
were talking about the breeding aspect
was that
even talking about seeds today
when you know when neville was on mr
nice or whatever he used to talk about
people would all the time [ __ ] that
they wanted all these pure indica
hybrids
yeah but if they didn't yield to the
roof and they weren't amazing in every
way they'd [ __ ] up a storm and so he
was constantly thinking about like what
he could release
and what the public would accept
yeah so it made me think that even today
right now we got there's a difference
between what the public says it wants
and then where it's money talks
in terms of buying seats
because it says it wants a lot of stuff
that it doesn't really support
exactly exactly right
i think it's the price compression like
everybody's looking for everyone wants
something different but they all want to
sell that have the same sales strategy
right
purple frosty and want to sell 100 pack
right yeah um they're i mean they're not
everybody i mean there are companies
that are phenomenal
they're working on on providing unique
varieties to their business regardless
of whether or not it's a hype strain or
not and and they're in all markets i
mean there's um
you know there's there's a good amount
of those companies that are working on
it now
um
but the problem becomes depending on how
big their business is is
the most productive varieties typically
aren't the dankest and if you're selling
to a wholesale only market and aren't
vertically integrated it's really hard
to grow a two pound variety instead of a
three pound variety or whatever the
difference is
and
just like fruits and vegetables the big
old monster tomatoes typically are the
ones that taste like water yeah for sure
yeah i mean that's that's like uh one of
caleb and i's running jokes dude is that
the shitty little thing in the corner
that you thought about killing ends up
being the clear winner in the smoke test
always and you're like why is that
[ __ ] run over there like why is that
one head and shoulders above all these
beautiful producing structure amazing
dense buds all over it and this
stressed out little thing here that
almost died that's the one that everyone
wants the smoke
i think it's a
i think the the smoke ability of a
stream is a combination of two things in
my opinion
it's the type of and how much resin
there is
on the plant material then there is
how the plant material smokes itself and
those are two completely different
things yeah that's why people like hash
is because you get rid of all the plant
material so now the [ __ ] that like has
good terps or good trichomes on it but
shitty plant material you can smoke it
now strawberry banana it's like man the
flower is completely
nothing to write home about but yeah
make some fresh frozen hash with it's
great it's awesome yeah you know
banana smoothie so
there you know there's a purpose for
that
but
when you start talking about like mass
versus trichomes
if you increase the mass but there's
only the same amount of trichomes it's
inevitably probably going to continue to
taste worse so whatever has the least
amount of
mass that smokes poorly of flour
material with the highest concentration
of resin good tasty resin
it's probably going to be your best
wheat so
to me it's just a trichome concentration
versus
plant mass
that's
interesting yeah
i i look at it a little differently
because i i talk about burn ability all
the time right because that's really
important to me
but i i think that there's like a
there's like an air to bud ratio
you know like i mean obviously some
things you put them on this you know you
put them on and and the thing is huge
but it weighs three grams
other thing you put it on and it's the
same it's the same size and it weighs
eight
you know so i think like how dense
things are like one of the things i like
about diesels is it kind of has all
those like nooks and crannies and hills
and crevices and different things the
way the bud forms
so it's like it's not that dense
right and then i think that makes it
that's what i was saying is the amount
of trichomes versus the mass of the
plant material the plant material yeah
and it seems like that stuff washes
better because there's more surface area
where like this super thick stuff you
almost have to chop it up into little
bits to get it to wash well because
there's only so much exposed
exactly
how much
can you get on x amount of mass of flour
and it's things like bubba right it's
like
you know you could bubba doesn't have a
lot of surface area to put
because it's so dense with plant
material yeah yeah and why does it test
low and why does one little nug like
this turn into like a joint that's
[ __ ] that fat
yeah yeah that's why because it has a
lot of plant material mass
yeah
i mean there was there was an aspect too
where i used to have this i used to have
this judge of whether i thought things
were
like perfect density to me
like when i was breeding stuff a bunch
was could i break it off in the dark and
put it into a pipe and smoke it
effectively
and if and if you can't do that without
like the snow used to be like that like
you almost needed scissors or a grinder
you know if you just broke off a big
chunk and shoved it into a bowl or a
bong or something like that it would
barely burn
yeah
it's too dense prohibition selection
standards
you know and you know cookies cookies
cookies can be like that too it can be
too dense
yeah
for sure you know it breeds a certain
density
what have you been focusing on in um
on your projects lately like uh is there
anything you're stoked about anything
you're working with lately that you're
like [ __ ] this is so unique and so
different that i you know i'm gonna work
on this for a few years anything like
that currently going on
i mean man i'm just always just
selecting through plants i mean i just
popped like another 500 seeds the other
day
for me it's i just want to find new [ __ ]
all the time i mean
[ __ ] half the time all like i just went
to california and went to all these big
grows and everything and met up with
everybody
except me
well
everybody um everything is on schedule
but uh
the like
the one that i wasn't really
particularly impressed with was the one
that all the biggest growers all said
hey can i get a clone what's up with
that one i wanna i need to i need to
make this one a strain or whatever right
and it's like well i didn't even think
that was that out of all the stuff i
brought that's not my personal favorite
you know so for me it's like i never
really know what's [ __ ] i just try to
grow really good weeds and [ __ ] that i
think is unique and tastes really good
and has that
the right ratios everything we were just
talking about
and um
man everybody i let everybody else
decide what what's really unique to them
because if you told me
you know
10 years that papaya would be unique to
people i'd tell you you're [ __ ] crazy
right
that's the most
run-of-the-mill [ __ ] on the [ __ ]
planet at that time right yeah but so
only 10 years later
you know dutch skunk number one fruit
terps
is unique because everyone grows only
gelato so
yeah yeah if you would have told me
skunk one would have had a comeback i
would never in a million years have
believed that
exactly
i mean there was there there was a time
you know in mendo where
you couldn't give a a calli pound away
yeah and then you know and then the the
nails got invented and people started
dabbing
and angie became popular
but
i couldn't believe tangi when it when it
hit i was like what what are we redoing
calio again what the [ __ ] going on
here right
but but we forget that you know the
majority of the smoking population is 18
to 28 years old
so after
most people turn 28 they get kids family
they smoke less they're not involved
and
that [ __ ] whatever was
old for the people that just quit
smoking is brand new to the next
generation
yeah i mean we we had a we had a like a
15-year downturn for perps
and then it came back with a vengeance
yeah totally with a vengeance you know
there there was an era a long time ago
when when everything purple went like
crazy
and then that wasn't the case for a
decade and a half or something and then
it came back
and all of a sudden
you know i you hear that like very 2005
statement you know like i don't know if
this is purple enough could this be
darker
you see people extending the periods for
these strains now by like adding two
novel things together so you got like
tropicana cookies and it's like just
tangy but it's purple like the
blackberry right and it's like that and
then people are like excited about it
again you know yeah mendo per same thing
you know it's like people get tired of
it when it's just a mental perk but you
know call it forbidden fruit and now
it's the hot [ __ ] and now yeah i mean i
it's crazy
um what's crazy about the forbidden
fruit is that when citrus is strong
it's like one of the most dumb it can be
it can breed one of the most dominant
terps at times
yeah for sure
you know
and then it's and it's often a one or
two note terp
where it's like you don't get other
scents it's like when it's citrus it's
just like pop it's citrus
yeah and that forbidden fruit is really
weird because it smells just like it's
like a one note purple
it's a pretty plant
it's pretty super pretty
super pretty and like uh and all that
and you know but yeah it's it just it
smells like if you like orange citrus
and that's it well
i think here's uh an important thing to
i think
what we're talking about is really a
product of the how easily information is
spread nowadays because like you were
talking about before
how
uh plant diseases were isolated to
small groups of people if if at all
because people didn't really share
plants the same thing was true with the
selling part of weed 20 years ago as
well
is
i don't know what the [ __ ] people were
smoking in georgia or tennessee right i
just know what i can buy around me
that's it
and
uh so i didn't have this con this
preconception that
i can get some purple weed that smells
like orange there was not choices like
that so everybody just basically created
their own
standards of quality
and
preference
and those were localized to even just
small groups of people right and i think
that's why we had so many unique strains
that
were able to survive prohibition
is because the whole market wasn't
gelato
or whatever because
no one had a big enough growth to do
that no one knew about a strain enough
to do all that [ __ ] so um
you know every so like strains like hp
13 survived because that was the best
weed that a whole group of people in the
country could get
and they demanded that product so that
clone survived and that
you know that was one of the benefits of
prohibition is that it actually did help
keep some of the diversity alive because
you had these independent markets that
weren't affected from external external
input
and now we have the opposite where
everyone is so influenced
by external input that
almost no one keeps anything unique
around anymore at all and the customer
doesn't even
know that they want it because it's not
even available in the marketplace
oh i mean that's something i trip on all
the time is because
like california like in in some degree
like or where i live might be considered
kind of like a you know the forefront of
certain things good and bad and one of
the bad things was like the the whole
like named clone craze that took off
where you know first it was purples and
it was cushes and sours and you know
just but what that meant is that people
kept dropping stuff and we talked
earlier in the show about how
that g13 cut probably survived in ohio
because
like you you grow weed in these areas
where it's good enough weed that it
always sells and there's not pressure to
change so they keep these favorites
wherever they go
ohio
is are they even legal yet or no not
exactly but i just meant like anywhere
anywhere that doesn't like california
pressure i mean i'll tell you so to me
the first real
praise was the purple craze in mendo
before that people just grew good weed
and it all sold
right and then when the purple craze hit
and it became about the mendo p or the
urkel or the gdp or you know these half
a dozen different purple strains there
would be people that would come up from
the bay and they were like i will buy
every gram of this weed that i can find
yeah and so that created this pressure
where all these different growers
were like well why do i want to grow
this other [ __ ]
i'm just going to turn this 40 lights or
whatever into urkel
and boom it out because these people are
going to cash me out even for my odd
pound
of course yeah and so with every time
that happens diversity gets [ __ ]
and then you fast forward right fast
forward 15 years from then
and when the purple craze hit
everybody starts hitting up like the six
people that kept purple
you know like everyone i knew had an
urkel or grape ape or uh or a gdp or a
mendo p cut oh yeah you know there was
an era after that where like every
single farmer i knew indoor and outdoor
ran some sour diesel
but if it's not if it's not what's the
easiest thing to to sell then they drop
it
you guys feel like we're in that stage
right now
currently with anything
yeah a bunch of shits getting dropped
yeah
i mean i'll tell you something crazy
dude i had a buddy from from soham hit
me up
and say that a bunch of brokers were
starting to talk about wanting sour
diesel this year
and they couldn't they couldn't find
clones of sour diesel and soham
weird that is weird because it's been
three four years and everybody's been
growing gelatos and weird hybrids of
gelato and these weird purple crosses
and jealousy and
you know that was the only thing that
people wanted to pay for
yeah makes sense you wouldn't think sour
would get pushed out but
it doesn't take that long all it takes
is a few seasons or one season
of your broker telling you i don't want
it
and you're gonna find something though
they they do want
you know or they tell you oh i'll buy
that but it's gonna be this but if you
had this i'd pay you this much more
yeah they're going to go that route
yeah it definitely doesn't have the
cookies appeal at all this isn't you
know but it's like but everyone had sour
it's just it's a globalization of the
marketplace right you know it really
it's a nationalization but california is
supplying is globally at this point now
and um
so it's just like you know kind of when
you travel the world nowadays right it's
like it's a lot it's not
nearly as
culturally diverse especially in the
touristy areas than
20 years ago or in particular 40 years
ago not that i ever experienced that but
um
it's just where we have this
information is disseminated so quickly
nowadays that it's um
that we're losing a lot of diversity on
the planet
for a lot of reasons and um
with cannabis particularly because it
was
prohibited by the governments
we have probably the very last
agricultural crop that had its own free
independent economy
and
um distribution system for a
multi-billion dollar planet plant per
year in value
with absolutely zero
government intervention and policies
that would dictate how and why people
would operate their business and now
i'll move to the whole opposite with
that with globalization and nationalism
with one exception to that they didn't
have any control
over how we set it up except for
things they did would make us adapt to
not encounter them
yeah so all the shipping methods all the
very all the various aspects of the
business was to work around
government intervention of any kind
so they didn't really they didn't they
didn't really dictate to us but they did
influence how we responded in a way
exactly but because of that
if we had a much more diverse
scene because everybody figured out a
different way
to manipulate the system to their
advantage so to speak right it really
was adam smith and the invisible hand
sure you guys familiar with that
no
so adam smith when he wrote about
capitalism and all that it's like a
super famous thing that he did but he
wrote about basically like real
capitalism is like there's an invisible
hand that takes the goods from where
they are
and pulls them to where they're wanted
to be bought
like there's a system that will get set
up if there's a demand in some place and
there's margin and profit to be made a
system will be set up by people to get
that profit and to bring the goods to
where the people want to be
yeah that's essentially what happened
with wheat that's how weed got spread
all over america when it was totally
illegal
was the invisible hand divvied it up
exactly
okay you know and then the invisible
hand is just it's just no government no
government making any rules i mean it's
interesting that like in california
especially they made a whole bunch of
rules and they crashed the very
successful system within five years
but that's exactly what we're getting at
is that like
if you let the government get involved
in anything they will ruin it right
that's the general
rule of thumb right name one war that
we've waged in the last 50 years in this
country where we want it
whether it was a foreign war or a
domestic war the war on drugs [ __ ] drugs
are more available and more planet
we don't win any wars war on
homelessness we don't win anything
i'm not sure if they're meant to be one
i i really don't know yeah there's no
profit in solutions yeah exactly that's
what i mean
it's [ __ ] up
but there's no profit in collapsing an
agricultural commodity that you're the
one taxing like the funny part is the
government's so bad
at their job that they're the only ones
that make money without having to spend
any in this real business you know right
i mean other than other than just
enforcing the rules that they that get
written but
they're taking in what a third of the
income and the whole state or more in
most of these cases
and
the the biggest loser is them
by collapsing the system around
themselves because
if the if the price of weed goes to
basically non-profitable and i mean look
i've talked about this for a long ass
time
without subsidies and or farmers unions
farming in america doesn't exist
you've been doom and gloom forever about
it i agree yes yes
but we're here now really no he has he's
been talking about dairy realities and
collapsing markets and and what happens
with industrialization and all that for
quite some time but here's the biggest
benefit right is because there's no
union
and no
subsidies to get this to survive
that
the consumption of weeds gonna continue
so a lot of people are just there's
nothing to save these big corporations
and these big investment
firms
yeah stay in business there's nothing to
save them right
and
in a
in the right scenario depending on how
much it ends up costing a lot of these
big businesses to operate
and how the consumers
perception and demands may change
small farms might be the ones that come
out winning
because there isn't
as we're seeing now in california and as
the as every state gets its own supply
set up and there's not this
um
distribution network this demand from
all over the world for export product
yeah
we're growing way more weed than people
need to smoke so all it takes is the
consumer demanding a little bit higher
quality product
um and the consumption amount or the
amount of players being too many for the
amount of consumption that's occurring
and
the only things that may be profitable
is small businesses
you know you guys did you guys not to
interrupt did you guys see that thing uh
in canada where they destroyed like
hundreds of tons of unused weed
they burned it
because of overproduction
yeah and they couldn't pump it through
the system and it aged out and turned
brown and you know they had all these
huge greenhouses and they did this big
power play there's an aspect it's
interesting that you say that dude
because
there is definitely a bunch of people
that are trying to get into the industry
by just having a better burn rate than
small farmers
what they're hoping to do
is bleed everybody out
be able to survive longer because they
have more capital and then take over the
bones and they end up with a bunch of
market share
yeah but what homie is saying is that
they could actually bleed out beyond
where they're willing to bleed
exactly and if the price spike doesn't
happen after that
to like be able to recover they're lost
because what they're trying to do is
they're willing to lose money now but
they're planning on making more later
and they just the plan is not to just
light a huge pile of money on fire and
watch it burn
no they exactly exactly but their
problem is that now that people are
growing
weed more easily everywhere right and
more quantity of it like i mean oklahoma
has intercepted pick six the whole game
from california in a lot of ways okay
and that's gonna continue to happen with
every new state that comes online and it
becomes easy to grow more
so like you know
companies like truly even florida
well you've got companies like jungle
boys and everybody else that can come in
and take their lunch from them from a
from a business operations standpoint
and quality perspective and then you've
got the the little small grower chipping
away at you too so i mean like
the market may not sustain their billion
dollar aspirations that you may not be
able to be that big and we're seeing
that in washington already the biggest
growers in washington are shutting down
2 000 light operations they're selling
200 packaged pounds wreck
right
the thousand light grows that bring in
buyers from out of state buy it from the
from the licensed place
that they deposit cash and the state
knows about it and it's like
the the supply it's there's so many
operations to supply the demand now that
i don't think there is like a rosy
outcome for them uh down the road
so they might just be lighting lighting
tens of millions of dollars on fire well
if they can't find
more money to keep sustaining their
money losing operations
it's they're done for anyways i mean you
know canopy growth shut down their what
did they spend 230 million dollars on a
greenhouse in medicine hat they sold it
for 35 million recently just to keep the
lights on i mean like jesus
you know
you can't run a business like that i
mean no flocana up by me they raised 175
million bucks
and they they pretty much blew it
right and so where's the ground gonna
come from when the economics looks the
way it does now
yeah and you know and there's another
aspect of it too and
uh you you know we were chatting about
this i can't remember it was last week
or the week before
but
like it is this weird thing because
since cannabis is legal in some spots
and illegal in others
right and the and the and the line
between the two is super murky
um there's all this there's all this
stuff happening you know where most of
the companies in california surviving by
back dooring
absolutely you know that's how they're
surviving and then and then on top of
that like up in you know when the hemp
when the hemp implosion happened in 2018
uh up in his neck of the woods in
southern oregon and all those areas
those places started growing at a level
never before seen
and there's all these there's all these
criminal groups and cartels
that started doing things on a scale
that had never been seen before
and daring the authorities to come catch
them
right and so there's massive amounts of
weed that are being grown i've read in
places that that uh you know a mexican
mexican import is down 75
from from the good days for them
right
and
and they
are
going into all kinds of different
businesses to make up that lost revenue
right and they're going to oklahoma and
they're going to oregon and they're
going to the desert in california and
they're setting up these huge depths and
shops
trying to make money
so it's like a total free-for-all in
that sense
you know it's like the the level of
overproduction is insane
well yeah and everybody thinks that like
it's gonna get better and it's like look
for just every person that's quitting
right now there's another person
doubling up their garden right yeah
there's another glass house putting up
another five million square feet this
isn't going to get that much better you
have to identify your own market and
then
supply that market whatever it is that
you do whether it's edibles vape pens
these terp carts
rosin pick your pick your thing maybe
it's all of them it doesn't really
matter
but the market can only sustain so much
of that right before
you start basically eating into your own
profits with your over production so
like i said as more people become
operational more good operators come in
more good black market operators
continue to produce in more states um
maybe it fizzles out for them you know
who knows
maybe it just can't sustain the size of
business that they want like these
people spent 300 million dollars
building this big grow because they were
planning on doing a billion dollars a
year in sales
but they only got to 150 million a year
in sales they're not really breaking
bulls right so
um i think that's going to be the
reality for a lot of these big
businesses and then
if you get these really big
overproduction situations like you have
right now
um
you're gonna see people shutting lights
off but the thing is is like as soon as
the the um
like all right let's say you have a 2000
light operation and you're gonna shut it
down for the time being
because you have two of these let's say
you shut one down
and you're like well we'll just wait
till the price goes back up well what
happens when the price goes back up you
flip the lights back on fill it with
plants and a year later the price is
back where it was again
yeah this is you know
ag economics you know this is just how
it goes
and
so
the real question is how much coveted
cash did we spend on
growth that don't need to exist
and if that's yeah really big which i
think it is
this over production will continue for
quite some time i would think
i mean really it's it's two giants with
a bunch of good weed growers getting
smashed in the middle
in my opinion because it's like all the
like the two giants are like the all the
huge black market things that have set
up by the various groups and then the
other giant is all the backdoor legal
weed that happens
and the reason why legal is so pissed at
the black market is because for the
first two three years they were dumping
all their excess product in the black
easy and that was their cash flow
and now
now they're getting cut off by these
ginormous scenes and they're pissed off
about it and it's tanking their price
and it's making their life harder but
but you know so they want they want all
the black to be shut down
but they only want the black to be shut
down so they could resupply the black
they just lost market share
you
they just need market share wherever
they're going to get it from well they
define what's white and what's black so
i mean they're the ones hiring the
lobbyists and are going to be hiring the
lobbyists so they don't find what's
white and black anyways i you know i i
worked on some on on some big farms down
in southern california for a couple of
years and uh
one of the things that the sales guy did
that was pretty trippy is he went and he
looked at a bunch of the data for all of
the dispensaries
and he was pretty much like you know
this farm that we have down here it
could probably supply like 80 or 90
percent of the volume needed
and he was like kind of from the the
real world so he was kind of tripping
out by this number because he didn't
know all the various nuances that we
know
you know but he was just looking at it
he was thinking about all the other
bigger farms than us and all the indoors
and all the depths and all the
everything else and he was like well how
is this working
the only way that the white market can
survive is if like 80 of them fail
if you're if they actually have to sell
within the state of california only and
no back door exactly yeah and then the
goal would be instead of like two or
three huge companies that suck that that
percentage would be a bunch of bomb
small growers that could actually give
consumers what they want well that's
what i'm getting at is that yeah the
market actually shrinks back to the size
that it's that's actually sustainable
for the state of california and not
including the export market
the most of these big growers are too
big for that
like they're they just can't get enough
revenue to sustain the business model so
they they have two choices they either
just shut off a bunch of operations and
keep their 200 million a year or
whatever it is they could get
or
and they just hope they can hold on to
that from little guys that keep chopping
at their at their bottom line or at the
top line so
you know it this may go back the other
direction and people don't realize that
and i think if people focus on quality
expanding their market instead of
chopping off your fellow farmers market
the
black market operators or backdoor
operators or whoever you are
you're gonna
continue to see growth in your space
regardless
that'd be my that's my opinion
i could even say 20 years ago the people
that i knew that were running 50 and 100
lighters that were really good at their
job
they still bought their head stash from
4 to 10 to 12 lighters
because those that there's just
something about like a a smaller space
that only per they don't you know like
you can you can
there's like
nobody agrees where craft ends
right
nobody nobody agrees when it's like it's
just a little too big to be called craft
but i can but everybody agrees that the
bigger it gets the harder it becomes
to manage perfect weed
you know
a guy that like works on his four
lighter after work and is in love with
it and spends a couple hours in there
every night making it just exactly
perfect he probably has fire well i
think as these as this profit margin
continues to shrink and then you got
these big monster grows
i think you're going to continue to find
it's going to be continued
to be difficult for these big businesses
to find employees that want to do that
[ __ ] too
right i mean where are you getting
skilled workers from in this marketplace
and my my buddy dude uh he jokes that
like it's like a [ __ ] factory job
it is and you're in there and the lights
are on and the fans are running and the
decibels are loud and you honestly
should have like protective glasses and
some and some that you know and some ear
muffs and some this is a good team it's
it's actually pretty fun because now you
don't have to man it you don't have to
be the guy like growing weed for
yourself is being that guy that's
playing the the he's got the whole
contraption on that's playing like fixed
[ __ ] yeah yeah right
like that what the
running and operating the whole business
itself is that and for some people
that's the right way to do it and if you
want to control your product and your
market and your marketplace that's how
you do it but these big monster grows
especially when the ownership has no
soul or passion for the plant and
doesn't want to fund any kind of fun
[ __ ] for their employees to do in it
yeah i don't think you're going to find
a lot of people that want to continue to
do that job long term
yeah
and i i mean there's there's an aspect
too where um and i want to say it before
i forget but when he was talking about
quality the other thing that i would say
that is actually going to lead to like
the next generation of like real elites
is if people want to breed
uh stop breeding for the market because
that's going to change soon anyway start
breeding weed that you personally think
is fire exactly try to find weed that
you and your friends love to smoke and
you love the buzz and you love things
about it grow better weed for yourself
the chances of that weed becoming
popular is way better than you trying to
create something that you think will be
popular grow weed you like
breed
my only business card and everybody that
knows me is a box of jars that's what i
show up with yeah i'm not gonna
hit but a box of jars right and then you
can because i can tell you pretty much
everything about a grower from a box of
jars
yeah you could you should be able to
you know and there and there's an aspect
to where it's it's
i mean we haven't even talked about like
if it went federally legal like the
international market and how that would
play
into
all this different stuff
you know because in each new in each new
state that goes legal
there's a bunch of investment money
hoping to like dominate and make a bunch
of money back
and it's kind of been swinging around
the country right now it's in new york
and new jersey
because those are huge places that are
coming online and all these people are
super excited about trying to you know
do that you know washington where he
he's up you know washington oregon were
ahead of california
and we didn't really learn any lessons
no we just we just would [ __ ] the bed
right away we're just like oh let's just
make a bunch of terrible rules
right away destined for failure
but i mean that's that may only make
sense for california with how we do
stuff so
yeah i mean i it's it's hard i will say
in all honesty it's hard because like he
said
this is it's agricultural which has its
own weird [ __ ] to it right
um and it's a multi-multi multi-billion
dollar industry already
yeah so it's not like they get to create
the industry from the ground up and like
tinker with it they're trying to bring
this huge thing
into the light
and they have no idea how to do it what
other thing have they ever done that
with
yeah that's a good point what have they
ever done
you know that's why that's why some of
this money is so excited they're like
what do you mean there's eight million
pot smokers in my state already
yeah that's a huge customer base most
things you you make that are brand new
you have to build popularity oh yeah
weed is super [ __ ] popular
like it's already popular so and no one
controls it so it's all tempting for the
money to be like i want to control that
for sure
you know
and i agree rings uh yeah i think
colorado probably was falling out uh
for cali yeah oregon too i mean uh
i was just like i've been going through
having to delete all my old photos to
keep my [ __ ] from getting uh
my account deleted and everything yeah
and like man i was i was like seeing
memes i was making in like 2017-18 when
everybody was talking about the sky is
falling and [ __ ] in oregon i mean
this is just reality for an agricultural
crop and if you're not prepared for it
and for
um being
flexible with how you're gonna operate
your business
it's not gonna be it's not gonna be a
good time you know
yeah
one thing i will say too and i never
really thought that i i i would see this
but
there's an aspect where like maybe for
the first time
like being an actual weed nerd who
really loves it is an advantage
because then at least you get to love
what you're doing
where a lot of people got into this
because it was easy or because it was
money or because there was a big margin
or because you know it allowed them
travel freedom or whatever and as as it
gets harder and harder they don't
actually like doing what they're doing
so they get a lot more frustrated as the
market changes on them
yeah this is just another job
you know yeah it's just you know and
they used to make a lot more for a lot
less effort
and now they're making a lot less for a
lot more effort
you know where and there's not there's
an aspect that i see in mendo all the
time you probably see it up there too in
oregon you know where it's like a bunch
of people that didn't really care about
weed but learned enough to make money
and run some big [ __ ] and make good
money for 20 years
now that it's going legal they think
they have this like lifetime of
knowledge about wheat
but they really farmed most of it out
and they were in it for luke and so
they're really not that talented at what
they do they really don't have the same
knowledge base as like people that were
nerdy about lead and kept wanting to
learn about what they were into
yeah of course so there's an aspect out
there where for you know like being
being like into weed helps because it's
gonna get rough yeah
it's gonna get rough the combo did go
sideways but sometimes that's what's
cool about it i mean we could have
talked about hash plants for the last
hour i suppose
in sequential order
you know i mean man who [ __ ] cares
yeah i enjoyed it [ __ ] joints here
what the [ __ ] do you guys want yeah
what are you [ __ ] bothering us for
yeah it is i mean to bring it back to
hash plants or whatever probably in the
probably in the last five or six years
as people started measuring returns
on on on plants
uh people started making hash seriously
for the first time in america on a
commercial scale
and trying to figure out what cultivars
and actually breeding for hash
which really wasn't done in the 80s 90s
2000s right
nobody really people were breeding for
flower
yeah for the most part you know people
weren't breeding for hash i can't
imagine well especially frozen hash
which is you know arguably some of the
tastiest hash for sure yeah they didn't
have the gear
i mean americans like it easy we don't
have like a village that we can just be
like all right for the next 12 hours all
you families you're you're like bashing
weed over a screen with no with no mask
you know
you watch some of those you watch you
watch some of those uh some of those
videos of what those guys do and i don't
know how they don't have an allergy
attack like every day of their life
because they're just in a [ __ ] house
oh yeah pounding they beat all [ __ ]
beat allergies moved out and did
something different yeah they had to
leave
they had these are desensitized people
because it's just a dust cloud you're
working in all day long exactly if you
can't deal with it you're not living in
morocco but the same thing is true too
where it's like there's a big push where
like a lot of the popular hash trains
they probably get popular because they
yield great not because they're the best
higher flavor
yeah there's always that pressure too
there's the money versus quality
pressure
i don't know number one was one of the
best hash plants for me ever right skunk
number one and it's hybrids from
amsterdam why because
sam bred the ship for
making hash
he's a resin farmer
yeah
hit like he
made the money that he made
by breeding a plant for 97 thc in the
trichome head and then selling that as
technology to gw pharmaceuticals like
that
that's his that's his claim to fame
right there and he's like the only one
that's
done that even and he did that [ __ ] back
in the 90s i mean
you know that it's an impressive feat
regardless
yeah every it's something every breeder
should be
but made a lot of
you know the netter hash and everything
else that became popular and now is the
water hash market
i mean we were talking we were talking
to uh camara a while ago and he was
talking about how's never even seen sam
smoke flower
that he you know he breeds he's a
resident that's what he called him he's
a resin farmer
yeah i don't like he does he likes to
breed for resin that's what he's after
that's what he's interested in that's
what he cares about
you know
that's pretty dope that's my um bubble
man doesn't smoke flower either it's
kind of the same mentality
not that dressing
but you know
i consider sour diesel the diesel family
to basically be like america's modern
skunk
yeah you know that
a very skunk oid you know type type you
know plant type aromas all that it's a
little different it's definitely not
skunk one but it's definitely like it's
in that family yeah it's modern skunk i
mean even just chem family stuff in
general is i would almost say is pretty
similar you know
yeah big tall running colos on a lot of
hybrids a little bit longer flowering
hybrid plant and
you know synonymous with
you know good quality and uh commercial
production
yeah
only women and slaves smoke flower
that's one of my favorite quotes ever it
is it's really funny quote
it's a really it wasn't yeah that was
one of the dudes
funny story i guess
when sam skunk man was in amster was in
afghanistan looking for seeds
he asked some of the muhajdin for for
flour because he wanted the seeds
and the guy looked at him and was like
only women and slaves smoke flour
men smoke hash
and he was basically like are you a
woman or a slave
and he had to explain that he wanted the
seeds from the flower he had no interest
in the flower to smoke whatsoever but he
wanted to make his own hash at home
and he wanted the seeds and that made
sense to the dude but he was literally
like women and slaves smoke flower
men smoke hashish so he handed them a
pair of chains
i mean culturally they're very different
you know
for sure i get it very different well
it's an unprocessed product you know
[Music]
and [ __ ] i mean
if i was if you just
if you just grow a field of seed plants
and randomly pick a flower to smoke
it's probably not the greatest
experience
no
no especially if the flower wasn't ever
bred for smoke
exactly like one of the one of the
things about sativas is at least the
like you know they were breeding for the
flower itself to be smoked
i mean one thing i find interesting that
everybody you always see this comment
it's kind of a
um
a misconception in cannabis breeding is
that oh just go back to land race and
it'll fix whatever problem someone's
talking about like
i'll always hear me nowadays because of
this and this and that
you should just
go back back to the land race yeah get
and make something new and it's like
if you've ever grown lots of land raised
varieties
sativa indica everything in between i've
grown tons of seeds from all over the
world
and
guaranteed
the vast majority of them have equal or
higher amounts of hermaphroditism
like you know the plants when you grow
them from seed and the flower's seedless
but it has those little tiny black like
doughs
and you like roll a joint up and it's
like all these little black specks on
the table right i've looked at them
under a microscope it's i mean it
literally it sounds like you have spider
mites in your in your flower but it's
i mean they're they're tiny
um those are really common do you know
the rosters pick those out
tiny trichome head or tiny trichome
heads and tiny calyxes i mean or bracks
yeah
it's like the majority of what's in the
populations is those type of plants now
the rest of them can be really nice a
lot of them it smells good as really
greasy as potent when you smoke it but
the flower itself is just not desirable
has lots of growth problems as well yeah
land race is like whipping yourself
it's definitely setting it's definitely
a lot it's pain
it's pain it's turning back the clock
and and then you if you if you think
that that's the way to fix a population
or something like that
it's basically you assuming that hey i'm
going to turn back the clock 50 years
and i'm going to do this myself from
scratch and do a better job than all the
people that have done it between me and
now and it's like dude
we're just like that there was a decent
population of plants for all of us to
start with in the first place you know
and it's like the the goal is to at
least make hybrids and select for plants
that'll continue to increase that
quality so that the next person that
does that that
that again
will continue to improve the population
better than you did and that's
that's inadvertently how we've gotten to
where we are with all the herms all the
feminized pollinate accidental feminized
pollination that gives us our main
breeding population of today
is because it was always the best plants
crossed with the best plants because no
one kept anything else for the most part
yeah we've gotten this question a few
times so i'll ask it what's up with your
malawi uh what's the sourcing on that
that came from uh the glassine up here
in
washington but by way of oregon
very cool um i don't know anything about
who popped the seeds i mean or how it
got here or anything yeah super um
super like land race like uh al uh
obsolete used it right uh
um
i think caleb had it at one point i
think um
shot 707 seed bank had it for sure and
ran it after from back in the day i mean
it was
it was one of those plants that had a
really
strong
like hazy aroma when you smoked the
flower
interesting somebody said more like
eugene gold
what's that i don't know when they were
talking about malawi
maybe that was another name someone
called it
well yeah we talked earlier about like
the weird instagram stuff and everything
that's been going on uh one thing we're
trying to put together that was going to
talk about tonight real quick before
we're done
is that we're trying to put together
the breeder syndicate social and i know
like i think fletchy you saw flanbelle's
social thing he was trying to put
together
we're going to use that similar type
platform so we can have
a nerd ig for us
so we'll figure it out but i wanted to
at least get that out there today so
people have an idea to look for it
for sure
yeah
uh anything you're dropping soon fletch
well maybe i don't know but i'm not
gonna plug [ __ ] on here we're just
talking we
that's cool as [ __ ] dude um
yeah
natto
no i mean i i i obviously had a pretty
wide-ranging conversation sometimes it's
good
we i had a malawi i don't know if it's
the same one uh how long did did yours
take forever to finish
it was like 90 80 90 days probably
yeah i had this one and i never could
get it to i needed to like dab it
starting in june
you know and uh and and i never did that
and i grew it inside a few times and it
took twice as long as everything else
that's the hard part about having
sativas is you kind of need their own
unique space
for their life cycle yeah
yeah
you know
because otherwise you can't like clean
and and reset and read you know you've
just got this like okay now i have three
plants that are [ __ ]
forever and a day from being done
you know yeah
yeah
cool all right um yeah check out readers
patreon go to google type it in
come hang out with us on discord we
shoot the [ __ ] all the time and uh
thanks a lot fletch for coming and
hanging out it's always a pleasure it
was super cool
everybody enjoy your friday night your
syndicates
be sure to check out our patreon by
going to google and searching breeder
syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsteads.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized
[Music]
you