ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder City game
so we're pretty excited today you know
we've been doing a lot of uh early
breeding talk uh trying to Source some
of the history of how we got to where we
are today we've talked about breeding
techniques we talked about a bunch of
early 80s and 90s seed banks we focused
on Neville quite a bit because he was
one of the largest seed banks in the 80s
and we're pretty excited today because
we have the other largest seed bank of
the 80s uh the super sativa seed club
which was next to Neville the biggest
seed bank in Holland at the time and
lots and lots of famous strains like
Williams Wonder and Beatrix choice and
things of that nature came out of their
seed bank and we're lucky in that the
founder is still alive and well and was
excited to talk to us so we want to
bring you a couple stage interview with
Corel who is the owner and founder of
the super sativity seed club and we're
going to be asking him a lot of
questions about the 80s the style they
were doing things how he got certain
strains and really all the areas of
Interest we can think of so this is kind
of like the the second big piece to 80
seed banks and modern breeding and we're
pretty excited so here it is prepare
yourself
okay let's go
so you are Carl it's pronounced Carl
yeah
it's an absolute pleasure to meet you
you're you're a a legend in this
business and a lot of us uh would love
would love to have this uh opportunity
to speak with you so I I it's an honor
okay okay take it easy man
I'm just a guy of Flesh and blues yeah
same here but it's it's really cool to
be able to have this opportunity to ask
you some some questions about the
history of sssc so where would you like
to start
yeah maybe
um yeah it's a long time ago already of
course and uh
1985 we started yes and and those days
yeah we were squatters and we we we were
like you are man really yeah we were
activists and
our idea was to
um yeah because in those days in Holland
it was not legal to grow yes but it was
like uh a little bit uh it was not it
was not a big deal to do it and not not
many people did it and um so um yeah we
started to grow and then actually
um we learned
about growing under uh mental health
life from people who went to the states
and they saw it there oh wow yeah
I work in those days in a coffee shop
and a friend of us he went to the states
and and and he saw how you guys did this
and nobody did in those days did this in
Holland and so um I thought yeah let's
give it a try and I think we were the
first to in Holland to to grow on the um
on the metal halites in those days it
was that's amazing yeah yeah and then so
uh we are we're looking to live close to
uh to the baker Horticulture Center was
hold on the Westland because the New
Holland is really we are the number one
in the world in the Horticulture and
things yes so um yeah
we decided to to start this the only
problem we we had we didn't have any
seeds oh so how does how do you start
sourcing your seeds and your lines what
makes you choose what you do yeah
because the thing is in those days the
the Cannabis was only
um
from the tropical countries uh yes and
it was all seated with a lot of seeds so
if you tried those seats and Holland
they didn't
they didn't they didn't flower in time
because we are quite known and then
those the sativity are from the Ecuador
yeah and so we we didn't have a success
really not and but one of the guys he
went to the stage of one of our friends
because yeah we've been in the seats and
he went to
um to New York and he had to a certain
office I I better I don't call the name
because this is them yeah and then they
said no man we don't have seats and uh
but he he said yeah but I come from
Holland and I came specially to you to
to pick up some seats and after one week
they said okay okay okay we will give
you some seats and those were the
William Wonder seats so those came out
of New York yes that's fascinating yes
and uh so then we started to grow
those sheets and then we will be at
quite not a big success but a little bit
says and after a while the famous damn
the screenman you've heard from him of
course yeah and he came to live in
Holland and and he contacted he
contacted us because he thought when I
live in Holland I have to be in touch
with the with the seed guys absolutely
and those days where you had Neville
okay and we were the second one and so
there were basically two seed banks in
the world that's right he came to we
became in contact with him and he told
us
um yeah and I come here to live in
Holland but I don't have a place to grow
and maybe you can help me or whatever
yeah she said hey I have a nice
collection of seats because he did a lot
of breathing already in the stage yeah
and um
his number one thing was skunk number
one it was really the uh
yeah the first Variety in the world that
really somebody took the effort to um
to inbred it and to to to to to to to
make a selection out of a big group and
basically so we we were very happy with
those seats and and he had something
from his private stash as well and he
said this is my private thing
but there are only 20 seats left
uh so he
um
um yeah he gave us his feet and those
were the the hay seats
oh so he sold you some of the original
hay seeds yes yes so he had 20 seats and
he gave 10 to us and and he gave 10 to
to Neville so these words from the same
batch you're a Neville
there were already like 10 years old and
he said this is really we need to
germinate them because because and I
gave it to you because you understand
how to do it and yeah so we can save the
seeds and
um we were not really
um we try to haste but we did we did not
like it because it took too long to
flower and it was Freddy small birds and
at the same time we were very glad with
the screen over number one seeds because
we were used to the fluffy the
sustratives that were from
South Africa from Jamaica from Colombia
so we were really happy to see the big
birds of the school number one
really a lot of residents and a lot of
smell and but we decided to make a cross
between security number one and the uh
and one of the uh the agency we had left
and from this cross we made a big
selection and that's then we were very
happy to find a one with the correct
correct the the smell and the taste of
the age and and the bird structure of
the screen gram run so that was really
happy that we could grow hazes but yeah
and they take fat birds and the nice
thing about this I still have this plant
and it's now 35 years old
and we we still have it and it's it's
our Flagship thing of course and uh we
have now based a lot of our crosses on
we made it with this old school lasers
we call it and it smells like catfish
and it's really a dark
earthy taste but it's then it's a very
uplifting high and it's really uh
yeah it's a really nice plant and it's
very difficult to grow because if you
make a mistake if your room gets too hot
it starts to flower again and it's
really a matter of
um yeah it's it's it's a difficult thing
to do I can't believe that that's still
around that's amazing that's absolutely
and you're still using it in your
current breeding programs yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah
um we stopped with the superset diva sea
clip after about five years because it
was really too
it became a little bit too successful
yeah I know what you mean and in those
days it was really
um yeah I remember a bit afraid of
Ronald Reagan the War on Drugs was going
on we're really strong in those days so
basically we quit the super city of seed
Club but I I kept on growing and doing
uh
doing cannabis and all different ways
and I like three or four years ago my
two sons I have two sons they are
Growers as well said I let's do it again
man why don't you do it because
everybody knows you and yeah
some people think you are a legend so
well let's do it again so we started
again and uh and yeah there's no quite
successful and now in Holland we are
also getting a situation of
of legal growing because yeah and all
that we have also always been on the
Forefront of the of the growing sure but
but yeah we lost a little bit because
you guys are doing it very good of
course now in the in the states and uh
in the legal situation and a lot of
um in a lot of States so um
can't stay behind man because we are the
ones who
exactly thrilled out to do the Cannabis
thing yeah and now we are looking at we
started a Lobby in Holland
and and we we also try to
uh to change the law we basically wrote
a law together with the Dutch government
and now there is going to be a big
um like a trial and the the Dutch
government uh has
given out 10 permits to grow legal for
the Dutch coffee shops oh wow and we
were we were lucky to want one of the
permits because 150 people applied for
the pyramid I'm sure and only 10 permits
so
and uh like from from 150 people uh 100
didn't make it because the plan was not
good enough and yeah they were not
because you needed to to uh to comply in
a lot of rules because you need to know
about cannabis you need to have the
money you need to have to to grow on a
big scale you need good context with the
coffee shops and we all have this so
um now we are very happy because then we
can do our breathing really because we
have done the breathing all always in
the illegal yeah same here so you can
imagine that it's for us uh difficult
because we like to see it but it's also
a little bit difficult to see that
people like
um
exotic mic exotic genetics is really
they can they can work in the legal
situation now for over three four five
years and you can see the results and
yeah he has a lot of people making seed
for him everywhere all over so yeah yeah
yeah yeah and um yeah and then hold on
to me we still have the like the the
strange difficult strains to grow
with the special
profiles and yeah that's what we want to
offer uh something different because um
it's kooky it's cookies everywhere
nowadays I I surely hope you guys stick
with some of the base old stuff because
that's what we need nobody wants cookies
anymore over here everybody's tired of
cookies yeah really yeah because over
here it's still new yeah it's still new
over there right like it's yeah yeah
and and like a strange but also an a
comic situation in uh that um we we went
to the states to get the seeds then we
grow we did a lot of uh breathing and
things then we sold it back to the stage
and now
the states is doing very well and now we
have to go to the states again
in that situation because we have
everything over here and and you don't
have to fly out to get it you understand
that so that's good that's nice that
it's going uh all over the world and the
idea of the super sativa seed clip was
because we were very politically
involved with our idea to
um
yeah to help the state is a little bit
it's strange to save but we were in this
position that we could do uh
Sami legal or things and in those days
you had a lot of people coming back from
Vietnam those were our clients you know
because they they ordered the cheese
from us and they they were the ones who
really uh did a lot of gorilla farming
and and and in California where it's
still going in the same place but it's
now we'll go it happened so uh rld was
when when we sell the seeds to a lot of
different people in the in the US
there will be a lot of different a lot
of refrigerated
refrigerators stocked with seeds so for
the government it's quite difficult to
stop this you know because yeah it's
spreading everywhere and and in those
days you didn't have the internet and
it's if you live in a certain city okay
you can spread the seeds
give this to your friends yeah it's a
bit difficult when you live in
California to to to to make sure that
also the people in
so we our idea was to to spread it
everywhere with the ID this is not going
to stop anymore then yeah that's it's a
beautiful idea it's like Johnny
Appleseed modern day Danny Johnny
Appleseed yeah and also we did we were
not in for the money because we we did
we we really were in for the love of the
plants and we still are and of course
the money was nice but uh because the
our business uh model was a little bit
strange because people from the states I
understand people money to to Holland
yeah without knowing who who we are oh
sure sure and then and then they had to
trust us that we sent the seats back to
them absolutely and the first few years
people were a little bit reluctant to
Santa's uh money because of course maybe
who are we nobody knew yeah and so at
one point people from High Times They
Came to to came to interview us because
we render and and High Times and they
thought oh man this is really
um
this is this is for Real yes so they
make it they made a nice cover story
about this from those days it's really
yeah it really exploded you know yeah
yeah and then we got we got we got like
um
people from all the from everywhere in
the world ordering sheets and we don't
uh this is really getting too big and
equipment is because
it was getting a little bit out of hands
yeah yeah it got a little hot because in
a lot of people
from Japan from Australia from Canada
from everybody start to order seeds
because it was really the first we
really were the first ones to do this
and yeah so it was a big uh big success
and we were
Robert Como Clark you know him as well I
think oh yes he told her also always the
wisest thing you did discreet with this
yeah we saw what happened with Neville
we saw what happened it ruined his life
yeah yeah yeah so so it's really uh and
now um
yeah we're still going strong and we are
still loving the plants and we we are
still very happy to um
to make combinations with the new things
from the states with our old stuff and a
lot of things turned out very well
because we like to have
we like the layered taste you know oh
yeah if we do something with Haze we
will be we can keep the the haste taste
but also we can combine it with uh like
gorilla glue or whatever and it makes it
really a a thing that we like that it's
not one taste but a lot of different
taste is in one variety and
um yeah and and we are not so afraid of
doing things like uh 12 weeks of
flowering and because yeah a lot of
people are afraid to do this and they
are
it's difficult but it's really worth
waiting a few weeks actually Americans
are finally
um being more receptive to Long
flowering strains as of the past maybe
two or three years I've noticed hazes
are finally starting to pick up in the
U.S whereas they were never a staple
here except in in Santa Cruz in the you
know late 60s early 70s mid 70s but
nowadays people want that they want a
little bit of that that trippy Colombian
and yeah yeah because we also we work
together with age seeds as well do you
know Asia oh yeah oh yeah
yeah that's what these are our friends
as well and they're a really good
company they have they I really have
like uh these
super strong that's sativas and and and
now like in an um in the legal situation
in in the US I do not understand why
people are afraid to from a longer
flowery time because if you have the
space to do this
yeah I can imagine in the illegal
situation when you don't have much space
it's a bit
um yeah of course and I can imagine that
you you want to speed up things a little
bit but but what I have seen always is
uh it takes four weeks longer to to
finish
but but the yield and get there
30 40 more yeah so at the end of the day
your results are exactly the same as
when you grow short flowering varieties
sure because the big the the the the the
what we and how long to always say the
the modern American strange they lack
wait
yeah yeah absolutely that's why we try
to make roses with the new American
strains to to to to get to make plans
with the big reels yes because sativas
you know how they how they flower the
the the the the birds are arm length and
yes and then the the cookies you have a
birth
you don't have anything another bird
it's nice but it doesn't bring weight in
the scale yeah no there's cookies is
very low yielding and yeah the high
doesn't last too long either so a good
Haze hybrid with the cookies would be
awesome you know bring a much better
height of cookies that isn't there yeah
yeah yeah yeah
so I have some questions for you
um do you have a lot of good um a good
memory for like where you sourced
certain things or the history of certain
strains that you put out no no no no no
no no that's a bit of a problem because
um the old school has
um the Clone we still have and I'm in
touch with in Canadia a lot of people
they still have the free slam the Indica
yeah yes yes but it was very famous
almost people told me that a lot of
people from 50 60 years old now that
they started when they started to to
smoke they all started with free slam
Indica it was over there it was really
uh a big thing yeah now um today I
talked with somebody from Canada and he
he knows a guy in the US who still has
the Beatrix Jewish and
um
m33 and the the thing is in in so many
years a lot of things happened so to be
honest I lost a little bit track of
where everything is now yeah and and in
those days we'll be basically uh the
families he provided us with seats and a
lot of sheets we we just took from um
from the backs of weed that we that we
yeah that we bought in the coffee shops
and and in those days oh but we were we
had to go fish in Amsterdam we had the
coffee shop it was called Durban Poison
yes and they only sold
um cannabis from South Africa yes so we
made a lot of crosses with the Durban
Poison because it's this South African
is also
it's part of the South and the world so
the flowering period is more or less the
same as we have in Holland yeah so this
was very nice to make roses between
screen number one uh German poison and
then we and then we gave it a nice name
and it was like our variety and it was
not a big deal because it was really
um
we took the seeds from the backs and we
grew them and we pollinated the the one
that we like best
and we had a new variety because in
those days it was not really
inbredding yeah we did not really do
that because to be honest the demand for
our seeds were so big that we even
didn't have time to do this you know oh
I bet yeah I understand that
yeah so um yeah one thing that's been
happening in the U.S the past maybe 15
years since I've been around I've
noticed there is a um and this this is
unfortunate uh seriously unfortunate but
every two or three years someone will
come up and pretend to have a big
collection of old sssc stuff yeah and
then sell it it's all fake you know yeah
it just happened to Beatrix Choice
someone just popped up with fake Beatrix
Choice that's probably what you're
referring to yeah that's not anyone's
collections over here you know who
Beatrix is yeah oh yeah oh yeah yeah we
we've studied your strains for so many
years
um the Williams Wonder clone is still
out here that that colony is still
available yeah there's still seeds every
once in a while you'll find Williams
Wonder seeds that are pure okay nice and
39 still around still around so it's a
famous one yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
because in the in Canada I went to visit
Canada and then the guy he get he he
showed me the freeze land indigo
then I was really like
there is of course a lot of things
happened or in all those years and the
ability is becoming better and better
and it's of course I was not really
um very proud to see the the fridge I
thought this is not really but we like
those days and these days you know yes
but I think it's more special are the
Hastings because the age is really
something uh something different and and
it's also um
for me as the owner of this super city
of sea Club it's sometimes funny that
people tell me things that I myself even
don't know you know yeah I'm sure yeah
you can imagine that um
because he had a lot of different
varieties and yeah for us it's different
than than for for the collectors you
know oh sure yeah it's really uh but I
really like it to her that a lot of
people are still trying to find the
roots from Cannabis you know because
it's basically it's basically uh even a
never he of course did a bit more than
we did and and because he was really the
first one and he yeah we were the second
ones and it's all
that's all for uh Neville he he's not
anymore with us anymore you know yeah I
was friends with him yeah yeah yeah yeah
so it was in there yeah but then the
nice thing is also that we we we got
some uh of his last work in Clone form
okay yeah we have the Outback Hayes okay
that's the one he made in Australia when
he lived in Australia yeah kingativa Ian
made all those for him oh yeah I don't
know yeah yeah he's one of my good
friends we were all working together
during that time ah okay okay yeah yeah
yeah and then we also could have a h g
oh nice yeah yeah and that's how and we
have also the nl5 times Haze oh good the
the the the the real the Clone that he
uh he selected him from a lot of plants
I really don't know oh oh so like there
is I think it's the A5 or C5 A5 no no no
no no no the A5 and the C5 we also have
oh do you have those two yeah yeah yeah
but because
um
there's a group of people uh yeah who
still have all those things and then
they um
yeah and and then in the haste world
it's still a little bit
nobody owns this you know yeah of course
yeah people think they do do you think
they do this is like uh we are like uh
um
uh activists you know we think uh I I
don't believe in owning screens and
ownings absolutely I agree not everybody
agrees with this but uh no not everybody
does agree with that um
of course uh when somebody puts a lot of
effort in in breathing a strain or
working a strain like many years then he
can then I consider it that he owns it
yeah correct if if it's long bred and
selected and a lot of work put into it
right now Gorilla Glue is going after
everyone yeah and also at the point when
somebody is selling in the seat uh Bank
a regular seat yeah then I own it as
well
you're buying the genetics right yeah
because and if you don't want to sell
the genetics you have to feminize it or
whatever and even then I mean if someone
feminizes your your feminized seeds then
you're just that [ __ ] out of luck
because you've sold it yeah yeah yeah so
so I'm not really busy and protecting
the genetics and uh sure and then and
maybe uh because I also want to ask your
questions of course yeah because do you
think do we see things happening in the
states like that people are trying to
protect
strains or genetics yeah people are
trying to patent feminization techniques
that they had nothing to do with
creating people are trying to patch
strains as quickly as they can trademark
strain names like doji Kush but but
names it's a different thing because
yeah but the plant varieties we can't
patent them yet but there are many
people at the Forefront of that trying
to get it the second that it uh happens
and it'll be a problem it'll definitely
what are they trying to do then because
and hold on do you have like um
yeah because we have a lot of
horticulture flowers and everything you
can you can patent if you can you can
own this train as long as it's as it is
different in a lot of expects than any
other screen sure and the second thing
you have to do you have to be able to
reproduce it and that means if you have
100 seats of the strain all the plants
have to be the same uniform so an IBL
perform and also and the next time you
show them they have to be the same again
yeah I don't think anyone in the U.S
except for maybe CSI Humboldt and a few
others uh uh 707 seed bank there's only
probably two or three people who are
capable of uh even producing seed lines
like that let alone so I think many
people are really going to be getting
the patents there's some uh breeders up
in BC that have been doing it very
seriously and big for a long time
that'll probably
um be looking for that in their country
because to give you an example if you
were like you know how long do you have
a lot of big seed companies tomato seeds
and everything yeah yeah and if you if
you buy a kilo tomato seeds you're
buying 50 000 seats and if you grow
those 50 000 plants they are all 100 the
same yeah uniform
and there is not one marijuana strain
around that it's uniform you know no
it's and and I don't know that marijuana
can be
um brought to uniformity because
environment takes such a a big factor in
in expression and also of course because
of the military multi multiple hybrids
exactly I I know for sure that in the
cookies there is something from us oh
yeah I guarantee it and and for sure
there is some screen number one in it
yeah the step the screenman always told
me everything but I think we know
exactly what cookies is now it's very
it's it's a simple simple little um
thing but to break it down to its base
components it's going to be something
like skunk one Afghani one yeah and I
like that I really like it the the smell
and The Taste and I really uh want to
say and good work but guys who did to
the guys who did it yeah it was an
accident but this is of course difficult
to make this uniform because yeah in in
the cookies let's say the cookies there
are maybe like 25 different varieties oh
yeah easy easy for sure yeah and those
were like the screen number one is all
is already those who already have like
five
yeah the varieties in it yes and then
you bring in more parents with all their
backgrounds and grandparents
the hybridization is like
there are one million swings yeah I
think exactly I try to keep it to the in
my work I like to keep it to a baseline
like a base Afghani or a base something
like that you know and cross it too it
may be a poly hybrid so it brings that
down dramatically you know like it's
easier to breed yeah and line breed from
it and select and at the super sativity
we are not really uh the body putting a
lot of
efforts in
um and and breathing and everything
because sure what we like is um when I
buy seeds I like to do final hunting
yeah and final hunting
uh yeah that's that's the nice thing
when we make a cross with with our age
then you will find a lot of different
things and one of the plants is really
something special you know oh sure and
that's right that's what what I like and
the the big LPS did
they try to sell to buy seeds and then
they think then we have a uniform group
but I always tell them please man do
female ending and I look for a nice
mother and go from there
yeah because I have a I have a quick
question for you
um there's been some myths and stories
over the years one of the stories that
came up recently and someone made a seed
company off of was uh saying that they
were breeding for you in Virginia to
make your skunk one no that's not true
that's not true I didn't think it was
true but I had to ask because it's a lot
of people
he made the screen number one and he
made he made it in California and he was
really the first guy in the world to uh
to to to grow in a big greenhouse and to
do really
um to do real
um breathing you know yeah and then
basically the the screen grammar one the
original one is
um
there are basically two phenotypes one
with the pointed uh one bit around it
and the smell in the days they were all
uh really quite uniform sure and that
was his work and uh in Holland in those
days uh all the breathing
was done with screen number one because
and it was really uh it's it's good
number one in the 80s and the 90s was in
every planet
um can we ask you the history on Beatrix
choice because again you brought it up
earlier and it's one that people liked
is there a certain history on it no no
really the the only thing is to be
honest I really I even don't remember
the uh it's been a long time yeah yeah
the cross that we make that we made the
only thing is that we remember we why we
put the name on it that that that's what
what was the name from
yeah because it's Beatrix is the queen
of Holland yes and so we thought uh in
those days like you like your T-shirt
man we were yeah we were like this and
that was those days and we had one
Victor Barn do you know Victor Barn
Victor Barn yeah yeah that's a nice
story to tell because in those days
um we had enroll on the Lockheed Affair
and the Lockheed that was like the
company who who built airplanes oh lucky
yeah yeah yeah and the Lockheed so our
the the
um the husband of our Queen was Prince
Bernard and he was he was like a naughty
guy he was doing he had a lot of
different wives and he was doing a lot
of different things and and he he made
he made a deal with the Lockheed and he
said I will make sure that the Dutch
government is going to buy your
airplanes
okay you have to pay me 10 million
dollars for this and look he did he did
that that has this this Prince better
not had to use a fake name to open a
bank account to put
there to let Loki put this 10 million
dollar on this bank account yeah and he
used the fake name Victor Barton oh
that's funny I didn't know that so that
was like uh
a little bit like this with them you
know I love that you're telling that we
can't grow a weed are you doing the this
kind of things yeah
yeah yeah yeah I am very I'm I'm very
politically active here
um
our government is very especially in
California certain areas of California
are still very illegal like a lot of
people don't know that like they think
California they think legal State
um I'm in a part of California that's
the Bible Belt so despite any laws our
county has overridden the laws and if
you get caught growing you're [ __ ] you
go to the [ __ ] jail you're done you
know so we're still very politically
active here trying to fight uh a lot of
that and everything's still done very
clandestine Black Market in most of the
uh States okay yeah yeah I know it I
know I know I I'm very good friends with
the people for humble seats oh yeah and
they always tell me everybody thinks
it's legal but still it's it's not legal
at all yeah it's scary scary in some
places yeah yeah so now for me the
circle is a little bit run because I
started this thing more or less and now
I'm very happy that I'm part of the
group that go to permit to grow legal in
Holland you know yeah for me it's like
uh the circle is around
[Music]
all right so what you just saw there was
you saw the first part of our interview
with Corel from Super sativa seed Club
Matt I wasn't unable to make it so Matt
did the first one we had a series of
follow-up questions and ideas and so
Corel was kind enough to come back and
chat with us again it's possible this
might be ongoing but for now we have a
two-part Series so the first was Matt
the second will be primarily me although
Matt might be in it for a minute and
after that we'll have some commentary
where we talk about what we learned and
what we were excited about hearing
foreign
you know we read the we read the
catalogs we talk and talk about various
things but we're all a little younger to
have actually experienced like basically
you and the seed bank kind of starting
off like yeah yeah yeah oh this one okay
that's kind of like you know you you and
Neville at the seed bank you you two
kind of started off what we consider to
be like the modern seed era right like
before you uh
we were really curious as to like
certain questions you know for instance
um you know you you mentioned before uh
when did you when did you first start
seeing like Americans come in and
bringing their seed lines like skunk one
and and the Durbin or Afghani one or
these different things
yes
um
we started in 85 and um
yeah yeah after one year or so the
seventh Kingman he came to Holland to to
live in Holland
and uh yeah he he wrote us a letter
because we were burning an ad an
advertisement in uh in High Times
magazine the Neville and the seed bank
did it as well so Sam told that when I
go to Holland I let's hook up with those
two guys and uh let's talk about cheats
and uh
I told them I met last time and then
those days we didn't have much feet the
only seats we have were from uh come
back from that we bought at the coffee
shops and it was all uh
sativas and so basically
um Sam the straight man brought all the
seats from the US to Amsterdam and of
course the the next one was Robert Clark
a friend of Sam's Green Man and after
that a few more came and the the the
nice thing about it is that the seeds
came from the the US to Amsterdam
then we started to send it to the US
again
and now it's again that we look into the
U.S to buy seats again from from you
guys
we were first more liberal than humor
because
in 85
it never has been illegal that will uh
in Holland but in 85 in those in the
beginning
not a lot of people they knew about uh
cannabis and they so basically we have
we could do what we want because nobody
knew about it and nobody uh even the
police didn't really take
um they left they let us do what we
wanted to do you know it's it's a and an
Amsterdam there were a few more we're
not burning of course he was really the
first one with the seed bank but he he
didn't respond it's International it was
only for Holland and he was really um
yeah he's older than me as well and he
um yeah he he also started to put the
coffee shop which is the first girl shop
is it the positronics
and then the coffee shop is the Mellow
Yellow and he's still around he
um he invented model that um not the
Rick Simpson Oil but then
yeah I I don't know he calls it
mediter and
um yeah he has a good
um he really there's a lot of good work
because
um he basically introduced to the Dutch
patients how to make your own oil that's
awesome he wants to teach the people uh
how to do it he wants that everybody's
an independent and independent from
Pharmaceuticals you need to make your
own medicine and I fully agree with it
yes so I think it really
um
he's still around and come back to the
question
um
Sam just kidding man he's nearly the man
who brought everything to uh Amsterdam
really yeah did you have any
interactions with uh Keys Hawker from
Loveland seeds no no no
he's older already yeah yeah no no no no
because the thing is um they um they try
to uh to push the as we call it the
native basically growing your own
backyard and we were more
um we thought uh is to call them the
rainy and the wet and let's go indoors
because we we saw it yeah we saw it
happening in the US and we were um
we were readers of High Times magazine
yeah we were lucky enough to have an uh
the American bookstore in The Hague so
we went there every month to to buy the
the newest copies
we were sure what what in America was
going on and yeah yeah that's more or
less how we started for us skunk one and
Haze and and those type of things are
very very famous strains and they kind
of became like the backbone of what you
guys were doing over there for a while
yeah what was it like to grow those
things at first we were very happy
especially with the screen number one
because
um they were not used to see this kind
of big butts and uh yeah stable genetics
because
um
yeah you can imagine if you grow
outdoors
sativa strained from the Ecuador
yeah it doesn't flour the flowers in
this in December and in December it's
cold and rain and snow so we didn't see
we we never ever had seen even Birds you
know yeah so uh this was a big game
changer when he came with his uh stuff
and especially uh the student number one
and the haze he gave us 10 seats in the
lost city he stayed from his favorite
variety and he gave the other 10 seeds
to Neville and
um
yeah we didn't pay too much attention to
the haze because it was long flowering
and only very very small bits and it was
really we were so happy with the screen
number one that we almost forgot about
the haze
luckily enough we made crosses between
School number one and Haze yeah and
because we had 10 plants and and
yeah two or two times we were arrested
by the police and they took all our
races and we we had only one left I even
don't know anymore if it was if it was a
boy or a girl but oh man he already made
the seats with
um the screen number one and I I still
have a lot of sheets
that we went between crosses between our
10 Aces
I try to germinate it and it really
doesn't work anymore
the problem was I I I kept them outside
the refrigerator for 10 years yeah I put
them in the refrigerator and I know I
still have them so maybe some of your
listeners yeah teaching culture because
uh in my opinion uh the seat where there
is only one cell alive still yeah
basically you could reproduce it but if
the government I don't think they want
to help us with this one yeah yeah if
they find in a seat of wheat in a
pyramid in in Egypt yeah they'll make
sure that it's going to work again oh
yeah but with cannabis seeds I still we
still have to find somebody who can help
us because I think the you know you know
what I mean oh yeah tissue cultures
teach them alive somewhere in those
seats still and of course it would be
nice to germinate it I gave it to a few
people
we will manage because I know how to do
it yeah yeah
of course yeah
yeah but that's a Pity of course and to
come back to your German poison I don't
know yeah in those days we had an
Amsterdam a coffee shop it was called
the golden poison and oh yeah the only
thing they sold was a wheat from South
Africa
I don't remember the names anymore but
uh the the the the the the the major
thing they solved with Urban Poison and
that's also why we we had quite a few
crosses in our first catalog with their
poison because we both see we both read
from them
and together with string number one all
the questions all the crosses with
screen number one
gave us more early flowering
and a nice smell so it was basically
um
a winner combinations
number one
well do you remember what any of the um
smell profiles of the different number
ones that you popped back in the day
were like yeah there's good number one
was really uh like the names uh the name
Tales at all it stinks like spoon oh so
back then it actually smelled like
skunks like North America yeah I I
really to be honest I never have smelled
it it's been getting milk but
it was more about the the that it was so
strong it was really strong you know
yeah
um in my uh that I have you can still
smell
in the back you smell the uh the screen
the the the strong smell of the screen
number one yeah and then together with
this with the with the Asian today it
gives you like
there's a lot the the old school is very
fully planned because if you make an
analyze of it
there is all there's only a perfume
that's the only Turpin that's in it yeah
and not too much as well but if you
smoke it it's really Disturbed smell and
taste that I have ever seen and wheat so
yeah that's a big mystery and and I know
it's about Philippines how is it
possible that the plant with only one
and not a lot of it can smell so strong
and taste so strong yeah do you know the
answer I don't know I don't know so
basically when you first got it it was
skunk number one was an early finishing
big bud very pretty it smelled like a
skunk yeah did it smell like did it
smell like citrus too it was there no no
no no no not at all no no no no it was
more the dark side of the like the
earthy
um
Rudy and yes yes it was not no no no not
any sweetness no not any uh any interest
in it you know because what we're
familiar with is as as younger people is
skunk number one smells like floral it
smells sweet it smells so you're saying
um that what what Sam brought over first
is very different than what ended up
being common in Europe later
yes yeah yeah because number one there
are still a lot of seeds Bank around and
they they they think or they they they
they they they know I don't know they
think that they still have screened
number one but there there is no school
number one anymore the only screen
number one that is around is very
diluted nothing to compare with um
there is no real skunk number one
anymore around
the interesting because when he went
there he gave seeds to you he gave some
seeds to Neville it sounds like he gave
some seeds to Bernard from positronics
Mellow Yellow
um what was the what was the little was
the community in Amsterdam then did
everyone know each other because yes yes
the the the the thing is we didn't live
in Amsterdam we still don't live in
Amsterdam and there wasn't the Amsterdam
scene was more about the outdoor growing
um and then and and
we I think we were the first ones in how
long to grow indoors
Sam teach a lot of people how to grow in
a greenhouse and since Sam arrived in
Holland the people started to grow in
greenhouses because
you could do it without a lot of trouble
because nobody knew about
how it smells and how it looks and
basically uh the the first five years
that Sam was around a lot of greenhouse
growing was going on and he basically
teached everybody and Holland how to do
it and we we didn't grow in a greenhouse
because in our opinion
it's more safe to do it but then of
course at the end of the day
all the all the greenhouses were always
always bursted
they could do one group maybe second
group was already uh this is a small
country
and there is no Countryside at all the
greenhouses are all always close to a
village close to a town with a lot of
people around a lot of people live in
one square mileage really tours
we have the country it seems like you
reclaim from the sea you know so yeah so
um besides Hayes and skunk what else did
you get from Sam
never
he get he got like early Pearl early
from Rob maybe yeah early Pearl and a
few other ones but also we were not we
were not too much in touch with Neville
because the Neville's approach was
different than our approach uh we were
underground people
and we were not really
um too fun to to receive a lot of people
we don't know in our house and then and
in those days it never had the uh
the Cannabis starts to let everybody
even more or less was welcome over there
but and especially when you came with a
lot of money to buy seeds everybody was
welcome
and we were always more like hmm
uh let's let's try to keep it
underground and let's
let's try to do it in a
in a more of a more or less safe way
because we we didn't want to get caught
and we wanted to do the one in this
business for forever you know and there
never was more of Daredevil when he was
like
I don't know who came to his house
anymore I I I I really don't know if he
knew I don't think so you know because a
lot of Americans in those days they came
to Amsterdam and then everybody was
welcome at Neville's place
we were a little more careful too
besides Sam where were some other
sources in the previous conversation you
had with Matt you told that a lot of
stuff you got you were getting off seeds
from buds out of coffee shops were there
any other people or sources once you
started making super sativa seed Club
where people coming to find you and
trade scenes with you yeah but they were
they were coming
couldn't find this
okay
the only the only one who could find
this was
Rosenthal and George Cervantes and
and the uh the chief editor of High
Times
um
Stephen
Hager of course yeah yeah yeah yeah and
then those were the only three people
who could face this because we were
really like
um
we knew what we were we knew we
understood what we were doing you know
so then that that leads me to another
question in your catalog you have
something called Oakland Indica yeah and
I'm just curious as to where that where
you got that or where it came from
you know I don't know because a few
times because we had a lot of clients of
course and then we we received a lot of
letters in those days and a few times
people sent us the seats but not only
only a few times and I think because
Oakland that that is from Oakland
because in those days we got like 100
letters every day you know and yeah it
was really fun for us to read all those
letters and also uh we
um we ask people to help us to to
distribute seats in the U.S and just we
were just reading the letters and we
thought oh this guy is a nice guy
because he understands how it works yeah
so it was a really nice job for me to
read all these labs and to answer them
as well because maybe even nowadays you
still get letters from people from from
the old days and they said ah nice to
see you back and do you remember that we
walked isn't there from you no of course
that's really uh really funny and uh
when we started again a few years ago we
got a letter from somebody and he says
now yeah nowadays Mother Nature is legal
in the U.S and that we really thought a
guy who who writes a letter and says
modern nature is bleeding now you know
yeah it used to be illegal but now we
are happy that it's legal and that was
those were the letters that we really
liked and there are people who
understood how crazy it is to make
mother nature illegal yeah it is wild
yeah so
um what you got about the Durban Thai
high flyer now that was one of your most
famous lines yeah we still see it around
today do you have any memories
surrounding it yeah this was a very uh
pure sativa of course and also um
because of Durban is still in the south
of the world that is almost in the same
latitude and Holland is
so the flowering times
they are more or less the same than our
flowering time because we our our
Harvest our Autumn starts in September
yeah and then also the the the the the
the harvested it's getting colder so and
we were lucky to have the Durban uh
traveling so early the Durban was a very
was the is the one sativa that's sort of
an early finisher yeah so so it worked
well in Holland yes and and and the
combination with the with the tie
because the tie is a very very late
flowering yeah then then
it's finished so like half October or
something and that's nice for us because
in October sometimes when you're lucky
the weather is still good yeah but but
our the our main customers in the US
were the people from California the
Vietnam veterans
[Music]
from Vietnam they started to do the
gorilla farming and they really they
made money with it as well so they they
did they send us a nice amounts of money
yeah yeah
well I mean from our perspective
um you know back then especially indicas
and things like that were pretty rare
yeah even though California and America
there was
um there was you know there was a lot of
things going on people didn't know each
other so really like one of the most
interesting things about what happened
with you guys for us is that
um you know like you were saying before
a bunch of stuff flowed from America
over to amster over to Holland yeah and
went everywhere in America
it went to the house that went to the
north New York it went to the Midwest
and that was our goal that was our goal
that's why we did this because we
thought in those days yeah there's no
internet so your your friends live close
to you in the same town so you can swap
sheets with your friends but it doesn't
spread the whole country you know and
then since we were starting we got
letters from everywhere Alaska Texas
whatever and then so
we thought when all the refrigerators in
the states are filled with seeds
it's a difficult thing to stop it and
there's this movement
what about the what about your what
about the creeper or the kyber pass yeah
the the degree decree we called it the
creepy because it was really
um the plant it was not upright but it
was laying down more or less it oh
that's why I always assumed it was the
high but it was no no no no no no no no
it wasn't it was not about the high it
was really about the the morphle logic
uh aspects of the of the plant because
normally a plant is like more or less
like a Christmas tree but this one was
like bending over and laying down
you know and uh yeah I I still like this
kind of uh plans because they they gave
you a big Harvest yeah room for bits you
know and yeah yeah and the guy the the
the the chiropractor and we cross it
with an Afghani
um I think yes because of Afghani and
Holland it will be the the hash from
Afghanistan was really very popular and
um I don't know where we got the sheets
from but did you guys ever grow flowers
for coffee shops or did you just focus
on seeds yes yes yes
yeah because we we were growing for the
coffee shops as well yeah yeah because
we they liked our indoor read because it
was quite it was new
and um in those days we um
we were worrying a little bit about the
fact that our wheat was Green
because
people uh they were used to to buy
marijuana was always Brown so half
rotten meat as we call it now and and
our indoor
marijuana was green so we thought oh
nobody's going to buy this because they
they don't because green the The only
green marijuana we knew was that I was
the neither beat and that was the wheat
that we grew in our backyard
and they didn't have Birds it was only
leaves and it was green so we were
afraid that people thought our wheat was
a little bit
so we tried to make we tried to make it
brown to to be able to to to sell it but
after a few uh
I don't know maybe after a year
everybody said I don't know the green
was the best one it's much better than
the brown round man no man don't worry
about the color will be buy it anyway
so yeah
yeah I was really that was a really
funny thing yeah that he really people
are really worried about the green color
they were really worried because it was
so because the part about that is that
everything was so new yeah yeah it was
new and then the first since Emilia that
I saw in Holland
that was somebody and then one year we
had we were lucky enough to have a good
September in Holland normally it's
raining in September already but in this
September there was a lot of sun
so in the coffee shop where I worked
somebody came with a garbage bag full of
big birds and they were not trimmed at
all and then I thought where does this
come from because this I really didn't
it was the first time we saw a green Big
Bird plant but this this was also I
think a German poison or something but
he was lucky
who grow some German poison seeds in a
year that we had a very good nice
September so the plant was to finish
and that was really the first time that
I saw shins
you got into weed was by working in a
coffee shop yes I worked in a coffee
shop when I was like 18 years or 19
years old and then one of the our
customers came to um to me and he said I
I am I I I I'm a reader of items
magazine and I saw how they grew how
they grow plants already because at
Roosevelt was one of the first started
with all data I think in the US and this
guy said I bought a metal halide lamp
because we have a big Horticultural
syndrome here in Holland and in those
days the the the greenhouse grower they
they used it to grow cake
the metal Airlines and he went there to
buy one and he said I want to grow
I'm about to start to use it and I
thought I live in a squat house and
let's do it so that's how it started
because this guy he he didn't
he was reader of items magazines
so we knew so most of most of super
sativa seed clubs uh work was all done
indoors whether you were growing buds
for coffee shops or whether you were
making seeds yes
we kept it inside yeah and that was all
because of um
you know and in a greenhouse it's the
Holland is too crowded to grow in a
greenhouse and it's uh
no everybody got caught always in the
greenhouse so
we're growing it you
guys did you have garages were you
growing in bedrooms no maybe we had
garages and we bought it at one point we
bought a house especially to do it and
um no no and I know those people are
squatters yeah you know what squatters
are yes
and if you are a squatter you always
have a house
[Music]
so you you squatted in the house and
then you set up some lights and you set
up some rooms to do breeding and grow
weed and you sold the weed to the coffee
shops and you sold seeds catalog yeah
yeah yeah and we were the best quarters
but we earned a lot of money
very cool
we're not in it for the money man
because but it was nice to have money to
do that a lot of money came to us of
course but it was not really our uh the
the basic thing
the funny thing for us is that now
um you know there's so many seed
companies in America and there's a lot
of seed come from Europe and everything
like that but when when you guys started
and when Neville started there was
really only you two yeah that was easy
like you said if you went to positronics
if you went to Holland and went directly
to certain coffee shops maybe you could
get some seed then in order to order
things there was only two yes really so
that your that your company's stuff and
Neville's company stuff got spread so
far and wide yeah yeah yeah but but when
Neville stopped
um
look over then they both basically
that's how sensation started they bought
Neville stock and then they started in
the name chances and then they've been
drunk is the the
the one that's the guy who started this
this is really a big
a big
um thank to Ben because he was really
the guy with the biggest balls you know
he he he
went on very very started where we
stopped
so do you think that um did Neville sell
his company to Ben and Allen because of
the trouble he got in
I think so yeah did you in the community
back then were you ever we like was it a
small enough community that you were
close to a lot of these people yes yes
but the thing I said I said before we
were not really
um we were we had our own group of
people and we were not we we didn't live
in Amsterdam you know so so uh you
didn't live in Amsterdam you lived in
different yeah yeah we lived in The
Hague that's good it's uh close to
Amsterdam but so uh
maybe to be honest we tried to stay out
of the all those
groups I had to keep your head and stay
quiet and yeah yeah
really and we were not like behaving
like rockstars or something we were just
uh we were just quotes running a
cannabis scene business so how did
um how did how did like Jorge Cervantes
and Ed Rosenthal how did they find you
did they write you yeah yeah they sent
us a letter yeah they write them because
in those days
you wrote letters to people
sure yeah
and you put it and you put the stamp on
the envelope and you put it in the
mailbox that was
maybe it's a good idea that we go back
to this kind of communication again
because nobody can listen to it yeah
yeah did they um did they did they bring
seeds too or did they want to just come
up
no but but I have a nice anecdote about
uh
Georgia Cervantes because he came to
visit us and he asked us to uh to show
around
um to show to show him the the Dutch
greenhouse because in those days the
greenhouses they they were growing and
metal under HBS large that we had
greenhouses with ten thousand HPS lights
in it and he never he didn't ever see
this and so we gave him a tour and he
came he showed up in the tour with a
nice t-shirt cannabis USA California
that's not how it goes you have to put
put on some some different teachers man
because we can't show you around in the
greenhouse wearing this t-shirt and said
oh why that is it's legal in Holland
isn't it no no no it's not legal at all
everybody thinks it's legal but it's
it's it is not legal so um we had to
teach a little bit how to behave in
Holland
we had the same we had the same issue in
uh in California where I live when
medical first happened 20 years ago a
lot of people thought it was legal
but it's really legal it was it was kind
of like Holland it was permitted but you
could still get in trouble anytime yeah
I know a lot of people from California
and they still they always tell me it's
still illegal man yeah yeah it's still
early it was still whether or not the
cop wanted to be nice to you they could
treat you any which way they wanted and
it was kind of the same about Holland
I'm sure too yeah it all depended on the
attitude yeah yeah and that's that's why
we try to keep a little bit underground
because of uh we wanted to go up on this
and then I I wanted to I I'm I'm having
a family and everything and I was really
I'm not that type of guy who wants to be
in the big pictures me either I feel you
on that
um uh so after you started breeding at
supersetv seed club for a while and you
realize that you got popular did you
start keeping a lot of breeding males
and breeding females like yeah yeah yeah
yeah basically we had like a nice
collection of uh of males and females
and in those days we did not do uh the
feminized breathing that didn't exist
yet so so it was not so very difficult
the breeding that we did
so we we sometimes did a little bit in
breathing and but not too much it was
more we we basically did funeral hunting
and the the best ones we liked we
crossed with each other
and
um yeah and everybody was happy with the
seeds because
for a lot of people our customers was
it's either nothing
or or something from Amsterdam that
really gave you nice flowers nice nice
bits and then the people that sent this
photo to them sent us letters and they
were really uh
they were really nice photos and uh
everybody was happy
it was really nice
so how many how many people were
involved in your in your company yeah we
were two people through the and like
four or five people helping us
like a little Collective yeah
at the biggest part of it how many
houses did you have or how many how many
different places were you grown like
five six different places
we did not do that because in those days
there were also people
who really uh after five years or so a
lot of people that came into the they
rented big warehouses and put 200 lamps
in it but we uh you know we we did the
damage on a smaller scale because we've
all been we were not growing that much
weeds people more more Growing Seeds in
those days you know
I mean there's a there's a lot of you
know you could call them American seed
companies these days
um that exist just like that
it's some basement it's a few bedroom
house
yeah of course I see a lot of people
they they have some clones and they make
roses and uh and and then you'll see
companies born yeah your skunk Haze yes
really old
yeah
how long does it flower for
12 weeks and then they better do the one
week of 13 weeks 13 is better yeah and
um
how did it I mean 35 years old I'm
always fascinated by how things survive
because
for us in America it seems like every
five or ten years uh the weed the the
seed game reinvents itself and you can't
get what you used to be able to get so
um
did it did was it just so such a nice
Cut and there's such a nice plant that
various people saved it and passed it
around is it something that has been
always in like two or three places and I
like to use that it was more like a
group of people we even work with
and
um yeah it's still around and and then
we let them uh we have our mother
planned when it's like uh three or four
months old we take a new cut we throw
away the old plant and we start from
with a little clone again and a few
friends of me of my they have it and
then yeah because you can you can
imagine in 35 years there are lots of
things happening awesome really
we are proud We are proud of it to still
have it and we are now working on on
trying to
um
to uh to breed and say yeah
we are working with a few American
varieties because we like the from those
days we like the big firm but with a lot
of resin
but sometimes it lacks a little bit of
flavor a little bit of taste and smell
and now we are trying to put the smell
of the old school Haze and the eye
preferable as well and the taste into a
new and and to the American rice
and that takes a while but um
it's really interesting to see a plant
that grows like a cookie or something
American style and then with the old
school taste and smelling that's that's
the thing that we are working on and
maybe people
some people knock down yeah why do you
do this you try to keep it like it is
but I want to because at the end of the
day a lot of people from commercial
these days and it's nice to have a big
yield of course
but also a fluffy bird is nowadays
considered like big quality a lot of
people don't understand that at the end
of the day your birth you put it in a
paper and you smoke it so it doesn't it
doesn't really a big deal how the bird
looks I agree the big deal
and how it works but
you agree and I agree but
a lot of people the eye also wants you
know yeah I mean and the way that that
social media works now a lot of times
the only things that people see of
different buds are pictures yeah and
might look very ugly even though it
might work wonderfully and make you very
happy and it might take great you can't
tell that through the picture yeah
because nowadays if you have five like
five different varieties and four of
them are American things and one of them
is uh sativa thing
and everybody says we don't we want to
we don't want to have it because it
looks strange for us it's French and
especially yeah because I'm 63 or years
old already so
and normally it's I think it's normal
that the younger people like other
things but we also want to show things
from the past
I mean it's uh I mean for instance you
know it's really interesting because for
us skunk one you know to bring it back
again is very very very different from
what you experienced I don't think I've
experienced skunk one like you remember
it no time that we got a hold of it what
you remember was gone yeah and that
happened a lot where if you don't have
old things or people aren't saving old
cuttings or you can't get old seeds to
sprout then the way people remember
something it's just gone yeah
how long ago you get excited again about
maybe you could restart super sativa
seed Club in a new form yeah yeah we
already started it but we we don't sell
anymore
because those were the wild days
nowadays it's uh it's not a good idea to
sell something in the US for a moment no
not yet it could change we're slowly
moving in that direction but I mean I
don't know have you ever heard of ditch
passion yes yeah because we were
together with this person they did a
friend of us and they they are this is
really a very successful seed company
but they don't sell one seat in the US
and if you know that the half of the
visitors of the website comes from the
US
today
it you know it uh hopefully that will
change in the next or so years yeah it
looks like America we're not complicated
in the US man with those federal laws
and uh it's really not a good idea and
uh
you know but maybe one day things change
and then we can because because it's of
course crazy that half of the visitors
of a website
it comes from the US it comes from the
US yeah they want to watch this but we
don't do it oh yeah I understand
um when uh so is is uh so basically you
you're making stuff for the Holland
market now
um European market for European market
you were talking in the in the previous
interview you did with Matt you were
talking about how you sort of like
recollected some other hazes besides
yeah because now I'm in a good position
of course to
I know a lot of people and I know all
the hats
from Europe you know no I mean you're
certainly of of that generation that uh
you know probably known these people for
decades yes yes and then and and then we
are happy that a lot that the haste
people always are the people who really
understand uh how important it is to to
save things
and then there is still a lot of stuff
around you know because we have
yeah like five five different loans
still and then other people are there we
have the old school age we have the nl5
timeshace
and they have the AC and the h
a and it's not the boy as everybody
thinks but because we have the girls
and we have the Outback H that's the
last thing Neville uh
the famous boy
yeah no no the thing is that there is a
lot of confusion going on always about
the Jesus boys and girls but what we
have is the A and the AC and it's both
wheels and it's really yeah yeah and
then
of course you have the A5 and C5
I personally don't have it but my
friends have it and it's really but when
we want to use it to make a cross or
something we can add it but
it's a group of people and everybody
knows each other
it's from the south
but when you when you're talking about
the girls that are A and C you're not
talking about A5 or C5 you're talking
about different that's different plans
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah and it's really
the um especially the ace
um
the the one I like best is the
outbreakers
the Outback here yeah because the
Outback Haze is really the the incense
smell and it has the instant smell
and it's uh it makes you a high totally
high it's really when you smoke it then
then you think Hmm
I understood it all
and then half an hour later where was I
I didn't try anything but
that's a female you got from friends or
is that a female
because we got to
um yeah yeah I don't think you know them
she's called Mishka
Mishka is a famous activist here in New
York she's from France it's a it's a
it's an it's an older lady and she's
really an activist and she was the best
friend of Neville and Neville gave this
to her
and since it passed away and she also
Neville passed away
yes he gave [ __ ] to us also because
these older this is quite old already
and then see it's like what Sam did you
gave it to somebody who know who who can
handle it you know who know who knows
how to to save it are you planning on
doing some breeding with somebody doing
breathing the because we are now doing a
breathing but that's a feminized
breathing because when you have two
girls there's no man there's no male so
you know do you need to do feminized
breathing and we have now we have two
and still yeah
I think it's going to be a successful
project because maybe I mean when you're
breathing you have to establish a few
girls girls already not too much but our
goals are always the high the smell and
the taste those are my top three yeah
it's nice when there's a world of resume
to be seen but we don't go for flowering
time or something I don't know because
now we also can do some breeding and
legal situations so then we don't have
to worry about flowering time
right yeah because a lot of people there
DNA genetics you know them of course yes
maybe they are also friends of us in
this day said yeah it's nice what you're
doing but it's going to be um
a problem to sell those seeds because in
those nowadays people don't want to
spend 12 or 12 weeks 30 weeks waiting
for their office anymore it's changing I
think I hope so because when you're
growing legal like you guys can do this
there why why should you bother about
the flowering time yes no it's checking
for a long time they were right people
didn't want things that went longer than
eight to ten weeks yeah because you have
to run a little bit of pollution put the
police on their heels and to make sure
that it comes in fast but there's a lot
of people now that are willing to do 12
13 Even 14 week strains if they're nice
enough people are getting excited about
it and also regarding weight
the extra three weeks will give you 40
extra weight right the best the best
yielding varieties are the sativa
varieties and we are they all laugh a
little bit about
something making a little bit thrown
about in your American strains you like
that
but they don't yield
no no there's a lot of them that don't
yield that's very true
um of course yeah so they don't
um you know they uh so your your skunk
Haze the haze in it is from one of the
ten seeds that Neville's that stands
there is nothing closer to the real
haste than the screencase that I have
because most people it seems like most
people in Holland ended up using a lot
of Neville's hybrids of haze and those
could be a lot of the one the cuts that
got saved yes but as a result of that
that means that most Haze is only from
one or two plants
yes so you third you have you have Hayes
that's not even his which is pretty
exciting yeah because the the difference
between uh our Haze and Nepal stations
never never did all the his crosses with
the Northern Lights
and we did it at screen number one and
foreign
like A5 and C5 and all those it's all
um Haze with Northern Light in it and
Northern Light is not really a plant
with a nice taste it's like a metallic
a metallic taste and it's really not uh
there are not the terms in the in the in
the crosses that never made are not so
nice then the Terps in the and the
screen case because the screen was a
really dirty
so we were already that our line our
line is it's currently number one and
Neville's lines are a bit with the
northern northern lights and Northern
Lights came from the U.S
are there are there coffee shops and
stuff like that where where people can
still get your skunk Haze on any kind of
basis yes yes yes yes
it's still available like if people were
to go to you could find it
only a few people grow it because it's
complicated to grow right we really need
to uh to have your climate under control
and in an illegal situation it's not so
very easy because then you need to work
with Airco
units you know because the the screen
case when the temperature
rises above 28 Celsius then they start
to run the boots and that means then it
gets very fluffy and sometimes you get
like 10 branches and then you start
again and when this happens after eight
weeks of flowering again the 12 weeks of
flowering starts and then it then we're
talking about 20 weeks and that's too
much
if you really know how it's really a
very difficult plant to grow
if you have too much nutrients they
start to stretch and they start to do
crazy things
do it the right way it takes 12 or 13
weeks yeah and then the right way is not
one hour above 28 degrees Celsius
when you have one day when your Airco
breaks down or something
it's gone so you you uh what what
excites you about
your new uh your new Venture with super
sativa seed Club are you working are you
working with your son are you working
with us
yeah yeah
and then and also um we are
um we are very close to get the permit
to grow in Holland uh legal
yeah yeah because now the the Dutch
government issued 10 permits to grow
legal for the coffee shops around and we
were lucky enough to to win the lottery
because it was a lottery 100 150 people
applied for the for the license and only
40 went through the first round because
you you need to be able to grow a lot of
weed you need to have money you need to
have the skills to do it you need to
have the conference in the coffee shop
and we all have this and uh then
basically there were 40 people left and
then they they made a lottery and we
were lucky enough to win one of the 10
pyramids so when you win it does that
mean that at some point in the future
like Matt and I could fly to Holland and
we could buy Super sativa seed Club weed
at Coffee yes and it would be branded
and we know it was from you and you grew
an illegal facility and then you'd sell
it to like damn or somebody like that
that's the idea yes that's the idea
that's very exciting yeah yeah that's
the idea yeah yeah yeah yeah
it will take because now it's a
government business so it takes a little
bit longer you know as you can imagine
we are waiting waiting waiting waiting
there's that one one in a few weeks or
months we will get the pyramid and then
it's very important
in a peaceful way
because that's that's a it's a lifetime
of waiting for that huh yeah because
that for me especially it's uh very nice
because then the circle is around you
know
yeah
uh California is the same way it's just
become legal but a lot of money a lot of
rules a lot of regulations a lot of
government involved a lot of permits
yeah uh lucky enough to uh to have the
example of Canada and the US to tell our
government
if you want to make this a success don't
make the same mistakes as they did in
Canada
so because in Canada people from the
black market
can't be involved in this but here in
Holland we taught the government without
people from the black market this is not
going to be successful no the people
from the black market they know how to
do it and basically where does the
government
it can get information from the account
you can't read the information about
these kind of things in the paper so you
need to talk with people from the black
market
we basically helped the government to to
make this happen
you did you worked with them government
is wise enough
to understand that they don't can do
this without the black market
so then when if they make it legal will
you mostly be going in greenhouses like
traditional we will do a combination of
greenhouse and indoor growing and indoor
growing organic maybe it'll be worth 100
organic huh yeah you call it bio over
there no that's bio here yeah it's
calling by yeah
yeah
so yeah and then the circle is around
and yeah
so I mean if if you want to wrap it up
here that that that's wonderful
um I thank you so much for your time it
was wonderful to hear these stories yeah
let's keep in touch and you're an
amazing interview man you you know your
[ __ ] I love it
[Music]
all right that can
say it's part of the interview
um so right now we're gonna go over some
of the highlights of the interview
things that we we picked out and thought
were very very unique and uh
otherwise important to highlight
so let's talk about some things
uh well probably in no particular order
but one of the really interesting parts
for me was hearing him talk about the
imported weed from South America from
South Africa and Durban and that you
know you and I have talked a bunch in
the past about how we thought most of
the Durbin in Amsterdam came from what
Mel Frank gave to Sam Skunk Man sure we
thought that's what proliferated most of
what was being used back then right and
so while certainly that that was
proliferated over there and plenty of
people sold it and bred with it sure now
we find out that there was literally a
Durban Poison coffee shop yeah Corel and
others were getting bag seeds from
seeded cannabis from Durban uh and using
in their own work so significantly
widens the gene pool of what we thought
and it also could lead to uh where you
know Mel talked extensively about how
his uh Durbin was much more anus much
more licorice in flavor and he's not
sure why the Dutch bred it in the way
that they did yeah but with that tidbit
of information it's possible that his
was anise and so there's an anocyte to
Durbin but then there's also a more
terpenoline leaning uh Durban that came
from South Africa and was found in
seeded wheat yeah and that could account
for the vast differences between those
two Durban families uh yeah because it's
all kind of gotten the same
classification but as we know just
because it's from the same region
doesn't mean it's it's remotely the same
no not whatsoever so that was that was
pretty amazing information because we've
us and others have assumed for a long
time yeah that most people were selling
the same Durban Poison yeah that was
fascinating uh what are the one of the
points that I thought was really
interesting and
it's something that's been kind of uh
mythical ever since sssc kind of you
know moved away from the scene in that
you know there was a lot of rumors
building up about why that happened
um there were people coming out and
saying I worked for sssc and I was sssc
America or my uncle you know or my
uncles bread
certain lines for sssc in Virginia or
somewhere in America I thought that was
fascinating to hear that there were no
Americans involved in sssc because
that's been a rumor that's built up in
many a few at least companies have been
started off that yeah I mean certainly
there's uh more than more than one
person has had claims of that level so
it was interesting to hear that while
they did Source uh uh stuff from America
like apparently as we heard uh Williams
Wonder uh yeah from New York which is
pretty cool I've never heard that part
before yeah I hadn't either and
obviously he talked about all skunk
coming from California and the Sam Rob
group you know to them
um but it does seem a little bit like
Neville they collected they collected
some things and he he talked it was
pretty cool how he talked about people
with straight write him letters yeah
that's how he met made most of his
American Connections was people like Ed
or whoever writing them letters and
wanted to come see them can you imagine
just being able to write in a letter
being like hey I'd love to come visit
and all of a sudden bam you're there
you're at the camera people are standing
in seeds or buds yeah America's
certainly contributed to what they had
to offer uh but apparently I mean he
said you know all their breeding was
done and five or six homes basically uh
you know that type of thing the other
little tidbit that's not really like
seed specific but makes a lot of sense
was uh you know when he talked about how
easy uh it was to get busted in
greenhouses because all of Holland is
highly developed and so a greenhouse is
in a neighborhood yeah
living in Mendocino County and anybody
that lives in the western part of
America we're pretty spread out yeah
there's lots of remote rural areas
there's lots of places you can do things
you can buy property where you can get
away with it yeah um and it was pretty
it was interesting when you think of a
society that's so much older than ours
and they've just populated every good
part of the land yeah and so there's
really nowhere to hide so for them in
order to not get busted
um it was I mean he basically said it
was like you were one and done at most
of those places
one of my favorite Parts was when you
were interviewing him and he was talking
about maybe you can uh go over it a
little bit more because you were doing
the interview but when he was talking
about the green bud and and not being
able to sell green Bud because it wasn't
what they were used to oh yeah if you
see my face on the video I think my eyes
are probably as big as saucers because
one of the things that's interesting in
talking to like the you know what we've
talked about is like the Pioneer
generation yeah you know uh is you know
like Rob Clark and some of these guys
that were writing the Bible for breeding
is just how new it all was yeah and so
to think that in the mid 80s as they
first grew weed for themselves that was
the first time any of them had seen
green Bud yeah because brown and gold or
red or various kinds of cure or whatever
that was the standard there was no other
kind just awesome
that it looked that way when it was
fresh yeah
they grow homegrown and it comes out the
way homegrown does and they're not even
sure they're going to be able to sell it
because no one's ever seen it I'm sure
they didn't even know if it would get
them High when they first looked at it
if it was so different you know I mean
so that just goes to speak to the level
of pioneering that they were trying to
have to figure all this stuff out the
other part that's just a little tidbit
but I found like endlessly amusing
honestly is that obviously in a an
American weed culture we can kind of
trace a lot of strains
um back but then there's like a nickname
you know where nl5 skunk one doesn't
stay that way it gets nicknamed
something else sure something maybe this
nl5 Haze gets nicknamed dog [ __ ] or
Electric Boogaloo or whatever yeah and
so you know we have this whole counter
cultural thing in America of relating
our strains to various pop culture stuff
that's current for us right yeah and so
to hear that whole story about Victor
Barn oh yeah that was cool and the way
that and the way that they that who
whose name it was and this hustle and
how they had to have a name to deposit
all these millions
um obviously not knowing Holland you
know culture like that yeah I never had
any idea that that was related to
anything like that but it does tie into
the fact that weed people have always
had kind of a knack to pick funny
tongue-in-cheek kind of names for wheat
yeah like an electric Choice he said
that was kind of like a [ __ ] you to the
queen of Holland that's yeah exactly so
punk rock is that you know so yeah I
mean so both those things both those
names
um that Traditions has continued
throughout the decades people are always
coming up with clever plays on the
culture that they're in yeah and so
while you know Holland weed culture and
American wheat culture is obviously
quite different it was pretty neat to
hear that they should we share that sort
of you know and on top of that too I'll
just say as a general sense uh
everything he said about his attitude
towards weed and their approach towards
things and all that like I pretty much
agree with I mean it was obvious talking
to him his heart was in the right place
they were pretty counter-cultural people
they were trying to get away with it
they were trying to overgrow or change
things yeah
um and that was my my favorite part that
endeared me to him was his yeah
nature you know even even for I mean
obviously there was a financial
component for him him and people doing
what they were doing but in a way it
started to counter cultural revolution
uh the reason why people are so
interested in super sativa seed Club is
because so many legends exist of weed
grown in Canada and America of those
strains by people yeah absolutely from
them so they played a pretty big role
hit them and Neville are really the two
groups that started spreading all this
seed everywhere yeah
um and that that's pretty important
because they laid the foundation for
what came after I mean it's all it was
also interesting because we've already
you know we we always wondered but
hearing how when they saw what happened
in Neville and they saw green Merchant
and they saw the international police
pressure that that's what made them
decide to disband for a long time yeah
and not continue because they saw you
know the price that a lot of these
pioneer years paid had to do this kind
of stuff
um you know was uh was pretty intense
yeah uh another thing I want to mention
just before I forget
um and that this might be really
pertinent because it's kind of a
experiencing a Resurgence but
um you know when he was talking about
his skunk Haze oh yeah yeah
um so first of all that's another piece
of of evidence that you know there was
at least three people that seemed to get
haze from Sam Skunk Man when he came
over to Holland the first time yeah
Neville yes and Corel correct and and
you know they all you know their stories
all are all similar it was interesting
to hear that um that maybe there wasn't
even that many Haze seeds given out
yeah you know uh maybe that leads to the
fact that he didn't bring over that that
many yeah and was kind of hesitant you
know and only wanted to give out so many
before he could make his own breeding
and increase it again
um but if we were able to talk to him
about it it would it would actually
answer a lot of questions so hopefully
in the future he'd be into it yeah and
one thing that I think for all the
modern Haze freaks out there because
with the A5 and C5 sneaking out and a
lot of people breeding Cuban black Haze
and nl5 Haze I think is having a quite a
bit of a Resurgence as piff or church or
different things like that is how he
talked about how this skunk cage that
they've had for 35 years if you grew it
uh under you know in America in American
American terms 82 degrees Yeah uh you
know if you grew a cold it only took
about 12 12 and a half weeks to finish
and it Formed nice buds yeah but let it
creep above 82 for even an hour or two
and you've got a running long sativa 20
plus week they would add another eight
weeks a couple months so wild man and so
they you know it was really interesting
to hear that because there's a lot of
people playing with hazes right now sure
and if that holds true uh I wonder if
people ran rooms in the low to mid 70s
and were militant about keeping it that
low yeah there's a lot of people that
run CO2 in their rooms there's a lot of
data out there where you might run your
room in the low to mid 80s to get VPD
yeah you know or to to get more use out
of your CO2 and try to Rapid Fire yeah
and that might be the exact bad approach
for running some of these old hazes yeah
so maybe if you know people are
listening and interested and you have
hazes uh try running them in the low to
mid 70s yeah and see if they form a
little different and see if they finish
faster because the difference between 12
and 20 weeks is a lot yeah yeah that's
tremendous that is tremendous
you know so it's it's also interesting
in that you know maybe we can eventually
get to work on some of his stuff over
here but most people's Haze stuff comes
from the plants that Neville found yeah
and so it was crazy to hear that the
skunk Haze that he has is a Survivor
from
uh Haze seed that he found yeah so it's
not Haze or hey C
it's
another Haze that is now trapped in
genetics that maybe could be used and a
lot of the issues with Haze or
inbreeding because there's only a parent
or two yeah so when you only have a
couple parents being used and mostly C A
is still way more rare to even use
um third parent
adds a lot more genetics yeah it sure
does
that's a good direction and potential so
it's pretty interesting maybe you know
he's been talking about during that
interview they're starting up the the
company again and they've got some
initial work coming out so uh that that
made me quite a bit more excited yeah me
too about anything that uses that plant
because the other thing too relative to
that plant is I I thought his in his
talk about how different skunk one was
in the mid 80s when it first arrived
then what it became later on yeah a lot
of people have considered that skunk one
has been this consistent thing and we're
used to Citrus or grapes or uh you know
maybe some cheese or Funk yeah uh but he
said it was kind of rank when it came
over so that that does I wonder if that
holds true to to stuff that Sam Dave had
uh said about breeding out skunk
bringing out the actual skunk skunky
smells I should say I mean there's not
that many people we should talk to that
we're growing skunk in 1985 but yeah the
other interesting part about that is
that obviously that skunk Haze that he
talked about contains that raw more raw
skunk one yeah that's in addition to a
double and another Haze the other side
of it is this you know
um maybe before it was hard selected in
that direction that we're all so
familiar with yeah it could be like
closer to something like an Afghan Haze
that could be really ranked yeah yeah I
mean it was it was interesting tidbit
because you have so few people you can
talk to about what was mid 80s skunk one
like yeah yeah it's true it's true he
obviously bought it and bred it and sold
it and it was a big part of his catalog
and the years they were in operation so
uh hearing his opinion about how mid and
late 80s skunk was vastly different than
what came later was to me at least
confirmation
you know that uh that you know the state
that things were in
I thought it was it was pretty cool when
um I think we were talking about
Friesland Friesland Indica where he was
very honest and said he wasn't really
stoked with where he's seen freeze land
been taken now as as it's been grown and
bred and fginned like he wasn't really
stoked with the current offering of
freezeland out there
I mean you know I I understand from his
perspective like absolutely one thing
that's certainly true is with Instagram
and other forms going on these days is
that that's the way that a lot of people
interact with a lot of cannabis they
never get to try yeah so looks have
become incredibly important yeah you
know uh and you know so you you go to
the looks of some of those 80s and 90s
strains
they're pretty rough yeah there's
something a little rough you know
there's pretty pretty rough they might
not be the most resonance they might be
kind of leafy they might look kind of
fugly yeah put that next to like you
know
um some kind of very modern very
gorgeous looking plant yeah and by looks
alone it kind of looks like you're you
know you're drawn in squiggles or
something you know it's like sure for
sure fingers you know but but it also
reiterates that like you can't you can't
just look at effect with your eyes
exactly so it could be a super there's a
lot of haze out there that's kind of
ugly but it works really good I mean
there's a there's there's famous Haze in
New York that gets sold Brown yeah and
in modern times it's not very easy to
sell Brown wheat no but that name sells
it that name it also it tastes great and
it works that's true yeah so the smoke
is great you know the fact that it I
mean even so you know uh you know we had
this we had this cut that you know uh my
friend helped make the the chocolate
diesel right yeah and it and it was a
combination of chocolate Thai across to
the 91 and then cross the Sardis oh yeah
yeah it was crazy too like he it was
legitimate old like
80s chocolate Thai smaller than type
stuff right and eventually it got lost
because it was super potent it was like
top Super Thai super chem it knocked you
on your ass but it cured Brown yeah and
people hated it yeah for that look that
look uh even chem four
um chem 4 can sometimes cure to like a
very light brownish it still looks the
resin and all that and the butt itself
looks amazing
um but people don't like brown the old
Clockwork Orange mom was the same we
called it orange not because of the
flavor but it was more because of the
actual color of the plant when it was
done you know it was more of a golden
orange brown look to it it was unique in
that sense
but really I mean you know you you
talked his interview is not that much
different than what a lot of us have who
have bred in various houses in various
ways and tried to get away with it here
and there
um you know and they were just grabbing
the best stuff they could at the time
some of them were straight strained some
of them were bag seeds that they found
out of good weed and coffee shops yeah
which is how a lot of breeding in
America happen too later on as well a
bag seed uh has ruled the game for you
know and uh and so it's cool that things
are opening up uh and we can talk to
people like that who have such a vastly
different experience of starting them uh
yeah you know maybe we can get some more
you know things open up a little bit
more in America and over there there
could be some actual like more closer
collaborations yeah because obviously
there's been a lot of illicit flow back
and forth between the Dutch and America
and Canada
yeah but it would be neat to be able to
one day to actually do it yeah because
we each have some pretty amazing things
and we have some different lines and we
have some things that's segregated from
each other over time uh you know you
talk about him being able to go to
Canada and there's there's some super
sativa seed club stuff that still exists
sure uh and they might be able to get it
back and then you know that brings me to
another part though was when I was
talking to him and this might have been
um actually a private conversation but
it was it was talking to him about the
people that have made whole companies
off of selling
um elicit not not elicit but like unreal
reproductions of super sativa C Club
just to mark it on the name and move
seats fast and when he was talking about
resourcing genetics that's going to be a
problem that is an actual issue now that
so many people have made different super
sativa seed Club Repros and it's going
to make sourcing a little harder for
some of it well we we've talked about
this on previous podcasts in the sense
that uh it's really only in the last
maybe five or six years that there's
been a massive Resurgence in trying to
find ancient and original beings yeah
there was a big era where everybody
wanted new new yes uh and the old stuff
was most of the stories were pretty
honest because nobody cared yeah exactly
how now that things have legalized and
things have opened up and lots of people
have kind of the same things uh there's
been this massive explosion of I found
these seeds and my old connections
dresser like Grandma's freezer my this
my that these have been Faithfully
reproduced and not just sssc but every
old legendary line you can think of
there's dates associated with them some
of them are super early too early yeah
it makes it really hard to sift through
yeah um and find the real
um because there's there as people get
more excited about weed and people get
more excited about the history and stuff
they're gonna just they're gonna want
just like we do they're going to want to
try some old pure lines yeah I would
love to dig through everything from the
seed bank and sssc uh now being my age
and knowing what I know now it would be
amazing to dig through all that uh and
so and so people pray it's you know it's
kind of like the roadkill skunk thing
where uh there's a there's a market
demand for certain things now and so
there's a market demand for old yeah so
hopefully some of his old stuff
legitimately did exist
yeah um but I know I know a few
reproductions are out there that that
are legitimate for some of them but it
just goes to to say that it's cool that
that people are getting so into
researching cannabis to the point of
really getting into provenance and stuff
like that so it combats that because if
stuff like that doesn't sell if these if
these guys who are doing these
reproductions that you're it's pretty
obvious usually when these guys are
working their games
it might be obvious to us it might be
less obvious to others depending on you
know uh how how in tune your scam Dar is
or whatever but that's true I do think
that for most people you know there's a
lot of strains I'll be frank like I went
to a lot of Amsterdam trips I bought a
lot of seed uh most of it was not
Keepers yeah I did find some cool stuff
certainly others found some Elites that
have survived to this day off the same
lines that I bought yeah back then it
was a total crap shoot and there was
there was a lot to not be impressed by
so uh you know him looking and being
honest and being like Oh the free Sunday
wasn't it's not so nice yeah
um but still if it is real the cool part
about it is is that opening up the gene
pool and adding genes that have been
lost over time and aren't being used we
have too much overuse yeah of too few
lines in cannabis right now so a lot of
80s and old things by themselves might
not be all that great but they could
widen the gene pool and you never know
what they might pop in out crosses
absolutely uh you know for we you know
we just uh you know CSI who knows where
the ABC work will go yeah uh that's
still in its infancy as you start
hybridizing it with things and adding
those genes in and making poly hybrids
with it so to me some of the most value
if anything from the 80s or early 90s
survived even if by itself it's not that
great uh it might might have traits or
things that you add into something
really inbred yeah and you get something
surprising yeah you never know how
terpenes will modify other terpenes or
dialic Expressions you never know and
with new and novel expressions or maybe
they weren't new in novel in the 80s but
they're back to being new and novel now
and that we never know how that'll
change and modify snow and you know one
of the things about breeding is you tend
to get good results when you cross
things that that are very dissimilar to
each other yeah
um and so taking something that hasn't
been really worked with much since the
80s or early 90s and isn't in a lot of
this cush Skittles cookies whatever
blends of things it might pop some new
and cool things in that regard so
you know all in all uh I thought he was
a wealth of information absolutely super
engaging and pleasant he seemed like an
older version of us yeah you know he did
so that made it like really fun and
relaxing to chat with him about
everything sure um he seems willing to
maybe do some more and so there's I'm
sure there's a lot of history uh and
experiences that he's seen uh that's
right up our alley so you know no
promises but we'll see what comes of it
yeah uh and in closing yeah I think I
think we learned a lot I think there was
a lot of things that weren't very well
publicly known that he clarified and so
not only from a historical perspective
but for the current uh I think it was it
was really a it was really a good
interview
foreign
[Music]
yeah I was really really stoked to be
able to speak with him it was it was it
was one of those few times where it's
someone that you've always wanted to
interview and speak to and they weren't
a complete disappointment it was
absolutely an honor yeah it was great it
was great so I hope everybody enjoyed
listening to it
um you know it's a little bit strange
it's two-part uh and uh we'll see how
things go but we hope to be able to
bring you some more of some of the
Pioneers in cannabis and their view on
things and how we got to where we are
so you know thanks and peace everyone
thank you
[Music]