welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate hello everyone welcome to the
Breeders Syndicate I am your host
thousandfold sadly today we were meant
to have Matt but something came up last
minute for him so we will be running the
show without mat um as a I don't know as
an aside I I I Can Only Imagine that he
he's not too disappointed to miss
growing round taes he he's he's
expressed his indifference before um but
it's always fun to have him obviously so
it's sad that we don't get him tonight
but that is okay we hope he is doing
okay um today we welcome back scone
scarecrow and Kyle from the previous
Growers Round Table um but for the first
time we welcome
bumat so this show tonight is actually
going to be about organ oranic growing
and I wanted to State a qualifier here
which is that organic Growers maybe
somewhat ironically tend to be some of
the most tribal dogmatic scary people in
the
community we're not here to be you know
the people on this on this panel are not
here to be authorities they're just here
as Growers sharing their thoughts
sharing their experience so unclench
your fists put your knives away
take your hands off the keyboard and
just try to enjoy the show if your
opinions differ feel free to comment
later
on okay so maybe since bumat is new to
the show uh I want to invite him to
speak on a couple of things uh one thing
I'll get him to repeat because he told
us a bit about this before we hit record
is what his recent you know what his
current growing situation is like um and
secondarily uh why he wanted to do the
show in general um
bumat do you w to tell us about what
you've been growing you told us a bit
about your situation moving just before
tell us
again yeah so I um I just ended up
moving up to the Rockies around 9,000
feet but um the last two years I've been
growing in an apartment down in the
Denver area um I was growing in a
2x4 uh which a 300 watt light just
really small um really confined space to
uh do my stuff but um now I have a
little bit more space up here but I did
just Harvest last May a round of Trinity
Bubba Kush um from twg and I had a five
potential Keepers that moved onto the
second round one of them didn't end up
cloning so it's down to four now um that
they're going to get moved on to the
second round but yeah and then as for
the second part uh I want to do this
show mainly because I feel like
it's a because you've said um and many
others will point out that organic
Growers are really tribal and it's
really hard to find a good discussion in
my opinion where people can actually be
fair and not be overly biased to one
side so I kind of wanted to have this
conversation more just on a grounds of
being able to actually talk about these
ideas and share these ideas with others
because I feel like gr organically is
kind of Pitfall and there's a lot of
hard like ways to find information and I
feel like we between the three of us can
really guide some people and help um
provide some information and helpful
tips yeah absolutely and um thank you so
much as well for you know initiating all
of this I think you spoke to me about
this like a year ago yeah it took us a
little bit to get to this but um I think
once
we I think once we knew we could get
screw and Kyle as well I kind of forgot
um that we we had more people I know
that we have more organic grow was by
the way it just took me a little bit to
kind of like think of who who might fit
so yeah appreciate all of you being here
again uh maybe bumat last question for
you is how long have you been growing
and how long have you been growing
organically
for um so I have a little bit of a mixed
career uh I started in Organics and I've
grown everything at home has been
Organics but the last two years I've um
almost two years it'll be two in
September but I've worked for um an MSO
here in
Colorado I'll keep the company name uh
for later for you guys um but uh yeah
I've actually really enjoyed it and um I
kind of call it's weird I call it um a
mom and pop MSO because the owner is
like an old Forum head who ended up
getting some funding from some friends
and it would he's a really good guy and
really loves and like has a passion for
genetics so it's a lot it's a lot of fun
for me to be able to like bounce ideas
off him and he's been growing for 30
something years but I personally have
been growing since 2019
I don't really like to count that first
year because it was so so horrible we
can get to that one later um but uh
everything that I've done which first
two years were outdoor and then I bought
a tent and really [ __ ] that first
round up as well and then as well and
then I've just kind of slowly learned
everything I could from resources from
build a soil YouTube channel to Jeff
lenell's teaming with series and um all
sorts of other podcasts uh that I can go
on and on about it later uh but yeah
that's kind of where I've been
at awesome man thank you um Kyle and
scren U maybe start with Kyle obviously
you guys have been on the show before
but again just as an icebreaker warm up
maybe tell us again about uh what you've
been growing recently and your your
setup and style okay uh well thanks for
having me again um I do you know t uh
you know mostly it's the Rev uh
basically it's kind of all his stuff uh
it's you know TLO it's everybody thinks
it's like a kind of you know it's one
one thing but it's kind of there you can
do different kind kind of styles within
that so you know I just kind of do that
and I've kind of mix it around just
based on what's going on at the time um
since I'm going in the garage my uh
environment changes so I just kind of
I'm always kind of doing different stuff
uh right now I have uh see I got some
Santa Cruz wreck uh some blue dream s1's
um see what else do I have in there uh I
think that's oh I got some this is a
black poison from the Rev growing in
there and that's pretty much it I'm try
doing uh some reversal stuff um just
kind of playing around doing a whole
bunch of different things actually
so yeah very nice that's really it not
too much from the last episode really
I'm just same same old same old I just
keep it chugging along
one question I had for you was um how
much how much experience you have with
synthetics uh well I only know from
seeing other grows and that's mostly
from my family uh in meno and they did
uh a lot of Depp and outdoor so mostly
it was mostly a Sanic type of thing they
basically would pick up whatever was at
the grow shop because they've been doing
it so long you know was type of The Grow
shops would hey we have this we have
that and they would throw it out there
and so basically I know from that and
they always grown really good stuff but
obviously I found out later on you know
when you do that outside it doesn't
really
affect stuff because the decomposition
of so it doesn't really matter what you
put because the decomposition uh it just
kind of gets rid of anything that's bad
because it's outside so the microbes and
stuff are eating away and it so it
doesn't really matter what you put
outside type of thing so it's not really
Sanic uh if you I it's kind of hard to
explain I guess um but uh yeah that's
the only thing I don't I've never did
seanic anything so yeah no that's cool
and I'm sure we can get into some of the
details that are on um scen tell us a
bit about what you've been growing
recently and your experience with
Organic your setup kind of
thing uh yeah um so I just recently
harvested a Skyline from H&amp;L and I
harvested a pea Berry and a bubble
bberry V2 from
Matt
um and in my other flowering space I
have garbage cloud from uh from pack
going right
now um my setup is I mean it's pretty
simple I have one uh 4x4 for my veg and
in that I have uh one of those Chrome
racks um so I have like three layers to
be able to move plants through it um and
then I have two 2x4s for flowering and
one 3x3 for
drying simple small space uh but I'm
still able to go through quite a bit of
numbers
just um by keeping things like
small yeah yeah and in terms of like the
synthetic organic thing you know in your
experience how much have you how much
time have spent with either
approach
uh so I when I first started trying to
grow I was doing just like you know soil
that I was stealing from around town and
[ __ ] um but like I never harvested
anything or you know like other than
some wispy bracks and stuff um and then
when I started like actually you know
buckling down uh when I got back uh back
home in 2011
I went to hydro uh just
because you know I I got a Ed Rosenthal
book and was like [ __ ] it I want to try
flood tables I guess and that's when
like I actually started
cropping um I did that for
till
2015 early 2016 and I had to take a
little bit of a break um for a couple
years and when I came back I I wanted to
I wanted to try out organic so I've been
doing doing the whole like quote unquote
living soil stuff um for the past four
years
now and yeah I don't know I mean I grow
I I want to preface all of this whole
episode by like I don't think that
anyone style has Supremacy in terms of
like smoke and all of that um it's more
so however you grow best yeah and I am
not a good hydr grower but I am a good
organic grower that's the only reason I
do it it's not because of some weird
dogm or anything like that yeah yeah
yeah many of us I think just grow
relative to I don't know AR arbitrary
constraints in our lives right like the
the space that you have the the products
you have access to at the time like you
know there are lots of
like arbitrary reasons why we grow the
way we do um and I think like I was
saying to you guys before we started
recording I think really the value in
hearing from different people is is
hearing about the different conditions
that they grow under and why things may
or may not work under those conditions
uh rather than just trying to State like
you know silver bullets uh like oh yeah
this is just good like an abstraction of
anything that's never true right with
growing we know that so I think this is
just a broad invitation to to all three
of you to you know think about your
experience think about why things may or
may not have worked and for what reason
um and I think talking
about uh tech tech and strategy in that
way is uh a little bit more um generous
right because we're not just saying oh
we just we do this because it's good or
we do this because it's the best because
that that's never that's never really
true in isolation of you know everything
else um with that qualifier I might
bring it back to bumat um well one thing
I I guess now we we're kind of getting
into the the the actual meat of the
conversation and there's a point here
about you know how one might try to
Define organic growing and there's
another phrase that you use bumat that
was kind of intrigued by which is uh the
Great Compromise so maybe do you want to
kick us off with some of that like what
are your your thoughts around you know
what what is organic growing and why do
you think of it as a great
compromise all right that let's get into
the meat of it this is going to be fun
so um first I'm going to kind of Define
at least from everything that I've read
and my an adonal experience the kind of
key differences between salt and organic
just on a very simple level there's a
lot more depth that we can go into this
later or another time but um salt is
essentially the most basic form of
mineral that a plant can absorb if it's
held in the right U suspension for it
and Organics is creating and utilizing
like a relationship a symbiotic
relationship with um fungal networks and
microbial networks within your actual
media um to facilitate an exchange of
sugars from the root Zone in the plant
uh with those microbes it'll exchange
those nutrients um
the Great Compromise is a
very growing organically indoors is kind
of ironic in a lot of ways um it's an
artificial light source uh you're using
uh more often than not a potting soil
that's coming out of a bag that's being
mixed by somebody at a facility and not
using traditional amended Earth although
that is a possibility if you have the
space and are willing to commit to it um
but the Great Compromise really centers
around what indoor grower has or indoor
organic grower has to
do when they're growing because you are
never going to actually follow nature
100% when you're adding in artificial
things so in my instance I was growing
in an apartment in a 2x4 for the last
two years and I I wanted to run through
plants I wanted to see as many different
fenos as of many different plaques that
I could see so I spent the last two
years just really going at it and never
grew the same plant twice um it really
taught me a lot and it forced me into
growing smaller sized plants in that
space and using one gallon pots which
ironically goes against a lot of living
soil kind of principles and ideas with
the small pots um I know I'm going to
get attacked for that one it's not
living soil
but I made it work it's very much
possible um if you just really pack you
know what if you know what you're using
and you understand the system
fundamentally you can appropriately size
your plants prior to flow with the right
amount of veg time and you can make the
system work um you can use things like
enzymes you can use uh all sorts of
ferments uh different things like that
to that can Aid and catalyze different
processes within your media to really
get the full use out of it um
but I've tried growing in 20 gallon pots
in a 2x4 and you can only fit two of
them in there and it gets really crowded
really fast so I was forced into a much
smaller compromise with smaller one
gallon pots in my space but
largely the compromise is an individual
compromise for every indoor organic
grower who's trying to find or trying to
follow a general PR the general organic
system of growing
cannabis so uh bum I have a
question yeah what's up so what what are
you doing uh for nutrition are you using
like fish
hydrate um to to feed them or you just
top dressing a bunch what what do you
because one one gallon is small so how
do you uh compensate for
that uh yeah I was using a lot of things
like fish hydrate and
uh
oh happened again all
righty okay so yeah I was using a lot of
things like fish hydraul aate and top
dressing a lot um I was also using
things like uh build of soil's big six
micros um I'm going to name drop a
handful of companies I am by no way
sponsored in any shape uh this podcast
is not sponsored in any shape we don't
not get paid for this we would love a
check though so come on on let's get it
but um yeah I was using a lot of things
like that in top dressing uh I'm a big
fan of uh Clackamus cot actually um I've
a lot of the build of soil ideology
which is a lot of things that taught me
like kind of the fundamental living soil
system principles um are derived
directly from a lot of the things that
he was talking about on the forums back
in the day so uh he's really big on
things like vermac compost which are
just essentially worm castings um and
and other things like um sprouted seed
teas I don't really Brew teas just
because it was really difficult and they
absolutely stink in
apartments um and that's kind of really
inconvenient for when you're actually
growing in a confined space where you're
not allowed to do that um but more or
less I was the way I was growing I was
doing like a weekl long veg I would go
straight from clone into a one gallon
pot of build of soil soil just any
runof-the-mill um um and essentially
when I would mix the actual pot and when
I was transplanting I would add probably
about
onethird of it as worm castings and then
I'd take some lava rock which are just
essentially really porous and AD Iration
and add about a third of those in and
then I would just grab about two pinches
worth just I'm more of a kind of just
dump and you'll see kind of cook at the
end but uh I don't really use a lot of
measurements we we'll get into this
later when we talk about pH that's going
to be a fun one too but um yeah I was
taking things like Kashi blind which is
a fermented grain product that is really
rich in things like nitrogen and I was
using other things like that to kind of
catalyze my process and allow I'm I kind
of followed a really intense dryback
push for the first couple weeks of
flower and that would really allow my
roots to get established within that
media and between depending on what I
was growing in the length of flowering
time I would top dress sometime between
day 14 and 28 um if things are going
like 10 11 plus weeks I the longest
thing anything I've grown is 13 weeks um
I would do something like closer to 28
days if I'm doing something shorter like
a eight to nine weer I'm going to do
something more along the lines of day 14
because I don't want a large amount of
nitrogen going into the later flowering
period i' would rather have the plant
try to pull as much of it possible um in
the beginning so when it's actually
using that in the earlier stages of
flower rather than getting an over
nitrogen um fed plant at towards the end
of flow but uh yeah I would kind of also
I remember KT talking about pulse
feedings being a thing from TLO I have
anodal experience of that working really
really well for me I would do something
like on day
um yeah about day 21 I would do a really
in high dose of like I want to say it's
two teaspoons per per gallon of of fish
hydrate and like a a dose and a half of
what's recommended for the um
micronutrients from the big six and I
would just really hit them hard for that
day and then that can would usually last
me about two days so it would be like
day 21 22 would get a really intense
feeding and then I would literally just
be water only with a handful of like
really small added um additives like uh
kuaha extract um or like a Horticultural
coconut
oil
um or a freeze-dried aloe vera powder um
anything like that that's rich in sapon
ISS that will help aid with like minor
turpine production and stuff like that
although that's kind of based on Theory
I've seen antidotal evidence in my own
grows of it
helping H nice
um how you you also grow in relatively
small containers right are were you
saying um what are your comments on this
uh yes I will I right now I'm doing one
gallons and I started out in twos and
threes but uh I wanted to look through
more plants and I've slowly adapted to
where um I'm able to do one gallons with
the with the TLO uh since everything's
pretty it runs pretty hot in t uh I'm
able to do the one gallons because
there's enough food in there to where
I've only done water before you're not
going to get yield but that's not what
my uh importance is I don't care about
yield I care about just good smoke for
myself
um uh yeah I don't there's not really a
whole lot I do I've done all kinds of
different stuff because like I said
within TLO there's different stuff you
can do uh there's a microp pond uh
strategy you can use um which is like uh
after watering you can add uh stuff on
top say like alfalfa meal you can add
that up until about you know the about
halfway through so say about day 28 you
know you could stop something like that
uh it's kind of weird for people because
I know they think that will cause a lot
of harms I know that's a big thing with
the trantel I believe that's how you say
it I'm not exactly sure uh because I
always have to read I I never hear
people read uh uh say words I always
have to read them myself so I'm not sure
what that is but I know that's a big
thing with Al falam uh people think um
and there's just other stuff I've done
top dressings and all that uh spikes
there's all different kinds of stuff you
can do uh and I just kind of utilize
depending on what's going to happen in
the future depending so if right now I'm
running really really super hot so I
wanted to make sure I have a lot of food
so this time I did spikes and I'm doing
um uh the churn it's a little bit of
microp pond uh just doing different kind
of stuff because uh everything's just
everything's messed up right now so
because there nothing's nothing's uh
going right you know I'm all every day
switching so especially in the
California
heat yeah very nice thank you um bumat
did did you have any prompts for Kyle or
scrwen based on what you were saying any
questions for them in
turn um not off the top of my head I'll
let you know if I do
though uh what did you want to move on
to next all right I have a fun one uh
we're gonna go back to the first round
table of you spindle NN and local um
we're gonna touch on yeah we're gonna go
back uh we're gonna touch on the higher
floor and higher ceiling than salt um
topic I really yeah we're going back to
it I want to talk about this okay okay
do you want to St really clearly what
what was said uh what what was said in
the episode so the conversation that you
guys had really centered around the
concept of Organics in general having
essentially a higher ceiling and a
higher floor than salts um I really have
mixed feelings about that statement kind
of as a whole I feel it's a slight
misnomer um because I feel like the
level of Entry to find really good
knowledge can be quite difficult it for
a new person I would have sorry to
interrupt you but yeah I would have
thought it maybe higher ceiling lower
floor yeah I would risk that's
definitely what I would have said
because I've myself have grown some
absolutely horrendous
Organics um i' I've seen it myself like
I've been there so I I wanted to get
KT's and scr's opinion on this um but I
essentially for me I feel like once you
understand the basic concepts of like
how these systems work and how you're
kind of utilizing the general
relationships of microbes and and fungus
within that root system it's pretty easy
to manipulate but I feel like getting to
that point like takes a little bit of
more dedication and like actual time
like researching and understanding
general concepts within
Organics um but yeah I I wanted to get
the other two's opinion on that because
I feel personally
um a lot of organic Growers are so
tribal they will not they're not willing
to admit that you can grow bad weed
organically but I know from firsthand
experience it's very possible to
do okay yeah that that's a good one yeah
uh maybe you go back to scrwen uh before
Kyle and scren what's your experience in
terms of like the best and the worst you
know like uh how hard was it to get
going you know yeah uh so I definitely
agree with that you know you can grow
bad organic weed I promise you um it's
not very
hard
uh but the top end um that I'm a little
iffy on because I've had really really
good um like pure salt run
stuff um maybe like shelf life I I've
definitely noticed that
um like even I you know my friend group
down here uh some of them do grow both
ways and there seems to be a a
longevity
um like bonus on their on their organic
stuff it just the quality seems to stay
a little bit longer with it and I don't
I don't know why um I don't know if it's
because it's just more
well-rounded
like while growing or what
[Music]
um but yeah there's a lot of really bad
information about Organics um and I
don't
it's I don't know it's hard enough as
someone new coming in even when you get
you know good information it's hard
enough to start kind of actually
applying it correctly and
stuff
um but there's like there's a lot of
real you know you could always just go
off of the bottles hey I'm going to get
a and b and this dude told me to get you
know a cow mag supplement and just go by
the the rates that it says on the
bottles and you're probably going to do
pretty all right you
know I think that's a really good
observation though and I think bumat did
I mean all of you have alluded to this
in in some degree or to some degree the
notion
that the resources that you have access
to and the information itself is kind of
like a not a it's a
I was going to say it's a problem but
like you can talk about technique but
like yeah if you if you can't even get
reliable information then you're not you
know how do you even start properly
um Kyle what's your experience of the
floor quote unquote and ceiling of
organic
growing oh yeah well uh I only grow
really great stuff obviously no no no no
obviously i' gr I've obviously grown
some bad stuff obviously you can I mean
that that that's that's kind of silly um
uh everybody has bad grows I I don't
care who you are I've seen it every
everybody has bad grows if everybody who
doesn't is I think they're they'd be
lying to you got a pretty bad going
right now yeah yeah I mean hey it
happens I mean yeah I Ally I always have
problems it's always I'm always trying
to fix something it happens you know
open your tent up and it's like oh great
here what what what I got to fix today
I'm thinking oh great just water no it
ends up into you know 45 minutes of
something you know trying to fix
something or you know what happened um
trying to figure out well hey why why
that H you know why is this color on the
leafes now why what you know type of
thing
um yeah and as far as resources uh what
I found was best to uh great organic um
resources are older stuff like rodale's
rodale's organic composting rodale's
organic um gardening those are really
great books because they're older and
they don't have a lot of that corporate
growing type of stuff in um thrown in
there type of thing so I always found
the older stuff is always better to go
back on especially the books but
rodelles are always found are pretty
good too for especially for organic
stuff going back for um for starting out
because it gives you uh not just it's
not just cannabis it's growing organic
all in general which is great because it
gives you the whole spectrum of all
plants and I found that was that really
helped me out understand uh before I
even started growing uh I help me
understand the basics of what was going
on and then eventually once you get uh
you got to be consistent with it and
then once you get consistent with you
kind of just fall into your own method
and that's like me like some of the
stuff I do I just kind of don't even
have to measure type of thing I just
kind of know oh this is what's happening
and then I fix it and then you know you
just kind of get into your own method
and then you just kind of know what's
going on so
um I should have said this earlier uh
when I introduced this whole episode but
I'm not an organic grower uh so maybe
one thing I wanted to and it's probably
a bit of a tangent for now but uh one
thing I wanted to ask for any of you
really but maybe I can direct it bombcat
to begin with are you able to generalize
for me what the major differences
between the I guess m popular systems
are that you guys have have discussed
like you know you mentioned um what is
this like
T knf like living Soul like are there
you know are there broad distinctions
that you could draw that like might help
people understand what these different
approaches
are yeah so um these are all kind of
systems that have been founded by
different people in different areas for
different needs overall um living soil
no till there's a lot of academics that
are like very very highly educated on
soil science and soil biology and like
the makeup of soil and all of that and
they a lot of them are really pushing
the living soil noil type of systems for
larger scale a um like agriculture to
help preserve and feed more people
without essentially destroying the
environment through commercial
agriculture that's a whole argument in
of itself um T I am not the most
familiar with I'll probably definitely
defer to KT on that one but for knf and
jadam they are kind of offshoots of each
other I believe k&amp;f was the original
what k&amp;f stands for Korean natural
farming and it's largely centered around
being able to farm in a system that is
entirely closed Loops to anything
outside your local so you're not using
anything commercial whatsoever
everything that you're using is um
essentially fermented and then used
within dilution rates or varying
dilution rates for different things um
there's so many different types of
ferments that have offshoot out of that
um then there's jadam which I believe I
could be wrong on this one but I believe
jadam was written by the author of k&amp;f
son who um focused more on less a heavy
um
food within the ferments and more
focused on like microbial and bacterial
growth and uh using those fungal and
bacterial systems within your soil
um and then you have like smaller little
cannabis based offshoots from those
systems like I've heard people talk
about like Pacific Northwest Natural
farming um there's all sorts of
different kinds of thing but essentially
each one was founded by a different
group or
individual um that all kind of are
slightly off and different from each
other they're it's kind of like salt and
Organics Al like in the broader sense
like it's each system is a a little bit
more applicable and easier for certain
individuals like I have a couple buddies
who are absolutely phenomenal k&amp;f and
jadam Growers um everything they do is
focused around fermenting and harvesting
within their local using all sorts of
crazy stuff like horsetail nettle and
fermenting those in different types of
um sugar Solutions with water you can do
all sorts of different stuff like that
but they are all different systems
within the larger category of growing
organically with living soil kind of
being the most traditional amended Earth
style of organic
growing no thank you that you did really
well because like I I you know kind of
just fir it at you on the spot um thank
you very much for for that um we can you
know if we return to that like the floor
ceiling
conversation was there anything else you
wanted to add on that I saw that in the
outline you had an analogy skiing snowb
is that is that yours yeah that's me so
um at least I don't I can't speak for
everybody on this but for me I've done
the little bit of both and I picked up
snowboarding really really easily and I
had a really hard time picking up skiing
um but once I picked up skiing I found
it a lot easier to actually do like ski
and do that instead of snowboard and I
found it much more difficult to get
better at snowboarding than I did at
skiing so for me it's it's like a really
clear reference that it's like for some
people U growing within Organics is
definitely going to be the better way
it's some for some people it just fits
their individual system of how they
understand to grow plants um and some
people have a really hard time with
Organics and some people have a really
good time with Organics the same way
with salt uh I wanted to reiterate a
point I believe that both KT and
Christen made earlier that there is no
individual way to grow everything
universally better it really comes down
to the individual and their preferences
and their understanding of the systems
that they're using and the time spent to
actually understand what's going on and
how those processes
work well said um any comments or
questions from Kyle L Kristen at this
point no not that I can think of that's
pretty good
nope
um I don't know when you were talking
about this uh skiing snowboarding thing
it kind of brought to mind like do you
think an implication here is also that
if
you if you can understand organic
growing
um how I put it do you think it
necessitates having a finer
understanding of the plant and its needs
and the the the ecosystem and all that
seems like that's kind of what you're
saying
I think it
definitely yeah I want to say Yes um
it's hard to say that with absolute
confidence but for me personally at
least from my observations it feels that
like I'm at least in my friend group I'm
a little bit more in tune with having to
deal with like individuals on an
individual level and kind of Aid to them
so I feel that yeah it kind of forces a
like a more Keen Eye and like a little
bit more centered focus on like each
individual as opposed to kind of being
able to run a system where in salt you
could it's a universal recipe that you
slowly adjust over time for those
individuals once you've actually
understood them um it kind of goes back
to the idea of like Organics the plant
feeds individually within an organic
system as it pleases pulling what
nutrients it desires out of it
soil within that facilitation of
exchange of nutrients for sugars in the
root zone so in Organics it's indiv the
plant actually is doing all the work for
you in the root Zone all you need to do
is give it little things here or there
to do like to like essentially as
additives but that's that's at least my
perspective on
it I've heard this go Kyle you go oh I
was going to say well I think it's more
of like a I guess uh I don't know
without without being offensive it's
like a trust thing so I mean I mean
you're basically an Organics you're
you're you're letting it's a more of a
like Teo is like basically all natural
it's it's as close to mimicking Mother
Nature as possible uh so you're you're
trusting that the plant knows what it
what it what it knows to do for tens of
thousands of years compared to say Sy
synthetic you're you have to feed it
every single day day uh and to me that
like you're not having trust in what the
plant does type of thing like you you
want to have control over everything
that you're feeding it and compared to
Organics you're just having trust that
what you put in there the plant's going
to know what it what it does type of
thing very well
said we talked about I don't know bumat
did you want to get into like you kind
of went towards mechanisms like uh
uptake and in the outline you have a
point that's like comparing nutrient
uptake between organic and salt I mean
is that what you you just highlighted
essentially yeah more or less um I can
kind of go I can refer back to my
outline real quick um but
essentially all right I want to phrase
this correctly um Organics is creating
and utilizing the relationship uh
symbiotic relationship with various
fungal and bacterial systems in your
media that facilitate that exchange of
sugars and um that's actually called the
ryop fagus it's a relatively newer
scientific discovery I want to say it
was first written about about 20 years
ago um uh you can look more into it but
that essentially is the
actual exchange where the actual
exchange happens with the
bacteria in when you're feeding chelated
nutrients to a plant the
actual I wna sorry I want to phrase this
correctly but the
actual um bacteria that are creating
that Exchange in the root Zone start to
die off similar to how muscles work this
is the uh the best way I've understood
it um when you don't use a muscle over
time it dies off and it atrophies that's
essentially what happens when you're
feeding chelated nutrients to a plant's
root Zone um when you're using an
organic system what's going on is
through that Riso fungus the plant is
forced to exchange sugars for that
nutrition otherwise the plant doesn't
have the ability to actually uptake the
nutrition it's within that actual
symbiotic relationship which is where
the exchange of nutrients occurs for the
plant to actually feed
itself so um yeah I believe that really
highlights the main one um second big
difference I've read and seen um is that
through these relationships with uh
fungi and
bacteria you can more easily access
second like secondary metabolites which
can Aid in producing a higher quality
product that is no guarantee that is
what's happening that is my
understanding from my reading that I've
done on this subject um it's a very
nuanced and very complex subject with a
lot of arguments and a lot of different
perspectives on this side um but from
everything that I've read and gathered
this is essentially what's happening in
your root system I and I'm not saying
that grow if you're growing in an
organic system and you're applying that
trust of the plant to act like do
everything that it
needs you
are it's not there is I'm not saying
Organics is better overall because of
that exchange you can still grow
absolutely phenomenal product just like
scrwen said um with salt nutrition I do
it at work pretty like every day it we
grow great product it's easy to do um I
believe that this is where the echelon
of like the high the highest Echelon of
highest quality cannabis can come from
but it's not a guarantee in any fa like
any way um it still requires all the
effort and the individual attention of
the grower to actually get that done
within that system I just believe the
system can help you more easily access
it once you have a better understanding
of it as a
whole very nice yeah I'm I'm very
impressed that you
can I'm I'm trying I'm walking a fine
line I know I'm gonna get some DMS about
this but it's I'm everything I'm reading
I'm going off of it is stuff that I've
read online more often than not coming
from academic sources um I majored in
English in college so I have no issue
reading I will dive head first yeah I
dive head first right into a 60-page
paper if I need to understand something
just so I can make my life a little bit
easier in that actual understanding of
the process totally and and I will say
this as well kind of going back to my
earlier qualifier like we're not here to
um distribute Theory perfectly that's
not really the point yeah we're here to
to kind of talk about experience and and
opinions on on these things so yeah we
we may not get it perfect but I think
people are going to get the idea at
least
um
okay uh anything else on on this on the
me on mechanisms uh bumat otherwise what
would you like to talk about next um we
can touch on like cat on Exchange if you
want to get into that like with cocoa
versus like a a traditional potting soil
type of thing I have a rough
little paragraph on it um maybe before
yeah that sounds good I mean before we
dump uh jump into that Kyle and scren um
what different kinds of media have you
guys
used uh well I've only done the refo so
right now I'm going I'm doing my
recycled uh soil and it's been five
years and so yeah I just been Recycling
and re amending and in the beginning I
did use coco as a pH buffer but uh well
obviously so get out there but that's me
then for irration uh but I don't use
that anymore because uh but I could use
coco because it does decompose So
eventually you know uh that's Obviously
good for you know what I in in my thing
for the decomposition and it's a pH
neutral so um yeah that's basically it
I've only used the the revs remended
soil
so nice
SC uh so I I mix soil up um just like
your simple the quote unquote Coots mix
which is just an augmented Cornell mix
um and in one of my beds I used black
leaf mold instead of Pete Moss and then
in the in the other bed I used your
traditional uh stagnum Pete Moss as the
base they both work fine they both have
been working fine for years now
[Music]
um and I just I just use a like a
regular uh not out of preference but
just because it's what's at my uh at my
local hydro store I get uh the builda
soil 3.0 for my veg stuff since that's
actually moving
through nice thank
you yeah bumat uh we can talk about C
exchange nutrient uptake soil versus
Coco if you want to kick it off all
right um so yes soil has a higher Caton
cat ion exchange than a media like cocoa
um but in my opinion that negates the
whole concept of um the individual
plants having a preferred rate of
nutrition over the course of veg and
flour um there's something to do with a
media like cocoa that acts kind of more
like a direct inject IV where everything
that you're watering into the the media
itself the plant is immedi if it's in
the right suspension the plant is free
to absorb all of it and there's nothing
stopping it whereas in soil because you
have that relationship with the microbes
and fungus that the plant uses to eat um
it allows the plant to actually dictate
which nutrients are uptaken and which
nutrients will not um the roots of a
plant grown in a salt system lose that
ability to pick and choose which
nutrients are being absorbed if it's in
the right suspension ultimately the
plant is going to uptake it as a whole
um I feel like a good kind of way to
describe this is that uh salt gives the
grower a lot more control to be able to
choose what's available when for the
plant to eat whereas in soil you're
giving that trust in the plant the
actual control to grow and choose what
it wants when um I've watched firsthand
at work um we use Athena 3.0 recipe we
run that high EC we're we're a
production facility um and I've watched
firsthand at work that like plants will
not be happy and will not react happily
to a High feed if that's not what they
want um a great example of this would be
any Puck type genetics that I've seen or
Puck hybrids for that matter that I've
seen they are not particular fans
whatsoever of any high nutrition um I
did a little antidotal experiment for
myself um my boss was kind enough to let
me take one of those home that didn't
make the cut and I was curious and I ran
one of them just in the tent just to see
like I wonder if this plant will grow a
little bit better if it's just not
getting pushed as hard by being forc fed
things that it doesn't necessarily want
at this time um the plant the plan at
work was about 2 feet tall little like
individual bra stacked right on top of
each other and at home when a in a one
gallon pot with a really heavy top dress
on like I think it was day 17 um it
turned out phenomenal and it grew to
about a three and a half 4ot plant in a
one gon pot um smoked great looked way
better smell was way more pungent um
this is just kind of more of my anodal
experience of like actually seeing that
plants don't always like being force-fed
certain things at certain times um I
know local prior in one of the round
taes has kind of brought up that uh in
like Jacks there's I believe it's um
nitrogen is tied to calcium and so it
has like he has he said he's voiced that
before he's had a hard time with uh
certain plants not just not wanting that
much uh nitrogen but he they need a
little bit more calcium at the time so
those those two being tied kind of can
cause some problems um but this is just
from my general experience and things
that I've been listening
to yeah Kyle and scen any
any any like anecdotes from your own
experience on this
topic uh well from my understanding when
you feed uh well at least liquid sanics
the way I understand it is but the
preservatives and additives that get
added that keep it for shelf life that
is actually what fees the nutrients to
the plant and it's all force fed that's
my understanding of what I've read and
stuff like that obviously that's not
anecdotal you know because I've never
done that but that's why I think Sanic
works as it's overfeeding and the plant
just takes what it can and that's
actually from the preservatives of an
additives it's not actually the
nutrients that's in it and I don't know
about the nitrogen and calcium as far as
I know calcium has to be delivered
through the plant in the soil or through
water because it's not mobile so I don't
actually know about that
part um I think that's pretty much it
that's kind of what you know what I was
thinking about while he was uh
mentioning all that stuff yeah thank you
scen any thoughts on that any
comments uh so I don't think that I am
um smart enough to have that type of a
you know conversation but I will say
that um in Hydro it felt like whatever
whatever I ended up selecting was
essentially whichever one you know ended
up best which that's normal
but in my soil runs while I'm you know
sifting through packs of seeds
it's a lot easier for me to even if I
can't nail it like nail a plant to
really [ __ ] perform best I still get
a much better Baseline that I'm able to
end up with you know a product at the
end to decide on hey this is you know is
this worth keeping moving forward and
trying to like get it to its best
yeah absolutely that makes sense I mean
I I was thinking right well bumat was
kind of giving us a a really nice
account of like the various mechanisms
that I guess there are a couple
different ways that some one could
approach this you could you could I
imagine uh make changes purely based on
your observations right without really
knowing the theory which is like a just
a process of like trial and error heris
stics like
you're basically just watching the
plant and trying different things and
seeing what it does right which is a
different way of looking at it it's more
of a like blackbox kind of approach and
maybe uh coming back to bump cat I'm
curious like when you when you were
getting into this like I imagine at
times your experience and the theory you
know wouldn't always be in Step um did
you find that you had to do a lot of
experimenting on your own um outside of
the theory to actually like refine your
approach yeah there was uh I'm still
experimenting to be completely honest
with you um every run I always learn
something new um this plant never ceases
to teach me something that I thought I
understood um but yeah this
my my growing career has been a lot of
trial and error and just trying
different things and seeing how they
react um being forced into the 2x4 is
really like kind of forced me into
actually being able to understand and
run through plants like the way that I
wanted to I needed to understand what
was happening with the actual mechanisms
so I was forced into very much like
reverting back to just the same books
going rereading the same passages over
and over again just to make sure that I
fully understood the concept and that I
didn't misread or misunderstand what
they were actually trying to communicate
um same thing with the build-a soil
videos it's because Organics tends to be
in larger pots it's been a constant okay
what do I need to do to adjust for this
is this I know that like for example
diesel plants are really heavy eaters um
I know that if I put a diesel in a one
gallon pot that's over8 inches when I
flip it to flour it's probably going to
end up close to three and a half four
feet and it's going to be really really
hungry so I know I I need to feed a
little bit more with in my top dress or
maybe add in even a second shot of like
fish hydrate early on in flour to kind
of alleviate the pressure on the media
doing all the work um but yeah it's it's
been a constant run of trial and error
little things here and there okay let's
try feeding one plant the whole way
through flower and see what happens with
no flush uh let's do one where they're
going to get just water only let's do
one where I'm going to do a little bit
of pulse feeding with a top dress
um and it's it it really comes down to
the individuals as well um certain
plants don't like certain things like um
I ran a Sensei star Puck a couple fenos
of that and one of them did not like
anything to do with a mustard meal that
I used in my top dress which kind of
catalyzes the microbial processes and um
within the top dress to break down a
little bit faster it made the soil a
little hot and The Roots freaked out and
the plant just died like and that was on
day 23 um it's a constant trial and
error of new ideas like okay what about
this um let's try this here it's just
it's constantly just let's do little
adjustments one at a time to see what
happens and how the plant
reacts yeah and why I wanted to gesture
towards this is because it I think it
highlights really well that despite
there being a lot of theory and a lot of
theory that one could go and consume
there's obviously going to be a limit um
to how much that can apply to your
specific situation your specific
individual and so yeah there's there's a
necessary limit to Theory and how much
it can do for you and I just wanted to
you know yeah point that out yeah you
can absolutely you can absolutely drown
in the Theory online um there's
everybody has an opinion and everybody
body thinks that their opinion is the
most based in fact um my biggest
recommendation would be to check them
against other sources do the little bit
of extra work do that half hour of
reading it's really going to go a long
way it's going to save you a lot of time
and
headache yeah and I I think about this
uh in not just in organic growing but
like in all facets of of of this plant
which is that
um you can't take theory for granted
there is no
there's not going to be any Theory
that's comprehensive enough to tell you
everything you need to know about your
your plant like that's just not reality
and so there's always going to be some
experimentation and experience necessary
for you to you know really get really
get there Kyle did you want to say
something about that I was gonna say
Socratic heretic is like how I like to
think of myself I know enough to know
that I don't really know anything but
I'm still going to kind of do my own
thing so that's what I just that's how I
look at
stuff yeah I mean yeah exactly because
when when SCU was talking before I mean
I think he's being really
self-deprecating by saying he wasn't
smart enough but I for me I think the
the theory is really intimidating um and
so I can see why people would be like
look I'm just gonna work with what I
have see how it goes you know tweak it
as as it goes and I'll keep an eye on
the theory but it's not going to
like yeah fully informed SL overwhelming
um yeah just want to point that out in
in my opinion honestly the theory is a
really good general guide it's nothing
that's going to work 100% of the time
all the time it's yeah you're still
going to be going back and checking
Small Things doing small differences
that are going to be better suited for
your needs at the
time yeah and there's something else you
mentioned earlier as well which is if
you have the
patience and time and effort to go and
look at as many different perspectives
as possible that would be very valuable
because then you can at least compare
and you can see where they overlap and
where they don't and I'm sure that would
be a lot more constructive than just
like borrowing into one buying into like
one single Theory and like committing
everything to that that single
Theory yeah all right I got another
topic for us um
pot size I heard chren mention earlier
that he does beds I had a couple
questions for him what size beds are you
running in the 2x4 and uh how often are
you re amending
those so I have been
uh you know attacked about it before but
I run two by4 beds in my 2x4s
essentially the entire bottom is uh is
soil
um and now I do take uh like my plastic
Solo cups that I use for uh for pots for
seedlings and clones and stuff um I have
those pushed behind the bed so that it
creates like a air gap there so air can
still be drawn through
um yeah uh I re amend
them when I flip I usually add about a
cubic foot of compost or castings
depending on you know if my uh if I have
enough for my worm bins or anything like
that
um when I don't I usually just use you
know like Malibu or oie Mountain either
of those two just CU they're pretty
solid and
consistent and I add some bat guano and
some insect frass in that top
dress and then about two weeks later I
had
uh what's it called Soft Rock
phosphate um just to kind
of essentially I'm G what I what I'm
trying to do is give it just a base of
of food to eat um and then depending on
where I'm at in the cycle what I'm
adding dry amendments to kind of steer
it a little bit uh for down the
road want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out