ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
[Music]
how's everyone doing
well before natsu gets here don't forget
to join the patreon guys we have some
cool [ __ ] going on tomorrow there's some
fights
um
i'll be watching and
it'd be cool
um
i also have the hawaiian lights drop
for the patreon folks all the hybrids
are out
they've been out for about a week i'll
be adding those to the um
non-patreon
very soon so
we got those going on lots of good [ __ ]
popping off
farm stuff too if you checked out those
femme lines those are up right now for
everyone
there he is what's up
what's up yosela bastard how you doing
i'm all right i got allergies and my
internet connection sucks today so i
apologize ahead of time for
any [ __ ]
ah it's all good i'm still getting over
the sickness that i've been having
mostly just uh in my chest and in my
sinuses still it's [ __ ] bad though
whatever whatever i got was bad
i don't think i'm getting sick i just
think it's
mendo in springtime and things are
blooming
yeah
everything's out and about you know
yeah yeah it's about that time isn't it
it is here it's good you know things are
i mean event like what's funny is like a
million years ago when i first came to
california um to see the grateful dead
in jerry garcia band
um i came out here in spring right yeah
and everything was green
and coming from illinois where i'm from
where it's flat as a pancake because of
the glacier it was i thought it was like
ireland
yeah it was all like rolling hills and
flowers and it was brutally cold where i
lived and it was so nice here
and i had no idea got to like 110 and
everything died in summer
yeah
you know yeah oh i know oh i know here
it gets to be like 120 so well yeah you
you live and uh you live in the literal
frying pan yeah we live in hell
yeah you live in hell so
uh that's not my favorite part of
california what
i know i know dude i know you know i
mean i appreciate the desert but it's
not it's not my spot we burst kevin
mccarthy come on
you you did you know if you like flat
and dry and very very hot you know yeah
warm nights and good people good fun
yeah indeed
so what what is our topic for tonight as
far as education goes as far as
education goes i thought we would chat
about a couple of things
we would talk about maybe sort of like
the very late 90s early 2000s uh period
in the west coast
and because there's a whole bunch of
stuff then
that's pretty pertinent to now
it was all kind of going on and then i
think we might talk about at some point
probably will fit in because it's been
uh a big topic amongst us this week is a
little bit of like authenticity
yeah and uh how to you know how to
address that yeah how do you address
authenticity in these uh
times where everybody's making money off
something being authentic
well yeah and people you know people
have their own their own motivations
their own wants needs and desires
yeah you know that type of stuff and so
you know because
um
some cherry pie cush talk
cherry pie might be able to fit into
that a little late i've kind of avoided
the whole cookie thing yet yeah it's
probably a couple episodes on its own
and it's pretty complex so
uh we probably will chat about that at
some point but it needs uh that one
needs some fleshing out a bit
yeah i would say yeah yeah it's gonna be
a deep one
yeah that's a deep one and there's a lot
of people making a lot of money off it
and there's a lot of rep on it so the
more money and rep you have it kind of
ties into the authenticity thing we were
just talking about yep uh you start
talking history and it interferes with
anybody's money or rap and all of a
sudden they're extremely upset
yeah you know
uh
you know i mean i made this i made this
like joking post i don't post much
anymore on ig but i made this joking
post i saw this cartoon and it was like
i remember it differently
in a way that fits my world view and
paints me in a positive light
yeah that's for sure and you know
relating to weed history like you run
into that a lot
yeah you know you you run into that a
lot
you know so
um
maybe we should uh i don't know what are
we we're getting up to 150ish people
here yeah we like to [ __ ] for a
couple minutes and allow people to show
up yeah you know
yep and get to a certain point before we
start chatting so
here's my here's one just
what is the best blueberry not so dog
the best blueberry so this is another
one that when i tell you what i think
people will get upset at me yeah yeah um
because uh you know if you talk to uh
second generation genetics who is jd
who's dj's son or dj they will say the
only legitimate place to get blueberry
is them yes
right yeah
but the you know for some reason the
blue bonnet seems to throw these days at
least
uh some really potent blueberry terps
and it's not mine i didn't make it i
don't get to take credit for it but i
did use it it's just yeah to be
transparent yes he did use it so i had
no i mean
there's actually a tie-in to
well i have my own blueberry line that i
created before
during the time that blue bonnet was
being made and the
lone star was kind of competition to me
at the time and i was very egotistical
about my blueberry of course because
everybody thinks they have the best
blueberry and i used it and it did very
true for blue traits and very beautiful
blue terps and very pretty but it didn't
have much potency a resin production to
speak of and i think lone star did it
better than i did i really do
so yeah and what we're lucky
is that it still exists
yes and you can still get it from a
number of different sources yes
wow
a ton so
uh we're getting there i think we're up
to a decent time so we're gonna start
um and uh these talks have kind of been
we've we've been kind of moving forward
we started in the beginning in the 90s a
bit now we're starting to move forward
we actually still have like a third wave
of seed banks that matt and i want to do
um that we never actually dealt with
that involves canada and everything else
but it starts to get a little bit more
dispersed and difficult to get the the
accurate stuff so it's taken us kind of
a while yeah so yeah there's a lot to it
and there's a lot to cover you don't
want to leave out a lot of stuff and
you don't want to forget a lot of stuff
and some stuff we do leave out and
forget and have to go back and tag
because it isn't that important so yeah
and that's kind of you know that's kind
of one of the things about these talks
is there a bunch of history there's some
there's some speculation there's some
bullshitting um they're trying to be
conversational and tell people about the
memories that people have
um they you know we'll talk about things
but they they get people been under
shape already
um so rather than talking about like the
third wave of seed banks i thought we
could chat more about like what was
happening on the west coast yeah which
is where matt and i both live
uh what was happening on the west coast
in that era and how specifically
california and how that kind of like
started to impact what came after
yeah
right so
just to let everybody know
um in 1996 in november they passed the
215 act uh the proposition 215 in
california
and that made it was the first state
where you had medical
yeah now you know medical was uh
very restrictive at first and it was
only about four or five conditions that
it applied to
and the cops had spent their whole
career just busting anyone with weeds so
they were also slow to change
yes because they saw weed and they were
like [ __ ] you it's weird i'm arresting
you
and so people think that it like just
became legal in 1997 uh it did not
um it started a slow process
right
and the era we're going to talk about is
sort of like the very beginning of when
gorilla started to end and that process
started to really take place yeah you
know there was the very beginning of
medical in california so things were
starting to open up
people were starting to be less
secretive
um and as we mentioned on shows before i
think it was 1999
that overgrowth started
and not that long after the cannabis
world started
i i don't know the years on when they
started
um so
you know after a few years you had this
network of people
um that were connecting via these
via these you know these forums
yeah
and chatting and stuff like that and so
one that ended up happening
is
uh you know this this started a whole
wave of different things it started uh
there was you know really the forums
were the first time you could really
ever trade outside your circle that you
knew in person yeah
you know
right
yeah i mean even even today i i still
see people uh you know in other states
where they say you know i can't get that
clone i live in this state and it kind
of blows my mind because back then even
like that we didn't all live in like
people were getting bubble clones from
ohio you know that were in california
you know what i mean like if
you didn't necessarily go to the state
to get it
yeah and i mean you know one of the
things that's interesting about that is
that
you know there's there's different
people uh for a lot of people
um we have a good buddy of ours that
lives back in the midwest
and
you know for him the forums and ig and
discord and stuff like that was a way
for him to talk to other weed nerds yeah
right but for somebody like me who lives
in mendo like everyone around me does
what i do
yeah so there's no shortage of hanging
out like i'm surrounded by people like
me so there was some people that like
were
you know really intent upon getting on
there and that was their mode of
communication
yeah and some of us just lived in places
and stayed off all that
yeah you know so like when you popped up
or whatever it doesn't really like
correlate to like what you're up to we
all lived in the shadows
yeah right so
tying into that i'm uh i'm probably in
my
i don't know what it is i'm probably in
my mid-20s
or so
and i meet this guy and i don't think
it's weird to say his name his name was
ron uh yeah no right yeah yeah and uh
matt knows ron
very well very well yeah and ron was
around the character and he's still
around
and he did this thing where he started
throwing these harvest parties in fall
uh in
in my area and he actually threw him
he'd rent like a big ass [ __ ] house
in
sonoma county uh healdsburg outskirts
areas like that like a big mansion
essentially yeah and he had like a
catering company and so this thing would
be you pay a certain amount of money and
this thing would be catered and then all
these heads would come
right
yeah and so it was the first time for me
uh that i really was around like
um that kind of scene because most of
those people that were there
like they knew each other from overgrow
or cannabis world
yeah there was like groups that came
with people like me and stuff like that
that like were from that area as well
but there was a lot of people from all
over
and if people are running who want ron
is he's uh ncga nor cal growers
association a lot of people associate
him with like the blue widow cut that
was one of his uh big jams
yeah and he used to help people get set
up he's always been pretty politically
active
yeah you know he's always been a lot of
the fares and a lot of various things
that went on you know with he usually
have a booth and he politically
organized early
yeah
i'd say he got me my first uh emerald
cup cannabis cup or a cam cannabis booth
that was the first booth i ever shared
in emerald uh cup was was with ron
yeah yeah
yeah so i mean i i i
i went to this thing i don't know i was
23 24 25 something like that
and um i went with my friends
i got invited by a buddy of mine and
what was neat about it is you go to this
place and you walk in there like you
know huge dining room table or whatever
and everyone that wanted to share you
would write
your name which was usually like the
handle yeah yeah from the forums or
whatever you would write your name and
you would put some weed in the bag or
the jar
and so the whole table is full of
different kinds of weed and hash samples
right yeah
and then it's you know and then it's one
of those things where you hang out for
two or three days and smoke a ton of
weed and trade seeds with people and
trade trains with people and shoot the
[ __ ]
yeah
right so
i go there and i'm young
and i'm hoping to meet like i am like so
convinced dude that uh that i'm gonna
meet these old timers
yeah uh meaning my age now but that's at
the time uh you know i uh oh dirty old
sog was there look at that
um
anyway so
i'm all convinced i'm gonna meet all
these people and they're gonna they're
i'm like it's gonna like unlock the key
to a bunch of old-school strains i want
yeah right
and i get there enough there wasn't some
of that there but
there was there was so much like
everything that was super popular in the
very early 2000s
right it was like
apollo 11 apollo 13.
c99
uh you know white widow hybrids freaking
uh ssh hybrids uh yeah he's telling us
the best times i ever had they were
super cool parties yeah it was it was
really cool to to see
i mean there's a bunch of people there
who i won't mention because they don't
want to be popular
but i will tell you that's the first
place that i ever met csi in person
yeah uh that's the first place that i
met uh shaw who some people probably
know is 707 seed bank on ig who did the
you know the chem the chem dog bx2 and a
bunch of work with cat piss
uh yeah a lot of people got bubba kush
from him
yeah you know um he's a he was a pretty
big guy back then yeah he was pretty
involved shaw
uh you know uh people like jason king
from the can of bible kyle cushman uh
jack herrera
um
you know just you know a bunch of
mountain men from mendo and humble you
know yeah uh you know very and then
various types of people like chip uh who
now has a uh the real dirt podcast i
think yeah yeah um
yeah but he was actually when he at
those parties that was before he started
royal gold he was still working on like
cocoa fiber then that was so long ago
coco fiber wasn't even a commercial
product available in stores yet yeah he
was planning on bringing it to uh
uh to america yeah he hadn't started
royal gold but he was planning on it
right that's wild yeah and so and so a
lot of us that was that was a lot of
times where the where we got to put
faces to names
yeah you know like i didn't even know uh
dirty i would have loved to have hung
out and talked to dirty old saw i didn't
even know
you know if i met if i know your real
name i i don't know it so hit me up but
there was a but there was a bunch of
people there yeah and so like chip for
instance who started royal gold um he
uh he had just come back one of those
years he had just come back from
switzerland a tour in switzerland right
because for people that don't know
switzerland was like the first place in
europe to really open up to cannabis
like outdoor and greenhouse style um and
so when amsterdam and holland got rough
uh shanti and and uh breeder steve and a
number of different people shifted over
to swiss
yeah right and so chip had gone out and
visited those guys
right and so he's got all these pictures
on his computer of like these
greenhouses full of neville's haze yeah
like 10 foot tall plants direct planted
in the ground
so
it was just uh yeah vic high it was just
really neat because it was a lot of
it was a lot of connected people it was
a lot of people that were active on the
forums
um it was
five or six or seven years uh before
the reversal era
yeah
so everything was everything was red
seeds
yeah
everything there wasn't any
nes one i don't even think i'd heard the
term s1 outside of a book yeah
i don't think so i doubt so everything
yeah everything everything was hybrids
you know and people would bring their
hash bring their seeds bring their own
personal breedings
and it was like a way instead of mailing
each other and giving out addresses and
dms and all that it was like a super
swap meet
right
and so it was really neat in that regard
because
for one thing
uh ron had a catering business so part
of the money that everybody pitched in
he hired his whole team
and you and he made two meals a day for
three days
that's wild that's cool yeah you got to
sit there and roll joints and smoke and
shoot the [ __ ] and pull tubes and trade
seeds and then you're [ __ ] starving
right and then like some like tuna on
crisps comes by the thing you know and
you're like
i want some of that and you're just so
high and you start eating some of that
and drinking how you feel a million
times better
um and so
the reason i bring that up is because
while now with a lot of these events and
a lot of these lives and a lot of a lot
of times like
uh putting a face to a name has become
common yeah but back then it was
uncommon yeah very
so it was like really it was really it
was really like unusual and neat you
felt special
yeah
you know and i mean there was uh you
know there was times where i mean i went
i went there i think yeah the foods were
to die for olds and they were really
good they were fully catered full-on
meals they'd have snacks and hors
d'oeuvres that would be get brought
around finger food and stuff it was
pretty decadent
yeah you know and then just like
anything else even if you're an
experienced smoker
you start smoking 8 10 15 kinds of weed
you don't normally smoke yeah and it's
the first time you're smoking all of
them
even weak or moderate weed will get you
pretty baked yeah eventually if you're
just pulling all day non-stop yeah you
get [ __ ] yeah and so you know there
was different things where it was like
you can't hang out with everyone
yeah so you know you make friends some
friends i made there um you know
i kept up with really well
yeah others like csi i didn't catch up
with again for a number of years after
those yeah because you just you're in
different directions people you know all
that different types of stuff and um
you know uh eddie just it was kind of
just like a who's who
yeah and a lot of a lot of the times
those people fletch people that weren't
very well known then yeah but now
they're all hella well known yeah
you know and they have some of the best
seed banks you know some of the best
breeders around
some of the best collections of weed
around
yeah um you know when i went there i
didn't have most of the stuff that i
have now but i had i had the maui and i
had the the chem 91 and the super skunk
and i had the super dog
um my uh
my buddy who doesn't like to be
mentioned uh you know uh from staten
island he came a couple years with us
you know
um because we were still like right in
the middle of doing that super dog
project then
so
yeah we had different phenos we had the
super skunk we had different things we
had hash that we had sifted from things
and
all that so
it was just a really neat
gathering and time period
yeah people keep asking like what
happened but i think i think we did a
good job of recreating a little bit of
that just a few years ago
a lot of people weren't invited you know
because it was smaller but i think i
think that there's still an ability for
our community to pull together like that
and have these big events where people
just get along chill and smoke weed
yeah so it was a privilege because i
wasn't around for for the wrong parties
at all but it was a privilege to be a
part of the the canned illuminati
parties those are it was [ __ ] insane
to be a fly on the wall at those events
yeah i mean they keep they do keep
happening
um but i i will say that like they
probably won't happen like that quite
again
no um just for the simple fact that [ __ ]
changes yeah you know uh nobody knew who
csi was then
nobody knew who fletcher was then
nobody knew who i was that you know i
mean there was people that were known
you know but a lot of them were we were
all in our 20s or whatever just trying
to figure out you know various aspects
of life
yeah you know and we were all learning
and trading from each other and seeing
what was up and it was uh you know it
was just days of and there also wasn't a
bunch of money or rep involved
yeah it was kind of like the last era
before that era started
yeah it was so we were all young
innocent and dumb and you know and all
that kind of stuff but and
less of a competitive nature maybe yeah
we were all i mean honestly
i came home with so many seeds from that
event and i gave away
you know thousands of seats
yeah for free
yeah we just traded
yeah oh you've got some sweet tooth by
blockhead from steve
you know oh give me a hundred of those
and i'll give you 100 of this into this
into this into this okay cool you know
and it was like try it out
yeah it hadn't been monetized yet no one
really believed that you could make a
bunch of money in america selling seats
yeah i bet especially that area it
wasn't
it just didn't exist yet so it was like
all these heads each with their
everybody was happy to like if you could
get people you respected to grow your
beans
oh yeah that was everything
[ __ ] man that was like you know and then
they hit it and they were like dude i
found fire in your weed
yeah now you're like walking around you
feel good about yourself
yeah
you know
good job
and uh
you know and uh yeah in the forum era uh
caleb was white trash redneck or
inspector
now he's csi
yeah who's turf bugs i've never heard of
her
oh my gosh
we're going to bounce around because all
those different things sort of interact
so just to kind of like put a
um
you know ron's parties were where a lot
of us made friendships with each other
um where a lot of us met for the first
time it brought together different
disparate groups of
uh weed heads
yeah from their 20s through their 40s
you know 50s
it went on for a number of years uh it
you know it happened in the in in the
falls there was a lot of fire outdoor
and i should also mention
because this is pretty important to that
era where this is before the urkel
and the and the purple craze really took
off yeah and so
um that's really important because
all good weeds still got grown and was
sold
yeah there really hadn't been waves
where it was like get this one cut
yeah and this cut you can sell all of
that that hadn't really happened yet now
i i attribute a lot of that to [ __ ]
jason king too for hyping cuffs up so
[ __ ] hard that era
i mean you know it's it's it's hard i i
don't necessarily attribute it to him i
attribute it to the brokers
sure because i can't i can't talk about
other areas but like in mendo let's say
if you wanted to have a 50 lighter and
you wanted to sell every gram of your
weed you grew
yeah and you had granddaddy purple or
urkel or something along those or mendo
perps it all went yeah if you had sweet
tooth by louie
maybe not
yeah maybe
i mean you probably could i'm not saying
you couldn't yeah but there wasn't
buyers shooting up from the bay like
give me i got i got room for x amount
find it yeah give me that sweet tooth
yeah you know i mean but you know
because all that all that work i should
say that like so
and we'll talk about that um at some of
these things but
um
what were the all the popular things you
can think of
were at that party both as flower and
hybrids yeah and seeds so the white
family was crossed into everything
uh dj shorts the blueberry family was
crossed into tons of stuff
uh brothers grimm was crossed into a
different amount of stuff
yeah um
you know and then you know a bunch of
classics and things like that there were
a little around nikai was still doing
big stuff federation was still doing big
at that time uh people i can answer that
question someone just said where's jason
king he's on maui uh we'll we'll talk
about that in a minute um because that
was actually well that'll overlap but it
really was
it really was like you know you hear
about the legendary harvest festivals
that happened in humboldt or mendo small
little gatherings and stuff
um that's really what it felt like to me
yeah it felt like being able to go to
one of those type of things and
back then
you really just talk shop and weed with
your close group of hermit friends
yeah
so getting to getting to go to like and
hang out with dozens of different people
for three or four days and chat and chat
it up
uh really set the foundations and a lot
of the a lot of the friendships and
stuff uh for later
yeah it really made a big difference i
think
um frank you know friendships were
forged there transfers were made there
but you know ideas of things
yeah
for a lot for a large part of it and i
think like when you started coming in
heavy
like it was all a bunch of that stuff
yes yeah it was still very much around
like when i first started coming in
heavy i was looking for the blue widow
clone i was looking for the the sweet
thing clone i was looking for all that
[ __ ] yeah you're looking for all that
and that was like that was everywhere i
mean that was like what everybody had in
clones what they had in flower and hash
and seeds and all these different types
of stuff yeah you know
kyle was there documenting it for high
times although i don't think ron let him
actually made an article about it yeah
because he wanted to keep it like on the
down low and not [ __ ] it up you know
yeah for sure um
but uh but you know it was interesting
and the reason why we're gonna kind of
bounce around all these different types
of stuff is it all overlaps
yeah
right so
um somebody asked about jason king it's
probably a good time to chat about that
a little bit sure so
at that time
uh there was this guy's name's jason
king and he
had this idea
that i'm going to take a bunch of
pictures of famous strains
and then i'm going to write my own super
opinionated blurb about each one of
these things yeah
and he called it the canon
and i don't think anybody knew what he
was doing at the time uh would be would
matter but what he did which is super
cool is he came out with about three can
of bibles
yeah and they sort of document this
whole like late 90s through early to
mid-2000s era
right before the clone wars
where all these specific clones of kush
urkel sauer all that started just
dominating and a lot of these random
hybrids started to becoming hard to find
yeah
right
um so he came out with this can of bible
and i remember getting it and uh
one of the coolest things about the
first can of bible was that the entire
first introduction
uh is written by one of my weed heroes
uh rob clark
yes
right and rob did rob did this thing
where he wrote this big introduction
into the canon bible which honestly
i'm not sure anyone could have done that
and given as much legitimacy to jason
king
ron clark writing a big long seed
history and clone history introduction
yeah because like i've said before ron
wrote the bible for rob
rob clark wrote the bible for seed
breeding marijuana botany he wrote
hashish
uh he's legendary he's an encyclopedic
knowledge he's definitely like one of
the elders of the whole marijuana thing
yeah you know uh he's made lasting
contributions to cannabis and so him
writing that and what he did is he
outlined
which strains which was a huge debate
even back then yeah which strains went
to amsterdam as clone onlys
and which strains went to amsterdam as
seedlines yeah
and a timeline of who gave what
that was kind of brief but who gave what
over there yeah and then a timeline of
like all these different seed companies
and what years they released different
versions of things yeah that was one of
my favorite they his chart on the uh
release of seat companies it was the
first time i'd heard of like lowland
seats and all that [ __ ] you know really
per the pearl stuff is him someone's
asking that yeah pearl is all the pearl
stuff is related to rob and so
so for a lot of us that you're trying to
piece together all this [ __ ] here's a
guy in the know that knows all these
various seed companies and breeders and
work and all that
and um
you know he he outlines this thing yeah
okay
so
uh you know so he so he comes out with
this thing he writes this big long thing
which is amazing it's my favorite part
of the book no offense to the rest of
the book yeah and then the rest of the
book is a bunch of jason's opinionated
comments on different pictures of wheat
he's taken and what he thinks about them
yeah from all over right so i get this
thing
and uh i'm super nerded out by it and i
love it okay
well uh
flash a little bit and there was this
gentleman who
uh just passed away not that long ago
but uh
um
his name was eddie lepp
yeah okay and eddie lep had a farm in
upper lake which is about 20 minutes
from my house
um and he grew a bunch of wheat there
yeah okay
and he really blew it up he's he's one
of the he's one of the best best
he was one of the early biggest
flaunters of 215.
yeah like i'm gonna follow the law come
get me
and so a lot of people
um
that uh a lot of people met there yeah
right and so i met jason king uh both
there and i should should say at some of
those early ron parties okay
and we became good friends
right yeah uh through you know through
those connections through hanging out at
ron's parties and then through
um you know he was he was a photographer
and trying to document weed and
everybody back then was fascinated that
eddie left was willing to fill a field
full of cannabis and be like come get me
yeah yeah
you know
uh and so
you know and and and so i decided to
help jason with his with his project
yeah he wanted to make a second can of
bible
yeah right and
i'd lived in mendo at that point a
number of years and
matt as you're well aware uh weed was
weed world was still insulated then yes
very much going to get a bunch of
pictures uh you're not gonna meet all
the right people without an n
yeah yeah it's still kind of that way
for the old school guys though you know
what i mean like but nothing like guys
are hard to talk to but nothing like it
was yeah before you couldn't even find
how to contact an old guy at least now
they have like maybe an ig page or some
some way you can track them down
that's true when i first got into this i
remember i tried tracking down dj's
short to speak to him you know
no dice you had to find where he was
going to be speaking and see him in
person if you wanted to get a hold of
him at that time
so we'll crazy we'll bounce we'll bounce
around just so everybody knows i'm going
to talk about eddie and that then that
whole era because that's pretty cool but
um so these things will all overlap
because they're all going on basically
at the exact same time yeah
ron's parties uh eddie's scene at an
upper lake um the stuff that i haven't
talked to canada bible all this stuff is
all like happening and and as part of
the same flow same few years right so
um so i become friends with jason and i
decide to
um help him with his project
yeah right um get him introductions to
people let him meet other people that
can help him kind of navigate through
humboldt mendo
um and document and all that type of
stuff so
as a result of all that
um
you know and i should say this is that i
i was pretty good friends with jason
back then i haven't
we've drifted apart he's lived on maui
now for a long time and i don't i don't
go to hawaii or haven't had kids so
we've kind of drifted apart we're still
on good terms
um he's a super opinionated guy and he
used to drive some people nuts
it very true very true like there are
people that will be like that guy drives
me [ __ ] nuts i always got along well
with him yeah right
and on top of that i was very
sympathetic to what he was trying to do
yeah just another weed nerd trying to
[ __ ] put the pieces together yeah i
strongly disagreed with them about
certain things oh you know yeah and all
that you know and we would battle about
you know all kinds of [ __ ] you know um
but that's not that's not any different
than today with people um but he was
documenting and there's a lot of there's
a lot of things in there you know like
you talk about like the bull ride
there's a lot of stuff
yeah that fell off the wayside that's
documented yeah
you know
um and uh and so i started helping him
figure out this different stuff
right
and and and you know and me and eddie
and some other different folks
um started helping them put together the
can of bible yeah right and by helping i
just mean making introductions and and
you know
can this dude with a camera come to your
scene
yeah
because that's kind of crazy right you
got to have some trust yeah can i bring
a dude with a [ __ ] camera yeah to
your scene
yeah you know
uh and just so people get an idea this
is pretty funny um i remember uh jason
got a 12 megapixel camera
yeah with a super nice lens on it to
start taking pictures because the first
can of bible was all film right yeah
that 12 megapixel camera with a super
nice lens
was over 11 000
oh my god i'm dead serious dude over
eleven thousand dollars because i was at
his house
he actually
rented this house from eddie left that
was in lake county not at eddie left's
property but a separate home healed yeah
like i said i lived 20 minutes in there
for we were so we were together all the
time
and uh
you know at like like i said before
about rock about ron's parties at the
time i was growing the super skunk
um
the uh the the chem dog 91
uh the black the black domino the snow
the trinity
a bunch of the super dog crosses and
hybrids
um all that type of stuff and so
you know i started helping them get all
this stuff photographed
and and documented
and you know and it was pretty neat in
that regard um because
uh
you know they um
there's a lot of stuff that was like
that's been lost
yeah but there's a ton that's in those
books but there's video but there's
picture evidence and there's various
aspects right
and uh
you know so
if people are interested because of that
close relationship
um i had a bunch of stuff that ended up
in that book
um
the the i grew the dog both i was in
this process then of growing a bunch of
my favorite strains completely organic
and then full salt
and
then in the same room at the same time
right next to each other and then doing
a bunch of blind taste tests with me and
my friends and trying to actually see
yeah
which is better
right so i so there's there's uh the
chem 91 is in there is both dog and chem
dog
grown both ways
uh my mendo perps is in there the snow
the trinity
my super dog seven cut that i lost
is in there which is a hybrid between
the uh myself and the guy from staten
island made this line
basically a super skunk chem dog line
um the purple effects
yeah uh which is mendo perps crossed
with fx which is a cool story
um
actually somebody said coral reef that's
not mine but uh our buddy fletch has
been hunting for that for a super long
[ __ ] time yeah so if anybody knows
where the coral reef is uh hit us up
but anyway like
that that that um
that superdog thing is is the odd
connection that me and you have where i
spent years and years and years trying
to figure out who made the [ __ ] super
dog by asking around the whole kim fam
all that [ __ ] and at one point i
couldn't get any [ __ ] answers like
half half the people would say yes it's
jesus it's the same thing it's just
another name you know we made it yeah
it you
turn out to be that way but i remember
before we met i remember in 2010 i made
a super dog 2010 trying to recreate
what i had read about in the canon bible
because i could never [ __ ] find it
and many many years later when we
finally interacted i'd realized you were
the source of the super dog and that was
really interesting because it was such a
big long chase for me because of that
book
i i remember i mean i i don't really
want to tell the story of how i lost at
all but
um i i remember like i mean i had it at
all those ron parties i passed it out
freely to a bunch of people
um i gave a bunch of superdog hybrids uh
to mandelbrot
and it ended up being a lot of the basis
of a lot of his males
that he started using to get started
because even back then everyone had to
use pollen yeah not that everybody
doesn't use pollen today but everybody
had to use like males yeah like full
regular males reversals were
six seven eight years away yeah
then um so i i didn't even we didn't
even know it was but the only reversals
anyone ever heard of is accidental herms
yeah that was reversals
and sometimes if people wanted to make
accidental
they would torture their plan
they would make it dry out they would
make it almost die they would [ __ ] with
its life cycle they would just capture
it and see
can i get it to pop a bunch of pollen
right
yeah
so
technique yeah like i don't have like i
lost the super dog i lost the purple
effects but there's write-ups in that
book of it
right
which is pretty neat because then
there's there's at least pictures of it
yeah that's how it got documented and
why we still know about it
yeah and i should tell i should tell a
funny story just because so
uh jason had this girlfriend named
rebecca back then
and um
he uh she was from north carolina and
they had this strain that is is semi
known right now called the mothership
yeah and it was this old ass weird
sativa um and jason just raved and raved
and raved about it and so he got his
girlfriend's friends to mail it to him
in uh in lake county
yeah right so you're thinking today you
know with all the mailing tech that
people have you're thinking some like
small innocuous package or whatever
yeah so this this [ __ ] thing shows up
and it's a box that's about a foot a
foot
wide and a foot you know this and two
feet deep right yeah it's a big [ __ ]
box
you know
and we open it up
and inside are two mother ships with a
bunch of with a bunch of stuffing around
them in one gallon pots tied to stakes
and they're like they're like 18 to 24
inches tall
yeah so instead of the person mailing us
cuts
they mailed us like one gallon pots of
dirt and 18 to 24 inch tall plants
in that box that's all there was you
open the box and it's like two plants in
there
yeah that's wild but it was so unusual i
think i don't think the post office was
hip yet to like weed and like especially
plants in the mail sending big ass
plants in the mail no probably yeah and
there's actually in that can of bible
there's some uh there's some pictures of
that mother ship because i was one of
the first people that grew it um because
i actually had running grow rooms and
there's pictures of the mother ship at
eddie lep's property there's pictures of
the mother ship from my greenhouses and
stuff it was a really unusual plant but
but yeah it got mailed to us in the most
sketch way imaginable
i remember
in cana bible if i think it was the
mother ship that at one point jason king
was trying to say this has to be related
to hp13 because i've never tasted
anything like this that was one of those
extreme speculations that he was uh i
mean i should say i mean he's my friend
and everything like that but yeah you
read the descriptions of like the dog
and the chem dog and different things
yeah and i even wrote down like lineage
in history for him
and then when he went to do his artistic
interpretation of what he wanted to
write you read it and you're like oh
that's [ __ ] yeah oh well
oh well but that happens all the time
people talk about all this journalist
quoted me incorrectly or took me out of
context or whatever else so but at least
that's a documentation and it was there
yeah
you know
um and well so one thing i'll say and
then we'll move on and we'll talk a
little bit about eddie's situation right
is that
um so we did that
uh
i'm gonna lose my train of thought but
um jason decided to do a can of bible
release party
for the second can of bible and he
decided to invite everyone that it
contributed to the book
with pictures right and everyone that
helped him put together and who's who
and um
they uh
and he rented out this very this very
magical place which i don't know if most
people have heard of there's this place
called or springs in mendocino county
and it's a natural hot springs um and
you know so it's got all these like
cabins in the woods and stuff and all
this beautiful redwood and it's right
next to monkey huh
no i'm saying yes
and it's right next to montgomery woods
which has some of the tallest trees in
the world
right i think three out of the five
tallest redwoods are all
in mendocino county right next to this
this hot springs yeah so it's pretty
magical place right
so
he does this thing where he throws this
three-day can of bible release party
right and we all get to come and we all
have our little rented cabins and
whatnot and it's the same thing like one
of ron's parties essentially it's a
bunch of seed swapping and trading and
all this different stuff and
eddie left's there and and rob clark's
there and and you know uh caleb and shot
like all just all the people i already
mentioned
a lot of the same people are there and a
lot of people that contributed to the
book eddie lepp
his whole entourage and all these folks
right so
i got to meet uh one of my heroes
at the time who's that
i got to meet dj short
[ __ ] a that's one of mine that i got
to meet too what a coincidence yeah so
um and that was that was kind of intense
because you know uh as we've mentioned
on previous podcasts you know if you're
on a weed nerd on the forums
you've got this is way pre-cookie too
right you've got all these like you know
test grows and stuff on the forums of
all these beautiful blue families
hybrids yeah and blue and blue work and
you're like holy [ __ ]
yeah so you know i'm in my mid-20s or
whatever and dj is significantly older
and so you feel like you're meeting an
elder yeah and you're just starting to
[ __ ] around you know my buddy from
staten island and myself we've been
breeding for a number of years at that
point with our super dog and different
things
but we finally felt like we were just
getting started and here's this guy
that's like was released in europe in
the 90s
yeah worked with sag martha worked with
dutch passion had canadian stuff had
this whole movie
and everybody back then
was kind of on his jock
yeah
wouldn't you say oh yeah yeah
everybody
i mean he was kind of a famous guy then
you know he was internet famous him
hempy vic high
uh you know there was some really like
famous
internet personalities on those early
forums yeah yeah they were
dj's work was one of them he stood out
yeah yes right yeah and he was one of
the first american breeders
since the breeders who first brought
their stuff over to amsterdam like sam
and rob and all those guys he was like
the next wave of people that got famous
yeah
and there wasn't that much competition
either yeah people say hempy hempy was a
[ __ ]
heavy had a lot of good points but man
was he a tough character he was a
[ __ ] like he was a little booker he
was uh he was he was if you said
something i mean a lot of those guys
like tom hill and stuff
if you said something ignorant they'd
just tear your [ __ ] head off yeah
hippy can't even be put in that same
category he made
he think as an idiot
he was he i mean you know i had to deal
with him too much right
so anyway i um
you know dj is at this at this can of
bible release party right
and he shows up at the time i'm all
excited but to him it was probably like
there was a bunch i was a custy right
yeah
so he shows up and he's got manila
little manila envelopes you know
with just you know 50 100 of all his
lines yeah
which i think back then was only four or
five
yeah it was only a few lines at a time
that he would ever sell and they were
just super expensive for for the time
too
yeah he had blueberry
um and he had
huh flow
and blue velvet
yeah and maybe the moonshine
yeah blue moonshine or old time
moonshine one of them yeah blue it was
blue blue moonshine blueberry yellow and
blue velvet yep
those four and so
uh
csi and i get to talking to them you
know mm-hmm
and uh
i have to say and he's still around and
stuff and all that so he's gonna be kind
of irritated at me but
um it was my first experience with
realizing that a lot of these old-time
breeders
don't know that much
yeah i mean i thought here i am this
guy's this guy's been doing it 15 20
years longer than me
yeah you know he's made all these
amazing strains everybody's getting all
these amazing hybrids out of them and
he's releasing all these inbred lines
and who doesn't like the word juicy
fruit tie or purple tie or this or that
so you're all [ __ ] pumped
and then you start talking to him and
he's vague as [ __ ]
yeah it was yeah
like super vague
yeah he's um i think that is one thing
that i have found with people that whose
opinion i respect
everybody that has met dj short
including me has had the same experience
except that he
with me he just told me i don't own my
own company and that was no you know
he wasn't he wasn't he was open and he
talked for a long time and we talked for
hours over multiple days
yeah he's shooting a lot more talking
together he was super jovial and and
conversational and all that so i don't
want he wasn't
he wasn't like we were talking about
empty he wasn't a dick yeah yeah you
know but but you know i kind of feel
like having being a weed nerd myself and
talking to tons of breeders
if there's one thing you can do you can
talk in detail about your own [ __ ]
yeah you should be able to because it's
your [ __ ] and it's like you're [ __ ] a
weed nerd and you're [ __ ] into it and
it's you know
yeah it's your passion and you know and
you can just do that [ __ ] off a memory
you don't need and he just kept saying
stuff oh i have to go back and look at
my notes
yeah i'd have to check my notes and you
know i'd ask him
like why didn't you know
did you ever did you ever back cross or
did you ever use any of your original
genetics again yeah and he was like no
you know he's like at the time he was
like i still have thousands of seeds but
they're so old and i haven't stored them
well i don't know if they pop yeah
right
and so i just remember
like walking away from there and uh
just being like just i just thought i
was gonna get a wealth of information
yeah
and in the hours and hours that i talked
to them i don't i don't even know if i
got
too many tidbits
yeah no
you know and then if you read his book
now it's gonna sound like i'm dissing
him it is a very very rudimentary way of
growing inside
it is yeah definitely now the one thing
i will say that i think is super cool
about his book is he does describe a
bunch of uh
uh weed that he smoked when he was
younger that's my favorite part of the
book
and then he also does this thing
where he has this i mean we didn't
no one used the word terpenes back then
but he tried to make like an olfactory
chart yeah like a smells chart and break
down what smells are related to what
yeah is a really good chart and it was a
fantastic chart i highly recommend it
still because anything that trains you
to speak about things in language is
helpful yeah
yeah so i mean he was talking about like
squirrel cage fans and you know i mean
that's kind of like you know he kind of
grew in trailers and organ and
and use that used very 80s tech and
never really advanced right
um
but be that as it may despite being very
disappointed by talking to them about
things i still bought like 400 450 of
the seats yeah every line he had the
velvet the moonshine the blueberry the
flow i bought you know i don't know 75
to 150 of them yeah right
um and i and i i went home and i grew
them all out
yeah um i think is the name of the book
is like cultivating exceptional cannabis
or something like that yeah that's it
right off the top of my head something
like that it's got a really pretty flow
plant or something on the cover yeah
extremely purple
i think it's a flow but some other
people have said it's a blue satellite
too like there's some some discrepancies
on that as well well one of the things i
mean when you interviewed uh chimera and
red
yeah you know um you know one of the
things that chimera is good friends with
dj so he's not going to say anything
rude but what he did say is he kind of
basically admitted that he thought that
everything that he had was like the same
line
yeah and it was just different express
like
dj would see an expression within the
line and he would be like oh this is its
own thing it's blue velvet yeah and if i
just breed stuff with expressions like
that it's its own thing
but that's not really what was going on
either because he was crossing opposite
to to
opposite when he was doing line breeding
working directional which is what you
don't do it was very artistic take on
breeding for the time and he and and in
fairness like we said before i they were
writing the book as they were going you
know like these were guys just getting
into kind of reading there was no books
to be had you know at the time when dj
was doing this so mad props to him for
[ __ ] doing what he did i i was able
to
uh work at the bunch of his work that
i'm stoked on um i'm not as stoked on
his uh human work um as far as
human breeding but other than that you
know like as far as cannabis breeding i
i owe a big debt of gratitude to him i
mean i'm not but i just you know it's
one of those like he
that's the conundrum right is that it is
you see all this amazing stuff you see
how it all works you get it yourself and
i grew up imagine people listening i
grew out 450 seeds over the next year
yeah
and uh
you know i'd like to say i found a few
keepers that i i miss
yeah i did
yeah i did i it it was unbelievably
beautiful a lot of it
especially pre-cookie there was
lavenders there was blues there was pink
there was purple there was various
shades of in-between
it didn't have a lot of terps
and it didn't have a very potent high
most of it yeah yeah for sure um but
when i outcrossed it to different things
i got way better weed
than anything of the pure lines i got
from him so you can imagine how [ __ ]
excited i am right because now there's
no seed bank there's no middleman it's
like i'm getting handwritten manila
envelopes from the guy
yeah the real deal holyfield
am i gonna find the fire yeah here it
comes right
real [ __ ] labeling backing everything up
i mean you know how it goes when you're
running hundreds of things and you want
to keep track of it what the [ __ ]
yep
you know it's uh it's a huge pain in the
ass
yeah i just recently did that i mean
people were talking about you know
popping 450 seeds in the in the chat not
finding anything i just recently popped
almost the same amount of uh
stuff from from uh blue lines and uh
went through all of it and had a very
similar experience now i i will say
something because there is some there is
like a an economic aspect that we don't
talk about right where back then
um you know most fire indoor was you
know four to forty five hundred
yeah a peak yeah so
it was really easy to grow flower
and have a side room or two with a
couple of lights in each
for experimentation
yeah
you know the the rate you know a 12
lighter could was was everything you
need in life if you wanted to
so
uh the economics were really easy to
allow people to experiment and [ __ ]
around
yeah now things are super tight and it's
gotten quite hard and mathematics and
economics are much more difficult right
in this particular period of time
yeah um but back then
you know it was like that's what kept
the cropping from being boring
i got a question for you this is a good
question this is from the chat but it's
a good question and relevant where did
that swami guy come from was he around
when you were hanging out
so
i no
no
no no no
no no
that's weird swami
i did i did not i mean he's a pretty
recognizable character
yeah
you know yeah you wouldn't have even if
you didn't become friends with him or
whatever like you wouldn't have mistaken
him no i don't think so no and you know
we'll get we'll get to that i don't want
to i don't want to break it up but we'll
get to that um when we talk about the
authenticity part in a little bit here
yeah sure um as far as that goes because
there's a bunch of people that one of
the things about cannabis i'll talk
about super briefly is that you can just
sort of step out of the shadows
yeah and then people are like i don't
believe where this person came from if
i'm i'm i'm who i am i would have known
him yeah
you know
um so you know it's it's one of those
things where uh
there's a lot of shady characters in
cannabis
and there's a lot of and there's a lot
of people who make good and bad opinions
about people on the internet that you
have never met and you don't hang out
with in real life yeah
you know matt and i are friends in real
life
yes
you know like we're real life friends
we've made
made real love to each other so uh you
know platonically from a distance
you know all that
um but you know it it's different and
you have a bunch of people who become
fanboys or girls of different people
and attack whoever they want to and
stuff like that you know and it becomes
difficult because they don't know their
enemy
and they don't know their friend
yes
either
they know like a a social media
construct of that person sure which is
not the same thing
no
so but we'll get to that in a bit so
scrolling back you've got you've got
ron's parties
right yeah uh being sort of a nexus for
this thing you've got uh
you've got the can of bible parties
which were another nexus bringing people
together you know
um yeah but i was i have to say i was
super disappointed because i really feel
like
you know if you take home 450 seeds from
four different lines from a breeder and
uh you don't find anything you really
think or one i want to keep you know
yeah that's super disappointing
yeah that it is disappointing that's a
lot of money so it's a lot of my i mean
he gave me a good deal don't get me
wrong it's not like i paid full custody
because i'm at the no he liked to make
money too
but yeah but the the size of the room
the amount of just everything that goes
into the economics is growing it's a lot
of money it's a lot of time
and you know like i talked before it was
like you know there's there's eight or
ten american elites of nl5 hayes yeah i
ran 60 70 no 5as and didn't find any of
those keepers yeah but other people did
yeah you know
um so dj was a disappointment just in
the sense that he comes from like a
different generation of weed nerd i
think yeah where they're just not that
deep into detail
yeah you know i mean one thing you can
say about rob clark or sam skunk man
it's whether or not you want to believe
a bunch of what they say or not they're
heavy on detail
yeah a lot of the old a lot of the old
guys you talk to
um you know they're light on detail
yeah they don't remember or they try to
make it up they did it
yeah but they just don't like it's even
the same thing with like the sour
stories or a lot of stuff that happened
in the 90s that we try to get to the
bottom of yeah they didn't know it was
going to be important
i'm pretty sure dj thought he was always
going to be important based on having
met him i'm pretty sure he always
believed he was going to be yeah i mean
like i said over that weekend i probably
talked to him for five six hours seven
hours yeah we were there for three days
all we were doing was like
literally smoking weed and hanging out
and shooting the [ __ ] eating food
dude i would have loved to have had that
opportunity with him i just it just
seemed so
not interested in discussing anything
with me and it was it was it was hard
because i did look up to him so much and
it's not that i lost respect for him but
it's just like the more i learned about
breeding and
hands-on the more i learned about
why his lines turned out the way they
did and why i was having such a hard
time
working those lines you know um it all
made sense in the end and i mean you
know i don't i'm not dissing him because
like you're [ __ ] around the 70s or
80s or even in the 90s or whatever it's
like
you learn as you go you know you
bottleneck something when it's early on
and that's what you got
yeah you know i i'm not dissing him by
any means because there's a lot like i
said there's i think his lines are
overly inbred
yeah but definitely over the embryo but
some of the most fireweed at those ron
parties was out crosses of blue blue
work
yeah so there's nothing wrong with
having an inbred kind of unique to the
cannabis scene line
and it takes some outcrossing to really
bring out its true character
no that's kind of what what breeders
would want something very stable and
worked you know i don't think that's a
diss necessary now of course how do i
wish
that dj would have repopulated his juicy
tie and his purple tie and his original
lines every four or five years and kept
fresh seed of the original things
yeah sure of course i do do i wish he
was interested in them and didn't just
let them go to [ __ ] even though he had
them
yeah
well yeah i do
um but you know i mean everybody looks
back on when they were younger and was
like boy do i wish i did this
yeah yeah i mean who doesn't have those
regrets about their 20s
yeah you know i don't even remember what
happened in my 20s so right so shit's
[ __ ] up you know and
so so that's happening um all these kind
of bible things are happening they're
all getting documented in that regard
and eddie leps was another
place that was kind of like ron's
parties or the cannabis parties where
um people overlapped a bunch
yeah because people wanted to come out
and see this guy is growing a thousand
pounds in his front yard
yeah holy [ __ ]
yeah he's a wild one now
now it's like it sucks because you know
uh what happened to him is he ended up
going to jail for 10 him and his wife
ended up going to jail for 10 years
yeah um
and you see gardens way bigger than his
all over the place now yeah and he
didn't people should know this he didn't
just go for it okay he did this crazy
thing this is probably worth mentioning
where
the law said you were allowed to have
six plants and a ten by ten
yeah so he mapped out his farm in ten by
ten grits
and he collected
right
um
you know he collected medical cards for
each grid
yeah and each medical card was tied to a
specific grid
yeah and you could give him
your strains to grow in that grid
and he would do a certain amount of work
like feed it and water it and this and
that but like you could come out there
and do your own de-leafing and your own
various aspect of different things like
that you could put in more work
yeah if you wanted to and really make
your 10 by 10 nice and then there was i
don't need to get into that part of it
but there was a split between him and
you
yeah you know so honestly it's like he
didn't just like blow it up and go for
it
he literally
had 10 by 10 plots with six plants per
plot
yeah tied to a medical card and he would
just stack hundreds of them yeah he was
just challenging the government to
challenge their own
like little
gray areas of the law is what he was
doing pretty punk rock i might do yeah
super punk rock super rebellious and he
wanted to have eddie left gardens all up
and down the [ __ ] the highway
yeah he literally felt like most people
wouldn't be able to grow their own
but why couldn't you come
bring your medical card to eddie left's
collective
yeah and grow your own fairly near your
house where you could go ten to your
plants on the weekend
yeah
you know and what happened to him was he
he had this huge plot in his front yard
i'm not gonna dig him out i got some
posters from him and a bunch of pictures
and stuff but it's too hard to show like
on the thing
um but anyway he
and then the the last year he had
he decided to get seven acres across
highway 20 from his house in upper lake
and he was going to grow about
13 acres of cannabis
yeah dead serious 32 000 plants yeah
that's a lot for the time yeah uh 32 000
plants all
documented
right yeah all with all with and i
begged him not to
yeah because i was like dude i don't
think the dea i don't think i don't
think they'll let you get away with it
like i'm worried like they'll come down
and they'll bring the hammer down
you know
um yeah some photos of that are in the
can of bible 100 there's a whole thing
on eddie in the can of bible actually
yeah um you know and and there's
definitely pictures throughout the can
of bibles that are from eddie's spot
uh you probably won't recognize him if
you hadn't been there but anyway um
so i begged him not to do it some other
friends begged him not to do it but
there was other people that thought he'd
be fired and they were really pushing
their boundaries yeah they were pushing
it hard
um and uh you know he got raided by the
dea
it cost him a lot with 32 000 plants you
know and he
he him and his wife got 10-year
sentences
yeah uh 10-year federal federal
sentences and the [ __ ] the the shitty
thing about federal sentences is that
you have to serve 85 percent of the time
it's not like the state where you can
get off halfway for good behavior
yeah and him and he was a vietnam vet
and him and his wife were older his wife
passed away in prison sadly
yeah um and then he got out and uh
you know the world had changed
he went from being this like rebel
maverick kind of center of attention
which to be honest he was kind of
egotistical and he had you know he tried
to form a cannabis church and
yeah
you know he was [ __ ] that's you know
there's a lot a lot of characters right
so yeah um but he got out in the world
to change now there's all these
[ __ ] doing gardens his size
yeah and it's all fine
and you know he gave up you know um he
gave up a lot for that
yeah and he got hammered pretty [ __ ]
hard and there's people there there's
people that
i i mean i'll mention a few people i
guess you know um
one of the one of the skittles crew that
like that spun off into dying breed and
now is his own person shiloh probably a
bunch of people know um
i was like the second person in mendo
that shiloh met yeah um him in dallas uh
who's got another you know who he works
with now um they both were working at
eddie's
yeah there was a bunch of people that
became kind of well known later
that were kind of eddie's farm hands
back then
yeah you know and we're cause it was a
big deal it was a big mess
he wasn't the most organized character
either so you can imagine
you know
he was definitely king of his hill and
he spent a ton of time entertaining and
being himself
you know yeah and then you're trying to
grow thousands of pounds
yeah
you know
uh and uh you know and but we were all
young then a lot of us hadn't none of us
really made our names anywhere you know
it was all people that you know it was
just it was a smaller world
yeah
you know for sure um
and so but eddie had a bunch of parties
at his house he had a bunch of
gatherings at his house
a bunch of people from spy rock and bell
springs would come down because they
were shocked that he could they did big
[ __ ] up there but they lived such a
crazy lifestyle um they were shocked you
could do it literally like you dr i can
still dr i drive pius house pretty often
still
you can see it from the highway
yeah yeah his old house that he lived at
for a long time um yeah and that's the
house that's in the can of bible
you know
um and it was like a who's who of
legalization guys uh i should i should
say something else um you know uh his
last years um
jack herrera moved and got a house right
down the street from eddie
yeah i passed by that house too eddie uh
jack herrera was at a bunch of those
parties
um i have some signed books by him and
stuff like that he was over there a
bunch just hanging out you know yeah um
you know he had he had some health
problem right there on the 20 yep he had
some health problems and some strokes
some stroke issues and stuff like that
so some of his last years he was
you know he kind of had like uh
um you know sometimes some parts of your
face don't work the greatest yeah but
his mind was still there even though
sometimes he struggled to get out
certain things yeah um but you know jack
is another hero yeah he had a whole
cannabis cup made after him he was you
know he wrote the book on the hip
possibilities
yeah um you know it was it was kind of a
it was kind of a smaller world
yeah
but it was all those ron's parties
the can of bible parties
eddie lep's whole situation this was all
sort of like a norcal
you know uh emerald triangle lake county
kind of thing that was going on where a
lot of people were fighting were
starting to come off their hills and and
and meet people
you know and it was pretty it was it was
pretty integral to what came later i
think
yeah
you know it was a lot of us that are our
middle middle-aged now and are trying to
pass down history
we were looking up to people like eddie
lapp or rob clark or tom hill
who is a cantankerous old man
yeah
yeah yeah i mean he was i love nice i'd
love to get him on here but we'll see
well he was a little he was a little
nicer in person but man uh if he didn't
know you and you said something dumb on
the internet you know
yeah he was going to he was going to uh
eviscerate
yeah he would have visited failure at
all
your ego he would rip it out of your
[ __ ] and make you feel like the
smallest little [ __ ] in the world
yeah people are saying there's very
weather might there's people saying oh i
might have met you back then not so it's
very possible
yeah you know that you met me um or i
met you i mean there was a lot of
comings and goings then even at those
parties at ron's parties like
um it's not like i got to meet and like
made lasting relationships with everyone
there
yeah some of them were 20-minute
conversations some of them were hours
yeah some of them were in the tight
circle of people i was hanging out with
all weekend because that's how it worked
some of them were on the periphery i
mean it's just kind of one of those
things and none of us were none of us
were
anything then yeah we were all just a
bunch of young weed nerds you know yeah
tom was like yeah i agree dirty oh tom
tom was super nice to me
but you read some of this stuff when
people ask them dumb questions online
and holy [ __ ]
yeah
right
yeah i mean he's he was highly
intelligent some people don't suffer no
foods no he was highly intelligent and
he didn't have a lot of patience
yeah i i yeah i i can i can definitely
relate to that sometimes
yeah i mean but you you see that you see
that even now like you get so burnt out
by dealing with people you know yeah um
i think the same thing happened to
sam skunk man
to some degree oh yeah yeah you know uh
he was probably nicer and more chill and
then you get you have to answer the same
50 questions a billion times and you get
accused of all this [ __ ] and all of a
sudden you're a cantankerous old man
yeah it's very easy to fall in that
category
you know but those guys were all legends
all heroes to us vic
tom hill
hempy
you know uh these were all like leaders
of the scene you know um and and
old-timers to us
yeah you know tom's got to be i mean
tom's got to be 20 years older than me
i don't know maybe maybe i don't maybe
50s
you think he's only in his 50s yeah i
think i think you're pretty old actually
i think you're probably older than him
you're under 60
yeah you know it's all the oil of olay
keeps me young
or whatever but
the reason why i'm babbling about all
this [ __ ]
is
it's where a lot of people because there
was essentially like there was
essentially like
uh what's the best way to put it maybe
the best way to put it is that
in the 90s most weed scenes were
very isolated to themselves
to very small circles it was very risky
it was illegal everywhere no one was
really chatting
the grateful dead dead tour fish tour
that kind of thing there was some
overlapping things because people would
meet
and not be as scared because nobody knew
where anybody else lived yeah
no i'm not dude i'm 45. matt's joking
960. he's lying i'm 40 i'm 45. no i'm
definitely not 16. definitely not
um
you know but
but you know i mean and i'll say the
same thing too because i just saw uh on
my buddy who i was talking to earlier
today uh skunk the
skunk vas on the thing right
i go to ron's party and i am so hoping
to meet
all these legendary people and strains
and [ __ ] and i'm like just hoping to get
hooked up you know
and not to be a dick but like i felt
like i had the chem dog and i had the
super skunk and i had the mendo i felt
like i had the best weed there
yeah i was like i had me that tore
people's head off
yeah you know
and and uh
you know it's not to be bragging or
anything like that because it was
literally just the luck of the draw and
the luck of my friends yeah
you know um
and uh and dead tour you know was one of
those things where
um
it was it was sort of like a huge weed
emporium
yeah and it made a lot of these
connections
and it made a lot of these things that i
tied in and the whole reason i came out
to mendocino county
um was because i had a buddy who lived
in ukiah which is in the heart of mendo
um who after 215 past was like dude get
the [ __ ] out here why are you living in
chicago
yeah so it was literally connections
from dead tour that like brought me out
here right
so
getting back to what i was saying is
that
in northern california and in dead shows
there was a weed scene
and on the forums it developed a weed
scene
and in the emerald triangle there was
kind of a weed scene right
and then these parties and these events
and stuff was sort of like the first
mixers
yeah they were the first places where
these scenes started to like overlap
where the forum scene and the mendo and
humboldt scenes and the grateful dead
scenes and all these different groups
that have ties to different circles they
start like a venn diagram the circles
start crossing
yeah and i honestly think that's set up
kind of everything for the american weed
scene for later
i think so i really do like none of us
knew it at the time
no by any means it wasn't like we're
like oh we're here for history you know
it was just it but it did it was it was
the merging of things i mean i should
say even back then this was a few years
after ron's parties but
like um
you know i mentioned the purple effects
that's in the uh that's in the can of
bible
maybe i should talk about that for a
second because people might be
interested in that
uh the purple the purple part of purple
effects is just mendo perks right yes
and the effects was this old garlic
blood strain
that i got from uh the head grower who
worked for tim blake
yeah now tim blake now is very famous
because he's the founder of emerald cup
but back then he was just a big uh
guerrilla outdoor indoor
farmer
yeah and his his main worker was about
my age they are the purple effects and
they gave me the effects which was a
super golden
gorgeous frosty terpe thing right yeah
and uh
you know there wasn't any reversals but
how the the purple effects got made
um
in the can of bible is that
i had a system that got a little
stressed because i had an air
conditioner issue and it took me a few
days to get it fixed
and you know as as csi will tell you you
stress the mendo perps and the [ __ ]
will harm yeah right so the mendo perps
hermed all over the effects that was
right next to it
and me and a buddy got about a thousand
seats
jesus 800 to a thousand i mean at the
time we were hella pissed and the reason
we got that many was because we had like
these six or seven you know quarter
pound six ounce you know effects plants
all around it
that we couldn't sell
yeah they were chock full of [ __ ]
seed
but we cracked this thing and it ends up
being super terpy
um
you know and all that and it ended up in
the can of bible it was gorgeous weed
um and you know i should say that
there's been some battles amongst the
crew we'll talk about that too but
um some of that weed exists still i
don't have it i lost it in a bust but
some of that weed exists still and it's
in
um it's in the rose
it's in the sprite
um it got passed around at some of tim
blake's early and you know people should
know that tim blake had this spot called
area 101 in uh north of leightonville
right yeah and he threw a bunch of weed
events up there and he threw um a bunch
of like essentially like weird raves and
different kinds of like musical
gatherings and and all that kind of
stuff and it was kind of like a scene
and you know the first half a dozen
emerald cups
were all super local events held there
yeah
um and so i passed out a bunch of seed
there was a gentleman that used to work
up there and used to work at reggae a
bunch called fuzzy
um that's not his real name but that's
his nickname
and uh
you know and all that and stuff and so
you know he ended up getting the purple
effects from me and and that's who the
you know tony mendo and those guys got
it from
yeah and it got blended into skittles
and it got got all these different
things you know and it lives today
yeah you know uh now but that was a
total that was before femmes that was
literally an unintentional
fuck-up uh where in summertime the ac
went out for two days
yeah and you know it got hot and then i
put a new ac in and everything was good
and then the mendo p just threw through
pollen
yeah and i had a and i had a feminized
cross
um people are asking what about
california black rose as far as i know
it's the same thing same thing um so
what happened to them
is like a lot of cannabis terms
uh rose is trademarked
yeah rose is a very specific kind of
wine
and there's also another
c company that has a totally different
line called rose as well relentless and
that's not related to i don't think it's
related to the same diamond greek one
but uh don't quote me now that i think
about i don't know but it was very
different so they had to change it uh
because they got because as you get
legal
and you start entering these things and
stuff you start getting sued
yeah you know girl scout cookies and
thin mint is cookies because they got
[ __ ] sued by the girl scouts
yeah you know the reason why skittles
has z's
yeah you know is they're trying to skate
around these these trademark laws right
so
rose is russian og
crossed with skittles that's the z
across the purple effects that's the e
and it took second place i don't know
three four years ago or whatever at the
emerald coast
so what i got out of them and this this
one's been i think i have a screenshot
of it there's russian kush oz kush
effects cross back to skittles is the
claim yeah something like yeah yeah so
it's getting close to that but they had
the the seeds that they had were purple
effect seeds from from fuzzy that was
from me
yeah because back then it was like there
wasn't any
i mean in this same time frame um i
should say this too but you know uh my
buddy from uh
me and and uh uh skunk va's old friend
who um with the chems and stuff we were
working on these superdog projects
together and crossing them to all kinds
of different hybrids and and clone only
as we had
um and my buddy mandelbrot
uh at the time who wasn't into seeds or
breeding wanted to get started with weed
and i ended up giving him a bunch of
seeds and a bun and some clones to get
him started on this project and he ended
up becoming pretty well known
um some of the stuff he got famous for
was based off that work some of it was a
little different from different things
yeah um but the
the reason i brought that up isn't to
like lay claim it's to say that back
then we were very free with trading
things
yeah because no one ever thought that
they could come out of the woodwork and
lay claim to anything yeah
yeah right
yeah that wasn't a worry
now it's all like [ __ ] you you can't
breed with my my cut that's mine that's
my seed line i want matt knows this more
than me because
um i i've avoided so far a lot of the
weed politics by giving away a bunch of
seeds for free
yeah and when you sell seeds like matt
uh you end up getting you know i want
half the seeds because you use my cut in
this one cross
i want rep i want you to mention me i
want you to give me money
uh it's my [ __ ] you don't have
permission
so many blow jobs i've had to give just
because of seeds it's not fair it's not
fair yeah it's not you know i mean do
what you love do what you love so that's
what i'm good at so yeah yeah i mean so
there you know there's an aspect of
politics but this was before that
politics yeah people just swapped seeds
people just swapped
you know people just swapped cuttings
people swapped you know all this
different stuff it wasn't like you know
you didn't want your name attached to
weed
yeah because then they'd [ __ ] find
you what the [ __ ] is that
yeah it's ridiculous you know you be you
you get you getting [ __ ] you get you
get in trouble
yeah right you don't want anything named
after you what the [ __ ] is crazy you
know yeah and then and now it now it's
come full circle it's 180 degrees and
now it's like
someone's like i didn't breathe this cut
but i did make it famous so therefore if
you're making any money off it you must
give me money
the rule of the mac
and it's yeah and it's it's in my terms
yeah you know i want seeds i want money
i want rep i want all three
and all this different stuff but it's
just like those things
i mean it's even like you know people
were asking way earlier on the thing
that i have to sign a disclosure for dj
yeah dj came up with all that all that
this is my [ __ ] you can't do anything
with it way [ __ ] later
yeah yeah at the time there was no
at the time there was no i mean people
should give credit you know i mean i
just saw uh homie mentioned that people
should give credit you should say that i
got this from this person you know you
also should um if you got a cut from
somebody um you should give it back to
them if they lose it
yeah that's really good etiquette you
know um i've had multiple things that
i've lost
and i've tried to get back from people i
i mentioned the purple effects that's
one of them that exists i can't get it
back without trading other things for it
yeah which i think is uh super shady and
a breach of the code
at least the code when i came up
um you're definitely supposed to
do that there's some honor i mean half
the reason people trade things is so you
don't lose things
yeah because angry girlfriend angry
boyfriend bust fire landlord moving
accident
whatever
you know
all those different types of things
um
you know you you trade things back
amongst people you know yeah i mean one
of the reasons you know i'll say this
because he's because he's listening or
whatever but i mean one of the reasons
why the chem 91 didn't get lost
yeah was because there was a tight group
of uh you know four or five of us
myself uh skunk va i see collective my
buddy from staten island who all had it
and all lived in norcal
and you know we all kept it alive
you know people sometimes people got in
trouble some people had to move
sometimes you had to get back from
somebody or whatever
and it was like we were all heavily
invested
in making sure these things lived
you know yeah i mean that's that's why a
lot of these cuts are still in our group
you know like in our our tight circle
because
you know we all
move around we all [ __ ] yeah you know
he said he's just saying i'll just say
i'll just say this uh and i gotta keep
thinking because i keep wanting to say
his name but skunk yeah i like i have a
hard time bullshitting at pace and
reading comments at the same time
um yeah i mean he did you know he
you know um you know there were some
people that lost it i mean my whole name
you know he just said that i had to give
ic back the cut like five times
yeah my whole name not so dog is because
our buddy from staten island drove up to
cic collective
and got a bag of dog and brought it back
and it wasn't the dog because
dude was dude dude used to party and he
got mixed up and mixed up his clones and
he grew a whole room of chem dog and it
was like romulan or something like that
you know it really was
we had to give it to him back because he
was like what do you mean it's not it it
has to be you know and i'm like no dude
it's not so dog it's not it we had to
call him up and homie was all excited
he's like i've never seen it look like
this you know
and i was like the reason why he's
everybody i stuck my head in the bag
because i was in the bag i was in the
car with staten island i told it before
and i looked up and i'm like there's not
some dog it's not dog i don't know what
you're talking about you're tripping
you know and
you know that island today
that's crazy this is good because they
you know they used to be
yeah they used to be best friends and
i'm not you know there's and i should
there's aspects to stories i always
leave out because they're personal and i
don't think they're super pertinent
yeah i'm just stoked for us because i
want to get both those [ __ ] on
here at the same time with you
it would be cool to get homie to get to
come talk because a lot of the story
people should know and that people are
like oh not so wasn't there this that
whatever else a lot of the stories i
have
um you know
come from staten island or come from
skunk va
talking to them 20 plus years ago
yeah before the forums before the fame
before he got on and got his handle
skunk va you know before the cut was
getting traded when it was just our
little crew that had it
yeah you know honestly like they don't
come from me
they come from my memory of like what i
remember about sitting around shooting
the [ __ ] and growing weed and and doing
[ __ ] together yeah you know
um it would be it would be a really neat
uh thing to do
um both to bridge that gap between the
two of them and get them to talk back
and forth you know yeah um and you know
we've been trying to get dude on here
for a long time actually
i'm trying to get skunky too he's just
so shy he's kind of a he's kind of he's
kind of prickly but i mean i him and i
were him and i were you know me and um
and him and and skunk va we've all known
each other a long time
yeah really a long time way back and so
you know at certain point you know you
bury the hatchet about different things
um it's hard you know it's hard it's
it's hard being in weed and having all
these like interpersonal you know you
mix business and friendship
yep
you know and people have different
memories about [ __ ]
yeah you know and all that so
uh
you know it uh but yeah it's good i i
spoke to uh
uh right before the show actually um
uh skunk va and i were talking ab uh
chatting back and forth a bunch via text
about some stuff and uh we have a ray of
hope
on something that we maybe thought was
long lost so
if it's if it so develops i'll report
back
um but that's what that's what we try to
do it's like old friends trying to look
out for one another yeah you only make
it through this world you know the
people are much more important at the
end at the end of the day than the money
or the fame or the [ __ ]
yeah i'm i'm big into people
you know i need enough money to survive
you know but i'm big into people
yeah you know
so
um it's i like to see my friends doing
good i like to see and we've all you
know all of us are like semi-autistic
weed nerds in some way or whatever you
know and like you it's odd you know
living alone or living by your you know
living amongst uh you know small groups
of people
and living weed and taking a bunch of
risks and staying secret for a long time
like me showing my face is [ __ ] nuts
yeah
you know and now i show it weekly
you know and
you know so i just i just thought it
would be it would be cool because this
era is like right before kind of matt
came into things
yeah
which is like i apologize because i keep
trying to get
uh shows done where i make it like more
matt's era than mine
um because there's my arrows were like
smaller then
there's an era where like you know i was
having a bunch of kids and had some
issues or whatever and
and matt was super engaged
uh when i was a little less engaged but
so far i you know i'm gonna drag him
kicking and screaming into his era
where it's mostly him talking and me
shutting up but he keeps making us do
these things where it's it's a little
older stuff
yeah i think i think it's a lot too
because i've been you know doing the
live feed for a long time and i think
for
this many years i think people are more
excited to hear from someone else for a
bit and i i'm excited to hear like from
an era i wasn't a part of and i think
nobody gives a [ __ ] to hear what i have
to say about something i wasn't a part
of and i don't either so i think it's
it's it's not just about my ego on this
thing i think it's good to to get all
aspects of history on here and you know
there's a thing too where it's like i
mean we didn't know back in the day
that the chem dog was gonna become super
famous
uh yeah it stayed alive um because our
buddy from staten island used to take it
to
like you could meet him outside of any
jerry show outside the war field and
probably buy a 400 ounce
yeah you know um you know all that you
could
uh you know
um when's when jerry garcia died you
know um and he decided to and and you
know skunk va came back to california
you know he got cuts from homie and he
started he started growing because all
of a sudden he was settled down
he wasn't traveling and seeing shows and
stuff and that's where some of his
polaroids come from of that old skunk
cut
you know and you know small group of us
were growing the dog and we were always
we called it you know no one called the
chem 91 and all that that's all like
later we all called it the dog
yeah and you know uh skunk va and our
buddy from staten island they mostly
grew organic um so they didn't want to
call their weed chem
yeah they weren't gonna call it the chem
dog
i think that picture i think that
picture of the super skunk for me at
least
and what i'm interested in is one of the
most important pictures that anybody
could have kept that and some of the
josh dog pictures
um yeah those are specifically the
shower picture and or pictures of sour
pictures the old super skunk super super
[ __ ] important for solving that weird
mystery of like was this super skunk cut
the same as the original super skunk cut
that was hard that was hard to figure
out yeah and uh that helped a lot i mean
there's a thing too like part of the you
know we don't need to go over it again
um but we'll talk about it just really
briefly we were talking about like ron's
parties and these and the triangle and
the dead scene and all that i mean the
whole reason that the francine um got
taken out east and you know the super
skunk came west and all that stuff was
all because of jerry shows
yeah that our friend and and skunk va
were at
and friends of his from back east and
smoking weed together at the show and
then people wanting that stuff and so i
don't need to you know i wasn't there i
don't need to tell that part it's you
know that's that's he's told that story
pretty eloquently and stuff like that
but it is it is showing how those
circles overlapped
yeah you know and one led to the other
and stuff like that you know and so
you know huh let's lock in skunk va for
next week next friday's got the aov on
and he will be happy to to be performing
thank you skunk va i don't know if he
said i don't know if he's we locked him
in but if we did
we're gonna
chat again this weekend i have a i have
a line on something i thought was long
lost that's dear to both of our hearts
so i'm trying my damnedest to make sure
i can get it back to all of us uh yeah
we'll see
you know and i do believe
i'm not particularly uh
uh superstitious
um yeah but i do believe in in the
energy of the plant and i do believe in
the universe a bit like making things
come to you and i can say for everyone
out there
uh for me at least the number one way
that you get the cuts that you want and
you get the things that you want in
cannabis is by treating the plant the
right way and having the right
intentions
yeah
that's what i say because that that's
going to a long term that's going to get
the right people to trust you
yeah and that's going to lead to what
you want and i do believe the plant has
an energy
and i do believe the plant wants to uh
wants to
um you know
wants to find people that'll keep it
safe
i agree i really do i don't know there's
not i can't prove it obviously but i
believe that there's collectors out
there and the plant hides
yeah in places where it's hoping that
someone cares about it and isn't just
monetarily attached to it
yeah but loves it
you know and a lot of the things that i
have
um i wouldn't have because i would have
gotten rid of them as soon as they were
unpopular
yeah
but i personally liked them and cared
about them
and then there's friends of mine that
feel the same way and that's why they
have their [ __ ]
you know yeah and so it's it's a general
theme among our friends yeah it's a
theme you know and if you get it's like
you get trusted in circles and
you know maybe we can go into this
there's an aspect of like authenticity
that we were gonna talk about before
right because we are kind of getting an
hour and a half into it so maybe we can
talk a little bit about this and there's
there's aspects of things where
now that i'm being public
okay and i'm starting to tell some of
these stories
um
i should say that there's a lot of
things that maybe like five or ten
percent of the wheat community knows
pretty well
yeah um that becomes difficult where how
do you let the other 90 know
yeah so there's a lot of like accepted
facts among small groups of people that
want to trade this kind of information
right sure and then you want to get it
out there
and you get [ __ ] attacked
yeah and so you know matt can attest
that he tried to get me to do this for a
long ass time and i wouldn't
yeah
right i mean well i mean you were just
watching what happened to me and you're
like [ __ ] that i don't want that in my
life i was also like you know i mean i
did i did caleb's event up in uh uh
that's right
you know and it was like i showed my
face i was in front of a huge crowd yeah
you know of people and i was just like
oh my god you know i mean i didn't give
my real name but it's still at the time
it was difficult
yeah but
what it comes down to is that if
what convinced me to do it
is is like if you don't try to get some
version of the truth out there or what
you believe to be the truth
and it's just going to be overwhelmed by
[ __ ]
yeah right and there's an aspect where
it's like and i really get upset about
it sometimes
where there's this ig thing where people
pile on each other
yeah okay and you know matt's a villain
on ig
yes i want to be to a lot of but to a
lot of people that don't know him in
real life
yeah you know and if we want to fast
forward a bit before kovid um matt and i
there was other friends that helped and
stuff like that so i'm not trying to
just to diss anyone i'm not mentioning
but matt and i and a few other friends
kind of like uh got this idea to throw
what we called like the can illuminati
party yeah and it was sort of kind of
based on ron's old parties and some of
those old gatherings but more modern
yeah and we decided to do it the same
weekend as
emerald cup
you know because um
everybody would be in town
yeah so we rented a huge house
and invited a bunch of people over
on friday and saturday night of emerald
cup
and both years you know we had hundreds
of people come through the house
yeah right and believe it or not nobody
punched matt
no what do you know nobody attacked matt
there's a lot of people that you that
you don't imagine that like respect them
a whole bunch
yeah i don't know about that but they
didn't punch me yeah you know you have a
lot a lot of friends you know there's a
lot of friends you get a bunch of
collectors and breeders and weed nerds
and people in the industry that come
through and want to hang out with each
other
and you got to realize that like we were
trying to throw an event where it's like
those guys spend all day at their
[ __ ] booth
talking to customers and trying to give
their customers a little bit of
one-on-one time
yeah right and then at the at night time
you know they get to come out and hang
with a bunch of people just like them
yeah and trade weed amongst people just
like them and shoot the [ __ ] and you
know trade cuts and talk about [ __ ]
and do all this various [ __ ] you know
yeah and so we really had a good time
those couple of years before kobe [ __ ]
it all up
yeah that was fun dude yeah we had you
know we had a lot of people we had you
know csi and bodhi and connor i mean you
could go there was hundreds of people
there
yeah a who's who not everybody but a lot
of people you know some people were busy
or burned out or whatever you know
yeah
and so we were trying to recreate some
of those like more innocent time parties
yeah and
you know and you know and i brought tons
of weed
and various friends brought tons of weed
and we just have like a huge table full
of jars that were labeled and anybody
could freely smoke
yeah whatever they wanted
um and even even like just like the
forums there was a bunch of friends i
made on ig
that some of the first time they smoked
the headband some of the first time they
smoked the real chem d some of the first
time they smoked this different stuff um
was at these parties they might hear you
talk about it but they don't actually
see your wheat
yeah
you know and then they get a chance to
do it then you get to share a bunch of
your weed with friends and you get to do
all these different kinds of things you
know and so
that part is really neat because
that kind of i wish you went too dude
we're gonna have another one after covid
um
you know
there's uh you know it's it's just like
a who's who of people that have been
around for a long time and you would not
believe
how little beef there is
yeah there was none any person
there wasn't any beef it was just a
bunch of friends it was smoking out
eating a bunch of food having a great
time you know trading beans trading cuts
making connections putting faces to
names right yeah
all that different types of stuff
right and so
you have an aspect where
we've had some issues this week where
you know you start having these talks
week by week and like i said matt's a
bit of a villain online and because now
i'm coming out and we haven't even hit
some of the controversial topics yet but
as i'm coming out and talking about
stuff
um you start getting enemies
you start getting people that are
annoyed that people are listening to you
or not believe your version of events
or you know on ig or on various discords
they want to like disparage your
character and say you weren't around and
say
that you didn't have anything or your
weed was [ __ ] or your seeds suck or
whatever
and honestly like it becomes really hard
because a lot of people that are
listening
you don't know the person you're siding
with and you don't know the person that
you're against in real life yeah
like in an honest real life
yeah no you know so it becomes hard how
do you choose
you know how do you make stuff happen i
mean there was people that were accusing
me this week of not even see the chems
until oh eight
yeah
you know and then i came out of nowhere
and that all my stories are lies and not
so it just means the stories are not so
and let's let's be fair though like
the the people that were doing this were
people that were in the outer circle of
our friend group and never made it quite
on the in circle because they were
they were bad people and they [ __ ]
people over or they did certain things
people haven't seen pretty bad
yeah you know and that's my point right
so matt will come out and say this
person's a scammer he's stealing cuts
he's trying to [ __ ] you over he's trying
to take your money
yeah and then that person and like and
and some bots and like a bunch of fake
accounts and a bunch of people that
bought seeds all attacked matt
yeah you know he's a [ __ ] he's a jew
he's fat he's this he i got oh
nazi he's a knockout jewish nazi all
these various things they're getting
attacked and so as i become a public
figure a little bit like they start
attacking oh is that that party as weed
sucks this and that everything else and
let's find people to throw barbs that's
part of it
yeah right and i'm not even saying you
should trust me but what i am saying is
that
you know weed as a a lot of people lived
in the shadows yeah and it's not
documented and the reason why we're
doing a bunch of these stories
is because we want to get oral history
out there and we want to do it in a
conversational fashion that doesn't bore
you to death
yeah
and we try to do that and then that
steps on toes and then people are
furious
and so they they they can't [ __ ] with
the story
right
um but so they'll [ __ ] with matt or
they'll [ __ ] with me or let's say you're
a liar they say oh i know for a fact he
didn't touch chem until after oh eight
or he didn't have this or his this his
headband is watered down or whatever
they want to say about matt it's just
the 707 yeah just just some [ __ ] and
it's like
you know and it's like you don't want to
spend all your life [ __ ] like
refuting a bunch of [ __ ]
yeah you know because it's like
everybody that knows me
knows me
yeah
you know and matt and vice versa you
know and so we're trying to get truth
out there we're trying to get truth that
like we're not making any money off of
you know a lot of these a lot of these
podcasts are like weed infomercials
here's three hours of why you should buy
my seats yeah let's talk extensively
about you and why you're great and why
you're integral to the story and why
you're a cannabis historian and why
you're so amazing
and this is going to help you make money
[ __ ] i should have been inserting myself
into all this old [ __ ] god damn it yeah
you know and it's like you do need you
know we do plug for two or three minutes
some stuff that matt's doing or you know
csi or different people at times because
there is a financial element to like
making all these different types of
stuff work right to some degree um but
really what it is is that now that i'm
old and i'm in my mid-40s or whatever uh
there might be people that are 23 that
want to hear
yeah or might be 40 and want to hear the
real truth and then eventually you just
have to decide because there are some
real scumbags
yeah that just come out and insert
themselves and then rely on if you speak
up i'll blow up your [ __ ] life and is
it really worth it
yeah i'll attack and attack and attack
and attack and i'll [ __ ] you over and
i'll make your life miserable for weeks
so shut the [ __ ] up about what you all
know
yeah and there's so much of that
honestly and it's coming from so many
[ __ ] angles
like it is a headache
it's rife for shade balls beans have
always been shady and they're not
getting any less shady
yeah
you know they're just not yeah you know
no and there's no way there's but
there's a bunch of us
you know who have been around long
enough
you know i mean there's this running i'm
not gonna call him out or whatever but
like i don't even it was like a super
long time ago and like me and skunk va
were talking about whether or not we
were going to go to these like dead
shows in the city
right and he's telling me he's like man
because he was he's a little older than
me and he was on tour for longer than i
was so he has more connections than i do
to be perfectly frank because he's about
six or seven years older than me um yeah
you know he was like dude we could go
but he's like then i'm gonna see this
guy and i know he doesn't pay his child
support
and i'm gonna see this guy and he owes
my friend 15 grand and i'm gonna see
this other guy and he and you know these
people's backstories and then it's like
you're gonna see some people you're like
so stoked on
yeah and then you're gonna see some
other people and you're just gonna be
like man why can't you be cooler we were
friends
yeah you're kind of a [ __ ]
yeah
pay your kids you know yeah pay your
child support pay my buddy back you
ripped them off when you were down and
out you know yeah and that goes on in
weed world
yes and then uh what city san francisco
at the time at the time both uh him and
i lived in northern california he lived
in sonoma i lived in mendo so we were we
were thinking about going down to sf and
catching some shows at mountain view or
something
um you know and that's the thing is like
a lot of times i'll talk about things in
like a general sense
um because you start calling out
individual people and then the next week
of my life is [ __ ]
that [ __ ] trying to defend themselves
yes
and you know and blowing themselves up
yeah and me and homie matt and i and me
and skunk we know a lot of history
yeah not all of it is not all of it is
is beneficial to the people
no unfortunately but then you can't you
know it doesn't pay to spend your whole
life trying to warn the fam unity
about no jack off because it's
whack-a-mole
yeah i tried that i really did and and
it just it did not pay off it was it was
detrimental to my career
i will say i don't recommend people do
that for
any reason whatsoever if you have a an
interest in being successful
yeah i mean i uh
so yeah you know i mean there's there's
that aspect and so i'm not saying trust
me or trust matt
i'm saying like if you're giving us your
time every friday night you get to talk
to us at length and ask questions and
stuff eventually
you have to maybe you can hear enough of
things that you get a general sense of
who we are
yeah but i will say that ig is an image
and the sociopaths are very very good
at curating an image
yeah you know they do best
and um you know and yeah someone just
said nobody's perfect people aren't
perfect you're right
people aren't
you know um people aren't perfect and
i'm not even trying to judge people
that's why i'm not calling anybody out
by name
yeah i'm just saying a general i'm just
saying a general state of events
i do have someone i was gonna call out
by name but um
it's uh it's getting late and there's
one more big thing i want to i want to
get put aside so it's not just my
opinion i'm actually using their words
um yeah i'm not gonna it's not even a
big enough deal really but it'll just be
funny
or someone i once looked up to
do it
do what
whatever you were about to do or you're
not no no i i still need some of the um
the ultimate details yeah yeah so
because i don't want it just to be my
opinion i want it to be dude's own words
sure no i get it yeah so i mean and
that's kind of what we talk about like
when people are like the can illuminati
you know yeah the can illuminati is not
like some kind of organization or
membership there's no dues you know
there's no one that controls it what it
basically means
is that you're enough of a weed head
that you care enough of the history to
hold on to strains to hold on to seeds
to want to dig for the truth and you
talk to other people like that and it
basically it's a it's a like-minded
group
of people and we know who each other are
and it's like even amongst that group
there's not even really trading
no there's just like dude like once you
know it's like uh you know a skunk va
and i were talking earlier today about
it it's like we're not going to trade
anything
no like it's like oh you need a couple
of these and and i can get you this or
whatever it's it's not like a trade it's
more just like you know
yes this is what i have this is what you
have yeah you know i'm not saying
there's anything wrong with trading
because trading is perfectly acceptable
especially if you don't know each other
but once you've been personal friends
for a couple of decades
yeah it's just friends helping friends
yeah you know and a lot of the ways that
this stuff exists like you know our
history that's really why i'm chatting
is because i don't want all of our
history to be lost
no
i want it to be out there in some kind
of form and it's almost all oral
yeah and and with a lot of the forums
going down over the years whether it be
from the feds you know getting a hold of
the ic mag server to
uh you know can a collective pot pimp
any of the the uh seed depot any of
those that have gone down they had a lot
of uh information on them like c depot a
lot of people that people look at today
as old school heroes and whatnot or
really trustworthy people all popped up
on seed depot and their whole history is
gone because that's that site was gone
the dude disappeared after [ __ ]
everyone over they owned it so um that's
gone but it's in a lot of people's
memories so this is really the only
chance we have to put that out there
yeah and so we're just we're just trying
to we're just trying to like regurgitate
stuff
and get it out there and get different
versions of things
yeah you know
um and
and you know like like anything you know
some of these stories there's people
that have different memories
yeah there's people that have different
versions even like the three or four
people that were there might not tell
the same tale
yeah they were the ones that were there
i know i got a nickname for being a
power bottom at the last party and i'm
pretty sure i was power top pretty sure
you know but i mean it's cool because
then you get then you get you know these
parties these gatherings and stuff they
really are bonding
yeah they really are where human
connections are made
you get to smoke a bunch of your good
friends weed
you get to see them in person you get to
hear what their voice sounds like and
and hear them laugh
you get to break bread and food with
people
you know yeah um and you get to share
weed and share experiences and so i
think that's you know what maybe we can
get the cantaloupe can illuminati
parties together again
uh now that covid seems to be dying down
and there's lots of people that are
either been infected or vaccinated and
it's not so much like the plague yeah it
was for a few years where it was
shutting [ __ ] down
um but those kind of gatherings are
important and so tonight you know we're
almost at two hours so i'll probably
shut up here in a second but
i just wanted to give like a general
random overview of some of the
overlapping things that were happening
in that era
yeah that really set the stage for
everything that came after
yeah it was really where a lot of
friendships were made it was where a lot
of trading and a lot of seed exchange
was done it was where a lot of cuttings
and a lot of people smoking other
people's weed and learning happened and
then a lot of those guys um ended up
becoming super well known in the
community
yeah
you know
um so you know it it it uh
you know but you don't know it at the
time
no that's the that's the funny thing
about history is you don't know if
you're if you're making it you don't
know you know so
um but really what it boils down to is
we're all just people
some of us
care about the plant
yeah uh some of us care about rap and
money and and and you know scamming
people
and there's a big conflict between those
two right now
yeah in the community there's been one
for a long time yeah but it's gotten
more public and i mean even like you
know matt's been doxxed before
you know and even some of those comments
i was referencing we're not going to
mention this week people were saying my
real name
yeah
not that i cared to some degree because
um
it's it you know like i'm showing my
face every week so yeah principle of the
thing though you're not saying your
christian name every week no i'm not
saying my christian name every week or
anything like that you know and so you
know but but what's funny about that is
that i can use that later to prove
something that would like blow them up
in the face
yes
yeah and i've been pushed enough enough
times by this human being to
you know just suck it sucks to have to
do it but because
they're saying such extreme [ __ ] like
there's only a few things in life that i
take real personal is when you talk
about my friends family or you call me a
[ __ ] nazi like
i spent my whole young life
just literally fist fighting nazis and
being punched by them many many many
times so i take it very seriously when
someone accuses me of such things so
yeah and you're here
and i'm a jewish mexican
yeah
there's not there's not too many
nazi jews you know it's kind of unusual
but so anyway matt if you want to do
your plug because we're almost two hours
here or whatever
yeah so we have our patreon it's called
the breeder syndicate patreon the way to
find it is to go to google and type in
breeder syndicate patreon if you go to
patreon and type in breeders senate kid
it's not going to come up because it is
a pop channel and you cannot search pot
channels so go to google type in breeder
syndicate patreon tomorrow i'm going to
be watching fights if you want to you
know hang out and do some fight watching
we could do that
we have uh the the santa cruz goat farm
um
fem lines the the reversed arcade train
wreck lines um up for sale right now on
the site go check them out my boy packs
a [ __ ] killer dude and he made some
killer things including the santa cruz
blue dream um train wreck which i'm
really really stoked to see um
we also have uh me and csi's hawaiian
lights drop i'm about to make the
hawaiian lights hybrids public so
everybody can [ __ ] join in and
and grab that [ __ ] um so go check it out
um yeah so i think i think that's it go
go check out speakeasy
they do all the editing of the podcast
and stuff so um go give them support and
follow and and
i'll just say one thing after matt did
all that you know we're getting up to
200 230 250 people a week now doing this
every every friday
um thank you all for listening
yeah thank you all for taking time out
of your night to [ __ ] with us and
ask questions as always
you can reach reach me on ig you can
message me um
he's been approved improving or
approving people so i've literally
approved like 1500 people this week and
it keeps going if you really want to get
approved send me a message
um and i'll see it and i'll do it faster
for you i'm trying to get through but
everyone i really appreciate you giving
us your some part of your friday night
and we're going to try to get more
topics and more history out there
and keep it fun so thank you all so much
thank you guys uh see you next week
cheers
[Music]
you