foreign
[Music]
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
and by the time by the
by the very first time
when it started to hit me
and I'm like wow
[Applause]
I got high
[Music]
all right so we wanted to start
um an episode talking about the Forum
era because I I was a part of the Forum
era but you guys were a part of
different forums than I was on so you
had a lot of interactions with different
characters and a lot of them are um you
know kind of legendary dudes and and
you've had interactions with guys that
are really really good archivists that I
I have not had the pleasure of
interacting with so I wanted you both to
kind of talk about your introduction to
the forums I mean it's going to be two
different uh stories so uh Rahul you
want to start what was your introduction
to the forums
uh you know early 2000s I I discovered
that people had started using the
internet for weed and I was shocked
you can imagine right I mean I'd I'd
um anyway I I looked around I was doing
a business trip out to Amsterdam and and
I I knew that's where the weed was so I
figured I should try this new tool and
try and find stuff about coffee shops
and stuff and and
um you know that was basically it I was
scared I was scared to be on any site
that talked about weed back then
um you know the early 2000s were time
before proxy uh servers were out there
and so you know having having anonymity
of any kind on the web was really a
pretty fuzzy idea for for most people
and you know a lot of people just went
up there boldly you know um with a you
know fake name and and keeping their
fingers crossed that nobody's gonna put
a sniffer on the line and start tracking
traffic and grabbing IPS but you know it
really wouldn't be it was you know just
painfully simple for for tech people to
to really get some useful information
back then if they wanted to
um
you know I finally got over my fear and
said you know screw it I'm going up
there and uh my my Landing
uh spot of choice was Mr Nice so I've
been I've been kind of looking at
different forums out there for
um you know the community how people
treated each other the knowledge level
you know figured it out real quick that
a lot of these places were organized
around specific companies so that they
were you know they were just the
marketing uh communication site for
their customers and and the company
themselves and but you know there was
bias in every one of these places and
sure
Mr Nice had a great you know had a great
story about you know this is straight
the original stuff from Neville you know
in a world of imitators we got the
original stuff and we're the only place
that still makes it the way they they
always were co-signed by Howard marks
too uh Howard marks right and and you
know who had nothing to do with the
Neville you know back doing that stuff
but but you know I mean super cool guy
in you know R.I.P we we don't miss him
but um yeah I mean you know it was the
best story out there and and uh what I
didn't realize is that there were like
Wars going on between these between
these different forums for the different
companies you know Scentsy Mr Nice had
had people who were going on like rate
what appeared to be like raiding parties
to other people's forums going and
posting a bunch of troll noise and
stirring up trouble then running away
you know it was the equivalent of of you
know kids at a school dance you know
afraid to go talk to the girls on the
other side of the but you know they were
all defending their their Legends you
know their myths that that you know the
story The the foundation story between
our seed lines is cooler and and older
than the founder Foundation story for
your old seed lines and you know that's
really nothing's changed you know in in
20 years with that regard
you know the story cell pictures cell
you know just now before all we had to
worry about was the story being a lie
but now these days I mean the pictures
are
geez man it's like they don't even need
a plant to start with by the time they
start photoshopping everything up like
that yeah I mean with AI that's actually
a thing now like the AI can develop
cannabis plants so all these guys like
they don't really even have to put any
effort into testing really oh you need a
new picture here AI done yeah you know
so I don't know I mean Mr Nice was a
great place
um you know the these it's volatile up
there you're dealing with people who are
you know taking a chance with their
their safety and and uh you know their
livelihoods and by posting up there on
the on the internet trying to make a
connection with somebody else who you
know who's into the same stuff they are
and it's uh you know sometimes people
get really stressed out
um they they start worrying and getting
paranoid about their security up there
and you see people just kind of flip out
and run away
um you know it happens it happens even
today oh yeah you know
but um yeah Mr Nice was great I I know
that most most Old-Timers were up on
overgrow and and cannabis world and some
of these other forms I I came in right
when overgrow was about to get raided so
I was like yeah I started sniffing
around I was like hey maybe this is it
maybe this is the time yeah right right
I almost signed up I might have even
created a profile just before just
before they got raided I'm not yeah
yeah yeah so you came you came in about
the same time I did then right around
the 2006 2007 era
uh yeah as far as reading you know yeah
online reading and stuff like that yeah
no accounts no no longer okay no PM no
nothing just pure pure um
uh what do you call it stalking or
whatever yeah lurking lurking I was a
big time lurker that's the man cyber
creep is what we call him I mean
Echo what what raho was saying um I also
I did not know very much about computer
technology or how it was tracked and I
always felt like it was a risk and so I
was sort of like scared to look at
overgrow in cannabis world but I was
also like a a fly to Honey or something
like I couldn't resist so yeah I just
tried to avoid like trading or doing
business on there or like telling too
much about my personal life because like
I remember like to speak of of Mr Nice
or Howard marks I remember reading his
autobiography and he said one of the
worst things he ever did was set up like
a switchboard in Amsterdam that he
thought was going to be smooth to like
clear all his calls through like that
just allowed the American government to
listen to everything I was I was saying
yeah it was like the worst decision I
ever made but I was trying to
consolidate things and so I had no idea
about ipns or vpns or any of that stuff
that Raha was mentioning back then I was
not computer savvy in that sense so I
had no idea if like a interested party
could just pop up and see my address
yeah but
um overgrow and and cannabis world were
kind of different in the sense that I
would say that like overgrow uh had like
a wider range of participants so it had
like way more like [ __ ] posting
teenagers yelling at you but then it
also had like Sam Skunk Man and Camara
and like different really Heavy Hitters
at the time posting on the Breeders you
know the Breeders lab and and that kind
of thing and you know
um Mad Jack you were you know you were
showing off some of the the art that uh
you know existed back then that like
Growers would put on their their
products and you know Sam was showing
off his collection you know one time of
all the different art that he had
collected of the you know the localized
and stuff and so that I found
fascinating
um cannabis world had a little bit more
like adult discourse it was smaller and
it was policed a little bit better as
far as not police like by cops but
police by like members yeah where they
didn't allow quite as much rudeness and
quite as much like you know throwing poo
at one another
um and all that and you know it was
interesting then too because it really
documented well like the switch from
Amsterdam to Switzerland
um when breeder Steve and Shanti and a
bunch of those guys transferred from
Holland over to uh the big Swiss and
that was in a lot of people's cases that
was the first time they ever saw large
grows yeah
um you know like greenhouses full Acres
of that type of thing I mean there was
obviously some select people that had
done that themselves uh but for the most
part people first saw that on cannabis
world and
um you know and we learned a lot I mean
and that was also to what rajo was
saying Sam Skunk Man had about four or
five different handles uh he was know it
all for sure he was Jingles he was Sam
Skunk Man and you started getting people
that got started getting very vocal
about their version of their narrative
yeah and pushing that narrative very
hard and what we've learned over time
with the forums is that the people that
are often and early they you know
typically
um that becomes sort of like you know
cannabis lore yeah right and there's a
lot of people that might add more Nuance
to it but the people that were willing
to get out there and type it up and put
their story out first
it carried a lot of weight that people
were willing to do that we um we had an
example earlier before you popped on
where um we were talking about the chem
dog story and we popped up an old uh a
graph of like you know chem 91 chemd and
then the maybe chem four I think and it
was like the tree of lineage of things
that had been crossed to it and what was
related to it and stuff and that lore
has been there for ages and even you
know the other day we brought it up that
things are always fluid and changing as
we learn new things so yeah so it was a
good example of it
foreign
you know one thing that I I think we
should mention too is that so I live I
live in Mendocino County which is like
tons of people grow weeds so yeah I was
able to hang out with folks
um and talk weed a lot all day long is
just part of my daily life but the
forums what was so attractive about the
forums in my opinion was it was the
first time that like nationally and
internationally people could talk and
there was a lot of people that started
talking from you know places that were
much more sketchy back then uh police
States if you will states that didn't
have any medical didn't have any
recreate didn't have any of that yeah um
and so for a lot of those people the
only place they felt safe to talk about
it was online
they didn't talk about it with their
friends they didn't talk about it with
their neighbors there might be a tiny
percentage of people that even knew what
they were up to but if they were weed
nerds they had this burning desire to
chat about it
and online provided a semi-anonymous way
to shoot the [ __ ] about cannabis
and it was really interesting for a lot
of people because before then it was
just small circles and groups and you
know and friendships and you know you
really didn't see how the other half was
living
and pay phones and pay phones
so mad Jack what was your what was your
first form experience what what brought
an old vet like you onto the scene to to
mess with the the newer generation
well when Arizona went medical I got my
green card in 2012. and because I was
more than 25 miles from the nearest
dispensary I was able to it said license
to cultivate so I could grow my six
plants in my backyard or 12 whatever it
was and
I felt relieved because I was doing it
semi-legal I mean you always supposed to
have an enclosure with eight foot walls
and one inch thick metal door some crazy
yeah regulations but I decided mine was
safe enough close enough and I started
searching online
I had done quite a bit of research
already on weed just to see what was on
the internet probably starting back
I don't know I would go to a store in
Sedona they had a T1 line and a T1 was
like Fast yeah it was the best
this is during dialogue days and the
dial up at home if you were trying to
even look at one photo you would wait a
minute so a single naked lady took
forever
so going going to the this video store
that also had T1 lines they had little
booths where you could get on the
internet and it was fast I could do in
one hour what would take me five at home
yeah and it cost I think it was nine
dollars an hour
14 is their T1 and somehow
I've then I started
well that was the early stuff but later
once I got my license in medical I
thought
I wonder what the seed world's like and
I started looking around and I found Mr
Nice Forum of Mr Nice seeds
and some of the original people on there
like sensimilla
um and a few others became sort of
friends you know I talked to them on
on the uh Forum there
and that's where I met rahu he had a
different handle at that time and one
thing led to another then I went and I
discovered icy mag and I joined in 2012.
and the same year
and
a little time went by and then I think
it was Elmer Bud it was either Rahul
rahu you remember it was either you or
Elmer that invited me to this other
Forum called for myself I can say that
the the thing that was so crazy for me
about
um Mr Nice specifically was I I think it
was I can't remember if it was 09 or
2010 but all of a sudden Neville popped
up on there and started answering
questions yeah and I was like oh my God
you can just talk to him and you can ask
him all these burning things that I
wanted to know about and then there was
people like um he went by dog list but
there was you know Ortega there was some
other various like Heavy Hitters from
that zone that like once they realized
Neville was on there they joined too
yeah and then and Yosemite Sam from
Amsterdam and then so as as some of
those real people started joining there
was an ERA there from probably I don't
know 2009 to maybe 2011 or something
where all of a sudden for me being a
younger guy compared to those guys you
could listen to some of the Giants talk
about Maple Leaf or talk about this or
you could ask Neville questions directly
about some of his lines and he'd give
you answers and where he got the and you
know Seattle Greg was posting on there
about the NL and all of a sudden you had
this collection of you know of sort of
like what I call like first generation
you know Growers and breeders and
Hustlers and movers and shakers all
communicating and you could read what
they were talking about to each other
yeah it's it's still there that's that's
such an awesome well and uh so you know
and and then so I kind of felt like I
was a fly on the wall and I started
screaming you know I started saving
basically every novel post and every you
know of course it starts all the
arguments and the back and forths and
like the are you telling the truths and
like the do you remember this the right
way type of deal
um and but yeah that that was what was
so fascinating to me about Mr nice was
that all of a sudden all these cannabis
like Legends
uh pretty much everyone with the
exception of Sam
yeah no Sam would have we would have
they were talking about the wars earlier
like me and a few others would go invade
icmag and and do the JibJab memes like
the fake Kung Fu ones uh representing
Neville and it would be like arguments
between Neville and Sam and we would
post those on icmag and they'd come back
on Mr Nice and post theirs over on ours
it was like uh yeah it was a full-on war
that was the first that was the first
time I saw you Matt you know met where
it met you online anyway and yeah you
know I but you know not so you're right
that was a magic moment at Mr Nice when
Neville came back there and you know the
ability of any member to just pop in and
asking questions and you know what just
and the attraction how how people could
not stay away like you mentioned Chimera
and
um you know Matt was there of course
um
who wants a dogless Tempe
heavy and big and big herb and there was
yeah big herb was definitely there there
was a lot of people that were that were
involved and like Kanga kangavida and
when I when I first got when I first
started really meeting people in
Amsterdam I realized that like there was
a bunch of older guys that had beefs
with each other that didn't get along
exactly and they had their versions of
events and then they would just continue
said war on whatever Forum got created
this is my story and then they'd be like
no no no that's ridiculous this is what
happened you're so full of it and there
was these camps that would form on like
Matt and I joke about it of like which
Shady character do you believe more yeah
because you could poke holes in any of
us really to somebody yeah you know
and uh but yeah that was dogless dogless
was Ortega you know
um and you know he gave Neville four or
five super important lines
um that still remain there's a lot of
mystery to them
um but just watching those older guys
communicate with each other and dropping
things that that were maybe normal to
them but were gems to us was a was a
pretty magical time that era of Mr Nice
forums was pretty cool yeah yeah and and
of course like like you mentioned there
were other other people that weren't big
shots at the time but turned into big
you know people that that we've all
heard of today
um and had valuable things and valuable
Insight you know to add to like you know
what what what was Santa Cruz like in
that early late 60s early 70s era what
was this going on in some different
depth to things and so there was some
really intelligent cannabis conversation
going on uh in those years right there
that was pretty cool
yeah a lot of it sadly some of those old
Neville posts have been
disappeared manicured yeah they're
getting they're getting cleaned up to to
help with the Clutter yes on it I think
yeah anything anything contrary you know
um last night did you see that when I I
think I texted it to you last night not
so it was a screenshot of a post from
Shanti
saying that uh nordl is super skunk oh
yeah he did that on IG two days ago or
something like that is that confusing to
you at all uh it wasn't so much
confusing I mean the the problem that
you have with anyone not just Shanti but
with anyone is that you get their
version of what's going on and do you
have others that will can corroborate
like what they're talking about you know
and it's like you know I know for a fact
we know for a fact that Sean that
Neville sold a huge amount of seeds to
to Shanti and that they worked together
and did various things together for a
period of time
and so there's this no seed company that
I'm aware of has ever admitted that
they've ever lost anything ever uh and
Simon Simon has admitted he's lost the
parents to Kelly Mist I believe but it
just in general in general you know like
I think this is what's crazy is you guys
is that like if you go on Scentsy seeds
website right now they still have
Neville photos from the 80s yeah as
their description you know for their
depicts for their descriptions of their
lines and those and those photos were
taken in 1988 1989 and 1990. yeah and
they're still the same ones that's not
even the worst part though I mean then
you read the stories and it makes it
sound like the dronkers climbed their
way through the Himalayas to get meet
the farmers you know and they personally
brought it back you know they in a CIA
helicopter you know I mean it's just
it's Neville was insane Neville was the
only one to admit yeah we lost that yeah
this died yeah this changed that was my
fault and the rest of them almost
universally are like that makes
identifying things difficult because
um you know they people obviously don't
want to admit that they lose certain
things because they want those modern
sales right you know it goes beyond that
though I mean let's assume that the cuts
got lost but so what did they have to
dig through to replace it you know or
that you know of course they never admit
that they lost anything okay so we'll
take that for granted and then then we
assume okay they they won't admit it but
we know they've lost something so what
did they have to work with to to to pick
The Replacements themselves you know in
the case of Neville he did you know he a
lot of the posts that were deleted were
talking about indicas and his breeding
work with indicas yeah and uh which is
is interesting because I haven't seen
that instant post that you're talking
about where they're they're claiming
that that nordl is uh Super Skunk yeah
but you know you can see that this is
one of those things where it's partially
true you know so the parents of Super
Skunk Afghan T and and skunk one are
contained in normal yep sure no doubt
but do we think it's pure Afghan t plus
plus skunk uh one probably not no right
no I mean oh how we wish it was right
but it's not and Neville in those old
posts that are now missing you know
talked about how he mixed he crossed all
of those Maple Leaf
um cuttings together yeah you know he
had the ort 15 the Afghan s Afghan T and
big bud Kush 4 and one that was a big
bud like yeah he called it big bud but
it was not the big bud strain right
correct so it's like go ahead go ahead
and answer I always view Shanti as a bit
like the the The Bridge Troll or the
Sphinx that wants you to answer the
three riddles and so you know you're
like just give it to me clear and he'll
just like you know he'll dance around
the topic
you know and so you know we know
um one of the interesting things that we
found out is that we weren't exactly
sure how large The Collection that he
bought off Neville was and apparently
it's so large that people involved think
that he couldn't even get through it in
a lifetime if he wanted to wow yeah so
then it really just becomes about like
does he have the eye and does he have
the selections because he has the
genetics it's just he you know how many
mothers does he have how many fathers
does he have is he pulling them out of
f2s you know I agree completely but
there's actually something even more and
does is he even doing the selecting
himself anymore yeah sure yeah exactly I
mean uh because
I don't know I've seen some I've seen
some people working
Ortega and and some other some other
fresh seeds from them that don't look
the the phenos that I saw you know 15
well 10 10 years ago are not in there
anymore yeah right and I was like dude I
don't know I need to tell you if if we
would have known if I would have known
that basically every five or ten years
the seed game completely changes and
what you thought would be available for
a long time has now disappeared forever
um you know Matt and I were looking at
uh we I have a friend with a freezer
that got out of the game and gave all of
his seeds to a good friend of ours and
most of most of those seeds are from
2009 to 2012.
and Matt and I were just shocked that
like maybe one percent of those seeds
are still available today if you wanted
to buy them yeah yeah so you know the
the Neville era the Scentsy ERA this the
serious era like all these different
seed companies maybe they have the same
stock for four or five years right and
then something happens like we know that
Shanti got raided in in Switzerland what
did he lose then
what did he have before what did he have
after in a lot of those cases
um they don't it doesn't benefit them in
any way to like be completely up front
so then they're not
you know yeah
um yeah and and I've been we've been
trying to get Shanti to admit for years
if nordal was his version of super skunk
and he never would
up until do you remember do you remember
um raho when this strain came out
because it was originally another strain
that he had listed and I think it was
just called Afghan skunk at the time and
he said I'm changing this to nordl in
honor of
I can't remember what it was [ __ ] in
honor of maybe the Mr Nice movie coming
out yeah it was the code name that um
Howard marks used to describe a load of
hash but I think it was because the
movie was coming out in UK and he
renamed it in honor of the movie because
in the movie they make that a big deal
okay I remember correctly the context of
that too because I met uh Neville uh
briefly a few times and one of his
Partners in the 90s in Amsterdam and
after he left Scentsy he had to call
Super Skunk Ultra skunk
because Sensei had trademarked the names
to most of his genetics yeah and so
therefore since he owned the name super
skunk and so from the time he I mean I
remember because I bought some Ultra
skunk he had to call it Ultra skunk
um and so in in that case if Shanti was
going to sell his version he literally
couldn't sell Super Skunk the only
people that can sell Super Skunk in
Holland are Scentsy seeds
because they bought they owned the um
they they trademarked almost all the
names yeah to be honest I'm kind of
shocked he didn't like throw devil in
there and [ __ ] and like all the other
stuff that are like Afghan skunks you
know
so there's so I do give shauncey a
little bit of slack in the sense that he
has to be it's hard to it's hard to say
some of these things because there are
there is some legality and that's what's
kind of going on now too is people are
starting to try to patent names in
America in different areas and different
regions and being like oh well we have
this name
um and you know uh but it's interesting
too like um you know like the one name
that they didn't for some reason they
don't have a patent on an L5 Haze
but they do on super skunk
yeah that's probably the Illuminati has
something to do with that yeah yeah the
can Illuminati
yeah and then and then and then they
patented all the NL names
you know so they had to call the NL
stuff different work
yeah that's why that's why I believe was
it Dutch Passion Matt they had to call
their nl2 version Oasis yeah I believe
so we'll find out we'll find out they
they seem to be open to talking and yeah
I will say Dutch Passion um out of all
the Dutch companies I've ever reached
out to Dutch passions like been open to
sending me their old catalogs scanning
them in like helping with the archive so
I'm stoked to interview them because
they have an actual genuine interest in
the culture and I remember like they
they were actually have been at the
Forefront of some cannabis technology
um I want to ask them about their
artificial seeds they were the first to
push artificial seeds and and sell those
and some of their clone clonal strains
as artificial seeds and uh it
disappeared I don't know if they only
tried it in Europe for a while but it
was it was so far ahead of its time this
is like 2012 when they were doing
artificial seeds so I even think they
were the first person I ever saw talk
about feminized work I think there are
some of the first that we're selling
feminized before Americans you know
people like you Matt or CSI I think they
coined the terms
some of the first people that were
involved on the American side of things
I think I first saw it from Dutch
Passion offering up
you know feminized
Bitcoin the term I didn't know anybody
ever made some of the sold some of those
artificial seeds which is basically uh
tissue culture right and a tiny little
capsule is that basically the idea yeah
some sort of Mary stem or whatever some
kind of colonial tissue yeah some kind
of tissue I remember Camaro was talking
about that and I was like yeah this is
another thing I'm never gonna see yeah
yeah yeah I was super stoked when they
started doing it but the problem is
because it's a
um it's it is tissue culture not
everyone can get these things to quote
unquote germinate you know I mean it
takes real genuine care and yeah you
don't just throw it out in the yard and
set up the sprinkler you know I mean the
idea was that you like yeah the idea was
that you could hopefully like plant it
under dirt and it'll just grow but I
mean people have enough time hard time
popping normal seeds let alone
artificial seeds you know well he was
talking about that stuff about the same
time that he was doing his massive clone
collecting
all over North America who's that
Chimera yeah yeah he was talking about
oh we're going to make these artificial
seeds it's going to be tissue culture
and we'll preserve them forever you know
it gave everybody the idea idea that he
was going to be
the dude repository of all this precious
germplasm for the rest of the world you
know and he's going to out of the
goodness of his heart I will say that
when I was reading on the Breeders lab
on overgrow
that Camara was one of the most
intimidating people on there at the time
I was probably in my early 20s then and
uh the depth of like breeding knowledge
that he had like in the education that
he had and sort of like the
ego and dismissiveness that he had like
it uh it really made me
um but it also made me it intimidated me
for for lack of a better term I was like
am I how am I but then there's this
weird part where the older I've gotten I
definitely think we need you need to
know some of that but breeding is as
much art as it is science to me and you
really have to have the eye and some
luck maybe and really and really test it
smoking wise and see what's going on
because it's not just strict science
um what you're after is invisible well
we were talking about we were talking
about this the other day it's so it's
it's a great point you know of all these
all these multi-million dollar bankroll
um genetics operations that are trying
to come up with the next big thing in
cannabis you know what have they
produced every year a new batch of
winners comes from the from you know
from banjo Point Moonshiners in the
Hills yeah blow away everything that was
done the year before and yet you got
these boys in their white lab coats and
you know with the with the gas
chromatographs you know looking at the
DNA and what are they coming up with
did his when Matt did his uh actually
talking about that I will say that I saw
an interview with Shanti that made that
I kind of totally agreed with him where
he said that his CBD work is very
scientific and it's very documented and
it's very by the book and it's very that
way
but he said the Cannabis side is almost
all judgment and art yeah and I found
that very interesting observation that
he felt like the science of getting
these CBD CBG CBN type things it was
very very documented based and it was
very very testing based and he said the
Cannabis side is still the eye
it's still looking and hunting you know
part some of the goals of that of that
um CBD or the hemp Market is to come up
with strains that will will produce from
seed consistently low levels of of THC
with you know those those threshold
levels of cannabinoids that allow them
to legally grow it and it's and it's
really it's It's tricky to do that and
then once they once they figure out how
to isolate you know certain ratios then
they're they're trying to explore that
and create you know in strains in seed
that can produce other cannabinoids you
know to the exclusions of others
um all of this made necessary by
regulation of course you know if you
could just grow you could separate the
different cannabinoids and have one
plant that grew them all but you know
because the laws
differentiates between hemp and
and uh regular drug cannabis and you
know they have to treat these things
differently but yeah I mean one thing
that's interesting about that too and it
was like my second favorite part of that
Shanti interview was that he said that
one of the differences between what he
was doing with his crew and others is
that a lot of others were working with
hemp to breed CBD and CBN and CBG stuff
and he was trying to breed that stuff
from drug cultivars and bring it out in
the regular lines that had already been
bred for consumption and I thought that
was an interesting approach you know he
wasn't necessarily trying to breed it
from hemp he was trying to bring it out
in the lines that already existed
from the Cannabis side of things
I've grown some of his lines that look
like they might have had some hemp in
them I would concur yeah
this is completely off topic and I'm not
trying to derail it but uh raho your new
Avatar is the stuff of nightmares but to
get back on to get back on target for a
second one of the things that I do think
was revolutionary about the forums
opening up was it really was the first
time that people outside their own
friend groups in the Cannabis space
could start communicating with each
other and people from different parts of
America or Europe or Australia or
wherever could start talking about
something in ways that had never
happened before and so despite all the
the the the attacks and poop throwing
and wars that got started over things
and people being mean behind their
keyboard it really did Advance a lot of
things and it really did give a base
um for people to start discussing things
in public because at the time that all
those at the time that all those things
first came out I think overgrowth
started in the very late 90s
if I recall correctly only California
had medical at that time yes um so it
was just in the infancy of you know not
being totally illegal everywhere yeah
um and you know and it started to slowly
spread but I do think that
um you know and there's a lot of people
we could probably talk about like like
you know we everyone laughed when I said
hempy the reason why everybody laughed
was because he was a you know he was
argumentative you know and people had
personalities and people like Vic high
or you know people were famously like my
God you say the wrong thing to Tom Hill
20 years ago uh and he would just tear
your head off 20 years ago daily back
then you know like yeah in that in that
era and so there started being the first
like weed internet personalities and
then when people like Sam skunk man got
online or people like Khmer like there
was like Heroes that started yeah
um and it was also the first era to me
where visual aspects of cannabis became
very important like when people started
posting their stories around
um you know blueberry yeah and people
started posting these crazy I mean
that's where your passion for it started
right Matt you start going online and
looking at these posts and you're like
what is that thing yeah what is this
story and what is this name and why does
it look so mutant and why is it blue and
why does it have all these purple leaves
and especially like pre-cookie it was
wild looking cannabis oh yeah I was you
know
and people started exchanging Legends
and like I still have things saved you
know from you know kangavida and these
different guys talking about the
difference
we're talking about the mate mangling it
but posting these moem you know uh these
these different moemphinos and where
people got things and these on these old
school photos and you know stuff from
Switzerland and all that and it started
giving people a view into other people's
Gardens almost for the first time yeah
outside of friend groups what's this Mad
Jack from from Reiko
I was gonna ask if either of you know
Reiko I don't know him personally but I
know who he is sure okay
says it's join date was 2006. but this
is these are photos from 2004 of a 79
AFI and a Pakistani 1982. oh nice
yeah
the different structures look at him one
looks like Urkel I bet that's a Packy on
the left I would guess
yeah the left is The Afghani oh wow
oh look at my dumbass [ __ ] I was
thinking the same thing yeah
wow that's very cool the one on the left
looks like Bubba to me
deep chunk
yeah I just see Urkel looking at that
bad boy it has that same overly leafy
structure and you know what's funny
actually I got a picture of G13 the
other day and ran it by Neville's old
partner and he's like yup that is G13
that's exactly how I remember her and it
was from an old cat and it wasn't even a
catalog it was an old magazine clipping
uh I think from High Times or head
magazine one of the two and it was of
Neville's grow room and I had G13 it had
a few shots of nl5 but that also got
Neville's old partner to tell us
that G13 was Apple smelling green apple
smelling which I never knew and I've
always heard rubber all this other stuff
but I've never heard it directly from
any source that had it you know like
what the the scent profile was and he
says green apple
that's what yeah that's a good I can
hear that as you know I can interpret
that as being kind of salary citrusy
maybe you know with a little bit of that
that acidic bite not necessarily Citrus
but
um I don't know the other thing 18 has
some too the other thing I found crazy
about the forums is like you jump on and
you see some threads that would get
locked
and then you'd be like oh why did that
get locked and you jump on there and
then there's like all these spicy
arguments that go you see my name
about what's true and what's not and
there's people that you know that was
kind of the first time where your
popularity in some instances like LED
people to whether they were going to
believe you or not and people would
start poking holes in stories and it's
also the same era where a lot of people
have told a bunch of Stories on various
forums at various times and some of
those Legends don't line up and it's
like all their own words and so in 2004
this is what I wrote and then in 2010 I
kind of changed it and I wrote this and
now in 2018 I'm talking about this and
now today I'm talking this yeah and it's
interesting because it puts down on not
on paper necessarily but it puts down to
some degree a record
um you know there's some things like
icmag like you guys were mentioning even
on Mr Nice it puts it down on a record
until someone in the managerial capacity
on the Forum decides to either lock or
eliminate certain posts because it
doesn't fit a narrative yep so it's not
perfect because definitely on icmag
there's been there's been things that
have gone off the reservation if you
will and uh the thread or certain
comments disappears
yeah and I try to remind that to to
people who are researching nowadays that
it's it's hard to remember a few things
if you're like let's say you you showed
up uh 2016 past you know 10 15 after
that what you're looking at is a very
um it's a just a small sample of the
forums that were available like icmag
THC farmer roll it up
um but there were a lot more reforms
than that a lot of private forums like
we talked about there were there were
other just smaller forms couch lock Cafe
you know uh pot pimp there were there
were a bunch of them out there and those
are long gone seed Depot gone and you're
seeing a small section and most of these
forums were run by people
selling either a seed bank or had a seed
bank carrying many breeders or were run
by a breeder themselves and 99 of the
time you were it was very clicky so
you'd have people who were asked kissy
to the owner of the Forum they would
become the moderators and it would
become a lot of cheerleader rah-rah
stuff I felt like
um and it happened everywhere even on my
Forum you know like that I ran it was it
was very riot-centric because that's
just the way it worked out you know but
people are seeing a very small
screenshot so if you're coming into the
forum era now trying to go back research
you're missing a lot of context and a
lot of data is mainly what I'm trying to
say
yeah people uh people delete posts they
threads are locked or or post deleted
um sometimes
you know entire threads are are removed
yeah do you guys do you guys remember
the Crusty buckets oh yeah
I mean there was these Canadians on
there that were growing like in in grow
rocks and they were growing like very
few plants but they were growing two to
four pound plants inside on this crazy
hydroponic nft method called crusty
buckets and there would be some forums
there would be some threads that would
just go on for hundreds of pages yeah
um a combination of people asking tons
of questions or the original poster
posting updates
um you know people started posting like
grow pics and you know like I bought
these seeds from this group follow along
as as I pop these things and see what I
find uh and you know and a lot of like
Matt's writing a lot of those cases it
was it was specific to like who the
Breeders were on the various forums yeah
um but I have a bunch of cool picks from
Mr Nice of various is people trying out
different seeds or some of those old
timers coming on and you know posting
stuff that they had and then you're like
oh that person saw that and that era wow
yeah okay I'm gonna really like pay
attention to what he's speaking about
because you know there's not very many
references to it the either you guys
remember bite me from Mr Nice oh yeah I
can't find him and I've been trying to
find him I know you guys have other old
friends out there so put the word out
for him he was such a nice gentleman an
old Smuggler and he's responsible for
one of my best-selling lines of all time
and I've never been able to thank him
but he was a wonderful wonderful dude
from Florida see what I can find there
was a guy on there named Big Sur who
used to post a lot about apparently he
was from Central Central California same
general Santa Cruz type of region and
you know he offered up a lot of his
opinions on like what was around and
what he was seeing and what Hayes was
like and like different you know just
different stuff like that and whether
it's true or not it's always valuable to
get different people's opinions on the
same era because people have different
memories and different experiences too
it's a it's a little sad when you see
people like you know I'm not going to
say Big Sur because I'm not sure if this
applies to him but you know older guys
telling stories from way back
and and they're active and they're up
there you know every every week or you
know every couple of months they'll show
up and they're talking about what
they're doing and over time that they
just start kind of dropping off showing
up less often until finally they just
don't come back yeah um you know I've
seen enough of those
that just the really old stories kind of
like what what were you know Jackie and
I started talking about when we came on
here are the older ones are are
disappearing at a at a rapid rate so I'm
glad you guys got us on here I don't I
don't like to think of myself as being
in that category of a you know a
perishable item past the sell-by date on
the Shelf but yeah I mean dude I used to
ask this is probably 20 years ago now
but I used to ask my grandpa like what
it was like getting old
and he was he shows you know is the
weirdest thing ever he goes in my mind
I'm like 28 with a bunch of wisdom yeah
until I drop something on the floor and
then I bend over to pick it up and I'm
like oh I'm old you know and and it's
crazy too because it's like that to me
like you know I grew up in the 80s the
80s doesn't seem all that long ago but
boy it's getting farther away all the
time and you know the like the first and
second generation even of of cannabis
growers in America that span the 60s and
70s those you know that's you know
there's there's less and less you know
viewpoints and then the 80s even there's
less and less viewpoints and so that
kind of History like that's why I think
this is so cool of what we're all doing
is like getting some of that oral
history down whether it's written down
or whether it's like you know talked
about on on like this is pretty
important or a strain or a strain index
online that you know one of those things
one of the craziest things about out
this was like being able to talk to mad
Jag about like skunk one from the late
70s or early 80s yeah like that's wild
to me because having someone that had
actual experience growing it then like
and growing a good amount of it and
being able to see what it was really
like
incredibly rare not only that to me it's
it's not just having someone with
experience that grew up back then but
someone that had experience growing
other stuff and had experience with
cannabis and different the different
experiences cannabis had to offer
already before a growing skunk one so
they they could sense those nuances
those fine difference and smells that to
me is what what separates this story
specifically from a lot of other
people's old Tales yeah I agree skunk
one and 85 you know it was skunky yeah
exactly yeah this this is having someone
with with the nose and the eye that was
there that is is interested in the
genetic aspect too that's as nerdy as
all of us and and as advanced as an
archivist as he is I think that was that
was key and that was really important to
have that
one of the things that super humbles me
in cannabis is that um
it seems like the early raw work that
people do ends up being the best
and then they get older and more
experienced and they try to make it
better and they make it worse yeah you
know and you know Neville admitted that
like he got the haze and you know the
f1s were the coolest thing he ever did
with them and the more work he put into
it he goes none of the poly hybrids were
nearly as nice as like the one the first
crosses I made yeah and he's like I
tried and I tried and I tried and I
tried and then I had to agree that like
the first stuff I did was better than
anything I did after that
hey can I ask you guys a little NL
question sir have you ever found an
elfino that was high interpineline
yeah uh I want to say yes in nl5x2
I agree and a lot of the nl5x2 Repros
that came out from Old Stock uh have a
lot of mild to moderate terpenly knows
interesting Danny's have it as well it's
a trolley so it's it's in the Afghan
Pakistani lines okay so you know that
terpenolene is so so strongly associated
with Neville's Haze yeah right and I've
heard you guys talk about that once you
get it in in a line it's it's damn near
impossible to breed it out if you decide
you don't want it in there anymore
um just kind of curious because you know
I think a lot of people associate that
terpenolene
um with Haze a
right because yeah yeah you don't really
get those phenos in an SSH or a mango or
any of those other skunk NL Haze combos
that are around you don't get that heavy
you get it from Neville's right
so people think okay what's the
difference between Neville's and
everything else Haze a is the main thing
and so they immediately attribute that
turpinawin to the haze but I'm wondering
if it just was the female that he used
to make Neville's Haze that had a
terpenolin Dom
you know Northern Lights mama so the
interesting part about that is that if
you believe Neville's tale about nl5
he grew a bunch of the seeds and they
were a big mix of Indica sativa hybrid
phenos that were all over the place and
crazy
and there was this one Fino he found
that almost looked pure Afghan and
that's the one that he picked to breed
with but the seed line itself was
definitely a Afghan sativa mix
and so it's entirely possible that in
Neville's selection of nl5 there was
some genes in there that combined with
other genes could pop out that
terpenoline in Plants very much so see
Matt's going to get excited about this
because I I remember Neville's
statements differently than what you're
saying not to so uh oh yeah let's hear
it yeah so I mean you're saying that um
what do you know what did you say oh he
went through the the seeds he got right
so there were two at first he wanted
cuttings and seeds from the original NL
crew and then he had a falling out with
those guys who knows what it was about
maybe money I don't know
um and and he wound up going to kind of
somebody in the NL crew orbit
not the original guys to get those seeds
was that Seattle Greg was the guy in the
orbit so I believe Seattle Greg was the
original guy that he was getting him
from okay and if I remember correctly it
was Don Downs the Indian
that he got it from the second time and
then he was around them that he wasn't
he wasn't a veteran his son had served
or something and he you know they they
kind of anyway it's it's got all the
Hallmarks of of one of those old
[ __ ] legendary stories but
um you know the the main thing is is
that Neville Neville blew his deal with
the original guys and wound up going to
kind of a side periphery guy to get the
seeds that he would ultimately work with
yeah and and those seats you know that
Neville said that he concluded that hit
the the the five The Cutting he kept as
an L5 he believed it
he differentiated he called the U.S the
US five cut he said that there were only
two true true breeding male lines in in
everything that he got it was the nl1
and the nl2 were the two male ones he
had he had to work with I remember that
and he called the the nl1 a pure Afghan
and he called the nl2 a cush yeah a cush
type you know based mainly on the smell
of uh Juniper but and he said that the
rest of them were a big hybrid mix and a
mess yeah yeah but they were labeled I
think he might have said that they they
came labeled as this and that and the
other thing and they tended to run true
to what the description said they would
and I might be mixing that up but I
think that's what he wound up saying
that you know some some would be more
narrow Leaf than the others you know
based on what they've been outcrossed
with hybrids but as I understood it
Neville he had the five clone right from
from Greg and crew well he got it he got
that later after he had done his own
selection of of Neville's five because
regardless when he got it he didn't like
theirs so much according to him and he
made his own cross that he called nl5
using the Steve Murphy Afghan and what
his Mazar or the Steve Murphy Afghan
cross to the Hawaiian cross to his Mazar
or something like that so there's a cool
story they agree when they finally when
when they got the nl5 Clone that they
had selected from America and he got to
Amsterdam apparently they sent it over
in a terrarium full of plants and in
order to get the Clone over there they
took a pair of scissors and they cut off
all of the serrations on every leaf of
the nl5 No No Greg um I I asked Greg
this story
he said no they took it to a florist who
made a flower pot type thing and they
just stuck that in there he said he
didn't know anything about the
serrations interesting maybe maybe it is
yeah they might have the florist might
have done it one thing that
Greg mentioned that that Matt and I
never knew whether to believe or not was
Greg always Greg said in this one post
one time on Mr Nice in fact that
um the nl1 was actually Steve Murphy
afghan that he had gotten from Steve
Murphy combined with a Neville Afghan he
got from Neville
right and people speculate all the time
about which of Neville's afghan that was
that was used to make the cross and
Neville never answered the question so
you know for anybody to say it's this
one or that one you know what there's no
evidence to support it you're just
there's one there's like one or two
people I can ask that may know but not
more than that and even they I doubt
they'd know that one right
yeah but that's that's one of those ones
that the people who are saying those
things say it with such conviction that
it sounds like that you know they were
there when it happened but yeah you know
it's so yeah the nl1 is supposed to be
uh the the Steve Murphy Afghan times
some other athies from Neville
apparently but who knows what what it
was
um it was the purest and the interest
the interesting part about the
interesting part about that is that you
know if you look at like Neville's nl1
um every time he tried to make a back
Cross or every time he tried to
stabilize something that was from clone
he always used nl1 pollen to start the
process yeah because he said that it was
the only pure Afghan line he had that
was reliable
um and everything else he had that was
an amazing Afghan he got mostly in Clone
form nothing will devolve every show
into a show about Neville
everything I mean we were talking you
know Sunday up what the hell yeah he's
like he's like forums yeah well let's do
it
it does suck because we were also
mentioning to get it back to the forums
um the reason why we sort of lost
Neville on Mr Nice was him and Shanti
behind the scenes kind of got into a
tiff with each other over money and
access and seeds and this and that and
Neville got mad and left I will I will
actually say exactly what happened
because I was there and he told me
exactly and he's no longer with us so
I'll tell people his opinion because he
was very adamant about this he said he
sold Shanti the seeds uh when he did for
I want to say 250 000 or 150 000 so that
one I can't quite recall and he felt
that when he came back in 2010 that
Shanti had more than made a fair share
of profit and that he felt he was still
owed even though that wasn't a part of
the deal he felt he was still owed that
money because Shanti had capitalized
very well on his work well not just his
work but his name his name and that that
was the main thing yeah his reputation
is everything he'd been making it sound
like those two were you know back in the
rooms together doing selections and
shaking the males you know I mean listen
that wasn't happening you know it was
Shanty working with Neville's stuff
occasionally they'd exchanged a message
or so you know like how do I find a
skunk one plant that doesn't suck yeah
and Neville would say well you know if
you figure it out let me know yeah and
he was just in in at the same time
that the opinion of a lot of people
there was that Shanti was not as upset
or not as stoked
with all the attention Neville was
getting
um
yeah he wasn't back online you're like
oh my God yeah one thing that we could
maybe ask Mad Jack and and raho when you
guys first started getting online and
first started looking at forums what was
the kind of information or the kind of
stuff you were seeing that like really
excited you or like changed you know
like because I mean it's different for
all of us you know but like what was
like you know when you're perusing
different threads and seeing different
things were you after history were you
excited by some of the new stuff you
were seeing people post uh was it the
ability to connect and start direct
messaging with others because it sounds
like you guys built your friendship
um off of the forums
you know
something interesting about the forms
that we haven't mentioned is that um
there's a good number of people as
myself too that were um banned I was
banned from icmag and I was
you know I was
actively moved down to get banned I was
actively recruiting super nice people
and people who I liked for another forum
and it was a small form and since we're
talking about forms then one day I came
to go get on icmag and it it wouldn't
let me on and I found out from other
people were there saying oh you're
you're your threat is still here old
school Arizona I said but I can't get in
there so I talked to I actually emailed
Tom Hill somehow I don't remember how he
did yeah Thompson straighten things out
send Tom in there
we need the voice of reason and I got
back in and oh wow and he did something
I don't know what it was and it lasted
for about two more weeks and then I was
gone again for good and one of the
people the only way it happened but one
of the people that I was recruiting or
asking if they'd like to to join this
other forum narked on me and my snatched
well how how else would it happen yeah
and I never figured out who that was or
they were reading DMs like they always
did but anyway I I waited a year and
then I went back on under a different
name and I was concerned that maybe they
were tracking IP addresses and they'd go
oh here's magic trying to sneak back on
but they weren't and I've been on since
then I go on about every six months I
went on today because my ex-grow partner
I was telling Matt earlier
release the information about the book
he wrote called year of the magic and
it's it's a fictional story that uses
our experiences
and he uh
so I at some point did you meet like
um
you know Paul Newman out in the desert
on a motorcycle and save his life with
some water and he he rewarded you by
giving you a tab of something that you
don't really know what it was did that
happen did that really happen this
fictional account
the not that one
um
my it's my ex-girl partner and he's he
is using the name mad space capital j a
g and I just posted a little link on
there to my mag.com website because five
people have the right to use the name
magic and I and I talk about that on my
website because they were people who who
grew with me and they they deserve it
especially him because he did it for two
years with me and the two big years when
we grew skunk it was John and he he
lives in Taos and he has for years 40
years now I think and
um he's not worried about being exposed
or talked about so I'm mentioning it now
and I hope this I hope his book gets uh
you know a lot of traffic I'm sure it's
killer yeah so anybody listening right
now you know
um when this book is out please give it
please give it a look it's from uh
right now on Amazon I believe
the year year of the magic okay yeah and
what's the author's name
uh John Slater
s-l-a-t-o-r there you go and it's j-o-n
just John Slater
John John Morton the BBC for 10 years
before he came to the U.S and when I
tried to get him on the on a
particular Forum since we're speaking
about forums he was the fact that he was
into movies and filmed all sorts of
people got very paranoid and saying yeah
well what if he starts taking on our
photos and posting them and putting them
in a documentary so he didn't he wasn't
allowed to join yeah
because he had too much and it's so
ridiculous you know when somebody when
somebody first comes on the forums it's
like John did you know back then the
author uh it's it's weird you know
because you're first all of a sudden
you're inundated with real live people's
opinions about these products and maybe
you've been looking at High Times or
whatever all you've seen is advertising
information yeah glossy pictures you
know maybe some pretty girls you know
they they mix it all up to hit you from
every angle and and then it's got an
exciting story about some Intrepid
adventurers climbing up into the
freaking Himalayas and battling the yeti
to steal his seed stash and I mean it
just goes on and on and and you believe
it and then you get there and there's
half of the crowd on on the Forum that
you've decided to read is saying that's
all lies and the other half of the crowd
is saying it's all true you know yeah um
but you immediately realize that you
know it's neither it's neither all or
all or all true or all false but man
that's kind of an eye-opener and and
then you know the whole experience of
like like group dynamics you know where
people will align up around one color
you know we're the we're for the red
seeds you know no we only grow blue
seeds around here it's uh just just a
horrible thing but
so your question I got on because I
wanted to see what was out there in the
whole weed world I knew it from my
perspective in the people I knew in
Arizona but and
other places but I just had no idea that
it was so expansive and when I saw Mr
Nice seeds and all the things that were
possible I bought some seeds in the uh
auctions they had yeah that were in
Switzerland I believe they were mailed
from Switzerland and
um they got through fine so it was kind
of cool were they in were they in straws
oh wow I think they were
yeah no one of the one of the ways that
Shanti like those guys like to send
things was they would put seeds in in
like a plastic straw write the name on
the straw and then burn or seal the ends
of the straw itself yeah and and uh
that's just why I asked because I've
gotten straw you know corrugated seeds
I've gotten lots of lots of straws from
Shanty and I ordered um from him before
the auctions even if we want to date
stamp it and you know before we even
started auctions and and I got them in
straws even then did you did you ever
used to get um shanti's old private
email lists of his seeds that was good
yeah I was trying to dig up one for not
so because he had never seen one of his
old like when you were um if you're one
of the Breeders that was on a site
during like that Neville era he would
share a list with some people of the
like one-off crosses and stuff he made
you know you could buy some people yeah
so like I I've been trying to find one
of these old lists because I had a bunch
but I don't have them anymore speaking
of uh just uh just to fill in a little
bit speaking of magic talking about
getting banned
um yeah there was uh there was a lot of
ways that people got banned uh some of
it was you started talking about a
narrative that the owners or people that
were connected to the owners of the site
didn't agree with uh that could happen
sometimes it was just you would get on
and start talking your truth and then
you'd be immediately crapped on by a
bunch of different people calling you a
liar and calling you names let's face it
like a lot of cannabis people like you
know social interaction is not our
strong suit right so you get online and
you start typing out your truth or
whatever and then a bun and then 20 kids
are insulting you and telling you you're
a dick and you get mad and then you
start saying ruthless things back and
then you know yeah that's the mat the
mat version right
um and and you know then you get banned
for you know or your thread gets locked
because it goes beyond let's talk about
facts to like let's let's throw insults
at one another until somebody cries yeah
um and so you know forums were like and
there's also the you know you talk about
the keyboard Warrior thing where
Anonymous people getting annoyed with
each other can spit some pretty you know
pretty heated stuff back and forth
um and you know sometimes it's very
difficult how do you you know there are
some legitimate long-term liars and
scammers that have used the forums to
advance their interests and then there's
also people like mad Jag or others
coming out of the Shadows just telling
truth and how sitting there in front of
your computer do you differentiate
between the two
it can become quite hard and some of the
scammers are extremely personable yeah
and some of them are Elders in the
community and and you know like you want
to to trust your elders because that's
how we're a lot of people are raised you
know and then there's people like you
know Tom Hill or or hempy or different
people where if you cross them the wrong
way they're just gonna like you know uh
they're just gonna write out a a a
written evisceration they didn't have a
lot of patience
who went by the name weird I think Matt
we talked about this but yeah he was
always giving Tom Hill a hard time in
the early years that I was like 2012 13
14 yeah
um and Tom would just let it happen but
then when he came back like you said he
would just pound the guy you know and
there was some thought that weird was
actually a woman I'm not too sure that's
true but
he was very intelligent he wasn't just
like yeah
saying you're a liar Tom or whatever but
he he just wouldn't let go he was very
much a bulldog Tom earned a knew he
earned a new fan the other day
you know what oh sorry Matt go ahead no
it's okay yeah he just earned a new fan
on Instagram the other day that is
convinced that he's gonna prove that
Toms Hayes is a hybrid somehow I don't
know great another another another Don
Quixote there yeah helping at windmills
yep
um and yeah it's already that a lot of
times people in cannabis are better with
plants than they are with other people
yeah and so you start interacting with
other people you know and and it you
know forms it's like it's hard to stick
to the facts
people get upset people don't like being
called a liar people don't like being
called this or that or whatever and then
there's people that just doubt
um or they they read other stuff and
they get their facts wrong well you know
the weird thing is like how long do you
have to be online before you have your
first experience that it's like oh my
God something I was absolutely positive
was the truth is not true
you know because that happens with with
you know pedigree provenance stories
it's and it but it takes a while you
show up and and you're you're you know
you're a virgin you believe everything
you've been told by the marketing of
every seed company ever yeah all of a
sudden
right watching especially on cannabis
world uh where uh Sam Skunk Man was know
it all for sure
um watching those arguments about skunk
one and Haze go down uh you know you're
like well what do you believe
which people there's all these people
that are absolutely certain that this
person's full of [ __ ] and this person's
absolutely certain that they weren't
there and they're full of it and people
get defensive and we just go on and on
and on and on
pages do you know the story of white
widow very well the two competing
stories
uh well one of them is that let's see
there's a Brazilian sativa and manga
Rosa
Rosa and the Corolla a random app
there's a random Affy in there somewhere
in one of the stories yeah and and the
Kerala yes so and then it's that's
Verner right or or ingomar the shame
there you go ingamar or Shanti one of
those two both of them claim to be the
the Creator correct
um and I believe Shanty has a little bit
more detail in his in his description
about how it came to be the other one is
just kind of like well I woke up one
morning and I pissed out White Widow
yeah it was um it was a it was a like a
hash Bean if I remember correctly in one
of the in ingomar De Shaman's story was
that a bean in a hash if I remember
correctly there's something called the
plank p-l-a-n-c-k which is some kind of
Colombia or not maybe it wasn't
Colombian something like Brazilian and
they and I think he did say Corolla as
well and I believe he traveled to India
to get his as well just like Shanti did
and they both magically came back with
this same exact or not exact but similar
parentage hybrid with the same exact
name my experience at the same time the
people in Amsterdam tended to believe
ingmar and the people online tended to
believe Shanti uh it's definitely
indisputable that Shanti is the first
person to release a seed line to the
public using that name
um and this and it does appear that the
you know all the Hybrids you know and
things like that that started dominating
the cups like the White Widow and the in
the great white shark and Rhino yeah
right and you know even like Peacemaker
yeah peace peacemakers
no I don't think so yeah ingomar's
Peacemaker
yeah I think these guys all ripped each
other off and everything said most of
the people trying to find a good guy on
that list is just it's it's you know I
mean I don't I don't I don't condemn
them for it or anything but there's a
lot of money involved I mean there you
know I remember because I was a young
kid I was you know I was a young adult
then I'll say you know barely barely
legal if you will and uh getting those
High Times and they would have these
high glossy photos of all the winners
yeah 95 96 97 and all that and you'd see
the AK-47 and the White Widow and the
right Rhino and the great white shark
and they won and they were like the best
weed out there and
um you know uh those kind of strains
started dominating so it was like they
probably made milk they probably sold
just umpteenth million seeds based off
those spreads so many people from
America coming to Holland looking for
those exact strains that they saw in
High Times so there was a lot lot of
monetary battling going on over you know
over access in that in that regard
marketing the marketing Legends were
were the difference between you know
first and last
um yeah I mean I would any and even even
when if we're talking about the forums
to Trail it back to that again like the
I would say that the forums are really
what made DJ Short and his blueberry
work famous it's what made the original
Brothers Grim with the Cindy 99 and uh
and all that very famous you know Vic
High's work back then
um some of some of the smaller breeders
that were just getting started
um a good long 200 Page thread on
something could spark a career
on some of those early forums because
there wasn't that many people doing it I
mean I remember looking at all that
blueberry work and being like I never
see any weed that looks like that that's
crazy looking yeah let's go spend a
couple of thousand dollars and then does
it smell like fruit does it smell like
it looks why does it look like that and
then there was a time we've talked about
this on a previous podcast but we I used
to go to these parties
um that were basically a gathering of a
lot of these people that had met online
is that how the party went and yeah
not quite but I thought this was a
different podcast it's uh no not quite
but they but everything when I was
hoping to find a bunch of like ancient
varieties there and like everything was
crossed with blue work white work Sweet
Tooth you know it was all those early
2000s famous you know breeder Steve DJ
Short
um you know white widow white family all
that because those were the big seeds of
the time and it was also
pre-reversals and pre-feminized work
so it was all kind of normal stuff
you know I was hoping to find a bunch of
ancient stuff and it was all the most at
the time the most modern you know all
the most modern lines the new new the
new the at the time the hype right you
know the hype blue widow
you know
um you know everything by sweet two
three
um everything by Louis you know
everything by uh Blockhead about all
that kind of stuff Penny seeds yeah
Cindy 99 the first edition of of
Brothers Grimm when it was Sly and Mr
Soul those guys were very famous on the
early forums yeah and then they then
they disappeared and it's like the the
demand for their seeds increased when
they were no longer around which had
that that whole uh phenomenon of you
know creating a whole bunch of new
people
you know making their f2s f3s of of
Cindy 99 and discovering holy crap this
stuff breeds true
or like the the Dutch Flowers group
um they were some of the first people
that were they would they would write
online like what I consider now to be
like professional ad copy
uh you know of their strains and it was
very done and it was designed to elicit
emotions and feelings and they would
write extensively about how amazing it
was yeah and they would do that for
weeks or months and get everybody hyped
and tell them they didn't have enough
seed to give everyone and then they
would release their seed online and it
would sell out instantly and they would
do that every time huh
how about the first
first seed sellers that were massive
like World of seeds where you could go
on there in Great Britain and they had
they had every other Seed Company you
know they represented just hundreds and
hundreds I remember one of my first was
seed Madness that was real big from the
UK it was seed Madness they had everyone
remember Heaven's stairway yeah that was
that was earlier before the UK slam
haven't I didn't realize it at the time
but Heaven's stairway was tied into both
overgrown cannabis world
and so when they got raided
um both of those forums went down yeah
because I didn't realize it at the time
but that was that was the that was the
group they were all the same it was all
different facets of the same the same
same group I think it would be
interesting to talk to Richard
Calrissian now
um if he would
um his name's well known I don't mind
saying it you know the old owner of
Heaven Stairway
um it would be very interesting to talk
to him because he would have a lot of
answers about Dutch Flowers and a lot of
other companies that are very vague
because he worked with everyone the only
time I've ever got info on Dutch Flowers
oddly enough was from Charles Scott
reefer man and he was who kind of gave
me info on it but I don't want to repeat
it because I don't even know if it's
true coming from him but I will say that
like Dutch Flowers they would write this
ad copy and they would just write like
descriptions of strains that went on and
on and on and on and by the time you
were done reading it you were just ready
to spend a thousand dollars out of your
pocket as soon as they would let you to
get as many of them as you could and
then they'd sell out and you couldn't
get them and there'd be people online
laughing that they got some and all
stoked and it was like unbelievable how
much they were willing they were able to
build momentum for each seed drop yeah
and they reminded me of
that reminded me of alien genetics when
they came out on the farm in like in
2011 2012-13 like it was just like every
drop they did was just like thousand
dollars a pack two thousand dollars a
pack every time and nobody knew who they
were but nobody cared you know it's
really expensive and there's not enough
for everyone but we're gonna drop it at
this time and you can all fight over it
and it would really and it was like it's
a it's a cool way of like how human
nature works when you hear something
that's rare and desirable and you see
other people posting about how bad they
want it and you want it it's only going
to be there for a minute and you're just
like take my money please yeah yep it
was really clever Herbie's Head Shop
as the largest UK cannabis seed bank
back then too yeah I'm looking at a list
I have all these bookmarks in my Firefox
and some of these hyper samias in Spain
I bought some from in
whatever you bought a bunch from them
and they didn't pop right the
hypersamians well I I no I got my first
packet came with a footprint on it
that's right that's right that's right
and these people were nice enough to I
didn't even have a a way of making a
digital photo to send to them but they
they believe me and they said it again
and I got them but someone in the post
office you know just you can tell you
can tell that Herbie's a good guy from
that picture of him on those their ads
with the dreadlocks and everything he
looks real cool
that's got that's got to be herbie right
right
I thought that was him
so uh yeah I mean and then then you had
these people who wrote These Legend
stories right like like the origin of
skunk one yeah it's like a novel you
know it's like a short it's like a short
fiction book
Empty seeds did them Scentsy seeds had
great lungs yeah it was like I remember
I remember Jessie's pretty well for Mr
Nice yeah
I thought Jesse wrote those and the
thing is the Scentsy ones are almost
identical yeah which made me think holy
crap was he actually working for both
both sides of the battle you know what
is it wouldn't that be funny yeah if you
remember Jesse posted fake pictures of
UK cheese as the head picture for UK
cheese too it was a little cuisio
um I always get it wrong I would say
it's white skunk but it's like white
he had a whole series on Mr Nice where
he would come out with a lot of the
original strains and these extremely
long and detailed stories told with
utter confidence about where they came
from yeah and uh you know it it uh you
know it's uh sometimes they say like in
news it's better to be first than to be
right yeah you know
um and that is the case online as well
get your tail out there
um and and and and get repetition going
on and defend it and then eventually
it'll burrow in and become part of the
fabric of the story cannabis ear worms
and then and then some people on uh on
your podcast will invite you on to
explain how that story doesn't make any
sense anymore
you know you know what's funny is one of
the decisions that Matt and I made about
the podcast and the reason we started
talking about old stuff from the 70s and
80s first was because there was less
people that were going to get super
offended and fight with us instantly
about telling what we know because it
goes against what benefits them or
they're making money on some angle on it
or whatever
um there's uh there's very there's only
so many people that are actually
interested in cannabis history most of
them are interested in making themselves
look good and making money CSI often
reminds me
that we are weirdos because we actually
give a [ __ ] about what's in our weed
like we are the we are the actual
weirdos that care enough to Archive to
really delve into what's in strains and
then what's in those parents what that's
weirdo people stuff and we're those
people and he reminds me all the time
Matt not everybody cares like that it's
kind of weird that we care like that so
it keeps in perspective you know so yeah
it's a minority a dying minority that
are uh genuinely interested in strains
it could be growing minority you know
why does it have to be a dying mind
because I I really know I I'll disagree
on that one strongly because I use this
analogy all the time but like I kind of
think cannabis right now is where like
wine was in the 70s where it's like
people know for the most part they know
about white and red and what they know
about red is red goes with like pot
roast and it's like deeper and like men
drink it and white wine goes with fish
or it's like your lady likes it it's not
as like it's not as robust and then
that's really what people knew mostly
about wine in the 70s right and then you
fast forward with 30 or 40 years of
education and people are talking about I
like my Cabernet Sauvignon from this
appellation in Napa or this part of
Mendocino County or I like it from here
and these guys that make wine these
Vintners are my favorites and there's so
much depth now and you have like someone
yes that come to the table at fancy
restaurants and explain the nuances of
these expensive bottles they want you to
buy and so I think cannabis will go in
that Direct action for some percentage
of the market there's going to be a
great desire for information it's just
we're in its infancy and so now people
are fighting over the history
um you know because it's going to become
more important and people are going to
want you know marketing stories too you
know they're going to want to sell their
version of things makes sense to me
market trends yep
so all everything you just said sounds
right on I you know the question would
be is that percentage that are
connoisseurs that are willing to spend
the extra for the good stuff if you if
you compare it to the uh to the alcohol
business model you know that the
majority of people are going to buy you
know the cheap beer that that you know
they get the best bang for the buck
other people uh you know become you know
like to get the good stuff they they
drink in moderation and savor it and you
know make a big deal out of it whatever
same thing with same thing with cannabis
except
um
you know there's just there's so much
some cannabis and alcohol aren't aren't
the same right I mean you drink you
drink a gallon of one kind you drink a
gallon of the other you're gonna be just
as dead either way
but you know with cannabis the
differences are so great between one
strainer another so it's it's not
exactly the same you know it's not like
10 10 hits of bad wheat is not the same
as one good hit yeah you know and
there's and even if it's just a small
percentage that's interested in what
we're interested in that has the
potential to still be millions of people
spread out over over you know a wide
area of humans you know well that's
where those numbers grow is by the Gen
the increase in number of people who
smoke in general yeah right I think that
the 20 if we're going to think the 20
are ever going to give a [ __ ] about
about quality
um you know then that that number how do
we grow that number of 20 so that you
know an army of of old school Hill he'll
you know boys from the hill can keep
making a living off of their special
their special stuff I have thoughts on
that too because coming from like being
like a Grateful Dead hippie when I was
young and all that like when I was
younger the only place you could get
organic food was basically like crunchy
co-ops and odd places right and then you
I'd like to say that it was like us that
pushed it forward but we really didn't
who really pushed it Forward was like
there was some yuppies and some
wealthier people and they're like you
know I drive a European sports car I
wear these really nice shoes I wear
tailored suits why don't I have a nicer
grade a foot
you know and and there's going to be a
whole group of people that get into it
and they're going to want a nicer grade
because everything they also they have
in life is nice right right like that's
just how you know they have nice wine
they have nice shoes they have nice
belts they have a nice car they live in
a nice zip code you know uh all those
different types of things and as you
know some percentage of them are going
to get interested in in cannabis and
they're going to want high-grade
cannabis because they get high grade
everything yep
you know and that's why they're the
reason why you can go into any grocery
store these days and there's at least a
small organic section
you know yeah well and plus you know one
difference between food and cannabis is
food food would be
described as an essential right you have
to have it to live cannabis is is not
um necessarily unless you use it for
medicine that sure but again you know
you don't need Italian leather shoes to
live you got a lot of people buy them
yeah
you know wow and if they don't fit you
have to acquit also yeah
those Bruno Molly well I don't know what
I'm talking about first out of my price
range this might have to get edited but
Matt I have to bail in a second oh
that's all right we're good right now we
have about an hour and a half in and I
know Rojo's got a bill soon too
yeah all right so let's uh let's record
some kind of exit
okay
go ahead not so if we're gonna record
and exit uh I will just say that the
forums were amazing because they were
the first time that worldwide cannabis
enthusiasts got to insult each other
share information throw poop at each
other fight about what the truth was and
share their personal stories outside
their own little friend group and for
good and bad it totally changed how
cannabis people interacted with each
other it made a bunch of friendships it
made some enemies it turned something
from very local for most people into
Nation or even internationally wide it
forged a bunch of friendships over a
long period of time of people that met
through forums and and direct messages
and stuff like that and so technology
combined with loosening laws in America
that made people feel slightly more
comfortable to get on and talk about
things is really what sprung forward
um you know a lot of information
exchange
um and I don't think any of the four
people on here talking today would be
talking without that
internet advancement
for lack of a better term that's why
we're we we've met each other yeah all
four of us absolutely
you know so I I say that like you know
that that change was a sea change
because it brought together a lot of
disparate groups of weed enthusiasts and
allowed them to make friends or argue or
both or whatever and and push
information and history forward so um
it's uh it's been a massive positive in
my opinion and the massive number of new
strains hybrids really was fostered on
forums you know where people exchange
seeds and sent you a private message and
said well I've got these and you've got
those and then next thing you know
they're being crossed with another one
and
proliferating crazily
and also one thing I should say too that
made me think of it when you were
speaking is that it used to be before
the forums and before the internet that
it was only a very few number of seed
bank seed companies that were allowed to
sell stuff and when the forums came
about a lot of private hobbyist breeders
started being able to exchange their
work with each other
and as majag said that was revolutionary
and pushed forward hybrids in a way that
no one expected because it went from a
few dozen companies to literally
thousands of people exchanging their
work with each other of Their Own
Private projects and and getting famous
and some people got famous but even if
they didn't it just spread the germ The
Germ plasma around all over
yeah thank goodness Sam and Rob Clark
Booth told me that the only when I was
asking them at a later date the only
seed company or seed bank that they felt
was legit with seedsman
in in Amsterdam season
just for whatever it's worth
it
yeah well they've sold a lot of stuff
through seedsman and uh and they aren't
one of the more widget houses out there
that's for sure you know I think that
the the internet
allowed us to grow the community I mean
not so you were a deadhead you know went
out on tour you know bought bought
whatever you bought on Shakedown Street
and got friends probably still from
those days I I didn't I never was a
deadhead you know I I like their music
but I never went and saw them tour and I
I hate that I missed that but you know
it seems like with Jerry gone and that
we all know that that that movement that
served a function of of propagating and
preserving genetics you know people
brought their best to the show because
they wanted to show off to their friends
and you know I mean it wasn't just to
make money to get to the next show or
whatever it was you know there was Pride
associated with that and competition
um when those when those events stopped
you know I guess I guess the internet
kind of took its place it did I agree
that's a great Point yeah and and you
know and it took it to places like Way
Beyond we could have ever gotten to in
those parking lots and cell phone
numbers or you know what however the old
connections were maintained yeah pay
phones and beepers you know this this
summer will be 25 years uh that I've
lived in Mendocino County and I
absolutely would not live here if Dad
had friends that I knew from from shows
and tour had not lived here and invited
me out yeah 100 so I mean this you know
the health the health of the community
as it exists today is because of forms
um you know and and I I like to
differentiate between community and
Industry you know the community is all
the people that kept this stuff alive
when it was illegal everywhere and and
and getting caught could be the end of
you know ruin your life literally
um you know all those people who who did
the work when when the when the
the consequences were so grave you know
those people are part of the community
and the industry I think we all know
what the industry is you know it's it's
it's the big business that that hopes to
get rich off the back of of that Legacy
and you know I'm not I got nothing
against big business but um
you know it's it's a if it seems that
the two the community and and the type
of things that the community has has
worked towards and values is is it a
collision course or in direct conflict
with the industry
right that the the industry is all about
money and that that drives you know
um production practices way you know way
down in a negative way for Quality
um standardization everything turns
everything homogenization right
everything is the same you get the same
mediocre crap everywhere you go and
um you know that's
I don't know so I'm I'm all about the
community versus industry and and the
communities wouldn't be here without the
internet so that's a great Point art art
and economics have always been
uncomfortable bed fellows right yeah
nice is that a quote or did you just
make off the top of your head I just
it's definitely not me but I just spun
it off the top of my head you know yeah
well that's right on
all right you guys got anything you want
to get in for this week
Mad Jack is your mustache bigger this
about the same yeah it's handsome that
is a handsome mustache though
I shaved my beard off a few episodes ago
because you're right it it makes you
look much older and I am much older so
it makes me much much older yeah it
might be an episode coming up where the
beard leaves and it's it's him and I
with the full stashes so we'll see yeah
handlebar's dashes
okay I'll have to do mine just into a
mustache I've never had one just
mustaches ever but uh as far as you guys
know I've got a full mustache right now
there you go I know you are a operation
you are a specter a ghost
disembodied voice disembodied voice on a
yeah interesting but everyone always
super appreciate everyone listening and
everyone's time okay yeah don't end the
show yet so mad Jag um what was your
partner's friend again uh his name
it's called year of the Mad Jag awesome
all right everybody you've got a whole
um an icy mag he's got a whole thread so
fantastic you can see it and read a
chapter and the rest of it you can get
very easily so
all right he's not gonna hard copy
publish it he's working on a second one
right now that's going to be more
um real like a biography in in
[Music]
foreign
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
started to hit me
and I'm like wow
[Applause]
I got high
[Music]