welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
Syndicate welcome to breeder Syndicate
I'm Matthew here with my co-host
thousandfold today we have a really
really special show special to me
special a lot to all the The Forum
members of the community from back in
the day um we have everyone from the
Cana Cabana that made that place special
that built it up and each one of these
guys really brought something special to
to cannabis other than just the Cabana
so each has their own unique stories how
they came to it and I'm so stoked I'm
honored thank you for doing this with us
it means a shitload to me is someone who
grew up looking up to you guys and with
that thousand take it away
bro yeah you know I feel very very much
like a guest here I'm very remote from
all of you and and and especially remote
from that time in cannabis so yeah I'm
also just very grateful to be here um I
thought we could kick it off with a
little Icebreaker we do a round table
each one of you tell us uh how did you
get into forums uh into the forums to
begin with uh as part of you growing or
you know Journey um maybe we can start
with D
Man sure uh I'm Dean I think everybody
knows
me uh knows the
forums uh I think I hit the forums you
know like
1997 when uh overgrow was still I think
it was called the Edge back then or
something like that and uh what a wild
ride that was when you first get on the
internet and uh it was the coolest place
ever dude like all these other people
grow that's when I just really started
getting growing weed indoors at that
time 97 98 and finding that dude people
were sharing genetics all over the place
so it's like wow this is cool so that's
where I kind of got started hanging out
there and pretty Rowdy place at the time
but it was definitely cool uh other
like-minded people around and uh didn't
know that existed you know especially on
the internet you know which was all
really new that at least to me I knew
I'd been around for a
while same here for sure um why I didn't
mean to interupt go ahead Darren please
no no I'm done dude I discovered it
basically
after I guess my dad gave me a
uh hand me-- down computer around
1990 4 or
so and didn't really discover the online
cannabis Community till closer
to uh
19 oh help me out here Darren when did
we when were we and and how late late
90s dude it was it it was late 90s yeah
yeah really pre 911 for sure like few
years before 911 okay so I I taught
myself to grow all the before that
without the internet I had to go Source
uh little underground books from Shady
little
bookstores uh here and there and finally
piece together how Hydroponics might
actually work of course I didn't have
enough sense to go to the library I
guess but um and then discovering the
forums
that was like oh this was everything I
needed I just I can't believe I didn't
have this trellis netting on my plants
to hold them up and here's a picture of
what I need to do and it's like oh boy
you know these forums are going to be
fun and they
were still are but they were right how
sir what do you got well uh late 80s I
uh moved to Colorado and uh could not
find good pot here on my own so thanks
to my great wife I was able to start
growing on my
own uh found the Internet by looking for
seeds um yes wasn't uh too long you know
after the late 990s I started really
looking for seeds I came across uh overg
grow in cannabis world and uh and
actually came across demman then and uh
became like his primary beta
tester um and at the same time I was
beta testing for Mota
Rebel uh had a great time because the
genetics were coming to me from them and
a few other folks up in Canada on the
west side
from uh where dman is we're sending me
genetics as well so um I kind of became
a weirdly I'm a very small scale grower
as most people who get to know me know
um but I ended up at one point holding
genetics and supplying clones to God I
don't know how many people Steve right
between you and me we sell stuff
everywhere everywhere everywhere
everywhere the world
possible we tried to get stuff there
yeah once we learn and we had the
hardest trouble I think with Darren
through the well Darren's a troublemaker
it it comes
naturally I mean packages made it to
Hungry with clones no problem but
couldn't get them past Canada security C
is Hardcore still still it's hard to get
CL over that border dude I don't know
how but cushy man that guy can get
clones over the Border I don't know how
he does it he's got a [ __ ] secret but
he does it but I'll tell you just just
to jump in here of all the elite clones
that you guys have heard about in the US
they they went through these two guys
hands before they went to anybody that's
amazing uh yeah Steve and and and how he
dude everything went through them
everything uh and that's that's kind of
weird
because you know we're older than
everybody else it's well we had to start
out with seed because we definitely
didn't have clone connections and then
when we finally discovered the online
community it just opened up everything
and then you're just the kid in the
candy store right
um I think I bought my first seeds for
Mark Emory way back in the day wow
and and he sent me strains I didn't
order but that's
story go
figure I remember the way I met you
Steve we were you know we were talking
about you know how nice it would be if
we each had different different bud to
smoke and next thing we we knew we were
trading through the mail you know all
kinds of samples to each
other and uh you became my Prim AR
source for oh I want to try to grow that
hell
yeah is I think I think a lot to
SK pretty much still to this day yeah
got a bunch of new ones actually the
whole new batch I got in most of those
just flopped
unfortunately you running cookie stuff
now I am running some some cookie
strains I've got the garlic cookies
which I really like got a bunch of other
new stuff got this modified grapes which
I haven't grown out but Howie has he
says it's very
nice be back
yeah I've got not that you can see this
tiny little itsy bitsy
bud I can go get a bigger bud but that's
what I'm smoking smoking this little
modified grapes right now well yeah if
you want it's the size of a grape it's
actually actually The Bu Sour Diesel
they're really nice and
dense and the buds the buds on the
modified grapes are very reminiscent of
the ice cream cake yeah um they look a
lot like the ice cream cake but when you
smell them you can tell they definitely
two different different beasts it's just
they look almost exactly alike
growing could be twins aside from modern
genetics let's talk about what you guys
were first seeing when you when you hit
the scene like a lot of course a lot of
strains didn't have names at the time
but when you started seeing that like
Darren what do you what did you see dude
it was like you know back then it was
the
sorry see me yeah yeah yeah oh sorry
back then a dude it was like a you know
the white widows a secret Coke recipe
white widows a lot of you know blueberry
not and not just DJ shorts um oh it's
real blueberry though yeah like uh dude
the seriously the best blueberry not not
DJ or anything but was that sag matthos
blueberry dude like that that [ __ ] rock
that was some really good stuff um and
then dude for for me it was like I never
really bought you know breeder seeds
like at really at all I found cbay
through cannabis World dude and that's
where I spent my money dude there was
like and some of those guys you know
like never heard of before like most of
them you know just probably dude some of
the best genetics ever came out of there
for cheap dude like you mentioned motor
Rebel one of them motor Rebel like dude
Joey weed you know like that's where I
got my start um there was the the three
three SE or the three C's the classic
clone company I actually forget who that
was but dude and you know katsu's
Bluebird his collection like that dude
just like ruled he just bought
everything right yeah he did he spent a
lot and dude if I I sold my own seeds at
cbay and that would be the only way I
bought seeds was uh some serious seeds I
would just instead of taking cash from
RC I would just say send me seeds that
he had on the board right and the sagath
blueberry literally the only two breeder
seeds I ever bought um everything else
was cbay and traded straight up freebies
dude that was what it was great back
then like nobody really cared about
money like even cbay dude like nothing
other than you know Dutch flower stuff
nothing went over for like 25 30 bucks a
pack like it was awesome awesome
like that was what made the forums fun
for me dude and like everybody wanted to
talk like everybody was willing to share
like we all had our little knowledge
like you know I had all kinds of Outdoor
Experience before I had the indoor
experience so I like to hang out there
and then it's it's like Steve said it
was like a kid in the can store dude it
was awesome and and people were awesome
there there was Trolls but for the most
most part the
first the first few years it was like
this is cool dude like had no idea and
all over the world like Australia New
Zealand like you know Fiji like Growers
from all over the world it it was
awesome and then dude you could
literally ship clones and seeds no
problem back then no problem that was
super easy but after 911 then everything
just slamed shot right well back in the
day get a priority mail package in two
days like it was supposed to and the
Clones would still be
alive were you seeing skdy excuse me
what kind of stuff were you seeing when
you first uh got online oh boy um before
I got any clones in the mail I did buy
some seeds and had some good ones I had
DJ
Short um hello not not the blue be can
you hear me hello oh flow thank you yes
had the the
flow and like an idiot I didn't keep
that one but this was way back in the
day but yes I had the DJ Short flow I
had a DJ Short Blueberry and I also had
a blueberry that someone else had given
me which could have just been a mirror
image of the DJ shortes but it was just
real wonderful
blueberry um I bought those legendary
packs of slider from Sager mantha and
grew those out that's where I found the
Cherry slider that's right
legendary yes I will regain that one day
um smoked it never grew it but and then
what else did I oh my God bog strains if
you remember bog oh yeah his his Boggle
gum and sour
bubble yeah I don't think I had
necessarily think I had the sour bubble
I may I very well may have this is a
long time
yeah that's true not really this is when
I was down in New Orleans at at the time
and did he have bog Bubble at the
time he had something called Remember
Boggle gum yeah yeah actually that was
good bogs Boggle gum dude that was good
that was good oh and I I had the th
seeds Bogle gum or excuse me th seeds
bubblegum as well and I had
thc's chocolate
chunk which I didn't really find any
chocolate or any chunk about it it was
just one of those hit and miss sort of
things didn't you do the choco diesel
too though skidy yeah it's your well
that was that was way down the road
after um after Santa smoke had his
trivia contest late one night at
cannabis world and gave out the packs of
seeds that's right chocolate diesel
you're the original chocolate diesel guy
I made one much later and people would
would ask me if I was the chocolate
diesel guy from gorilla GL I was like
uhuh that came before me you know yeah
there there are two fenos out there
there's another cannabis World alumni
who's at the Cabana now uh knucklehead
and knucklehead found a separate feno
from what mine was so there's a
knucklehead feno and then there is the
skiddy feno um prettyy sure mine was a
bit more distributed yeah that than the
knucklehead
right how what did what did you see
during those uh First Years what
strengths were you running into well of
course I ran into dman so I was beta
testing a whole lot of his stuff um same
thing with Mota so I saw a lot of those
strains
but I ran into just different groups of
people we had lots of lots of very kind
people so I had strains from cabbage man
196 69 cage um I had you know strains
from
stash um just all kinds of stuff I was
seeing a lot of um Aloha White Widow
crosses seeing a lot of Black Widow G13
crosses a lot of G13 gorilla
arm oh I remember yes yep back in the
day when we originally started here you
know in
Colorado I also was able to Source some
Romulan and some of the Colorado peab
Bud um which back in the day you know
thinking about it I really wish I knew
how to clone and keep plants back then
because there were some real Cherry
plants back in the day um we also saw a
tremendous amount of Durban in
Colorado um in the late 80s early 990s
um always a pleasure to
grow um uh we even ended up getting our
own cut somehow or other Colorado has
its own Durban cut um I think not sure
who that's care of maybe Stacy mure oh
Maybe Might Have Been instrumental in
that um another real nice guy and then I
um was privy to helping
these other two gentlemen run an auction
for a gentleman in Australia named Rod
wall um back in the day to help him get
out of some troubles so I was kind of
the middleman for I don't know how many
thousands of
seeds that um different members across
the different forms donated to us so we
could have an auction and send him some
money and uh so even today in my seed
collection I still hold some things that
they everybody gave me extras so I would
have for me um I'm still holding seeds
from back in the day from that auction
wow gotta find something to do with them
yeah yeah I mean are they in a fridge
yes oh yes good man good man did it
right bro so you mentioned someone from
Australia was that later to be Dem man's
buddy or different person from that
region uh it's a different guy different
guy when we first got on cannabis World
um back in you know I I got back on OG
in 90 I think it was 99 but I didn't
move over to cannabis World till 200000
that's where D and I started really
connecting um but back then we had a
grip of folks who were from all over the
world growing they were a lot of them
were there for you know having stairway
for for seeds to get you know
from you know uh
cbay yeah and um we a lot of us we all
have things in common you know so you
meet people different ways
and um that we just had people from all
over trading us stuff we had guys in
England uh I remember the original UK
Cheese came to us is that Viral vision
from Vision
yeah and uh you know when when we all
first saw pictures of it we saw pictures
of this white plant sitting out
somebody's backyard in England and it
was like wow what the heck is that yeah
yeah is that covered in mold then we
find out I I remember that very photo
that was that was wild it was and we
have it and and and vision made sure
that a group of us got it skdy me and
and God Rest his soul buckwheat you know
was in the early days buckwheat was
heavily involved with us in in making
sure a large number of members got a
variety of clones uh that we were being
sent from you know Canada through uh
Vision Creator and Thunder monke yeah
shout out Vision he watches sometimes
and uh you know being in Canada Vision
it was easy for vision to get me the UK
cheese right so yeah right one Coast to
the next that was easy like and back
then you know that was I'm pretty sure
pre 911 is or right around there when it
still easy to get stuff across and like
I said you know Howie he was the uh
repository for all the Clones dude like
everything went through him and it went
to everybody
um I love small space and was able to
pull it off that's amazing I had I had I
had two lights to grow to grow my my
plants under and then I had a front room
with a bunch of t5s it's still
there I don't use it anymore thank
thanks thanks to skiddy I don't have to
worry about moms anymore which is great
for me um but at one point I I was
holding 26 to
35 moms at any given time and and there
was a whole group including Kirby who
knew that if they needed clones they
would just call me and come over and I
would just kind of turn my back and they
would just go in my room and made what
they needed and that's you are the
holder of the strains well it's called
easy maintenance too right like it's
easy maintenance for the mom let other
people come over and keep it pred back
for it really wasn't you know it really
was it worked out fine for me you know
at the time to be able to do that and
again I had people passing through
staying with me like you know skiddy
stayed with me when he moved out here I
had the doctor stay here for a while um
sorter um God Rest his soul when he
first moved to Colorado he stayed with
me for a couple of weeks um you know
I've had a lot of people come and go and
a lot of good people come and pass
genetics sort was another one who bred
genetics kind of in the backyard
secretly and everything that anybody
else thought was worthy he would try to
breed f2s of yeah and I also have a in
my repository some of his f2s from a
number of years ago um a lot of those
are almost all Aloha White Widow
crosses cool very cool was that was that
uh through JoJo's work that he was doing
f2s of or someone else's like NCG yeah
he was doing someone else someone I
forget who originally put out the Aloha
White Widow thought that was
jojojo JoJo yeah yeah sort had a yeah
sort of had a lot of mental health
issues um he was um super obsessive
compulsive and had paranoia yeah but for
some reason that strain um helped him
get through his
day so you know he tried Crossing it to
all different kinds of things to see if
he could get a better more vigorous
plant that would help him yeah and in
turn um he was one of those people who
posted up on cannabis world you know
only minorly but all of his posts were
like oh I just made these crosses and
these because as if anybody wants him
yeah and he was constantly sending out
seeds to people um I still making the
rounds still I still come across a few
people I know who still grow um he had
an Aloha white
widow um Crystal
locomotive no no it was uh it might have
been my train wreck
but
yeah and I I think he had that cross and
I think he he passed that around a lot
it was again everybody was trying to do
their part to make sure everyone in the
community had what they
needed yeah his his his uh biggest most
famous one to this day a lot of people
don't know is the grap stomper clone
came by a Jojo and it was renamed and
stuff but that's where it came from so
it's cool to still see it moving around
Jojo great strains he remember he had
came out with a candy Haze and something
other Haze was the Blowfish I thought
Blowfish was Dutch Flowers flowers he
did a lot with Dutch Flowers I've never
been able to unravel it though like he
did Blowfish f2s but he also sold seeds
to RC that I think were sold as Dutch
Flowers but I don't even know who Dutch
Flowers was dude dude you're on the
great track there Matt I honestly think
that Dutch Flowers was RC
that's what reeferman told me he said
that he I can't confirm that but that's
why hunch dude because yeah you
know to deal with RC a lot right because
you know getting paid and stuff with
them their writing styles were very
similar dude very similar I had some
emails that was like wow dude just the
way they word things right and they had
best descriptions right best description
right yeah and speaking of Jojo dude
like such great strains probably went
over like 30 35 bucks 40 Buck Max you
know Max dude like nowadays you know you
would just kill for that kind of stuff
and it's like oh yeah dude it it wasn't
about the money back then it really
wasn't it was all about yeah it was kind
of cool to you know get a few bucks you
know because it wasn't a lot of money
but it was just collecting it was like
you know almost like collecting baseball
cards really like Kirby says you know
people collect seeds like baseball cards
now but back then it was crazy just
katsu right you know he's got one of the
biggest baseball card collections I've
ever seen oh you remember D Man remember
a cademy yeah dude yeah that guy yeah he
bought everything fastest bidder on CW
there
was sniper dude what a
sniper you couldn't win a pack from him
if he wanted absolutely dude yeah he
would snipe you right to the end
like man after my own
I just wanted to say you know like I'm
I'm really enjoying just being a fly on
the wall for this conversation but it
sounds like just such a a radically
different time to where we are right now
dude it was it was so different it was
there there you know not going to say
there wasn't snakes but we weren't we
weren't privy to them I'm sure like some
of the guys that were really you know
running the the the hard traps and out
in California that were you know really
facing hard if they got caught you know
those guys yeah you could see where they
were you know a little closer to the
bestest they wouldn't share as much but
uh it slowly even those guys started
coming out when it seen you know I
remember that what was that guy uh with
the black the Blackberry guy S blaz S
Blaze yeah dude like those guys like you
know at first dude that guy showed some
pictures blew everybody away no ever
seen [ __ ] weed like that magenta weed
bro yeah and he would just wouldn't say
anything but then slowly even he would
come out right so but for the most part
it there was there was no sketchiness no
one was trying to get a leg up on
anybody it was like dude it's like you
know how he said we just wanted to make
sure everybody got a taste of everything
that was going around and get it to
wherever we could I
I I do remember when I first got my
first clones in the mail I think it was
T that sent them and I got the sour
diesel the Bubba Kush train wreck
Orga help me out here guys wasn't there
two more wasn't it like the Holy Grail
of seven strains at the time
well I don't know about your end but
dude this was catsu sent me all my gear
that I had that I was breeding with and
that was maybe part of the seven strs
had the Bubba cush East Coast sour
diesel train wreck I had the uh a11 the
genius cut um I think I had the
chocolate diesel was c99 out yet yeah I
had the c99 cut I had uh and that was I
believe 180s cut um that was the the
most prominent good cut at the time I
probably still is to this day um and
dude it was so cool this is how cool it
was so katsu's in the states Southern
State not going to say which one he
[ __ ] UPS me those clones at 4:20 his
time in a Southern US state and they
arrived in Ontario at my [ __ ] door at
4:20 the next
day rooted clones dude by a ups dude and
we never had that look we have to try
that next time well we never tried UPS I
guess that's true and then like three
years later I called them all When
Heaven Stairway got busted because I
figured they're coming for us right so
lost it all but that's how easy it was
back then and nobody cared like it was
like nobody everybody was looking for
the Holy Grail but everyone wanted to
get it around find everything just get
as many people looking for it as
possible with as many strains popping
billions of seeds everybody was from
cbay oh yeah it it was just a wild fun
time and then it got ruined super neat
right it was a real small crowd at the
time much small yeah there there was
there was different people in a group
and depending upon which segment of a
group you were in you might get the
clones before you know I might get them
before D would get them or before skdy
would get them but everybody knew I was
going to give them to skdy or vice versa
yeah we had we had guys like raos Ros
yeah you know who was sharing genetics
kind of really as secretively as
possible you know we had you know
Barefoot who was sending seeds to all of
us behind the scenes without saying
anything I was good friends with you
know I I feel like I made a connection
with like ctg I was getting a bunch of
stuff from him um great breeder dude
great breeder yeah to this day you know
good gear genetics his brother goodar
yeah yep good between good gear and and
his and his brother medk kind we get a
lot of our gear from them even today you
know we we've developed relationships
that are you know
years of of making I I opened my home
and had parties with you know upward of
30 people on 420 and I didn't always
know everybody who showed up at my house
you know those are fun
barbecues we had we all had a good time
we all made good friends that's how we
met Kirby dude I flew in Canada for
those parties they were [ __ ] awesome
they were better than the ones we had in
Canada yep and then and then there were
the cups you know out in California
where we
met all the guys that you know that we
kind of hold dearly old
SG and you know Rosso
NCGA Slayer you know NCGA he's been good
to me too over the years I was actually
just texting with Elie last night about
his Detroit uh Redwing so
nice yeah we had we just had a we had
great people you know uh every single
one of them
uh Chip Baker you know uh Ed larus
TC just huge crowd of people and
everybody who anybody foundo of
something if you wanted it all you had
to do was ask yep you know was was good
good times and safe times pre pre the
covid stuff that's for sure yeah we with
our group and uh our group that we have
going right now we really tended to
Model A lot of what your guys' parties
were about how that all worked with
clones and bring that into the modern
era so hopefully we do it some justice a
little bit but it sounds like it was a
freaking amazing time to be alive a
little jealous but I'm I'm I'm stoked
also to hear about it from your guys's
eyes like was there any memorable
moments during any of those parties you
could think of where someone was you
know kind of wild absolutely dude I was
at Ho's at one of those parties and the
first time I met Kirby and that was the
first time he Kirby gave me my first J
ever the first time I did a shot her I
think that was in like I GNA say that's
at least 10 years ago now like
2014 or something I don't know it was a
really nice day like I remember that
Kirby was way ahead of the he was
[ __ ] right dude I haven't looked back
since then dude I'm a dab [ __ ] head
dude I smoke more dabs than I ever do oh
I had to stop unfortun I did too I did
too I got after a while it's
cop knocking at the door no dabs small
one hits fine bubble fine this something
about those dabs no thank
you well I mean memor memorable for me
about the parties of course is I mean
all the people who I met including some
who are no longer with us like
zo you know Matt um and Sorter and you
know and I we still have a lot of good
friends our friend Bud span came to a
lot of the parties we're still friends
with you know Kirby because of the
parties and green mofo and and one of
the funny stories about one of the
parties K the
first party Kirby came to he bought a
brand new dab rck it was over a $200 dab
rck he got one hit out of it and then he
dropped it on my concrete
patio um we laugh about it now it was
kind of a stinging memory and he always
joked about it he never once got upset
you know Kirby that that's kind of guy
Kirby is you know just roll with the
punches but uh didn't didn't Kirby have
a whole dab case like a specialized
briefcase with all different I bet
folded
we call those trap trophies yeah and
then when it became unfashionable to use
the torch if you remember he not only
brought the case with the dab rig but he
brought like the battery to heat
everything up oh he brought the whole
set up and it was like mobile dabs yeah
yeah he had he had quite the setup and
he was the first person I ever met who
was making the giant Bazooka tubes yeah
you know to blow hash it was kind of a
cool cool thing you know so he was doing
it at scale like when I first met him he
was he was the dab man at scale in
Colorado big time dude dude dude he was
the guy who was buying the giant tubs of
[ __ ] you know [ __ ] butane is like
he went to the supplier or something the
supplier is like dude we we can order
that in for yeah and he's like oh yeah
order me as much as you can
get what are you using it for oh it's a
sign project or something science yeah
science science what one of the most
well-known things with UD d man is the
spice Brothers era and it was you and a
person named Fett can you talk a little
bit about how that came to be sure
actually uh Fett was he's he was in
Australia um just a a wild manad for
sure
um yeah we just hit it off because he
was a big
uh indoor grower in Australia which
which you think when you think of
Australia you don't really think indoor
grower you think more like outdoor right
but um he and not to say he didn't do
outdoor but I don't think the um you
know the ground in most of Australia is
indicative of doing outdoor grows like
you really need to like you know like an
augur to dig the I think CR is just so
hard you need to condition everything so
dude he was doing indoor stuffff and I
how I stumbled onto him he was posting
pcks of these [ __ ] water jacket
cooled lights like these high pressure
sodium light I remember those right and
I'm like what the [ __ ] are they doing
down under dude like never seen anything
those are the on those are ones where
they actually putting down into the
plants like not over them they were down
inside with the water tubes yeah and he
could put your [ __ ] hands right
around the lake like no he and obviously
in Australia anyways we just started
talking and
uh we just started trading some strange
again it was all free he's like hey M I
got something you right here he's like
can what do you got what you grow in
Canada I sent him some stuff and next
thing you know it was like he started
breeding some of my stuff I started
breeding some of his stuff and we were
like it's a good collab let's put it
together and and we did a few just our
own things
and that's right around you know the
time that just about a year maybe two
years before Heaven Stairway went
down and brothers Grim went out of
business W they stopped selling seeds on
Heaven Stairway yeah anyways right and
dude if you wanted brother Grim seeds
back in the day they were like 150 bucks
a pack like they were top of the line
that was big bucks back then right and
not everybody could obviously afford
that so when they stopped selling seeds
and I I knew that because again my close
relationship with RC at the time and uh
so we reached out to um Mr Soul at the
time and said dude do do you mind if we
you know knock off some of your strains
make some FPS and send them out on the
cbay for everybody to [ __ ] get you
know a chance to your genetics and sure
he gave us permission to do that and
dude that's basically what we did and
that's how we started spice Brothers was
just basically knocking off everything
Brothers Grim right right and uh dude
that did some really crazy things over
there again once I got the a11 from
katsu that was really cool that helped a
bunch of the genius crosses genius
wonderful oh absolutely and F did the
all the Green Giant and res
crosses what's that did he have the
Vietnamese black stuff too yes dud so he
was one of the ones uh him and kushy man
are the only that I know personally that
actually got the uh Anonymous Vietnamese
black yeah and dude he crossed that
Vietnamese black with legit Neville's
Haze yeah yeah yeah oh dude and I never
smoked it but I seen pictures of it and
I I talked to people that did smoke it
it was like wow like trippy sativas like
and that was
F trippy sativa guy what did you call
that one 303 spice or something weird it
was 303 spice yeah oh my God look at
that and dude I remember even all
the Green Giant uh crosses like huge
buds dude huge buds like huge Buds and
then he got into that uh the Lou Han one
too where yeah uh he crossed that with
the Neville
Haze again he'd love the sativas I guess
Australia is a good good place to do the
sativas Outdoors if you can find the
suitable soil to do it uh then uh we
just once Heaven Stairway went down he
went over to that um what is that UK
place cuz at the same time as Heaven
Stairway was getting busted seeds in the
UK became
legal Gypsy C Depot no Gypsy no no the
other guy doc something uh oh
Dr Dr Green Thumb doc Green Thumb no no
no no no no it's not he's in Canada
herec
yeah he had a forum and he was selling
seeds over in the UK so that's where
faret and I ended up our relationship
ended there right so like like literally
I shut down everything right after
Heaven Stairway went down so yeah so a
lot of
people but I sent uh I sent all my stock
to to Doc chronic that was anything
spice Brother related and F and I just
split it up after that and uh dude then
he just fell off the face of the Earth I
wish I could find that guy I reached out
I I can't find anybody that knows him
the last thing I did here is that he got
bit by a black typan oh Jesus and I
think that's pretty pretty rough snake
in Australia and I he he made it but I
think he got pretty [ __ ] up from that
um who is this F oh okay so yeah I don't
know what happened to him dude I've had
people reach out to me over the years
asking where he is and I'm like dude if
you find him let me know tell him I'm
looking for him like yeah I would love
to reach out and get a hold of him again
right but uh you remember his strain
dizzy the aie type y definitely not hies
yeah definitely not dizzy was the the
weird totally I don't look like weed
weed right yeah yeah the not ABC not ABC
right it's not ABC it's not
AB never release it
uh he would never even send me any seeds
he crossed that [ __ ] with everything but
uh everybody wanted it but nobody could
get it I wonder why why he held it so
tight I know Hy worked on it too or
something similar maybe not ABC maybe
not the same yeah uh but again you know
I and now I know that uh inspector's
working with it like he's got some
crosses of it out there so yeah I think
it's very interesting I'd love to grow
some right I think it's cool looking you
know like I'll get you some
don't know what it smokes like but it's
interesting um yeah that that's the
spice Brothers thing dude uh it was a
good relationship we had a lot of fun we
had a lot of fun that's one of those
things like whenever I would find even
today if I see spice brother seeds I get
really stoked and try to get them from
whoever has them so like that that's a
very fond spot in my heart you know like
when I see spice brothers that's special
to me absolutely D I'd love to get some
actually I have a couple of packs here
I'm not sure what they are and somebody
sent them to me with some original D Man
seeds in the original Heaven Stairway
pack too actually I just sent the uh G
Black Widow to cushy man because uh he's
looking for that the vomit Fe fenal
again yeah you also did Endless skyw
work right yeah yeah I helped develop
that with Doc Green Thumb that's right
yeah tell me more about it uh it's
Iranian Inda um crossed with uh a strain
of his called grenadine which is a G13
cross yeah uh I'm not sure what
G13
AG13 um he had very few seeds of it he
was building a house and he sent me I
don't know I don't know couple of dozen
seeds I worked through them and made
some you know f2s for him and sent him
back like couple thousand seeds and that
was my part with it and he ran with it
from there and made his own selections
and I actually sent him the mom back
with the seeds that I had found so oh
wow yeah cool guy uh he's still in
business now doing lots of good stuff up
here dude like one of the earliest
feminized seed sellers that I remember
that was in North America uh right up
there with the the classic clone company
from C forgot who they were but they
were the first ones to get a hold and
that was uh I think it was hve again you
selling his uh yeah whatever it was yeah
yeah we we tried it the exe it worked on
a couple of strains and a couple it
wouldn't yeah that's that's that's what
people don't realize like with reversals
like it's not all inclusive no matter
what spray you're using no matter what
type it's it really is dependent on the
health of the plant the type of plant
the genetics of the plant how it revers
absolutely abely agree I just found uh I
don't know if you could see
these yeah I can see those what you got
that is a JoJo candy Haze and this is
something by barefoot Alpha Kush it
looks like Alpha Kush F
200 I don't I still have some Crystal
locomotive that JoJo did nice I I I'll
tell you that was a good strain yeah it
was it was a very good strain so were
his train wreck s1s I love those yeah he
did kill her stuff way way ahead of his
time he was I honestly think that and
this is just my opinion I honestly think
a lot of
the Kush fenos that are going around now
all came from CB dude those first
feminized bub crosses I bet that's when
all of a sudden that you started you
know seeing that KATU found a KATU one
and then there was Ghost found one and
then there was the abusive
and is great right and then they all
just kind of came around around the same
time that that first feminized Bubba
cush cross came out it just makes you
things things that make do make a lot of
sense kind of does right but uh whether
they are or not I don't know it's just
funny that they were everywhere and
there's so many different fenos and it's
like well we all know that it's really
hard to get an identical feno from the
mall absolutely right you can but it's
there so but there's close and different
nuances and I think that's my personal
opin that's a lot The Story Goes is that
the Bubba Kush seeds that went out were
half OG Kush and half of a plant called
Bubba that was in or lights plant so
like norn lights OG Kush you cross them
you're GNA get OG Kush Expressions even
in the S1 you know what I mean like
absolutely and they may not be identical
to that Mom thata but they're close is
right it's like any S1 right
like the recessive pop out yeah yeah hoe
you mentioned peab but earlier was did
you ever hear of it referred to By Any
Other
Name well no I got to Colorado I lived
in Wyoming for a number of years before
I came to
Colorado by the time I got here it was
the Colorado pona Bud the peab bud if
you were lucky you knew somebody in that
specific area or
somebody you know local who knew
somebody um
and you could get it you know pretty
handily back in the day and um the
Clones were held really tightly by the
group in the valley was not something
that was readily shared with
Outsiders um at one point um I had the
Clone um but it was before I had a
medical debacle back before I met most
everybody and and uh I lost pretty much
everything I had after that and could
not get it back
um I am uh really hopeful ctg who had
was originally from
Colorado um who's now working with some
peab bud that he got from um assorted
sources um and I'm hoping that he gets
the gets it he's saying it's going in
the right Direction so I have really
good faith in him as far as his breeding
and abilities go so um it it was uh it
it was called the ponia paralyzer yeah
there you go there you go you to say it
yeah it had it had a couple of other you
know schnazzy names depending upon where
you were I happened to I happen to live
in the Denver area um but if you went up
north to like Fort Collins where CSU is
uh everybody referred to it as the
paralyzer everybody knew it was the same
bud and um you just could you couldn't
get the Piney taste out of your
mouth uh it was that really thick
beautiful heavy
smoke um that's perfect for a you know
nice Colorado night sitting out under
the stars or under a
campfire you know um if few years ago
one of
friends Mir hit me up and he's like hey
I have some um seeds and I didn't know
who Mir was at the time like that wasn't
from your guys's era I just thought he
was some guy on Facebook that people
knew that was kind of old school he's
like hey I have some Netherland purple
indicia but I'm pretty sure this is the
I think he said pona purple paralyzer
gave me the seeds of it and I was me
like oh maybe I should give these to
pebd because he called himself peab bud
so he's looking for it I've regretted
that ever since like I want to see in
those
things I actually gave to my friend Matt
Elite to give to PE but and I think they
stayed with Matt for whatever reason so
they may be coming back so I'm pretty
stoked about that see if we can get it
back yeah thumbs up there I'll tell you
what your
luck you know and like d said yeah it
may not be a perfect expression of what
what it was but it's just like uh it's
just like anything it's um you you
know
SGP it's still good pot right you know
we were joking about that you know uh
with the East Coast sour d which we got
back you know not that long ago and a
whole lot of people were like oh it kind
of grows funky it doesn't have really
tight nugs and and you hear people and
you're just like could you just smoke
it don't don't evaluate it based on the
fact that the name is from a 20-year-old
strain like evaluate it based on what it
does for you you know I mean it's still
as good today as it was 20 years ago
when we first got our hands on that's
what's up skdy sour dies thank you sky
thank
you someone identified it as the 96 cut
to
me if that Rings any bells there's so
many different cuts people talk about
now like they've named so many I mean I
think there's only a few Cuts back in
the day that people had and now there's
like 90 thanks to the different seed
lines and whatnot and people making
claims but yeah the one the one name
that I do hear attached to that a lot is
Mir too his name yep I've heard that he
was passing it with the 77
crew oh that's why I've heard yeah yeah
so were any of you guys in the 77 crew
I no no but I mean I'm good friends with
you
know several people who who definitely
were yeah you know we we were really
good friends skidy and I and and D may
even knew him we were good friends with
sco yeah who was a you know key member
of the
77 um and you know 77 himself too right
with right yeah yeah exactly we were
part of cool enough kids to be part of
that club yet
yeah back at back at that time we
weren't the cool kids well again like I
said D it was a different time people
were really you know after having
stairway got popped people went [ __ ]
tight lip it was like private s started
popping up everywhere and it was like
because like legit dude you could
[ __ ] go to jail in the states for a
long time Fu nobody was going to jail in
Canada right for growing weed ever and
even still now with it legal have to
really [ __ ] up to go to jail but in the
states dude like yeah W I was growing in
Louisiana you
know ended up at Angola yeah but you
were also you were also one of you know
you also were immediately like okay I
can open a private site and you did and
like you
salvaged right you salvaged how many of
us like right away from that Core group
of you know CW people that we've been
interacting with already for a number of
years I mean you know so so I did have
the racco lodge open before we did the
Cabana yeah yeah dude okay I yeah and
remember remember all the you know
remember all the people that were there
that AR you know we are we ar
necessarily in total contact with every
day now but I mean we had know bud
meiser and we had you know moonshine and
Dr you know Mr dank or Dr dank or what
you know we had we had the doctor you
know that's that's before the doctor
came and the reason he came and stayed
at my house is because he met me you
know through the Raccoon
Lodge you know uh when you know when he
needed a place to crash out here and
same as you you know like you know the
Raccoon Lodge tightened up a lot of our
friendships you know that we already had
because we moved from kind of becoming
friends in public and then being forced
into a private kind of smaller world
where some of us really bonded very well
together how the The Refuge of overgrows
this how essentially the as we're
getting into this the Raccoon Lodge into
the canic Cabana started then yeah we
were in TCB first wasn't that and then
TCB with clips and
C nugs yes
running and when they discontinued
that's when I think yall said Steve open
up a raccoon
Lodge something Incorporated everybody
from there into the Raccoon Lodge and I
think at that time that's when cannabis
world where we were all mostly hanging
out it was starting to get crazy like
you know there was the trolls from
overgrow were St starting to Mo you know
migrate over to you know I think there
was a shark tank at cannabis world to it
just started getting messy and it was
like you know that's when the sharing
was became a lot more private and where
the private sites came in much handier
right like you didn't want to really
broadcast so much then
exactly people were starting to realize
that it took work to find fenos and they
weren't so willing to just willy-nilly
throw them out there to just
a lot people started hoard strains
absolutely right well you know well and
again depending upon your perspective
because I remember at one of the big
parties in
California when you know I I first met
you know uh
inspector and um you know he was
explaining to me how he was a third
generation grower and that some of the
strange were in his family from his
grandfather's time yeah and that he had
made a family commitment not to share
them at that time um till he you know
till you know he had an agreement with
his father and grandfather that you know
they would come a point where he would
share them but it it wasn't then and he
was trying to explain to me that so does
it make
me you know a greedy person if I can't
share something that promised my father
and grandfather I wouldn't share no dude
it doesn't you know I I hold the man
he's a really great great guy and I
really love him for his principles he
was very firm in what he could and
couldn't share and you know he developed
that into a a huge you know situation
like he's got going on now and you know
God bless him he you know he didn't
betray his face family he didn't portray
his morals and he was able to do what he
you know he's still now and now he's
sharing those genetics yeah but he's
very still very very Hardline honest
probably one of the biggest influences
in my life on uh what I what i' model my
character and and how I carry myself uh
he is the most honest person I know it's
crazy I've seen people accidentally you
know send him
$14,000 and and him return it because
they didn't put you know what they
wanted and he doesn't want to give the
wrong thing it's it's crazy what I've
seen him do yeah wow yep the guy is just
a walking Book of
Knowledge you know
like when I when I met him in California
at one of the parties there it was like
dude he was so much younger than
everybody else too right it was like and
you know we're all do sampling these
strange you know [ __ ] try to go
through 32 strains in like two days or
something the Cannabis World Cup and and
here's the
inspector over there just like a college
kid taking an exam right he's like
[ __ ] just so serious and dude like
yeah pretty cool those were really fun
times like yeah we the parties were
[ __ ] Wild Man and and those parties
were W just walking books of knowledge I
mean just didn't matter what situation
you were in I'm a small scale really
little grower but I mean there were guys
with big outdoor grows there were guys
with big indoor grows guys with little
outdoor grows little indoor grows there
was just a full spectrum but they
included you know inspector shaba the
doctor Ross Oro NCGA demman you know the
over toes and the over toes Kendo you
know Kendo yeah God God bless Kendo you
know he and I he and I are brothers from
another mother that just don't see the
world from the same set eyes I love wild
man he is a wild man you know I I've
spent I spent a week um with him up on
one of his you know grows um when he was
still down in
Cali uh out in the boonies and it was a
crazy time he's a he's a super crazy
crazy guy um we had an episode with him
we have a full yeah we know I seen it
yeah you seen it yes sir yeah we we
watched we watch I'll just say for the
record when it came down to whose idea
it was for the secret mods at the Cabana
if Kendall thinks it was his idea
honestly dude that was [ __ ] 18 years
ago I don't know whose idea it was if he
says it was his he's probably right and
kudos to him for thinking about it the
only thing I'll say about that was was
it was shitty for me because all the
mods were hidden but it was me that
always had to go deliver the bad news or
deliver the punishment right it was
always like all these guys had secret
[ __ ] moderator handles right the big
banana or the Rock Lobster or something
right comes in Rowdy nudy you know
whatever but it was always d man that
was like hey you can't do that because
the mod team said well D man's an
[ __ ] well okay whatever have you lied
the crown bro that's how it goes I know
I know
right Kendall Kendall was a big part of
the command dud like getting the
commander up and running for sure dude
like yeah definitely um yeah same thing
with old SG
absolutely dude absolutely same same
thing with Muggles God Rest Soul Muggles
buckwhat buckwhat you know we there was
a couple other ones in there too that
just shout out to Funky nugs funky nugs
too yeah right funky nugs yes
yeah oh and JJ Jameson yeah J Jamon JJ
Jameson who still around and peaks in
now and again but you know we don't hear
from him much um but yeah we've you know
to this day we still see you know people
pop in and out from 20 years ago and
it's nice to know that some folks are
still rocking it
hard um got good good breeders like Jay
the case are still out there stash still
out there working hard yeah I think uh
jaay he's a New Zealand fellow too right
yes yes oh wow interesting he actually
popped in recently since the uh re
Reborn The Rebirth of the Cabana I think
so yeah saw he's still around yeah he's
still around so in terms of timeline
when was the the original kind of
inception of the Cabana December the 2nd
2006 my birthday wow yeah right I was
coming online that's how I remember it
yeah when uh cannabis World went down we
went over to the Raccoon Lodge Kitty
skdy hosted us there and uh we we sort
of just reached out to some members at
the Raccoon Lodge who we thought would
be a good fit you know like Muggles and
you know old so and you know buckweed
and Howie and obviously everybody
Ander we had a bunch of people help us
in the beginning you know absolutely and
then we just banged it out over five
months there you know we were just
racking ideas off each other's head what
would work what wouldn't work that's
where we kind of realized you know we
didn't want a shark tank no no politics
no politics uh we obviously thought that
you know Firearms wasn't a good fit and
uh uh we were we were unique like that
AB from some of the other sites
absolutely and I think a lot of people
didn't like us like that we were known
as the Carebears I think the
carear uh because it stood the test of
time though like doing it a certain way
keeping it a certain way keeping a
private all those years letting certain
people in sounds like you did it like an
onion where there were layers and you
involv certain people in fit better and
and molded better yeah absolutely and
when we first opened it you know we it
was sort of like if I'm not mistaken
these guys can correct me it was sort of
like we left the threads open somebody
would nominate somebody in and they
would kind of like get a vote on it and
then we started realizing that that's
not really fair you know everybody sort
of deserves a second chance if if a
member a current member is vouching for
them well they're putting their account
on the line we felt that was good enough
so we just started locking those threads
for nominations if somebody wanted you
in dude you were in it was simple as
that
yeah and it worked good that way for a
long time we had a lot of participation
and then when Colorado went legal then a
lot of people came in from Colorado like
so it just like a boom that's when Kirby
and you know Green mofo and all those
guys even back Big Sir it was just it
was we had influx of members there right
is that when Tiara Rojo got
into Roo came in Paco came in for a
while came in everybody came in for a
little while especially a anybody who
was friends with Kirby yeah when Kirby
came in just a whole influx of guys in
his kind of little Core group at that
time came in with him and um
you know a lot of them have have always
been members some have just popped back
in Paco popped back in not that long ago
as well I know Paco yeah um I think it's
great to see um just the fact that
there's a renewed
interest we were you know we were on a I
was the last captain of the ship these
two guys ahead of me Led Led the place
for a lot of years and had everything
going pretty good but but you know uh as
people age in attrition and you don't
have as many older members meeting new
people to invite
in we became kind of the road to you
know self defeating prophecy where you
know I
was you know I was asking people for
donations and looking at the thing as a
dinosaur like when when do we go extinct
when we run out of when we run out of
donations yeah the key the key to me is
kind of like what do what do I do to
help lead the ship into a new era
and you know that's where curbs comes in
you know the the the line on the story
you know when did you guys start talking
about doing that with curb about maybe
Changing Hands he he approached
me in all honesty to my my two friends
sitting here in all honesty Kirby
approached me last year last summer um
early in the
summer um Steve was having an off
season Darren was in the
hospital I kind of hinted something to
Darren about it way back then and he
seemed really amable to potentially
letting Kirby you know take
over but Steve's POS you know situation
was such that he and I weren't able to
actually communicate out you know what
Kirby wanted to do so I kind of kept it
in the back of my head and I literally
said to Kirby you know give me some time
you know let let Darren get out of the
hospital let you know let Steve get
through his stuff everything everything
magically worked itself out and Kirby
actually called me that week and said
hey you you talk to those guys anymore
and I go no but I will right now I'll
call you back in a little while hung up
phone with them called D that was
actually a
Friday Y and
uh then called Cur back and said dude
you're the man you you've got you've got
a plan you've got an idea it'll save us
from going
extinct I really like the
concept we've always worried you know as
we've gotten
older things have become more legal when
Darren originally took this thing on
under his belt he had to worry about
Canadian laws Canadian
police I was living here in Colorado
where things were always fairly
mellow Steve who was bouncing from
Louisiana to New York and then
eventually ended up here thanks to you
know some coaxing from my family and I
yes got him out to a good place you know
a place we knew he'd be able to
establish
and here we all are you know it's years
later and the S side still running
itself just fine when I took it over it
was still running itself just fine
nothing wrong with the site except that
as older members pass and we've lost a
lot of good
people as people's situations change and
they leave and don't come back
back you've got you know a handful of
guys who are between 40 and you know 80
years old we're not bringing on any new
blood can I interrupt and ask you know
what did you guys think of Instagram
when it was coming online I don't even
know when that was now I think about it
um but how weird of you how were aware
of Instagram were you guys when it was
emerging or how when did you guys look
at it and think ah this is this is like
the new form that people are
communicating in if it weren't for
Darren and St talking to me about
Instagram I'm the least
technologically uh inclined of the
group Darren starts telling me yeah you
don't have to go to like you know IC or
you want to look at Pop pictures you
just have to go to this this new thing
I'm like new thing yeah yeah the most
people just post
pictures and there's like thousands of
and I like fishing and fish just yeah
you could go and look at thousands of
fish and fishing pictures I'm like
really he goes yeah you can go and look
at thousands of pot and pot pictures I'm
like oh
really shean poot exactly right yeah so
now you got me interested yeah it was
really D and Steve who got me to even
understand that there was something out
there doing that kind of stuff well I
actually joined Instagram in 2015 I'm
not sure when it came out the only
reason I joined is because um my young
daughter at the time I don't how old
would she be then she would be 15 um she
had Instagram account and I don't know
she was telling me she had all these
followers from school and I'm like okay
well I'll download this app and you know
I follow my daughter dude she's got 870
[ __ ] people following on Instagram
right I'm like what the [ __ ] is this who
are these people following my little
girl right yeah right I just tear a
strip off her get off that platform G
she's like Dad they have pot pictures
I'm like what wait what
what I started looking oh [ __ ] dude
there's like really cool pot pictures on
I started finding people I know from the
Cabana like oh this guy's over here too
cool how do I work this right so for me
it was 2015 and yeah I just never really
looked back I was it was kind of cool me
because we had such old V bulletin
software at the the command it was like
it was really hard to post pictures
because it really sucked right it hard
uplo it was hard right didn't like it
right so it was like Instagram was easy
so I seen right away dude like once I
seen that dude there's like thousands of
cannabis accounts there I was like wow
this this is the new trend okay I think
the forums are going to go really bye
bye now right yeah uh luckily I don't
think that happened dude I don't it
turned out obviously as we all know
Instagram sucks yes yes they suck for
yeah I would love to hear your thoughts
on on that as
well I've got six sorry I've got 6,000
followers on Instagram and any time I
make a post nice 10 10 people like it
yeah know it's like I just like dude I'm
not even a big guy you know it just says
I sell cannabis seeds or you know I
breed cannabis seeds and that's enough
algorithm says no [ __ ] you dude you
nobody I know the feeling yeah not even
your followers right so it's like yeah
it sucks dude and I see like all these
big accounts you know like like CSI and
you know like he's
got you know a quarter of a million
followers and he's got like you know
five accounts and they all have the same
because they're all backup accounts
because one gets banned or shut down and
he just has to start it's just it's a
Time suck dude it really it's really bad
and that's when came in and said dude
let's make the forums relevant again you
know you can post pictures and on the
Forum it doesn't really it was never
about
pictures for for the rebranding or the
rebirth it was just about you know the
comments making it more uh relevant for
the communication of the plant you know
on Instagram you can't do that you know
so one I'll interrupt here and just say
that one thing we've discussed in the
past is like how kind of going back to
some of the early points you guys made
how well connected you all were and how
meaningful those connections were uh one
thing about Instagram is obviously
everyone's quite alienated and quite
isolated and you have these very uh
brief interactions with people on a post
and then the next day it's gone right I
mean not it's not gone but like you're
gonna have to go find it in the abyss of
the
timeline and so you don't really have
that kind of accumulation of history as
you would on a forum
thread or or the the interaction you
know from the original poster whoever
posts that awesome pick you know they
can post their little description of
what this is but it's not indicative of
having a conversation you know or or
even asking a question you know it's
like we need the help desks again we
need these breeders to have their own
fors where they can you know communicate
with their customers and it's just like
if you look at the Ganda now just about
every breeder that has their own form
there dude they've been an original
member like great either from inception
or from the Colorado influx of 2012 like
you know and some of these guys are
[ __ ] huge breeders right like so as
we all know and that's what they need if
we can get content there and get their
customers to come and interact with them
we know they're busy people but you know
even like inspecta dude he's chiming in
people are posting stuff about his
strains and that's what we wanted we
wanted place for the Breeders to be able
to talk to the customers you know and
and answer some
questions like it used to be you know
like get away from the Instagram yeah
you can post the pretty pictures there
but we know that when you know inspector
posts a pick dude it's not hitting a
quarter of a million followers like ex
it's if he hits
1% maybe two% I don't know like whereas
you know I'm not saying you I'm not
being naive saying that we're going to
replace Instagram it's not a about the
pitchers at the command it's about the
interaction and about even the smaller
guys like these upand cominging breeders
that's who we really want to help give
them a platform that Instagram can't do
like these guys are just a shadow band
with you know a thousand followers just
because they're posting cannabis
pictures well come over to the Cabana
dude what Kirby's giving it [ __ ] free
ring dude post your seeds post your
Groves you know we're going to
eventually you know hopefully have a
maybe sort of like a cbay kind of
platform you know like that would be
cool for up and cominging breeders again
get a name right yeah absolutely
absolutely yeah so just to make it
really clear to the the people listening
um and watching the can Cabana is now
open again oh absolutely just to be
really clear yeah we haven't actually
said that but yeah yeah inviting people
to go check it out it went back public
100% on January 1 so dude please
register uh it's it's wide open you can
look at the Forum now um you can see the
18 years of History that's there from
everything that that has been posted um
lots of skdy pck Skitty grows I'm sure
there's a few Howie grows in there lots
of dman grows but uh if you want to post
you got to register you know so it's
we're it's not a hard ask uh you can
read it it's there for you to read we
hope that you see something that entices
you to make you want to join um because
there's up in coming things there's
things that are coming you know um
probably some giveaways you know we're
going to have some Cabana packs things
like that with some seeds maybe from
some upand cominging
breeders you know we just want to see
people posting their grows and if we can
help like as we still know lots of
people are still just new Growers right
now we're seeing it in the Cabana you
know people are saying I'm just got two
or three grows under my belt this is
kind of cool it's like yeah we forgot
about that you know we all got so tired
of answering the same old questions over
and over again that we forget that dude
we have to pass this knowledge on yeah
we can't we can't just not you know
can't rely on other people just to do it
for us they're probably more new Growers
now than ever
before definitely Point yeah
um and they have so many more tools than
we had right you know LED lights and you
know yeah all all the cool toys to have
right
and so everybody knows Kirby was
supposed to be here but he got stuck in
an airport so yes a separate episode
with him or another one of these because
there's there's so much absolutely we
got to get Kirby here because you know
we can we can give you the whole history
of how we got to the gavana but it's
Kirby's idea and his baby from here dude
and he's got big plans and he's going to
make forums relevant again you know like
we're not going to say we're going after
other forums but dude we're going after
other forms yeah yeah the the ones that
were there like I I don't have any good
relationship with them honestly my my
whole my whole relationship with that
was I would go to a forum it was usually
run by someone who ran a seed bank
they'd see I have a seed company if I
don't interact with them in certain ways
I'd be banned and that's really my my
whole experience of form didn't happen
that way with you guys and that's really
what happened at the Cabana you know the
original because that was part of the
other things that we had like we said no
seed sales you know we didn't want any
seed spam so we literally by policy
pushed all of our
friends I'm still scared of post and
Seed stuff there bro like it feels so
weird it's all good now dude Kirby said
it's good to go Rowdy NY Rowdy NY he's
retired dude
we but the reality is
that we need a new approach to move
ahead the dinosaur either collapses and
goes extinct or we move ahead
having had all those parties and
interacted with a lot of guys who are 20
or 30 years younger than me who have
other aspirations and ideas which I
wasn't thinking about or didn't didn't
ever think about I guess um you know
really brings a whole new perspective to
what what we want to do we don't
you know we remember the days when at
seed Bay you know like if you bought
something from you know doc green thumbs
and you had a question and you posted up
in his help Forum like what do how do I
grow this or how long does you know yeah
you get either him to answer himself or
one of his helpers or you know a group
of four or five other people would jump
in and answer and try to help and that's
part of what you know is missing out
there is yeah it's easy to go buy a pack
of
seeds but what do you expect from it
yeah you know and it's good to have
people you know I mean that's how my
relationship with d my relationship with
Moto Rebel you know was all based on
beta testing they relied on me to be
honest which I brutally
was
both and you know and I and I always
tried to be as descriptive as I could so
if somebody put themselves in my shoes
you know all right I'm gonna grow a few
of
these I could give them an easy way show
them the picture show them the root show
them the plant through several stages
and then show them Buds and flower and
then show them a finished picture and
then you know I think de appreciated
that it it allowed us to become you know
personal
friends um way back you know before it
was Posh to be friends with someone on
the internet I I think we also knew that
intrinsically him being in you know
Canada and me being in Colorado we were
absolutely no harm to each
other but we became you know we're we're
the three of us right here with the
three students we're brothers absolutely
guys are brothers brothers that's it
I don't only a brother only a brother
would fly down to Canada to his other
brothers in New York City I'm in a
[ __ ] truck and move him to
Colorado without him without right yeah
oh and that's an awesome story as
well another time when there's enough
time but yes Darren drove a 18wheeler
with all my life's possessions from the
Bronx to Littleton Colorado wow when
when my flight was delayed and I was
supposed to accompany him yeah that that
is a brother right there EXC me when the
house sale was delayed yeah yeah that's
what it was yeah but it it was it was uh
oh it's a great story dude you gotta I
gotta tell it now the night before the
cop Sky lives next door to a New York
City Cop oh narcotics in his basement
she was a Narcotics detective and she
was not nice so never that she she was
not nice she did not get along with skdy
so we got this [ __ ] giant new hul
truck loaded up with all skitty's
possessions in the driveway and it's a
shared driveway with the the cop and
skdy right skiny doesn't I I own it she
had to ride away through it to get to
her parking spot in the back and all the
time that I lived there over five years
she abused her Privileges and she parked
her cop car right there in my driveway
blocking everybody from using the
backyard are you [ __ ] kidding me and
after a while I got pissed and I'd start
knocking on her door and asking her to
move her freaking cop car and this is
all the while like she'd stand in the
driveway talking on the phone underneath
my second story air conditioner dripping
Sour Diesel on
[Laughter]
her anyways we we had all stuff loaded
on the truck right before we're ready to
leave right and then the next skinny and
I we we hop on the subway we go down the
Time Square go get some dumplings or
something just to chill out do some last
minute tour stuff for me we come back as
soon as we walk around the corner sk's
walk there's [ __ ] cop cars everywhere
right [ __ ] we're like holy [ __ ]
what's going on right we walk up to the
driveway well here's the lady cop being
a [ __ ] Karen get this [ __ ] truck
out of the driveway get this truck out
of the driveway right and meanwhile it's
like it's dark and on skiddy street
there's parking on both sides of the
street at night in New York City this is
the Bron we got this in the Bronx we got
this giant like 26 foot truck there the
cop says well you're gonna have to move
your truck and I'm like move it where I
can't even get out of the [ __ ]
driveway
dude tow it we're going to tow it I'm
like dude go for it go for it right now
I want to see you tow call the tow truck
right now let's see this right the truck
was there they couldn't do it because
they didn't have the space to pull the
truck out with attached to the tow
truck so tight people parked right up to
the driveways and stuff oh yeah there's
no way you were getting a [ __ ] tow
truck in there to get this giant truck
so anyways the cop had to tell the the
lady Karen cop dude just shut the [ __ ]
up they're leaving at 6 o' in the
morning morning just stop being a [ __ ]
and go to bed skinny and I went in the
house got high and I [ __ ] left the
next morning and drove to Colorado and
ended up at Ho's house with a giant
truck in front of its house I should
still think about that horrible
woman anyway sorry to Sidetrack that was
just a funny funny story of moving skidy
out New York to Denver she was kind of a
Top Cop she actually escorted Escobar
when he was no no no um
who's the one that they brought here and
Chapo El Chapo Chapo she escorted El
Chapo at one point if I'm not mistaken
and she made made herself a name with
that
now
uninvolved in said truck you guys left
out a very important part of the
story so you know Darren left Steve's
house and New York headed for
Colorado and you know the average speed
limit between here and there is
like oh you know 65 to as much as 75
miles an
hour Darren calls me from I want to say
it was like somewhere near Ames
Iowa seems like he should be
closer why the truck wouldn't move out
of low gear oh no it's it's got a
governor on it right so this truck is
it's not doing more than 55 on a
downhill slope
dude I remember going through the
Poconos like [ __ ] a crawl up [ __ ]
10 miles hour like dude this is gonna
take me [ __ ] forever what did I sign
up
for I was I was supposed to be with him
but my house sale was delayed so I had
to stay an extra day in New York and
Darren was on a time schedule to get
this done then he had to be back to
Canada oh
wow well like you said that's a brother
that is a brother brother yeah Darren
huge points that
day anyways it's cool that and then how
he let me stay there in his basement for
a month or whenever till I rented my
first house yep so this is where the
forums could could lead and I'm sure
we're just one of many lifelong
friendships that those old forms you
know uh started you know like uh for
sure like I I know these guys still talk
to other people that uh from from years
ago you know like uh it was a fun time
and it it would be nice to make forums
fun again um what I you know I don't
want to even jinx us but uh we we've had
no real trolls or anything like that I
don't know if trolls aren't a thing or
if they just no they're definitely a
thing oh well dude like but I'll tell
you one thing Kirby's not going to have
any [ __ ] any patience for that but it
seems very cool dude the receptions has
been very cool um we almost got a
thousand new members since we opened up
January 1 so awesome not just barely two
months dude like you know it's not huge
or anything but dude I'm grateful like
that's awesome that's new blood people
probably going to you know dip their
toes in the water and feel how it is you
know because they might have bad
experience with other forums like you
said Matt right I'm the king of the bad
experiences of forums bro all of them I
think I I you know whatever but uh real
real quick can I please give a shout out
to detective Diane spangenberg in New
York Bronx yayy what's up
Dian Diana
spangenberg
Stenberg spank Spang I think a Spang and
n and and a
Berg well the way we made a lot of
lifelong friends you know absolutely
dude some really cool people have passed
dude like some really cool people like
you
know yeah it's just like you know it's
like 20 years is a long time you know
like and we're older you know you guys
are a lot younger and uh I'm sure you
guys are going to do it all Justice I
know Kirby's going to do everything this
dude it's like uh he has mad respect for
us um we have mad respect for him for
what he's doing um we love him like a
brother um we wish him nothing but
success uh yes absolutely 100% dude
we're behind him we support him and
we're gonna be here to help him uh I
don't know you know how Hands-On we be
like without skitty's being a huge help
to us right now like dude since uh
switching over to the new sen4 software
and all that oh I bet sky skdy has been
like the go-to guy we've been rocking
his socks off dude and he's just been
like a trooper I'm
thegeek we're still waiting to get the
rest of our smilees back but we'll get
there one day I'm sure I've been
busy I had a
hard I was going to say too that uh for
our little collaboration here this is
also potentially just a beginning like I
don't know EX what kinds of shows we'll
do with the Cabana and you guys in the
future but I can see lots of
possibilities like we could do
little uh highlight segments from the
Cabana we could do really topical ones
if you guys want we could let you guys
host your own show if you want so I
think there's lots of interesting
opportunities to come I think three of
us might like to do some comedy
skits
together you guys you guys is like uh uh
what do you call it symbiotic nature
with each other and how how each other's
balls like it's perect love it dude and
like you know I'm sure like Kirby he
he's got Big Ideas he wants to do events
um he wants to get the Cabana out there
and you know he get some merch going and
stuff like that and you know more
podcasts things like that you know for
sure uh definitely uh I want you guys to
have a Discord Channel too I think
that's that's gonna be part of
it the Discord thing and we we stumbled
famously well I'll help you guys if you
need can I have many more Bronx tailes
oh I love those yeah bet you have tons
there we do have the Discord uh thing uh
loaded up on the site but none of us
really know how to use
it not true sorry use it I I use Discord
all the time for playing Pokemon go oh
well you know I I've played the game as
well I like that game sometimes very
entertaining like we need to get Howe
into ours then yeah I think how need
meet Denali don't you think like him and
Denali like we have a friend that's
probably about your age but he's also a
fish a fisherman extraordinaire he's
about to go fishing with uh someone real
famous in our community and um he's also
a weed guy and those two things I mean
you guys would get along
just dude yeah he likes to like he says
the tug is the drug tug is the drug
that's how I got along with you know I I
met you know dem man through Growing
Seeds I met skiddy through trading buds
I met buckwheat back in the day because
he posted up at
CW way back in the day a picture of a
fly he tied for bass
fishing and I literally was like it was
really a beautiful handtied frog with
movable arms and I was super impressed I
can't tie anything like that and uh God
bless him he sent me a box of them you
know we became good friends him me and
wayos went fishing a couple of
times um you know half of it was for me
was just meeting new people putting
myself out there and man the community's
just been a a great thing you know oh
for sure dude absolutely we're still
waiting for waos to come back seen him
strolling he needs he needs a little tug
as the
drug I need to I need to get him on some
fishing or something and try to twist
his arm I really like that tug is the
drug thing that's great
yeah that's how he tagline that's my
tagline yeah this has been awesome like
the the Cabana is going to be way
different than the other forms yeah
similar in the whole question and answer
thing but we're not going to to have any
troll [ __ ] like that and it's going
to be like fun again we're going to make
it fun we're going to have contests
we're going to have you know
news you know it's all it's all new like
it's all up to date and everything yeah
there's a lot of post to read through
and we encourage everybody to read every
last one of them dude like there's so
much knowledge there all 18,000 Pages
there's such a value there like I was I
was I wrote down here but I don't I know
we didn't bring up yet but like the
free-for-all Clone like most people
don't know about that anymore that was a
big thing with you guys
right sorry what the freefor all free
for all yeah the
FFA you guys remember that one was that
over your head it was it was a it was a
oh my God now it's over my head we
talking a strain yeah it was a specific
stra that was passed out there I think
it was a mass super
scum I I don't remember that one no I
don't remember that one either but there
are so many in lot during my era yeah
yeah that's
funny well sometimes it's hard for us to
stay relevant because we want to still
grow the old school strains where a lot
of people just like 1980 just called
they said they want their pounds
[Laughter]
back um and that's the thing for me dude
I I popped so many seeds and including
so many of so much of my own gear it's
just hard to remember standouts like
there were so many standouts but you
know you're always just moving on CH so
many seeds and and if you didn't pop
them like as we know they're just going
to go to waste dude like yes still even
me you know ien I haven't bred a seed
since 2017 and 2018 and I literally have
like millions of seeds like what am I
going to [ __ ] do with them right it's
like I live and and and story of my life
I've given away far more seeds than I've
ever sold like I think we all have
right
buiness I gave away like most of my
collection because they were just going
to go stale just like these JoJo packs
or the JoJo over there which is I'm at
that point too 20 years old it's like
yeah well and not everybody stored
everything good so I'm hoping that you
know there you know tissue culture or
embryo Resurrection
yeah maybe that's something you know
dude cuz I am sitting on some pretty old
seats that were not stored properly that
I just would love to get to you know
some free 911 stuff but that's you gotta
keep
cross I have stuff dude from you know
that goes back to the late 90s
ridiculous right start busting some
seeds man some of the original stuff
that we got and I I wouldn't even know
what to do with it if I germed it you
know I have such limited capacities to
do that I gotta find somebody who wants
them though that's the problem send me a
list we'll find some people that'll pop
them for sure that's probably the idea I
forget I forget who said it but it was
one of the the wisest you know comments
I ever heard or read on a forum was that
if everybody just took a single pack out
of their collection and just started
them just one talk everybody and just
see what's there dude we could find the
new new from the [ __ ] old time right
like and that's all it would take you
know few thousand people just popping a
pack from like the [ __ ] early
2000s yep absolutely kill cookies and
kill cook thank you thank you I'm on
that path man like I I'm still on the
blueberry path where we like finding old
blueberry for me meant the world you
know and finally we locked it down got
something that's true truly blueberry
tasting and smelling and you could pop a
pack of seeds and they're all clones of
each other you know oh that's cool dude
long time to get that that Tony guy his
blueberry was [ __ ] so he originally
sourced his from DJ Short so it was the
same stuff but it was it was a very
early generation before it was super
inbred with just a few plants it was
before that so it still had a lot of
open space you could still find that
super actually blueberry smelling
planto after a while was just gone so it
was all about chasing those down yeah
the one I had back in the late
80s early
90s um that was a sativa is and just
little sparse little little popcorn nugs
up up down and the stems were blood red
yep seriously and it just you could
smell one blueberry plant over a whole
room of another strain I I got something
for you brother I got some cool [ __ ] for
you promise you I think you're going
like it okay it's exactly that it's red
stemmed super blueberry oh The Taste was
so wonderful yeah that's been my biggest
Chase in life and like once I found it I
I haven't left in like six years now
same thing anything else and I can't
believe I let that go along with the DJ
Short flow yeah flow is cool we have
that too we kept that around too the
actually is Dutch Passion
flow well it was
passion buy a pack of those original
blueberries it was my first ever grow
you know where I didn't grow bag seed
and of course I knew nothing about
cloning yeah she's have these beautiful
blueberry plants that stink like
blueberry pie and have these beautiful
red stems yep and of course I could
never get them again yeah yeah um Dutch
Passion DJ Short sold his seeds through
them after SE mattha
yeah I thought they even used his stock
or whatever but later on they used his
stock themselves this was this was back
late late 90s I want I want to say that
this was before I move before I moved
from New Orleans to New York
um sorry we definitely we definitely got
all that we definitely got all that in
Spade so I I i' like to see what
Canadian guys that that love blueberry
think and some of you guys that have had
it before I think it'd be a fun fun
journey and there's I haven't tasted
anything like that since that was just
it was so oh I got a garden I can get
them into there that's not a problem
yeah yeah I got you guys covered I got
you guys covered on it for sure happy
too how how you want to run any you I
got you too brother yeah oh yeah yeah
definitely that experience is smelling a
real blueberry plant that doesn't smell
like skunk doesn't smell like anything
else but just truly blueberry jam it
blows people's minds when they smell it
and see it taste it my story was when I
was living in New Orleans I lived in a
50y old house and I had a grow in the
back bedroom back of the house
overlooking the backyard and if I was
down outside in the backyard I could
smell the one or two blueberry plants
over everything else growing in the room
at that point those were the first seeds
I ever got actually this is even well
before I was on the Internet or anything
and a friend of a friend went to
Amsterdam and brought back SE there one
strain was mind
control one was Valley
Girl maybe it was just the two strains
but it was a there was valley girl and
the mind control and they were both
phenomenal strains yeah and of course
the lost to history at least for me but
we still talk about the weed me and some
old friends to the
St but why did I even bring that up um
blueberry smelling out the window okay
yeah the Dutch the Dutch cluster the D
it was a room full room full of valley
girl and just a couple of bluberry
plants would just overtake all that
strain I'd smell and this is before I
was smart enough to use carbon filters
or even knew about carbon
filters was barely on the internet then
and so I had like a real stink going on
man and fortunately it was in a part of
town where no one probably either gave a
[ __ ] or if anything they would not nark
me out just rob my
house anyway this is way back in my
ghetto growing career back back in the
day uh I was growing with 4inch Rockall
cubes in rows of rain gutters that I set
up on a
tilt with one gutter at the end to catch
from all the other drains going into a
reservoir
and for as horrible as the system really
was it got some really good results this
was
888 is
88 dude I think skinny pioneered a lot
of
good no no I'm sorry that was 90 was 993
is excuse me the 80s I was in
Minneapolis I used to do I got my start
in Minneapolis
um like I might have mentioned no
internet nothing this is way back in the
late 80s and had to go Source books from
it was shinder books on henin had some
obscure weed growing books and started
out with that uh was able to Source some
Rockwell professional lights we didn't
even know anything about so we went to
some like building supply store and we
bought a street light like a great great
big metal halight and we strung that up
in the
basement yeah when when I first saw my
dad's girls he was stealing metal haides
off street lights first I ever saw
indoors were my dad's like that yeah we
had a metal metal haide and we grew in
South Minneapolis was my start I do guy
up here that used to go to uh Public
Works auctions and buy old street lights
right from the for the old
municipalities when change the street
like he just go buy the old [ __ ] D
Ste just steal them new bulb in it good
as new yeah there you go right you scrap
the whole arm part and scrap metal and
just keep the [ __ ] light
part that's no dude never never
underestimate the Ingenuity of a
cannabis grower that's right that's
right they can turn Apple into a pipe
bro
[ __ ] I turn rain gutters into a hydro
system yeah you probably develop
nutrient film technique yourself bro
exactly I was gonna say dude people have
been copying Skitty tech for a long time
as long as I remely Skitty Tech is is
like the bomb yeah that's legit too
there's only one thing to skdy Tech you
got to follow what the dude
says
100% Sky Tech I've had more than a few
people ask me you know oh can I change
up the NES a little bit in the rockel
cubes no absolutely not like go talk to
skdy he's gonna tell you no exp way you
want the results you gota you gotta
follow the recipe it's like Bak good
good baked goods you know and that's why
people will wait for skinny pox right
because they know yep um and that's also
why you'll hear hear me rant one day
about all this crop steering crap with
where they push the high ppms I hope
none of you guys are super crop steering
fans because no I can rip on it and
Darren many years ago Darren talked me
into trying a very low PPM grow with my
rock bull less is more less is more more
and while I did switch to EC instead of
PPM anymore I still keep it low and I
grow it like a 1.0 I try telling the
same thing like like you don't
necessarily need to raise the nutrients
until it's telling you to do it until
you see exact why would you push like
that you get the resins and the flavors
and everything once you start pushing
that you lose it to trade out for weight
and everything else exactly and then
they're
like oh my God they're getting like a
runoff of three point something yeah
right are you are you buying it for good
weed or are you buying it for biomass
right biomass right yeah they're growing
it for the biomass I I think yeah they
really are it's like you know they're
all using you know I guess salt
nutrients nowadays I guess got really
popular whatever bulk whatever I still
use pure blend pure blend Pro hard to go
bad with that dude that has great flavor
in it I grow in dirt he grows in dirt
this old man I grow in dirt reality
reality of growing the dirt is like I'm
very small scale I grow for me my family
and the reality is that yeah I can look
at at the Gary Payton you know I can get
a clone from Steve of of Gary Payton I
can grow it he can grow it his is gonna
yield you know twice three times as much
as mine in some cases the way you know
he grows and the way he pushes
things but we both have different needs
sure so I go for you know I go for what
I'm going to
consume you know what comfort me is part
of getting my hands dirty I used to be
an archaeologist so oh wow I didn't know
that yeah so I like playing the dirt um
a lot so it's it's always been you know
it just was a natural easy way and again
before the internet you know when I
picked up a few books it suggested that
the easiest way to learn was growing in
dirt I have and I I've you've been using
the same basic formula now for almost 20
years nothing changes I love
it I got a man providing me a great set
of
clones so it's always great that's how
it goes so is there anything else you
want to get in before we wrap this
episode I have a feeling I'm gonna be
doing a lot more with you guys this is a
we got we gotta get we have to we have
to do it earlier gonna join us you need
it earlier yeah I'm actually nocturnal I
was supposed to be in Dead about four
and a half hours
ago I'm at the total end of my day and I
that my wife has brought
me that's
lovely I've been I've been taking bites
while I've been putting my head off
you've been trying to sneak it off off
the
camera just been
smoking I'm mostly pet my cats and I
took two bong hits well that'll work uh
dude all I have to say uh to finish off
if that's where we're going is dude we
got to get Kirby on here because the
next part is like it's it's where we're
going dude it's a this he made us do
this I I we busted his balls I I busted
all your balls by proxy to get you it
was it was well worth it to be honest
mat you've been busting my balls even
longer than that oh yeah oh yes yeah
yeah that's what I'm known for I'll say
shout out to De man for helping me
coordinate as well like de man
you know send on the info yeah yeah no
problem D thank you guys for having us
on it's a
pleas yes fun I appreciate the sorry the
opportunity to speak yep same here dude
appreciate the opportunity uh just tell
it how it happened you know as much as I
remember want to sit at the table with
The Syndicate check out our patreon and
our link tree or description below our
merch site is officially live we have
all sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies
to sort you out and shipping is super
fast and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out