ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
[Music]
i found this pack and i was like oh my
god there's a shitload of jesus ones in
here
oh there you go cool
but then i remember these are the fake
display seats that i used to put on the
counter at emerald cup so oh snag them
they wouldn't get anything
damn
got by myself
you know
like i can't tell you uh how much it
makes me sad sometimes when i find old
seeds yeah and then none of them pop
yeah it goes from like hope and
excitement and joy
to like worry to like oh man yeah
right i just got this in and i'm gonna
show it off because it's our buddies
this is this is seriously a nice [ __ ]
presentation like the terpene kits from
crybaby
this is i mean
that's nice dude yeah it's like pro fish
i mean it'll be good
he's down we got a plan to have him on
to talk turkey i know i just wanted to
show it off for him so people can see
before we do the episode
hey it's pretty professional there's all
kinds of cards in here that just that
describe everything it tells you how to
go through it
uh lots of tips and tricks
cool
what's interesting about it is like they
uh you know they have those kind of
things for perfumes and like yeah i had
some friends that were studying because
i live in wine country right like
studying to be someone yays yeah and in
order to do that
back then like this is like 18 years ago
or something they would buy these like
thousand dollar kits
yeah and the aromas were there to teach
them
like what an advanced taster was tasting
or smelling when they like you know were
talking about merlot or whatever and
they were talking about woodsy notes
with hints of raspberry and all that
they had to be able to like learn the
language
and so they had like a whole book and
all these scents and all this different
stuff and so for terpenes with weed it's
like
teaching people how to talk about smell
yeah that's a big part it's a you know
thing but you can if you can do it too
and it's probably like most breeders and
weed nerds biggest
weakest weak area yeah i know it is for
me i'm not i'm not a terp expert by any
stretch of the imagination no definitely
not neither am i you know and neither
are a lot of our friends yeah
you know so i mean there's an aspect
where it's like
it's just you just lack the language
because you don't encounter how to talk
about that language
anywhere yeah really
terpenes and like wine sommeliers it's
all about using your eyebrows
and like
and your eyes to express
yeah you know i mean it it uh
it's and then it's okay and then it's
all relative to that human being's
ability to taste
yeah
i have i have a really bad sense of
smell
so my taste is really off too you know
like the whole the whole shebang sucks
up upstairs here in this region right
yeah the whole
everything everything in this region is
sucking
we're slowly climbing up there yeah yeah
it's weird when i have to do it on this
[ __ ] account like most people don't
know to follow it even though i said it
so hopefully still
shadow band or whatever on the other one
from doing live
i checked it this morning and it was
like nope you cannot do lives
oh man yeah well it is what it is
it is what it is i'm used to it by now
but yeah no people should we're gonna do
a whole episode i'm not exactly sure
when but we're going to have our our
buddy crybaby on and he
has a lot of knowledge and language
around aromas terpenes scents
what causes smells what are the
components of it and he'll be able to
speak a lot more intelligently than
either matt or i can
uh yeah i think you know
so uh that'll be soon i hope
he was the one that was uh first telling
me to stop calling skunky [ __ ] terps i
was like oops yeah they're like theol's
and like yeah but what's interesting
about that is even like the uh and we're
like rambling for a while waiting for
people to show up but even
what's interesting about you know the
thing about theolos and stuff is how
they're volatile
yeah right where terpenes are longer
lasting and i would always notice about
the old super skunk that i had
that the last two or three weeks before
harvest and the first month after
cutting it it was just rank
yeah but if you kept it long enough even
if and you know in a nice jar in the
dark or whatever it would eventually
just kind of turn into generic green bud
did you find that the more it kept its
moisture content the longer it lasted in
the morning as it oh yeah certainly yeah
it was actually kind of tough because it
was one of those nugs that you were like
it was famous for like looking dense but
weighing light yeah yeah you put this
thing that you think was like a huge nug
and you're like oh man this thing's
massive and it's like 2.8 grams
yeah it just it had like but it had
really good like air to air to bud ratio
so it burned really well yeah cherry ink
is very similar usually snappers of it
uh some bud like like kush's especially
and a lot of this cookie [ __ ] um you
really have to cure it right to get it
to burn well yeah
you know um but but
uh you know super skunk you could burn
that like pretty quick
because it just had like a good amount
of air
it sounds like denali saved that cut
from uh panda
oh that's good yeah i'm real stoked
about that
so we're up over we're 100 and 810
people maybe we could start chatting
yeah do you want to answer a few
questions first and then maybe it'll get
up higher a little bit yeah i haven't
even [ __ ] looked to be honest i've
just been bullshitting
um someone just asked about mango haze i
could talk about mango haze there you go
mango
mango haze is like a super nice um
line from shanti baba and neville
it's uh nl5 haze by skunk haze it's a
sister to super silver haze and it uses
this famous cut called the 122 or the
mango which is like my favorite nl5 haze
cut and it's still alive over there i
think it's still shown in coffee shops
and uh johnsy has it apparently
um yeah but yeah it's it's a little bit
more hazy it's a little it's a little
like it's got a little bit more of the
flavors that i like it's got less
terpenoline than super silver haze it
doesn't tend to yield as much
um
but uh but it's a super nice plant and i
think it's likely one of the ones where
he still has the right parents yeah i
can't say for nobody can say for sure
but i think
people still find really nice plants in
that line yeah they do
so it's not just a there is a clone only
mango haze too i believe i don't know if
it's from the same seed line but i know
miami mango has that one and it's it's
like uh terpenoline and mango it's it's
it's one of my favorites it's like uh
i've seen some tests on it and it's
terpene content it's pretty off the
charts yeah it's pretty high
um and uh yeah so that's mango haze it's
kind of mango haze and super silver and
neville's haze are kind of like the
final three hazes that came out
yeah at the end of like one whole era
you know
so that's starting at the end not the
beginning
but um
you know uh let's see
skunk haze a lot of people in europe
don't like the skunk cases quite as much
because they felt the skunk aspects kind
of overpowered the
um the haze like the more delicate haze
aspects that they liked uh that's why
they were always kind of looking for
like bland indicas to cross it to
yeah to allow you know they kind of
wanted like very little terp
cuts
to blend it too to see if the haze terps
would come through
so
um
anyway i don't know uh we're gonna we're
gonna chat about haze tonight which is a
super controversial subject so
a disclaimer this is just kind of like
our opinion on it and like what we see
um
in the forum days when things got
started some of the longest running
threads ever
were arguments between all these old
timers over haze
on cannabis world on overgrow probably
on icmag
it would just go sometimes it would go
into the hundreds of pages
yeah of people battling back and forth
over what was the real haze story
like one of my good friends over on mr
nice did probably what i think was the
best
uh
treat us on haze like overview on haze
during that time before any anybody else
had really been able to track down
anyone to talk to it was my friend
bigger or um off mr nice i see there's
someone with that name in here but i
don't think it's the same dude it would
be awesome if i remember him mr nice for
sure bird was a cool dude
i haven't seen him in a long time though
so i don't know if he's still hanging
around or what the deal is but he if you
i think it's still up on mr nice and for
the most part i know it's been
considered one of the more accurate
histories on it
um but there was some stuff we dug up in
the past few years i know bodhi found a
book um
about santa cruz or written in santa
cruz
and santa cruz history and it actually
mentions a few of them by name and it's
one of the first things we found where
there were other names in it
you know full names
i mean so there's an aspect where
like uh you know hayes has a history
dating back to like the late 60s early
70s yeah so it's hard enough to decipher
stuff that happened 15 or 20 years ago
uh much less 40.
so there's a lot of
forgive me hazy stuff around the origins
of it and on those threads there's tons
of arguing that's going on yeah there's
tons of arguing
um and there's you know uh
sam skunk man has his version
and you know he's posted under different
names about things he claims to have
been a neighbor to those guys
um but i think what's fairly well
accepted is it started out as colombian
by colombia
yeah
i think we could start there it was
colombian by colombian
from import weed and they grew it in
greenhouses in santa cruz and areas that
were mild like that
because you needed those mild
temperatures
in order to take it till december or
january or whatever the hell it was that
they pulled it down
yeah um they hadn't figured out depths
or anything like that yet and so it got
pretty famous
um i know matt has a poster somewhere of
it um it got
early on got named and got kind of
legendary
um you know it was sold high-end in new
york i believe
um
for you know uh quite a bit at the time
yeah it was considered like the super
connoisseur weed right yeah i would say
all this is pretty like standard and not
argued about that much
yeah that much that much it's it's
considered to be correct i think that
that much is considered one once you get
into like who's responsible for what and
what happened when and how and all that
that's where it gets kind of dicey yeah
um but basically what seems like and
there's a lot of stuff where you read
online where it'll talk about like it's
a colombian by indian by thai by mexican
um you know uh
sam swears that it's colo by colo
yeah
you know and all that stuff was added
way later
and isn't really part of it i remember
yeah he said the indian was added way
later if at all i don't remember was
that his claim or not i think he said
that the indian was in there but it was
like it was added as the separate
hybrids he offered
and never got mixed in with the
you know with the core with the core
amount of hate so we always had separate
haze
yeah so
you know when it really boils down to it
or whatever it just seems like haze was
you know a mix of colombian
strains or whatever that they got out of
seeds from import yeah and they got
lucky
and admittedly it doesn't seem like they
knew what the hell they were doing
yeah you know um
and it got pretty famous and so there's
a lot of stories and a lot of mystery
between
late 60s and mid 80s
there's stories out of santa cruz
um there's a series of brothers they
wrote some stuff and high top like
there's all these various things and
and uh you know
there they've been debated ad nauseum
other places so maybe we don't need to
like delve into that part because you
can find that everywhere but what is
part of it is that what's indisputable
is that in 84
84ish or so
um sam skunk man brought it to
holland
yeah
right so
these guys grew haze it got famous
um they were growing it in santa cruz
area uh it was a mix of sativas uh
mostly colombian
it was getting sold in new york and then
at some point sam took a version of it
to
holland
yes
and as far as we can tell
he um
you know he gave it to three people
right
yeah that's what yeah yeah he gave it to
uh uh positronics
who he actually worked with
yeah
and he gave it to corel from uh
super sativa seed club yep uh that
carell talked about when we interviewed
him and he gave it to neville yep
and um all three all three of those guys
made hybrids with it
and sold seeds
um from that and pretty much all haze
that we can really
we can really trace uh comes from either
those three people
or stock that made that sam made himself
in amsterdam later
yeah off seats he kept for himself
and we really don't have any verified
american
haze do we
yeah
i mean we have we have the originator
that we all agree i think everybody
agrees that lund was a part of it
um debatable on the the lady kathy yeah
it's debatable we don't have i'm just
gonna say first name since it doesn't
really neither here nor dare but um
there is one guy who keeps all the
posters and as he explained it to me
was that the posters were hung up in the
dealer's houses that were verified legit
haze dealers and that's kind of how they
verified if they were getting real haze
or not if that poster was in their room
then they knew that they were getting
legit hey there so that's how he told it
now if it's true or not i don't know but
he seems to have the lion's share of the
original posters
and he got them somehow
yeah
somehow
so
you know and then like a lot of those
things like
not everybody
not everybody involved
uh probably has told their story
publicly yeah by any means yeah and so
and you know there's a few people that
are loud about it that insist they know
what's going on and but what we know is
it made it there
yeah it made it to amsterdam and
everybody's all the stuff that made haze
famous sort of came from amsterdam back
to america yeah
i would say yeah
wouldn't you yeah i think yeah it didn't
it wasn't like haze popped up here and
kept rocking and everybody's rocking a
cut from here
so what we don't know is it seems like
you know when we interviewed corel from
super saint eva seed club he gave us a
pretty interesting tidbit
and that uh sam only he didn't think sam
had that many seeds of it because he
only gave him like 10. yeah
and he thought that he only gave neville
some
devil disputes that
um but be that as it may um
you know uh
um
neville ended up probably making the
most famous hybrids with it
by far
yeah by far
you could say that you know um but
positronics had it as well original and
so did uh super sativa c club yeah
they all had originals and it seems like
when you read the stories about what
neville and all the rest of them did
is that uh they were kind of like us
growing you know it's kind of like the
sour that you know a lot of the starting
stories it was like a bunch of kids that
were young
that didn't know what the [ __ ] they were
doing at all
and they made a bunch of rookie mistakes
yeah because they weren't used to
growing something that took 22 weeks or
whatever and it was a jungle plant and
you know and it seems like a number of
them got lost
yeah by everybody
accidents didn't you know mom got killed
they didn't think it was worth much it
took you know 25 weeks and never
finished
um you know that kind of thing and so
um they didn't realize what kind of gold
they had
i don't know not at the time
so much hindsight needed for that yeah
they had they had no idea so neville
neville had you know a few males and a
few females that he burned through and
didn't keep
um
before he you know he ended up i mean he
ended up only by 1990 he only had one
plant that had lived
yeah
you know um
and so
someone keeps asking did sam get invited
sam's never wanted to come on the show
so no
i mean outside to be honest that's why i
i said at first like if you want to hear
sam's opinion about it
um there you could go hunt on overgrow
you know archives or something or
anything like that like he's posted
a ton
on his opinion about it it's there's not
a shortage of sam's written history
that's why we didn't focus on it for
that long
um you know he disagreed with me on the
uh kathy part so he said that the grand
daddy mike was incorrect on that
you know that that's that's what he said
and it might be true you know so yeah
that's what little i know from him after
i told the story the last time based on
granddaddy mike um that's the one thing
that he had he said it was it was very
good but that's not correct so but from
the the reason why we kind of glossed
over that part is that it's the hardest
part to talk about because it's the
least documented yeah you know and it's
a bunch of history from a bunch of
people doing some black marketing
illegal [ __ ] in america yeah all trying
to stay under the radar and as far as um
as far as the uh
you know the haze goes and everybody
knows hayes what we just mentioned
positronics
uh neville's stuff and super sativa seed
club and sam are the sources
yeah
that all the haze that we talk about now
descends from
yeah that's where that's where it all
comes from it's either hybrids they made
or descendants of it or whatever and all
the companies like the flying dutchman
or any of these different groups seeds
men that sold pure haze
i believe they were all just buying
kilos wholesale from sam
yeah i don't know i'd love to be able to
ask him for sure but it sounds like he
was doing a lot of reselling like that
yeah i mean he basically what it sounds
like is to not get in trouble
uh he didn't sell directly to anyone
outside of holland because seed sales
within holland were legal
yeah so he was willing to wholesale um
but he wasn't willing to retail yeah
so he ended up working through
positronics he ended up i mean that's
how i mean you know it's funny when
people talk about all this like rare
skunk one that used to exist
and we asked corel about it he just
laughed and he said everyone gets skunk
one from you know buying bags of seed
from sam stuckman
yeah
that's where you got your skunk one
right
santa cruz but getting back to hayes
it's
someone asked about the ac tase related
to santa cruz original haze um i was
just going to say that's that's by old
testament one who was british so
i really highly doubt it was sourced via
santa cruz
this is just my my theory on it um it
yeah i mean i think i think they sourced
it through pozzi maybe yeah i don't know
who who i i know tom hill's haze line
was positronic yeah his was and it was
his was very different from the old
timer hayes yeah so you know um oh yeah
all tom hill's work and stuff and the
deep chunk hybrids and all that stuff
about positronics
um
they uh
um that was all from
for a while there sam worked with on
some fashion at pozzi
yeah um helping them breed and do
working with werner and stuff like that
and helping them breed different stuff
and and working lines and positronix was
just one of those early seed companies
um you know when sam first moved to
amsterdam he was looking for connections
people to sell seeds to and people to
work with
yeah and he kind of ended up dealing
with everyone in town
but that was only like a few dudes yeah
that was really like ongoing then or
whatever right
and positronics also like a lot of
people don't know this part but um the
positronics haze 19 skunk one is what
gave birth and is the same thing as the
metal haze that i think bodhi just
released f3s of so if you do want like a
worked version of that line that's a
very good way to get it
so i don't know i've never heard numbers
until the corel interview but corel
swore that like
uh pozzi him neville they only got like
a handful like 10 seeds each yeah yeah
the first time i heard that too and then
um and then sam held the rest back that
he had for himself to make his own open
pollination that he did later
yeah
um but i you know i'd never heard that
before
um but then you know corel was there and
we weren't so exactly yeah uh you know
uh neville's dead now but he claims he
got big bags of old-ass seat
but only got
you know eight or ten of them to pop out
of the entire thing yeah
you know um
you know and uh
so
anyway they um
you know he comes in mid 80s or whatever
he comes here and and he comes he comes
from california to holland and he sells
hays seeds to multiple different people
and starts working himself and that was
the start of hayes becoming famous yeah
um and it really didn't for at first
even like the very first thing that
saint that uh neville offered was
actually a northern lights crossed to a
female hazy hat
yeah
that was year one so there was like this
haze b that was a girl
and it was nl1 haze b
um and then the next year he came out
with nl5 hates
i didn't even know that i don't think i
knew that part about the b girl yeah
yeah yeah if you go look in the in the
88 catalog
um he has i think it's actually an
nl1 by rudor alice
hybrid and he crossed it to haze b
um and he talked about it being female
because he was like trying to to like
tame the the crazy lead time to flower
it yeah
right calling you out someone's saying
you're incorrect
i'm sure about what
i don't know i don't know
how sure
am i on it i don't know i mean we could
i got i got the
catalogs around here but he
the the first two hybrids he really he
he really tried to make was uh
um he crossed it to maple leaf afghan
tea
and uh he crossed it to um
uh nl5 hayes
okay and nl5 hayes he re he he released
um
uh the other one i don't think he
released to the public but he gave to
friends or whatnot it is a big herb is
this the big herb from mr nice forums
oh okay there you go
long time no see dude oh man that's so
cool i've read so many of your threads
on uh mr nice
i've been looking for i've been actually
looking for big herb for quite a while
that's cool
i'm glad you showed up yeah so i mean he
you know um one of the cool things about
mr nice is that
um there was a time in 09 you know 2010
or something where neville was very
active on there
yeah and a ton of knowledge about what
happened
uh dropped both publicly and posts that
he made and via dm and communications
with various people that were active
at the time yeah um on mr nice and big
herb was definitely one of those guys
um that was active in communication and
like matt said he had a great write-up
on the history of it
that you can probably still go read
yeah herb was around when when when
neville came back and i started getting
[ __ ] around with him and trying to
work the bubbas and all that [ __ ]
and uh it kind of petered off on the mr
nice forums after that it really really
took a dive after all that [ __ ] yeah so
somebody just asked a question which
i'll answer just because it ties in
uh they were asking did neville have
both an a and a c male and did he use
them to breed in various things
um so what it sounds like
uh is that neville ended up with two
guys
right yeah and uh the a and the a and
the c right and
it was easier to use the males because
it was easier to collect pollen and then
dust a bunch of indica females at the
appropriate time than it was to try to
deal with the females i guess yeah so
for lack of a better way he ended up
with a couple boys
and um
the
uh the a
he lost in 1989 he did a huge seat
increase and put all of his best indicas
in there like the g13 and the nl5 and a
bunch of different stuff and then
him and his workers forgot to keep a
backup in the bedroom
yeah so he bloomed every a male and they
all died and he lost it
so after that
happened so often keeping big libraries
too
so he never sold any commercial he never
sold any commercial amounts of haze yeah
he popped them himself and gave out
various phenos of it which we'll get to
in a little bit
and he might he gave some private
amounts of seed to friends
um other breeders uh people early on you
know what not but
it was never sold commercially so
everything you ever could buy
commercially
was the sea dad
so all nl5 has all nl5 haze that you
could buy from the seed bank or from
scentsy seeds was the c dad
right and that's so that's kind of like
what
everybody's got
yeah i'd bring big herb on the live i
don't know if he's ready to just beat
pop on on camera all of a sudden but
he's more than welcome to come on
it's no but uh we'll read we'll
definitely reach out to you after the
show he's a wealth of knowledge yeah and
would be cool to add to things but um
you know so neville
neville had and nl5 hayes was probably
the most famous it's probably what put
hayes on the map to be perfectly honest
yeah
uh and what i mean by that is that it it
just made it a permanent part of
cannabis lore yeah it inundated the
united states it did and he you know in
89 and 90 the pictures on the front of
his catalog or an nl5 haze a
yeah uh huge running colas big bud you
know
all that and it was that and super skunk
ended up being him and scentsy's
best-selling seed lines
so nl5 hayes kind of changed the game
and um
it was super potent
and it's probably i've said it on shows
with matt before in my opinion it's
probably the most successful hybrid ever
made
i wonder if it's because like
the line was kicking out more
keepers you know things that people
wanted or just because so many were sold
you were eventually gonna find a keeper
because it wasn't super easy to find
keepers in all those packs was it i
never found a [ __ ] keeper yeah and i
bought i definitely i bought plenty of
packs yeah not plenty but i mean i
probably bought seven or eight packs in
the in the in the mid-90s
but then other people from that same
year and same era as me uh there's
things that are still traded today that
were found right around then
yeah so it's just the mis it's just the
mystery of seeds you can find it in one
and you can you might not find it in 200
yeah in a way you know um but it seems
like that that strain was consistent
from somewhere to 89 to the mid 90s
yeah uh neville says they lost the nl5
mom before he left scentsy which was in
95-96
um but
and and basically like all the all the
haze that we know of all the phenos that
have been kept
all seemed to trace back to that late
80s through mid 90s era yeah
and there's a [ __ ] yeah and there's a
[ __ ] bunch of them
right there's a shitload i mean some
that may not even be identified as nl5
hayes like bull rider might be nl5haze
based you know yeah old betsy yeah
exactly the sister of bull rider or
whatever but yeah
so what ends up happening is that
um maybe we can like uh
you know that's interesting uh big herb
because we've always wondered there's
been a rumor that the cuban black
could have been from gifted seeds to
someone that neville knew
you know and it could be it could have
been a in that case um
but i've heard that rumor too i don't
know if it's true
um but uh i poo poo the cuban black i
don't give a [ __ ] what anyone says like
the at least the clones circulating
right now
in the community because i knew exactly
who brought it in and that dude kept
[ __ ] lying about everything he had so
i think it's very i'm very skeptical
skeptical with what uh
with what goes around today as a human
black case it might be some kind of l5
phase but it is not the original i know
what what you know i mean we can you
know we're bouncing around and i
apologize because it's like a
multi-decade story or whatever but yeah
basically
uh and we can dive into different parts
at different times but
um basically between you know 89 and and
95 or so there's probably like
uh
10 or 15 elites
maybe a few more yeah that have survived
from that era that are all named cuts
and still held on to
yeah um of
mostly nl5 haze
um whether it uses the a dad or the c
dad but some g13 haze some hash plant
haze
um various different things
yeah you know i've only ever had the
hash plant haze and hybrids
they um so basically yeah neville
basically crossed it to like all his
best indicates
yeah so it got crossed the hash plant it
got crossed to g13 it got across to nl5
it got crossed to nl1
uh anything that he had that was an
indica that he thought was a bomb clone
yeah
uh got you know so so that's kind of
where like people are talking piff isn't
one thing all this we'll get to that in
a second but basically what happened is
is that there's a whole series we can
talk about of famous clones in europe
that neville hunted and found and then
passed out to france yeah and those got
those got held and like some people call
them the southern the i almost said
southern humble the southern holland
south holland crew
yeah south holland crew um and they've
been sold in coffee shops for decades
yeah when i when i first went you know
to coffee shops in in amsterdam you
could get nl5h8 you could get a5 you
could get c5 you could get g13 you could
get hash plant haze
basically every every trip i went
somewhere had
you know various versions of it yeah so
they were sold and a lot of people came
to holland to smoke those hazes
so there was these famous cuts and
there's a lot of them that are 30 years
old now or whatever that got
um
that got saved in europe and there's
like a whole map to that and then at the
same time
there was a bunch of people that were
trading seeds with neville
uh and buying a bunch of neville seeds
and it seems like a combination of new
york and florida
right um it blew up and got super
popular yeah and there was markets for
it a lot of the people in florida were
actually sending it to new york
because it blew up in new york and
got a top dollar and there's rumors
that it's been kind of a thing in new
york since the 70s
like there's always been a high-end
clientele of like wall street brokers
musicians artists
connected people that are willing to
drop big money for haze yeah
as long as i've been a smoker you could
go to new york and find hayes yeah i
wonder why that is
it just caught on and never
i don't know
um but like i wonder why dominican cruz
picked up on it new york i wonder why
certain ethnic you know
groups just
navigated to that specific type is it
that new yorkers just tend to like more
speedy weed you know i mean
in in this case the best haze in the
world in my opinion is in amsterdam
and you know new york and florida
yeah the west coast gets jacked
like we literally we get jack and super
silver haze and uh you know like we get
a lot of hybrids of that kind of thing
and those are more like the poly hybrids
that came later
yeah right like uh you know they on the
east coast they have a bunch of f1s and
s1s of f1s and you know and there's a
people are going to talk about it you
know there's people talk about names
like heights hayes downtown brown
uh pith
church
uh cuban black um you know it seems like
there was groups of dominicans and
groups of cubans that had it on lockdown
yeah you know people call it block work
uh because they could get it on the
block there was green haze there was
brown haze
right
yeah and it's really hard if you're not
from there
to know all the different
you know are they phenos are they the
same thing grown different ways are they
called different hybrid names is i mean
i i talked to some people that were in
the know
and i used to think that it was like you
know half a dozen names from the same
couple cuts
yeah
but it turns out that in the 30 years
that hayes has been popular in new york
and florida there's a [ __ ] plethora
yeah
there's even there's like poo day that's
another one i always wondered what that
stood for
this is a weird word yeah i mean there's
all kinds of nicknames and stuff and so
yeah what's crazy about the haze is that
the
and don't take any offense to this
anyone but like the cubans and the
dominicans and whoever that were running
it they viewed it very much so as a
business yeah and they held that [ __ ]
[ __ ] type they weren't into into
sharing it with trading they had like a
market and their market was good and
they were into it and there's dudes that
i've talked to that like their entire
career basically just grown hays
yeah
you know that's all they needed to do
was grow hays get it to new york boom
they're good right so they don't share
that [ __ ]
so but what's interesting about that is
like unlike a lot of like random cuts
you get like where you kind of have to
get the cut
a lot of those dudes once they realize
they couldn't get the real cut they just
went and bought beans because you could
still buy the line yeah and you but you
know and it's like imagine if your
buddies are selling it for a ton of
money
you might go to amsterdam and buy a
hundred seeds
yeah and come back and pop a bunch and
then all of a sudden you've got the
you know i've got i've got the piff
yeah i've got the cube in black
you know they called it
my experience and this is this is uh
i remember big herb i was trying to push
a bunch of these off on him because i
knew like no one wanted them but when i
got the pif the dominicans asked me not
to release it pure that was the only
request they had don't release it pure
and i wasn't gonna [ __ ] snub that you
know like you didn't want to piss anyone
off so i never did but i really regret
it yeah i mean they have a there's a
market so i don't claim to be an expert
i mean there's there's different people
we could probably bring on maybe in the
future
that know a lot more about the various
names and origins of the various
different haze things from new york i
just wanted to bring it up in general
that there's a bunch of cuts that get
passed around in florida and new york
more but but florida too
and a bunch in holland and between those
two areas that's like 15 different cuts
yeah at least a bunch so
it's probably the line that has the mo
we're lucky if one or two phenos of any
famous thing survives from the 90s to
today yeah
right
can you think of any other line from
that era that has as many cuts as nl5
haze does that still float around
not even close man we're still trying to
find a single a lot of these lines you
know
yeah so
you know and so you know some of this
stuff people are talking about gold or
brown haze or whatever um in my opinion
uh and i've seen it in like chem 4 and
i've seen it in various strains
you know certain strains just when it
when they're when they're around oxygen
they sort of cure a little bit brown
yeah i used to get remember like the the
real cherry pie when it was growing
would be like deep purple and would look
all crazy
when i did it depths and then i dry it
and three weeks later it would the the
the purple would turn a little light
brown
oh man i hated that about like
blackberries too like that beautiful
magenta red as it dries it turns just as
nasty
and some of those some of those haze
crosses turn brown as they dry it's the
colombian influence i believe and so it
might be terpius all get out and fresh
and smell delicious
and someone looks at it and they're like
this shit's old
yeah you know old weed you know
so it's just like it's a it's a uh
you know i mean even like we i was we
were talking about it i was talking
about it earlier today but i have a
buddy who made the chocolate top the uh
the chocolate diesel
yeah right and it's and that stuff it's
basically a chocolate tie by dog by sour
diesel
yeah and it was phenomenal and we had it
for a long time and no one wanted to
ever buy it because it cured a light
brown yeah because the chocolate part
wasn't so much it smelled like chocolate
it was that the tie was brown
yeah and and and like karel said back in
the day they wanted that brown yeah but
that brown was it was good brown it was
fresh it wasn't like it was [ __ ] up
but it just a little yellow little brown
little off colors yeah but what's crazy
about haze is that that is like death on
the west coast
right brown any kind of brown color at
all and it's like doom and i can see
people in the comments or whatever
talking about all the uptown brown's my
favorite
yeah that's the one
i'd give me that brown
yeah
you know so
uh there's a bunch of stuff like that
where i can name them real quick um when
we talk about a or c it's just basically
like a holland shorthand for
uh which man which hayes male of
neville's was used yeah right so there's
at least three c5s
um that float around holland that are
still alive for sure um one of them is
the is is called the one and that's the
mom of uh super silver hayes
and it's
floats around it's actually in america
right now and it's what people some
people if you see people posting in
america of c5 it's that cut okay so the
c5 cut in america is the one the c5 cut
in america is the it's like the
terpenoline bomb yes it's what made
super silver haze so traprindling
dominant yeah you know
um and uh you know and so it it's um
it's being passed around it made it over
the oh and it's really amazing uplifting
super potent weed
it just you have to be able to handle
terpenelene
yeah if you don't like your pedaling
it's going to be a real problem
i smoked your pilling all day
and uh and so there's like three c5s the
final c5 was my favorite i used to smoke
it over there in amsterdam
it's the they call it the 122 or the
mango
and it's the mom of mango haze
and it just taste it has more of that
mercin like uh i don't forget i forget
what the terp is that leads to mangoes
but it smells like ripe mangoes
and it's got a great high
yeah c5 isn't ssh c5 is the mom of ssh
someone just said so so then there's a
there's three cuts of c5 at least over
there there's two cuts of a5 they say
there's a
g13a there's a g13c
there's a hash plant by c
um
i might be missing a couple i don't know
but there's a bunch of them over there
um
and uh
and then most of the ones in america
are are you know nl5 across the sea
yeah um even i should mention too that
um neville gave soma of soma seeds some
g13a
and he took a mail of that and all of
soma's
sativa and hazy lines
are based off that that mail
that he kept
from some g13a seeds that he got and so
what it seems like and neville was
pretty open about this on um
on the uh on the forums over there
was
uh hayes does not like being cross to
itself
no yeah at all and what becomes hard is
especially with the c
the more you cross haze to itself
uh neville called it cat piss we would
probably uh we would probably call it um
uh ter pedaling
but but the more you cross it you get
terpenoline dominant and then only
rarely do others any kind of and that's
what everybody thinks of is jack
jack terps train wreck terps yep uh
super case uh super silver haze terps uh
that kind of stuff tends to dominate so
yeah what it seems like is
the best ones the ones that everybody
keeps are the f1s yeah
of haze to some indica
and the poly hybrids like super silver
haze mango haze uh jack herrera that
kind of thing they don't seem to be as
people don't seem to have keepers of
those the same way not that there's not
cuts of them that don't float around it
might be nice
yeah um
but we should mention too because it's
[ __ ] we're it's kind of like a ramble
or whatever but
most of these things are they're one of
the most unique things about hayes is
that
most of the good ones take between 12
and 16 weeks
yeah
long time long time
a long time like i think the cuban
blacks and a lot of the ones in new york
90 to 100 days is a pretty common
rate to take those ones
the dog [ __ ] which is about the only
west coast one that's any good
um that one's
12 13 weeks easy you know
um all the stuff from europe uh
you know was is all 15 16 weeks
yeah
you know and so that was one of the
things that neville and shanti and all
those guys that were [ __ ] around with
it one of their criteria was they didn't
want anything longer than 16 weeks
yeah
because it was impractical because
asking someone to flower something for
four months is already impractical yeah
especially if it's a money-making thing
yeah
yeah you know so there's an aspect where
it's like i uh
you know they cut it off they wanted 14
to 16 weeks
you know and it seems like the earliest
good ones are more like 12 and 13.
yeah you know
um but 14 to 16 seems to be the most
common range that a lot of them fall
into i was a big fan of the old sog
super silver haze that was one of my
favorites that ran pretty quick and was
mostly skunk one dominant it's pretty
cool sure yeah i mean those you know the
super silver haze and the mango haze
were both um two different nl5 haze moms
crossed to the same skunk haze dad yeah
right so the skunk helps like throw
especially in the super silver it helped
it throw bigger longer thicker colas
yeah and it could shorten up the time a
whole bunch
in my opinion yeah you know
um and uh
so you know they so then it just became
going back it just became [ __ ] famous
yeah everybody had haze
and all these seed companies wanted to
obscure exactly how they got haze but
hayes just became
haze for a while was sort of shorthand
for sativa
yeah it was the sativa
right yeah
and you know and uh it got famous in
america it got famous over there
it was all these various different
things
um and it seems like you know like i
said the f1s seem to be a lot better
than the poly hybrids yeah now the poly
hybrids weren't nice i've grown nice
super silver haze i've had keepers of
mango haze i loved
um but
it seems like all the most favorite ones
are f1
yeah
so some type of afghani or [ __ ] cross
the haze across the haze very two very
different things slap together
and then you see what they get yeah and
even with those things crossed to it
still the keepers were 14 16 weeks yeah
so essentially like you're taking some
colombian and like shortening it from
20 to 24 to 14 to 16. i've seen uh
columbia black go up to 26. that's
[ __ ] insane yeah you know and so
people are talking about pif piff is
just
you know pif is a catch-all term
yeah or um it's one of the nicknames to
hates
yeah you know people can argue i'm not
going to sit there and say that i have
some encyclopedic knowledge of how all
the new york haze terms came about
yeah um but it got a bunch it was
popular enough for long enough that it
has a bunch of nicknames
right yeah i said it before heights
hayes uptown brown
cuban black
um block work huh yes
church
frank
short for frankincense
you know uh all that all that different
types of stuff said
stands for pure i didn't know that's
what it meant i don't know if that's
colombian for pure dominican for pure
they had a lot of nicknames yeah
you know and probably just like kush and
just like cookie just like everything
else it got popular people got bag seeds
people got lines
from amsterdam still and popped their
own thing and added their own name to it
because they're trying to cash in on the
thing
so
it's really hard to say but
rarely you know that line was available
for seven or eight years in seed form
okay
i have an idea
i have an idea for a little game we can
play
i'm gonna name a few different haze cuts
and you're going to say
pass or smoke
and you're going to be passing it to an
idiot or you're going to smoke it
yourself okay indeed
okay
um
a5 smoke
smoke okay
c5
smoke
okay i knew you'd go for both of them um
dog [ __ ]
definitely smoke
have you smoked all betsy
no
no i haven't tried it nope or bull rider
to be honest
yeah yeah that's the mo i haven't smoked
for a bull rider that i know of you know
like it just wasn't it already died out
by the time i got san diego
um let's see here i'm trying to think of
some some good hazy cuts that you've
tried
uh
cali mist
smoke
there's nothing you're not gonna smoke
that has haze in it now that i think
about i don't think i could name one
could you
i could yeah i i would there's
there's not really a jack i've seen
that i wished i had a jar on my on my
on my on my on my shelf there well so
jack you're gonna pass on a jack that
guy would pass on the jack or a pass on
jack
jack to me is like a huge yielding skunk
one
on a haze frame
yeah you know and it's like just i
i don't know it like the type of
terpenoline that jack is is not my
favorite
it's more like it doesn't taste good to
me
you know i know people love it you know
and people loved it because they got two
three pounds of light with it and they
crushed it in depths and greenhouses and
they basically grew the [ __ ] out of it
until the buyers were like uh
you know yeah yeah
how about you
have you tried amnesia yet amnesia some
watered down [ __ ] i thought it was it's
one of my favorites really all the
reasons
is one of my favorites by far because
it's so like perfumey fruity like it's
just nice man
yeah i don't know i mean i like i like
the i like the church the frankincense
the mercene
yeah um i can't i'm not a terpenoline
hater by any means like i said i mean
like i said c5 is a terpenoline bomb
yeah but there's a difference to me
between terpenoline that has a little
bit of sweetness or creaminess behind it
and like i just sprayed my mouth with
like floor hanger yeah that's true and
that that terpenoline you know it's like
and i think for jack and stuff like that
there was just a bunch of badly grown
jack
and it overwhelmed just like train wreck
you know it overwhelms people yeah
you know like that durbin um that durbin
from colorado or whatever that one's a
terpenoline bomb too sure is you know
it is
super terpene and you know it's like i
like there's all kinds of wheat i smoke
i'm not a hater on it yeah um but when i
when i the interesting part to me is
it's not so much
the only thing i can think of that's
like really strong terpenelene that i
love the high
is the c5
interesting
i don't know about that does it for you
you know i don't know why that is but
yeah um
you know but they uh
you know what's cool about it is that
because it made money in coffee shops
for so long and still does
um it's still hoarded over there yeah
and people accuse us reporting that [ __ ]
is legit hoarded dude people are like so
many people put stipulations on those
[ __ ] cuts
i mean like
there are certain seed lines like me and
caleb can never release
no because they'll be they'll be super
pissed off and people will be angry and
it's like
and you know it's been monetized over
there for so long and been sold in
coffee shops and if you got the cuts you
had to give kickbacks to the dudes that
i was like very
so those things it's like and they don't
give a [ __ ] they don't want to trade you
for [ __ ] they have what they have and
they don't it's so that's like the
ultimate hoarding because honestly
um
they didn't slip out until neville died
yeah
yeah the entire time that he was alive
that [ __ ] was on lockdown with those
guys yep
right yep and then
two only two of those cuts maybe more
but only you know but
yeah
i love that
one of the sources for those cuts
i was sent a list with those on me i was
like i want those two
and the dude didn't even know what the
[ __ ] they were until i told them what
they were and that was the biggest
mistake i ever made
i don't i don't like to dick people and
be like you know i wanted i like to
trade equal value so even if they find
out later it's rare they at least got
their worth but
yeah i mean the hard part is the hard
part is that um
you know these things would never be
popular okay yes no you really have to
you really have to like the high um
because yeah
you should know what you're growing too
because i see a lot of people asking
about the a5s ones and stuff like
that that's not going to be a super like
marketable commercial crop nowadays that
would sell really well i think people
have this like fantasized idea because
you're saying it's dank and they they
respect your word they don't understand
what it would what what this definition
of dank would look like
dank and ugly
it is [ __ ] like i mentioned before
like people were talking on the thing
about how much they love the uptown
brown yeah you couldn't sell uptown
brown in california
no [ __ ] way no way don't get me wrong
even if i agree with you and i say that
weed's amazing it still wouldn't sell
here yeah it just couldn't and like if
you see the pictures of a5 there's no
resin production anywhere on any leaf
no for miles and you just look at it be
like [ __ ] that dude sucks it growing but
really
it's the plant it's ugly yeah but it
works
you know and so you really have to be
into the high so it's like they're every
like all these dutch you're like trying
to hoard it like americans are gonna
like [ __ ] with their money yeah yeah
when you really have to be a consumer
like a lover of cannabis because it
takes four months so you have to plan
that it's going to take twice as long as
the rest of your [ __ ] yeah and you got
to keep it happy and healthy and bug
free and pee and all the various issues
free that long and it don't wash
yeah and then you know and then you get
some great weed yeah you know and so um
so it's not you know but in in holland
it's like all my first experiences with
smoking all those ones were all haul and
grown
yeah
and maybe i could tell a story that
people uh people might like so
i went and saw this room in holland that
was growing neville's haze and uh c5 and
then 122 right
and so i go into this room and it was
one of
i only met neville a couple of times but
it was one of his partners okay and so i
go into this room
and
it's like there's like one gallon pots
on the ground
okay
um with those grodan like
rockwool croutons yeah you know like the
yellow and the croutons yeah
little crouton little squares right yes
one gallon pots with these stems coming
out of them that were like that big
and those stems went six seven feet up
in the air
yeah okay bare right and so imagine this
little one gallon pot with this stem
that's like half as wide as the pot yeah
going six feet straight up and then
branches everywhere and like two or
three layers of
uh of netting
yeah and then they just had a bunch of
600s on the ceiling
i i forgot to tell you i had a
conversation with seattle greg the other
day and he said when he went into
neville's grow room
instead he said when he first got there
neville was growing rockwool slabs on
the ground on the ground yeah and they
had they had drains in there or whatever
else and they would be honest like the
slowest constant drip ever you know
um but it was like you're looking at
literally these they were probably 10 12
20 10 12 foot paul plants that was like
where the weed was
and it started at above i'm 6'3 it
started above my head that's like i
walked in and all the netting was above
my head and there's these tiny ass
little pots on slow drip and just like a
sea of spears
how big was the ceiling how tall were
the ceilings they were pretty tall they
were like 14 feet or something like that
yeah they had to be i mean if the
[ __ ] canopy starts at the top of your
head that's a canopy started the canopy
started about seven feet it was about
half a foot above my head
and from seven to ten feet was where
most of the weed was and then the lights
were hanging off the ceiling and it was
like six feet like you looked and there
was like a sea of
brant of of stock
coming out of the thing and going up
above your head and then branching out
into huge branches all over that's wild
it was pretty well i've never seen at
the time i'd never seen anything like
that before in my life because people
people are confusing they're saying they
thought you were five foot ten no that's
me i'm five foot ten
yeah i'm six three so
it was above my head and um you know
what's crazy about that is that their
drip system fails for instance that
shit's dead in like two hours
yeah that that's what's always scared me
about like drip systems feeds hydroponic
systems i mean it was literally on like
the slowest drip you could imagine it
was basically constant yeah
you know it's constant feet during the
light cycle you know
so
um
yeah it was it was pretty but that's how
they grew and that was neville's haze
and the mango haze and the c5 yeah and
those were all grown for coffee shops at
the time
yeah you know
um and they were dank i mean the
neville's haze um
is is a5 by hay c
you know and the cut that i love still
exists i hope that it gets sent over to
america sometime
um i would go what the [ __ ] are you
laughing at
everybody's doubting my height
no he's short
like ten
huh liars
he's uh he's short i don't know
he's he's short you know
so five ten is a little short you're
right
he might uh i don't know
girl pinocchio knows
there is uh there was some really good
neville's hazes there's there's rumor
uh
it's really hard to substantiate
anything with shanti or any of the euro
guys in general
um so we don't know if neville's haze is
the same or not yeah
you know um we don't uh someone asked if
we could break down karma's a5 s1 yeah
he should change his name to snitch
hayes s1
yeah i mean
you know he he reversed the i i don't
think the i don't think the um
i don't think the haze is like being
bred even to even to
um out crosses of themselves yeah they
certainly don't that doesn't seem like
they like to be s1 very much no
there's a lot of ugly and then
[ __ ] i mean yeah there's a lot
of ugly you might get and that's part of
the problem too is like when it comes to
haze
you know
your the best stuff is gonna be three to
four months
a bunch of it's going to be junk a bunch
of it's going to be jungle weed yeah
you're not going to know for forever it
takes a long time to freaking uh
you know to get it going so it's like i
mean i could tell a story that i i've
told privately or whatever but uh i went
out i went out to the cannabis cup and i
think it was 98 or something like that
and uh it was the first year that they
released uh neville's hayes seats
yeah okay and neville's haze was so
everybody knows it was supposed to be a
private breeding um of
of neville's and he was trying to make
what he called the holy grail yeah a
haze line so he took
um he took
his favorite a5 um which which was on
the cover of the 89 and 90 catalog that
female and he threw that on the haze
email yeah and it was the first time he
tried to breed both haze dads into a
single thing
and they found this cut over there that
was the strongest sativa i've ever
smoked in my life
i've talked about it before it's i
remember it
that neville's hates oh it just never
tastes female you know yeah yeah it it
make i mean it it is unbelievably potent
in a way that weed is not normally
potent yeah um and so
i smoked it over there and it blew my
head off like it it made it hard for me
to walk downstairs
yeah
i like held onto the railing and i felt
disassociated and i felt
like it hit me in a weird it made me
feel like i was smoking kind bud with no
tolerance yeah
like i got it was intense
and i got high for hours and so i just
brought some of these seeds home and i'd
never grown an extreme sativa before
so
i was going to breed with this [ __ ]
and i grew it for a few months i took
some cuttings
and then once they rooted and i knew i
had backup copies i flipped it to see
what was up
yeah well i flipped it at 12 12. you
know this is like 1999 or something yeah
i made that mistake before too yeah and
it it vegged for months with no pistols
yeah just you wait when you're like week
seven you're like yeah and i was like
what the [ __ ] like all my shit's
finishing up and it's barely starting
and i was like oh yeah so
i like i i tossed them and then i took
clones and i flowered those
and then i put more [ __ ] in there
because i was trying to breed with it
and then the same [ __ ] thing happened
right and i didn't know at the time
that a lot of those guys over there will
tell you that if you really want to get
your sativas to do well
yeah clone them a few times and let the
plant itself get to be six or seven
months old yeah because that's its
natural veg cycle before it would even
start to bloom in the tropics yeah you
got to realize it's going to veg for a
long ass time
and he's like no if you're getting an a5
cut that was popped in 89 you can just
flip it yeah obviously yeah and then i
didn't know anything about 11 14 or 10
11 13 or 10 14 or anything like that
which is basically just like for people
that don't grow
it's uh how much hours of light and how
much hours of darkness yeah so 12 12 for
uh you know 22 years ago or whatever
that was fine for all my indicas
for neville's that was like veg
in order to get it to start i had to
give it 11 hours of light and 13 hours
of darkness it had to be over six months
old and then i had to finish it at 10 14
for like the final six weeks
yeah
yeah and so i [ __ ] up a bunch
yeah i did that with the malawi too
buddy's the one who taught me that trick
because i would have never i wouldn't
even made
sense of it back then no i hadn't i had
no idea i didn't i didn't even make
sense of it until i had a buddy in
amsterdam who
grew for neville and i went back to
europe
and saw him the next year and told him
like basically my follies yeah and he
just laughed at me and he laid all that
[ __ ] out
yeah and i had money i had no idea dude
i mean it makes sense when someone says
it like and then you're like oh
god that makes sense and how easy yeah
every other strain i'd ever grown of
cannabis at that point in time when i
turned the lights back to 12 12
everything i needed to happen happened
yeah that was my first experience with
like weed that didn't do that
you know and and so that's only with
extreme sativas if it's got enough
indica and it should trigger
[ __ ] it's only and it's only if it's
from seed
because seeds know they're young
someone was asking if any of us had
grown kelly missed here's an old
original pack low numbered pack
early on of cali mist that we haven't
popped yet
one day huh natto yeah one day
um you know so i mean it should be said
about the cali mist uh simon worked for
neville
its origins are unknown
neville thinks that it's an nl5 haze a
female
um
it uh
but he think he you know he thought that
everything in europe was based off his
work so that's not surprise he thought
everything in america was based off his
work but what is interesting is that
having talked to some dutch people
um
they say that um that the
uh
the the cali mist was based off a mother
plant called the mango
yeah
now whether it's the same whether it's
the same mango that that founded the
mango haze and the 122
or whether it's a different thing
i can't say but they said for a long
time it was alive in europe and then it
got and then it got lost
yeah
so
um
people talking about kelly missed
western winds i remember western winds
has some cambo in it or supposedly it's
the same [ __ ] thing yeah and it has
camo in it so people did
so people that uh people that um
that don't know
uh tony from sac martha and simon from
sirius had a company that we talked
about before cerebral seeds for one year
right
and they split up tony made sag martha
seeds simon made serious seeds
and
simon's version of the cali mist was
called cali mist
tony's version of the same line was
called western winds
which is i think one of the cooler names
in cannabis i always liked the name
western winds
i thought that was a super neat name
just makes me think of gas
you know so
so yeah so i've heard people in europe
tell me that they preferred tony's
version to simon's
that the western wins
um
but you know then
it's hard to say uh those guys don't
really reveal parentage
no uh we don't know what's in the cali
mist we don't know what's in the bubble
gum we don't know it's in the uh ak-47
um it's it's hard to say
um but but the 90s cali missed
simon got busted in 99 or 2000 when they
changed the laws
and it seems like several of his lines
changed after that yeah and the cali
mist was one of them
but in the 90s there was some really
amazing cali miss cuts
yeah it was it was a nice line
um you know so
um you know yeah it's it's that's kind
of what happened it's like people
you know people were getting you could
buy um
they called it uh pure haze f10
remember from uh from uh flying dutchman
yep and they'd straight up tell you 80
of it is junk
10 of it is is is pretty good
and 10 of it is special i don't know if
if flying dutchman said that i know tom
hill said that
i'm pretty sure that in the description
they talked about how inbred it was
already
okay and that its best use was for
hybrids and outcrossing
but if you were trying to find a winner
be prepared that only less than ten
percent
yeah so you'd have to do like at least a
hundred one hunt
yep
and so doing a hundred hundred plant
haze hunt is a [ __ ] nightmare those
are expensive
yes expensive and nightmarish because
it's gonna be a bunch of jungle weed
and the shittiest looking weed
could end up being fire
yeah you're not gonna know until you dry
it and smoke it you're not going to know
how potent it is it can be like look
resin-less
yeah and still take your head off
right yep
i mean so
but what's cool about it
is that it was so fire that it's become
one of the most common names in cannabis
and it's been blended into all kinds of
[ __ ] for forever
yeah
you know blue dream has haze in it
you know lots of lots of huge yielding
plants have haze in their background
because of that stretch
yeah the stretch the yield
the high if you could throw if you could
like jack herrera was basically figuring
out a way to get skunk buds on a haze
frame yeah and if you could get a
ginormous haze plant with huge skunk
running colas and a little nl density
then you're three pounds of light bro
yeah
yeah three pounds of light three pounds
of light bro i just didn't know the days
you're supposed to [ __ ]
lollipop on for three pounds of life but
i don't remember it anymore
so maybe i don't know maybe we should
we've been we've been
rambling about haze for a minute maybe
we should talk a little about so neville
made neville made all these um
all these hybrids only a few of which he
ended up selling to the public
yeah but there was a bunch um like the
g13 haze crosses and uh
the the silver haze which was afghan a
maple leaf afghan tea by haze and
different things he passed out to
friends
and peep other people in amsterdam and
even some people that bought seeds off
him early on
yeah so those things got spread out a
little bit and there was keepers that
were found
even though you could never buy g13 by
jese
yeah
you know they had it
and then you know um after that
uh he started trying to make poly
hybrids and blend them all together and
cross various select cuts he'd found
he tried to cross he was trying to do
skunk hate skunk nl and haze mixed
together
yeah because he considered those to be
like the three most famous lines in in
holland yeah so can i get a plant that
contains all three
and what it sounds like
is it was just a terpenoline nightmare
g13 haze uh all the poly hybrids you
wish yeah yeah yeah you know
um and you know he so there i went to
the the first cup i went to was the
jacket there was a cup in 1995 uh
cannabis cup in amsterdam which is the
only place that they were
and in 95 uh ben and alan drunkers
this was actually i guess yeah it was
95. so ben and alan drunkers
wanted to
um have a commemorative release because
the whole theme
for that uh
that cup was jack herrera and the
emperor wears no clothes yeah and the
impact that jack pereira had on the
cannabis movement
right so let's keep going keep going one
second so there was all there was all
this there was all this theme or
whatever right and so neville had been
working on this
this nl5 haze by skunk haze
but he hadn't really found what he
wanted yet
so
ben and alan drunkers because they were
scentsy and scent and neville was at
centi at the time they convinced him to
release this sort of like not ready for
prime time thing
um and call it jack herrer
okay so that's how the jack herrera came
about was they had they already had a
pheno of it
um that they had at the cup that they
had flour at the cup
and then they they released jack herrera
as a seedline at scentsy seeds that uh
at the cup that was like a big debut
was you could buy jack herrera at the
cup
damn it i thought i had my jack hair 95
poster here but real quick anyway so so
jack got
jack got uh jack got released
um jack supposedly is the genesis of
[ __ ] uh brothers grimm c99
is bag seed from a uh coffee shop in
amsterdam of jack herrera yeah
is the supposed is the supposed origins
or whatever it is so
yeah it's a backseat so it could be half
jack or full jack
as you know
supposedly if you believe him it was
found in a bud of jack herrera bought at
a coffee shop
yeah and he brought it home and did [ __ ]
with it so
um neville wasn't satisfied
with the with jack herrera he felt it
was still unfinished and he left
um he left uh scentsy later that year
and he kept working on
the project and he got uh shanti baba to
help him
and they basically they had the mothers
that they wanted they were going to use
the c5 and the 122.
and they kept trying to find different
skunk haze dads that would do what they
wanted
yeah and according to them
it took a long time and a bunch of
different males and a bunch of different
growing [ __ ] out a bunch of pain in the
ass
but uh after a few years they found a
skunk haze dad
that worked
and neville preferred that skunk haze
crossed to the uh c5
and shanti preferred that same dad
crossed to the 122
and they couldn't agree on which one was
the better line and better
representative
so they released both
and they called the
skunk haze by c5 the super silver haze
and they called the uh mango haze by
same skunk dad mango haze
you know super super haze is one that
i've actually ran a bunch of and that's
one that i had the hardest time finding
keepers in but i have smoked others
keepers like i said the old socks always
one of my favorite but there are some
really good keepers out there but i just
never had luck with super soaps i
brought i brought some to um
i think our party a couple of times
it wasn't mine wasn't super elite i
wouldn't say it was a nice cut um it
yielded like crazy it was great to death
and great to grow outside yeah and it
had a lot of qualities you want in mold
resistance and just general happiness
um you know it had a light terpene base
or whatever but
um
but so basically super silver haze and
neville and uh mango haze are two
sisters crossed to the same dad
you know so they're pretty close
uh but they're just different you know
um super silver haze tends to be more
terpenoline mango haze tends to be a bit
more mercine
more bit more mango style i tend to i
like the mango haze better as a haze
the super silver haze is a crazy
production plant
yeah um and then i've had some euros
tell me
um
like uh gene finder
that there was a super silver haze in
europe that was like a 14 weaker that
was like their all-time favorite
interesting that one seems lost
oh that sucks
it does
uh but there was an outlier that was a
more hazy
more you know more more you know less
skunk
more haze and that was supposedly
phenomenal
um but in a poly hybrid it's going to be
hard to to find something
you know
um neville complained
that none of his poly hybrid work was as
nice as any of the f1s
yeah
no matter how hard he tried they just
weren't quite as good
you know um but i will say
that that neville's haze that he made
it's the most potent sativa i've ever
tried in my life
and i know that cut still exists in
europe
yeah
so it's really amazing you know what's
interesting i just thought about it
i don't think most breeders or seed
makers even talk about the failures
anymore
no
well that's because um most of instagram
and social media is marketing
yeah yeah i guess it doesn't pay to talk
about your failures like do you know
what you know i mean you know what the
greatest cure for powdery mildew was
what instagram oh oh you know you're
right yeah it just disappeared never see
it gone
so weird yeah no one ever struggles with
it
right and then you know why because it
gets curated out yep
you're like oh this is a beautiful bud
and there's like one spot of you know of
mildew on a family for your whatever and
you're just like [ __ ]
i remember you know
this is a little off topic but i do
remember
when swerves cali connection story came
out in high times and he was so proud
and you [ __ ] took pictures of it
threw it online and the first thing
everyone sees is big old powdery mildew
[ __ ] spots all over his leaves
yeah we used to get grilled if you'd
show up with powdery mildew on anything
so i think the uh internet culture kind
of
negated that because people would get
[ __ ] railed on see you want to know
how i'm i'm not big on conspiracy
theories
yeah you know but i'll tell a story that
most people don't know
uh is that
the thing that sent powdery mildew into
northern california mendo and humble and
made it forever an issue yeah it was
osama bin laden and 9 11.
why is that
it's [ __ ] crazy so
9 11 happens right it's september 11th
and he crashes he crashes these
airliners into the twin towers right
yeah so everybody's all freaked out and
they shut down airliners for three days
yeah okay but they were worried about
them al qaeda planning biological
attacks on cities
so they grounded all america's spray
planes so they couldn't spray biological
agents for eight weeks
okay so from septem so from september
11th all the way through september all
the way through october no spray paints
could be
in marin in sonoma in napa in mendo you
couldn't have spray plants okay and
that's how a bunch of those places
control powdery mildew
wow okay so then in the santa rosa paper
which is the big town in sonoma
afterwards you see things like robert
mondavi and other people losing millions
of dollars in grapes this year to
powdery mildew jesus and all those
vineyards are all right by the highway
yeah and i [ __ ] you not dude
in the 90s and in 2000 2001 all the
hydro stores i would go into
none of them had any powdery mildew
control
none of my friends had powdery mildew
powdery mildew was something that you
got like
outdoor maybe in october maybe a touch
here and there if you got unlucky
never saw it never saw it indoor never
ever ever not not a single clone ever
and within two months of 9 11 happening
every single one of my friends had it
yeah and then within a year or two every
hydro store had a whole shelf
oh no here's how to kill the [ __ ]
you know there was stuff there was
biologicals like aq10
um you know there was there was uh you
know you know there was it was learning
about how to kill that [ __ ] and how to
get rid of it was uncomfortable yeah it
was really bunk because it looked like
in the beginning it wasn't [ __ ] up
your weed
yeah but it really [ __ ] up your weed
oh it really [ __ ] it up you know it's
like you think spider mites are [ __ ]
up your weed they're not really [ __ ]
up your weed
that's really really messing with your
herb and so it took a number of years to
figure out how to not transfer it how to
you know no one had ever dealt with it
yeah
i'd never seen it like the first two
three years i lived in california four
years maybe i never saw a single indoor
my friends or myself that ever had it
yeah
none that's crazy that's so nothing
crazy and now it's like it and then once
it became but then you if you if you
think about it right imagine
thousands of acres of grapes
kicking off clouds as the highway drives
by
a pm that they can't treat
jesus christ
it just it just it just got all over
people's [ __ ] tires it got kicked in
the air it got all over the place and
then
it's like it's been i'm not saying that
that's the only reason but it's been a
problem ever since yeah in all honesty
and then all those clones from norcal
get spread out all over
yeah and then people get pm and they
don't know how to deal then they know
how to get rid of it yeah
and you know um and it's you know it's
it's just one of those pathogens
yeah it's it's obnoxious as [ __ ]
it's it's evil
i was just gonna run these by since
we're winding down on time i was just
looking these these were in the same bag
with the cali mist and the bubble gum
and stuff i actually was able recently
to send a bunch of these back uh old uh
spikes of life
i have some old legend seeds actually my
my last pack of the johnny blaze that
people were mentioning i finally got the
to get those back in the hands of red
who made them
so i think red might be making some new
versions of the old legend seat stuff
soon so people that were interested in
those you might actually
just come back to tuition
legends was a good was a good company
for
a while there they had a bunch of good
[ __ ] yeah right red spreads the [ __ ]
i like that guy a lot
i do you want to you want to do some
quick questions sure
we can do questions all right
uh any that you saw that you want to
pick up on oh man now you're going to
call me out and make me remember
yeah if people are listening
ask questions right now yeah if you have
a
dying question that you have to ask
can you speak on the highlights what's
plant like how does it compare to the
nl5 i'll do that real quick
i also sent red back some legends
ultimate indica dookie he also got the
legends ultimate indica for me um
hawaiian lights is
oddly enough it's more afghani even than
the nl5 it tends to be more broadleaf
and expression um we saw some bubble
looking types in it that weren't bubba
smelling but they were just the the
typical above a structure
lots of resin production
there was some color in these lots of
tropical terps lots of pineapple
just all through the the tropical range
um
trying to think of what the best way to
describe that is but it's really hard
tropical think tropical basically
tropical afghani and that is essentially
what hawaiian lights comes out like
very variant but they all
are pretty much broadleaf
so yeah that's that's hawaiian lights in
a nutshell we'll have caleb come on and
talk more about it soon um
we're going to be dropping the
hybrids i believe this weekend
i'm going to do my best i've been
packaging a bunch trying to get through
all the packages in order so once those
are done then i'll add in the hawaiian
lights hybrid so keep your eyes posted
on writeseco.com
and humboldtcsi.com for both so there's
a couple there's a bunch of questions
out um
there's uh there was some stuff on
leather chirps
uh the a5 and some of the some of the
rarer haze terps definitely have some
leather in them
uh animal and leather i actually kind of
prefer that dark profile to like the
super bright fruity
terpenoline uh type of thing on it um
you know there's there's haze lines
available all over the trouble is just
pulling out what you
want out of them you know there's some
america
leather is also motor rebels heroin um
his version of steep tucks arowana which
is very different it's very there's a
lot of leather in it there we go someone
else just said it too yeah yeah and
there's um
there's you know there's some american
seed companies that i won't that are
uh you know
that they're crossing things to cuban
black and other haze things
um there's obviously some european seed
companies like shanti baba that have
some stuff there's a big debate on what
he's lost and what he's had but um you
know you can definitely get it seems
like the mango haze
um is still really good from him
um you know there's smaller breeders
doing smaller work on hazes
it definitely is easier to get a well i
don't know easier to get but
um you know there's there's good haze
cuts out there that are starting to slip
out a little bit more wide
um yeah
you know that kind of thing
so
you know uh people were talking about
when did the first cookie pop out
that's a whole show in itself but
probably by probably like
09 ish
yeah
i would say uh i can't talk about
somebody mentioned the legitimacy of uh
scott from rare danks neville's haze
couldn't tell you just no idea uh you
know neville's haze has been for sale
for a long time if he used neville's
haze from neville couldn't tell you what
arrow was from
um no information on that as far as that
goes
uh but
you know um
you know there's big debates people talk
about newer
newer releases of shanti's stuff don't
have that
um people always get that way sometimes
i wonder if it doesn't have that or just
you found it in one or two packs and
then you go through five or six more
packs looking for it you don't find it
yeah is it in there
did you just not see it that time yeah
did the luck of the draw not pop up you
know because it's it's a it's a super
[ __ ] to find one that you want
purple haze was a super famous
um haze from the original
um hayes lines from america you know
they kind of sister
they said they kind of bred it out on
accident it was actually magenta haze on
the poster now that i think about it
magenta
yeah you know um
you know so the problem with haze is
that it's hard to find keepers it's rare
but there is a bunch of interest in it
all of a sudden in the last two or three
years and so that's gotten some american
breeders collecting cuts and making
hybrids
um and you can find johnny come lately
[ __ ] you know just just be
prepared to hunt through some jungle
weed
and you know and don't don't let you
know we should mention um we should
mention that uh
if we're talking about jungle weed there
is a super famous cut
of uh nl5 haze a
i think in holland and it's called dr
grinspoon
it's it's called quays [ __ ]
okay whatever quays dr grinspoon i'm
just gonna say most people probably know
it is one of the other it's not the same
thing okay anyway quakes some call it
place yes so
the the point i was trying to make is
when you watch this thing grow
it's a million little calyxes like this
[ __ ] big it's like the kind of thing
where 99 of growers would cut that [ __ ]
halfway through
right it produces a million little
one-hitter type bong rips yeah but the
weed off it's unbelievable
yeah so if you're growing haze
don't go by looks
yeah wait until you can smoke it and see
what the effect is and see what the
taste is yeah because some of the
shittiest looking weed imaginable
and i'm talking ugly like like like haze
is not
ig photogenic
no there is a lot of ugly haze brown
shitty [ __ ] growth hairy looking but
then you smoke it and it tears your head
off and it tastes delicious and you're
happy and giggling and life is good
yeah so you really have to make sure
don't don't give up early
because that's what everybody does uh
yeah i bloomed out the quays didn't keep
cuts i was like what's this [ __ ] and i
did pollinate it but i was like
i mean you know neville even talked
about like his favorite female
he blooms it out and it took 20 weeks
and he thought it was the hairiest
ugliest never finishing piece of [ __ ]
ever
and he cut it down and he hung it in the
corner and he killed the mom and then a
month later he made some hash out of it
he said it was some of the best we've
ever smoked in his life and he still
regretted losing it yeah but by looks it
was the ugliest piece of [ __ ] he'd ever
seen
yeah
you know so you can't judge hayes hey
this is not cookie haze is not
photogenic
he's what you're going for with haze is
taste and effect
yeah
you know it's gonna be a gnarly big ugly
plant you could get some pretty ones
it's not impossible
but don't give up if it looks hideous
yeah there's only a few people i've seen
make pure haze look photogenic and very
very few yeah and then on top of that
what's gonna happen more often than not
is that ugly piece of [ __ ] that you held
onto that you had dreams for that was
going to be it isn't it and then it's
just an ugly piece of [ __ ] you know and
you're like yeah okay because that
happened to me quite a bit too you know
it's like i buy all this neville's haze
and it takes me [ __ ] forever to do it
and it's like 14 18 whatever weeks and
then i'm like oh i don't want to keep it
yeah no i will i will say like i never
really rocked rare dateless stuff just
because the guy was a dick to me
but um
a lot of people do like the moonshine
haze i i got to smoke it once at uh one
of the jennifer cannabis cups at some
mad ball or something i can't remember
who was playing but it was some punk
rock show and it was it was pretty good
not gonna lie even as biased as i am it
was pretty good for a [ __ ] haze i
think rich did a good job on the moon if
you limit your seeds to only people you
think you like you're really limiting
your seeds in cannabis
yeah
yeah very much so
much sometimes weirdos and and [ __ ]
and whatnot sometimes they pop out fire
yeah you know
yeah and yeah i don't even know dude so
i'm not even dissing him i'm just saying
that you know that
that uh um it's tough that's what makes
haze tough it's tough to find and so
it's cool that people are trying to make
like more accessible hazes and then it's
kind of gaining in popularity again
especially from some of these smaller
seed companies and people trying to pump
it in new york because
um that'll keep it alive
you need periodic booms of interest
to keep things going
yeah
you know you really i said when i was
selling pith nobody wanted it and now
it's very in demand i wish i would have
sat on those seeds
froze them you know till now but that's
not how [ __ ] works yeah
i was i was joking about uh rare skunk
one the other show yeah you know 15
years ago you couldn't give skunk away
no
couldn't
you know a lot of the companies put free
skunk one or skunk haze or skunk
whatever hybrids one hybrids out there
yeah because they just had so much they
just had so many stock and they never
sold any so you might as well make
people happy and throw in four seeds
freebies
yep
now people are like well maybe there's
some secret sauce in this old skunk one
that i can find yeah the secret skunky
smells you know you'd have a lot better
luck hope hunting for something secret
and haze
yeah um than you would in in skunk one
that's for sure gunk one you people have
probably pushed it to its limit
yeah
hey is there still surprises and people
ask i should just remember because it
popped into my head people asked about
the band-aid haze seven
yes because that's a cut that floats
around i will say that people i respect
like yo sami in europe and others
have told me they view that cut
as equal to the old cuts that they hold
that's pretty cool so it's the first
haze in a long time that they feel
is as good and stands right there with
those old 25 30 year old strains that
have been kept forever that's
interesting and it's a lot more
accessible to people yeah uh in in you
know in america than a lot of these
other ones that i talk about these
things are i should mention people think
i'm connected or whatever i have been
[ __ ] hunting all of these european
haze cuts since the 90s yeah
you know and it it was like the white
rabbit it was like multi decades of
looking
yeah and there's still some like that
neville taste cut i want that thing so
bad
um i know where it is
i can't get it
you know if it's in america i don't know
about it
yeah um you know but uh anyway the
band-aid hey seven is an amazing cut
uh amazing effect they're growing it
over in europe they love it it's easier
to get in america than the rest of them
yeah it does take forever you know so be
prepared to go 14 weeks or whatever
um but it's a it's a fire cut by all
accounts yeah um and uh i believe that's
cuban black
uh haze cross to a5 tai
i believe so yeah whatever cuban black
is
but yeah so whatever so it's possible
that you know it's that it's it's a c5
cut by an a5 cut by some a thai male to
provide pollen maybe maybe yeah but
whatever case may be um there's a cut
you can still buy band-aid hay seeds
there's various versions of them
and there's at least this one cut that
came out uh elite status
yeah and the people that have been
running um a lot of these hazes for 30
years if they think it's as good as the
rest of them
you know that's pretty high praise from
them
yeah yeah adoptee is doing a lot of work
that he's a good dude
so you know
um yeah we did talk about tom hill just
in in brief
uh not very not for very long um
you know but tom hill did release did
have tom hill hayes
and did have tom uh hey tom hill haze by
deep chunk
and uh maybe some other more work around
that yeah and i believe all of his stuff
descends from positronics haze lines
the fuzzy brown is is
kind of saying that you're wrong about
a5 and c5 not existing i don't think
he's confused no they definitely exist
yeah
they definitely exist but what i'm
saying is that there's there's various
haze cuts that i know are alive in
europe and i don't know if they're alive
here
yeah there's a5 and c5 that have popped
up in america and there's a number of
people that have them
um there's still politics around
releasing seed around it
uh or trading it or whatever so they're
still tough so they're alive um some of
them
actually to be said uh some of them have
uh
some of them have the virus
yeah so be careful
yeah i haven't run the sssc hazes
someone's asking about but
um
that's a good thing to mention because
one of the things that's interesting is
almost all the haze that's available
is
based off of neville's work which is a
couple of males yeah right or some posi
work or whatever but neville's seems to
be the stuff that everybody found firing
yeah and when we interviewed corel um
corel had
a they had a and it's been confirmed by
friends of mine he has a 35 plus year
old skunk haze
yeah that he made from haze seeds given
to him
yeah and what's interesting about if you
were to get karel's work and cross it to
some of neville's work
is that it's not neville's males
yeah it's another genetic of haze
yeah so it's not quite the same
bottleneck yep
um whatsoever
you know because haze doesn't like being
crossed to itself
so
and it's from that same batch of seed
that neville got
you know yeah so i didn't really realize
that until we talked to him yeah that
was a mind blower
but his ssc
hybrids off that skunk haze should be a
completely different haze that's been
available up until recently yeah
but from the same seats from the same
area
i i'm gonna be really excited with some
new outdoor space to finally run some of
my ace collection and other [ __ ] stoped
finally get to pop the sssc stuff
because i've really wanted to
yeah so i mean there's i don't know i
could i could try to
you know at the end of it i could try to
name you know there's
there's uh dog [ __ ] and the call we
haven't talked about the colorado cough
no didn't talk about the cough the cough
is another uh i think we did an nl5 haze
episode though
yeah you know
so there's there's there's cough there's
dog [ __ ] there's cuban black uh
dutch tree
uh uh sweet skunk from your from canada
has a bunch of nl5 haze in it
um or is it
you know at least in its original form
so there's a bunch of american cuts that
float around
there's eight or ten dutch cuts that
float around i don't know what that all
adds up to
um but what's great is that it seems
like from uh from a line that was
available in the 90s
um yeah there's the stew which is one
that i don't actually somebody mentioned
that i know i don't even know that i
know of the stew the stew is an old
um as another old nl5 haze from the east
coast i've never actually grown it it's
been one of those rumors
that i hear about
okay i've heard stories of the stew i've
talked to people that i trust
that uh have talked about the stew
um i've never seen this do
you remember
is it kind of like disco stew in the
simpsons where like the d rubbed off his
jacket so it was the stud and then
i almost want to say people might get me
wrong but it's like it's uh uh
the stew might be from jersey or
something close somewhere in that new
york region
okay um and it's old but i uh but i i
don't know anything about it but it is
it is another supposed nl5 haze cut
um that and and island sweet skunk is a
little different than sweet skunk and
then mark emery did this thing
uh you know that confused the lineage of
it um but as far as we can tell there is
a real
um there is a real sweet skunk that was
basically mostly nl5 haze
yeah
and it got caught did did did uh
um steve cross it to like grapefruit or
something
or yeah i don't know what it was crossed
here
so you know anyway um
the uh you know fork you know so it's
it's cool in the sense that there's a
bunch of different phenos
yeah that have survived
you know um all females obviously we
don't have any i don't you know people
are asking me where could you get real
nl5 hayes male pollen
and i think that might be lost to time
yeah we have uh one of our buddies um
kim blackburn is is a part of the cough
crew so we have people closer to the cop
that know the history of it real well so
i'll probably bring him on at some point
working man to
talk about it he's a cough fanatic yeah
and he's got he knows he knows the story
pretty well i mean there's some there's
some still confusion about it there was
cough one and there was cough two in
colorado yeah i used to smoke the cough
in the 90s i had really good friends of
mine i grew up with that ended up moving
out to boulder
in the mid 90s and i used to go out
there all the time and that's where i
smoked that sandalwood tasting ak-47
yeah and some of those other famous 90s
colorado strains
um
but yeah the cough exists
um the new york stuff exists strawberry
cough is much different
um
i don't know the origins of strawberry
coffee
i know what cushman says i know that it
is exactly like herb beer and it's
chirps
and has a lot of similar uh traits to it
i like some strawberry filled haze
or whatever that's worth yeah
and the cough you know the cough
basically like got famous in fort
collins but i think it came from
connecticut
um i don't want to misspeak but our
buddy working man knows like
the people involved and like the people
that brought it to colorado from there
and all that different types of stuff so
um it definitely is
uh
you know yeah you never know the dog
[ __ ] the dog [ __ ] i really wish still
had its original name
uh its original name is right up there
with western winds is one of my
favorites the dog [ __ ] in minneapolis
was called electric bugaloo
yeah you know what sucks is like i was
um doing the labels for the uh
the dog [ __ ] crosstalk hawaiian lights
and i was like i just wanted to put
electric boogaloo but i know
most people won't even associate that
with the dog [ __ ] cut and they'll just
sit there
you know yeah
you know it'll just sit there but but
electric boogaloo is like
one of the all-time great names
yeah you know i loved it
uh
we still have we still have good friends
that grow the cough
that we talk to all the time um so
luckily the cough is alive and well
um you know there's
there's a haze in florida that got
shipped in new york
you know um there's crews of cubans down
there there's crews of cubans and
dominicans in new york that run it
there's you know hayes
cabin fever that's totally incorrect it
was what i was just talking about it's
not [ __ ] mad farmer he had nothing to
do with that cut it was a cut at a blue
sky cafe
um originally and it was made by lion
something farms you can still find the
info on icy mag way back when he made it
long before mad farmer came to this and
it's an aft gooey cross deep chunk it is
not strawberry cough deep junk
so it was just relabeled by blue sky
there we go
i mean one of the things i should say
about one of the things that draws
people to hayes is that
we live in an indica dominated it's like
the exact opposite of the 70s and 80s
uh where
excuse me where sativa ruled the game
yeah we live in an indica and indica
dominant scene
yeah
and hayes is a tie back to that ancient
you know uh no longer available import
and it seems like it gives people a
better high in a different way
it has a different high profile it hits
people and even if people are extremely
used to and experienced with smoking
chems or you know ogs or whatever you
can smoke some haze
and have it hit you like a brick
um so even though it's ugly and takes a
long time and has these various issues
uh it's popular for my favorite reason
for weed to be popular
because it works good
yeah effect it works good
you know so that's the best reason to to
like weed it's weed that works
weed that works
you know
yeah so
all right i'm gonna we're at uh 103
minutes so i think we are good for this
session we are good for the session so i
mean once again everyone thank you for
giving us like uh your friday night to
listen to
me ramble
and uh you know and whatnot and matt and
shoot the [ __ ] and uh
you know you can reach out to us on our
discord on our uh
um
on our speakeasy discord uh you can
reach out to us on our ig pages
discord's easier we always are now
read your syndicate discord the
speakeasy discord's a different one oh
yeah that's right see and i misspeak
well i should let you do the i'm so bad
at any kind of promotion i know i
appreciated it i was watching i was
letting you roll but yeah so the the
breeder syndicate discord uh we post on
there quite a bit uh we answer questions
all the time we're always down for
people to give us ideas of it's all
about like what you guys want to hear
about we're trying all the time to like
bring people history and make it modern
and tie it into what they know and
expand people's knowledge and stuff like
that so
um once again uh into it you know you
can search for breeder syndicate on
google
right we just need to get patreon
reader syndicate patreon see i i i this
this you're almost there i'm almost
there
i'm almost there but anyway thanks for
listening everyone
we'll have we'll be there we'll be here
next week i'll see you soon hawaiian
light typewriter it's coming soon right
if you're a patreon member you'll get
first access to them and they're way
cheaper for you so cheers cheerso peace
[Music]
you