foreign
ERS Syndicate update not only is our
merch store up at syndicategear.com but
all episodes will remain free but what
we need from you is interaction if
you're watching the show for your first
time kick back and enjoy it if you like
the show feel free to like it but if
it's your second viewing we ask a gentle
person's agreement that you click the
Subscribe button it costs you nothing
but it helps us tremendously with the
sneaky YouTube algorithm
leaving comments telling Natsu his voice
lulls you into a trance works as well we
hope you take the time to do this we try
to put out the best possible shows for
you we can and want to build this
community thanks again from all of us at
the Breeders Syndicate family
welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
cannabis strain history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
welcome everyone I'm Matthew this is
Brendan from zomia Collective uh this is
the breeder Syndicate and today we're
going to be talking about land races
um what's been going on in Thailand the
current political climate and kind of
what zomia Collective is all about uh
first off like I said this is Brendan
from zomia Collective it's a very
special group out in Thailand and uh
I've been speaking with them lately
about what's going on out there and and
just been totally Blown Away fascinated
interested it's very rare in our
community where I I run into someone
where I feel like their passion is at
the the true fervor level that mine is
or a lot of my friends are where it's
just like this is what we live to do and
I feel like like Brendan is one of those
so welcome Brandon it's nice to meet you
man yeah no thank you
um it's a pleasure to be here honestly
so
um you know when you're when you're
talking about passion that's what it's
all about you know that's what we live
for here yeah I can tell and like from
the type of political activities you've
gotten yourself into and and the The
Works you do for social change it's it's
very very humbling to watch from from a
person you know way over here it's what
I'd love to be doing so mad props tell
me a little bit about zomia tell me tell
me what zomia is in the first place
a collective
um it's uh it's a project that's working
on long-term land race conservation in
Southeast Asia but fundamentally it's
much more than that it's a social
movement
um it's a concept in political
philosophy and anthropology
um that's sort of grounded in an
understanding of the indigenous people
of the Hill tracks of Southeast Asia
it's a sort of non-jurisdictional entity
which comprises about a hundred million
people
um speaking you know so many different
languages all of whom are united in a
sort of a refusal to partake in the
state in paying taxes and you know being
conscripted and instead uh you know live
in the in the Hills away from everybody
else one of the things that unites the
region is the choice of crops namely
cannabis and so
um with a foundation in political
activism which we can get it into if you
want a sort of nucleus of of
cannabis breeders Growers
Village elders and tribal communities
formed into yeah or Collective with this
purpose of preservation the land race uh
cannabis in Southeast Asia perhaps even
Beyond that's amazing um can you tell me
what kind of pushed you in this
direction uh where did you grow up what
got you into the southeast Asia climate
stuff like that
sure uh personally I'm I'm back I'm from
The Basque country but I grew up in
Scotland and that was kind of where me
and Matthew were talking uh kind of a
little bit the the sort of Trainspotting
uh style of things you know we were
buying cannabis from pretty sketchy
places from a pretty young age and
I mean for those who know you you know
what the scene's all about and
when you catch that bug and especially
for us we were really lucky to get stuff
like gold stamped Mazar
um you know Goldfield like black Afghan
um despite being you know in a really
Northern remote location we did benefit
from some of the sort of uh the the the
small scale Smugglers before the the war
on terror and the changes in the
airports you know sort of killed that
and from then it was you know at 16 I
came out to
to to India and then to Southeast Asia
and ended up never never leaving
um you know a lot of my formative
experiences were there
um I fell into the into the wine
industry strangely enough as a sort of
you know francophone in Southeast Asia
right
um but you know there's this kind of
there's this I guess this racism I
suppose where where the or internalized
racism I don't know what how you want to
describe it but there's the need for
like a token french guy to sell wine
um in the fancy restaurants and it
doesn't matter whether he's Basque or
actually French or not you know close
enough you know yeah right and so I as a
lover of you know good taste and you
know and everything else I always had a
bit of chip on my shoulder about good
food sort of being so expensive and you
know this was my way to to be able to
taste what I wanted to Taste and to talk
with chefs and that kind of stuff and it
was great but I also it was great it was
also terrible and I got very
disillusioned and so when the
opportunity to sort of bring the
the structure of uh somelier in
particular to the Cannabis world came
about I jumped on it because it was you
know the the culmination and honestly 16
year old they wouldn't have believed it
you know it's just a dream country right
yeah absolutely and so
um basically lucky enough to be working
in in restaurants with a budget high
enough to pay for traveling in terms of
r d and pre-covered a lot of traveling
you know looking for indigenous or
traditional fermented beverages for for
food pairings
um let us let me in my team
um to be in contact with a lot of
communities who are also growing
cannabis and in the course of you know
spending time in these communities
learning how they ferment different
grains and cereals pulses Etc into into
alcohol and drinks the opportunity came
about to to to sort of learn more about
the land race cannabis and it was very
nicely timed
um a few years before the legalization
in Thailand which gave a little bit more
confidence to us and to others to be
able to sort of open up because as I'm
sure a lot of you are aware the panels
disease for you know engaging in
anything kind of isolated in Thailand
before legalization where we're very
very severe yeah and so it was yeah it
was really about it was about timing and
about passion I guess and a lot of a lot
of like-minded individuals with you know
a singular Target I guess
um and that Target again being the
conservation of of land races and I
think it's a subject which it's pretty
easy to be passionate about you know so
it's a certain substance there's stories
there's there's so much to it yeah
there's a lot to it um you're talking
about like going into the communities
and looking up fermented uh different
fermented drinks that's fascinating man
like what yeah well can you give us an
example like bang is that like do they
make fermented bang and stuff like that
um well you know I've actually never
seen uh fermented bangs
um it's not definitely not out of the
bounds of the imagination no you know we
we're looking at doing in this
particular context sort of pre-colonial
Indian and Thai recipes and wandering at
our intellectual dishonesty at charging
really high prices for French wine
pairings with that you know yeah yeah of
course and so it was a matter of yeah
trying to find you know different sort
of unique things which we could bring
that value element to the to the
customer to the person consuming the
beverage of yours a complex drink with a
good taste and a story there's quite a
lot of them around but unfortunately we
don't really find them so much in the
big sort of urban city context where
Bank might be consumed you know and bang
is a regulated good so it's sold in the
government shops you can find it outside
of course but uh primarily it at least I
associate it with a bit more of an urban
context whereas the drinks we were more
in tatiskar and jharkhand in orisa in
the tribal regions
um you know mostly grains rice
one of my favorites in Thailand is
called Sato there's different forms but
essentially it's a glutenous rice with a
little yeast cake called lupang which is
made from a bunch of different local
herbs and essentially you get a little
clay pot and you add your your rice and
then your your lupang and your water you
fill it up with a little bit of water
and then you seal it off the top of the
jar is sealed off with clay and that'll
be left for a few days and you can just
burst there's like a bamboo straw you
burst the clay seal and you just pop it
straight in and drink right out of it
and
got the most wonderful like sour uh
funky fermentation Aroma frankly
um and you know that provided a really
solid base which experiment with
infusing different you know flavors into
it making it sparkling that kind of
thing
um you know I mean the the equivalent of
you know a really expensive wine if it's
something going to be like you know
traditional there's a lot of racism in
the world of food and you know Thai food
Indian food is very often looked down
upon and so for it to sort of be valued
as an equivalent by something like a
Michelin inspector it needs to really be
sort of yeah yeah I bet
so as a sommelier did you guys uh did a
lot of the experience with like
chirpings and stuff cross over into
cannabis
yeah at the end in my last job that was
something that we were playing with
quite a lot the last two jobs actually
um I was uh I was the beverage director
for a group which included some cocktail
bars and a couple of restaurants in
Bangkok and they were very sort of
progressive and open-minded one of the
owners smoked a lot of weight
um and so it was a little bit easier to
sort of Swing those things however we
weren't able to actually roll it out in
the dining room because it was before
the legalization yeah and despite you
know terpenes not having any cannabis
it's not the sort of attention that any
sort of restaurant was looking for at
that time
um but we were playing with it because
you know apart from the fermented
beverages they're talking about they
have alcohol in them and there's a lot
of people who don't consume alcohol in
Asia and so
um we were looking yeah much more at
doing stuff with tea uh Botanicals of
which you know terpenes
um key component in almost any that you
look at
um so as a stoner I'm always interested
in sort of you know finding some OG Kush
taste and some mad tea from somewhere or
something like that you know yeah of
course as you got into the Asian
political sphere and you started making
these connections and inroads what got
you then to move from maybe
um as much of a preservation of Thailand
races which was really you know the main
starting goal into working with the
farmers and making sure the farmers are
absolutely taken care of
I see those two things as absolutely
synonymous that's beautiful
um yeah I mean I I can go in more into
detail if you'd like but please do well
there's a lot of conservation
um I see people tagging their indoor
grows as preservation runs
um you know and the thing with zoos is
that they're pretty big entities that
require a lot of coordination and moving
parts and until the Advent of pretty
strict regulations
um and even despite that they can be
pretty dark places
and so
when I think of exit to conservation I
think of yeah little amateur zoos
um it's a noble effort but ultimately
the only people who can grow
significant populations of open
pollinated cannabis
um from Land race genetics
is people in the traditional land race
growing regions I mean they don't have
to contend or at least for now with all
of the licenses that's needed in in the
west or in North America and Europe
um they don't need to contend at least
until recently they didn't need to
contend with hemp Farms or contamination
those kinds of things and so
I'm hesitant to say that no preservation
can be done outside because I think it's
pretty obvious that it can but at this
point the focus seems to be so much on
um getting seeds out of the traditional
growing regions and into cryogenic
storage or into long-term you know
growing facilities and there's not much
thought going into actually just helping
out the farmers who are growing land
races in the traditional growing region
and keeping them growing these
traditional yeah like yeah they're
already doing it like and the problem so
I'm playing a lot of places including in
Thailand
um people are coming all over and
they're like oh well listen like we need
to teach these guys how to be more
profitable so they can sort of keep up
with the modern industry blah blah blah
blah this is not the solution answer
sorry this is not a solution either yeah
um by modernizing and changing either
the target of their growth for example
to move away from tariffs to trisift and
bubble hashes and Parvati and other
places this changes the way that the
selections are made and despite being
maybe quite subtle
um they have long lasting consequences
you know and so ultimately we'd be
looking at providing essentially a
subsidy for Growers that are growing a
product which unfortunately is not
profitable in the modern Marketplace but
has significant value for the community
and Industry as a whole yeah um and you
know giving them that incentive to make
the choice to grow these land races
despite the disadvantages that are you
know created by legislation policy Etc
um you know because ultimately everybody
has families to take care of and you
know wants to eat and so when faced with
a choice of or not necessarily the
choice when faced with having a
long-standing land race grow
no more customers and knowing that all
it would take is to switch to a modern
cultivar for your Market to suddenly
open up you know that's that's a choice
which almost every land race farmer is
facing today and we need to give them a
reason to
if you like hybrids let's you know keep
doing what we're doing
um yeah it kind of reminds me a little
bit of The multi-state Operators
dropping the prices you know below
um
a sustainable uh you know price yeah for
producing yeah because they can afford
to sustain that and take that loss
yeah exactly so it kind of feels like
the same
land race farm
everybody sort of recognizes
it is what they have but nobody's really
willing to actually hook them up or even
able really to buy their products and so
it's just kind of going to disappear in
the meantime and that's what we hope
hope to address and to to redress and so
what we do essentially is we approach
the it depends who we're approaching and
when but if we can we're approaching the
the community as a whole
um the the village elder or Village
Chief or whatever the equivalent is and
you know coming up with some sort of
agreement for them to continue growing
land races and for us to to make an
attempt at you know offering their
germplasm
um and seeds to to the International
Community with for which to breed with
um the idea is that you know people back
home don't need to be concerned with
conservation if we actually let the pros
take care of it in a way and then they
can have fun creating all the crazy
hybrids from the final hunt which can be
done each year in such a of you know
genetically diverse population right
yeah
yeah so that's the way we see it that's
amazing man
um the the whole the whole way that you
approach it is very I don't know just
socially conscious to me and I and it's
something that's been lacking a lot in
cannabis
um I think a lot of people that I've
I've seen over the years tend to maybe I
don't want to say exploit the farmers
but it's hard to say anything other than
that because they they try to get the
cheapest absolute price so that they can
then take a cut off the seeds over the
top and that's how they make their money
you know but back it all goes back to
what is the incentive for the farmers to
keep growing these when people come to
them like uh without using any names
like a big Seed Company you know from
Amsterdam that says hey we'd rather you
have you you know you give us your land
races we'll store these in German flag
you can grow some of these feminized
seeds in the meantime you know like this
is how this is how things disappear for
good and uh I appreciate your work on it
hey look I mean I I don't think that
we're going to be able to to prevent is
going extinct unfortunately but we'll
definitely do what we can with you know
the communities that are willing to work
with us to to try and keep what we can
for as long as we can but ultimately
it's going to require a concerted effort
on behalf of the entire Community
um ultimately there needs to be a demand
for tejuana driven products and a clear
understanding of what theof driven
products are ultimately I think a lot of
people they want to have that experience
of the Colombian gold or the Thai stick
that they had back in the day and you
know that was all imported cannabis and
so if we want to return to experiences
like that we need to consider a
normalization of trade since that's so
so far away it seems to make sense to
support the the land race growers in the
meantime by breeding with their genetics
so let's define land race as you see it
as you understand it because that's
super important
you know I I I hate to do that actually
because
um but I don't hate to do it but I just
think that
um there's a lot of uh opinions and a
lot of oh sure words out there
um I don't see why we need to reinvent
the wheel every time you know like it's
my take
um is not as as interesting or I think
um as accurate as the numerous studies
which have been published over the last
few decades
um you know dealing with land races and
also specifically defining land races so
um
I would say that um I can actually
remember the name of the authors of the
paper right now there's a paper called
towards an evolved concept of land races
which
um basically
it's looking at the history of the
definition of the term and making a
proposal that land races should be
considered as basically in Dynamic
populations
which can be subjected to introgression
while still retaining their designation
as land races interesting and that's
important because the earliest
definitions of land race on grunker for
example but even you know until seven
which I think was 1998
um were much more about static
um you know the land races uh monolithic
never-changing thing right yeah and if
it becomes polluted it's gone and if
that's the case then they're destined
for the museum and they'll never you
know that's not my that's a quote from
the paper you know they'll yeah they'll
never get out
so
in one sense that makes a lot of sense
on one side that makes a lot of sense to
me on the other I think that the
implication of this sort of evolved
understanding of land races
um is
is underlined by a world view or sorry
maybe sort of a structured by a
worldview which cannot consider a future
where indigenous people might be sort of
left in peace to grow alone you know
like the paper can't even consider that
which bothers me fundamentally because
as
a naive dreamer I suppose I'd like to
imagine a future where you know
everybody could be left alone yeah
I suppose that is somewhat unrealistic
so you know given the context the
capitalism will continue to expand into
every single possible Market that it can
land race cannabis in traditional
growing regions far away from the
nearest road to City no exception
um you know if that's the case then then
I think that that paper does make a lot
of sense
um if we if we are going to integrate
these communities into the global
economy and their crops into the global
economy as Commodities then certainly
there needs to be some sort of uh
new look at how we Define land races
yeah I would basically say yeah go go
read the studies don't listen to me like
I've got nothing fresh to say on the
definition of land races you know I'm a
bit boring on that I'm happy to defer to
the to the scientists but that's a great
answer because you know some people will
insert their their opinions as facts
state it very confidently and that's
that you know and and the real answer is
man just gotta do let's check out the
research and stay up to date with the
research right yeah yeah because it's
changing you know and it has changed
um and the way we interpret the study
ourselves you know the I read it you
read it and somehow we come up with two
slightly different conclusions you know
so I would rather instead of um because
I see that something that's happening a
lot
um I'm constantly having these
conversations and I feel like instead of
constantly Reinventing the wheel and
giving our opinions as to what the
definitions of these things are we
should maybe be doing more reading as a
community and and seeing what you know
the biologists have to say about land
races because there's a lot of work done
for foreign land races for weeds Etc
yeah and despite the fact that there's
very few cannabis specific studies
there's a lot of studies on similar
organisms hops Etc we can learn a lot
from yeah so people that are watching
this probably one of the reasons they're
going to come to watch a show about
Thailand races and and we talked about
this yesterday what is the chocolate tie
it's always the first question I get
I've worked with a line called chocolate
type from a dude named Dro who
supposedly sourced it from the people
that DNA down in there and sourced it
from to make chocolate back in the day
there's of course all these fantastic
Legends and fables of Pasa dipped you
know heroin infused cannabis there's all
these Tales of what chocolate Thai is in
your experience what do you learn about
chocolate pie
um very very little and I think that's
the the message here is that
um in Thailand the area which produced
cannabis the largest area isan
um was incredibly like really really
poor until quite recently and the idea
that farmers were sort of walking around
eating Nestle chocolate and naming
things I mean not saying that no one had
ever heard of chocolate in Nissan in the
70s but it's an English word and it's in
my opinion a pretty sort of pretty
clearly it's foreigners who you know had
some accession or selection
or bags of weed with some seeds in it
you know
um and they had you know a chocolate I
really because I really can't speak on
DNA or anything like that at all I can
think of is you know having gone through
the motions myself asking pretty much
everybody that I can you know deal with
chocolate Thai and you know being met
with the same thing one issue is that
um a lot of the traditional knowledge
here in Thailand has sort of slowly been
sort of dissipating and becoming
unstructured and a lot of the youngins
are learning from the same sources that
we are and so you'll meet some
especially ethnic pie like they'll be
maybe aware of chocolate Thai and maybe
if you rocked up to Thailand and a few
years ago and you asked for it you would
have got something and they would have
told you it was chocolate pie I don't
know
um I can't speak for anything like that
but what I can say is that as far as
large open pollinated populations of
cannabis that we could describe as land
race that the farmers are sort of
engaging with and in their head
conceiving of as chocolate Thai that
doesn't exist as far as unaware of
um what I can say though
um to give people some some hope
yeah exactly exactly is that
um the
the aroma of chocolate also that of
coffee dark earthy musty Aromas are very
typical of narrow Leaf drug type land
race when it's been subjected to
compression curing which I think a lot
of you will know is Thai sticks and so
um I guess when you have this sort of
um this mechanical pressure plus
temperature plus time we see significant
impact on the terpene profiles when we
can add anaerobic conditions on occasion
aging underground or these days in
vacuum seals we do see some pretty funky
Aromas coming out of it but one thing
that's quite consistent is a sort of
earthy chocolatey character
um that's something that I've I've had a
lot in my time in Southeast Asia in Laos
in Cambodia and Myanmar and elsewhere
with the older you know six month plus
Europe staff and so
I don't want to speculate too much but I
think it would be interesting if it
turned out to be some sort of uh you
know terpene
um which which was sort of maybe about
synthesized
um during this aging process
um and you know who's leading to that it
could also be a combination of different
compounds which are leading to this
smell but uh yeah there's definitely
something to to research there and I
think for those interested in the
chocolate pie your best bet is the final
hunt the the Lao isanjinpu and so for
that you can approach squirrel tail
Tiger Tail Thai mango snake teeth
um a bunch of other stuff
um and you know you'll find pretty
consistently you know applying these
compassion curing techniques that you'll
have these chocolate Aromas they're
delicious by the way
um if you nail it you're looking at a
slow degradation of the chlorophyll
leaving almost everything else intact
and so you've got a very smooth smoke
which doesn't have this sort of Full
Green character which chlorophyll brings
which is so ubiquitous the smoking
cannabis flower and I'll say as a note
that
um you know just as sort of curiosity a
couple times we've had some some
professional similes coming into our our
we're partnered with a dispensary in
Bangkok and they have a total of 64
trains in the in the in the shop front
now and we let all the summer there
smell them and they're like yeah next
next next next next they get to the
compression cured Lao gold land race and
they're like oh what's this because it's
the only one that doesn't smell green
yeah and doesn't have that chlorophyll
and then wine green is an aroma that's
very sort of uh we
yeah it's viewed as a flaw almost yeah
almost universally and so yeah I think
that there's there's something to be
explored there and I think that there's
a reason why so many people are in love
with this chocolate pie with the myth of
it with the story because there is
something there that's you know
rewarding delicious
um I just don't think it's a strain a
strain it's a proper yeah yeah yeah I
know what's interesting is growing up
here and in in the 90s earlier that 90s
uh getting a lot of Mexican compressed
Rick constant and in that Mexican
compressed brick I've always said it
smelled like minty chocolate but
definitely a cocoa type smell and I
would I mean it was compression
cured and sat forever so it it kind of
you know speaks to what you're talking
about very very very interesting
um you mentioned of course the the
infamous Tiger Tail squirrel tail can we
start talking about some of these
different uh what you would call like
maybe an expression of these different
land races or yeah yeah sure so
um
it's gone really confusing and that's
the picture that I'm trying to paint
yeah um the way I'm explaining it it's
probably going to be a bit confused and
what I'm explaining is very confusing
yeah um essentially
the first attestation to the word
squirrel tail in allow script
um that we saw was in reference to
um traditional tip weaving which is a
style or a better squirrel tail is a
pattern found in traditional kit weaving
which today is practiced in silk and I
think one day I'd like to find if I can
a traditional Thai fist or you know a
weaving historian if that exists oh
right did they did they make it with
hemp because that would be my interest
to be a hunch yeah I mean squirrel tail
the Tiger Tail
um these are many things
um it's all down to the the Lao isan we
can call it so on both sides of the
Mekong in Thailand and Laos live
speakers in the Thai side it's referred
to as a region as isan or the Korat
plateau and
essentially
the words that are used to describe
cannabis of a certain archetype
um or squirrel tail tiger Tails Tetris
so squirrel tail describes like a big
like cheerleader like Pom-Pom style but
you know like really like
yeah not to leave very puffy and then
the Tiger Tail is the it's more like the
the creeper I've heard it referred to in
English as a Creeper stuff that makes
sense like Robert describe creepers
I think so yes you have a lot of lateral
branching low to the ground with these
these branches sometimes forming new
roots and then big swoopy main colas and
strangely the English translation
um for Tiger Tail is sometimes rendered
as Rudder and I'm not sure who got
confused the English speakers of the
Thai but some of the ties have also been
telling me that no this is Rudder as in
like
boat Roger uh yeah something they'd be
most used to seeing I don't know but in
that sense I was thinking just like a
long upright rigid object but you know
because if you look at some of the Tiger
Tail they really do like they have this
huge main top caller and then the the
branching's already low to the side
there's quite as with a lot of these
things there's a lot of different
stories but so far you know the we were
able to differentiate between the the
the the structure on these two
um and then also the structure for the
type for the snake teeth
um which is the
the vine like growth kind of like Dr
grinspoon where you have a running
cowlick structure
um and then the mango or would be the
you know the mercy enrich
um accessions
um but it's also pretty common to find
mango Aromas in Squirrel tail tiger
tails and the snake teeth so ultimately
I think that originally it would have
been a singular gene pool which during
its dissemination and the cross-cultural
contact between the thighs the Lao and
other groups in the region
um seeds were exchanged planets were
exchanged and we ended up with both
autoctonus
um you know land race populations big
open pollinated populations
um sorry optometrist and allotones in
different regions
um a bunch of inbred lines some single
plants
um
reproductions from Single Seeds you know
multiply it into millions and then
disseminated and then it's a mess and a
lot of them carry the same names
um so I think it's best understood you
know as
archetypes within the gene pool but have
since become established as their own
land races and in some cases more like
modern strains as in ibls yeah yeah and
all of them coexisting uh temporally and
geographically in some cases pollinating
each other yeah it's just like really
really complicated
um we basically have done our best to
I ignore everything that we sort of hear
and focus on what we see yeah and look
for large open pollinated populations
that breed true
um they seem to have you know
um seemed to express what we consider to
look more like a primordial character
but ultimately as long as the population
size is big enough and it's grown in
open pollination then you know that fits
the the base criteria and so we're
looking to collapse from everything but
what we're sort of getting involved in
heavily is is what we can determine to
be the more I don't want to use the word
pure because it's not accurate but the
the stuff which is grown properly
managed properly and not just you know
every single little thing that we can
find because honestly it's a rabbit hole
there's at this point since legalization
every single Uncle you know whoever had
a single plant in his back Garden making
seeds and selling them
um giving them away you know people are
selling clothes for about 30 cents a
clone on the side of the street in in
Bangkok out a little trucks and stuff
and so I believe there's this really
intense sort of mixing and hybridization
of everything going on at the moment but
that's just sort of the culmination of
the last
um 40 50 years and so as far as the
laoisan gene pool is concerned
um we've been looking at plants that you
know look like a squirrel tail look like
a Tiger Tail and our captain big open
pollinated growth in Fairly remote
regions where we can and basically
that's taken us out of isan for the most
part
um and into the into the more hilly
regions where you can find that
you know we can get that distance that's
required to you know to totally prevent
the the cross-contamination
so you've done you've done a lot of work
in Thailand to you know try to pick
apart a lot of these stories and over
time it seems like zomi is kind of
spread out a little bit are there any
other areas that you you've been really
excited about that you've been looking
into I mean you talk about you know
around Thailand there's you know
Cambodia Laos Myanmar are there other
places in there that you're excited
about or elsewhere
yeah absolutely
um Cambodia is you know the place that I
spent the most time personally so I have
a really soft spot for for Cambodia and
a lot of my best friends or or Cambodian
people that you know they were little
rascals and now they're big Rascals and
we're looking forward to being able to
to return there probably this year and
look at what we can do to expand our
collection
um try and see if we can recruit some
some different communities into into the
collective and bring out some new seeds
otherwise Laos you know that's always
one of the most interesting regions
um if you're you know the Thai
nationalism prevents them from admitting
how good the Laos and weed is and the
laoshin reverse with the tie they're
both excellent
um there's a lot of synergy there
um and you know Laos has a few iconic
areas producing you know land race
cannabis that we're really looking
forward to to go to uh in particular the
the C pandon the the four thousand
Islands which is
basically an area of the Mekong where
there's cataracts on the border with
Cambodia and Laos and Mekong spreads out
into these loads of islands and it's a
pretty well known tourist destination a
place where a lot of people have you
know fond memories of kicking back and
fishing and smoking great pot from the
60s onwards and it has you know
there's not a lot of places left on the
Mekong the islands which grow this
beautiful golden weed which all the
old-timers are looking for and so that's
probably going to be one of the the
priorities in terms of where we're going
to be going around it's not necessarily
grown within the main areas but you know
along the cataracts there's there's a
lot of people growing here and there and
we're looking forward to getting some
seeds so yeah golden meekong wheat
blouse that's going to be I think that's
going to be a big hit with the
old-timers but there's a lot of stuff in
the north of the Street near the border
with unan and then of course the the
Bola Haven Plateau
um that's beautiful coffee growing
region with a significant amount of uh
local population belonging to the Lavin
ethnic group who's a very talented
cannabis Growers
um there's so much in Laos that we can
explore it's really a very very diverse
country very small but with a lot of
diversity in cannabis and in the people
the Landscapes and everything Myanmar
unfortunately is
um this you know I mean it feels a bit
silly saying unfortunately in the
context of seeds because that's not
really what makes it sad obviously but
me and Mars undergoing you know uh
severe political upheaval Civil War
um if anybody um
you know wants to wants to help out
they're taking Volunteers in Chiang Mai
right now you can go and uh sign up to
go fight for the for the militias that
are fighting against the government it's
it's absolute chaos out there it's been
getting really really really bad and you
know we we're not doing anything in
Myanmar right now
um
yeah it doesn't make any sense it
doesn't sound so safe right now or or I
mean people's priorities are different
right now yeah that's it people's
priorities are different and and we
don't feel like
um we've spoken to you know to our
contacts out there and we theoretically
could get seeds out but it just again it
doesn't seem like a priority
um I think the priority probably seems
to be for us now to to continue focusing
on our work in Cambodia Laos
um and in the northeast of India in you
know mizoram tripura nagaland Etc
but we're also very very excited to to
be bringing out some some Colombian
genetics hopefully soon oh wow
yeah well we're all very excited about
that and this is a lot of similarities
with the tie it seems between you know
the Caribbean and Latin American Gene
pools
um we're looking forward to having
closer collaboration with us and you
know Growers members of our collective
in that group and together try to build
a better picture of you know what's
going on with the land races between the
two regions a lot of similarities in the
in the the sort of setting up
semi-outdoor uh curing styles with
golden weed as a result that kind of
thing and so
our
um yeah our boys are based in kalka but
they're mobile so we're looking forward
to Bringing out some some genetics from
there pretty pretty soon
um pretty sure the next dropped or the
the current drop is I just we just came
back from from Himachal Pradesh but uh I
think next is going to be yeah in that
order Thailand Cambodia Laos followed by
followed by India again
can we talk about some of the current
recent accessions that you got
um that are on your site right now let's
talk about some of those so people have
a uh an understanding from you other
than what you write which is uh like
that's kind of what initially drew me to
you you know a good friend of Neville's
um send me to your son said you've got
to check these guys out man like this is
legit and I did and it's not just it's
not just descriptions like lulling you
in with you know words and marketing
it's how you collected it it's how you
listed the accessions it's done very
well like in my opinion very
scientifically and all the details that
people need to know
um a lot of people will of course Be
Wondering like what is this taste and
smell like what's a THC content you know
like what's the high yeah and and and
not not understanding that like they're
thinking of it from a very modern
mindset of what's this going to be like
in my room indoors and we just it's not
something you can really tell them you
know how this plant that grows outdoors
in in this Expresses in this environment
now it's going to be indoors in your
environment where it's never been you
know so yeah please talk about some of
your your more recent accessions and and
what people can expect
sure so yeah like uh like you said we
don't really we don't really put you
know like expected yields or you know we
do we do go into terpene profiles a
little bit but you know not massively
and certainly not THC percentages or
anything exactly I'd like to know that
you know we've found some accessions in
Cambodia which have very few trichome
heads on them however they absolutely
laugh and so I'm just gonna go ahead and
go on a limb and say that maybe there's
even some other kind of annoy to play
there
um and so you know measuring you know
that strange quality or that accessions
quality based on its THC percentage just
seems like an absurdity yeah um there's
so many missing cannabinoids out there
like that we that aren't tested for we
have no clue what is causing some of
these highs right right so for as far as
the most recent exceptions we were in
Parvati Valley which um is you know one
of the the true hot spots of land races
in the world in in India
um it's maybe not as much of a priority
as far as conservation goes the farmers
there are pretty pretty well off and
doing pretty well in fact they don't
really need our help in the same way
that farmers in Southeast Asia do but
it's important to us because Parvati is
one of the most visible one of the most
famous of the growing regions in in the
whole world and so you know without
having you know a few pictures and some
accessions from Milana it's really hard
to have that clout as a you know a land
race Collective you know is that where
Milana is in Parvati Valley or is it
called it is yeah yeah it is so is in
the state of Himachal Pradesh which
basically means like the you know the
the Himachal Province and machale is
like a Heavenly Mountain I believe in
and it's the it's you know the the place
outside of Kathmandu so basically a lot
of um
Parvati Valley is in is in Himachal
Pradesh which is in the north of India
near the near the border with with China
and not so far away from Pakistan
kashmirs in between it's in the the
northwest of the of the country
and it's basically a hub for cannabis
growing since the since the 1960s as one
of the sort of the tail ends uh of the
of the hippie Trail you know other than
do in Nepal and starting I'm not exactly
sure when but you know I would say maybe
late 70s early 80s a lot of Italians I'm
coming to Parvati
um La Paz and Malana villages in
particular and
um and getting involved with Charis
production there and so it's had a big
International reputation
um and in Europe
um avati hash is not necessarily the
most common
but in a lot of places in Italy um in
the Scandinavian countries is one of the
prestige
um hash that is is available on offer
and so for us it it's it seems like you
know a very a priority let's say
basically because you know when
foreigners are learning and educating
themselves about land races one of the
first places that they learn about is
generally
you know Tosh this kind of thing and so
yeah we we felt like in order to bring
attention to smaller villages in other
parts of India and in other countries in
Thailand
um that it was in the best interest of
approaching and working with the farmers
there and so but the farmers there
they're not the
conservation is needed everywhere but
Milana and liminal but Parvati Valley as
a whole is sort of one of the more
stable
um one of the larger land race producing
regions the people there are holding on
to their Traditions pretty hard
and so it's not necessarily an area
where we can engage in necessarily the
the same type of conservation work that
we can in tribal regions in the
northeast of India or elsewhere
um but it's somewhere where we you know
could Source some very high quality
seeds from very very famous gardens
maybe you know do our part in helping to
build up the body of knowledge for what
could eventually be an appellation
system in the region
um and you know that that in particular
is something with it on a personal level
I'd love to to see happen and you know
it'd be a privilege to be involved in
anything even remote to that
um I think Parvati is one of the the
Grand Cru so to speak of the the
Cannabis world there's a lot of it's a
storied place with a big diversity of in
French we call them reliodi and Klima
they refer to the smallest Geographic
designation basically individual plots
sometimes having multiple within one
Vineyard and so you know in Parvati we
see a similar system with very small
individual plots making up a
constellation that forms a larger sort
of system that spread throughout the
whole valley and so that provides us
with a lot of different Expressions
um you know of that gene pool from the
various sort of terroir of the area
whether they be the the dark side of the
valley with a lot of humidity a lot of
rain or you know the the best most sunny
spots at High Altitude above Milano
Village right and everything in between
and so in total we made 74 accessions
um which I
I maybe it's I don't need to but I just
want to point out like how much tracking
was involved
you know Gardens that are uh you know
between let's say 2 100 to 3
4 000 meters basically at the highest so
um between well like six thousand to to
almost 12 000 feet
um and a lot of The Villages for example
uh Tosh
um maybe I don't actually know the exact
outside
um the result is 2600 or so
um and the provide Ram Fields above it
are hitting 3 000 right and so yeah you
need to get up to Russell and then up to
the fields Beyond so similarly to in
Southeast Asia we're next to the rice
fields there's these little Huts where
they dry out
um a lot of the products and where they
rest
during the hot parts of the day there's
rubbing houses in a lot of the higher
fields in Parvati and so a lot of the
time we were hanging out with the boys
there and asking them you know like you
know what's the name of this Garden
what's the name of that Garden you know
can you make sure you separate plants
from those two next time you rub we'll
we'll give you more money yeah honestly
they do
they think they're like why would the
Foreigner pay more
for knowing that it comes from one
garden and not the other remember let's
put some [__] stamps on the Charis
and uh yeah right that's very Western
mentality and
um I think but I think it's it's
rewarding and it helps it helps the
farmers differentiate their product
without having any change on the product
itself and you know it helps us again to
to bring a better clearer picture of
what is going on in the gene pool in
that area and to represent that visually
a text and with our seats
I'm really excited about that um you
were telling a story yesterday about
hand rubbing that I thought was
fascinating and like the one thing that
like
as as a person you might have a few ocds
um like the idea of hand rubbing like to
me is is skin cells and stuff like that
like that drives me nuts but I
understand the tradition and the quality
that goes along with this and you had an
interesting story about like how bad it
can screw up your hands
um can you tell me a little bit about
that so people can understand what goes
into this yeah
um I'm actually what I didn't mean to
emphasize that honestly like the I think
the eyelashes are more of a concern than
this really yeah yeah because you like
you'll never even really see the skin
cell you'll just notice that your hands
feel a bit papery and thin right and
then you know if you let them dry out
afterwards they'll get all ragged but
yeah you'll often notice little
eyelashes because they're always hunched
over when they're oh yeah yeah or when
they're rubbing so
um basically you know everybody all the
foreigners they come up to Parvati for
the first time and they have it in their
head that they're gonna you know run
naked through the field of weed maybe
yeah something like that right yeah
[Music]
and then I also want to say before I
before we say anything else you know
because a lot of these conversations in
the past have led to people going to
where we've talked about on the back of
me explaining where the grows are if you
go to Milano Valley and you touch any
plants expect to pay about a 500 fine
for every plant that you touch every
time you touch one they are not so keen
on foreigners coming in and but in other
places in the job you can yeah probably
run naked through the fields as you
imagine you could it could and um you
know the the first thing is like okay
well I'm not gonna buy hash while I'm
here because I'm a cannabis nerd and I
know how it's made so I'm gonna rub it
myself yeah early and you go up and you
rub and you rub and you'll notice that
unless you're doing this regularly it
takes a big toll on your hands the
terpenes are somewhat caustic and you're
applying a lot of pressure onto your
palms and specifically when you're
collecting the matter at the end you're
pressing your thumb not only is it
pretty bad on your our joints pretty
quickly but you'll notice blisters on
your thumb if your Technique isn't on
point
um so I think that yeah for people who
have these kind of like uh you know
whether it's OCD or just you know being
concerned about hygiene which is
reasonable you know I get yeah yeah
I can't even see the skin cells but like
even when I when I'm like doing that at
home like going through picking seeds
and I've got like caked caked or resin
on my hands I'm thinking but if I smoke
this
it's not really going to be perfect you
know but yeah also also
knowing about melodic cream that is like
in my mind like supposed to be what the
ultimate hash what I understand melonic
cream so that's like there's no way any
skin cell would make me pass up some
melanocrine to try you know the top
level cream will have very few skin
cells in it because the whole point of
cream is for it to be very delicately
rubbed yes um and so when you do rub it
delicately there's you know and also
we're talking about you know for for
someone with soft hands who doesn't rub
every year then yeah it's going to be
filled with skin that's a good point
whatever your calloused hand not so much
yeah yeah
um I will say though that during the
season you'll find the whole village is
empties and you know
in a way you could child exploitation or
whatever but I mean I mean it's not
really like they have such thing as
child care up in the hills either
exactly they'll leave the kids at home
yeah they come with and the whole family
rubs and you better believe that the dad
is gonna tell you later like yo this is
my 16 year old daughter who rubbed this
her hands are really soft you can pay
more for this you know oh I bet yeah you
do that they're always like no no this
is the youngest you know the this is my
wife or it's always the wife daughter
who's gets the highest prices that's
funny very typical though yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah
so is there like you mentioned Colombia
is there any other like pie in the sky
like ideas you want to pull off with
omia that you haven't yet
yeah
um we'd like to I mean
a lot of things we'd love to to get more
into the production uh and aging and
then selling of Thai stick and Charis
um those are what we're passionate about
traditional compression curing and
traditional hand rubbing you know the
the artisanal craft which don't involve
the mediation of many tools or Machinery
in the elaboration of traditional
cannabis products that's always going to
be something that we want to get
involved in so I just maybe if you'll
allow me want to go back a little bit to
Milana
um oh man
yeah no I think I think that there's a
bit more Nuance that needs to be
explained here sure
the cream the Charis is rubbed from
domesticate plants
um which over the course of the last 25
years in particular every single farmer
who has been around long enough to see
it talks about a decline in THC levels
and in in tricome density and so it went
from being a lesser amount of plants
needed to rub 10 grams to a much higher
amount of time
um 10 grams and so
my personal experiences in India were
not in Parvati Valley actually the first
ones
um they were in mostly in kinar in spiti
um in the more remote regions of
Himachal Pradesh where there's much less
of a tourist drug trade and much more of
a local traditional consumption and
there the Charis is referred to as
jungli jungli being the word which gave
us the word in English for Jungle it
means forest in Hindi and his Forest
hash in that regards can be thought of
as hash rubbed from feral plants yes now
the hash rub from feral plants in my
opinion that is the Pinnacle of the
world of Charis because not only have
the domesticate plants been losing
um I can't really explain much more
about why but the the the testimony of
the farmers that they're losing
um THC content over time
um whereas the feral plants are becoming
irrelevant with very few people outside
side of like for example in Kulu which
is at the bottom of the valley
um it's a much bigger city it's outside
of property you'll find drug addicts
like you know going and rubbing
handsworth from the feral plants on you
know Dusty ice plants on the side of the
road that happens but more and more in
the main sort of producing Villages like
rasal Malana there are far less feral
plants now than there were before
because the feral plants are often the
first to be targeted in in eradication
campaigns you know the cops will come
and put a little bit of pressure and the
cops themselves probably won't be
clearing the fields but they'll be
telling the villagers
and they'll clear the federal plants
below the village that are in plain view
of the path yeah what's up which you
know and that doesn't satisfy the Cubs
then maybe they'll cut down a few
domestic Fields so I think that really
the sort of the Pinnacle the Holy Grail
whatever you want to call it is the the
jungli is the and not all jungle is
equal it needs to be
who can rub very well and can rub a good
quality cream slowly without much
contaminant but if he rubs from feral
plants you can expect a bigger diversity
of cannabinoids and terpenes which you
know when consumed fresh or aged leads
to much more pronounced and distinct
experience and I think that's where the
magic of of Parvati and Charis in
general is is is live resin made from
you know live plants
um funnily enough all the all the Gora
you know all the foreigners they're
pretty excited about consuming it fresh
because that's when it's really terpy
but also quite caustic on the throat all
local swear by smoking it after a year
when it's lost a lot of its taste but
it's much smoother and provides a more
competitive narcotic kind of effect
that's really interesting
uh I think so too man I love going out
there and trying all this stuff you know
the locals are like yo like because it's
they don't have some they produce a lot
but they don't produce a lot of the best
grades you normally need to commission
that so if you wanted say a few kilos of
super cream or something you'd need to
come in advance and say I want you to
make and you need to trust and stuff and
so when you're sort of going there on
the spot and asking them give me your
best stuff they're kind of like don't
smoke it too quick and I'm like here I'm
on a mission try everything
as fast as possible so you better
believe you know yeah dude
yeah man I you know usually my I have my
co-host NASA with me and right now I
would be making a joke about sending him
over to suitcase some a lot of cream and
bring it back you know what I mean the
the old traditional suitcase if you get
my drift yeah
come on yeah human wallet
I remember back in uh I was in Denmark
for a little brief period of time
I'm at a Danish chick and they're pretty
famous for bringing bringing the dudes
back to Denmark and anyway
they got this little hippie commune
there that sort of or anarchists call me
in the
um let's change a lot but basically
there's kind of this Marketplace and
it's all it's changed a lot a lot a lot
so but back in the day I remember there
was always
um ass hash or briefcase hash uh well
like eggs or super flat or big bricks of
kashmiri that came God knows
but you know it was always like the the
briefcase hash yeah man that was yeah
yeah how often did you choose the ass
hash
honestly I don't like it you know like
you know what like uh there's a study
with Madrid where they found that like
every sample of uh of hash that they
they found was contaminated with fecal
matter oh wow do you ever heard of that
yeah yeah brutal look I think you know
I'm not that's definitely not something
I'm looking to consume yeah
but you know in order to maybe sort of
contextualize this and
um everything else that might seem a
little bit odd about hygiene that we're
talking about
um I I think I'd like to sort of
um explain a little bit about how
um you know an analogy in winemaking
would maybe be the most uh illustrative
um and it's that when you have an Old
Winery with you know very porous walls
from an old traditional building you
know one that wasn't built you know up
to code or according to what some
bureaucrats wanted just traditional
building you know people knocked it up
because they needed it
um those walls will accumulate yeast and
all these things over long long periods
of time but when you're talking about a
country which has you know heavy
bureaucracy especially when it comes to
things like food products you know the
US does not allow like I mean maybe this
has changed but I remember like it was a
big deal that if you guys didn't allow
like raw cow's milk cheese which is like
the best cheese yeah
live you know lactic bacteria culture
leads to much more complexity of taste
and flavor
but there are a huge big hygiene you
know concerns in the U.S which
confuses me because I also get told on
the other side that standards are lacks
compared to the EU and so I think
without being a chauvinist or without
trying to
um I'd like to I don't know I guess
praise the the the the Europeans for
having that sort of uh ability to be
very hygienic when they think that it
matters yeah during the harvesting of
the grapes and everything else but
allowing certain contaminants during
other parts of the process because
they're either a part of the traditional
method or they have some sort of an
impact on the taste or something sure
yeah in that regards I I kind of place
the skin cells in that regards if you're
a Craft Beer Drinker you'll probably
seen the Brett beer that's came about in
the last sort of
10 years or so and you know we describe
it as like barnyard
Aromas and smells right and taste we
find it very typically in well it's
caused by bacterial infection which you
can get rid of through proper hygiene
yeah I find it a lot in French wines and
you know Americans you know they they're
pasting panels when the supermarkets are
going to buy like onto the side of
leaders and stuff and they're like no
hell no and it took you know decades and
for the craft beer and hipsters to come
out and be like no these bacterias are
actually okay and we're gonna
incorporate them you know voluntarily
into the beer and then that's still
changing the mind but there is a big
difference sort of
um there's a big difference in
um the the way the traditional lot
driven products are conceived of and the
requirements you know a lot of people
um where I come from might say that if
you
create a formula and you sanitize
everything then it can't express the the
soil and the culture and the life you
know yeah so so bear that in mind if you
feel a little bit disgusted by finger
hash yeah yeah you know it's it's one of
those things where it's like hey I can't
see it but in my in the back of my mind
it's always there you know
someone's proteins yeah you know I will
I'll tell you what what you really
should worry about and this is this is a
significant concern actually is is
adulterance
um adulterance
um caused by the I mean the size of the
of the fields in place like Parvati or
in uttarakhand they've increased
passively you know 10-fold 100 fold or
in you know different places over the
course of the last few decades and they
still can't quite meet um demand and so
you know there's always sort of a lack
of product and for example in Parvati
the backstop is made up by Nepalese who
themselves make up the the laboring
class in Himachal Pradesh and they also
often rub hash on contract for himachali
landowners and if they can't meet their
quotas they'll incorporate a little bit
of Nepali hash into into the Milan at
the bulk it out so they can get a better
price per gram from their landlord
um and then down in the in the valley
it's definitely being contaminated or
adulterated with all sorts of things
like dupe like incense sticks henna
um just mud
random crap
um just in order to to you know bulk it
up and I mean I don't know explain why
they do everybody knows why they do it
yeah but the other thing when you're
getting only the top quality and you
know it's not adult rated well then you
need to make sure you know you're
probably going to want to rub it
yourself if you're worried about hygiene
is that they do stuff like when they're
first starting they'll rub their
eyebrows in order to get some oil on
their fingers and that will provide the
the first
um you know because what you're trying
to do is you're trying to lift the
trichomes off of the off of the plant
yeah so
in they need you need good weather
conditions and you need your hands to be
the basically the perfect humidity and
smooth if they're too dry or something
it's not a real problem if your hands do
need to be conditioned somehow the
easiest way is to spit on them or to rub
your hair to rub behind your ears to rub
your eyebrows and they do that and the
most oil that part of your face yeah
yeah yeah they got the same and so yeah
honestly I probably shouldn't be saying
the stuff on
but it's the truth you know it's part of
the culture and how exactly and frankly
when you're combusting it
yeah you're burning the [__] out of it
right but but I understand the icky part
of it yeah I mean yeah it's it's just
one of those things as an OCD person
like that it just yeah but I I can get
over it pretty easily when it comes to
weed or I mean I just think back to the
[__] that was in like
hard drugs that I did and it's like it's
finger like worrying about skin compared
to some of the cut that was in hard
drugs like it just it seems uh silly but
yeah there we are
so a lot of people that are going to be
going to your site after watching the
show which is um zumia cannabisco.com
so we do start by consensus and the
consensus was a an unwieldy and
cumbersome website name and
advantages of being uh you know a
collective led by consensus but yeah
cannabisco.com so one of the first
questions that people are going to be
asking and I know and you're probably
going to get 100 emails about this after
so I figured maybe let's just try to
curb some of the emails what's what's
one of the lines you would recommend for
a California indoor garden from your
indoor garden indoor light Garden from
your uh selections and exceptions
so I think that there's like um it's
kind of like the Chinese restaurants in
the UK or the US you know people feel
more comfortable with kind of like an
intermediary or familiarity of some sort
yeah Fleet in diversion perhaps a little
bit less feisty and so in that regards I
think some of the land race ibls can be
quite appropriate for Growers who lack
the confidence to approach you know a
long flowering varietal in that regards
the the the classic sort of uh lowland
Thai stick accession from us would be
the Dai Deng which is the
transliteration for Red Thread
um that's the the legendary Red Thread
Thai sticks from from Eastern from back
in the day we're working with a clan
from Macomb who you know have been
working with old seed stock reproducing
in a in a pretty large population now
since quite a few years before
legalization
um yeah and so that would be a little
bit you know shorter flowering
um a little bit you know more it's still
going to have a lot of vigor but it's
going to be a bit more uniform in its
canopy and its growth patterns and so as
far as the the sort of the very
equatorial lines I think that would be a
really approachable line for beginners
saying that the picture I think that's
on the background here of the of the
post of the issue and that's a scar
Karen genetics from the King kachan
National Park area on the border with
Myanmar in Thailand yeah I can see it's
huge plant grows really vigorously you
know it's resistant to everything you
don't need to walk too much don't need
to feed it much it just grows like hell
and so if space isn't your concern you
know then you know you can consider
going for something like that
um but ultimately if you're working with
really stretchy long flowering varietals
like this there are quite a few tricks
that you can take
um to both shorten the flowering and to
manage the canopy more evenly maybe we
can get a little bit yeah please do
people are going to be wanting those
jobs
well so I would say that if you have the
ability if you're not a commercial
grower even if you are and you have the
ability to sacrifice a space for a cycle
in order to do final hunts I think
that's the way to do it
um the idea of you know stabilizing
Pinos and also you're going to be
dealing with the intersex traits that
are common in the Landry's Gene pools of
Asia yeah and so you know breeding with
those can be a bit of a challenge
however doing Mass selections you know
hunts based on big amounts then putting
your your cuttings from select mothers
directly into flower in small pots with
a high planting density you can turn
pretty pretty fast cycles and you can
get really good yields and so I would
say if you have the ability to do so
please attempt to follow this uh this
path as it's probably the most
commercially viable otherwise
um the Indian Land races from the
Himalayas they're going to be somewhat
shorter than the ties
um the difference would be 24 to 20
weeks or 20 to six weeks not huge but
still if you're if you're somebody who
struggles to maintain the plant's health
during long flowering periods then maybe
you're looking you know to shorten that
down a little bit you'll find that in
the in the cultivars from higher
altitude and from more northernly
locations in general your your Thai
varietals your cambodians your laotians
are going to be
depending on you know you and your
growth we've seen seven meter plants in
the village in sagang and Myanmar so
that's that's your upper limit
um
so generally speaking LST a lot of
pruning a lot of cutting back topping
Etc I think the techniques that can
benefit you
um if you have the ability to let the
plants grow without any sort of topping
they do respond better to this yeah
these plants are not used to being
individually cuddled their land race
plants coming from huge Fields the
farmers do not pay attention to single
plants yeah
fields are too far away too high up too
remote Etc and so
um you know they a lot of them will
never ever have been talked before you
know and we've seen that given the
intersex traits being a little bit of an
issue for some people
if you have the ability to to not stress
them out then you know don't stress them
out
um but at the same time you know we
we're saying that in order to earn on
the side of caution yeah my personal
experience has been incredibly resistant
hearty vigorous tolerant plants that
basically take whatever you throw at
them and I find it funny to contrast
that with the image that a lot of people
have as these really sort of finicky and
difficult to grow plants like no not at
all the opposite they're difficult to
make them stop growing like you're
you're trying to you're trying to manage
them and that's that's that's a whole
different new different set of problems
basically I think a lot of that is for
people trying to bring in stuff that's
been acclimated to Thailand Outdoors to
indoors and they just don't get it like
they're trying to feed it you know GH
nutrients like just
stuffing it full of nutrients and stuff
and that's not what a lot of these land
races want they don't they don't respond
well to that of course it'll make them
finicky yeah yeah you know I think one
place where the Cannabis industry is
really far behind in regards to
um in regards to the wine industry or
other teeth is in terms of understanding
soil compositions and minerals Etc
um the you know clearly fertile loamy
soils lots of water that is strong
vegetative growth that is not what we're
seeking to necessarily do especially
with plants that have such a long
flowering period and we're trying to
reduce the overall cycle
um in the wine industry for example we
apply such techniques as partial root
dehydration which would be which will
serve to stress the plant in very
tactical ways in order to induce
specific physiological changes that we
want to see in the plant's phytochemical
makeup right yeah chemical makeup
um and so as far as that goes with these
land races you'll find that they're not
growing in sort of like these beautiful
pristine soils like you know like we're
talking about like if we're in Cambodia
a lot of the time this is going to be
maybe a bit sad to hear these days
um The Growers are no longer next to the
Mekong floodplain areas they're they're
in freshly deforested rainforest which
is often been deforested for Timber or
sometimes specifically for growing
cannabis and so in that regards the
jungle soils are often very very poor
in Parvati Valley we see totally
degraded soils from overuse of urea
and very very very acidic soils on the
bottom of slopes where everything's sort
of draining down and accumulating and
the plants are still thriving
um relatively um yeah we've got
different criteria here too when you're
growing 25 acres on a hillside it
doesn't really matter if you have one or
two plants that are a little bit raggedy
looking
um
no one's ever going to see the flower
it's going to get robbed anyway so yeah
it's a little bit of a different
concerns in that regard
that makes sense
um yeah the way we treat plants in the
U.S compared to these big massive Fields
is night and day different uh we're just
modeling them it's cute you know yeah
all right
taking care of your babies and for
people that are worried about intersex
traits and stuff just remember like
anything if you're watching this
anything
intersex like any other trait in
cannabis whether it's purple whether
it's a scent it can be bred out or bred
in you know I mean this is something
that can be selected for or selected
again so you're a little scared of
things like that it's it's very easy to
work out yeah well yes yeah
[Music]
I drew are patterns of cultivation
um including periods of time where many
males are being called before reverting
to Total open pollination for a few
decades for example
um that'll be enough to bring out
interest X traits in your population
sure
um and if you're talking about you know
hypothetical land race which has been
growing on a hillside or maybe that's a
bad example on a flood plain for a long
time there will be maybe a little
portion of the field that's
raised above the water the water level
and so you know every again this is
totally hypothetical scenario I'm just
making up sure here every you know maybe
60 years you've got some catastrophic
plots and once every cycle of floods
they happen to kill all the males yeah
literally every single one if the plant
or the population did not have the
intersex trades within it then that
population would just disappear
um with the flood correct and so it's a
survival mechanism that's found in large
cannabis populations and so it just goes
hand in hand with land races but
especially with land races that have
gone through periods of intense
cultivation
um or which are being grown according to
the the modern sort of reading practices
of separating males and
it makes sense that's some good context
to add to it
so is there any other strains you want
to talk about or get into
um before we wrap it up like because I
want I want to be able to point people
to some specific stuff they could check
out on your site is there something
other than what we've mentioned sure
well we talked about the sort of the
easier to approach ones
um which again I don't think that
there's you know maybe necessarily a
huge difference in the in the skill
curve acquired sure but I will say that
kronkravio
um cronkravia is the reputed to be you
know the most potent the strongest of
all the the land race has grown in in
territory of Thailand
um and it's it's a wonderful it's a
wonderful kind of a succession
um we we see phenotypes that are really
really resonance with a sort of
fermented sticky Sweet Lemon character
which I very personally fond of it
reminds me of my experiences with
um cannabis from Amsterdam in the late
90s with amnesia hazes which have this
sort of it incense incensey kind of
lemon character the best friend kravia
expresses itself along those lines and
it's very very potent it grows with a
pretty unique uh bud structure which I
think will take a lot of You by surprise
um it's it might if you look at it if
you look at it from far away it looks
like a totally normal Canada flag you
look at it close up looks a little bit
more like a mutant the the butt
structure very loose and open and that
allows for the UVS to penetrate you know
deep inside and so it
it's
it's rare to find sedative narcotic
cannabis due in in Southeast Asia due to
the long growing period
where the trichomes are taking a long
time to ripen but we found it on the
cronkravia there's there's you know such
penetration all the way in that we're
seeing quite a high amount of photo
oxidation and so if you cut it at the
right time it's got this clear bright
racy cerebral high but if you let it go
all the way which can be as long as 28
weeks you'll definitely see a lot of
really dark colored trichomes in a much
more narcotic sedative effect and
personally I've really enjoyed both
expressions of the of the krunkravia in
that regards otherwise the Thai mango is
like you know everybody loves mango it's
such a Delicious Fruit
um and you know the mango expressions in
in Asia whether that's you know mysuru
or high or Cambodian mango or whatever
else they range from the sort of the
green mentholated camphor mango blue to
the or ripe red juicy mangoes and people
price different things generally if it's
called mamuwan which is mango and Thai
it's going more for the ripe mango
Spectrum as the green light blue is
something that's more commonly found
across the board in Southeast Asia in
we've seen a lot basically
it's a red mango that sort of really
valued and prized as far as that goes
um lowland areas where mango
traditionally was grown and selected are
pretty much overrun and so we our
accessions in the north of the country
around Chiang Mai with some smaller
Growers doing open pollinations in in
the sticks um like 80 to 100 150
kilometers outside the city and one of
them one of the groups is a Hmong group
in DOI in tanon the tallest Mount Chiang
Mai and not only is it one of the most
stunningly beautiful places that if you
just if you could picture yourself
smoking weed from that place in that
place it's really just have an honor
but the Thai mango from this
due to the altitude in the cold
temperatures which is not that cold in
Thailand but in 2000 meters two thousand
feet gets a bit nippy comes across
really purple and so we we used to back
in the day sell that as the the Thai
purple mango and selling out like that
every single time so we actually just
took the purple about the name because
we wanted people to try other stuff you
know yeah but yeah you you probably
should check out the time angle if uh if
that's your thing if you like purple
colors otherwise we made some selections
from Individual black plants in Parvati
Valley namely in nirang
um also in Tosh I think Tash is really
the two to look out for the shoran and
[__] Fields they're really high altitude
Fields above the Tosh kutla and you know
there we we saw maybe like one plant in
10 showing any coloration one plant 100
showing significant and then one in a
thousand being like pure black or dark
maroon red kind of purple and so those
plants we made selections from and we
separated those out so if you're looking
to Fino hunt
um you know those are going to provide
you you know a slightly better chance
than the general population
um which is which which one specifically
is that
um well maybe I'll just explain to you
how we split up so we got the general
populations which are from you know
we've asked the farmers to basically
basically mix all this that's actually
what they do by standard they rub plants
from all the fields and they sit in
their house and a little pile of seed
accumulates below them and we ask them
just to sort through it to clean it out
Etc sure the selections is either us or
like members of our team or the Farmers
making selections so it's like a village
selection then that that's just when
we've gone there for two three days for
example
um we're going and looking for all the
best plants that we can
um and putting the side the seeds aside
for those apart from the general
population and then there's the single
plant selections which you'll see or
sorry the the Leo D we need to figure
out an English word for this I don't
know what it should be man but in French
it's Beauty it's like the climate it's
like the plot the plot is such a clumsy
word it's not very romantic you know
yeah right so I don't know we need to
come up with the word for that but yeah
so the the plot selections are obviously
selections made from Individual plots
um you know as I said before we're
encouraging the farmers to rub from
Individual fields and to tell their
customers the name of the fields that
they're rubbing from as a way to
increase the value of the product
um and so we're making selections from
those two and then the individual plants
and so for example it'll be like um the
Tosh goodla which is the name of the
village and then shorang the name of the
of the of the garden and then the black
selection and so you know that's your
your single plant selection from from
the guy
that's awesome to make all of them
available so people actually have a
choice you know
well well well well well well
subscribers and patreons get first dibs
so let's talk about this real quick um
because I didn't even know this was a
thing and I'm gonna join myself I went
and bought seeds from you before we ever
spoke because I was so stoked about this
and like the purchases from the site go
to the farmers which is super important
to me and and Noble as can be and and I
commend you for it
um but the patreon thing I want to join
so let's talk about some of that
so yeah well basically the we talked a
lot about incentivizing the communities
the way to do that is to you know as we
said to sell their seats and to get them
paid for it and so yeah
um you know given that a lot of what we
do is touching on social issues ones
that you know deal a lot heavily with
with class with race with with
colonialism Etc
um and given that there was a need for
for me as a foreigner and for a couple
of other foreigners to do administrative
slash communication roles
um we felt that it wasn't right to you
know take us take a cut out of the seed
sales and so instead what we set up was
um a patreon program and a subscription
program on the website and you know
during the course of our work
um we you know myself personally when
I'm traveling all you know for example
if I'm accessing the general population
I'm going to go go see some go see the
village and go pick up a restock on on
the general Pub a few others there's
going to be like maybe along the way
some Uncle who's like yo
here and there and that stuff that we
can't it's not we because we're not in
the business of doing reproductions
right like yeah yeah we don't get seeds
from the hill tribes or whatever and
then grow them out in Bangkok no no it's
directly so we almost you know I mean I
have my own grow but I have so many
things because we're like okay so we're
gonna get these these small quantities
the rarest stuff and that's gonna be for
for the Nerds you know for the people
who are really passionate and who want
basically you know hand selected
um seeds from from people who are
currently and actively sourcing in the
traditional growing regions you know
hand selected point of origin seeds and
so yeah that allows us to to draw an
income which allows us to do the
recruiting work to bring new you know
groups or communities into the
collective
um and so it's it's working with a lot
of synergy
um
yeah maybe we're not the best at keeping
all the social media up to date which is
probably why a lot of you guys might not
have heard of us until now
um but we definitely you know we we hold
it down with the seeds and you know I
feel like everybody involved is
satisfied with the amount of genetics
that we're that they're getting from us
we're we're doing our best to stand by
our people you know ultimately doing
solid by the traditional indigenous land
race Community growing communities in
some ways
um takes bread out of people's mouth in
the west
um and so we you know we want to be sort
of as as as honest and as helpful
um with people in the west you know to
give them you know as much of a room at
the table as as we can you know because
at the end of the day
we see this as as a
a way to form new connections and new
Bridges between the communities in
different countries you know we're so
disconnected right now
um and with integration I think we would
all benefit right yeah I I would think
so I mean that's what this is all about
in the end for for us and it's why we
started The Syndicate and yeah I mean
it's you guys are doing your thing on
the other side and hopefully you know we
were talking even uh more recently about
um The Strain database we're building
and stuff so hopefully even we can
continue to collaborate on stuff like
that like I've asked you to help with
the uh land race portion of our strain
database that we're building that I'm
really super stoked about to have
something accurate and uh yeah there's
all kinds of fun collaborations that we
can do and reach out and some of it to
some people seems like pie in the sky
stuff but I think we can accomplish a
lot I agree it's time for for a little
bit of time to come out of the Shadows a
little bit
um you know particular countries like
Indonesia with a rich tradition of
cannabis are very very very oppressive
and so it's not for lack of want you
know we you know people have always
wanted to reform these legs and
collaborate but now the time feels right
and you know and so if if we can you
know help some someone make a name for
themselves by breeding the next kind of
this Cup winner
um from Fino hunting some land race gene
pool they access through us you know
that would make us happier than anything
we really we want to lift people up on
in everywhere we can yeah
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out
breeders Syndicate update not only is
our merch store up at syndicategear.com
but all episodes will remain free but
what we need from you is interaction if
you're watching the show for your first
time kick back and enjoy it if you like
the show feel free to like it but if
it's your second viewing we ask a gentle
person's agreement that you click the
Subscribe button it costs you nothing
but it helps us tremendously with the
sneaky YouTube algorithm
leaving comments telling not to his
voice lulls you into a trance works as
well we hope you take the time to do
this we try to put out the best possible
shows for you we can and want to build
this community thanks again from all of
us at the Breeders Syndicate family