breeders Syndicate update not only is
our merch store up at syndicategear.com
but all episodes will remain free but
what we need from you is interaction if
you're watching the show for your first
time kick back and enjoy it if you like
the show feel free to like it but if
it's your second viewing we ask a gentle
person's agreement that you click the
Subscribe button it costs you nothing
but it helps us tremendously with the
sneaky YouTube algorithm
leaving comments telling not to his
voice lulls you into a trance works as
well we hope you take the time to do
this we try to put out the best possible
shows for you we can and want to build
this community thanks again from all of
us at the Breeders Syndicate family
[Music]
connected with everything around me
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
when it started to hit me
and I'm like wow
I got high
[Applause]
[Music]
love that music
so first we are going to talk about
um something that's been going on
in the market you've been paying close
attention to which is
what's going to happen
up to
and post legalization as it pertains to
other countries importing uh cannabis to
the United States
and we wanted to talk about some of that
I know a few years ago I started seeing
a lot of big graders start moving to
Colombia
that's when I first noticed it was about
two or three years ago there was a
almost a mass Exodus of some of the
Breeders going down to Colombia and a
lot of people are trying to import
American strains down to Colombia I know
Bridget Steve was one of them down there
too Charlie Garcia those guys went down
down to Columbia yeah most of funk told
me about Charlie in fact Charlie wrote
me too because he was so sad with all
the things that had happened at Ace that
he decided to just go somewhere noon
being Spanish he would fit down there so
well oh yeah and I'll bet he I bet he's
digging it in Colombia and I bet they're
digging him probably treating him like a
dignitary you know really yeah like
royalty I would I would assume he's been
around forever he's done a lot you know
and and that would be a huge fit down
there
and he knows a lot of people so that
when it comes time to Market
you know he knows how to do that is
Colombia I don't really understand the
Colombian Market as much but is Colombia
as controlled by cartels as say Mexico
is currently
I don't believe so I think the
government has stepped in by legalizing
and
they
they monitor everything they I'm sure
there's money being passed around to see
who gets what licenses because that one
article
said that there's only
there was how many I said that there's
only like 16 or six that were allowed to
produce seeds yeah but there was a lot
of
um licenses for Growers yeah 60 or 70.
so only 10 percent roughly
were allowed to uh produce seeds so
they'll be producing their own down
there and with someone like Charlie or
breeder Steve they'll get the right
genetics design you know they'll yeah
and I'm sure that that Charlie's
searching in the
back jungles and Corners to find it's
close to land races as you can oh I'm
sure I mean he's he'd be one of those
ideal people for Colombia I think
because he understands
um different types of of uh
not just not just strains but types of
strains how they grow in certain
provinces and certain certain elevations
so I think you'd be excellent for that
like like finding a strain and he
understands breeding he understands
working a line acclimating it so I yeah
he's a great person to be down there
doing it I'm kind of shocked that
there's so few people allowed to produce
seeds I don't know that the U.S market
has a cap on the number of seed
producers uh licenses and stuff
I think it's kind of late if if there is
going to be yeah I mean yeah yeah
there's tens of thousands yeah there's
so much so could they be so brilliant
that they're realizing that the future
for their seeds would be if they're
certain lines like Chiba or
Santa Marta gold and they can regulate
and make sure that the six readers of
seeds really have that so that when they
sell them
um it could be
Thailand's done something similar kind
of as I understand it's something
similar with their Heritage strains with
like the silk squirrel tail the Tiger
Tail snake teeth there's a few other
kinds from Thailand they consider like
Heritage strains however they put a lady
in charge of it named I don't want to
say her name a lady in charge of all
this stuff and
um it seems that she doesn't even
understand that most of the ties that
were sold during that era were laotians
so she she's putting out like this big
thing where like almost reparations that
American farmers owe Thai people money
for growing Thai strains and using them
over the years when in fact they're
probably lay ocean strains so her
bringing this forward will kind of
probably point out that most high
strains or laotians and that probably
the Thai is oh reparations to lay oceans
if she keeps pushing it that direction
because she she just doesn't understand
the culture she doesn't understand the
history of the strains but she's in
charge of it and I think it's it's
disappointing because I feel like that
happens a lot in corporate Canon America
uh obviously in Thailand is is that you
have corporate money coming in and
corporate money
choosing who is to head The Who
spearhead these
these campaigns and most of the time the
people with the money and incorporations
do not have access to the people who
have the knowledge or have been keeping
this clandestine stuff you know uh
keeping track of it the archivists they
just don't have access to these people
or even know so
they wait to be approached by these
people who tell them I am that person
and it almost I almost feel like they do
they have no way to check do checks and
balances on if this person's full of it
or not and it's almost like a to me it
feels random on who they choose like uh
you're gonna be the lady you know like
you're going to be the guy to represent
it and um I know a lot of Thai people or
people in Thailand right now
um that are super interested in land
races and preservation are a little
upset about that because I mean now
she's representing certain strains as
their Heritage strains that may not even
be they could be you know Dutch hybrids
of stuff and they will always be pushed
as their Heritage straight now because
she said so
hmm
yeah it's it's fascinating the politics
that go behind
all this stuff because you never really
realize how much it's going to affect
potential future written down history
so I found the article from April 12th
of 2019. so we're talking two years ago
and it says there's a hundred and twenty
six
um companies in Colombia at that time
that's two years ago but only six in
proceeds
oh wow yeah 126 had been cleared to grow
and have
huge but only 16 of those 126 were
qualified to produce
um cities since these companies are
allowed to register genetics in batches
of 10 at a time and the phytosanitary
tests will mandate them to cultivate a
test batch engage its properties before
it can go to the market or register the
genetics several well-known land race
strains will be featured
so they are going to try to do that um
that Heritage strain type thing that's
kind of cool
yeah Santa Marta go
um
Chiba
black hopefully hopefully they choose
someone like Charlie to spearhead that
that would be cool someone that actually
knows their their business or or not
must have Funk or someone cool you know
I know he's not there but it would be
nice to consult
I'm pretty sure they'll need testers
yeah that's for sure yeah
um
so what do we know about the what do we
know about the political climate in in
Colombia as far as so we talked about a
little bit about cartels in Mexico how
does this how do you think this
interplays with moving the product from
Colombia through Mexico because it's
going to have to pass through Mexico to
get to the US unless it's done on
airplanes right
um yeah I guess I guess I I don't know
why I would assume that they can't do it
on airplanes if it's legal though I'm
still in like that Outlaw mindset like
we gotta smuggle it the 747 pack yeah
UPS like the way UPS will pack
certain carrier planes you know they own
them and use them but that size sure and
then they'll be they'll be perfectly you
know protected you know they'll keep
them
oh I'm sure they may vac seal them I
don't think the glass bottle and like
some of the
Boutique companies in Northern
California but they'll definitely
they've learned their lessons over
decades so
and they may have some that they ferment
on purpose and help
bring about changes in the Smoke
qualities
it'll it's I don't know when it'll be
but once we're federally legal
I bet they'll have their lobbyists
already waiting and already had their
plans made they may even right now and
when it happens they'll Rush In And
there'll be all these companies in
America fighting saying we need to have
tariffs we need to have tariffs and stop
them coming in
um so it'll be interesting
Washington DC battle
you know it almost I mean it kind of
would be common sense that a lot of
these companies because we know a few
years ago that a lot of people moved
down there and started doing this that
they are I mean these what were once
cartels maybe or maybe what is backed by
clandestine money in Colombia and and
Mexico
um
they have way more money than a lot of
the the corporations and it is what I've
been trying to tell people like a lot of
the the people that are in the US right
now
um a lot of the major companies let's
it's uh for example schmungel schmoys
um something like that level of bigness
and they may not have enough money at
all to be able to compete with the
international market I mean that's just
a fact I mean we're not talking you know
the hundreds of millions of millions of
dollars that we have in America to
invest in some of these cannabis
companies you know we're talking like
billions and trillions of dollars being
invested and a lot of these people look
at these companies that were started by
actual Growers some into some cases
getting investments from uh you know
doctors lawyers chiropractors that money
is not going to hold any weight when
these guys come in it's they're going to
get crushed because there's no way it
did just by simple economics I mean
um
the way it works is you know if someone
has x amount of space and it's 10 times
the space that you have and they can
sell it for pennies on the dollar
compared to what you can afford to sell
it at
and they can afford to take a loss for
10 years there's no way to compete
that's just how all capitalist markets
work
um in a new in a new market where
I guess you could say this this is not a
new commodity but it's going to be
considered a commodity in a broader
sense for the for the world term that
people can uh invest in it's going to be
a commodity like pork bellies or
anything like that and and when those
come into play it dumps out any mom and
pop chance of being able to ever compete
again if I was in charge of a big
cannabis operation in the United States
I definitely have my representatives in
Colombia Thailand and tropical areas
right now which I wouldn't doubt
um if Spain has such a large presence
down there from the people like Charlie
that are the Growers then there's they
have friends who own stores and
companies in their countries there's
plenty of millionaires and there's quite
a few billionaires these days
um yeah why not you know it makes more
sense in South America I guess or Mexico
or maybe even Thailand for the cartels
that are doing other things illegally
you know pain and opium and then they
make billions of dollars and now they
can put it into something legal it's
like washing their money it's like it's
beautiful and wanting the money to
retirement so how do you think Mexico is
going to interplay
um in this whole transition I know you
know I mean Mexico is a bit behind
Colombia as far as uh how people are set
up there
um the politics are going to be much
different I I don't know how much
different I don't know the level of
political corruption in
um Colombia but I'd imagine it's
somewhere on in between Mexico and the
us as far as corruption and politics so
I I just wonder with
with the powers and the money that the
cartels have in Mexico
how they will
how they will be prepared to enter the
market because with all that land in
Mexico and as cheap as land is in Mexico
I mean it seems like that and the
climate or the determinant factors on
where a person can grow cannabis
essentially on where these Farms will
start popping up around the world
Gustavo Petro
is a former Guerrilla fighter and he is
now the president in Colombia and that
makes a big difference because he's
going to
he has a much different view much more
down to earth he's not like the high-end
Only Money person
being yeah
um it says he
is it an economist politician but he was
a former Guerrilla fighter and he's been
in prison since 2022. yeah Mexico has
too much corruption in Murder yeah
Columbia you need to kidnap capital of
the world but Mexico is far and above it
now
because
I don't know it's just so split into so
many factions when you had only four big
Godfathers and godmothers in Colombia or
five it was very organized but Mexico if
you look at all the cartels
yeah maps that show like 25 different
ones and they're they're trying to
combine and then others are fighting the
others I I think Mexico will lag far
behind
however it's so close to the United
States
that will have a spillover beneficial
effect for them just like think
automobiles everything was Ford and
Chevy and then suddenly Toyota and all
these other countries I mean German okay
Volkswagen was always here too and BMW I
guess but suddenly
when the Imports started flooding to the
United States they came in with some
great quality and stole away a lot of
the market and now they've been playing
catch-up for years for it in the Chevy
yeah
with electrifying it's going to be
interesting because Tesla kind of broke
the ground but now there's companies in
China that make electric cars that are
seven thousand dollars yeah it's gonna
be hard to compete with that even if we
tear fit 100 14
000 for an electric car just to use in
your neighborhood and around shopping
and stuff yeah those will sell like
crazy oh yeah yeah affordable affordable
electric yeah that'd be insane I mean
you know what's funny is uh you know I
collect a lot of different things that
I've talked about and in the over the
years I've watched the guitar Market
specifically
and the knockoffs that have come and how
fast the turnaround time is on Guitar
knockoffs now is literally it went from
probably five or six years from a model
being released to where you were able to
buy that model
um bootlegged in China pretty easily you
know for 300 to 400 as opposed to ten
thousand or fifteen thousand you know
really that much yeah oh yeah that much
of a difference
um because they're doing like they're
doing like Custom Shop like like artist
Edition versions like perfect replicas
that you can get and sell for 500 bucks
because they're doing it in Mass but
they're doing it so good
um and now they're down to they're down
to about two months two months after
each uh uh line is released for guitar
maker if it's a high selling line
they will have it knocked off in two
months now as opposed to six years
there's no turnaround time whatsoever
it's crazy and I'd imagine
um it's like that with a lot of stuff
China's able to reproduce and produce on
such a level and on such an affordable
level that we couldn't even begin to
understand over here six cents a gram
production price they're predicting in
Colombia
um I think we're going to see a replay
in the weed Market
Mexico could certainly compete in their
more tropical areas like Oaxaca and
Guerrero because people live in the
mountains and they they grow their own
beans and it's a much simpler life like
much of Colombia Colombia has some big
cities though and yeah a port on the
Caribbean and a port on the Atlantic so
they can ship right from the Atlantic
side right up to LA or San Diego or they
can ship right to Miami from
you know Buenaventura I think it is the
one that's by Santa Marta and it you
know
they could pick up a little Jamaican
along the way you know yeah right
because the Jamaican by the way son do
you do you ever see a country like China
entering the the Cannabis Market based
on culture and religious aspects
not for a while
I I don't know
Thailand and look at all of Southeast
Asia you know kalamantan and you know
the guys on the forums from Australia
certain people you know Wally duck and
bucket bong and a few a bunch of others
they've gotten strains from
and these are these are land races that
aren't polluted yet there aren't any
Dutch citizens well hippies they yeah
it's just more difficult of a society to
just go over there I know Rob Clark's
been there and so has Shanti Baba
because they're both big fishermen yeah
and they love to fish from the shore
type and Rob holds some records in New
Zealand the annual things there that
they have so now yeah World Records I
have photos I I
don't have his permission to pop them
this year yeah
If he if he'd let me there's some
amazing he sent me of him barely holding
a 50 kilogram fish in his arms oh my God
looks like Papa Hemingway he's got white
hair now and white
he's in his rubber clothes because he's
on the beach you know pulling these in
and he uh he loves it that's his thing
and apparently Shanti Baba
and he were thinking of maybe even
getting a little tiny Resort
in former Borneo calamenton yeah
who knows wow
yeah right over to some place where the
people running it were
long-time friends that'd be really cool
long time friends and Seed nerds like
stray nerds that you just sit there and
nerd I mean yeah it'd be amazing
wonderful I've never made a Time
that Americans can go to Colombia and
not get kidnapped or bothered because
from you know someone from Spain
speaking perfect Castilian Spanish you
know they're going to fit right in but
yeah Americans are still viewed I
believe in many of the countries like
south of us
every everyone's gonna
someone's gonna be willing to pay for
you if I agree yeah maybe it's only 10
grand and not 10 million like if you
were really special that
I don't know maybe it's only 400 you
know but that's that's months of of
someone's livelihood there and that's
enough for them you know what I mean
yeah
if I could get a special you know
endorsement says do not kidnap front
you know I was watching something the
other day on um it was a guy that went
to Pakistan and he was going there to go
up through the kunduz valley basically
he was going from like the kyber pass
over the conduce Valley and up through
Pakistan up through Nepal and everyone
that he met along the way were just the
most kind you know sweet people the the
cultures there are absolutely insanely
sweet and like most of them he'd be
saying like have you ever seen Taliban
out here they're like I've never seen a
Taliban this is Pakistan we don't have
Taliban maybe down in Peshawar you know
like in the big city but they're like
they've never been up here like so they
they one thing that they were impressing
in this video the whole time the
Pakistan people were impressing like
Americans are very welcome here we love
Americans we love people from other
cultures and in a lot of these places he
was going were um Greek Greek
um descendants from when Alexander the
Great passed through yeah that Dash
Trail area so a lot of these yeah the
Huns of Valley yeah or the Huns of
people yeah and and that's where this
guy was staying with a lot was with the
Huns of people and they just seemed so
nice and friendly just wonderful
wonderful culture
I have a little booklet I got in the
health food store in the
early 70s on the whole hunza story and
their diet they eat a lot of apricots
which has a lot of benefits and
they're they don't eat a lot of meat if
they do it's probably goat meat uh yeah
lots of yak yeah yeah
and hunza Valley until maybe 10 years
ago was very difficult to get to you had
to Trek for A's to get there now I know
there is a road that leads in there
however the people are probably still
just as friendly they called it like the
Garden of Eden like it was a paradise
hidden and these people lived in Perfect
Harmony and whatever they have
um different districts different little
Regional uh voting areas well not even
voting like people in charge that were
voted in by their their tribe because
they were such good people so it was
good good
yeah it it I know that um the dude who
went there it was mostly because of um
the whole Shangri-La story like he was
trying to figure out like where where
this was kind of considered or where it
was just going in that area and yeah I
if I remember correctly it was either
the Huns of people or
um somewhere close to there where they
were saying they're not Muslim so they
are looked at as second-hand citizens
not really quite
um
they're not given proper representation
in Parliament and Pakistan and stuff
like that because they're not a Muslim
culture and yeah I thought that was
absolutely fascinating that this little
tiny Bastion of like free people exist
in their own little area in Pakistan and
they're just so sweet they seem sweet
and I never been there but they seem
sweet
but I was thinking about the uh kogi
people who were all white and they live
in the Santa Martin mountains there's a
a beautiful
movie that came out maybe 20 years ago
and it's called Uh message to little
brother I think was the name of it I I
researched this the other day again and
it's about an hour and a half long
documentary and you can't go into the
kogi
highest Villages they they have them
blocked on these paths up into the Andes
you can get that far but they won't let
you be on that and wow they have the
right too because it's their land and
they they consider everyone else in the
world like us little brothers and they
were this was in
environmental movie showing how they
have noticed the snow is no longer on
top of Santa Marta there it's the
weather is changing and and it's because
of little brother not knowing what he's
doing and talking with nature and right
next door is Venezuela and there's parts
of Venezuela and then going to Guyana
that are un almost unexplored
and then right below that's the upper
end of the Amazon
which is also very little unexplored and
fortunately there's people helping the
tribes there maintain their lands and
hold back the
people who chop down the rainforest to
make the palm oil plantations
really
it's amazing
we live in interesting times that's for
sure I
I look forward to seeing Santa Marta
gold coming in original it would be so
cool or well how can some strength of
oaxacan that no one knew existed because
the people there were guarding it yeah
became legal and they were no longer
criminals they had friends who were in
the city who knew how to bring it and
yeah it'll happen
I I still think that there's a good shot
that we have these Colombian Golds and
oaxacans even in the in U.S seed
collections I'm sure you know even even
with Rob Clark and and um
and others like that you know uh Watson
I'm sure they have these old stuff I
mean Watson said a million times that he
has everything that he's ever touched
and see stored frozen forever so you
know I I hope that they do bring these
back out and grow them at point of
origin type places you know like grow
them go take it back to Columbia grow to
point of origin bring some of this
natural stuff back that that has been
wiped out
that'd be cool
one 1977 guerreran seed
that a friend found in his desk it's not
viable
and down the road with the advances in
PCR and DNA and RNA
it's very possible they'll be able to
deconstruct it just by breaking the seed
and taking the remnants of whatever's in
there and the genetic code yeah and
re-engineer it uh I don't know if this
is good I think it's because it's
possible you know it's GMO you know so
it's very very possible I mean it's it's
not easy like it shouldn't imply that
it's easy but it's definitely very
possible to take something that has its
genetic code and if they understand the
genetic code and how to reinsert it
it'll take years to understand the the
DNA map of cannabis and what goes where
and why but it's at some point they
should be able to to have a um would you
call that like a blank canvas type seed
that they can inject this code into I I
definitely think that's in our very near
future and something like that will be
absolutely so important to have
tissue culture yeah it's at a Cutting
Edge right now and the company that's
really the most advances in Canada and
they recently opened in the United
States I contacted them maybe a year two
years ago called them in Canada and they
said at this point having a Single Seed
like that it isn't feasible but it's on
its way and they feel very confident
that they will be able to take a seat
like you said and
somehow take what's left in it and
inject it into tissue culture and then
grow it again and then
cross it and make new seeds of the exact
same string so
hmm
I think it's not too far out
no I don't think so at all Kerry Mullis
is the cool guy he was a surfer too who
invented PCR basically and oh really and
he died just a few years ago
he wrote a really cool book that I have
and he did a lot of acid when he was in
college and he more or less saw the RNA
helix or whatever on acid and that's
what allowed him to then make the final
steps and make PCR real and he worked
for a company at the time so they got
the got the patent for it
he got the Nobel Prize of chemistry that
Year by the way and his friend said you
should just quit your job and then do it
on the outside and he estimated it would
be worth
this is 20 years ago when you wrote this
book I believe he said it would have
been worth about a quarter billion
dollars that oh I'm sure and today be
worth probably 20 billion dollars you
know because PCR is used in everything
yeah that's how it goes when you work
for a company they own you and they own
your they own your soul all these books
are non-fiction almost every single one
I have probably 40 50 fiction books but
yeah
and now with the internet I can skip
most of these books however there's
still my friends
right I can't let go of this stuff like
every move that I do is insane mostly
because of my book collection it's
insane it's heavy there's so many boxes
of books but and I know a lot of these
are online but like at the same time
there's a lot that aren't you know and
there's the ones I've been trying to
scan in and get out there for people
because I really have this this fervent
belief that like in order for us all to
progress and get at the level to where I
wish people were when it comes to
breeding and cannabis breeding and
taking it seriously we all have to be
have access to the same information and
be on the same playing field to have you
know expectations of people to put in
the work and to know what's what so if
I'm not making that available and I have
the resources too then I'm part of the
problem that's the way I look at it it's
weird but yeah so I I'm determined to
get it all scanned I had 10 feet of
National Geographics at one point
because my grandfather gave me a
subscription when I was nine years old
and for the next 15 years and then when
he died a friend of mine picked up where
he left off and kept sending them to me
but once it went digital and I realized
you can search every copy yeah or what I
need in my life I gave mine to the Boys
At Girls Clubs and it was 600 pounds
and I was so happy to give them away
because they would use them to cut out
photos and yeah yeah collages or do
whatever they're doing in their class
and that was fine
I did the best
but um now in High Times that's a
different story I'm give those to the
Boys and Girls Club
[Laughter]
definitely going to hold on to those
yeah you need to those are special I
mean
share them with people like you and
other friends yeah
like since since high times has put the
whole archive online like I have several
and but I still find myself picking them
up every time that I see them for
whatever and I'm like man I know I can
just go access it online but there's
something about having a hard copy from
the 70s being able to smell it and flip
the pages and re there's something about
that that I'll never be able to walk
away from smell of books the feel of
books also
I underlined I I'm not keeping a book so
that it'll be valuable later unless it's
one of the ones I collected as first
editions so I index my books and I open
the front page and it's got my index
and
this is just a small one where I you
know I wrote that many things
like page 91 is about shin splints page
it's about ligaments and yeah
it's just that's what the beauty of
books
you know I never um
I've never really taken notes in books
but I had a uh or notes on books period
I always memorized what I could and I I
when I was doing a lot of UFO research I
ran into a guy that just blew my mind
because every single book he had a long
list of everything he had ever read
about it and and he'd be like have you
read this book no here here's my notes
and I'd be able to read it real fast and
I was like this is so useful if I would
have done this for every book that I've
ever read I could be helping a lot of
people like really fast yeah so now I'm
making a habit to do stuff like that to
make notes to you know
well I think it's super important
probably the best book on it's called
The Rocks begin to speak
and it's by Levan Martino and about
petroglyphs yes and but this guy
um he was raised on
his
his part native American and he was
raised
and
this is how I index my books oh wow you
know
all the all the pages that have
things word order Clarity you know like
yeah
a lot of archaeologists thinks he's full
of it
he's no longer alive
however he was the first to start
like he said rocks broke the silence and
I've used his techniques personally in
even a Mad Jack Cannon there's lots of
petroglyphs and yeah
there's one that's very Sim simple
that's just a circle with a dot in the
middle of it and it means something
there
and
you see this on the Rock and he said he
walked around the Boulder and on the
back side there was a spring
wow they had
anyone in it didn't matter what language
you spoke they all spoke sign language
or Rock writing language
and it's it's incredible I and if you go
to other countries like Central America
South America
Asia there's petrobus or you know
hieroglyphs all the glyphs in the world
um it's just wonderful to me I think
it's amazing there's stuff like that to
even be found in the United States
because the United States like when we
think about our history we think of it
traditionally being you know 600 500
years old from um the European Conquest
but realistically like like you said
magic there is a beautiful I I've never
seen petroglyphs in person but I can
imagine the energy the
the vibrations around stuff like that
has got to be magical
one of my favorites that I've found I
think I sent you a link to the nfts I
made because I was
searching when nfts first came out a few
years ago it was a big and I searched
openc and wearable and all these sites
and no one had done anything with with
weed yeah I found one finally one photo
of a of a flower
some guy had posted on openc but yeah I
think all kinds of stuff and wove them
together and one of my favorite most
rare
petroglyphs I've ever found with my
first grow partner Doug the second
actually
um
showed
men on horseback
and
it was early conquistadors because they
have helmets
and it's it's a fairly rare thing to see
there are a few in northern Arizona and
Utah as well but this is
not in magic
came in proper but five miles away on
top of a Mesa where it drops off into
another Canyon
my friend and I were hiking over to look
over the edge and see these other
Canyons we were considering other growth
spots and we found this and it's um it's
pretty stunning to see a horse shape and
a guy on it and he's got a helmet and
this dates back to the first
conquistadors in the city it's got to be
them documenting seeing these guys come
through or like I'm trying to figure out
what they were seeing
in the 1500s since 16s because they
conquistors went through Arizona all the
way up to the Hobie reservation they
came also from Santa Fe which was their
Capital at the time
and mogulan was one of the first Spanish
Governors so the mogiano's
Juan Ignacio Flores moyon
no I didn't know that
yep he was it's for four years in 16
like 10 or something he was the governor
okay yeah and you can see they're on
horses clearly and their human humanoid
forms and they all have
headdresses on
and that the horse was introduced as you
know by conquistadors to North America
and
they were
stolen many times I don't think they
were traded that often because they're
too valuable in the early days but
Native Americans got some and then the
Plains Indians I mean they were there
was hunt hundreds there's tens of
thousands of wild horses at one point
you know just like there were millions
of Buffalo
and they were the the main ones but to
go over rough Terrain in the west the
conquistors yeah
they don't show up in many petroglyphs
the books that no and this one is
beautiful
yeah it's almost like a freeze frame of
of one of them talking like looking back
and talking to one of his other people
like that they you know what I mean like
giving them orders his hands up
directing there's
three clear ones
yeah marching and then below that at the
back left and looks like another human
feature like he's on a horse perhaps too
or he's falling off and then below it's
difficult to see I have the larger
version that shows this whole Boulder
this section you're looking at here is
about two feet wide
and wow
well three feet wide and two feet tall
this
photo is but each of those horses
petroglyphs are about I'd say eight
inches tall maybe ten wow yeah when we
saw that we were like oh my gosh because
you know
they're not crazy documented in any
Petroglyph books this picture that
you've taken no and I've been wanting to
go
um get with my friends at Coconino
National Forest
but I've known them for 40 years the
archaeologists there there's a new head
archaeologist Peter pillis was the
previous archaeologist and
he
loved petrobless too
there's two huge sites outside of Sedona
honaki and palatki palatki's open to the
public honakis uh where tours go and
they walk you through and they describe
stuff and Peter came down once and gave
a three-hour class that I was fortunate
enough to be a part of with three other
people and oh wow they went over what
they were saying about stuff and then he
told them if they're full of or not
and they were 90 totally wrong
this is the Sean's cave and he said well
actually in the sonawa which means
without water that's the nickname the
ancient people of the Verdi dollar he
said there was no no
documented signs of shamanism at all
oh
Shaman's cave because of the petroglyphs
that were associated with it so then he
would go through and then say what was
more likely
um it was an excellent
and I was I wasn't I had already been a
grower 20 years before I met Peter and
and he uh
I shared some things with him but I
never took my Petroglyph book I have all
these and as photos which I've since
digitized as you can tell here yeah
I was stunned never ever and I've been
to
newspaper not newspaper rock but this
big one that's up near the hope you Rez
and other areas
fascinating
one of the largest
in northern Arizona is called newspaper
rock and it it was a site that was used
for many years
people would add to it and add to it and
it was like a newspaper they akined it
to because it had so much information
that was obviously packed into the rock
over many decades not just one person
sat down for two years didn't you
graffiti
this is this takes to do one of these
figures this is called this patina is
called desert varnish and it appears on
rocks as they get older certain types
this is volcanic rock and it gets this
brown or blackish patina
and to Peck into it it reveals the real
color of the lighter Rock underneath
but it takes hours and hours to do one
of these you're using another rock in
your hand that's hard like maybe a piece
of granite or something and make a point
so that you can Peck the design you want
so yes this might have represented more
than one person leaving their
information over many years it's hard to
say I yeah I think the top three at
least so the front two here were
probably
simultaneous
in one stretch maybe in a maybe they
spent a week doing this who knows
you know I just think like the part that
catches me is is the guy in the Middle
with his hand up like director like that
because it's like it's almost like
obviously he was the boss
whoever it was they were portraying him
as the boss
he may have had a stick in his hand to
whip the horse with you know because
they didn't have oh yeah
so it may have been they were portraying
that he had something he was hitting the
horse to make it go faster so I don't
know that's true
but the Spanish used either that would
be another interesting thing to study
it's definitely put something on his
head
oh yeah and the guy up front here you
know had these rival tribes in the
Plains Indians they were lots of
headdresses but that was this late 17s I
think or maybe mostly in the 1800s these
are going back to 15s and 1600s when the
first horses came through in the sonawa
and the mogulan people saw them
yeah passed through and they were just
like what the heck are those yeah yeah
they didn't even know what horses were
right no no can you imagine
a horse
and there's humans on top of them just
riding them around
wearing armor and helmets and because
they were worried about getting shot by
arrows yeah how quickly though like the
Plains Indians adapted to be able to to
or Native Americans were adapted to be
able to ride horses and became very
proficient Horsemen bareback too yeah
amazing it's just amazing how they
adapted to that
oh it helped them hunt and made their
life easier
yeah I I they call them dog soldiers too
um the people that rode the early horses
they were they they were comparing
courses to large what does it feel like
to be around these petroglyphs did you
get any like I know it's it's kind of
hard to quantify spiritual spirituality
and feelings and stuff but did you ever
get any kind of
spark of energy or any kind it kind of
sounds so weird saying that but did you
ever feel anything around these
petroglyphs of note
um
yes but it's hard to quantify like you
said Sending next to a fire
we we made underground fire pits so that
the Flames wouldn't be visible sixteen
hundred of feet above us was a small
Pueblo the Bruins of just two foot walls
but the outlines created made about 20
rooms and wow and down below the
boulders that next near the creek that
had the some of these petroglys had
outline of that structure you know 16
rooms little squares so they they had
some very interesting communication and
to feel first that next near the creek
that had the some of these petroglets
had outline of that structure you know
16 rooms little squares so they they had
some very interesting communication and
to feel
well to be growing weed in the middle of
all that was very
um very powerful If We Had a Farm where
and just had 10 acres it'd be cool
but being surrounded by this and at
night hearing a creek flowing by and
Bears smashing through the bushes and
stuff it's like the only thing that
divides you from the people who wrote
those messages is time and like what a
small barrier in some ways an
understanding
and understanding yeah so I'd like to
talk to you about one thing and this is
um something that I feel like it like I
talk about it a lot but I'm younger so
even in my generation it was almost a
loss or unless you were into uh maybe
tattooing or even Plumbing or part of a
union job or something like that which
is apprenticeship learning a craft under
someone
um learning
learning the The Apprentice men
Apprentice Mentor role where you snap to
it do what you say you know because
you're learning
um and and how that applies in modern
days and and how much of that is missing
now
in your time when you wanted to learn to
grow were there guys that you could
Apprentice under how would you have
found an apprentice in the 70s
let's say or 60s uh to learn to grow in
76 when my dealer friend from Tempe said
let's grow our own and I went sure
um I already had a green thumb as far as
I worked on five acres of garlic with
some other hippies and Cottonwood
Arizona and I love taking care of plants
in my yard Vines anything that could
make it pretty and beautiful
I planted a few trees already so I kind
of knew
soil culture a bit comfortable to step
in then yeah and yeah what I didn't know
is anything about
the needs of cannabis as it grew and
especially when to harvest it and how to
Manicure it how to dry it manicure so
that was self-taught with my friend he
had never grown either and luckily we
had the Growers guides and later
marijuana botany and all these fantastic
so I frequently say the word
the written word has always been my
guide and my mentor I I would buy books
and books and books on everything and
just read and get ideas and ways to do
it
I didn't Apprentice it as a carpenter or
plumber or anything like that today
you know with the Advent of more
artificial intelligence doing other
things
really if you can fix air conditioners
or heaters or Plumbing or electricity or
build things
you're not going to have to worry until
it's like George Jetson time and your
robots that can walk around and do
everything
um I don't know that that day is going
to come but
probably will I don't yeah
maybe 50 years from now or 30 years I
don't know they're they're creating
robots to fight other humans which is
stupid or other robots but
yeah uh part of it you know being an
apprentice to a great mentor would be
fabulous
um I know people who have gone to work
in Colorado at Big rows and learn the
basics and after a couple years they
come home and they they've learn what
they needed to know to feel confident to
do it themselves
but so wait
but jumping out yeah like you mentioned
if you're not invested in it and you
haven't put 10 or 20 years in
you you can always just quit like you
mentioned and walk away whereas someone
who spent a whole lot of years learning
how to refinish furniture or build
furniture or anything uh
I have a nephew who's learning about
furniture right now and he's refinishing
it and starting from scratch but I don't
think he has a teacher other than
Maybe YouTube
you know and that's that's a legitimate
method of learning now that wasn't there
when we were you know doing stuff oh
yeah oh yeah I was gonna change out my
headlights and my Tacoma because they're
10 years old and they're they're fading
and I've bought 3M cleaners to put on
you know and wipe the glass it's not
even glass it's polycarbonate and it
works for a while and then it goes back
to being bad yeah so I looked online at
a guy who shows how to replace them and
there's like 10 different electrical
connections and if you could take a
photo every time you got to a certain
spot you're going to pull this one off
and this take a photo and then when you
pull it out take a photo yeah
I get to a dealer and paid them to do it
took them an hour and a half to put two
new ones in it would have taken me two
days
um
man I might have made a mistake and then
have to troubleshoot which wire did I
leave off or put on the wrong one yeah
no
um it wasn't so it cost 150 a light to
have them do it and it was worth every
penny so I bet those guys who did that
in an hour and a half they apprenticed
for many years yeah mechanics who could
do stuff like that I'm in awe of I never
really next to that level no
of course I ever did was change the
starter in my Volkswagen van I did that
myself I felt very proud
I bet I used to have a 66 bug and um the
idle pin would always mess up so I
learned that if I got duct tape and a
pencil eraser and put it on that idle
pin that it would fix it every time
that's about the most auto mechanics
I've ever done is the old eraser yeah
you uh turn it on its head and found a
workaround which I did which I've seen
some great mechanics back in the days
that could do the same thing and duct
tape man
and bailing wire Gotta Have balance so
when you think you're off road and you
hit that muffler and it's hanging you
can strap it back
so there's also
the idea and this this kind of goes
along with the idea of mentorship
apprenticeship and it's becoming a part
of a group
um for example when you become a part of
a forum
when the Forum days were around and big
you know ever I I remember my first time
coming on the forums and
trying to figure out how first what am I
what do I say without looking stupid
right how do I integrate into this group
that I don't quite understand some of
these subcultures like I was a punk rock
kid in my area growing up I don't really
relate to the deadhead Community very
much but that's a lot of this community
is the hippie community so I've got to
learn to integrate and communicate with
people I've never really integrated with
or communicated with or understand their
cultural subcultural level and
um we don't really seem to have that
anymore what we have are social media
where you just blast out whatever you
know but back then you had to integrate
yourself into a group to gain access not
even to gain access but to to learn from
each other and at that point you know to
share then Cuts were shared between the
group because you trusted each other you
knew each other you know and it was over
a period of several years where a lot of
these groups and friendships were formed
and bound and I I talked to the guys
today like in my in our patreon Discord
group and I see how some guys try to
assimilate you know and some don't it's
just it's very different than the Forum
error where you where you watch these
personalities kind of try to assimilate
whereas now it's just like
lots of clashing personalities all
falling on top of each other and nobody
really understanding assimilation into
groups it's very fascinating you mean
like I see maggots yeah yeah exactly
it's it's a bunch of personalities all
screaming at each other as opposed to
like a group working together I see Mac
had the great you know um SD's finest
group that did pretty cool the San
Diego's finest cuts on I see map those
guys did really good for a long time
um but they're so far and few between I
mean you have the land race groups on
icy mag that all kind of pulled together
you know over time and they have some
good groups and uh yeah they all had a
huge following Tom Hill eventually got
so fed up with all these um people
hounding him and he
he would just blast people
was one of my early Heroes of the floor
just because he didn't like it's not
that he would just go off on people that
wasn't it was that he would do it and he
was right and he was correct when he was
saying it you know and he was a
geneticist he could quit the top of him
if he and Rob Clark were sitting down or
someone who really knew genetics well he
he would have no difficulty you know
talking about back Crossing and uh just
all the different
mathematical formulas involved so you
knew what how many would be this how
many would be that way what Gene
Expressions would you expect yeah I love
that it's beyond me
um I can kind of grab the concept
if I'm growing a hybrid
and I have 10 of those come up and I
look at them I'll see differences in
them I'm not sure I could scientifically
say well one quarter we're going to be
this cross you know and or Express these
recessive genes and you know whoa yeah
it's something else yeah yeah trying to
have conversations with him is is very
humbling
on a burrito level you can go going back
to the uh apprenticeship imagine being
an apprentice
Petroglyph artist in the Native American
days or someone who made projectile
points whether they were spear points
for the Paleo Indians ten thousand years
ago to run up and kill Buffalo or the
Archaic Period that came next and they
were adult points that were looked like
large arrowheads and they would boost a
spear thrower spear and then finally the
bow and arrow showed up in the southwest
and little tiny points
which are sometimes called bird points
they had to be very tiny and sharp and
lightweight because they're going to be
shooting through the air on a stick and
if you put a big point on there
the that Arrow would just go
40 feet
yeah yeah so
those to find
to find their ancient work on the ground
when you're hiking is mind-boggling too
to know how long it would take to be an
apprentice and get skilled at making
those
when they had such a tough life to live
every day that they couldn't just take a
whole day to make points unless they
were special and they were so good or
maybe
women they they
believed that there was great women
Point makers too because they didn't go
hunting as much yeah and they were
taking care of the home front and
they would have possible time at least
before the Advent of
people growing crops and corn yeah where
you had to be out you know taking care
of the plants and
stopping animals from eating them wow
we've covered a lot of territory today I
love Petroglyph stuff dude like
[Music]
um it was like it was like I was
connected with everything around me
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
started to hit me
and I'm like well
[Music]
[Applause]
I got high
[Music]
breeders Syndicate update not only is
our merch store up at syndicategear.com
but all episodes will remain free but
what we need from you is interaction if
you're watching the show for your first
time kick back and enjoy it if you like
the show feel free to like it but if
it's your second viewing we ask a gentle
person's agreement that you click the
Subscribe button it costs you nothing
but it helps us tremendously with the
sneaky YouTube algorithm
leaving comments telling not to his
voice lulls you into a trance works as
well we hope you take the time to do
this we try to put out the best possible
shows for you we can and want to build
this community thanks again from all of
us at the Breeders Syndicate family