boom boom
let's get this angle going so you can
see that beautiful [ __ ] right there
because I like showing her
what's up everyone
about to get this [ __ ] jumping
huh anyway
any [ __ ] way so tonight we're gonna
um
do a little Kim 101 I use that term
because that was the original
um Fred on IC mag that covered chem dog
started by our buddy I Lonesome so this
will be the 101 video I wish I unless
would be here too uh on camera with us
but yeah no this isn't a customer this
is that's actually What's called the
Epiphone uh
it's an epiphone not a Gibson it's a
prism plus so it's all Epiphone parts or
I'm sorry El Gibson Parts pickups
everything in it coil splitting
but a really thin thin thin neck which I
love
so yeah
so yeah I'm gonna bring natto in and uh
it looks like there's already 90 people
in here so let's get this [ __ ] jumping
what's up Keith uh props to Keith too
because he's the one who really uh kind
of put this in my brain today to get
this going let's see where's where's
my buddy here there we go
yeah this is uh Bryn's paint not mine I
don't know much about paint what's up
dude Wasabi how you doing I'm good you
ready to to drop the verbal pipe bomb I
mean you know hopefully it'll be
educational yeah we'll try to keep
try to keep you know facts from uh
educated guesses separate perhaps yeah
yeah I think a lot of times yeah a lot
of times those two things got get
conflated yeah you know what people know
versus what people think you know yeah
so I think that's a good idea um
let's see first of course like you just
said we'll we'll start with the
disclaimer a lot of this is going to be
Theory and conjecture based on educated
guesses based on breeding
um based on talking to pretty much
everyone involved in the in the Kim
lineage and sour lineage from from back
in the day till now
um it's it's a lot of it was put
together by CSI Humboldt you know a lot
of what what what I've I've discovered
and he's discovered and not so's
discovered all combined into one grand
ultimate Theory however I don't want to
speak for him he can always speak on his
own I offered him to come on here but
he's always too busy so
um it's just going to be me and not so
and we're going to try to cover it as
best we can as accurate as we can and
and with the best intentions because uh
earlier someone wrote me and it was this
it was around it was this morning and um
he was just asking you know like is it
what is uh you know Kim D what is what
is Kim a what's all this stuff and and I
thought about I was like there really
isn't you know one place people can go
as a resource to really get a good idea
for what these lines are what's behind
them in the history it's a lot of
piecing together from different Forum
stuff and even then there's a lot of
stuff that's just not out there because
people are scared to step on toes and I
think it's been long enough that no toes
should be stepped on
yeah I mean it it's also true in a lot
of ways where
um
you know uh the truth the truth survives
a lot better when there's when there's
little fame or rap or money involved
yeah because there's no reason to alter
it and you know as soon as anything
becomes you know famous or you know
there's money involved or whatever else
then all of a sudden you know
uh sometimes there's battling amongst
people as far as like who did what and
when and how and everything like that so
yeah
um you know it's uh yeah and cam is you
know Kim's this this this topic has been
debated now for
uh when did The Forum talk start Matt
like oh six yeah somewhere around there
is when people started really jumping on
it yeah so probably like it's been it's
been publicly debated now in various
ways and various you know forms for 16
years or something like that yeah
um which is pretty incredible when it
comes to like a bunch you know a small
group of like hippie kids just partying
and then all of a sudden Fame happens
yeah you know exactly dude so let's
start with uh let's start with the
beginning
the chem 91 the the dog Bud bag seed as
it were all right so maybe maybe I'll
start at not the beginning but a
beginning right and then we'll go back
to the beginning so uh my my start in
the Cannabis story as far as chem dog
goes comes in the late 90s
um I had uh I just I recently found the
Mendo perps us and I'd grown a couple
crops of it and I had I had a friend uh
who will remain nameless uh simply
because he doesn't really like Fame but
I've previously referred to him as
Staten Island uh and you know as we
became friends uh he gave me the camp
what later be was called the dog at the
time the dog and the super skunk
right yep
um and we became like really really good
friends for a long time and so he used
to tell me a bunch of the stories about
the chem and how all that came to be and
this is you know this is
um late 90s early 2000s as all these
stories are getting told so uh that's
kind of my aspect into the camp yeah um
at the time
other than him uh and myself he had
given it a couple of years previous to
giving it to me he had given it to uh
the guy who's known on here as uh skunk
VA
uh you'll forgive me if I if I pause for
a second because I'm trying to like
instead of just saying all these
people's names I'm trying to use their
internet handle you know yeah which is a
little different because you know I you
don't ever call them by these things in
person right yeah
um but you know there was a few people
there was a couple literally probably
like four or five people in the state of
California that had it yeah right
um and then
you know you can fast forward to the
forums uh where uh skunk VA came out and
sort of the chemdog 101 which Matt
reference began to come out and all
kinds of people started debating various
aspects and but for a while say from the
time that it was created until it's Fame
as it were
um you know it was really only a small
group of people they kind of had it so
probably the the easiest way to that to
say it is
um in the summer of 1991 uh the chemdog
was seeing some Grateful Dead shows
and at Grateful Dead shows I've said
previously it was a really great place
to buy kind bud uh especially in the
early 90s it might have been one of the
only consistent places
to buy kind bud at the time right and so
he was I think he was 17 years old at
the time and he bought some kind bud
from a guy named uh Joe brand
and his and his kind of his sidekick uh
Peabody
right uh the story diverges right after
that because he either found
supposedly 13 seeds in that kind bud
or he or he got uh Peabody and Joe to
send him one more batch of something of
something yeah and he found the seeds in
that bud
but needless to say the reason why
people call it Deer Creek for younger
people is Deer Creek is one of the
venues uh in
um
the I'm getting confused by questions
tell him that Jason Kim that Jason King
wrote about was my cam that was my weed
I grew it and I gave him I even wrote
him out a list of what to say and it did
not make an accurate transcription into
the book sadly uh he took some artistic
license
um but
anyway uh you know so
um so chem dog takes it home right and
he has these seeds and he Sprouts four
or five of them or one or you know no
he's probably so he Sprouts a few
because out of that comes the chem CIS
and the chem 91. okay and I will say
about the chem CIS that my buddy from
Staten Island remembers it
yeah so you know two of them survived
yes of the let's put it that way of the
first of the first batch of seeds popped
two became named okay and the other ones
probably ended up getting lost
um everyone that I first met everyone
called it the dog
uh most of the Growers that had it um my
buddy from Staten Island uh skunk VA Etc
they were all organic Growers so they
weren't super hyped back then on calling
anything they grew chem yeah of course
uh and you know Americans we like to
shorten [ __ ] or whatever so most of us
just called it the dog yeah it was the
dog right and um
so You Know It uh so
chem dog had the dog and he was growing
the dog for a number of years uh and it
became kind of popular in the east coast
in certain circles and he was really
militant about not giving it out
right
um because he didn't want to get cut off
right he had yeah he had sort of a trap
Market this and that now granted you
know as the case may be you have to
realize that like at this particular
time he's you know 17 18 19 years old at
best yeah right uh these are Grateful
Dead kids right so my buddy from Staten
Island
has been trying to get it from him and
chem dog wouldn't give it to anybody on
the East Coast
okay and um
my buddy moved out to Sonoma County in
Northern California just North of San
Francisco and he wanted to be closer
to the Grateful Dead Jerry Garcia Jerry
band the Bay Area hippies right so he
left New York and
um
chem dog because dude was on the west
coast and 3000 miles away agreed to give
it to him if as long as he promised to
never ever give it to anyone back on the
East Coast yeah he didn't want it to
spread anywhere in New York or
Massachusetts or anything like that yeah
at the same time
um
he had this he had this weed
um that uh he smoked with these other
hippies at uh some Jerry Garcia shows uh
and these guys flipped out over it they
adored it they wanted it really bad and
so they said if you come to Virginia
right we will give you this skunk cut
that we have
and
um you know in exchange for this this
cut that you have
so dude arranged it
um to go to Virginia and trade uh this
cut for the super skunk and then he
drove to Massachusetts and met chemdog
and chemdog gave him the dog and because
dude had a couple extra cuts of this
skunk he gave one to chemdog and then he
took the super skunk and the dog and
drove West yeah
right that was about 1993.
yes or so no yes so that's that's kind
of that's kind of where like the the
West Coast kind of comes into it is he
brought it out to the West Coast
um and then that was 1993. and he was
pretty much the only one growing it for
a few years
either one of them on the west coast
actually uh nobody else had it uh so it
was basically like one small garage
and you could get either one of those
strains if if you happen to go to like a
Jerry Garcia show at The Warfield or
anywhere in the bay or anywhere in
California he would likely be there with
ounces yeah slinging ounces for 400
bucks an ounce right
uh so you fast forward a couple years
and uh it's 1995 and Jerry has a heart
attack and dies
and uh uh skunk VA decides to come off
dead tour
um and wants to grow some wheat and so
initially my buddy gives him the super
skunk you which is
um dudes taking some Polaroids and uh
he's posted them up on his IG so there's
some I think some 95 96 Polaroids and
let's let's go ahead and delineate here
that between start start calling it the
VA Super Skunk the one just try to refer
to it as that because there might be
other super skunks yeah sure so
that's the other hard part too is that
all these other terms besides dog and
super skunk came about on the internet
when people were trying to figure out
what the hell we had
so uh VA skunk
um Massachusetts Super Skunk chem 91 uh
skunk VA cut I don't think any of those
things really even existed until the
mid-2000s yeah yeah in terms of in terms
of nomenclature in terms of names yeah
yeah right to us it was like the SS and
the dog yeah yeah super skunking dog and
the only reason why I'm really telling
the super skunk thing for for a minute
is just because it ties into how home
you got it
and brought it West yeah okay so what's
something what someone should know is
that um
and uh he wasn't part of the he uh skunk
VA wasn't part of the Dead uh no
um there was a bunch of us a few hundred
thousand people uh that either went you
know that traveled around with the Dead
uh while there was dead shows up until
1995 and he was one of those people yeah
he was one of those people uh Peabody
was another one of those people so it
was Joe brand there was a lot of people
that went to shows and hustled various
things to uh
um to make it to the next show
yeah you know uh and so you know
um
and uh don't get one of the questions
don't get caught up in questions don't
get caught up in questions yeah don't
worry about it yeah so we'll cover them
so he um so he got you know so basically
what it boiled down to is that there was
one guy
from 1993 on that had it on the West
Coast yes right and he promised he was
he's always been kind of Stingy about
Cuts uh you know he kind of saw what was
coming uh you know it might have been a
lot of years off at that point but he
saw that there was a bunch of uh
shenanigans that was going to happen and
so he was always pretty militant about
getting trading cuts and stuff like that
um I didn't really trade Cuts with him I
just kind of by sheer accident became
like a super close friend of his yeah
and that's pretty much why I got them
yeah you know we just traded everything
back and forth because we were so close
right
um
and so uh
that's kind of the start now here's an
interesting thing my buddy from Staten
Island smoked both the dog and the chem
CIS back then but he didn't bring the
chemistus West because he thought it was
far inferior okay he didn't want it so
we know for sure that the chemcis was
one of the earliest Cuts oh he yes he to
my knowledge the chemists and the chem
dog or the dog are the two cuts that
came out of the first popping of seats
okay and they existed and he remembers
smoking them in you know before he moved
West in 91 92
um you know he you know so he I have you
know independent confirmation yeah right
that those both those things existed
that's that's good to know because even
I I had no clue if Ken because it's
always been said that Kim sis was a part
of the cam a through depop and that's
where it gets confused no he he actually
he and he thought it was ugly and he
didn't like the high makes sense and so
he didn't he didn't bring it West he had
the opportunity to bring it West
he didn't want it okay right
um you know and so that doesn't mean it
wasn't good or whatever it just yeah but
it was one dude's opinion you know but
it was ugly
um you know and it wasn't as good and so
you know
um so anyway so you know the the story
of Kim is that uh you know what became
known as you know chem 91 and CIS came
out of that first 91 seat pop yeah
right
um and uh you know it it goes off it
goes off on tangents because it ties
into sour and all these different things
but we can keep it yeah you know I don't
know we can keep it pretty close I'm
doing my best to not look at questions
but I know it's just okay and it's
cracking me it's [ __ ] hard
so
um
so anyway those those were those were
the first two cuts I mostly have
I'll say this I know a lot about what
happened uh on the west coast simply
because I'm good friends with him and
I'm good and I've known the other people
that had it for forever now you know
yeah uh and you know we also traded a
ton of stories about things before the
forums really existed
yeah and before it was ever talked about
or before we had any idea that like
anything of this [ __ ] was going to be
anything important yeah either right
because that's what happens with a lot
of famous weed is that nobody has any
idea what they're doing is going to be
important or people are going to care
right so it's not like everyone's taking
meticulous notes in case uh they get
famous later yeah these are we are
partying hippies yeah and take smoking
weed we're taking LSD we're trying to
chase chicks we're tripping around we're
doing our thing circle jerking all of it
yeah that was more like I think your uh
you know so to speak but I've seen I
don't know to each their own so
um you know but yeah that's that's kind
of what and you got to remember too for
chem dog I mean chem dog was literally
17 years old when he got these [ __ ]
seats yeah
I don't know if anyone I don't know how
old everyone who's listening is but like
when you're 17 18 19
you don't have very much together
no the fact that dude was able to throw
together some lights especially in the
early 90s when there was no forums there
was no information there was two or
three books you could buy yeah and some
friends you know I mean the tech was
pretty basic yeah it was not easy to get
information back then it was not easy to
learn like most of the time you learned
you did whatever someone who knew who
was growing around you was doing if you
knew anyone yeah I didn't know anyone so
I I literally started from books
um so you know he uh
yeah and it was totally illegal there
was no medical or anything like that
obviously but uh you know that's how it
started it started with with some
teenagers
and bag seed from a dead show
so as a result of that
um you know uh the what it is exactly
will will kind of be an eternal mystery
yeah
um you know and at least at this point
it's it's at least at this point that
we're speaking about it's a complete
mystery on what it is yeah and you know
and I should also say too that
um
they
chemdog wasn't friends with peabut or
Joe brand or anything like that like he
was they weren't in the circle of of
crew they were just like someone that
they bought weed off of at a dead show
or something here and there right so
those guys had those guys had no idea
for years and years and years that
anything came out of that weed sale yeah
like at all
you know
um
and so
uh you know people are saying being a
Skelly hash plant dog Bud stop it stop
it stop it there's all kinds of things
there's all kind there's all kinds of
rumors that have come out after the fact
right yeah but the bottom line is that
some older Partiers Who Sold weed for a
living okay who are constantly buying
and selling different types of weed on
dead tour
sold the sack of weed one day and then
15 years later found out something came
of it yeah so there was no like calls
back like hey that thing is really
special what what like there wasn't any
kind of information exchange like that
going and then and and to me this is
where kind of like
um well I guess maybe let's take it
year by year so let's get into the uh
the Kim a through D then I mean or can
be through D I guess if Kim's sister
because Kim's sister is considered Kim a
if I remember correctly same thing I
mean it you know I
so I mean you can say there's there's
rumors I
I was not
um you know I was not obviously on the
east coast and all this stuff happened
um but I mean I you know I was I knew
the various people involved
and that's what I was told yeah um what
we know for sure is that two keepers
came out of the first batch of seeds got
you yeah that's what we know for sure
um and then let's get to so we've gone
on about the 91 we haven't really said
about what we think it is or anything
we'll do that at the end
um let's do the the the D era
okay so fast forward nine years nine
years nine years okay right
um and maybe
God I should
I mean we have well I guess we'll just
Bounce Around in time fast forward nine
years and
um he's got some seeds and he decides to
pop some more seeds
okay
um any labels them whatever you know a b
c d e you know so on and so forth yeah
and it seems like the one true keeper
that came out of that was the D yeah
okay so
um
so there was the D right and at this
point the story has has been that he
found males and that he didn't find
males based on what post you refer to
and this yeah like a lot of things I've
said before I mean there's there's
issues with chem dog in the sense that
um not all of the things he has written
on the forums can all be true yeah yeah
you know I'm not saying he's a liar
because yeah I'm just saying that like
your recollection and this year versus
how you write it in that year and all
that type of stuff you know and what you
were doing and if you remember right
yeah um because you know I mean Matt you
know Matt we've we've uh We've chatted
with some very old school cats and some
of them have very poor memory on what
they were up to yeah that's for sure
that seems to be consistent among most
older heads yeah none of them knew it
was going to be famous or matter or need
to remember yeah or need to remember so
basically at this point we should say
that I'm not exactly sure when the sis
died yeah let's just say that there was
the the dog AKA chem 91 and then there
was the CIS yes and then there was the D
yeah so by 2000 there was
um there was three cuts
okay
and uh
um you know fast forward uh five or six
more years and skunk VA gets on the
forums Matt would probably remember was
it I see mag
I don't remember which one he popped up
on I think he popped up on the forums
talking [ __ ] about uh Cam and this and
that and everything else and that's kind
of where the skunk VA cut came from sure
the name because a lot of times back
then you attributed a cut to the name of
the poster who first talked about the
cut correct and it was super common
right yeah that was a very common
nomenclature way of talking about things
right yeah so
um
you know and then the I mean you know
there's uh so anyway so it gets it
starts to get famous
okay and other people realize it gets
famous
um and you know uh obviously skunk VA
kind of started the fame uh chem dog
gets back involved he realizes that
there's a bunch of stuff going on about
his stories I believe he started posting
some versions of his events right around
then
and somehow uh Peabody and Joe brand
find out it's going on and recently just
so so everybody knows like they're
talking about Joe brand I recently
talked to Joe brand and we're going to
do an interview but we've been having
um trouble like linking up the times to
do it so this is being told with his uh
input in it basically so when we get to
the one through four I'll start talking
more about from his point of view how it
went down as well so what I believe
happened is uh
um you know they uh these people started
talking back and forth and this was the
first indication to Peabody and Joe
brand that something had happened to
some weed that they sold 15 16 years
before yeah right
so and this year's
2006 2006 right yeah and so
um Joe and chemdog start chatting or
dming or whatever the hell
and
chemdog decides to give them Force give
Joe brand four seats yes and they were
even they even named them the reunion
seats that's correct yeah because it was
The Reunion because it was the first
time these various characters had
started chatting again correct after 15
16 years of not talking yeah right and
so they were supposed to be four seats
from the original bad was how the story
went the story went there were four
seeds from the original band so they got
popped and they got creatively named one
through four since it was already a3d
let's do one thing yeah they were they
were named one through four yeah
um so you know uh The Forum era was a
little bit different era in the sense
that things were starting to get traded
around a little bit more
different grows and different things
like that and like I said my uh
um my buddy who brought the Clones out
here was real stingy about trading cuts
and especially
um especially that and so uh chem dog
had made him promise to not really give
it out beyond the tight Circle and so he
kind of held to that yeah right
um you know uh
so but then obviously there's a bunch of
desire for it
right yeah and so I don't know where we
want to go from here
um but uh
that's well I mean that's the rough
story as it was told that's the rough
story so as it was originally told now
aka dog ak-91 yeah right uh chem CIS
those are the 91 pop okay some things
were popped in 2000 of that the D
survived and became known and famous
yeah and then some more things one
through four were popped in 2006. yes
and those also became named and those
also those also started getting traded
and this is where the story kind of
where where we ended up with the story
when all of us started kind of
researching it pretty hard is is from
taking that story that we were told that
they were all from the same bag of seeds
and then growing them and over the years
you know whether me you Caleb everyone
started collecting these cuts and
growing them out and seeing how that
compared to the tail and that's where
everything kind of starts getting
figured out uh over the years um from
Joe Brown to what he had as the Kim one
through four what thought he really was
I'll answer this question even though
you're telling me to ignore it the Joe
brand cut
um came because uh
Joe Joe Brown was a is it was I don't
know if he is was a hard partier
right let's just let's just put it that
way he liked to get high he liked to
party he liked to party on a wide
variety of stuff
and he traded people
um after he got a hold of the chem 91 he
traded from IC Collective correct uh no
yes hold on no no no no
so it gets it gets confusing okay
from Joe's point of view but uh but I'll
but I'll I'll go back to that so what
became known as the as the Joe brand cut
is Joe ended up the JB cam he started
trading people okay the chem 91 for
various cuts
and lo and behold it wasn't the chem 91.
so he sent people
you know some people call it the Joe B
diesel some people call it the Joe B Kem
uh it was obviously maybe a a JB 91
um that's what I'm referring to though
he got the cut that he was trading from
Icy Collective that's how it's not
accordingly okay so so here here's where
we'll go so I also know I see Collective
um and he has a different version of
events yeah so let's tell both so that's
so why don't you why don't you tell
Joe's version okay so Joe's version is
that um when he tried to get back the
cuts he went to IC Collective and I see
collectives sent him back cam a version
of Cam 91 that he thought that he may or
may not have known was the real one and
Joe brand immediately started passing it
out and trading it out
so uh could be could be um his uh I see
Collective story is not that much
different than that okay so I see
Collective story is that
um he lived in Oakland at the time uh
and he'd been in Tahoe and stuff too but
he
um
he had Joe brand and Peabody come out to
his house
okay and that was the first time it was
an OS it was it was a little bit after
06 I think it was right around that era
um but that was the first time that
Peabody and Joe brand smoked the chem
91.
yeah was at his house then they had
never seen it they they made they
obviously had smoked or seen the dog bud
or whatever the seeds came out of but
that was the first time they ever saw
the famous cut yeah okay and they had
the one through four
um and uh
they have the one through four and they
wanted to trade him
um the D and the 91 for the one through
four yeah and he said no
and he gave them the D but he would not
give them the 91.
okay now this actually I actually kind
of believe his version of Events maybe
I'll maybe I'll rewind a little bit so
because someone just asked where did I
see Collective get it
we all got it huh you already said that
I mean we're not paying attention we all
got we all got it from the same we all
got it from Staten Island yeah he's the
one that brought it West
um uh skunk VA got it I would say in not
96-ish or something like that uh IC got
it in 97ish when he graduated from high
school
um I got it in 98-ish
um so you know and that was kind of
where it stopped
so there was four people by night late
90s that had it in California right
um
so
um had to get the chem 91 somewhere
so that so I so I know where he got it
okay so Piva and Joe brain were pissed
that I I see would not give it to him
okay okay so they go to our homie CSI
and that's they gave him the one through
the four okay because they were like The
Originators
of you know or part of the original
story yeah they got
our buddy to give them the 91.
then they would have had the original
91. they did have the original 91. they
got it from Caleb 100 and Caleb and
Caleb he's told me that himself
but you have to realize I know you're
you're just think okay now I'm gonna say
this like you know Joe used to struggle
I'm uh and I'm not judging him on this
but no no yeah he used to he at that
time uh he did a lot of opiates yeah
yeah okay so he got the 91. he somehow
lost the 91.
and started sending out mislabeled 91 in
traits so yeah so so he puts the onus on
on um IC Collective but reality may have
been just a mislabel
the reality the reality is is that from
what I see told me and I don't see any
reason to doubt him he said he
absolutely would not give him the cut
well yeah and then he definitely aside
and then CSI told me he absolutely did
give him the cut okay so I I kind of
think that's how they got the cut yeah I
don't make the most sense I don't know
uh I don't know how long
uh Joe brand had the real 91 before he
lost it but when he started trading
people and that was that was like my
buddy from Staten Island uh and other
people's worst fear is they didn't want
people to start trade baiting it all
over yeah which is exactly what Joe B
and t-bud started to do yes except for
everyone that got the dog from those
guys didn't get the dog and you know
what we didn't even realize how how off
that was until I think our first real
inkling of of what had happened there
was when Bodhi started making crosses
with
um the 88 G13 hash plant and then that's
when people were like wait what is this
cut what is this weird cut so you get
you get into this thing obviously where
you know okay so you have you have Joe
Brandon Peabody's version and then you
have IC Collective his his memory of it
and then you have Caleb's memory of it
right yeah but what we know for a fact
is that these Cuts started getting
traded around amongst this little group
that's how I see and Caleb got the one
through the four
yeah right whether it was from IC or
whether it was from Caleb or whether it
was
they had it for a brief time yeah he
lost it somehow
um but he either was scamming people or
just had a mislabeled mom and was and
had just gotten it and was trading it to
all kinds of people for whatever else he
wanted to get for his garden yeah so he
was blowing it out there so maybe some
people got the real dog
and then later on people started getting
what became known as the JB cut yeah you
know and then people are trying to
figure out what the hell the JB cut is
and it's like JB maybe new or maybe
didn't know that he was giving out a
fake cut yeah so that's where you know
so if you guys aren't paying attention
just go back and watch it we're not
answering questions right now don't even
look at him not so
so anyway
um you know according to uh you know and
yeah I mean that's you know the my
understanding of it some people call the
JB chem but
um I see Collective said it was a diesel
type and a shitty diesel type yeah it
wasn't as good as maybe it was a diesel
bag seat or something along those lines
um you know and so there's this thing
where
um you know this stuff ended friendships
in a way like there's there's people
that I've mentioned that don't talk to
one another because of ego around this
cut yes you know
um to this day uh you know our buddy CSI
he didn't give it out forever and I
think he waited even something like 10
years before he started publicly selling
seeds yeah after he got it and he still
gets gets Flack for it yeah or whatever
so it seems like
um what happened is so now you've got
just so everybody knows you've got the
chem 91
you've got the CIS you've got the D and
you've got the one through the four yeah
so you've got seven
actual chem cuts
Cuts okay I'm circling that family and
if you include the super skunk amazing
I'm just talking about like what
supposedly came from the 13 seats okay
we're just limiting to that we're not
getting into any of its children or any
[ __ ] like that right so
um
you know so there's so there's a
situation there where
um you know we uh and the how we got
maybe I should say this how we got the D
is that in o6 when all this stuff was
happening
um chem dog didn't know no longer have
the dog
and he hadn't had it for a long time
um but when it started getting famous
and skunk VA started getting rep for
having this cut
he wanted it back
right yeah he wanted to have the cut
that everybody was talking about again
he hadn't had it in a long time right so
scum VA flies out to back east
and
um gives it to chem dog gives the dog
back to chem dog and he gets the D in
exchange and he comes back to California
and that's how me and I see Collective
and some others all got it yeah was dude
brought the D back yeah okay so
um
yeah you know I mean and and so now
there's so those are I think those are
like the the the basic facts of it yes
you know well um that's the basic human
story of it that's the basic human story
of it okay is that there was a couple
cuts from 91
uh that survived there was one cut from
2000 that survived and there was
um there's two cuts from o6 that
survived yes uh the one and the four are
still alive and verified the two and the
three seem to be gone they're dead yeah
um there's been some fake threes that
have popped up
um it's one of the issues with when
things that didn't get traded around so
much and they're only held by a few
people you know and some of those people
aren't the most responsible types
um accidents happen uh and so what we
have today as far as I know is the real
91 is alive yeah
the sis is dead dead and there are some
s1s that came from the CIS but the CIS
is dead uh that's what chem dog told me
and I no one seems to have it so yeah
um so of the of the 91 of the 91 pop the
91 is the only one that exists yeah of
the 2000 pop the D is the only thing
that exists yeah and of the 06 Pop
um the one and the four both exist yeah
right and out of that obviously there's
things we haven't talked about yet like
s1s and children of it and hybrids and
so on and so forth
um
you know uh
uh you know so I don't know I mean
you know that's kind of that's kind of
the as far as I know
um there's you know
there's four there's four living
original Kim cuts okay so now let's go
back to what we think they actually are
because I mean I think this is what most
people want to know
um we all know the stories we've all
heard that same rough same story uh
maybe with a little additions between
different people's points of view for a
long time so now we've got to figure out
what the [ __ ] are these things what was
the dog bud what was uh what likely was
it you know so let's talk about that
some of some of what uh so that's the
that's so the
the aspect around someone's talking
three CSI doesn't have three no he
doesn't shut up you know Matt Matt and I
are both really good friends with you he
definitely does he definitely does not
have it he had it at one point a long
time ago
um he had it at one point so you know
what's what's the best of them uh that's
preference based I suppose uh no
questions yeah I will I will just I will
just say my personal preference I think
the dog and the D are two of my all-time
favorite Cuts NATO likes the D and um
you like to deal a lot I you know I do I
do it's it's in it's in my talk it's in
my top just the tip
um you know and whenever I show people
the D they're impressed by it are they
impressed by it they are
you know they are impressed by it you
know so let's talk about let's talk
about the 91 what what was your theories
on 91 so
um
my theory on 91 is that we will never
ever ever know
what the hell it is
um the only thing that possibly offers
us an opportunity
uh is some kind of genetic testing
but it comes from so long ago that I
wonder if you'd even be able to compare
it to anything yeah I can't imagine that
comparing it to you'd have to compare
something and there's nothing to compare
it to for about so so you just so let's
put it this way right like I said before
lots of people were on dead tour selling
everything from burritos grilled cheese
LSD corduroy pants clothes everything
you could imagine to make money to stay
on dead tour and to go see shows and to
have a good time and to enjoy life right
Joe brand and Peabody were some of the
people that bought and sold weed on dead
tour
okay so they were constantly imagine
you're on dead tour for several months
right just and there was three tours a
year you know spring summer fall right
so you're on dead tour you're buying
you're buying pounds of weed you're
breaking them down into ounces and
quarters and half ounces or whatever and
you're slinging them yeah somewhere
amongst the Sea of weed that these guys
sold over the years one sack became
famous
they don't remember [ __ ]
right like they never even knew that
imagine imagine somebody came up to you
when you were a teenager and was like
Hey dude 15 years ago you sold me some
weed
and I got some really good [ __ ] out of
it yeah
right I mean maybe if you only sold one
or two strains because that's what you
grew you'd know but these guys weren't
these guys weren't Growers they were
Brokers yeah they bought weed and they
took it on tour and they sold eights and
quarters and a half ounces in Zips to
pay their way and to eat and have fun
and travel and whatnot right
so anybody saying that like oh we think
it comes from the Skelly or we think it
comes from this or we think uh it comes
from the puck or we think that's all
super conjecture it's all super stupid
in my opinion I know yes I've seen it
too I'll say this
um nothing that not the dog itself the
chem itself and none of its progeny look
like the puck it to me if people have a
problem understanding that it's because
they don't have a basic understanding of
afghanis like there are so many
different types of afghanis and it
doesn't it doesn't ever throw Puck
Thanos never a hash plant is so much
different than 1091 and I've seen so
lots and lots of phenos of ha of hash
plant children yeah and none of them
look like the dog yeah none none of them
look like the dog so I I have so here we
have you know I gave a basic outline of
the story that there's a bunch of [ __ ]
going on
right and uh and now we get into the
conjecture part right yeah the
conjecture part is like is
there's an aspect where you sometimes
the plants tell you what's going on
right uh and you know I've spent
countless hours
trying to figure out uh what's what's in
the dog
okay
um and by breeding with it it gives you
some Clues
okay so uh CSI and I
um both think that there's a good chance
that it is literally an S1 or a bag seed
yeah and the reason we think that is
because when he s-1s it
and he sells s1s it doesn't have a very
wide genetic base
right yeah it it throws a lot of
different types of potency but it
doesn't really throw a lot of different
types of looks correct correct you know
um the other thing too is that you know
the puck is short and squat and uh very
branchy uh the dog is very tall and
lanky they are totally two different
types of Bud structures completely
completely different plant structure
completely different budge structure uh
totally different Leaf structure a
little bit different terpenes
um you know I think honestly it's like
people are trying to shoehorn what it
could be
you know yeah um into what it is so one
thing I've noticed about trying to
figure out parentage over time the best
way I've ever found to do it and it's
not always it doesn't always work so
this is just a general way of speaking
but for chem 91 we're having no idea of
the parentage it holds true is when you
S1 it you're going to see those parental
phenos you're gonna see them and it
kicks fenos that have the same bud
structure in some of its progeny in the
s1s that look like sour and sour to me
is a typical Superstar type structure so
at some point in its history it's either
a pure [ __ ] Afghan tea that ended up
over here an Afghan T hybrid or a super
skunk hybrid in my opinion
um yeah so
what I can say about the like let's
start this this way what I can say about
the the dog is that by modern standards
it's not particularly pretty correct
yeah it's not particularly Frosty
it's kind of dark yep um and by looking
at it you would think it looks way
midsier than most modern wheat yes but
it has super rare potency yeah so as far
as effect it's an absolute champ
you know it can taste good uh it can
taste really good yeah um it can also
taste just okay
the potency is almost always there it's
really really hard to mess up the
potency
um
you know and so
you know we and and you know and so
these name games happen right like I
just mentioned some [ __ ] so the the the
the the chem dog has gone from chem dog
to dog to skunk VA cut to to chem to
chem 91 yeah the super skunk cut my
buddy got in Virginia has gone by Super
Skunk it's gone by mass Super Skunk
western Mass Super Skunk it's gone by
Skunk six
um and it may only be two of those
things it may only be super skunk and
skunk six and western Mass Superstar
might have been Antonio I mean I can say
that you know my buddy who picked it up
uh the guy told him it was super skunk
yeah it said super skunk on the label
and later on we talked to the person who
read it by our friend Johnny here and he
said that it was a super skunk hybrid of
sorts basically what it sounded like is
he was another kind of rainbow hippie
type dude and he had some various skunks
that he had gotten from Neville uh you
know
um and maybe sssc and he was crossing
them back and forth to each other and
the final thing he did was he crossed
that hybrid he had into Super Skunk yeah
and that's what became known as the
super skunk that is probably like uh
ital said earlier probably in sour as a
chem 91 hybrid I mean I I believe
strongly that it is I believe it that's
I believe I have and I I mean I have I
have some I don't have exact evidence
um I have some pretty strong evidence I
think yeah but so
so there you go I mean now we have now
we have
that's kind of the story
um and You Know It uh
you know there's conjecture what I will
say is that
I find it very hard to believe that the
chemsis the chem 91 the D and the one
and the four all came from the same
hybrid yeah
they're different enough that it's that
there it seems to me uh this is where
this is where it would be amazing to
have actual like human style DNA
analysis yeah where you you know that
was the big hope of uh the company that
won't be named uh his is that they would
be able to you know take these
long-running things and clear up these
family relationships
um so far that isn't the case
um you know I believe that uh
you know these things the thing is is
that people are talking about can we
talk about some new stuff Chasing Ghosts
these aren't ghosts uh these things are
some of the backbones of modern cannabis
of what we're going to be talking about
from the beginning anyways like yeah you
know
um so you know they're and you know and
and back in the 90s especially in 1991
um there wasn't very many seed companies
there wasn't as nearly as many places to
get things so what it comes down to is
you know
um a lot of these things that came out
in the 90s
um became the backbone and even if you
don't recognize them or have never had
them you've probably had tons of things
that they're in yeah
and let me let me throw this in there
too
so what when I when I when I research
stuff I break things down I try to use
like a logic tree like from you know
philosophy logic like you know you learn
in college
um
and we're still all starting on this
premise that this guy that we know that
sells weed
that was running low on weed went home
kept some weed for a guy he had only met
once
and sent him the same exact weed that he
smoked in Colorado or wherever it was it
that he had smoked it it sent him back
the last of that weed and the weed that
he gave him the first time didn't have
any seeds the bag of weed that he had at
home didn't have any seeds but somehow
that bad that Kim dog got had 13 seeds
in it so there's a lot of a lot of room
for human error in all of this you know
um so we've got to start it is a faulty
premise from the beginning and and if
you try to break it down logically
you're like oh yeah yeah Joe Brandon
Peabody were dudes in their 20s selling
weed to a teenager yeah
you know yeah I mean that's kind of and
then dude smoked the weed and they found
some seeds you know
um I uh
so this is where we get together this is
where we'll get to conjecture yeah right
and we'll mix some conjecture with facts
but this isn't I I said everything
before and it was kind of basic because
I just wanted to kind of give the
timeline of of back of fact yeah that's
generally accepted right so now we can
kind of go into what we think
is in this stuff yeah um
so I tend to think
um and CSI backs me up is um is that
most of the stuff out there
are hybrids of the dog or hybrids of
chem 91 yes right
um so
you know uh when I
people don't know this very well but and
I don't this isn't an insult don't take
this the wrong way but after
um after my buddy had given chemdog the
super skunk the super skunk was
legendary for herming yeah okay so in
um
in 1994 uh
the super skunk had hermed all over uh
chem dog [ __ ] yeah and chem dog called
up my buddy in California and was raving
about these hybrids
that he had found after the Super Skunk
could accidentally pollinated the dog
and and just to inject this here this is
where I Think Jesus was born in this
General and he so he he loved it so much
and granted he's only you know 18 19 at
the time or whatever yeah
um he loved it so much he started
growing these hybrids exclusively
instead of the dog yeah in 1994. okay
um and so
this is the weed that he was selling and
this is the weed that was getting passed
out that dudes were collecting seeds
from
yeah okay that they later popped
and that became diesel one and two yeah
and then something in their room hermed
again
and of those seeds people found what
became sour
yeah
right uh there's a there's a there's a
bunch of there's a bunch of [ __ ]
that goes along with that or whatever
but that's
um you know uh it's hard because you
know people like you know klopp uh who's
definitely involved in the sour and
everything like that yeah at the time
you know uh chem dog and my buddy from
Staten Island swears that no one else on
the East Coast had it yeah
he wouldn't give it to anyone on the
East Coast so you start to get different
people involved that start to claim
different things at different times
um most of us obviously weren't there
you know yeah so uh
you know it what are you gonna say about
those type of things
right it's another one of those things
where people start to create certainty
on a series of accidents that happened
when they were young and also partying
yeah you know yeah and now they want to
make it all intentional and uh you know
and so as a result
you know I can see in real Sour I can
see the 91 and the super skunk yeah I
personally believe that's the case like
you know chem dog called my buddy and
was raving about how much he liked
growing the hybrids that it accidentally
got made yeah and that he was filling up
his rooms with him and that's all he was
growing
and he told him that in 1994. 1994 is
the year that you know klopp you know
that weasel and Bondo and these guys are
getting this weed that they're finding
the seeds in
you know yeah um
so uh there you go
as far as that goes I actually believe
that the D is a chem 91 by Super Skunk
hybrid yeah I believe it very strongly
um that would make D either a sister to
sour or if it depends on which Super
Skunk was used because I know there were
more than one in that group I mean I I
because you know uh we did this project
called the Superdog where we tried to
take the density and the potency of the
chem dog and blend it with the the look
and the frost and the flavor of the
super skunk and so I you know uh my
buddies it's from Staten Island and I
worked on it for a number of years so
I've seen a [ __ ] ton of chem Super Skunk
hybrids yeah like a [ __ ] ton I've known
a lot of them and so to me like I can
just see both parents in the chemd yeah
you know can I prove it until we have
perfect genetic testing no
it's just we can never have perfect
genetic testing unless we have the
baselines which we don't I mean it's you
know it should be possible it's it's not
possible it could be possible like you
know like human DNA they could tell that
um you're not a sister you're a daughter
yeah we could do we could see some
relations like that but we could never
go back and say you know like what I'm
just saying like from from the from the
91 eventually you should be able to tell
her these sisters or children yeah from
the 91 for sure you know because we at
least have that yeah right and so
um you know the and the reason why I
think that is because sometimes the D
smells like super skunk when you crack
the jar yeah I think that dead rotten
body nastiness that everybody always
halitosis that they always talk about
that's kind of a rank skunk kind of
thing yeah uh the D Herms sometimes like
crazy in week three and four which the
super skunk was famous for doing yeah in
the D's case it's sterile pollen and the
super skunks case it was super live yeah
um but I I grew you know I still have
the the chem the chem dog I've grown it
for I don't know 24 years now or
something I grew the the super skunk for
10. um I think that they you know I
think that the sour the base of sour is
chem super skunk and I think that it's
very likely that
um that D is pure
uh dog and super skunk and and the one
that can that nobody ever mentions and
I've been fighting to get people to give
it its uh space in the family tree is
Jesus which I think is the pure Super
Skunk just an asthma yeah I mean the the
you know the the diesel is um
you know like I said the the super skunk
through live pollen both early and late
yeah
when you don't make seeds
um after you have a pollination of uh
you know of of [ __ ] it takes a good four
to six weeks for that seed to become
ripe oh yeah yeah right so
if you've got some late harm
unless you let that thing ride and ride
and ride and ride
you're gonna have immature seats
I don't think diesel looks more like
anything at all like d and even in the
s1s there's no D anything in it someone
had mentioned that so I mean I guess
what I'm saying is is that the point I
was trying to make is that for for
chemdog and these guys to be pulling out
tiger stripe seeds at eight nine ten
weeks uh a lot of times the SS was was
pollinating them through Herms two three
weeks into bloom yeah and that we why by
week eight nine ten they were ready yeah
right so it's very possible that jesel
is an S1 of the straight Super Skunk
yeah and doesn't have any chem in it
um
oh my gosh
well no there's some good questions come
on so we need to finish with with what
the one through four are all that stuff
first though so so yeah so so to me
um the uh
that's what I think the D is I can't
prove it
um I would bet money though
that money and how it breeds and how it
smells and how it looks I think it's a
straight dog SS hybrid yeah uh I saw
some people mention the one through the
four
um do you think it has some nl5 Haze in
it
I think that's very likely uh after
after seeing the one I think I think it
is the quintessential example of a nl5
haze dominant Fino
in the chem one through four line like
it's more it's very little Kim to me
it's very nl5 hazy yeah and so you know
there's there's an aspect to it where
it's like I just like to say this
because
once you get on the forums and once you
start writing stuff and once you start
chatting about things you're sort of
locked into whatever you wrote yeah and
I think that's been a problem for chem
dog yeah
um because people asked him what he
thought and he gave what he remembered
and then people wanted like deep deep
thoughts yeah on how it all went down
and I don't I think he kind of spouted
off as best he remembered and then
people wanted a lot of information he
didn't have yeah right it's indisputable
uh they're two of my favorite cuts that
these Cuts came from dude
yeah you know however they were formed
they exit that's the important part they
exist they're in the community they've
made amazing hybrids they're pretty
awesome they're super potent they're
nice
um you know the the interesting part
about the one and the four the one is
crazy it takes like 12 or 13 weeks yeah
okay
um the four takes 12-ish weeks usually
we have a buddy pip
um that you know he takes it 84 90 days
every time yeah okay it grows long
running Spears
um and so it's really interesting
because the D is a very short squat
Afghan line green Super Skunk looking
thing you know uh the dog is a very
weird looking non-frosty Afghan uh the
four is a super Frosty Long Spears like
your arm 12 weaker so how do you get a
nine weeker and a 10-weeker and a
13-weeker and a 12-weeker and stuff that
wants to be two feet tall and stuff that
wants to be six feet tall
um I mean it's possible and the one's
all mercy and dominant like no Cami
dialect type stuff at all you know it
doesn't you know and so what I what I
think is that um
the D and the dog are different the dog
is the chem 91 and the D is the chemd so
um so basically what we have is we have
these these various plants and to
breeders
um they don't look the same
uh and they don't
um they don't breathe the same
and their s1s don't come out the same so
you would expect if you did a bunch of
s1s of the chem dog that you would start
to see D finals or four phenos yeah or
this or that if they're if they're
sisters and it's all in there yeah you
would expect to see those things you
would see those females you don't see
Jack that looks like any of those no you
really don't and CSI has run out
hundreds of them yeah and other people
have run out probably thousands of csis
s1s too you know and so you know I I
think that you know I think that a lot
of them are from that
you know that dog SS combo yeah you know
um and so
you know I mean the good part about it
is is that the one is not is alive but
it's not really well circulated because
it doesn't look pretty enough and it
takes it takes 13 weeks but the four and
the dog and the D are pretty well passed
out and so lots of people have had them
um there's not really fake so before
yeah I've never really seen people pass
things yeah there's you know there's
been one or two fakes of the of the
actual dog but it's not particularly
common the D
there's a lot of fakes yeah tons there's
a lot of fakes
um and so
there's some chaos behind all that
um I don't know if we want to get into
all into all that but
um You Know It uh
and what I think
and this is not knocking Greg or
anything or chemdog excuse me by
anything like that
um is that uh I think the the fakes of
the D are all sisters
personally I think he had a bag of dog
Super Skunk hybrids
right yeah and when he lost the D he
went back in that same little bag
and pop stuff
and I think those and because because
the thing is that's weird is that like
three of the so-called fakes
um came people swear come directly from
chemdog yeah
then that's probably the case I mean the
people that I know that got it from him
there's been a few people I'm pretty
sure I can trust that got things from
him labeled as D that were totally
different they were they were I mean
they all swear they got it directly from
dude yeah and it ends up not being the
not being the original d yeah it looks
like the D smells like the D doesn't a
lot most of them don't grow like the D
if you know how the D grows and they
just relax structure they typically lack
the the the distinct flavor and the and
the potency yeah but they look extremely
close especially in a bag or in a jar is
dried weed yeah you know
um and so you know there's
there's at least three maybe four fake
D's yeah there's a lot there's a there's
quite a bit and I think those D's that
got passed out later or bought from
bought from chem dog or whatever
those things got trade baited all over
the place yeah they got exploded
everywhere everyone wanted to trade the
Deep
you know and so the real D kind of got
buried
um the least circulated of the D's yeah
it's the least circulated because and I
mean this is this is this is starting
this is going to get kind of political
or whatever but like
I mean we can just say it that
um most of there was a time where most
of the people in Colorado
uh that our chemfam didn't have the real
D no it was the uh Kim CSS one mostly
they went they went through two fake D's
yeah and they didn't even realize that
they had fake d
no you'd have to know to know they
didn't they didn't know and so they bred
with it and they traded it and they grew
it and sold it and all this different
stuff and it wasn't
um
it wasn't uh it wasn't it yeah you know
I mean in fact I uh I went to an emerald
cup once and I had a fresh jar of real d
ude okay and there's all these people I
don't need to name them there's all
these people that are like [ __ ]
patting me on the back and they're being
like dude you did the most amazing job
with this wheat yeah this is
unbelievable the flavor and the potency
you got out of this weed is just what
the [ __ ] did you do yeah right and it
turns out uh even though I was kind of
proud of myself for a minute it turns
out that
the reason why they were so blown away
by the flavor and the potency was that I
had the right cut
and they did not have the right cut they
had a difference and people were trading
all these different bags of wheat around
that weren't the right cut and they were
amazed when they smoked the real one
yeah you know and that and so and this
and this cut uh and you know it caused
some embarrassment
because some of these people are you
know chem fam or whatever yeah are tied
in or yeah or whatever the case may be
you know and so you know you're on
you're on Instagram and you're
pontificating or whatever about like how
you know everything yeah and then all of
a sudden you don't have the real D and
you try and you're using any crosses
yeah and you get the real D and then it
turns out no that's not real either yeah
right and so those fakes just got traded
so much that they drowned out the real D
they also look similar in pictures and
they look similar as dried weed they're
much easier to tell when you're growing
them side by side
and they're much easier to tell if you
actually have a jar of real D to smoke
next to them and there's also the the
um little bit that the the fake D or the
chem CSS one kicks live pollen whereas
the the KMD doesn't kick life you know I
mean I've had I've had the chemd since
06.
I mean maybe it produced a seed in that
amount of time but yeah um so I'll
answer that when my cut is super healthy
uh it almost never variegates
if you can't get your D to not variegate
it's not the real D yeah there you go
there's like they're they're people some
call some of them dirty D certainly when
it gets hungry I'll I'll make people
laugh and uh it likes calmag yeah it
does it's the the chems are the chems
are strong eaters and so sometimes if
you're growing organically or whatever
else and you know you have some
unavailability going on it can you know
it can variegate
um I have pictures of it variegating uh
there's one on my page but when it's
when it's Tip-Top shape and totally
healthy you can really look really close
and you can see slight variegation on a
leaf here and there but other than that
you really can't see it how how prone to
um Fox tailing is your cut
not
yeah see that's the other the main trait
of the the campus ss1 if you're if your
shit's real fluffy and fox tailing it's
most likely not going to be the one that
people use yeah the original and so
there's a you know there's I mean
there's I don't know it's what's what's
hard about it is you want to tell the
truth
um uh the the finest chemd i've smoked
it it's a nice cut it tests super high
it's not the real D at all and and also
also take into account that it's been
tissue cultured it has different
hormones in it it's it's it
the expression is going to totally be
different so it would be hard to tell
I'm not I I you know are you more
skeptical on it I it's not the D okay
that's not it's not doesn't mean it's
bad I haven't seen it so it doesn't mean
it's bad I mean I I've had friends that
have grown it that have bought it from
finest and run it in licensed Gardens
and stuff like that here in Mendo yeah
it's a nice cut it gets you super baked
it's not the real G yeah you know
um so you know there's and
man I don't know I mean this is the
point where it's like you want to tell
stories and then you're like okay well
what toes do I step on yeah yeah and
whose toes do I step on and this is why
the the chem story up until this date
has only been told certain ways because
like you tell this story like a hundred
percent as you as you can best tell it
with all the info that we have available
it does step on toes regardless even if
you don't want to it just happens yeah
you know like Joe Brandon people they
might get mad at me for saying that the
first time they smoked real dog was in
2006 yeah
you know
but it's for a better story the other
way but it's true they did you know like
people are asking them about all this
and that and everything they sold a bag
they're very important to the story
yeah you know in the sense that like
they kind of got it going but then they
don't tie in again for another 15 years
or something
you know so it's like people gonna get
mad and send me some DMS about whatever
you know because you know and and you
know there's an aspect to it too where
it's like
you know then there's people that are
you know approaching chem dog and
approaching others they want to breed
with the Deep they want to breed with
the chem Cuts they want uh you know they
want uh they don't want to get [ __ ] on
for it they want to be chem fam approved
right yeah and some people are like you
know uh and some you know and so they
Grease the wheels with money and they
make it happen
yeah and I'm not blaming dude for that
or anything like that like I I'm not
trying to you know it's hard to make it
you know somebody Out Here for a Pimp
well you know I mean there's there's you
know obviously there's certain lines you
shouldn't cross
but how you monetize things and how you
do certain things like that like I don't
really think anything dude has done has
crossed any lines
um
so you know yeah the CSI chems are
totally worth hunting through yeah we
said that like 90 times in this thing
very very very much so the one thing
that the chem the chem 91 does more than
almost any other strain
it throws potency in all of its
Offspring yeah it does whether it's
outcrosses whether it's the s1s there's
some s ones that are as potent or even
more potent than the mother cut yeah
you know
um and so yeah they're absolutely worth
hunting they're they're worth hunting
from CSI they're worth hunting from
skunk VA
um you know it if you have the real cut
you can make some really nice really
nice things you know exactly um you know
and then there's preferences too you
know like as as well like I tend to
think that the 91 is one of my favorite
cuts of all time I have and I made a
nice one yeah and you know and and I I
have some good friends like Matt that
aren't into it you know they they give
it respect for its potency and its power
and it's and its place but it's not
something they would be choosing to
smoke every day yeah no it [ __ ] me up
in a different way yeah you know and so
um I mean maybe we'll maybe we'll maybe
we'll say some [ __ ] about the D just
because it it I mean maybe it should be
said right yeah so
you know and I actually I think it's
killing me I don't I'm not you're
telling me not to look and I'm trying I
know I'm sorry that was too good anyway
um
and I think at times you know uh chem
dog hasn't been super trustworthy uh uh
not himself but like with some of the
people he was making deals with and
they're
um you know there's aspects where I
think maybe he gave out things
you know he like you know so
I mean uh you know uh when uh you know
people don't know this because uh
um
yeah you know uh as far as I know uh
skunk VA uh has the real D yeah um as
far as I know skunk PA is a really cool
dude and he's been married for a long
time I don't have anything but good
things to say about him
um Lucky Dog Seed Co I think you'll find
good stuff in his work he uses nice cuts
yeah in most of his stuff you know so
he's been super transparent with me he's
any question I've ever had he's been one
of the most forthcoming out of all those
dudes
I think some of his some some of his
interviews and stuff have been quite
honest from his perspective yeah um so I
got nothing but good no nothing but good
things to say about
um about that you know I I will say you
know mentioning the Colorado thing that
um
almost all of those guys out there had
fake d
right and they were convinced it was
real D because they'd never had real D
and they got it from Greg they got it
and they'll still argue until they're
blue in the face that they had the real
D that it never was the fake one
yeah they get pissed yeah yeah
um you know but I mean you know I I
mean that's the thing too is it's like
and then because it got famous all these
people want to jump in and you know they
and sometimes like you know you get paid
or you make some deal with someone and
then it goes bad and you don't want to
be embarrassed and so there's a lot of
shenanigans that have gone on around it
um you know and uh you know real chemd
is much better than the finest cut I
mean that's all all life but that's my
speculation I I would put I would put
the real D in my probably top five
all-time strains that I like a lot for
me because it's everything though is is
so subjective like we could never say
that like everyone's gonna think this
one's better than the other it's just
kidding it's a can't do that with weed
no but I mean I will say we talked about
Matt and I talked about it a little bit
on our last live uh you know I I brought
some real d a few times to our uh to our
some of our Gatherings that we would
have during the emerald cup outside
and it you know it it put a bunch of
experienced smokers on the ground yeah
why did people out you know it really I
mean there were some people that were
staring at the ceiling on the couch for
a number of hours off a couple of bong
hits some people thought about going to
bed early uh you know it was it was
unusually strong doesn't mean the finest
cut is bad I'm not saying that you know
a lot of times people have this idea
that if it's not real it can't be good
yeah and that's a different subject yeah
you know so it can be it can be not real
and good
absolutely
so
um there's an aspect to it where you
know I don't know maybe we'll throw some
shade or whatever but
um you know uh in Colorado
um you know a lot of people don't know
this and they think that that he goes
back [ __ ] forever in chem fam or
whatever but you know
um you know Duke Diamond paid chem dog a
bunch of money for the right to grow
strengths yeah and he got
um he got the D and the doll and the
chem dog uh and whatnot from chemdog and
he paid I don't know like 30 grand or
something like that that's how the story
goes that's how the story he paid a
cheap paid a chunk of money a chunk of
money for the right to have the cuts and
the right to breed with the cuts without
a bunch of [ __ ] yeah you know
basically paid for vouching yeah pay to
pay for vouching right yeah and so a lot
of people think that he's he's has some
deep tires been involved with the chems
for a long time
um he never came into contact with them
I don't think until he came out to
Colorado and worked with your buddy
Maddie Lee right yeah correct he he
never I don't think he'd ever maybe he'd
smoked them before but he never had them
he never had access to them and when he
wanted them he couldn't get them from
anyone out there that had him so he
bought them the only one I know he had
early was snow dog that's it no dog yeah
so
um
you know so then you know he ends up he
ends up breeding uh those cuts into
everything because it's kind of one of
the things when he started his own seed
company that was like he was rocking the
headbands and the chems super hard okay
so my buddy uh uh IC Collective he had
lost the D and he had just been out
visiting Colorado and he was like well
why don't you send it to me
yeah like sure so they send it to him
and he grows it out and he calls him up
and says you don't have real d
this is the this is what we call the
Bundy sis S1 yeah not real d
not even close yeah okay so for two
years uh three years something like that
uh those guys had spent all this time
breeding the the D into everything they
had
and then they quietly had to change it
to chem sis yeah they never intended on
on breeding with chemsis and I'll give
him credit for that he did actually he
did change it that's I that's all credit
because he most people wouldn't even do
that he did he did change it
um you know and then but it turned out
that Peabody and Duke diamond and and
these other dudes out there they all had
fake d
yeah it was it was Bundy S1 right and
chem says Bundy it was S1 of the real
chemsis they called the Bundy cut
because Bundy was one of chemdog's
growing partners
uh and one of the people that a lot of
the growing was actually done by him
um he's passed away now
um but it was kind of named for him yeah
he's he's one of the other silent people
in the whole history of Kim dog that
doesn't get talked about a lot but I
think he had more to do with the the
genetics aspect and the crossing and any
intentional Crossing that would have
been done would probably have been done
by him he had he had a bunch to do about
it but he was like a lot of people you
know there's uh there's the there's the
forward guy that gets the fame and then
there's some people behind them that are
doing a bunch of the work too that don't
get as famous for whatever reason
um and so one of the good things about
that is that
that schmuck joint breath uh tricked I
mean I think I can safely say oh yes
Mark he's got to be one of the rudest
[ __ ] on IG yeah uh he's a total
[ __ ] bag but he bought he he tricked pea
bud out of the dog and the chemd with
Promises of breeding and Seed sales and
collaboration and all that and then he
turned around and just started selling
Cuts as fast as he could mother them and
never gave Peabody damn thing and never
gave peabot a damn thing and told him to
[ __ ] off and die basically
um and he bled some friendships everyone
that he got everyone that got the D from
that dude was fake yep he was selling
three to five hundred dollar cuts of
fake D yeah and that's how [ __ ] goes
um and the the interesting part and this
is the reason why I believe that all the
fake D's are sisters to the D
is that at least three of them that were
absolutely positive came from chemdog
himself yeah and they're all very
similar to the D
right so yeah
um you know to to chem dog he's never
been the type to be so militant about
what strain it is when you were buying
chem dog weed it was chem dog weed
because it was from chemdog
he used to call the D chem dog
you know you're buying chemdot weed this
is the chem dog weed I have here's chem
dog wheat yeah you know so for people
that are like sticklers about things
that's not your guy you know
um
and so uh he was both the pre and the
Kentucky skunk guy uh he was a lying
you know he had the big tattoo on his
neck uh he was super rude to people he
was dishonest he lied he stole he
cheated uh he was very unpleasant human
being yeah he's in Oklahoma I think
somewhere likely failing
yeah I mean whatever he was he was one
of the rudest and shittiest people that
I encountered on IG yeah for those that
don't know you it is very hard to get
not so to see anything about anyone that
isn't a nice like the the only nice
thing you could say about them I have
rarely ever seen him yeah I mean yeah he
just is just I don't know just his
General human being but you know so so
that's the thing is that there was a
number of people that got a hold of Kim
and there's some chem people uh like my
buddy from Staten Island he's retired
now but who really wanted to keep it
very close yeah and you know and it got
out and it caused a bunch of Guff that
it got out like a lot of other strains
and
you know so the chemist as far as I know
and I talked to chem dog about this has
been dead for a long time yeah there are
several s1s of it supposedly that exists
the real D is alive
and at least three or four fakes
yep you know if you have What's called
the Dirty D and you like I said before
if you can't get the variegation to go
away it's fake
and they look very similar no one is
going to be able to tell you that you
have the the real d by pictures
yeah it's very difficult
um it's you know when you smoke it you
know
you know yeah I've grown some of them
side by side with the real D and you can
see significant growth differences
as long as you have a control group like
the real one to compare it to
yeah
you know
um absolutely uh I believe that
um it's 91 SS and it was all accidental
Herms yeah the sour story and the chem
story is All accidental hermaphrodism
there is no intentional anything in it
yeah it's all accidents
you know yeah I mean uh I never heard
Bodhi say a bad word about anyone I
don't really say a bad word about anyone
I just literally think that like joint
breath is one of the three worst people
I've met on IG yeah
um he's terrible and if you read his
comments and how he talks to people and
how he breaks his word and various
things I don't even want to talk about
it well he just openly racist and he
just is he just has all kinds of
terrible qualities
um and so I figured I'd mention that
because he literally turned around and
started a clone business selling uh
chemdog and D Cuts yeah as soon as he
got the moms big enough that was likely
his intention the whole time
um you know it's not a stupid question
someone just asked are the sour and D
sisters yeah no I think it's a great
question I think it's a great question I
don't think so but only because
um
we know we know from the story of the
sour that they got beans out of the
they got beans out of this weed from
from chem dog and it was it was very
likely it was 91 SS yeah so at that
point it's already a hybrid
right
um it wouldn't be it wouldn't be the SS
and the dog making seeds yeah and then
they grew up those seeds and which
called the diesel one and the diesel two
and then those things hermed
and out of that Herm comes the sour yeah
so do I think they're straight sisters
no do I think they're very closely
related yes I do so there's one little
part we hadn't gotten into because it's
kind of part of the story but not and
it's more of a recent type thing it
sounds like and this is this is putting
together stuff from skunkier from his
mentor me
Caleb not to all of us really and
everyone in our our can Illuminati group
um it sounds like at some point what was
given out and taken pictures of and
hybridized as mass Super Skunk might not
be the same original Super Skunk that
came from vam was traded so there is
that little Nuance so we should we
should say this too so there's an aspect
to it where like people don't like to
admit that they've that they've lost
things yeah and so you can go look on
after this show or whatever you could go
look and see those famous pics that
skunk VA posted of the super skunk yeah
uh from 95 96 all that type of stuff and
it looks very sour like very long Spears
tall lanky stretchy those type of buds
uh the super skunk that got passed
around Massachusetts and the stuff that
was in the High Times is a much wider
much thicker much shorter Afghani type
yeah and so I think I can't say for
certain like I said it's conjecture but
I think that you know
the super skunk itself and its children
and its hybrids produced a variety of
seeds and chem dog probably had a bag of
this seed and a bag of that seed and a
bag of some of this
and people have tried to recreate it
yeah there was also some busts involved
you know there was some other issues
there was various things
um you know and uh you know it um
you know I felt I tell are you from that
from that um crew with Camillo in them
sorry one second
because that that is one question I've
always had whether the one that's in
diesel is the one that's in sour there
was a couple there was supposedly a six
and an eight yeah you know
um we got I guess what we you would
classify as the six I suppose although
we didn't find that out until much later
um
but uh but that was the one that got
that got passed it out I'm not going to
answer which sour is better and which
one is the real deal we could do an
entire sour episode talking about it
um oh okay yeah
well that guy is super I mean yeah the
hard part about in there the hard part
about the sour crew is that you know is
that people have different memories of
things you know and weasel and vondo and
man some of these guys they don't all
agree on everything
weasel can't tell the same story I love
the dude he's super cool super nice I
love his listening to him talk about
history and stuff but he's had a very
hard time being consistent in his
stories from one day to the next
literally like there was a podcast maybe
a week in between the two where he told
completely different stories about the
history of sour so when when I going
through history and stuff when I see
that I usually toss it all out because
if it's an unreliable narrator as far as
being able to remember the story well
you know consistently I toss it I will
say this
um about this the sour thing is that
because the sour came out of a bunch of
hermaphroditic weed yeah okay I believe
there was a couple cuts even early on
right and then Bondo who was one of the
guys that actually lived in the
apartment where the accident happened
right yeah when he moved West he took
some seeds with him from that initial
thing West and sprouted and sprouted
some and kept a cut in Southern
California yeah
um according to him so I think you know
I don't think that there was just one I
think there was two or three
um and then uh
You Know It uh
it became the most popular weed in
America for 10 years
and then [ __ ] res named a strainer
and named his named his personal strain
after it sadly so who had the real one
who had the right one everybody thinks
the real Sour Diesel is the whatever one
they saw first yeah generally speaking
you know no it's true yeah I can say I
can say this about the sour I got the
sour in 2000.
and I've never lost it
I don't know which one it is yeah but
I've had it for 22 years now
so
um you know is it the first is it one of
the couple you know
um luckily for us most of the diesel
cuts are nice
yeah
you know when people talk about real
when people talk oh I can take trace it
back to 95 I can this I can that and you
should buy it for five thousand dollars
a pound because it's
you know that's a lot of marketing yeah
to me
but the sour story is confusing
you know and again it's more confusing
every day when people when newer people
enter the scene and claim old Heritage
on their sour cut and you know a lot of
people are still the past five six years
and they don't know these people are new
it just conflates it more and over the
years ago it's gotten even [ __ ]
crazier yeah and and so there's a thing
too where it's like there's a lot of
people that had sour back in the day
and they got rid of sour
yeah and then they got it back
and it wasn't the same one
so it's very difficult the vast majority
of people I mean I I see uh you know I
see people chatting about this or
whatever I mean you know if people
remember I'm not even calling dude out
but if people remember you know J plant
speaker went through a two or three year
period where he thought that like seeds
you know only growing from seed was the
way and the Clones were bunk you know it
was very you had probably had he's
deleted them all now but he's had
hundreds posts about it he was super
into seeds the market changed on him and
you know in 2017 or something he got
that sour back
you know and so he he's had the sound
he's had the sour about four years yeah
does that mean that he didn't he had it
in the past at some point you know sure
but most people had to get it back
because they moved on to other [ __ ] yeah
and that's how a lot of things get lost
is people are like oh I don't need that
right now homies got it I'll just get it
back whenever
and then they keep getting back the
thing that they don't remember yeah
you know so I mean
I have this thing and it's expensive and
it kind of sucks at times but I like to
keep weed that I like
yeah
you know and so some of these things
I've just kept for a long time like if I
lost my sour I would never
be able I I all the ones I've gathered
aren't the one that I have yeah
you know um if I lost the real D
um I mean I know a couple people thank
God but like if I was trying to find it
like one of you guys out there in the
community it would be really [ __ ]
hard yeah because there's more fakes
than not
um you know and so you know AJ doesn't
even the this the cut that AJ grows and
and moves Now isn't the cut that people
got as AJ's 20 years ago yeah no I I can
speak to that personally at the um first
Adam Dunn cup when he brought out his AJ
sour we were all standing around just
expecting because it was one of the
first times he'd come out in quite a
while and he was there with uh JJ and he
brought out this jar and said this is my
sour so we're all kind of hanging around
it let's see what his [ __ ] what AJ's
grown sour looks like and I shoot you
not everybody just kind of took a whiff
away
it was it was not it was not sour as we
know it it was very very different yeah
I mean it's been a really bad cure it
may have been any number of things but
yeah I don't know I mean there's people
that have the modern AJ sour cut
yeah and there's people that have an AJ
Sauer cut from long ago
and they're not the same no um um Big
Worm had a older AJ sour cut and it was
dank it smelled like sour you know but
I've had I have some health AJ's new
sour and it is not the same thing people
are saying does anyone else have and
work the same sour that you do I don't
know
how how could I know yeah you know I
mean I I don't know I mean people call
my headband not so's headband because I
seem to be one of the only people that
kept it yeah it's not like it's mine but
people are trying to figure out some way
to name it and had there's like eight
headbands or something so
um you know it uh
you know there's an aspect to it where
um
what's real yeah
you know do you uh you know there's
there's got to be five or six years ago
uh with Matt and some of our friends on
our Discord and stuff like that and back
and forth we started chatting about
aspects and they kept asking me which
sour is it
is it the choco is it the res cut is it
the AJ is it the the East Coast Sour
Diesel is it the shroomy cut it Amish is
it yeah there's so many yeah and I was
like I don't [ __ ] know I have no idea
I have no idea what you're talking about
what are you what are you talking about
because I never got any of those because
I got this hour long ago and never lost
it so I thought I had this hour so why
the [ __ ] would I trade someone else for
it yeah exactly right so I start
collecting these things and I get the
New York City Diesel and I get the East
Coast Sour Diesel and I get the the
Amish and this and this and this and
this and I'm like okay I'm gonna figure
out which one mine is yeah and I grow
them all out and none of them are mine
so I was like oh
you know it seems like the East Coast
sour diesel or what some people call the
East Coast Sour Diesel and the choco are
the same yeah I was the one who named it
choco cut and it was only because when
people had asked me like hey what which
cut is yours choco had the best
representation and grow and so they
called for that matter and it was the
best representation to grow that's the
same cut that is the um that that uh uh
the devil's Harvest crew Scott reach and
all those guys it's the same cut that
they run as sour and it's the same most
likely the same cut that CSI uses itself
as well Amish and shroomy are the same
cut right I have no clue those are two
I've never wrote so I mean I you know I
I tend to like you know this might sound
self-serving or whatever I like the one
that I have the best yeah and I like the
one I had best you know I I like that
one the best I do think that the one
that my our buddy pip gave me that was
ecsd yeah it was the mother of the Death
Star yeah
um that one I didn't like as much but
yeah I uh
um I like that one a whole bunch yeah
that's the people say S1 you're sour the
reason why sour is notorious
for not throwing pollen yeah you know
it's horrible you can cross things to it
right
um and uh Amish is the Pennsylvania one
yeah and it got called Amish because of
that
um so there's you know we've had friends
that have reversed the sour and gotten
like 15 seats yeah if that if we've had
friends reverse the sour multiple times
and completely [ __ ] fail and people
that are pretty proficient at reversing
not just me but others yeah and yeah
it's just not and CSI various other
friends
um a pip you know reverse some and
literally got like a personal amount
yeah and reversing stuff and having it
fail is expensive
so you know it's very difficult to so
there's and and you know and sour is a
wide ver is you know it's like everyone
how do I put this the right way everyone
claims to like diversity
but they still want to find the fire in
every pack yeah so you start selling
some Sour hybrids and start throwing a
bunch of a bunch of junk
amongst the gold and people are pissed
yes because they don't want to buy a
hundred seeds to find a couple that are
fire
yeah you know so sour has been a
difficult breeder and it doesn't S1 it
doesn't seem any of the cuts S1 well
yeah which is why you rarely ever see
sour s1s for sale yeah if you do you
should probably know [ __ ] side eye in
that [ __ ] and most often the the sour
cuts that are sold are high that are
that are reversed or something was
reversed onto them yeah it takes pollen
fine yeah and no mix you know I make
seeds it makes hella seed with that blue
bonnet process I did it makes it yeah
but you know making seed of itself not
so not not so simple not so not so
simple as far as that though
um I you know honestly dude uh there's
there's another question
I uh people think I hoard I don't hoard
um but I also sucks at passing I don't I
I don't I don't suck at passing either
what I suck at is I just don't I I don't
like to mail
yes I'm very I'm very in person
yeah like if if we can meet that's good
if I have to mail you something it's I'm
not good I'm just trying to beat it
truck stops I don't get it you know and
so people are saying death Coast diesel
death Coast Diesel from pip pip I'll say
this in in uh in full disclosure I'm
biased because pip is my good buddy yes
both of our Good Buddies
um so take that as you will but I will
say that his saurine
um there's a number of his hybrids that
a lot of fire has been found yeah
um yeah
his Rubber City his saurine some of his
other sour work
um you know he's my good friend he cares
he has real nice Cuts uh and um yeah
he's just serious about provenance as
any of us like he is very serious about
it getting it right and and but yeah
there's a there's a bunch of people
um and I I don't wanna I don't want to
judge people right but there's a bunch
of people that monetize their access to
Cuts yeah and sell cuts to whoever to
make money I've never sold cuts to make
money
uh I give cuts to my personal friends
so people would be like oh you're a
[ __ ] you don't give your headband out
and I'll be like what do you mean like
half my crew lived off the headband for
years yeah you know like if you're my
personal friend and we're good buddies
and or you know whatever like I tend to
share
if we're not like and you're like hey
can I just buy this thing off you I've
just I've just never monetized Cuts I've
given and I'm not even judging I'm just
saying that like I typically give I
typically trade with people that I think
are like have have a good heart and you
read the same way that I do
you know
um and so you know that's it's I don't
really sell Cuts I'm not I'm not hyping
that's the other part of it right is
that I don't I don't like I'm not hyping
it for you to buy anything from me yeah
you know
um original D is a tough one to find
info on because uh I did a live feed
just trying to show how to to find info
on something and use that as an example
I can't trace the the uh day record I
can't trace it I can't trace it back
past a certain point and it's it's
frustrating because it's one of my
favorite Gods so I'll say this too the
sour has a super confusing story
because the people involved don't all
agree exactly what happened yeah
um
and
um well Duke also someone's saying what
headband is Duke using uh Duke is in a
federal halfway house getting out of the
clink he's not using anything he doesn't
have any plants he's not breeding
anything the cut he had before is what
we call the the 56th day it's an OG type
um he never had the LA he never had the
day record he never had anything like
that yeah um he doesn't have anything
right now
um but he uh
so
um
so there's an aspect where before I lose
my train of thought the sour story is
tough because everybody back in the day
got their sour cut helpfully labeled
sourdie yeah all these other names came
about when the forums happened
so much later than that right yeah and
resdog [ __ ] made a made a line of
seed called sour d and sour was super
popular but we know quite a bit about
the story we just can't figure
everything out because people don't
agree yeah the headband story
is basically a total [ __ ] mystery
people there
and people pop up here and there and say
oh I know but who did it who named it
how they do it
I can I can say this I got my headband
cut in in very early 2000s and I've
never lost it okay it's a diesel type
okay
the what people call the 56 day
is a renamed OG Kush yes there was
violence in the Kush family down in
Southern California a guy fled to the
Bay with that cut
he wanted to grow and sell that cut he
didn't want the stress of whatever was
happening in Southern California to
follow him they decided they were going
to rename the cut
they decided on the name headband
yep and a dude in the bay uh a dude in
the bay
um
uh what gave out a mislabeled tray
of that headband yeah and that's how
um Bob hemp Hill IC Collective myself
right around 0.506 or something like
that we all got it yeah Lumpa headband
is also likely a renamed OG yeah and
he'll get super pissed at me for saying
this but it didn't pop up until about 08
or 09. yeah you can get pissed off he
wants but that's I mean it's just that's
even from him back when we were close he
would say it's just a [ __ ] OG you
know it's it's a it's likely an OG S1
yeah
um you know it uh it popped up by the
time that he was talking on the forums
about having it I'd had my my headband
for eight years yeah something like that
um I've been trying to look for
information on exactly what my headband
is for 20 some years yeah not easy
yeah it's not easy there's just certain
things that the headband is a very
mysterious story
um the 707 Headband is the child it was
made by mandelbrot it's the child of uh
my headband cut
um and my headband cut was actually
passed out quite a bit in Humboldt Mendo
but it's really finicky and a pain in
the ass and people got rid of it because
sour was easier to grow
yeah
so that's that's the deal with the 707
the 707 mandelbrot took the LA the the
LA cut which we call it the headband cut
and crossed into an Afghan and sold it
as the 707 he made it in Humboldt that's
the area code up here in Humboldt Mendo
so that's why he called it the 707. and
so after post swerve releasing his Sour
OG almost every single cut that was
found from that was called something
headband so at that point
I've actually wondered if my headband
cut is
um from the sour seeds that vondo popped
in LA could be yeah he told me he popped
seeds and he got a really nice pheno of
it I don't know that's complete
conjecture
um but you know I it's very closely
related yeah but actual information it's
kind of like when we talked on the live
actual information about Urkel the who
the what the where and the how no yeah
people don't know nothing definitive
nothing definitive people have a [ __ ]
ton of names that they apply to way too
many Cuts day Wrecker
you know uh original oh boy original
right yeah Loompa this that whatever
um underdog
the underdog OG I don't know Underdog
Goji is just lupus headband renamed it's
all the same [ __ ] all of it's the same
[ __ ] uh candy cut the firebomb Indica
Hawaiian headband it's had so many
things actually I'll say this Lumpa uh
you know Lumpa was very open with his
friends that he renamed the Lumpa
headband whatever he wanted to to Market
it at the time yeah
he said he gave it Fusion causes sales
yeah he he gave it four or five
different names yeah it's a great it's
it's very it's a shitty breeder
uh none of my friends it's very
inconsistent yeah let's put it that way
it's very inconsistent and um but it's a
nice cut yeah definitely gets you high
definitely works that was I expected a
lot more diversity with the Bonnet but
it made some fire [ __ ] with the Bonnet
but I've had other lupus headband
crosses that would just [ __ ] bombs and
it's just it's inconsistent so all the
stuff with all the stuff with sour and
headband and the diesel family there's
some fact and there's some conjecture
and I doubt
um
you know I I doubt that it'll ever be
completely cleared up yeah uh even the
guys involved don't all agree and as
Matt mentioned before uh weasel or
whatever
um you know he's talked and written
multiple different stories yeah there
was a guy that was wanted to ask about
Origins TK
or whatever uh that's another one where
the same gentleman has written three
completely different stories different
strains different years slightly
different versions and so even if you
want to believe that one of those
versions is true they can all be true
yeah they can all be true and in his
he's just seems to be more
more sure about what it was than he was
in the past I think that's the best way
I'd put it in in the in the beginning he
said in 1994 he got hired by the guys
that he was he was being paid for to
grow to go to Amsterdam and mule some
seeds back and they bought half a dozen
different seed packs and they grew it
all in this 12 lighter and it hurt and
one of them they missed a male or it
hermed on this triangle that they called
the triangle because it was from the
triangle area
and then he told us he was on our
Discord a few years ago and he told us
that he went there in 91. yeah you know
his current story was he went there in
89. yeah
um you know so he's he's written three
completely different stories with
different times different plants
different strains listed
so I mean what do you do with that yeah
what are you doing the same dude has
three versions of events you know
um you know I uh my favorite OG
I think a lot of the ogs are good
I don't think they're a lot different
than each other I never understood LA's
fascination with 40 different cuts of OG
and having [ __ ] dispensaries filled
with 27 different types of the same
[ __ ] thing yeah I tend to think the
oldest ones are good uh the TK I like a
lot
um certainly like the TKS ones from CSI
are amazing
um I like the Flowrider which I got
early so
you know I um
you know there's uh there's a lot of
stuff that goes on with that that
Famous Cuts that's what happens with
Famous Cuts people rename them people
get bad bad seeds and put their own name
on them right uh people call them
different names to sell them to
different groups of people yeah who you
get it from it bases what name you call
it because that's who they called it
um the ghost OG
um
today isn't the Ghost OG that was traded
long ago yeah not the same cut at all
the ghost that goes around us ghost
isn't even the same ghost the ghost that
goes around is Ghost Now isn't the
original ghost that was getting passed
out and that original ghost was getting
sold to people for thirty to fifty
thousand dollars a cut I'm talking about
the guy that goes around his ghost isn't
even the same yeah the guy the guy who
go throw isn't even the re isn't even
the original ghost that actually traded
it in the very beginning yeah that's not
the person that cut was named after chem
91 is is
I mean you could call it very Bland I
suppose I will say I said it before that
not always does the flavor pop on chem
91.
the potency and the effect for me is
almost always there the flavor that I
like comes out about once every three
rips
so I and I've talked about my favorite
chem 91 version
um was a chem 91 hybrid from Elite
cannabis and the reason I liked it so
much was because it was true to the chem
91 looks smell was more more terpy and
the flavor was so [ __ ] insane so if
any of you guys can get a hold of
Resurrection it's a great chem 91 seed
line you know chem 91 is like chem 91 is
actually quite a bit like sour uh sour
can be pretty [ __ ] hard to nail yeah
yeah you get it to reach its genetic
potential it is absolutely bomb yeah
yeah I mean there was uh I I believe I
I'll answer I'll answer dude because
he's tied into homie but yeah um I see
Collective I believe he got the dog the
91 in 1997 right after he graduated high
school he moved in with skunk VA yeah
and they lived together uh he skunk VA
was growing and that was the first place
that I see Collective lived outside of
um outside of his parents house you know
and so yeah he got it he got it right
around 1997 and that was multiple years
before any of us saw OG yeah I mean even
if you listen to like um
uh Bubba kush's story and those guys I
don't think they even moved West until
1996.
okay I got a question for you not so How
likely do you think it is that Northern
Lights is responsible in any way for
Camden anyone
I think that it's a reasonably good
chance
interesting there you go
um I can't post it here but
um I was talking before about our buddy
pip yeah and pip had a uh 88-day chem 4.
yeah okay that he had
um put on that he had just gotten done
and I had him open an 89 catalog of the
seed bank Neville's Neville seed bank
and put it right next to a bud of nl5
haze
and it was like it was really close okay
so you're referring to chem for being
you probably have it but how about chem
I think it's a reasonable chance I mean
uh CSI isn't it I I mean which Which nut
NL I mean look
um in 19 in in 1990 1991 NL was one of
the most common things you could buy
yeah there was nl1 there was nl2 there
was nl5 there was multiple hybrids of
each
so
um do I think that uh do I think that it
could be in there yes I do
um I think it I think NL and skunk and
Hayes are likely in most things yeah at
least one of the three and sometimes I
tend to disagree on on nl5 being in
camera 91 only because it's so it's so
uniform and stable you didn't say nl5 I
think NL is in it appear okay but I I
still think it's more likely going to be
an Afghan T descendant it could be it
could be entirely possible you know if
we move it out of the NL range
personally yeah but but that but that's
what I'm saying is that you know we're
we're going on 31 years now since the
seed has popped yeah um it's all this
part is all Theory you could sit there
we don't know that it came from dog Bud
we don't know if it came from the dog
Bud that was sold on the lot to chemdog
we don't know if it came from weed later
we don't know [ __ ] yeah we know some
weed sold on dead tour led to the chem
91. yes that's what we know yeah and it
was given it was the weed was sold to a
17 year old yeah buy some early
20-something weed hustlers
in a parking lot yeah out of out of the
car
at a dead show
so not exactly you know yeah the closest
thing that I've ever seen to 91 in just
growing General Afghani different types
there was an old Bazaar uh land race
that Soma was selling and I think DNA
sold it as
Afghan some kind of Afghan uh for a
while they were relabeling it but it was
an old Mazar and it was very harm thrown
and it grew very much like chem 91
endless white pistols uh had a little
bit of the leaf cannibalization stuff
um just the general structure resin
production and then The Afghani one has
a lot of similar traits which for a long
time I thought it's got to be an Afghani
one for sure so tell the Afghan T stuff
kind of came up I'll I'll throw
something that throw through me for a
loop um at one of our little Canon
Illuminati Cana Illuminati parties that
we threw during the emerald cup CSI came
down and was hanging out with us that
weekend and him and I had a long chat
about whether or not chem 91 could be an
S1 from nl5 Haze yeah and it kind of
blew my mind because I'd never really
considered it but it does have rare
potency it is tall it does take a long
time for an Afghan yeah we do start
these lives late uh we're Cali I can't
and help it
um I'm sorry it's late
and uh but that's the way it goes
uh Elite cannabis from Colorado is legit
yes very much so and so so you know kale
uh Caleb wondered you know could it have
been an S1 from nl5 Haze and it just
leaned toward the NL side
and that and you know and he thinks it's
an S1 of something
not a full hybrid just because of the
narrow range of Finos it throws yeah
like it kind of throws itself
yep and so from a breeding perspective
that's a really good hint that
um it's
um self
yeah yep that's a really good hit but I
do not believe ever
um I think the only path to any kind of
certainty
is eventually DNA testing that is as
accurate as human DNA testing yeah and I
have no idea when that is going to pop
up sure wasn't philos we are not going
to get any amazing new information from
Joe brand or P bud or chemdog or anyone
that clarifies it yeah
we're just not
you know so
um and that's not a diss on them it's
just you know a bag of weed was sold
that you know I mean you know everyone
wishes that like some of the most
important things you ever do you'd
realize it was one of the most important
things you'd ever do yeah but sometimes
it's just Friday night yeah sometimes
that ain't how it is
you know
um well we still have people in here I'm
gonna say I'm gonna throw up some
options at the very end on my website uh
luckily the website's back up running we
got credit card acceptance the sprays up
there to get you can we have cash for
money order ready to rock
um I'll throw some options up there for
something I'm not sure what but it'll
probably be breeders packs of stuff uh I
might do the the Blue Sour breeders
packs because it's a very it's very true
breeding to the sour side as opposed to
Berry doesn't come through so much and I
might do maybe a pack of the um sour dub
cross to diesel something like that
where it's very super strong
um super stock dominance so I wanted to
plug that in there right tico.com and uh
go check out Speak Easy seed bank they
also have some other stuff up there
um yeah so now they got that done if you
want options go there after this back to
the story
um people are talking about can you just
get a grow license and and do it all
legally the problem with getting a grow
license and doing it all legally is that
then it creating right now and incurs so
much expenses to go legal in just about
any state that it makes it really
difficult for people to just wildly
experiment with no Financial benefit
yeah it would be amazing if that was the
case and legality I was hoping for a
while would really open things up but
it's kind of limited things in a way
um you know because it's got It's So
financially expensive you really have to
win
it's going to be less and less coming up
because with more with more uh laws
going down about space how many plants
you can grow all that there's going to
be a lot less playing time you know I
mean people say just said Oklahoma even
in Oklahoma most of the people that are
out in Oklahoma that that are doing it
cheap they're blowing it up right now to
make a bunch of money most people out in
Oklahoma went there and lost that's
that's why I mean that's the thing that
people want to know like is that all the
all the breeding that I did for a long
time was financially very stupid
yeah because I could have taken this I
could have taken that same space and
pumped out weed that sold for way more
yeah you know uh way more you know and
so that's why that's honestly why I like
so much stuff comes from like a
relatively small group of people yeah
because most people if they're given the
opportunity to grow weed
they just try to grow as much wheat as
they can of something that makes them
the most money yeah
and especially 20 years ago when I was
doing a lot of my breeding
um before before you could monetize like
with IG and all these different things
and you could be a little personal
American breeder yeah like breeding was
like a labor of love
you know my buddy from Staten Island
talked about you know how how many seeds
you could make in a in an eight lighter
versus how many pounds yeah and he was
like man if we could just sell these
even for a dollar or two we could wait
way more money than that eight Miner
could make yeah but we didn't have the
infrastructure or the internet or the
this or that or whatever in order to
like actually like you know and then
even when we did get the internet I was
on the forums
they're in the Cannabis world and
overgrow era and then they busted
Heaven's get Heaven Stairway
and they shut all that [ __ ] down and a
bunch of people got in trouble
and I kind of hid on the forums until IG
yeah because I wasn't a computer expert
and I I wasn't good I wasn't going to be
like masking my IP address and masking
this and hiding like I wasn't computer
savvy enough you're not you're still not
computer savvy no but I just mean in the
sense of like trying to get away with
like selling a bunch of illegal [ __ ] to
people I met on the internet
it didn't seem it didn't seem uh it
didn't seem wise even when I got into it
I was one of the first people to sell
worldwide from the US and everybody
thought I was a [ __ ] idiot for doing
it and I probably was you know like it
was more risk than I should have taken
at the time but
um yeah that even the idea of that just
wasn't happening even when I came into
it which is much later than you
and it's hard I mean I'll say this too
like I you know I don't want to say like
you know some people might interpret
when you talk about truth or you talk
about your opinion uh there's a there's
a real common thing right now where
people talk about oh you're a hater or
oh you're dissing me or something like
yeah I'm not really trying to do that to
most people when it comes down to it but
you know people have their version of
events and people have their version of
Truth and most of the time people only
tell you the truth in cannabis if it
financially benefits them yeah there's a
lot of things that are sort of like
commonly known amongst the tight circles
that don't get put out to the common I
don't want to say Commons the wrong word
but to the masses because they don't
want the blowback
yeah you know they don't want they don't
want the attacks they don't want the you
know you're calling me a liar oh you're
saying that like something I said once
was inconsistent I thought we were Bros
you're supposed to back me up yeah and
that's how a lot of stuff stays secret
and that's why it took this long for a
lot of this to even come out would I
collab with Bodhi sure
um uh Bodhi is again he's a he's a
[ __ ] Lobo Bodie is a good friend of
both of ours
um you know I uh yeah you know
um
most of the time honestly I uh you know
I I I I use flour to survive and seeds
were the passion yeah for some people
it's reversed and seeds are the way to
survive and flower is the passion you
know I I grew I grew flower to survive
so seeds were I mean I gave I haven't
really sold seeds but I gave thousands
and thousands of them away
yeah and entire seed companies were
created off of it
um because back then the goal to be
frank wasn't uh wasn't rapper money it
was trying to make better weed
we didn't think there was any money in
seeds
yeah
you know do we think the dankety Dank is
going to disappear it could
yeah it's under real risk because the
powers that bee don't really care about
as you put it dankity dank yeah um a lot
of money that spends dollars with
companies
you're you're using your dollars like
votes granted it's not a political
process but it kind of is and if you
keep supporting companies that keep
doing these like non-stop gelato hybrids
cookies oh my God let me enter let me
interject sure since he does get a bad
rap these days and it's well deserved
yeah because Sensei outsourced all of
their work to Spain yeah they are they
are not the Legends they were in the 90s
correct they I don't know what what else
they have I don't know how much they
have that's real I know they got busted
in 1999 2000 and they move their
operation out of Holland into Spain and
they get third parties to make their
seats
um could they have one or two strains
among there that they sent to those
people and they have and it's semi what
it was I suppose
but they sell everything that they used
to sell they even use the same [ __ ]
pictures that Neville had in his Seed
Catalog from the 80s
they have
not updated their pictures yeah 30 plus
years yeah ever
foreign
I mean you know it you know if you want
better weed cross things that you like
together
give out seeds to your friends hold on
to seeds hold on to clones that you
think work really good for you
try to get some friends to back them up
too
you know I mean that's that's really the
way the the has the dankity Dank Will
Survive better weed will survive if
people make it a point even if it's
financially expensive to them
you know to keep it yeah
yeah you know that's really what it's
going to go down to so do you think we
hit all the Salient points of the the
chem stuff I think uh I don't want to
try to keep it in that region for a good
podcast audio podcast yeah we can I mean
even like when we went off on sour and
headband and stuff I consider that chem
family yeah it's still all very relevant
um you know and so
um but yeah I mean basically what it
boils down to is that uh chemdog
um through a series of accidents and
sheer luck uh
got some really really incredible
strains came out of his little circle
yeah and I think honestly he's more of a
glass blower than he is a breeder nerd I
don't say that I don't mean that in a
bad way people like no no people have
different interests he's a very talented
glassblower for sure yeah him him being
able to share some of this stuff with my
buddy from Staten Island and share it
with other people and have some Herm
accidents happen kind of change the face
of cannabis it did and so he deserves a
lot of credit for that because he as a
teenager was growing weed in a totally
illegal State and an undergoing risk
yeah and so if I've said some things
that counter counter dicks his Like
official word or whatever I'm not
dissing him
you know on any level
um he contributed a lot yeah you know
um people want you know imagine if
someone asked you to remember 10 or 15
or 20 years ago exactly what happened
and imagine you had three friends in the
room and they put you all in separate
rooms and they ask you to remember the
exact story yeah there's going to be
differences yeah
for sure and people's memories change
you know yeah and there's a lot of
people who tried to change the story for
their own good later on they weren't
even a part of the original curve so
yeah I think we covered it all yeah I
mean so now you have a lot of things
where you know chem family gets thrown
around and this gets thrown around and
you know it's like the people that are
that are most involved
um you know like my buddy from Staten
Island or even IC Collective or
um you know uh I you know for a long
time skunk VA but I guess he did a
podcast or two and kind of enlightened
things the the vocal ones were the ones
that were the least involved yeah
and The Quiet Ones happen to be the ones
that had the most to do with it
um I didn't I wasn't involved for [ __ ]
except where I got them super early and
I kept helped keep them alive yeah
you know so
um you know it uh and everyone's version
everyone's version of events you can
weave into the rest of the people's
events yeah and in some cases you have a
situation where you just have to pick
who you believe
that's sometimes what it boils down to
you know I mean uh you know I mean we we
have we have debates all the time and
and they'll be like I can't believe you
you believe that [ __ ] and I'm like
well the [ __ ] that you believe I
don't believe either
you know and as you can tell like me and
not so don't even necessarily agree on
what the what it could be what it's you
know the beginnings there's still stuff
that we don't necessarily agree on and
that we will debate like head to head
all the time because we're [ __ ] nerds
like that but yeah same with CSI same
same with any number of different
friends people have their different
ideas and you know like I said there's
there's fact and there's conjecture you
know
um and I try to be clear when you
venture from one to the other
um you know so
um but I do think that getting the
information out there matters because as
things legalize and things go there's a
lot of cool stories in cannabis that'll
just be lost yeah
so we're going to try to keep
documenting them as best we can
um hopefully this was enlightening for
all of you uh or or some people you know
I hope you uh I hope you enjoyed it and
and of course we we talk all the time in
the breeder Syndicate Discord
um you can find that going to Google and
you can type in breeders Syndicate
patreon you could join through there
it's five dollars a month and we all
hang out shoot the [ __ ] in there watch
fights and talk a lot about weed history
um the current political goings-on in
weed be that different breeders
different strains what have you uh
nachos in there too yeah
he's a hard person to access on
Instagram because I mean he's probably
got a million [ __ ] cue of waiting
people to approve and he doesn't really
memorize Who's Who and people like to
report accounts so it's it's a you know
it's it's an easy way to catch him is in
the Discord that isn't it it's it's more
communicative uh IG used to be better
when it was when it was time based
and before Shadow Banning and all that
type of stuff it's not it's not what it
used to be that's right in terms of a
communication tool at least yeah
um and so you know and you know you got
kids and lives and things and this and
that but
um I do think it's important to come out
and like say and have community
um and a lot of a lot of a lot of
unfortunately a lot of podcasts and a
lot of things are sort of like like an
infomercial about the person or their
own personal company yeah there's not a
lot going on where people just want to
talk about history or people just want
to talk about various aspects that don't
benefit them or don't burnish their
Legend you know and so I think we need
some more of that just in general yeah
and to finish this off don't forget
about Reddit seedco.com
[Music]
it is true because if you don't support
the real ones then it makes it much
harder for real ones to exist
all right well thanks for coming on not
so it's always a pleasure maybe we can
do Friday night is a good night to do
this for me yeah I think I think we'll
try to make this a regular thing so
enjoy everyone enjoy your weekend
peace