welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
all right one of the first things I
think since since we have you here
Shawnee like you know one of the things
that we're often talking about like
we're in Discord and stuff is hype
strains
um
people admiration different things
people experience as like as they're
just getting back into buying seeds and
and getting into the scene or in your
case getting back into it from um you
know being into it real heavy at one
point and one of the biggest things that
people come to you with is why you hate
root beer so much what's your problem
with Gene what what is this root beer
hate you have and you know I I've always
seen it from your angle but I would like
you to explain it from your angle for
everyone to hear because because when I
hear it I don't hear what they're
hearing
yeah well I I don't hear what they're he
I I can kind of
uh imagine what they're hearing but I
don't know what they're hearing either
but it's something kind of went like
viral in our server and it just kind of
blew up and
I think because there was a lot of uh
arguments around it as well yeah but
like
so yeah so like
I entered the I the the computer world
with IG and all this stuff and like you
don't know when you don't know people
you don't know all these like Brands and
you don't know all this stuff you really
don't have any idea what you're looking
at but like I I started to like well
hanging out with you guys it's like
question when I'm buying trying to
understand on a deeper level all this
sort of stuff so like when there's
certain things that are like super super
big and I'm like why are they big why
why is this like why does everybody want
this but when I ask those questions to
other people it's like I don't get an
answer either yeah
um and root beer was like the one I
don't know why that was the one that
stuck but like everybody wanted root
beer but I don't I didn't really
understand why and I don't think anybody
else really did either
I mean I think it was because like it
was just how you asked but why root beer
and I think someone took that as an
offense like it was so offensive that
you would even ask well but why what do
you mean why there's 30 of us talking
about how much we want it what do you
mean why yeah and Gene's cool and all
this stuff and like everything's
verified and it's like you know what's
the problem but I mean
it's nobody really experienced it like
very few people ever experienced it and
nobody really has any idea it isn't
really proven on any level that we know
but it just kind of like blew up because
of the memes right and all the joking
and and I like there was that podcast
episode where Gene was talking about it
and he he seemed really open about it
and he that he didn't want to release it
because he didn't think it would live up
to the expectation that had already
built up sure and that you know he
mentioned like her M issues if people
were running it indoor and all kinds of
stuff and people still wanted it like
crazy you know it's like I don't think
people even listen to him in that
section because what I heard was you
know maybe it's not as good as everyone
thinks right yeah sure I think he was
just being realistic yeah giving people
realistic expectations and um and that's
fair I mean like I like I've tried to
tell people when they were arguing with
you I don't think it is even necessarily
about root beer and it certainly isn't
about just Gene you know like don't even
have a problem with Jean it means a nice
dude but it's more about
the idea of why why is there height
behind this and and why are we feeling
that it's like sheep what's it what's
what's the cult the phenomenon of it
right yeah it's a phenomenon
because it just like it's this hive mind
mentality where you know certain things
get mentioned enough that everyone's
like damn I want to try that you know
but like what I want more people to be
doing is is to like understand what they
like what they what they want and if
it's something that they want you know
um
like I I haven't run any of Gene's stuff
but mainly because he from my
understanding he breeds outdoors in a
region that is far from me and I grow
indoors and it doesn't it doesn't make
sense for me to run his seed sure I like
I don't know I kind of like there's
other things I would rather do not not
because of anything against him or
anything like that but like
I've sort of ruled certain certain
things out due to things like I just
mentioned right like it's outdoor seed
yeah I mean I think that's something I
wish I not even just you or has and
again not even in relation to Gene
anyone should be taking that into into
what they're doing like okay I'm growing
indoor I need to have seeds and bread
indoor are these breeders breeding my
seeds indoor because if they're bringing
them outdoor and you're trying to bring
them indoor a lot of stuff that does
really well outdoor will have intersex
traits indoor it's common it's very
common so that's something people should
be asking but I don't even think anybody
even asks that like I don't you think
that was that's not even a part of the
equation when people think about buying
seeds like oh it's a breeders
it often isn't and like that like from
my experience like the average person
they're really looking at all the wrong
things usually you know they're looking
at like a name that sticks out that
either they have attachment to or what
whatever the reason or a certain like
term profile that it's supposed to be
promising you
or you know like very surface level
things yeah
um
and I find it interesting actually too
like in our server watching a lot of
people pop some things
that you know are probably going to be
like a high potency and then they're
like whoa this is a little much you know
like
maybe they got hit with that for the
first time and they're just like yeah
it's it's definitely potent but it might
not be what I want to smoke every day
you know exactly yeah so like I think
that's really great growth for for
people and I like I love that's what I
love about popping seed and trying new
things is like
you know it's all about what you like
and experiencing that and then trying to
search for the things that you know do
it for you yeah
that's perfect welcome pack
okay guys laptop pack and we also have
local botanist here with us so we kind
of just Joy jumped into the conversation
um it's we're recording it a little late
on Friday and uh we're just gonna have a
small round table talk about some
different things
um and of course we're going to talk a
little bit and and that kind of leads
into a little bit of what I was going to
get into about like putting people on
pedestals like yeah I think that is a
another factor I mean we see it and it
happens here you know like just being
totally transparent I see it happen here
with me with not so we try to keep it as
as real as possible and remind people
we're just [ __ ] like low rent Farmers
like I I grow a few types of plants but
I'm I'm not even
capable of being called a real farmer
let alone needing a pedestal you know
and other people don't necessarily
deserve that either but
um in the world of marketing and hype
you know dudes flashing Rolexes or fake
Rolexes that doesn't matter if it flips
by real fast you know uh pedestals
happen a lot and
and one thing I've noticed is what
happens when people have their their
Paradigm shifted on a breeder like let's
say that this is their hero breeder and
they find out something very devastating
it almost it almost breaks people
sometimes
you guys have seen it like people flip
the [ __ ] out sometimes yeah they do yeah
um it's kind of
it's really weird with like grown adult
men you know yeah it is that they're so
passionate
to that level it's like I'm not a sports
fan but I also get that Vibe when people
are like super into like sports dudes
yeah yeah I know it's like you're a
grown-up you know it's
a dream man yeah
it's a trip uh uh the the
um attachment people get to other grown
men like that yeah and admiration that
they hold and I get I get it like
because I had that like it's it's not
like something I don't understand when I
got in the scene like I I remember
looking up to um Adam Dunn like he was
one of the Americans that went over
there to Amsterdam you know and like
I've done Aaron we're over there too but
they were kind of like Hollywood knobs
so I didn't have I didn't like have any
kind of anything Vibe with them you know
but Adam seemed to be smart like he
would talk about his strains and
sourcing these these uh old California
and and American Colonial strain so I
was real into him and then over time
when you get to meet people and have
relationships with them and they become
much more human
you realize how much you did have them
on a pedestal at a time when people
because and very often you're
disappointed and sometimes you're not
sometimes people are as special as you
kind of always hoped they would be but
that's a that's a rare occurrence local
when you first got into seeds what were
some of the dudes that you were hearing
about that
um maybe maybe you got you excited at
first and later you you found like maybe
maybe I'm not so into it
yeah um so seats were really weird for
me
um you know like I bought like from
Nirvana here and there like
um Dutch Passion was another one but
like this was already like you know like
I don't know 2015 2016 so it's like
by then it's like nobody was really
looking into that yeah um and then I had
a friend who was generous enough just to
give me like a bunch of different seeds
you know
um
I think one of them was like uh
something called Blackberry cheesecake
uh like a heavy duty fruity cross you
know things like that
um I grew them and you know for the time
for me I thought they were good because
like they smelled different like it
wasn't just like a cheap ass bag on the
street you know yeah
um and then you know after that I I kind
of just started like thinking about
um you know like how do people claim
that they are making these crosses that
you know like for example like blue
dream you have 20 different [ __ ] blue
Dreams yeah and like you know a little
bit about me like my background is in
like genetics and botany and all that
and
um you know more so population genetics
and it's when you're going to college
for this your University yeah I went
yeah I got my degree uh two years ago
and that
um and so you know like instinctually I
kind of just thought okay like these
people say they have like you know this
blue dream or whatever
um it's like you know what's to say that
they're all gonna be the same you know
you have different pollen donors you
have different like you know uh pollen
receivers and all that so it's like
who's to see what's what and I I think
that's kind of like what struck like the
whole like provenance type of like you
know understanding it like knowing that
like not anyone is just gonna give you
what they say it is you know because it
the sad truth of it is is like it's a
it's a sketchy scene you know there are
sketchy people
um but yeah and you know as a little
time went on like I began to get a
little interested in history and that's
kind of like when I stumbled upon this
podcast yeah
um I listened to the first episode and
like I believe you gave crybaby a shout
out yeah um that's right like just a
little after that I joined breeder
Syndicate and like yeah I mean it kind
of went from there
um right
um luckily I was like
um
adopted into like a good Community
relatively early on
um so like I didn't have to go through
like any [ __ ] or anything or like
get my [ __ ] hopes and dreams Crush
like some of these other people do and
yeah at the end of it like
I mean you see these dogs they're almost
in the days when they hear about like
Our Heroes being Tweakers snitches and
stuff yeah and yeah the crazy thing is
it's like it's you know we're all humans
and it's like I feel like we should all
be true to ourselves and it's like you
know by claiming all these things you're
like lying to yourself and and what good
is that you know a lot of delusion yeah
exactly and it's kind of sad I guess but
I mean that's cool what's cool about the
server here is like like I remember when
I I was early on in there but like
everybody has bought [ __ ] you know
everybody's been taken and like it's not
like there's people in there that are
very experienced that are like never had
that happen everyone's had that hell
yeah you know and that's where it's like
some people take it super personally
some people are super invested
financially and emotionally
but I mean when the when open
conversations happen and it's like look
like this is kind of what we know
and it's not the greatest thing to hear
like I mean it's I don't understand when
people just don't want to hear it they
don't want to accept it or they're they
start fights over it or
you know
I I was not like that I'm just like holy
[ __ ] really tell me more you know yeah
like I don't like being wrong so help me
be right like that's get me there well
understanding is the most important part
right it's not about who good and who's
bad and who's this and who you know it's
just understanding situations and like
you said humanizing people like
like nobody's perfect you know there's
in the person in the world that's
perfect there's another person in the
world that hasn't done a stupid thing or
misstep or whatever but like
people that are actively like learning
and trying to move forward it's like
they're moving forward you know yeah
always
yeah you know one of the biggest
problems that I found since local you're
like a
um a university type dude was like I'm
still having trouble communicating with
University people on on the level of
like their geneticists their botanists
they understand breeding it in these
deep levels but trying to communicate to
them the history of cannabis
how we came to to the conclusions that
we have why we're there and why it
matters to what they're doing and why
they need to know this stuff before they
start like doing these tests on these
strains and comparing The Strain To The
Strain and why they need to know all
this stuff like how do we how do you
tell people that are obviously much more
educated and smart you know in their own
mind than we are
um how do you how do you explain that to
them what would you do from Europe
it's kind of a hard question but I mean
yeah it is a complex question I mean you
know I I after all like I just got my
undergrad like I'm not a PhD or like
Masters by like any means but like
there's definitely intentions for that
yeah
um but like I don't know I I think it's
really hard for them to kind of accept
us somewhat and maybe it's because you
know we're just a bunch of Deeds that
like smoke weed and nerd out about you
know [ __ ] that doesn't really matter to
the world even though it does yeah
um and that's like one thing I kind of
joked about like with people like when
they ask like oh hey what do you do as a
botanist and I was like oh yeah like I
study this you know it you know it
doesn't matter in the grand scheme of
things but to me it's really interesting
so yeah I'm gonna say [ __ ] in and do it
you know
um but I think like one way to maybe get
like attention of some scientists is
maybe trying to like integrate some of
like maybe the hypotheses that like we
have maybe a about certain families of
plants you know or groups of plants you
know like how can we integrate this into
like how they're study like what they're
studying so like for example the
professor that I was studying under at
my school
um she was interested in plant breeding
systems so like you know how like wheat
is is a [ __ ] dialysis right you know
you have your your male and your female
plants well you know she was studying
plants that were uh gyno-dialicious
which are female and like you know
hermaphroditic plants even their true
males so it's like you know I think
there are ways to kind of integrate like
studies between like the two topics so
it's like I think it's more about
relating it to their topic of study than
you know trying to achieve this goal of
you know maybe just sequencing DNA or
whatever just to see it's related to me
like it's like
I look at them at what they're doing and
I'm like how can you even waste your
time sequencing the DNA of this blue
dream cut that you went and Source from
a collective that you say 95 of the cuts
are similar to this one but it's
probably not even [ __ ] blue dream why
are you wasting your time because that's
not even having anything to do that
everybody in history is talking about
and that you're going to be comparing
this data to you know
we have to also consider that we need to
have information on what the parents
actually were it's not like you can just
take what what was it like a [ __ ]
Super Silver Haze and a blueberry like
you can't do sequences too separately
and expect it exactly to be related to
the blue dream that they sequence so
it's
obviously they're there they don't even
understand that part like they don't
yeah I know for sure and it seems to me
it's so scientifically obvious like if
you're gonna start at a place you're
going to [ __ ] crawl back up to the
parent line maybe you should figure this
[ __ ] up out along the way but like their
their ideas were like basically we don't
think or what
the most common sentiment I'm getting
from them I shouldn't say all of them
the most common sentiment I've gotten
from multiple people in that field is
how do you know you're right
that so that's that's I guess the beauty
of science you know like yeah and that's
what I've been trying to work on like
interpreting like or not interpreting
using the Bayes theorem to bring in to
to actually working that into how we
approach history and how we prove past
historical events
um within reason and within science and
I think like that's something that I've
been looking at as it's used in other
um
like in ancient religions and stuff to
prove what happened in ancient religions
even though all we have is texts you
know yeah and that's really the key
honestly like you know people who
witness certain events you know like
primary sources and all that you know
like uh primary sources are I mean
sometimes going to be some of the most
valuable sources but you know obviously
those may be biased defending yeah for
sure you know as you've seen dude like
we've seen firsthand like the best
primary sources and then it gets kind of
scary yeah I know yeah yeah yeah
um
but yeah like I mean I I feel I feel
awesome knowing that there's actually
like this theorem that people have
figured out that helps prove history
when it's based on written evidence in
the past it's pretty cool
for reference it was Dr Richard carrier
in
um one second I want to make sure I give
him credit for this because it is a
pretty uh uh it was proving the history
and on the proving history
yeah I think that's what it is Richard
carrier proving history
yeah and the Science World is like the
type of world that like if it's not on
paper it's
you know exactly probably not going to
be real so you know that's another thing
to take into consideration you know what
my mind why do these tests if none of
that matters why even do the tests like
it's you know it at that point it's
[ __ ] with ethics and it's like if
this is really something that they
wanted it to per se uh integrate into
like Pharmaceuticals and stuff it's like
you're also [ __ ] with that yeah yeah
if if you want to make it medicine then
you need the data that people use but
you need to go access that data that
people had you need to know what they
were smoking at the time not what you
think yeah and that but it just I don't
know it's it's been a long long drawn
out process trying to have these
conversations with these University
professors and phds and
and it's still gotten to me I feel like
it's gotten not very far yeah and you'd
hope things would get better with
Federal legalization but I just feel
like it's still gonna be rather tricky
to conduct any
kind of like uh ecological based studies
like I feel like it's gonna take I feel
like it's gonna take someone as that
just happens to get into the head of one
of these programs to end up being a
massive C nerd
actually gain interest in history and
really dive in and that's like a dice
roll because look at how few of us there
are in cannabis let alone this is a tiny
community
it really is yeah
what's your thoughts on it pack
oh um uh you caught me off guard here we
were just talking about the the trying
to talk to the university people about
why why they need to take
the history of strange seriously before
they start trying to [ __ ] with
sequencing and doing all that
um sure chasing it I I just have a real
hard time communicating with them on it
and if you know
I'm not sure if it's the Lost in
Translation possibly you know not having
the the same kind of reference point to
be able to speak their language uh you
know maybe it's something along those
lines but I I would imagine anybody
who's truly you know stepping up to the
plate from a scientific practitioner
level they're going to want to consider
you know all variables right and
you know
just the fact that it's been taboo to
research you know I wonder
you know people have kind of become my
optic or sort of conditioned into their
own as much as scientists are open
they're also you know kind of looking
along their own agenda for things and so
how you how you kind of introduce uh
another lens to look there is a good
question some of these people even smoke
which is like okay so you've been
smoking forever
I don't know I don't know it's just one
of those Stone thoughts they're not
they're not smoking the right [ __ ] it's
a problem exactly so one of the things I
also wanted to get into was one of the
number one questions we get asked and we
have you know we have me and pack on
here and we have Shawnee and local was
males people have questions about males
all the time Shawnee
load up some mail questions like that
you think people would want to know
about local users load them up
well like
um
like number one right like like if
you're looking for a male and you like
to use a mail
the only way you know is if you grow The
Offspring and observe the females
correct correct yeah
so I mean like
this I read this article and like me and
crybaby had a little conversation
about it
um
but like what the first question that
popped into my head was like how many
how many Elite males exist today like
how many people are holding males that
they breed with that they've been like
held on to for a significant amount of
time yeah and uh the answer was pretty
low right yeah very very low
very low I don't think that there's a
lot of um revisiting with certain males
um I think people when they do it they
tend to select another male from the
seed line it's very hard to do I know
when we were keeping Mel's alive over
the years before uh the moon situation
um it would it's just constant repotting
making sure the pot's big enough making
sure your mail isn't flowering uh my
bedroom is constantly 24 7. like just 24
on there's never any kind of darkness in
my bedroom because of males constantly
trying to keep males around second they
hit the bottom of the pot they'd always
start flowering in there and if it's in
the same location as a female room that
could be a serious problem like if
you're trying to take meals alive while
also making seeds of something else with
another meal that's not really that good
it's not it's not beneficial so you
always have to learn on the fly over
time when it comes to stuff like that
using special events really isolating
um still not advised to keep them in the
same room but yeah it's why you don't
see it very often there's like the haze
Haze AC mil that were real famous
um we kept the blue bonnet one alive for
a long time and it was over at Radio
Ridge until we got hplv and now it's no
longer with us it was a bummer but we
tried we tried to keep it alive to pass
out for other people to do blueberry
work that was the intent yeah it's not
that common and um I think the first
question I get the most is
what do you look for When selecting a
male uh the number one
well like
great they're pretty much all myths
though right or not myths but like
they're not all like 100 confirmed sort
of I mean it just like if you okay like
back in the day I remember when I
started I was told by by the Hunts
breath guy
if you want to find a male you want to
look for the one that looks most like
the female and grows most like a female
and the one you think is least like a
male in the end
like it looks like a female and at the
very last minute you realize oh it's a
male and that's a one so for a long time
I just did that you know and then as I
as I started going I was like I'm not
really getting anything anywhere by
doing that like it's not doing anything
special for me like I I didn't know if I
was trying to just make sure there was
no Herms at the beginning is that what
I'm trying to do because that seems to
be what people complain about the most
you just don't want herbs you know yeah
and as you're doing this stuff you're
seeing different traits pop out right
and then you see certain things from
from the mail land certain Leaf shapes
certain certain serrations like oh wait
that's a trade I can identify you know
and slowly you kind of realize
there's not just one male one trait one
one it's like trying to constantly fit a
square peg in a circle you know like if
you if you're looking for the same trait
in every male you're trying to fit a
square peg in a circle like if when it
came to the blue bonnet stuff it was
like I wanted blueberry versions of
everything if I want that I'm not going
to go to a
to I don't know Apple mints or whatever
and and try to make that Mail work you
know and just until it works it's just
not how it works so um yeah I mean when
you're selecting for a mail
you've got to start somewhere sometimes
it's as easy as one two three roll a
dice pick one if you don't know anything
about the line
um it's a lot easier to know a line grow
the line out know the females and that
way when you start seeing these males
pop out you can see their counterparts
in the female slowly but surely with
what traits line up with both of them
and uh yeah that's the best advice know
your line before you work it know your
line before you know your line before
you choose a male and and it'll tell you
everything you don't have to have any
questions I think I think your
intentions you know say a lot to you I
mean if you're somebody who's really
trying to go deep and uh you know you
got the means uh space wise time wise
and what have you to to go that way then
sure you know but if let's say you just
grab a bag of seeds right and you pop it
you got a couple males and you know
you're not a lifer necessarily but you
want to mess around
um or even like open pollination
situations right sure
um you can open Parliament with more
than one male you don't have to have
12 males in there if you have a 4x4 sure
there's like all kinds of consideration
in terms of what you're trying to get
into as well yeah it's what you're
trying to achieve are you trying to make
seats for sale are you trying to make it
just to learn the line I mean there's
all kinds of different reasons and
appropriate uses of things like that
sure yeah you may not have an
opportunity to go through five males and
grow out all their Prodigy and continue
to select and figure out how to you know
dial it in the way you want so
that makes a lot of sense
what about you local you have any
questions on males yeah right yes yeah
the question is like how is one maybe
able to distinguish
um one to let's say pull a mail from it
you know the original F1 versus maybe
pulling a mail for breeding later down
in the generation like are are there
instances like where people actually
like you know move a line forward to
select a mail or like
it just seems really odd
when I I can't think of a situation
unless I was like doing
like parallel breeding where I'm working
two two different expressions from the
same line then I would choose a male at
like F5 to cross to a nail like F5 up
here that's a that's a good case for
doing something like that like going
down she's in the middle up here as
opposed to down here
um
mm-hmm I I can't really think of any
situation where I would purposely choose
like an F3 male over an F1 mail for any
situation
I'm sure there are occasions where that
comes up but I can't think of one
um I mean yeah I guess maybe the only
instance I could think of is maybe
pulling like a male from an F2 because
it is your you know largest window for
selection
you know and maybe you to just bring
diverse more diversity yeah maybe yeah
but
but yeah I don't know usually yeah the
thing is usually if I'm working
something in my mind if I'm working
something forward I'm only going forward
for uniformity yeah of a trait never for
diversity but I'm sure like if someone
had like
10 seeds of a line that might actually
be a decent thing to do you know like
and with me when it comes to open
pollinations like I'm I'm All or Nothing
with open pollinations it's like yeah I
have to leave all the males in there
with all the females or one male one
female
um or or one male all females
um and that's only because like I feel
like if you're doing any kind of pulling
out based on like oh this thing's
herming that let's all remove that one
I'm artificially selecting just one
little thing away from that pool it's
only one little thing but I'm taking
away a trait you know I think it's not a
great trait but I'm taking it away but
it might be a link trait to something
very special in that line and you might
have just pulled it so so that's the
only time I would say like it's more
beneficial to have all the males versus
just choosing a few but if it's a space
consideration like pack was talking
about that's an excellent time when it's
like you know like you're not probably
not even making seeds to sell at that
point but you're trying to go through
the line that's a perfect time to you
know use what works for you you know
whatever's going to help you get through
that line more to understand it more
perfect case for it
I mean you know most people nowadays
dude are in it for themselves right um
yeah and this idea of like it being
you know a lifestyle versus like a
window of opportunity you have to jump
through
you know what I'm saying that kind of
separates the men from the boys I guess
like the ones yeah
it always has yeah
like when somebody gets the opportunity
to [ __ ] [ __ ] you over to try and make
the situation better it happened all the
time
like you know
because it ruins friendships man
Yeah well yeah yeah yeah what's the
difference between the long timers and
the short term timers in cannabis you
know like being in being in the seed
scene for over 15 years now I've watched
a revolving door of characters some of
them the most popular dudes you couldn't
imagine the biggest top of the scene
totally gone no one even remembers them
anymore you know um yeah it flashes in
the pan like that happened all the time
there's a high turnover rate in cannabis
at very few are people that have been in
it longer than 10 years in the seed
scene that have lasted that long and
that are still going through researching
trying to find the truth doing all that
stuff it doesn't yeah it's a hard thing
to to stick with you don't make friends
trying to find history and dude you know
if you're doing it if you're doing it
like you do you know it's for the love
so there's more to it than you know just
trying to get some and some clout right
and uh yeah in the world there's no
there's zero clout to be found at the
end of digging up history a lot I
promise people there's a lot of like
enemies to be made so I mean heck we got
our 420 sale coming up we're gonna kick
it off for 417 for the patreon folks so
April 17th we're gonna have
um let's see we got high-end Lonesome
buy any high and Lonesome seeds you can
get mule Skinner actually buy anyone
seeds you can get real Skinner
um by uh uh let's see what else do we
got pack we got yours we got the hell
melon watermelons Skittles Angelica by
by go farm seeds get that by
um right seeds get either Panda
woolfield or you can get something from
my private stash that is rare
um it'll be a grab bag so it's like
pretty much first come first serve it'll
be Panda's will fill first then special
[ __ ] for mine or if you really really
want to make that request for something
special of mine you can
um it's all gonna be 30 off all right
and yeah and I believe goat farm are you
joining that now let's do it all right
writing goat farm Gear 30 off coupons
um the coupon for the patreon people is
different from the coupon for the uh
everyone else so pay attention to the
social medias the patreon all that stuff
right seeds.com 420 sale am I forgetting
anything
yeah the starter and the 88 Afghan cross
yes thank you previous yep we got those
too so we have all kinds of freebies
like all kinds of great freebies going
out for everyone's packages this round
you can save up to 30 off that's all my
stuff all packed stuff um even the two
guys one cup stuff and the spray so go
check that out starts on 417 for patreon
people 418 for everyone else
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out Syndicate here.com we also have
an underground Syndicate Discord where
we get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out