welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey in defining my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
hey everyone welcome to reader Syndicate
welcome to the season finale of season
eight
um today me and thousand thousand will
be joining us we're going to be going
through users questions and kind of have
a relaxed Kickback episode to end the
season for a real kind of serious
breeding topic so yeah
um
let's kick it off
yeah sure okay so this is one we got
from Buckshot Hill actually a while ago
but we couldn't get to it and um we'll
see how we do okay so Buckshot wants to
know he says I've been talking with not
so about the early Pearl and how best to
proceed with my goals for finding a long
lost female or doing a 2.0 remake with
starting material that's period correct
the topic has been brought up to The
Syndicate before and it's been discussed
uh or maybe speculated that nl1 might be
the unknown indica
never used to make early Pearl improved
I've been planning across with silver
Pearl to bring the DNA of 90s early
pullback into the mix not so agree that
is a good direction for a starting point
I've also been looking into what pure
Indica would have been available to
Neville in 89.90 and big bud fits the
possibilities
I started perfect proceeds from pip and
lost Pearl from Greenhouse both silver
Pearl s1s
um what do you think uh you know does it
sound appropriate
um
yeah so this is an interesting one
because this is a mixture of provenance
and what we know of
these lines
um as well as a breeding question so
yeah
so what do you think
early Pearl is an early early line
um brought to the community by Rob Clark
I'm not sure who like the base is for it
I should say were brought to you by Rob
Clark I'm not sure who's actually
responsible for it
um later on uh early Pearl worked its
way to Holland uh and into Neville
schoenmaker's hands
um according to his one of his last
Partners
um early Pearl ended up being one of his
favorite strains ever and he was
constantly working to trying to find the
sweetness that was in the Mexican in
early Pearl because he felt like the
sweetness that was coming through in the
early Pearl was from the Mexican or
oaxacan type side
um so yeah that's that's the idea that
he was going for behind early Pearl was
the sweetness in that Mexican and he
liked the high a lot and I I agree I
like the high from the pearls quite a
bit
um
if I were gonna do an early Pearl
Project
like I think that's a great place to
start and mostly because I love silver
Pearl so much like
I don't know though I don't remember how
much different like the s1s like from
Greenhouse are going to be from like say
I had one early Pearl clone that went
around San Diego
yeah
you know like there's a bunch of
different ones and I don't know how
similar they all were to each other and
I don't know how similar silver Pearl
was to like the early broke one I saw
you know what I mean yeah um yeah but if
if you want a basis for provenance like
that that perfect Pearl from killer
killer some of the best silver Pearl
work that there is with silver Pearl
though there's definitely some skunk one
in it in the in the smells but
it's it's
a world of other scents too so it's one
of the few skunk one lines that really
doesn't get too muddled down with skunk
one you know and silver Pearl
um
yeah I those lines would be perfect I
don't know anything about like I said I
don't know anything about the greenhouse
line and they're not very consistent and
they kind of um I mean they're not for
their bait and switching in the first
place so
you know you never know what you're
gonna get there uh but with Fifth Line
I've seen it run it used it read with it
it's amazing so I think that's an
amazing thing to start with
um as far as the unknown Indica I think
the big uh uh definitely a viable option
um there's not a lot of reading that
Neville did where he didn't disclose
what he was using and I tend to have the
sneaking suspicion and it's just like
from knowing Neville and talking to him
and you know
messing with them that I think you know
usually when I see things like unknown
Indica being referenced by Neville it
immediately makes me think oh he's
probably using Afghani one or something
from Sam
because he hated Sam this company so
much that like if there was anything
used to name his work yeah if there's
anyone who would strip
from it would totally be Sam you know so
um yeah all he ever did was don't talk
Afghani one but I swear to God he used
it a lot of stuff so
um and and named it other things called
it other things you know so that's just
a theory I know some of the other
partners share that theory with me too
separately yeah because Buckshot
mentioned that his guess was big bud but
I imagine that if it had been there's no
reason for it to not have been named
right yeah yeah especially at that point
yeah fascinating
I guess
I mean I had a thought here which is
also uh and because he doesn't mention
it with a buckshot himself has
um a sense of the Pearl that he wants to
capture
um or whether this is kind of like an
abstract almost like academic thing and
he doesn't actually have that experience
I think um his family had a early early
Pearl cut or seed line but they like
cherished so that's why they're going
back to 100 so I think they have a lot
of experience with the pearls so that'll
be a tremendous help you know obviously
like if you have a ton of experience
with early Pearl and you're running
through a bunch of silver Pearl crosses
that's going to be
tons of help you know to select away
from the skunk one and everything else
cool all right
well Buckshot I guess you got to keep us
updated on how this goes yes please do
shout out to Buck and his wife
yeah I hope you're doing well buddy
okay
um
so this is a a bit of a broader question
Matt and this one has more to do with
the industry and maybe
ethics and philosophy a little bit as
well but Australia so
this is from squirrel okay and he asks
what's the difference between the
breeder a seed maker and a seed company
he also wants to talk uh he also wants
to ask you about ghost breeding
um yeah
and uh there's more to the question that
concerns uh Josie and subcool but maybe
I don't know do you want to like include
that no kind of just address his first
question yeah we'll do the first one
first
yeah okay so this is something like I've
spent a lot of my career trying to
not necessarily educate people on but
try to help Define this for the
community
and and make it very clear that there
are different categories
um so that when people are shopping they
understand who they're buying from what
they're buying and all of that and
that's the difference between a breeder
a seed maker what's the last one
they said Seed Company
I guess maybe that could mean like a
potentially like a seed bank maybe yeah
okay so yeah let's do breeder let's do
breeder Seed Company seed bank
seed maker Seed Company same thing to me
um
so a breeder let's start with a breeder
there is rarely going to be anyone who
can actually call themselves a breeder
in cannabis even though our show is
called the breeder syndicate
like realistically looking at
agricultural breeding I can't call
myself like a real breeder I don't sit
there and work a line for 25 years bring
it to Market you know like hunt Sports
in a line like all that stuff to me
that's very much breeding breeding
um in cannabis though we kind of
considering what we've had you know and
and who's led the way and and how
they've done it
bring has been a lot different from our
cultural perspective right it's so much
different than AG so the breeders in our
community tend to be what we consider
the people who have worked many lines
multiple Generations you know they start
with a goal they look at their Tools in
their toolbox be it clones or seed lines
and they say what can help me get to
this goal and then they you know they
use those tools and work until they meet
that goal it could be several
Generations in or it could be one
generation but that's that's breeding
breeding is just goal-oriented selection
to me
um
then there's seed making
and anybody can make seats
like that's not
that's not a secret like anybody can
make seeds and anybody can make seeds
that turn out decent
anybody can make seeds that turn out
insanely fire
um but seed making isn't necessarily
breeding
while you are making seeds while
breeding a seed maker is one in our
community the definition would be one
who makes seeds but they're not really
into the selection they're not really
working lines they're doing you know
one-off crosses here they are boom you
know it's and it's a very valid way of
um
selling seeds like most of the market is
this I'd say 99.9 of the market is this
I do a lot of this one-off crosses here
they are if you want to take it further
feel free if not you know drop it
um I think it's the most common thing
you're gonna run into in the seed world
is seed makers now you can have seed
makers that do breeding projects I would
say that I've done that
um but I've done more seed making
projects than breeding projects and I
think that's the majority of our
community
and then you have something like a seed
bank and a seed bank is somewhere where
you can go and get
the idea would be that you can go and
get a multitude of different options of
lines from a seed bank
um usually a seed bank hosts many
breeders
in cannabis in our culture that's how
it's usually gone down but then there
are some breeders like CSI that are so
prolific that you can literally get
almost any cross from them and they
become a seed bank in themselves they're
so prolific that's a rare rare
occurrence I mean there's people who
claim that they do that but there's not
really yeah yeah
um that would be the overall rundown on
that off the top of my head like the
main differences is goal oriented versus
um just strictly production and uh yeah
I know I didn't go into ghost breeding
yet
yeah I guess that that's like a natural
next yeah
step so I guess this is when um the seed
making itself or breeding I guess is
outsourced to someone else right yeah so
a lot of us have done this I've done it
I um I see no problem with doing this
for people I like to be transparent
about it but a lot of people that hire
me
don't want me to be transparent about it
and that's fine too because it's their
prerogative how they how they move their
seeds and sell their seeds isn't up to
me I just want to make so just to
clarify Matt you mean that you've um
you've done some ghost seed making slash
breeding for other people yeah for other
seed companies yeah yeah and and made
seeds for them they sold it under their
name you know and let them rep that as
their strain and and you don't really go
around telling people that you made it
because
you got paid up front and that's your
goal is to just do that and their goal
is to be the seed maker
um
it's it was a lot more common
um to see back in the day like things
like that I don't really know what's
going on today most of the ghost
breeding quote unquote ghost breeding is
done in Spain or in Colombia and people
are buying their seeds bulk from there
and I I spill I spilled this out in
other episodes but essentially like in
the in the mid 2000s the way it worked
was you know like Amsterdam would Source
out people were already making seeds in
Spain and they were making crosses of
things like random Northern Lights I
remember that the plant just said NL in
the in the um Buddha seeds room
um uh orange bud
uh White Widow AK-47 uh White Russian
White Rhino
blueberry
hash plant
like there's a lot of things like that
just normal generic things that you
would have seen in like scentsy's
catalog back in the day is what they say
they have in Spain and they make crosses
of all of these feminized crosses of all
of them every single which direction and
then the the Dutch company's given a
catalog and they'll look through it and
they'll say oh this is the closest to
what my Cali missed was or this is the
closest to what uh the White Rhino
hybrid we had was or this isn't even
close to gelato but [ __ ] it it's cheap
let's put it in there people will know
the difference a la Barney's Farm you
know like uh their people Punch or
whatever you could name any of their
their work
um work
um but yeah that's essentially how it
worked back then and they would go
through it they would try to find
something that was similar genetically
similar and that would be good enough
and you know 2005 on anybody that bought
anything from Amsterdam from any Dutch
company that's what happened they all
Outsource that's it was done it's a y
it's a wrap Spanish is Spain Spain's
making everything everything's now
confused because everything's being
relabeled and renamed you know so think
of all the Breeders post 2005 that were
using Dutch genetics to make their
hybrids
so Matt like from from the point of view
of these uh companies with seed banks uh
Outsourcing the stuff or you know kind
of picking from these catalogs the
incentives for them are quite clear it's
obviously going to be cheaper and blah
blah finally
I'm curious then this is a tangent for
you when you were doing it what was the
incentive for you or like why would you
have gotten into it
um why does one get into that so when I
got into it it was because I had small
spaces and the places that wanted me to
do these reversals had massive spaces so
even though they were choosing what I
got to work with
like I got to see massive populations of
done in these big reversals that I was
doing so my main motive was that just
getting to see populations grown and
traits and all of that didn't matter
what it was as long as I was getting to
see massive populations because that was
my goal was to see massive populations
and how and what what comes of it you
know yeah um yeah and so there were some
interesting benefits for you yeah and
sometimes it would be friends you know
like friends that had seed companies
that were down at the time and couldn't
make the seeds so I just be like [ __ ]
I'll glue it out there and do it you
know they knew that I'd do it and do it
right and
yeah so if any of you are still hiring
you know I do I do it
I don't know how many I don't know how
many seed companies are still in
existence after this uh fallout but yeah
I mean that was a big thing for a long
time uh making Femme seeds for other
dudes so they could sell them
yeah yeah and I I think you know uh in a
way when you first when one first hears
about this it might seem
immediately like it's a
scummy or kind of a scammy thing but not
necessarily right like it can it can be
super innocuous like that in that
situation when I do it like I'm using
the real clones to do it so you're
getting the product that you think
you're gonna get it's not like uh
you know like they outsourced it you're
getting calumist white rhino when you
think you're getting wedding cake you
know what I mean like it's you're
actually getting what you're supposed to
be getting the only transparent
transparency that's not there usually is
who made it and most of these guys that
I did this for don't even really
communicate with the public to say that
they made it or didn't make it it's just
assumed it's inferred because they're
such big companies They Don't Really
interact you know so okay so that's an
important distinction to make as well
that even within this
um Endeavor of ghost breeding or
Outsourcing seed making that there's
still a difference as it as it as there
is with actual breeding uh between the
people who are using
um the real materials and know what
they're doing versus the people who
don't yeah and there's one other thing I
definitely want to to put out there too
is that like
Spaniards got [ __ ] on a lot because they
were the ones making the seeds that the
Dutch were selling but
the the Spaniards did really good work
like I think they were very confident
the guys who were making the bulk seeds
over there were very competent
um they were some of the first pioneers
doing massive massive Femme reversals
over in Spain so I have a lot of respect
for those dudes a lot and it's just
unfortunate how it played out because
like in Spain it was just a bunch of
dudes with like no ego at all that
wanted to make seeds and that's it they
just wanted to make seeds and they
didn't care about a name they didn't
care about getting famous at all yeah
and yeah
right
the honest was I guess more on the the
people using these seeds and selling
these seeds on and what how they
represented them right absolutely yeah I
mean if there's no transparency it makes
it kind of hard right like you think
that Barn there's a guy named Barnegat
Barney's Farm doing all this killer
breeding right like yeah
yeah
Barney and Berner and there is no Barney
I wonder who Barney is
he doesn't even exist there's a guy
named Gary somewhere
yeah
okay that's cool I think actually those
were a couple of good insights that um
you kind of have talked about these
things before but maybe not in that much
depth so that's cool those were cool
anecdotes yeah um ghost breeding so it's
a tricky thing because like I said yeah
it's political
um
you know and and the weird thing was
that I've got accused of like buying
bulk seeds from Spain and selling them
and I was like for for a company to have
to do that like you have to be a pretty
wealthy company moving a lot of seeds to
make that a viable method for doing it
because you're buying bulk so you're
spending like 20 grand
I don't have 20 grand like to be buying
bulk seeds like you know so it just even
financially and economically it would
never make sense for me to Outsource
some not that big you know like
yeah like there's no reason to Outsource
um the kilowatt hours in Spain versus
the US was and the land prices in rent
was why a lot of people chose why Spain
ended up being the place to do all this
the permissiveness
um because it was wasn't super permitted
but it wasn't super
attacked
um by the local police there and the
kilowatt hour and the space is why and
and it's also why Colombia opened up too
and why Colombia is starting to produce
a massive amount of these seeds down
there for the Breeders up here the seed
makers like uh the compounds or whatever
of the world
uh another tangent
um and I mentioned to you that just
before we start a recording that I
watched the burn a video about visiting
Thailand to open the cookie stores there
but I also wonder next what Thailand is
going to
you know what kind of platform or um
possibilities Thailand is going to
introduce so I'm going to say something
very very it might hurt a lot of
people's feelings it might be a little
spicy
but I saw
the worst of California
go to the world go and be the worst in
Colorado and then they went to Michigan
the same people and then they went to
Oklahoma and now they're all in Thailand
like it's just like been this
downward slide of failure and of refuse
all going to Thailand there's good dudes
there too like the good dudes went but
like
a lot of Bad Dudes went a lot of bad
dudes that just ripped people off along
the way in all these states all ended up
there so I'm very interested to see how
that plays out because it's like they
went there because they think it's
[ __ ] Lawless and they get away with
some crazy [ __ ] you know but yeah I I
just don't know I don't know I don't
know if they know what they're in for
either
maybe uh either later in the year or
even 2024 we can try and Wrangle a
Thailand update from someone everybody
there I have everybody there right now
yeah that would be that would be really
interesting
um
to watch his journey it's rough dude
like when he first got over there
um I'm talking about HBK uh we
interviewed him right before he moved
and um just watching his journey on
Facebook just like even adapting to the
food and water was brutal to watch him
he just got so [ __ ] up by that place
you know like there's so many things
that I wouldn't even think about when
thinking about moving to Thailand to
grow like just basic food survival stuff
that our American stomachs can't take
you know things like that
yeah okay well I I think this could be
an interesting episode so maybe imagine
I can discuss this later yeah
okay well coming back to school's
question and I uh was there anything
else you wanted to say on ghost breeding
Matt before we moved on to the second
part
just that it's more prolific than than
most people know like
you know like it's it's hard to not name
names
because
people really think these people make
their seeds but like
the biggest sellers the people who make
the most money in seeds the compounds
the seed Junkies you know name a few
names
they don't make their seeds they're not
breeders
they have other people make them at
these facilities that are [ __ ] trash
you know like and they don't give a [ __ ]
who's making the seeds they just need
seed to put in a in a shell to sell as
long as there's a physical seed there
they're good because they don't give a
[ __ ] what happens to it afterwards as
everybody saw it with the Candy Rain
cookies you know like yeah nobody cares
but yeah that's it is the majority of
what people have in their collections
was made
ghost bread it was Ghost bread or made
in Spain or Colombia and they just have
no clue
yeah and so I guess like like you were
implying earlier ghost breeding in and
of itself isn't a good or bad thing
um it's a context and in some contexts
it's perfectly innocuous in another
context it's perfectly insidious
insidious it's as Insidious as you can
imagine in some contexts but um yeah
yeah it's um it's very mild it's just a
matter of well
you know at least you get what you got
yeah
it seeds it's almost the best you can
hope for anyone it's sad oh well at
least you got what you [ __ ] paid for
I mean maybe you know maybe it wasn't a
dude
his face was on that picture smiling at
you but at least you got what you paid
for and that's like that's sad that's
the best we can hope for really like
like it's hard to hope for a breeder who
will like write you back and be like
okay well if you're interested in this
line you know like here's some traits
and blah blah blah that that doesn't
happen I hear about it all the time
people email me and I'm like dude I'm
surprised you even responded I've never
had anybody respond before
you know yeah but it's because people
don't understand it's not because
they're busy people just don't know how
to answer the questions they don't have
answers to the questions that you're
asking it's about bringing stuff
and that's a reality like it sucks to
say and people are probably gonna get
pissed that I said it but it's a reality
it really is
yeah so it's a great question because
it uh
it sums up quite a bit uh it does the
industry I think it's one of the most
important topics to to probably recover
every now and then just because there's
so many new people coming in that don't
know that big massive part and when it
was going on during the mid-2000s I was
jumping up screaming stomping my feet
[ __ ] screaming it from the rafters
and that's when I was getting banned
from every Forum back then
it wasn't something that everybody knew
it was never it was never an Open Secret
back then even like it just wasn't
talked about you weren't allowed to talk
about it like
you know it's just yeah
Maybe
every year or every six months they're
they're certain certain topics that are
worth revisiting maybe like I think
that's a good good call
we can okay it's finally I just off the
top of my head right it would be fun to
like
uh get a Euro your Europe update be fun
to get a Thailand update it'll be fun
for you to do a reflection on the uh
American industry you know what I really
want to do too is a prediction episode
each year
predicting what's going to happen as
well what companies will do what what
companies will still be around and yeah
I think that'll be fun
yeah a little spicy
okay okay let's so
squirrel's second question which is
related also has to do with some of the
politics politics and complexities of
you know running these companies sure
um
and he wants to know about
the legacy of breeders or seed makers
who have died and some of the messes or
complications around that like do you
have any
yeah so
I think like the main one that most
people think of when it comes to messes
after people pass would probably be
Gorilla Glue
um
Josie Josie and Loan
I don't use a real name everybody knows
their names but I'm Josie and Loan
um are the people responsible for
Gorilla Glue and
near the end they had tried to do a
legal company and there was a lot of
like cease and desists sent out saying
you can't use Gorilla Glue for clone
which is a clone that was passed to
everyone and anybody that was using it
they were saying cease and desist too
they didn't do it to me because we were
friends
um but it wasn't even necessarily Josie
and lone that were doing it they they
had hired some legal stuff and you know
they had a friend named Kat who's super
nice I got along with cat real well
um nice person and she ended up being
who had Gorilla Glue after they both
passed
and um yeah it was just wild it was
different it was political I know
um I sat on my gorilla glue for hybrids
because me and Josie were gonna release
it as a collab and then after we passed
there was some lawsuits going on with
the company I'm like [ __ ] this I'm not
dealing with this [ __ ] you know I don't
get wrapped up in some lawsuit so uh I
just sat on him forever you know um
I know CSI like I I won't even
he he released Gorilla Glue in
collaboration with Josie and made sure
that his family's still getting money
for it too which I think is so
commendable there's all different ways
it's done
um
and it's just you know it really depends
up to the person how they handle it but
it's it's also that how the community
reacts
I think
um
that is to say like
you can't really ask these breeders that
are passed away you know like if you can
use their work right and like a lot of
times you know Suns pop up like we saw
with uh bog he actually had a real son
and then we had fake Sons pop up after
they died pretending to sell his gear
this has happened so many times after
people pass
happened with zochi when he passed
someone was claiming to be him selling
his seeds goat monkey
it's horrible it's one of the most
disgusting horrible things I've seen and
it's more a recent Trend when people die
for someone to pop up pretend to be
their son and sell their seeds
um but yeah it's been happening a lot
that's that's one weird segment of this
uh question
as far as like for me
uh using lone star's blue bonnet and
specifically because me and Lone Star
weren't tight we weren't enemies by any
stress to imagine we never argued or
anything but um
we weren't tight like we weren't friends
and I wasn't close with his friends that
are still around
so approaching the blue Bond stuff was
kind of weird for me and it still is to
this day because like I want to make
sure that he gets as much respect as
possible because it was beautiful work
that made all of the blueberry stuff
that I do that is so super blueberry he
did all of the work that made all that
possible and you know like when when I'm
looking at my posts people want to give
me credit and the whole time I'm like
but I didn't really do much you know but
people want to give me credit and I
don't know how his friends feel about
that because I don't want to so you take
credit for it but it keeps getting put
on me you know what I mean like
there it's complex it is so complex but
in the end like I just try to think
about it from my own perspective like if
I'm gone and the stuff that I had
anything to do with is still passing on
and people are still saying my name then
that's Magic
that's the only way you still live right
yeah
yep
I look at it but some of the people may
look at it different you know um
yeah people Sue each other over this
[ __ ] so
yeah
did you want to mention TGA or talk to
speak to TGA
I mean sure yeah uh
I mean that was a that was a hard one I
you know he's even hard to talk about
after passing you can't like let alone
not even talking about using his
genetics just speaking about it
um
because of all the things that happened
prior like right before last two years
um got pretty wild and hairy and humans
were human especially when they find out
they're no longer living some will make
amends with people and some will live
their life to the fullest that they see
fit you know and that's kind of what
happened there
um mostly what I see though in cannabis
is people being Sanctified after they
pass
um maybe unjustly Sanctified in many
ways
um and if you notice and like they give
they're given sainthood
um yeah
yeah I see that a lot like oh this guy
he was such a [ __ ] amazing breeder
collector he was legit newest [ __ ] and
it's like what
when he was alive he was one of the
biggest you know like not now you're
talking about just there's a lot of this
there's a lot because I mean people are
complex and not everybody's a good human
their whole life and some people are
really bad humans
um most of their life but when they die
in cannabis for some reason they get
sainthood though I think some people may
not see that same fate you know just
kind of I mean who you are even people
who are alive get that same Hood I mean
they may not deserve it yeah that's very
true that is very true
sainthood going on
uh yeah don't as we always say you know
um be very wary of having Heroes
kick over the statues so I say no don't
worship any statues don't have any
pedestals
because breed like breeders are all [ __ ]
ups like most of us are ex-junkies too
like whether whether they admit it or
not like most of us like have Shady pass
so a bunch of [ __ ] ups there's nothing
to look up to that's for damn sure
myself on a positive note I it is worth
kind of reiterating what you said before
which is that you know one of the least
I think or one of the um
one of the best things you could do is
just continue to gesture towards the
people whose work your work depends on
like in general whether they're whether
they're dead or alive exactly yeah I
always get always give thanks and just
not even just give thanks but just be
thankful in general like have that in
your heart like don't just say it like
how did your heart can carry with you
like in your projects like with the Lone
Star stuff like
I I try to think about that all the time
like I don't I don't let that slip from
from the picture you know and maybe
that's why I don't get ego with it
because it's not
you know what I mean like just have it
in your heart Harry carry that with you
don't just say it do it
yeah and I think I think for I said The
Syndicate it's clearly like a core value
to acknowledge
um that we are just one point on like a
long line of points you know in through
running through time
and that like
we wouldn't be here
without a lot a lot of a lot of my uh
Focus has been like trying to find
things that other breeders had already
made years ago that's been lost so it's
like
you know like things were made a long
time ago that were so good that we're
still digging them up like someone was
doing it right back then so good that
way better than what we have now even
you know so yeah
I don't know kind of a tangent
no it's cool I think it's you know I
think occasionally it's nice to have a
bit more of a like philosophical you
know ethical reflection on these things
so I think yeah breeding breeding ethics
is a uh one that I used to get asked a
lot on the live feeds you know about
breeding ethics how do you know if it's
okay do you ask a breeder
um you know that that's a I mean it's a
hard one to do because so many people
have different answers people go online
and they see breeders have different
reactions to people using their stuff
like I I almost like think it's silly
when people ask me if they can use my
stuff from stuff they bought for me you
know like but I know they're doing out
of respect but like for me like if you
bought a pack of seeds it's yours
whatever hell you want with it I don't
care whose it is you know like we put it
out there it's there to be put out and
if you use it that's
that is a her name's getting carried on
like if you use it there's nothing more
like to me special than seeing someone
that found something so unique and
special they wanted to bring it into
something and make it theirs
that to me is the ultimate win for a
breeder so when people get mad when
people like use males from their line or
use a female from their line or whatever
and want to kick back like to me it
blows my mind because the the
the respect has already been paid there
by them wanting to use it
maybe that should be another recurring
episode every year or so yeah probably
um
yeah ethics and morals in
2023.24 yeah they definitely change over
the years I'll tell you what they have
changed it might be a good thing to
revisit
like the name game changed completely
the name the name game that used to be
one of the most deadly serious games we
played in breeding was when we were
picking names making sure we didn't step
on any [ __ ] toes and at one point it
was pretty there were still names out
there you could use that hadn't been
reused if they weren't super obvious you
know you could have uniqueness in your
name still
um but you know if you weren't too
creative it was very easy to step on
toes and it wasn't like it is today
where people were like whatever you know
uh because there's so many names you
can't avoid but you're using names now
back then like people took that very
serious with like messaging people watch
your head like you better change that
now or else
you know yeah so yeah that's another
thing that's definitely changed it is uh
our policy today is were you here before
me okay if not [ __ ] kick rocks kid
that's the way I look at it you know are
you here before me okay then you don't
get to choose the name you don't get to
keep the name the dick move we gotta
start somewhere you know yeah
okay whoa slight change of pace we come
back to a much more practical set of
questions I think
okay
um simple one I think from freezeblade
you know when do you think is the best
time to pull to to take clones or to
take cuttings off plots
it depends
and what by it depends I mean any number
of factors is it a Seedling mom is it a
clone mom if it's a Seedling mom you
know is it going to [ __ ] up the whole
structure of the plant if I take the
Clones or am I not really worried about
that like there's many reasons like that
that I go into when I'm taking clones or
things that I take into account like is
this going to be something that I'm
flowering out am I taking clones in a
specific spot from the plant to make it
have a specific structure when it's
flowering you know yeah because that's a
big part of what what part of the plants
clones I'm taking how many I take the
shape of it that all goes into it
usually for me I wait till it's about
two to three feet tall before I start
making clones you know some people do it
at the first two nodes you know like
once there's a leaf material to take and
there's a node bam take it
um you know anything like that you can
get in that context do you see have you
experienced or observed um maturity
playing a very big role in the success
of routine
or not necessarily
um you know nothing that I could like
not good anecdotes that I could give but
I'm sure there is you know hormonally a
plant changes over time so I'm sure I'm
sure there is but yeah what I'm talking
about they're already so big at that
point that you're not really worried
about the maturity as much I mean uh and
when I run my plants I usually run uh
veggie 24 hours light almost always I I
can't think of a situation where I've
been running anything less than 24 hours
in Veg it's constant constantly on and
the reason I do that is because I also
do a lot of re-veging
um yeah and do in saying that like I
mean my plants grow pretty fast uh in
veg because the lights are on 24 hours
so yeah um
two to three feet
they're not you know there's no heavy
pre-flowering going on so yeah
what do you think of uh people taking
cuttings in the flowering stretch I know
that's quite common slash popular as
well I guess because you know you get so
much like extra vegetative growth often
that you have to get rid of anyway
um what do you think of pulling cuttings
at that point
um so what point are you talking about
later in flower or early in flower no
sir during the flowering stretch first
few weeks okay yeah no that's great um a
lot of times they'll have stems that'll
root better too
I don't know why but like they have what
are your stems and for some reason I I
have better luck with Woody or stems
like that or harder stems
um and hormonally I think they're for
whatever reason they're more able to
root at that stage hormonally because
they do root faster I found that out
just by process of
like
thinking I had something backed up and
clones backed up going to flower
something starting in flower and
realizing oh [ __ ] I don't have any more
clones of this and then having to take
loans that way that's when I started
realizing that there was kind of a
difference between how fast they would
root how well they would root
um and the type of routes they gave off
even you know what I mean so yeah that's
I've run into that that just by
happenstance you know but it is
effective
when you take cuttings at that point do
you have to deal with re-veging or not
really it just depends sometimes but but
usually it's not a very super long rib
Edge if anything it's like a week or two
Max but um if you get it at the right
time not usually it'll it'll revert
pretty quick
it's cool yeah nice
that was uh
good juicy bit of info I love re-veging
I love it I it makes me sad when people
say that they don't do it I don't know
why it's just to me it's so easy to do
and I I just I don't have a lot of
talents in life
um but okay even when it comes to
Growing like there's I don't have a lot
of talents when it comes to Growing but
I'm like better at this than anyone else
or better at that than anyone else but
I'm really good at revenging and I'm
really good at popping seeds like those
are two things that I can do
exceptionally well and re-veging to me
like
it's something I could teach anyone at
any time and it's as long as you follow
like a few simple [ __ ] rules anybody
could do it anytime as long as you can
put your lights on 24 hours guaranteed
yeah but a lot of people do have trouble
with it and I don't understand it
um
I don't know it's just one of those
things I've never gotten why people
black troubles or veggies yeah awesome
technique I guess to me you have to be
very patient
yeah I guess to me the main costs of
re-veging would be space and time right
um and money
and money well yes yeah but the 24-hour
light like a lot of people don't want to
do that because it's like doubling your
flower cycle of money you know what I
mean yeah it can get uh and get more
expensive that extra six hours of hour
hours of light a night is uh
okay
that was a good one okay
um we can move on to Digger's question
and I I think you had a sense of what
he's asking here I'm not entirely clear
okay it says pros and cons of steering a
line or clone with males a color
flowering time and stability of the male
or males use
so so what he's talking about I think is
using like using the mail
and breeding using the mail as basically
a stud using are all of his traits onto
the females and yeah I mean you could do
it it's you can do it with a female or
with a male it doesn't really matter
there's no set there's nothing set with
like all males
bring this straight all females breed
this way you know like there's nothing
it is so variable down to the the plant
and environment on what traits are
passed
that like
it's it's a very hard question to answer
but yes you can absolutely you know like
with the Bonnet stuff that's exactly
what I did was bringing towards the nail
that was it was what you which you would
actually consider a stud because I
wanted everything to be blueberry that
he touched and yeah and historically
it's been done a lot right yeah this is
a very common passion
um
yes and no yes yes in the way of like
skunk one
um was used as a male a lot nl1 was used
as a mail a lot by Neville but overall
there's been a lot of seed making with
males there's not been a lot of breeding
done with a male for trait selection
like that
true
yeah good distinction yeah
okay
that's a good question
um anything else on that if not we
cannot I think that's good
Stone root what are your thoughts on
convergent evolution through breeding
starting with rather different cultivars
by ending up in the same place through a
series of generations uh he says similar
to crabs in the ocean have you
experienced this I mean okay one thing
I'll say though right away is that crabs
in the ocean were not bread yeah they
evolved yeah um and I know what he means
he means that like throughout the
different
eras of creatures on the planet quite a
few different
um species I don't know how the right
taxonomy here but quite a few different
species have kind of converged on a
similar morphology a very crab-like
morphology throughout time
um I don't know if that is conflatable
with breeding because breeding is
actually active because he said two
different cultivars but that would mean
they were both cannabis
I think the crab thing was meant to be
an analogy I'm just kind of explaining
why the analogy doesn't really make I
know but like with this question he said
two different cultivars but it sounds
like you just said with different he
just said with different cultivars but
so not even necessarily cannabis is he
talking about just can't two different
candidates yeah yeah sorry he does he
does mean cannabis I'm assuming yeah
so like I was saying to you before the
recording like the the most obvious
thing that comes to mind that it's not
breeding is what happens when you let
you just let cat like you know maybe uh
drug type cannabis like go wild right
yeah yeah you can watch it regress very
quickly to him to him in a few
Generations yeah but I don't know if you
this makes sense if you're talking about
it from a breeding perspective
I mean
the only thing I can think of from a
breeding perspective that even remotely
comes close to this is someone currently
Crossing Hops and cannabis
Cannabis sativa you know like right a
few different kind of semi-related
plants and finding a way to interbreed
them but it's not done evolutionarily
it's not done naturally it was done
through breeding
um
like what he's talking about takes
thousands and thousands and thousands of
years you know like Evolution I it's yes
for Humanity yeah yeah yeah unless we're
talking about major major like GMO type
stuff
um Advanced science techniques you know
um yeah and I wouldn't know anything
about that
no I think you make a really good point
like you can't really have Evolution and
breeding in the same like sentence they
don't work like they don't yeah they're
not simpatico
yeah
okay there you go nice and Loud there
you go move on to screwstone skate cross
question
okay this is an interesting one so he
says we uh men also have talked about
growing for seed versus going for flower
production
um but what about the difference between
having a what he calls a regular veg
setup uh versus a setup that's more for
uh preservation I guess uh you know
keeping moms
um how how different are those setups
or can they be how different can they be
from seed making to keeping moms
no I think he means like production like
what what are the difference between
differences between a setup that you're
using just to like grow plants to grow
plants for I guess for cropping
um versus a setup that's just for
keeping stuff okay so
if I were doing just cropping I would
probably be doing a lot in tables
a ton
um if I'm keeping moms you can't really
keep moms in tables I mean maybe you can
I don't know anybody who does but
usually like can you explain a bit why
um I mean because they get so big
you know you can't really have those big
monster moms in in tables especially if
you're keeping them around a long time
and it also depends like some people
like to
do clone of their mom clone of their mom
clone of the mom keep it small
constantly clone them on clone of the
Mom it's a lot of work you can do it
that way and keep it small
um and that's the way you could do it in
tables technically you could also use
tables and re-vege so there's not really
any
there's workarounds for every situation
but ideally like
if I'm if I if I have moms I have a
whole room dedicated to that of just
moms in pots in containers in Cocoa you
know
um
and then if I'm running production
whether it's usually if I'm running
production for me I do it all in the
same pot and stuff like that but it's
because I rent and if I owned a place I
would be doing all [ __ ] tables all
day all day long
um so I guess the only difference would
be how you keep the moms longer in a mom
room I don't really know like
yeah I think like you were saying
earlier it depends right it depends on
it depends on what constraints you have
yeah like if you don't have a lot of
space then you might have to resort to
what you were pointing out before like
what I call like serial cloning where
you don't actually have a mom that
you're constantly just taking clones off
you have like a chain you're you're
cloning and then taking a clone off that
clone and and doing that successively
through time I did that for years man I
did it for years that way Solo Cup moms
Bonsai moms which is horrible like I
didn't understand like
I didn't understand that I was like
super stunting [ __ ] and like then now
I'm gonna take that and breed with this
super stunted plant because I made a
bonsai mom out of it you know like I
didn't understand what I was doing back
then and I don't know that I don't know
the ramifications that has for the
future of what I made back then with
that and
yeah just thinking about that that was
yeah
recycled clones
that's actually a really big question
but I think we still don't really have
great answers for which is yeah like you
say if let's say you have a mom and then
you've kind of had to you've been forced
to uh stress slash traumatize it in
various ways to keep it small what kind
of impact that does have on clones you
take off it later right and or even the
seeds that you make with it
epigenetically yeah
yeah
yeah you know I don't know what happened
there
yeah so maybe this is something you know
if anyone in the community has an idea
um or has seen any theory around this
like definitely let us know Chimera if
you want just let me know
yeah
uh I guess the other side of this in
terms of setup is like I can think of
things like
um basic things uh that you probably
have already thought through like what
kinds of other differences in like say
light intensity the feeding I know
you've covered a bit of that but yeah
feeding definitely
light intensity here's a weird one a
kind of it's on the topic but kind of a
tangent a lot of us are getting news
like a lot of us I mean like the oldest
ones of us are just getting used to LEDs
now or just getting to try them for the
first time and it is so [ __ ]
different like how the plants eat and
everything it's so massively different
so yeah interesting there are a lot of
things to take into account too just
from light intensities on Feed and all
that [ __ ] not just for breeding but for
anything you know
yeah and that's I'm someone who's only
ever had LEDs you know yeah yeah see
that's a trip for me like I started on
magnetic ballasts and t5s and [ __ ] like
that and like I still have t5s that I
would use because I'm [ __ ] old and
like I think that's a legit technology I
don't know I never I've never moved on
to LEDs mostly because I'm broke and
cheap but
if anybody wants to be an LED sponsor
get a hold of me
there you go Gotta use this [ __ ]
absolutely
okay anything else about the differences
between you know keeping plants for an
archive versus keeping plants for
production any changes in your obviously
there's a different mindset you know
obviously it's a different strategy
um
okay or if nothing else there we go all
right no I can't think of anything else
we can move on to South Coast Canada's
question
random one but does a male have
different traits as a okay I guess what
he's asking here is uh how differently
can a male plant but I think it doesn't
have to be just about a male how
differently can a plant Express when
seed ground versus like you know uh as a
cutting
vastly different vastly different it's
why I always say like if you're really
serious about it
about like a line and hunting through it
do run at all as seeds flower them and
then run it as clones before you toss
them because sometimes that change might
be so drastic that the Terps changed so
far that it you might have already
tossed a keeper if you haven't run it
the second time can can you break this
down a little bit Matt because I know
that like in the past whatever I
remembered you saying like I know for
example that the expression of um
intersex Expressions change a lot right
um but now you're actually saying that
even
Expressions might be different sent
um internode spacing all kinds it's
because it's there's so many different
hormones packed into that seedling mom
which is why it grows so different and
as you as it ages as you take clones of
that those hormones start to wear out
you know and and you get to see a
totally different plant it just grows
totally different as a as a clone
different root system everything
yeah another thing like that for me
anyway I don't really mean science
there's no main Taproom on a on a clone
you know like there's not like that big
hard main Tapper like a Seedling gets
this is another one where I think you
know there probably is quite a lot of
science underneath and oh yeah again if
anyone can chip in on this topic we
could probably revisit this because it
is quite an interesting and big one I
think awesome
okay
um was there anything else in terms of
differences that you could think of just
you know beyond the fact that they are
going to be potentially pretty major
ones
any anecdotes in particular Matt that
you can think of or
um I mean it's just something that we
see every single time that we run a
plant like every single time it's going
to change from um seedling and not all
of them change drastically some some are
real minor changes just you know a
little leaf shape
um width sometimes you'll just see that
or a little bit stockier a little bit
longer but sometimes it can be Worlds
Apart you know um that bubble gum clone
of the Northern Lights 5 was so pink
bubble gum when we first got it
yeah you're mind blown right but as a as
a clone
about Third Generation in it's a lot
less pink bubble gummy a lot less
it's one of those examples
yeah this is a this is a fascinating
topic I think yeah oh yeah a lot of
complexity here it's a ton and and it is
very sciency we've got a couple of
questions from in the wind and I think
generally what I get from in the wins
questions here is he's taken into
account some of the theory that we've
explained in the previous episodes
and on some of the complexities of
breathing like we pointed out there are
uh linked linked traits I.E genes that
are linked or grouped together for
whatever reason
um
and you know the inverse of that we
talked about I think where we you could
even have multiple genes controlling a
single trait yeah um and so for me the
vibe I get from him is like okay that
that that sounds like breeding is like
impossible or like intentional breeding
is impossible because of these
conditions and obviously it's it it's
true that it's extremely difficult to to
make predictable
um but okay we'll get into his first one
which is
how much of our assessment of linked
traits and true breeding traits
um can actually be observed in like can
actually be observed full stop
um that's kind of what I see in this
question he says how much of it is like
visual
um and can be perceived through effect
all of its visual except for effect
yeah
trying to think am I correct in saying
that I think so like most of the traits
that we breed for
observable in some way except for the
high
that's always going to be variable for
every single person every single
different time like
trying to explain this to the the like
normal person who goes into a collective
they're so mindset on thing oh do I need
a sativa indica or hybrid you know like
that's where their mindset's at whereas
like in my mindset I'm at I wonder if
this Bud from this plant is going to
affect me the same way it did last night
when I was in a different mood because
in reality that's where we should be at
yeah like it's that variable
um yeah so trying to quantify high and
breeding for high very hard very hard
because you never know if the next
person is going to have the same higher
the same reaction and you don't know
that if you're gonna have the same
higher reaction the next time you smoke
it
um yeah so in some sense it can be
two variable to account for
yeah but there are variables we can't
account for and breed for it
yeah so this is one of those questions
where like there isn't a straightforward
answer yeah like it depends on what
traits you are interested in and of
course within within the tools that you
have like if all you have are your
observations then obviously you can only
um you can only depend on what You
observe to exactly your decisions like
this yeah there's just there's no magic
shortcut to that if you don't have
access to you know other kinds of
testing exactly the in this is where
knowing your baselines having experience
running out the baselines going through
populations in the baselines in for
Baseline see our previous episodes
recent episodes
um
having that experience will help you to
make those selections and see those
traits that you're looking for and know
okay well it reads about this common in
this line it's about that common so
hopefully I'll see it in this you know
roughly this percentage in this
population of this hybrid Etc you know
um the more you Lo know the lines you're
working with or clones you're working
with the more educated you can be about
making those distinctions and
projections
yeah
and I think we we did talk about this as
well which is that sometimes you do have
to go forward and then go backwards
because you just don't have any other
way of getting more information yeah
sometimes it's literally you have to run
the progeny and not everything's a hit
you know
yeah that's what it is
so his second question is I think we've
more or less covered it but I'll I'll uh
sound it out anyway okay so he said uh
yeah how reliable is a you know visual
uh sorry observable slash like smoke
test in the search for Unique
expressions
and then he kind of goes into like
uh is it possible for something to not
express the trait in its first
expression I guess it means in the first
generation and then for that trait to
appear in successive Generations
obviously yes right yeah very very much
so yeah
um Tower recessive's work you know they
pop up in the yeah and after these f3s
you'll never see them in the f1s
um or in that first generation crash as
I should say
um yeah that's that's that's
it that's that's a part of it you know
that's a major thing yeah and again I
perceive underlying this question his
his real question is how can I predict
this and it's like it's the same answer
it's like either you have very good
information and previous experience on
how what you're holding
um does pass and breathe exactly or
you're gonna have to actually
do some work
test the progeny and maybe do another
generation if that's why you're looking
you know if if you're trying to trace
something down Generations you just have
you can't avoid actually doing it yeah
essentially
you know in in to this point like
I would rather see someone pop
100 seeds in a very small space and
flower them small to get an idea of the
population then run two or three plants
really big to try to get an idea of what
a clone's like
yeah you know like if if people are
wondering like
which would be better which would be
more ideal which would give them the
most information
um the smaller plants would give you the
most information and that would be ideal
um smaller plants can be just as terpy
and potent as anything else and if we're
going for assessing and learning about a
plant
um you know as long as it has enough Bud
to get you a few [ __ ] bulls so you
can get a pretty good idea if it's even
a high you enjoy you personally enjoy
um
yeah I mean just flower them out little
clones little little seedlings it's easy
to do
yeah yeah so I guess my paraphrase for
that is whenever you are looking for
stuff you face significant odds and the
only strategy that's viable is to go
with numbers numbers always yeah
yeah okay
um
we can move on okay NJ grow guy is
asking a question that I think you know
is always the question in in a way
um what is the best way to go about
extending stock on a pack of seats I
have a 12-pack and want to make more so
I can grow them out again would you just
op that pack or would you go and select
um you know maybe do one-to-one with
like your favorite from the pack
um
so so I in this case you know what I'd
say I would say if you have like 12
seeds I'd run them all I'd keep clones
of each just in case
now if it's already an open pollination
there might not be a need to do a
successive open pollination unless it's
solely for preservation and like you
feel like the last person probably
didn't do that good of a job like if
someone just did it for five seeds I
would probably re-op it again just you
know just because to bring out more
examples but
um
yeah I don't know
open pollinations are are great you know
if this is solely for preservation do
open pollinations but there's some lines
where if like someone just didn't open
pollination and
it won't kill you to just do little
selections from it to make the seeds you
would be doing directional breeding in a
sense and start that direction narrowing
but I mean
if it's plants that you like as opposed
to just random and you've already run
them then yeah that makes sense
yeah yeah I think again this is one of
those like it depends and it comes down
to your constraints like yeah I imagine
the risk with OP is that I think we did
address this in the Theory episode as
well is that
it's easy to lose things
um and it's not to say that you've lost
them forever but that's why I say it
comes down to your constraints like you
have plenty of time in the future and
you know you're going to have lots of
time then maybe NOP is okay but
yeah exactly
if you like if you're doing an OP
strictly so you can do a big ass pop
this one line that makes sense to me but
if you're just oping it just to pop
three seeds that doesn't make any sense
yeah I think that's a good that's a good
simile statement yeah
okay
Petty cheetah
I've selected a stable female from an
intersex prone lion and outcrusted to a
male from a stable line
in your experience despite choosing a
stable individual how often do you think
the intersex traits from the female side
get passed into the progeny
it depends again because we don't know
if that trait is a late trait don't know
much about that trait you know like for
this particular example
um typically typically generally
speaking though if you're if you're
breeding away from intersex trades let's
say this line is very very
um aren't prone and you find a a male
from a line that's just super stable
sexually
um usually you're doing a great service
to line if your end goal is to have no
intersex trades that's that's what you
want to do so that that's that's the
best method for it if that's the trait
you're trying to like
suppress that's how you would do it
yeah
okay
uh squirrel again is asking
let me see
so I think his question is
we often address
uh traits such as you know the most
common ones like uh scent
and he's wondering like and we have
talked a bit about this before but
do you have much experience with people
who have bred for bud structure for
smoking specifically
no um not that I know of but I mean
maybe someone does out there that's an
actual breeder but I don't know of it
and I haven't had that discussion with
anyone however I've talked about it
because I I hate I [ __ ] hate with a
passion super dense Bud like I like to
break up I my preference has always been
to break it up by hand really easy you
know not not thumb it up super bad but I
don't know how to handle bud you know
but I like to break it up by hand and
pretty much nowadays I have to use a
grinder every single time because this
stuff is so dense
that it was just it's pointless to try
to break it apart like that and I don't
like [ __ ] that dense
um and a lot of customers don't eat it
because it's usually mold prone like
massively mold prone stuff like that so
yeah I was I was going to say that even
if people in their work haven't been
explicitly looking for
um flower structure relative to smoking
people certainly pay attention to how
prone flowers out to Bud rot
um this is true
so that is often the kind of
corresponding
consideration like it definitely is yeah
especially for the grower side more
dense more density means more mold so I
mean that's why I just can't I never
could believe that cookies blew up like
it did not only was it a smaller yielder
but the density just made it a mold
nightmare for people so yeah it just
blows my mind
I have a question here for you Matt
which you know you know the Indiana
bubble gum cut is often cited for being
really mold resistant yeah
do you uh in your opinion like is it
partly the structure of the flower that
contributes to that or is there other
are there other qualities you think I
mean I I it's it's destroy it's pretty
dense it's not as dense as like cookies
but it's very dense Afghanistan yeah
it's just one of those things where the
genetics it's just very mold resistant
it's yeah so it's an example where it
wasn't it wasn't it's not necessarily
because of the flower structure that is
exactly
okay like um a lot of the urn beer stuff
the Swiss sativa strawberry stuff also
tends to be mold resistant and I don't
like early on I was trying to figure out
if it was tied to its scent like
whatever the oils are in its glands you
know whatever I never figured it out but
strawberry stuff is extremely mold
resistant as well
interesting interesting
yeah because I guess yeah paraphrase of
that is
the other obvious way something can be
mold resistant is presumably through its
cannabinoid like balance and all that
yep
okay
um that might actually be the end of our
questions today Matt bruh
well we are at the end of the questions
I know that
you wanted to talk about something else
yeah
um which one should I talk about first
so did you want to talk about your your
recent experience with cereal milk
and tell us what that is and what I'll
tell you about my experience the the
rundown on it so
I wanted to check out some of these new
buds
because I had not tried cereal milk I
had not tried jealousy
there's a bunch I hadn't tried from a
lot of the hype stuff not just cookie
fam stuff but in general generally
speaking
um a lot of the newer stuff I haven't
tried and people ask me a lot about it
and my normal comment is well what is it
is cookies crust or cookies probably
trash you know like in my opinion that's
usually what you get
anyway I I got some
and I probably should have taken
pictures but I figured it's cereal milk
I'm probably not going to enjoy it so
I mean I was that confident that I would
not enjoy this stuff
I mean that is a bias coming with the
bias to not wanting to enjoy this and
now you're not wanting to but expecting
to not enjoy it
so the bud shows up I look at it it's
very dense looks like cookies cool
um expected
and the density is just exactly like I
hate hard to break up
and there's not a lot of scent to it I
was expecting cereal milk to smell like
the sweet end of OG that actually smells
like cereal milk so like I thought the
name would be apropos and some kind of
extension of that because that exists in
that line why would you not choose that
expression to represent it but they
didn't
um
I think the name is a misnomer scent
wise it was very
Bland
um Terps
which also threw me off as far as like
I'm expecting this to not be very good
it's Surplus in a sense
I can't really even pin down a scent for
you on what it smelled like it was just
ashy maybe at best so
I smoke it
and about 30 minutes in I'm already
expecting this thing to be over and I'm
like I'm actually enjoying this I'm
giggly
this is giggly weed
and it was strong I had been dabbing
diamonds and sauce all day and it broke
through and
it repeatedly did that until the very
last bowl
so
because I I spend so much time talking
about like cookies being the end of
breeding as far as like the the very end
of where you can take that line
um I don't know much about Snowman and
Wildlife obviously it's some kind of
cookies cookies you know
but I was impressed and I felt like I
like
even though
I want so badly not to say that cereal
milk is is decent like it was pretty
[ __ ] decent and I was surprised
um
yeah so because I talked so much [ __ ] I
had to actually you know man up and say
that it was it was good I was surprised
and and I'm gonna try to do that more
often grab some stuff now and then from
newer stuff and you know maybe do some
reviews for people so that they can see
it and get an idea of someone who's more
used to Old School strains what my
opinion would be on stuff like that if
it's worth a [ __ ] because I was
surprised I was hella surprised that I
would even run that clone it was that
good and even though it was turpless I
like I wouldn't if I was an extractor I
would never run that [ __ ] but the high
from it was exceptional and um I don't
think the grower was anything special
but I do think that I was exceptional so
yeah I got to give him props where it's
dude they had someone make them a good
line
and I guess it's still consistent You
know despite with what we say like
despite of course us enjoying bashing on
cookies for various good reasons yeah um
there's obviously no reason why
outlies within that you know can appear
and be good yeah it's just the part that
blew my mind though was that it didn't
look like anything different than a
gelato you know it looked nothing
different than gelato 33 you'd look at
it be like oh that's a lot of 33. you
know
the smell nothing to write home about at
all in fact it was one of the more
scentless buds that I've ever had
but for whatever reason and like that
totally shits on that Entourage effect
type thing right like it totally you
the opposite of how it should have
worked in my brain if that's real
um but it did it and it had a great
[ __ ] high like markedly great
something that I don't see in cookies so
yeah it's it's definitely
um that that clone at least or the the
example maybe maybe it wasn't even
cereal milk who [ __ ] knows it came
from a dispensary so God knows but I'm
pretty sure it was and uh yeah it was
impressive
what are the implications of this
statement Matt are you are you telling
everyone that cookies is great and that
I'm gonna blow burner is what's gonna
happen
I'm gonna make me he's my puppy I guess
I don't know what this means but it's uh
what it means is that I need to start
giving some of these new things a try
and see if if uh I can't break some of
my own myths that I have in my head
about them or I can't prove myself right
but I'm determined now to at least like
maybe once a week if I can afford it
because it's expensive man legal weeds
expense the taxes on this unreal unreal
so yeah
um I would like to do that though once a
week you know grab some grab one even
one or two things and um
you know like another thing that I got
that I'd like to talk about that blew my
mind to Mango Haze diamonds and it
didn't blow my mind for the reasons that
you think it would it blew my mind that
someone would grow like a 14 to 16 week
plant and then extract it down to
Diamonds
what the [ __ ] was that who came up with
that idea and why did I buy it but I did
I did and there was no scent to it
really it was just diamonds it didn't
have an exceptional high at all there
was nothing Mingo hazy about the high to
me you know like if it was used if it
was a real 14 16 week grown mango Haze
it was lost in the extraction but like I
don't see any of these people running a
14 to 16 week Haze and extracting it so
it's probably around an eight and
extracted you know and at that point you
just have THC diamonds and you could
have that from anything and it wouldn't
matter because there's no
nothing else with it except just THC and
that's a very very
specific High you know yeah so yeah it
was almost offensive that um mango Haze
diamonds existed and I couldn't believe
they existed and I even tried them in
hopes that they would be something good
that they they just were diamonds
yeah I can I can totally see why it's
offensive it's like sacrilegious like
yeah it is
why why like they could have done live
resin sauce and I've been like [ __ ]
dope but they did diamonds like straight
just THC diamonds
what
yeah in which case why would you use
something like mango Haze exactly why
not you could use anything on Earth to
do that why would you use a 14 16 week
plan yeah so that was my experience at
the uh local collectives there was some
um a funny tale was that the place where
I got the um Juicy Fruit tie clone
add Juicy Fruit on their menu again so I
was like what they're growing that again
okay so I was gonna order it but I
didn't
I I don't remember why because I was
buying everything else it was too damn
expensive I just you know whatever but
they gave me a full free ounce of their
Juicy Fruit and Holy balls was the most
moldy [ __ ] I've ever seen in my life
I couldn't even identify if it was juicy
fruit or not I'm like I had to be the
[ __ ] that hits him I was like hey
bro that stuff you're giving out it's
all moldy you might want to check that
like it doesn't look good like even
though it's free like you're repping
your business you know
yeah
but yeah I won't say which business
because they're nice and obviously they
have my address but
yeah I think that it's a great idea for
you to periodically I don't know how
often
um get some products to review I think
that's that's fun and like for me you
know I have no other connection to
dispensary land yeah right so if
vicariously live through it
yeah
yeah that's that's that was my
experience like um what else did I get I
got some something called Inferno OG
diamonds and that actually was like had
some really
loud loud OG sense to it in the diamonds
it was really [ __ ] impressive like it
was some of the best diamonds in the
sauce I've ever had but it was just
diamonds but I didn't really see any
sauce but it was so loud OG
um smelling it was exactly like I would
have wanted
um
there was some uh Mars OG the place was
selling and that was just absolute
garbage it was uh just really poorly
grown like Athena grown you know just
[ __ ] smashed with nudes
it was it was not good there's not like
a really nice OG scent to it like I like
or flavor that was gone it was just
earthy really disappointing to be honest
with you because I used to love Mars OG
that was a really good OG
um
I can't really think of anything else
that that jumped out that was uh of note
I had a jack hero live resin sauce that
wasn't that good it wasn't that special
it wasn't even that Germany which is
weird for a jack her Alive's resin sauce
but it was in there it just wasn't as
loud
um yeah overall disappointing I don't
really do collectives like I've never
really done that it had been a long time
and it usually if I'd ever got anything
from a collective it would be a clone if
it's something that interested me you
know like oh they got that there let's
see if it's it you know
um
but yeah what a trip man what a trip the
taxes
the trash level of it some of it
surprisingly though like I said
something was [ __ ] good I was
surprised I was able to get something
decent there yeah
I mean I guess you could say the same of
like collectives and dispensaries as as
you just did about as we did about
cookies in general like obviously it
doesn't mean that like they're all bad
and everything's bad it's just sure what
the likelihood is
um and yeah there's obviously still a
chance that you can get some
some good products what's funny is some
of my friends are the people growing
weed for cookies that goes in those
mylars you know like yeah some of it's
good so
well I don't know man is this a good
point to like
do a little bit of an outro
yeah I got the subscribers
yeah yeah yeah exactly that's what I
mean like okay yeah maybe this is where
we talk about
well we've decided that this is the end
of this season
um this episode that's one another
series end of everything bye we're done
finished we're out oh oh yeah that's
right
now we've covered everything man there's
nothing else to say about anything so I
mean thank God that's it for us yeah so
one thing I did want to point out is
that we just hit 7000 Subs which is
pretty cool yeah
it's
I'll tell you why I'm proud of it one of
the reasons is that I I occasionally go
and look at other cannabis channels
especially ones that I really hate and
one thing I've noticed that I think is
so absurd but also so unsurprising is
that some of these channels you go in
that you see they've got like 100 or
like 200 000 Subs oh yeah but then you
go and look at their the actual views
that they get on their videos and it's
like a couple of thousand every video
yeah and so a lot of these channels
don't have real subscribers or if they
do they're a tiny portion of the numbers
that they claim yeah and from what I've
loved seeing from our data our analytics
is that our subscriber base is real
because a good portion of people show up
every week
and so not only have we grown
organically we actually have a proper
regular following and I think that is
something that you can't
take for granted you know I don't think
that this I'm not trying to like
be too self-deprecating or anything but
you know what we the kinds of
information that we're interested in
um are very Niche so we may not get or
may not even want to have a hundred
thousand Subs no but to be able to
develop a proper close following with
regular people showing up I think that's
very special in content land I never
thought it would happen for um cannabis
genetics because it is so Niche it takes
certain type of personalities to be this
into learning about what you're smoking
why it's affecting you the way it does
and like keeping track like the whole
provenance of everything and just try to
get to the bottom that's that's weird
that's super [ __ ] weird there's not a
lot of weirdos like us out there so
every time that I see like our
subscriber count growing it tells me
there's more people that are fascinated
by this topic and deeply fascinated by
it at that and that it blows my [ __ ]
mind because I I just watching the
forums over the years you know just a
few hundred people interacting on each
one and that was the best you'd get and
a lot of them are really mean and
weren't there for good reasons and these
are all like our our community is
amazing absolutely amazing if I died
tomorrow it would run itself and that's
what's so [ __ ] cool
I absolutely love it
I don't I mean I I feel like that's
possibly an exaggeration I don't I don't
know if you could die at tomorrow and
this I just run but we'll see I mean no
hopefully we won't see sorry oh my god
um I'm calling it I'm calling um a hit
on Matt tonight yeah yeah it's good a
thousand-fold show from New Zealand
um live from New Zealand reader
syndicate
uh what was I gonna say I think okay I
think my paraphrase of what Matt just
said though is that what makes me happy
is that there are people who are
interested in finding out the truth or
at least as much of the truth as they
can because that's what we're into yeah
um and it is
it is heartwarming to see
um it is encouraging to see yeah
um the other side of
I think uh this ending the season on
this note um you know we we covered
the whole breeding series I think that
was really fun it was really
comprehensive and I found myself
actually quite exhausted afterwards and
like not knowing what what kinds what
other episodes we could do yeah
um
but but in saying that I think Matt and
I have some good ideas for uh the next
season yes
um we have we're also toying with some
like trying out some new kinds of
content I don't know if it'll actually
come to fruition but like we joked at
least about maybe doing reaction videos
to Strain Hunters or maybe like burners
like funny documentaries
um maybe maybe we'll see and I'm also
thinking about doing like watching UFO
videos and getting really [ __ ] up and
commenting on them as reaction videos
don't you already kind of do that yeah
but I don't record it
I don't like let people watch me do
stupid [ __ ] and talk over UFO videos so
it might be funny I say stupid [ __ ] when
I'm stoned
but yeah we've definitely also got a few
guests in mind a couple of whom we've
actually like lined up and and uh a few
more uh from we still need to line up
yeah but still plenty more good stuff to
come so you know what I love that this
season thousand fold got to figure out
how hard it is to run the show behind
the scenes yeah weekly people
communicate and like you know yeah it's
not as easy it sucks it's not and the
funny thing is that you know I can I
kind of look back on a week and and
count the hours and be like oh it's not
it's not that much but I think what
happened why it feels kind of like it it
stretches throughout the week is because
yeah the start of the week we we have to
decide what we're doing yeah then we
have to try to coordinate uh
like the planning and recording of it
and then of course it actually gets
published later in the week so it's
actually kind of like an endless cycle
and I'm like I think now I'm like now
that I've seen what I've seen I'm like
forcing Matt into more and more like
organization being like no we need to
start like scheduling things in advance
I'm Gonna Make a list like a schedule of
episodes that we can cover and
yeah he has no idea he's in I'm the I am
the opposite of schedule and
organization it's gonna be great yeah
it's gonna be great hey it's worked I'll
put it this way Matt's put up with like
Matt's kind of been really
um
open to like you know what I've had to
bring so far so I'm hoping oh yeah
that's good [ __ ] I'm stoked I think I
think everybody all the feedback has
been great for this season people have
really enjoyed the content they've
enjoyed
I think a lot of people have really
enjoyed being able to have some like
from point A to point B to point C to
point d as opposed to trying to look at
through my ADHD brain because it's
everything that I produce is very
[ __ ] if it's just left up to me to
bring it to be it's it's just how I do
things it's just random thoughts at all
times so I think people really have
enjoyed being able to like follow along
and actually follow along so yeah yeah
looking forward to the next season too
dude
absolutely me too
all right I guess that's it
yeah I think that's all I have to say
okay so um
you know go to righteous.com for your
spray seeds we carry stuff from all the
can Illuminati dudes
um goat farm I am Lonesome even got some
Panda stuff on the freebies probably
gonna have some Panda stuff in the
future like carried
um who else we got the Rev smell boat
CSI collabs with not so right now we've
got the um the few cherry pie collabs up
that they just did so go check those out
they just dropped and um of course our
community has really really been built
through our patreon Discord like
that's made of family that's made an
absolute family I love some of these
people like there's gonna be a lot of
lifelong friends built out of that place
and people really genuinely care about
each other taking care of each other
it's insane to see
um and you can be a part of that
um for as much as a coffee a month like
you can be a part of that and chill and
hang out with us and basically it keeps
the trolls out and it's a really awesome
place and yeah do you know roughly how
many
people we have as members on the server
I think it's about 500. I have no at
least on the Discord but yeah yeah
probably about that I would guess I know
it got up to 900 at one point and then
cleared it out I think that included the
Free People yeah the free people I mean
yeah you know what I mean they were free
yeah and occasionally we'll do that
again we'll open it up for free so
people can get like an idea of what goes
on in there and see if it's something
they're even into you know some people
are tentative about Discord and chat
rooms and interacting we have a lot of
people that just kind of you know Snoop
from the background and learn as they go
and don't interact much and that's
totally fine too
um and then there's people who get up in
the mix and you know don't shut up you
know it's a great community
because like either Shawnee is either
feeling really good about people and
wants to open it up yeah or he's been
like a total Troll and wants to open it
up so that he can like kick some people
so yeah we'll see which one you guys are
yeah yeah but yeah feel free to come
hang out with us anytime we do this like
I said it's not when I say 24 7 I don't
mean I'm literally in there 24 7. but
it's Discord so we pop in and out all
hours of the day all of us not so
included all of us you know
um so come hang out with us chill
sit for a while and hopefully you'll
enjoy what we have to to bring to
breeder Syndicate in the coming months
yeah yeah and and I just want to
reiterate like if you missed not so he
is still very much
um present and engaged and active on the
server I'm just not letting him out
until we get 10K
um it's just he's my slave and that's
how it's gonna go
all right thank you everyone
thank you everyone and uh see you next
season
want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
top-notch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate here.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out