[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
live here i'm matthew owner of riot
seeds i'll occasionally be joined by my
cohost not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
[Music]
all right so yeah i i decided like you
know i mean we talk all the time uh
we've been trying to figure out the
whole
super skunk fiasco
yep
from from point of where
um
i guess uh
what what how do we want to um
label certain people
well i mean we can just call a skunk
boss gunkva
since uh everybody knows uh
everybody's familiar with that moniker
yeah but yeah
others hem dog is chem dog
that's another familiar moniker
skunk von maize old buddy
um
i think during the podcast he called him
his buddy from staten island
okay let's do that yeah and he's a
private dude and kind of out of the
scene at this point so we're just gonna
like not say his name out of uh
respect and that he's he's uh he's long
uh you know his part is important but
long ago so yes out of respect for him
we won't we'll just refer to him in code
yeah that's perfect strangely he's one
of those rare people in the industry
that is not seeking past fame
yeah no it's not peabud guys no he is
actually the opposite um
yeah so let's start with
where do you want to start the super
stoked story at where should we start it
at
uh we'll start at the beginning there we
go okay
so my buddy from staten island
uh
him and skunk vow were very good friends
and they used to travel and tour
together dead tour days right
and in the early 90s
uh dude wanted to move out to
the west coast in california
and he was more into seeing uh jerry
garcia shows than he was into seeing the
actual dead right yeah but jerry would
play at the war field
basically every month
right like a big ass hippie gathering at
the war field you know and so my buddy
uh kind of stopped touring uh moved to
sonoma county
um and uh started seeing every jerry
show there okay right
obviously jerry shows are uh
uh you know they're like honey to
deadheads
so
you know so a whole bunch of dead heads
would always attend uh these shows at
the warfield right
correct so skunk bob being
being from virginia
right
a lot of his old crew and mentors and
various things like that were east coast
right
yeah so
one time some of these guys came out and
from the east coast
and uh they
uh were partying with all those guys at
the warfield
okay
um
so skunk violence mutual friend
used to have this strain called the
francine
all right and then tell us about
princeton a little offset but tell us
about francine a little bit francine is
a mystery indica that uh we didn't use
the term at the time but it was about as
terpy as terpy gets
yeah um eventually dude dropped it
because
like a lot of afghans um it had a
horrific mold problem yeah and as you
know
you know when you uh when you grow
things uh that horrifically look
beautiful and horrifically mold
at times it's very depressing harvest
time oh yeah happened to you a few times
with a cut you can get ptsd
and
decide to drop it you know like
get people get emotional about it so
what does she smell like
you know it it was a really good
combination of like that
like that afghan kind of acrid funk
yeah right
but with with like a fruity
aspect but not like the tropical sativa
kind of fruit it just had like a really
deep like
like foot funk fruit kind of flavor to
it i think oh wow
so anyway so these dudes loved it
yeah
and
uh
um they loved it so much they were
willing to trade
this skunk that they had for it
okay
so separately to all this story and uh
skunkvas kinda talked about this
extensively on his on his podcast so
i'll just briefly touch on it but
chem dog wouldn't give out the dog which
is what we call it to anyone right he
held it super tight he didn't want
anybody in his circle getting it he
didn't want to get cut off
you know um or have other people sell it
but when homie moved to
california
he agreed look i'll give it to you
if you just don't ever share it with
anybody back east
yeah
right
yeah don't want to compete markets
totally don't make sense
don't share it so
basically what happened is that skunkva
arranged with his buddies
to trade the francine for the skunk
okay
yeah
dude decided to make a double trip where
he would bring the francine out
to virginia and he would trade it for
the skunk and then he would drive up to
massachusetts and he would get the chem
dog that was promised to him right
dude that's committed that is committed
in 1993
uh homie drove across a bunch of shady
ass states
with little plants
uh you know not very many and small but
still you know still yeah fancy if you
got pulled over he probably would have
had to eat them you know or something
yeah yeah and we have their state
checkpoints you gotta do all kinds of
you know this was actually pre-pre
uh to use a term we joke about mostly
the highway 80 drug checkpoints and
stuff like that yeah this was in 93 so
they really hadn't gotten wise to that
too much oh good if you took the middle
route uh you you were pretty much safe
for the most part i mean you could still
get pulled over you know
and he definitely looked like a hippie
i bet like he wasn't yet no secret sauce
or anything like that he didn't look
like a young republican or anything yeah
yeah and so so he drives out to
virginia and uh
and meets
um what we just learned actually
recently ended up being dude's actual
worker because the dude had already kind
of gone on the run for a bit
and was weaving
and so he gets this this super skunk cut
okay
and i want to interject as far as we
know the person we're referring to um
not by name the staten island guy yeah
that as far as we know this is
scumfier's mentor so this is how close
we can put skunk va to the beginning of
this cut as far as we know
the guy that agreed to do it is the
mentor but apparently
the guy that actually did the trade is
one of his workers exactly um but i
asked when all this confusion came up a
few years ago i read i asked
staten island um
do you remember the exchange
well enough to be absolutely sure what
did he call it
yeah
if you fast forward to like when i
became friends with these guys in the
late 90s it was always called super
skunk right yes
so
staten island uh he gets
you know he told me that straight up
dude said this is a super skunk cup
okay
so he gets it straight forward yeah so
he trades he gets it then he drives to
massachusetts okay and he meets up with
chemdawg
and he gets the 91.
uh we all call the dog but you know
everybody on the internet calls it skunk
[ __ ] or 91 or whatever so yeah but
everybody back then it was just the dog
a bunch of these dudes were organic
growers and so even though it was chem
dog they didn't want to put them on it
yeah my buddy they weren't super into
calling it chem dog because they grew
fully organic so
um so we destroyed the dog and amongst
all of us long before it got famous or
anything like that that's just kind of a
shorthand
you know i've been writing that on
labels now for
two decades right so
so
he got
an extra cut or two
of this super skunk
okay
okay and he gave one to chem dog
okay okay
so that's not so chem dog got it
basically by accident yeah he got it by
proxy just like by accident by proxy he
got it because homie decided to go to
virginia before massachusetts
that's crazy what a what a wild
yeah he could have reversed it and gone
massachusetts virginia home
yeah but he went virginia massachusetts
home
that's enough
it changed a lot
that act that choice in my opinion i
mean we've talked about this a bunch or
whatever that ended up
leading to a whole series of accidental
events that became super important right
right yeah so
um
you know so then he drives back home
right yep now he's got super skunk in
the dark
okay
and if you went to warfield shows in san
francisco to see jerry band you probably
could have seen him slinging all that
in front of the show every single month
yeah
um
so skunk fall took a different tact and
he could speak to this for himself but
he kept touring basically
right
so
when jerry died in august uh this next
week here we call this the days between
because jerry's birthday is on the first
of august and his his death is on the is
in a week now or something like that and
so these are like easter for hippies
yeah it's sort of like the yeah it's the
it's the easter week or whatever so
uh you know skunk vod decided to settle
down after
jerry passes
right
and that's when he started growing
now because obviously to grow you have
to be semi-stable it's not a really
dramatic lifestyle right so yeah um
so those pictures that he's been posting
of polaroids and everything like that or
after our buddy gave him the cut from
his friends in virginia and he started
growing it
yes right yep um so that's basically how
that's basically how this this cut from
virginia made its way to sonoma county
the bay and massachusetts
and see and then this is a great intro
too to the chem dog story as well which
we will cover in our podcast which
will eventually be here soon soon so
so that's the start of that's the start
of the super skunk movie um
you know i uh
i met uh i didn't know them then
personally uh a couple years after that
um and uh my you know my uh my buddy
uh he fell in love with the mendo p
yeah a couple other things or whatever
and so he ended up giving me the super
skunk and the dog for safekeeping
you know
and uh and that's in the late 90s and
that's kind of how i got it
and you've had it
well like not the super skunk but the
chem 91 and it stayed with you ever
since yep i've had that since i never
lost it no
unfortunately
the super skunk was lost uh but we'll
get to that
yeah okay so you know so we have this
stuff right
and uh
you know this is obviously
um
what is it
you know so late 90s 2000 2001 this
whole little era right then so you've
got like the internet is in it's like
infancy essentially right overgrow had
just began in 98.
yeah
so there really wasn't any internet fame
yeah right all these things that have
become super famous and like holy grails
and all these people trying to figure
out stuff right
uh
most of the stories that i believe
that i've heard about this stuff comes
from that era
because that was when there was nobody
gave a [ __ ]
yeah in the sense so there's no reason
to bull about any of it there was no
fame associated with it there was no rap
there was no
i mean it was literally like
there was like four people in california
who had it yeah exactly there was me
skunk
our buddy
and uh uh i see collective yes i see
collective yes right that's right who
was really close friends with skunk bar
you know uh yeah and and greg and that
and he
and he ended up like moving in with
skunkva and that's how he got the cut so
there was literally like four of us
yeah um so not very big and now back
then you had enormous rooms or anything
like that you know
yeah literally wasn't very much of it
even being produced
yeah you're blowing it up with the four
lighter essentially you're blowing it
mostly
eight six spiders okay
you guys are slinging hard
twelve lighters or whatever but yeah um
but yeah you know and so
uh so just to keep it back on the super
skunk tip
um
you know
obviously it's been quite a long time
um but here here's what i know for sure
um
it was uh
i never ever heard it called anything
but super skunk
um
obviously we've had some debate amongst
friends
oh sure there's a whole different thing
we can get into later about whatever
about some different
different names and stuff and yeah there
may not be the exact same thing through
different crews or whatever but as far
as as far as my little group goes
um
that's what it was always called
right straight super skunk and so buddy
from staten island okay
he would love like when we'd have
trimmers over
you could pull side branches of that
thing and you could hold it up to the
the picture in the catalog of the 90
seed bank
right
then it was like a dead ringer
yeah you would you could find buds on
the plants
that like match that look exactly
yeah it was very very uniform witnessed
him dozens of times over multiple crops
right
just because he was just so cool because
it's like yeah exactly like the picture
in the catalog right
yeah and he could show you hey this
really is super skunk you're buying you
know and so
uh you know in a lot of ways you know it
was a sketchy plan
um
that was you know that was the very
beginning of the 215 era
right um but it wasn't really you know
215 had like multiple eras right the
first five or six 215
like the cops the courts everything it
was still pretty much underground yeah
yeah you're still getting [ __ ] people
hadn't grown to like let's have a
greenhouse outside my back door you know
yeah none of that thrilling uh indoor
was still sketchy it was still not the
jam you know yeah
so
um so the super skunk
you know the last two or three weeks it
literally people joke about carbon
filter killer right yeah it was the only
strain i've ever grown that um
absolutely defeated every opportunity i
ever had to win
[Laughter]
i don't even know any other way to
describe it the amount yeah burn it
would give me like i would pull up with
two weeks to go in front of my house in
summer
and it would smell like a dead skunk in
my driveway
yeah i know the feeling not with skunks
but yeah every direction and and so you
know back then you're just like oh my
god you know that is yeah be
nerve-wracking and so
at which i had obviously people know on
this on this thing what scrubbers are i
had a a co2 scrubber with a fan
scrubbing the room
i had uh or a carbon filter sorry not
co2 i had a carbon filter right yeah and
um so that's scrubbing the room and then
i had a carbon filter on the exhaust
and then i had one of those huge uv on
air double
uh yeah um
you know ozone generators yes even did
the recommended 25 or 30 feet of tubing
before it went out the building to make
sure it had time to mix
yeah and it still smelled like i was
slaughtering skunks in my backyard
i mean
that's kind of how it was you know so
uh it was trippy in that regard
um and you know it
it was it was i don't know it looked
dense
even when it looked dense it was still
it still weighed light
yeah it was just one of those things
where like you you know you put a nug on
there and you're like oh this is going
to be impressive and you're like oh
no it's hollow how did they make hollow
weed so it was like solid but it was
fluffy it's like almost like ice cream
or something that had a bunch of air
whipped into it you know
and uh
um
you know and
the terp the weird thing about the terp
is that it was super volatile in my
opinion like it didn't really stink
until the last bit
and then it dunked for about a month or
five weeks after you cut it
yeah if you let super skunk go too long
in your jar or whatever it would have
eventually kind of smelling semi to
generic green butter
oh yes yeah that makes sense would go
from like i could crack a jar in the
other room and someone would walk in and
ask me what was going on like you would
have to like crunch the [ __ ] out of it
and deeply smell to try to get a whiff
yeah that makes sense but fresh
it reaped
yeah
um
you know and you know it's kind of hard
to trim it was it could be sparse you
know when it didn't
uh you know i mean for most people
um
probably the easiest way to think about
it
is uh you know real old-school sour has
a lot of similarities to it yes you know
so when sour doesn't want to come out
the right way
it's a [ __ ] to trim you know like
people lose people start you know your
your crew gets disheartened
oh my god i got a trim diesel you know
yeah right now i posted some stuff for
you the other night uh that i sent you
where like my old sour diesel cutting
it looks like those tops those colas
they really oh yeah see
those same super skunk
tops that skunk posts
yeah you can really see the similarity
in it you know
um so the other thing that that uh so it
had unbelievable terps i mean when
people talk about rks terps or whatever
else it was
the terpest
skunkiest rankest thing imaginable
you know
uh it really was um
and uh you know
it also you know uh it also hurt like a
[ __ ]
yeah that's that's like really the the
first thing i ever heard about mass
super when i first started getting into
the scene and learning the history and
stuff that that [ __ ] was a herm bomb it
was a herm bomb it could harm um you
know we would pull it about eight weeks
sometimes
you would um
you know you would try to take it longer
because you think maybe it needed to be
done more
and they would herm for sure
yeah
but the other thing is and this is kind
of weird about it
is that it hurt early too
because
well as a breeder right yeah
yeah if you let's say you pull the super
skunk at 58 days
and you find tiger striped beans in it
yeah when were those beans made yeah you
know they're
early on
probably primarily
because it takes a good four to six
weeks
yes premature to like fully mature and
get that dark tiger striping that looks
all healthy and stuff you know sure um
so you pull a strain at 58 days just by
the law of
how beans grow
yeah had the pot you know it something
bad bad had to happen in three weeks
yeah
yeah but that act that in my opinion you
know and there's a certain amount of you
know we can get to opinions about it but
that factor
created a whole bunch of weed that we
like
yeah i did that's that's the crazy part
craziest part about all of it through
live harms
yeah
and so okay so you know in the in the uh
you know uh
the the buddy from staten island right
he was not very into sharing
yeah no
um i uh you know when i got when i got
the dog
i had to promise that i wouldn't give it
out you know which i didn't for forever
you know yeah and i would have like we
would have like really good friends of
ours that would um
beg me for it and i'd be like you know
who you have to talk to
get him to call me and say that you can
have it and i'll take cuts for you
tomorrow
yeah but otherwise like i'm not breaking
my word yeah of course because like
we're all good friends and he's gonna
know you have it and then that makes me
look like an [ __ ] you know so no you
know
issues and it's like well this is the
you know this is what i had to do so he
wasn't as strict about the skunk but he
kind of felt the same way you know and
you know me like i try to be as like
as etiquette
as oh yeah possible with cuts yeah i
don't even like to pressure people i'm
just not into it like yeah have their
own vibe and their own energy about why
they come to you or not you know sure
and so you know so
what sucks about that
is that we didn't spread it very far
yeah right like we weren't on forums or
anything like that or whatever
um staten island buddy is not weasel
clop glass no
no no he's not uh i'm not paying very
much attention to the words at the
bottom of the screen so it's alright as
anything maybe mac can say it or repeat
it again or something but yeah he's
totally not it's totally not him um
so uh you know
so the fact there's two things right is
obviously back then most people are
growing for profit you know on some
level
and so having a cut that wreaks the high
heaven and scares your neighbors
and herms on you
uh you know it made it dicey on people
holding it
yeah and so
you know we never you know skunk bon
myself you know our buddy we never
really spread it we weren't trading we
weren't active on the forums you know we
weren't swapping cuts out right and left
and stuff and so
you know
uh that's uh you know that's a different
discussion but as you know like every
time
my opinion is is like every single time
a famous named cut happened
yeah like purple craze with urkel and
gdp
the sour the cushions whatever
a whole bunch of amazing diversity just
goes to [ __ ]
yeah because people want to fill their
room or their greenhouse or their
whatever with something that some guy is
going to come and snap it from them
right
yeah they they want the the ship that's
gonna sell not for the most so even
amongst most of my close friends i've
always had a [ __ ] of a time getting
people to back things up for me
yeah people want one or two plants that
they're currently doing for production
and they don't hold on to a bunch of
stuff that they're doing for safe
keeping or heads or whatever you know
yeah
um so it wasn't that easy for me to get
it to be backed up anywhere
right
particularly because uh you know when it
comes to you know production and stuff
like that some broker finding seeds is
[ __ ] doomed
um so like hey do you want to grow this
thing that could potentially lightly or
heavily seed your room
no not at all not not really no right
you know
so
you know i mean
uh
so we all grew it
um and sorry i'm sorry i just had to
boot someone i didn't want to but he was
being a jackass and being real rude so
oh i have no i i wasn't even paying
attention it's all good it's bad
um so i don't know i mean that's kind of
the start of the of the cali
super skunk
uh you know thing it stayed with our
little crew
um yeah
you know and um you know the
massachusetts side of things
and greg and all that other star chem
dot
i'm being real [ __ ] serious you're
being [ __ ] disrespectful as [ __ ] and
i'm gonna [ __ ] you up if you keep it up
knock it the [ __ ] off have some respect
i've been real [ __ ] cool to you
okay cool
so i don't know i mean so you know i
don't know uh
i have no idea like you know what
happened with chem dog in massachusetts
you know who when how he shared what
with you know all that type of stuff
um
you know as far as this as far as the
actual super skunk cut goes
yeah
you know but it's one of those things
where like
you know uh nobody wanted it until it
became
sort of this legendary famous thing and
then everybody started poking around
trying to figure out who might have kept
it
you know
so yeah uh staten island and i
um we had this thing where like two of
our favorite strains were obviously the
super skunk and the chem dog right yeah
and the
super skunk had the the lime green and
the frost
uh i mean you know from the chem du you
know from dog
dog isn't particularly gorgeous
it's not super frosty compared to
grains it's darker cut you know it
cannibalizes its own leaves it doesn't
even always taste great you know yeah
sometimes it can taste amazing and i
love the flavor but like i could grow it
all year long and only two crops out of
five be happy with its flavor at times
yeah you know and why exactly
um why why exactly that is i don't know
so we had this idea um and this is long
before
you know i mean there was no real
american seed companies or anything like
that right so
we were we were doing a bunch of
breeding but we were doing a bunch of
breeding that was literally for our
taste buds
like it was not for public consumption
at best it was going to be grown by us
and spread out
yeah you know we created this we created
this thing over time uh staten island
started it and i came on and helped uh
and you know we did some work on it
together uh that we eventually called
the super dog
uh which is in the can of bible the
second one i think yes
that was my first that was my first
experience with kind of
uh
really finding a strain that i wanted to
hunt
right there
even though i got along quite well with
jason who wrote it um and i gave him a
bunch of accurate information a lot of
that got twisted and turned
into some of his entries about the the
dog and the chem dog and the super
saiyan all that type of stuff you know
so
be that as it may what we were trying to
do is we were trying to
combine the terps and the look of super
skunk
with the potency and some of the density
and some of the the niceness of the dog
sure you know and it was like a you know
and so
um
you know and strangely
uh and this is another thing of why i
think maybe it disappeared as we we've
talked about this recently too
i i tend to believe
that the skunk and the herm is related
yes like i i can't say for certain but i
think it might be a linked trait i i and
there's a lot of uh
um
evidence for that yeah you know and as
you know um you know there's there's
very few traits that people breeding
have you know more prejudice against
than uh banana banana sacks with
hermione you know yeah
and so i think inadvertently
uh people bred away from the skunk
yeah without realizing it because
you know you breed some stuff it's a
hermit mess it reeks you're like oh god
that's a hermit mess i'm gonna get you
know i'm not gonna breed towards that
side
and
the idea that you could have a linked
trait where you have a very desirable
trait and a not so desirable trait uh
together
you know
is the biggest breeder pain in the ass
ever is a link trait with undesirable
traits he's like oh all the potency
comes in these low yielding ones that
suck
you know
all these
huge donkey dicks and like have the
structures incredible they're all bland
you know
yep and so
you know uh the problem is
is that you know you have a situation
it's like it's kind of the same thing
like you know like i told you about with
the trinity right where the trinity
didn't spread very far
and so
when we lost it and i kept trying to get
it back
um people would give me fakes
yeah
it's not because they were dicks most of
the time
but because they never had it back in
the day so when they got it from someone
they didn't they had no way of knowing
that it wasn't it
yeah of course yeah um and so then i
would have to be the bearer of bad news
you know and be like no this isn't it
yeah and people hate the bear bad news
and that's kind of what's happened with
this super skunk right is that yeah
there's obviously this desire in the
community
to have these these roadkill terps come
back right
everyone who finds super skunk
has a current seed company and is making
seeds to sold to the public
no one ever shows up
to
events with a couple jars of fresh skunk
and lets the proof be in the pudding
yeah right they get the cut they
advertise the cut here's the cut we're
breeding with the cut buy my seeds find
the amazing terps in the cup right
or they get kinks
you know yeah and so so you don't know
you don't know if if they're lying
because i don't know or whatever or
they just have no id they just never had
it in the past
you know to know that to know what skunk
is yeah but actual to what the actual
skunk cut is you know
and so you know by the early to mid
2000s it had been dropped enough
um that uh you know
uh various people had lost it through
you know lots of the same reasons that
everybody loses cuts
fires busts accidents breakups
you know people not returning it
um i had backed up with a couple people
they refused to give it back to me at
one point uh and then lost it in the
future and
um i had some stuff happen and i lost it
and we've been you know we've been
hunting it ever since and
uh
you know i mean we're both obviously
friends with skunk bar
all these new school super skunk finds
i mean what are you gonna say they just
end up they end up not looking i mean
what's awesome is that he's got these
he's got these you know uh these
pictures these polaroids
that are undisputable
that was the cut i had that is so big
that he has those pictures we're buddies
we got it from you know it came from the
same place the story was the same thing
you know so um you know it's it's it
and yeah you know you have all these
other shorter squatter afghan
all these other different looking you
know super skunk cuts
and then the other part of it too is
that you have people that like okay so
this guy had the super skunk at once
right
well then as soon as that dude verifies
right yeah well then all of a sudden
okay we have it now we can trade bait it
now we can get spread out now this
person has the cut and
you know that's the problem and that's
the problem you know and so
you know i mean before everybody who's
listening holy [ __ ] we're up to 242
people on this thing
but uh yeah
the super skunk was not a perfect cut
you know like it wasn't in my opinion it
wasn't the holy grail did it have
crazy rare skunk terps absolutely it had
that baits was it enjoyable to smoke
sure
right
i don't think it held a candle to the
dog the d
some of the cushes a lot of the modern
cuts right now that we would consider to
be elite you know
you would consider it to have
moderate potency at best
yes
you know it wasn't it you know i mean
you know various cuts have various uh
qualities and
and other things and you know and so it
didn't check all the boxes
yeah was it a great cut sure was it
worth having yes uh was it a pain in the
ass to grow at times
your yes
yes think about but you know and you
know i mean in
i think you know i mean obviously
you know all of
uh chem dogs early breedings were all
accidental
right
yeah you know that as far as we know
that's the correct yeah but he was well
i mean the thing is that nobody was
reversing back then
no jesus [ __ ] christ right and yeah
noah's making feminists
seeds back then and so you only you know
so you know the only way you're crossing
two female cuts is accidentally
yes you know and those accidents you
know um they led to some of the best
weed ever
yeah you know uh yeah
in many people's opinion
yeah and you know i mean that's that's
like a whole another
uh thing that steps you know maybe it
steps on toes or doesn't to talk about
all those kind of theories about various
things but
um
i have not seen the real super skunk
um since i i lost it um which has been
you know uh quite a while at this point
yeah we've been hunting it for a long
time um
you know i
i don't think it exists
you know
there there's always the possibility
there are still pockets in america
where um you know people aren't really
connected they're not on the internet
they're not dialed in to like the scene
so to speak
so yeah i mean obviously just like we
know right so
to jump on a european trip
everybody thought the a52 was lost for
well over a decade
yeah
right
yeah at least yeah
nobody could find it
and then karma found a guy
that was holding on to this cut for
neville
neville told him not to tell anybody
and it was the a52
yeah and karma wasn't even sure what he
had right so he had to give it to
yosemite
uh who he grew with neville forever to
grow it out and confirm it was it
so it's possible right it is absolutely
possible and i i think we are all
desperately hoping that happens too no
yeah it's possible that that could exist
because the a5 was lost
for a long time i mean a short period of
time that it was lost i mean i i think
it's i think it got lost in the
switzerland raids
um when they shut down shanti and those
different
and stuff and it got lost in holland
during the bust eras
and
then it was lost for
you know 10 12
14 years
something like that until it just popped
up within the last few
last few and now
losing friends fast over it everybody's
[ __ ] arguing over it real fast
i mean yeah it's cool that we that
people are still fighting over over
cannabis made in the late 80s
i know right
to how good it is and you know it's also
not only is a testament to how good it
is but like people want to make money
off it too some some people so
if you've got rare and and you've got
rare access and you can bring some
things you know you're you're you're a
breeder who operates in the market so if
you've got something nobody else does
and you can hype it and it's worthy and
you can
you know i mean that's what all these
super scum people are trying to do right
right exactly what's going on yeah they
make they're trying to make a bunch of
money before people realize they don't
have what they have
correct and that's that's the jam you
know a lot of people want to sell seeds
or pass cuts or do this and that and
you've got a good
at minimum four months three months
before you're going to get any kind of
pushback now the other problem is that
i've noticed
when people either invest in buying that
cut or they've invested um emotionally
in that cut at that point now they think
they've got
a really rare cut that's going to you
know bring some kind of value to their
life however they see fit and um
they're now
in that mindset where this is it if it's
not yet i don't have
whatever agenda
purpose that i have like i was saying
with the trinity people would get butt
hurt at me sometimes when i would be
like politely that's not it
and they would do a whole thing and you
don't know what i traded to get it and
da da da da da and i'd be like well you
know i'm sorry about all that like i
have nothing to do with any of that but
yeah remains to be seen it's still not
it
it just isn't it you know
and so
you know uh it's gotten to a point where
there's a narrow group of people who had
super skunk it
you know
and some of them had longer
relationships with it than others
and so some of them are a little bit
better at identifying than others
yes exactly
you know
yeah without
naming names or stepping on toes or
doing anything like that you know and
we've had issues in the past in the
community
with people that you know are you know
well thought of or respected that verify
yes then once it's verified
right
well that's all that's all she wrote
that's it it's verified you know
and then you know i you know i hit up
you know skunk bar or something and i'll
be like what about that verified cut
he's like it's not
it absolutely isn't it i don't know if
they ever had it if they think that's it
yes right and so you know like if he
tells me if he hits me up and he tells
me i think i found it
i'm gonna get excited
yeah absolutely because he's i i tend to
think him above everyone else is gonna
know that cut really really intimately
being that it came from his mentor and
he worked with it for so long
i mean you know the the fact the fact
remains is that him our buddy and myself
we cropped it quite a bit
for three years so you do that you do
crop after crop after crop for that a
bit you run anything for a number of
years is your is your main squeeze
you know you learn a lot about it
absolutely uh when my buddy and i were i
mean that's the thing too and you know
we've talked about this before is that
since we bred with it a bunch
i got to see
you know that's one of the things that i
really respect about you know uh say
like uh csi or archive who i see on here
you know um where there's only so many
breeders
out there right now that actually tests
their own gear
sure so don't test your own gear
you don't really know what uh
you don't really know what traits your
clones pass yeah you're never gonna see
it firsthand never you don't see what
how they breed did they breed clean do
they breed a mess did they throw
consistent phenotypes do they you know
growing a bunch of growing a bunch of um
uh
oh man uh
truth man someone's asking about truth
band
yeah that's that's a horrible subject so
um but uh
um
yeah you know but
so we grew us you know buddy from staten
island and myself we grew out hundreds
of you know uh dog and and skunk and
other various skunk hybrids you know
and um and we saw what it passed
you know you see what it throws out you
know
and so a lot of the the various like
semi-proven semi-unproven theories i
have about certain things we've talked
about a bunch
on my observation of like not very many
people
like have had both parents
yeah
my buddy myself we're like literally in
like a handful of people
um that probably had both
yeah and we're familiar with both
yes so and all that and so
um
you know uh
i mean
the the skunk definitely seemed to be
connected to herms
yeah the
you know when we were doing the the
super dog stuff if we bred away from the
herms we brought away from some of the
stuff we liked
so then the trick was to try to find
like
a minimal or acceptable amount of herms
yeah
or
okay like say take the chem d for
instance
yes md herms like crazy
at times if it gets a little test
especially in depth sure you know not as
much as indoor but in depth certainly or
if it gets a little stressed
sure but it's not live pollen
yeah it's not it's not it's sterile it
throws bananas but there's not really
live pollen in those bananas you know um
so then you're looking for you're
looking for
you know one throws herms and has the
stink but doesn't have the danger
inherent
in um
in all that you know yeah
it was a long and an expensive breeding
project uh
because back then uh you know obviously
herb went for a lot more and it was a
lot riskier
um so anytime you dedicated rooms or
areas
to constant breeding that could have
been just some kind of production run
and then you're not even selling the
beans they're just for you and your
friends
um
you know but uh
but you know we had we always had dual
stuff like we always had this goal of
trying to like
you know improve the gene pool a little
bit you know
create more weed that we liked
and so now it's like most most people's
breeding is like take two famous things
that people want
mash them together and then sell the
name
yeah right where it's like
we were like okay like we we like the
skunk smell and we like the color and we
like the
the you know the quickness and all that
can we marry that to the dog's potency
and feeling and warm happy buzz and all
that is there some hybrid that we can
create that marries those two things
together
sure and so that's obviously the classic
way to breed is you look at two
different things and you're like i want
traits from this and traits from this to
end up in its progeny
yeah right
you know and uh so that's that's really
the gig so
um
you know it uh
you know sadly it seems like a bunch of
the stuff that got passed it got passed
around in massachusetts quite a bit more
but it seems like from what we've been
able to determine
that it uh
maybe it the actual cut itself wasn't
passed around nearly as much as people
think
maybe in that one maybe bag seed maybe
something different got passed out and
it got called super skunk and it was
from said dude
so of course it's it
and then you're off to the races and
then that thing gets spread around and
then the more
you know i mean we've we talked about
this before too but like
you know rez calling his [ __ ] line
sour diesel
and then makes a [ __ ] line out of it
finding the actual named cut once
there's a whole bunch of of
you know
yeah other stuff out there that has the
same name
is problematic
yeah and it became damn near impossible
in some cases with that you know and uh
you know and so i mean
uh you know the uh
i think
the super skunk has a semi there's
obviously there's some pretty famous
people in the weed community that had it
so that ends like some gravitas to the
fact that it was killer
and then they was killer and then it
comes from this 90s historical era
obviously right
and you know and then on top of that it
it probably
is in a bunch of other things that
people don't realize it's in
right correct and everybody knows what a
rank skunk smells like everybody in
america for the most part is probably in
america yeah ones you know and all that
and so it's a really distinctive terp
yeah right
and it doesn't exist
it does not you know i mean some people
on here know some people don't but i got
lucky enough and i cracked them and what
became known as the mendo p you know
and what's interesting about that cut is
that
like if that cut didn't exist there's no
other
line that i know of that has those terps
yeah like those terps are in cannabis
obviously
yeah they're obviously in cannabis but
it's very unique the modern cannabis
and anything you find that ends up
smelling like that you discover it was
descended from that yeah right
and so
you know um
you know the the skunk nose in my
opinion
really only pops out here and there in
its descendants on occasion
yes that's the mendo perks yes mendo
purple indeed
um so
um
you know and so it just doesn't even it
it uh nobody's found it nobody's
nobody's made the terps nobody's found
the terps nobody's been able to produce
seed lines or cuttings
any time because if they did
it would be announced they would be it's
they would be at conventions or you know
emerald cup or whatever with jars and
they would be
you know it's a lost terp that people
want back
anyone who can capture that
that style terp into
a seed line that reliably produces it
and and let it stay in the bud form
is going to master it you know so um so
it's obviously a lot of constituents
of it
um
but man trying to get something that
really hangs with that smell past flower
is very very hard to do yeah and and you
know and so everybody ever it's got
universal recognition of what it should
smell like
yes there's a whole bunch of fake cuts
that people try to pretend smell like it
right yeah it really did smell like it
you know and so with it
there's no faking the funk
unless you have
skunk oil
you can rub it on a jar i mean yeah and
all and all that and all that
it's like it's like the scientific
method right like if somebody can't grow
it and produce the same smell
it's not there
yeah exactly it wasn't like you had to
do a bomber job of growing it dude you
know i mean
you know obviously in the 90s uh we've
all gotten quite a bit better at
gardening
oh yeah yeah older you get more
experienced you learn more there's way
cooler products that make your life
easier
you know um and i mean we used to mix
soil in a [ __ ] cement mixer
yeah from raw amendments
yeah yeah it wasn't all these biological
amendments there wasn't all these like
you know inoculants and
booze and teas and this and that like
there is now it was like there's like gh
and you know earth juice and i mean the
even just the stuff that you could get
and like you were and you were just
happy that the store carried
yeah sure pretty limited compared to now
you know
um
and so that terp just it just existed
you grew it uh you grew it um
someone's saying about the mendo perps
it is not from the pacific northwest no
think about that question for a second
think about that question
is mendo purp from the pnw i mean you
know it's too it's cool dude any ques
whoever asks that any question is no
he's turpin bird's cool yeah and it
really
down to it like most that's the thing
right is that
just so you know like you know matt and
i are gonna do uh we're gonna we're
gonna uh do a
a podcast pretty soon here and chat
about history and really what it boils
down to for me is like without the i
don't really give a [ __ ] about fame or
rep or anything like that
most of our history in the cannabis
community is oral
you know passed down from people to
people and there are people that have
heard the real deal and have verified
and cross verified
type stuff you know um but it can be
really hard for people to come along
later or don't have personal connection
to something i mean [ __ ] spreads
like wildfire at times
you know and certain people
have vested interests
in spreading [ __ ]
and so you know counteracting that with
truth
um and uh
you know so
but yeah you know it really is it is
it's an underground it was an
underground illegal venture
and lots of little individual groups
um you know like passing on knowledge to
each other
you know and it just so happens that you
know like uh the grateful dead
uh and the kids that followed the
grateful dead um that was probably like
the greatest open-air weed market in
american history at a certain point oh
yeah and after them after jerry died
started growing weed because it kept the
lifestyle going and for a while now it's
not it's not true anymore you know we're
just a segment but for a minute you know
in the 90s and mid-2000s like almost all
the best and and most famous cuts
came from some hippie or another
some crew you know some related group
and you're only so far removed from all
those people because it's a small world
so
you know
um
it uh
you know
most of this stuff i just got lucky
in the sense that you know i mean you
have no idea what's going to be famous
or not oh no you don't we're doing like
you know the dog didn't get famous
until
skunkva decided to get on forums
and start chatting about it
sure
nobody knew who
you know except for on the east nobody
knew who chemdog was nobody knew peabod
was nobody knew
any of these people's names or what they
were involved with or anything else you
know sure and uh you know so it's like
um you know all this stuff kind of
happens after the fact
you know when right you're just like
you're just kids
want more breeder syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsheets.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
you