welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey in defining my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
[Music]
hello everyone welcome to breeder
Syndicate I'm Matthew riot here with my
co-host Alison Fulton today we're going
to be discussing something that uh
it's one of the most important topics in
cannabis uh not just breeding but it's
an integral part of breeding which is
the name game how does it work what are
its implications
what are some variables that go into
selecting and how do those affect the
outcome of the final flower uh
medically or otherwise
um so yeah this is something I'm super
passionate about and we've been kind of
talking about it a little bit and and I
felt like as an overall arching theme
for um this season one of the things I
wanted to drive home
was reaching the end user of flower
because it's not something something
that we deal with a lot they're not
they're not our main
um
what would you call that are the people
watching our show they're not our main
demographic the end user of the flower a
lot of times the people watching our
show are seed makers or people
interested specifically in genetics and
breeding
but this season I really want to tap
into them because in the end they are
the people that need to know they are
the consumers and uh they need to
understand what they're putting in their
body and I I think this is one of the
few ways that we can do it so with that
thousand
yeah I think
the only things I'll add are this sort
of does apply to seeds as well and it
sort of does apply to clones as well to
a degree in terms of like the broader
market so I think in a way we will be
covering we'll touch on all of those
things I think uh and if we don't get
enough time we'll we'll return to this
because this is yeah like Matt said one
of the core issues
um that we we want to highlight
um
I don't know there's much else for me to
say
um
I think Matt you want to start with
from a Breeder's point of view initially
you know what goes into naming something
so
um when I started thinking about the the
whole topic and and how we could cover
it maybe or if it was even worth talking
about
I I wanted to start from a seed Maker's
perspective or a Breeder's perspective
um during the my early days
um so we're talking you know 2006
to 2012 right right around in that era
uh actually probably 2006 2010 and then
before like obviously before I came in
this is relevant
um but this is just from my experience
how it went
um different breeders had different
methods for coming up with names a lot
of those that started early on whether
it was from Neville you know saying wow
that that butt is awful large yielding
that is a big bud
um or uh wow that one smells skunky
that's skunk you know you would you
would pick things whether it was the
scent the look
um any number of things like that but
really obvious visual cues scent cues
stuff like that when you were picking
names
um sometimes it wasn't like that in the
case of something like AK-47 you know
um but generally speaking they were
pretty easy uh to assess like names were
individual
you knew if it was bubbleberry it was
gonna be Sega Mathis bubbleberry
generally speaking right before the
before the white labeling came on and
and all the [ __ ] shows started but um
let's see there's also the combinations
of when you combine strains like when we
started doing hybrids you know let's say
you have a blueberry and a bubble gum
you combine them and now you have
bubbleberry or we have let's say uh Girl
Scout cookies and blueberry now you have
cookie Berry or you know the white cut
across the Fire OG now you have White
Fire OG these were just really simple
ways to do it like there was a lot of
creativity in it but it helped it helped
Define what you were going to get and
and because of the name you knew okay
it's gonna be like the white it's gonna
be like the fire we're gonna see you
know projecty somewhere in between the
two and it's kind of how it went
um let's see
there was also I think the effect of the
different scale uh the number of people
who were in the industry back then yeah
as compared to now you were saying like
back then conceivably you could quite
easily search for the name that you are
you want to use and
feel like you have kind of done a little
bit of due diligence I think you wanted
to talk about like what due diligence
really meant back then or yeah
that's right um so it was a lot easier
to step on toes that's kind of the word
we always used
um or to avoid it
um because it weren't a whole lot of us
like people looking in nowadays like
look bad like look at history and they
see you know tens of thousands of
breeders and strains and all this you
know all these names but back then there
wasn't a whole shitload of people making
seeds there really wasn't so it was
really easy for people to communicate
with each other uh though not everybody
did communicate back some people
obviously were less communicative than
others but there was also very few
reference sites there were I mean we
knew the forums we knew where we could
search and look for names
um to see if it had been used it was a
lot easier to figure that stuff out
granted it wasn't you know Surefire but
it was pretty good it was pretty easy to
see if it name had been used and if
you're gonna step on toes and if so what
toes you were going to step on dude and
we could we just considered a due
diligence it was polite you know if
someone was around before you and it
chosen the name before you it wasn't
polite to then take that name use what
time marketing money they had put into
branding The Strain and then take it for
yourself and then try to bump off it and
that and it's like that in any commodity
any industry names uh are meant to
identify and and it was easier to do do
Jilla due diligence
um
but nowadays I think is where we're
heading right
and
it's not looking so good
it's not looking so easy
what are some examples to you of names
that just don't really mean
either what they say or just they just
don't really mean anything at all and I
know you had a couple of examples so
like recently doing the reviews that
we've been taught you know doing on our
show and and I'll talk about it some
more later because it's very it very
much ties into the whole theme of this
season
um I've run into some really confusing
stuff so for those who don't know real
quickly I've avoided the modern Market
as far as like what's being pushed or
hyped in in collectives and dispensaries
what you know the height Flower Boys and
the heady boys are smoking I have no
clue I have zero clue didn't care I knew
what I liked and it just I saw it as all
the same stuff however
um I've been trying to dive into it so I
can have an actual educated perspective
on it and not just speak
um from the hip
and I've been encountering a lot of
these these major uh I mean you know
clashes in in eras in Generations on how
we name stuff like uh for example I saw
Blue Sushi and I was like okay I don't
know what Sushi is right I've never
heard that one but blue that tells me
it's going to be a blueberry hybrid
probably smell blueberry that sounds
legit like that's because I like
blueberry that's when I see blue that's
what I go for I like things with with uh
that scent that smell that high
and I look it up and it's like some
weddings ghettels there's no blue in it
I was so confused I did not get it how
do you come up with Blue Sushi like and
that's aside from the fact of what Zushi
is who knows you know but the the one
thing in there that does speak to its
lineage is just the Z right that's it
that's it yeah if a z is in there so you
know it might have some Skittles in it
maybe if you're lucky they're like you
know I mean like nowadays I don't even
know that that means much the Z might be
more popular than the actual strain
Skittles now in strain names so you know
I I would bet that there's a lot of
stuff out there with Z in it that don't
have z in it you know in the actual
strain it's crazy
but yeah I think it's definitely worth
highlighting as well where like
uh just using the the letter Z is now
like adding adding something to your
name
yeah it has it adds content implied
context that may not be there yeah but
it's implied yeah for sure but it's also
based on the Breeders or whatever seed
makers knowledge that people are looking
for that in that signifier people want
that c yeah yeah but I mean a lot of
this I started seeing with like animal
cookies and Girl Scout cookies that was
like the first notable examples to me
um I mean granted there were blueberries
out there that were nothing blue or
related but that was just people I think
just really confused on what they had
but like when we got to Girl Scout
cookies and animal cookies
I was fully expecting these things to
smell and taste like
sweet
cookies and they just don't like people
say oh it's doughy it's you know like
maybe to them but like doughy
is not sweet cookies like it is not an
animal cracker like these are very far
from it you know wedding cake it's kind
of doughy
kind of creamy is it like does it smell
like sweet birthday cake or wedding cake
no not at all
um does it taste like it so
yeah I mean before this would anyone
have been like yeah I want some dough
Terps like it's that I've never I would
have never thought I've never heard that
you know like you'd be like oh you got
that Pine you got that that kush you
know but I've never I can't wait to
smoke that dough never had that now
doughy just sounds to me like something
went wrong
to me what doe implied was a bat like a
bad expression from OG kush or triangle
and a hybrid that's where you usually
run into like the bad expressions of
triangle and OG kush or the doughiness
which is bad expression or like bad
processing right like yeah yeah but I
mean when I say bad expression it's
obviously preference too because it's
not what I prefer like I prefer like
very specific ends of OG Kush and when I
hit that realm I'm like
common
boofy end so let's move the other
direction but someone found that as a a
very
um as their keeper and apparently it
resonated with the world so
that you know that that is just my
opinion uh but I mean then we have
things like gushers
um gelati uh gedapists just whatever
name they can throw on [ __ ] that implies
so much like I was seeing lychee
um
um tarot bun like there's these aren't
in cannabis I'm sorry
and and I don't know if it's
psychosomatism that makes people
think that this is what they're going to
experience and then therefore experience
it
like suggestion
or does the modern Market not care if
the name resembles
what the expectations are setting and is
it is it because I'm old and been in a
long time that I have those expectations
I don't know maybe that's something you
can comment on Thousand because you're
you're from a different era
I mean from a cynical point of view it's
unsurprising
um like you said previously you
could rely on names actually
corresponding with some quality of the
plant or some quality of some some
aspect of its lineage
um but increasingly as the names
themselves have
started to
you know have their own kind of like
clout games
yeah
um people would just
focus on engineering names uh and the
names themselves become
you know what people make the decisions
based on I don't think they didn't
adding anything new but yeah that's just
I mean like from your perspective like
when you came in and you started smoking
a lot and buying strains you know what I
mean did you have expectations at that
maybe these Skittles would actually
taste like Skittles
I mean that that first of all depends on
me knowing what Skittles even is right
not really or I mean it I'm sure I'll
put it this way I'm sure it is right but
candy because of the way the market
works here it's not like we all
we all have access to the same
information or it's like a unified scene
in any way it's it's still really like
fragmented here you know people are just
like
you know
yeah the Skittles candy for sure you
don't have Skittles candy
no we do we do okay that's right I guess
I just mean I guess I just mean that
like the conical Community or
quote-unquote industry here isn't
unified enough to kind of have a sense
of like
what these things actually mean
um
there isn't like a generally accepted
sense of anything but from your
perspective your personal perspective
having like having since you have the
candy Skittles there right like you have
did you have that as a kid
yeah yeah so if you're asking like you
know if I see the name Skittles would I
immediately make that Association yeah
of course I would did you I mean did you
have the expectation when you first
heard of Skittles The Strain yeah like
that's probably gonna be at least you
know somewhere in that room yeah
I've got a good anecdote for this which
is that the first pack of seeds I ever
bought was called gorilla Skittles and
it was from Barney's right yeah and I'll
be honest with you when I when I chose
it it was completely arbitrary I was
just I was so overwhelmed by the names
that were on those websites that yeah I
just picked a name that sounded
it's something that just stood out or
seemed even more bizarre than the other
names
um and at the time I had very little
appreciation for the history
um or what any of those things actually
meant uh sure you know what you get uh
photographs
whatever they've written
um and whatever other people say about
it right which I think you know I I
definitely have more to say about later
as well but yeah in terms of my initial
experiences looking at these play you
know uh looking at these products
yeah it was overwhelming it seemed
arbitrary
um and
yeah I don't know everyone watching this
right now in the comments below add in
your um thoughts like because I'm really
interested to see one what was
everyone's first seed purchase in what
year add that in also what were your
expectations when buying this and what
did you
what did you what went into your
purchase was it the grams per square
meter pictures name
um reputation of strain so yeah in the
comments below if you can if you can
tell us what you think I'd love to know
let's see
so we have the the seed buying
perspective a seed buyers perspective
kind of talked about that a little bit
uh we talked about how we choose names
let's see where are we at
I mean I'll just I'll say a bit more on
say buying I think
if you if you're new and you look at a c
bank website and look at the names
you you you won't have a sense of like
what's important slash popular yet
um so you won't you won't necessarily
know what chem dog means or what sure OG
Kush means or what Gorilla Glue means or
Skittles yet
and then in the absence of having any
context historically
um you do then gravitate towards brand
names that you are familiar with or
strong associations like you you were
talking about that
um and that's where the game you know
that that's where it gets it gets crazy
because
all you have
is you know in terms of you uh looking
at these things all the information that
you get is like yeah photographs
um whatever arbitrary information
they've decided to include uh whatever
kind of thin branding
um they've developed around these
products and maybe some like social
media interactions that you get to see
um
yeah I mean and at this point it's kind
of like
this is why like a lot of people ask me
why I got into this when did I get into
history it was because I realized like
kind of once I started seeing all this
stuff going through the logic of seed
buying I was spending my money on seeds
I had already taken a big dive at one
point on a massive purchase from
Amsterdam on a bunch of Dutch companies
and
I realized at one point all I have is
info from these people I need to know
who the people are giving me this info
and are they reliable
that that was the the point of where I
realized I need to see who these people
are like are they are they good
researchers are they passing on reliable
info is this something they're making up
are they the type of person who would
make something up do they have a history
of this you know that's when that all
became really important and and that's
when I started my journey and when I
started asking like at this point
between grower to buyer is there any
chance someone would have a motive to
change the name on what they purchased
as a clone or a seed to meet market
demand How likely is that to occur and
how often do we think that is occurring
you know that's that's when all those
questions came and started swelling to
me
okay maybe maybe this is a good point
for me to introduce a little uh
uh analogy
and this is actually something it's a
it's an article written by a writer
journalist called Jenny Odell and it's
called there's no such thing as a free
watch and I won't go into too much
detail
um that I would say that the
the piece itself is an amazing read for
those of you who are interested but I'll
give you a little a little rundown on
like
what she discovered and what this is all
about so
um I don't know exactly where she picks
up this lead right but she basically
finds online that there are a couple of
stores advertising this
very generic looking watch
um it's kind of just imagine like
a vaguely modern minimalist looking
watch that like
you know it's not very offensive but is
is also not super distinctive
um and she starts looking around and she
starts finding the exact same watch
being sold by all these different uh
e-commerce stores online
the way it's being sold uh is is one of
two ways one they say for a limited time
only you get this watch for free you
just need to pay for shipping
okay that's one side of it the other
side of it is they just say okay it was
fifty dollars it's marked down to ten
dollars right kind of pretty classic
schemes yeah and if you go on onto these
shops you know it'll have these fake
tickers that are like oh look like
people are buying it like live right now
yeah you can see like the numbers
dropping yeah and it's like you better
you better get in right you better get
in
and so she starts looking around a bit
more she starts examining the shop
itself
and she notices a couple of things one
when she looks at the photographs of the
shop and all that
she does some reverse image searches and
she finds that The Branding for the
store itself is all fake like the
photographs like for example this store
is meant to be based in like a hip
height of San Francisco yeah and they're
photographs of like an actual physical
shop sure she does a reverse image
search and like that shop that
photograph actually belongs to some
other shop of course no relation right
yeah and she looks into like the address
and it's not a real not a real address
um she looked into the writing that they
have on the about page and it's been
ripped from like
I don't know like the San Francisco like
city council website I don't know sure
um so all the branding information
around the store itself is all fake so
that's one level well the photographs
are fake
okay she goes deeper
she starts trying to find out how many
stores actually sell the same generic
looking watch and she finds a whole
bunch of them they're apparently in all
these hip cities Madrid London Paris
and they're all selling the same thing
they call them different names and the
branding's changed but they're the same
watch okay
so then she goes even deeper she tries
to find out where the watches even come
from right and quite quickly she gets to
like Alibaba and these like Chinese
wholesalers slash manufacturers
now the crazy part here is that she can
never find who actually has been
manufacturing these
she finds a network of quote-unquote
suppliers that I they are listed as like
manufacturers slash wholesalers
and so it's just this crazy
Human Centipede of like Drop Shipping
yeah no yeah for those of you
for those of you who don't know right
Drop Shipping is when the shop never
actually touches or handles any of the
goods they can order from a customer and
they simply send their order to the
warehouse the Fulfillment Place yeah
yeah whether that place is what where
they actually make it uh or where they
actually fulfill it that you may may be
another intermediary
yeah yeah yeah and so there's basically
this you can already see the possibility
of there being like a whole chain of
drop shippers
you know like this person's Drop
Shipping but the per that who they're
buying it from is also Drop Shipping and
who they're buying from is also Drop
Shipping and so it's just this like
endless uh
endless chain of like
fake Goods
and no accountability and no actual
origin yeah
um and I don't know I think that like
the analogies between something like
that and cannabis
I think there's a lot of crossover
tons
um you know the other day A bunch of us
watched a a documentary called
telemarketers and it was on HBO uh this
guy Patrick J pesvis and his friends did
a it started off that they were just
like junkies or one was a junkie and one
was like a young kid at a telemarketing
job and they were just filming how Wild
it was at their job where they were
getting paid to pretend to be policemen
calling for the policeman's balls to
seeing if you would donate to officers
such and such
and it was a similar idea to me and I
saw it very so many parallels to our
cannabis Community because
between that phone and and that at the
actual like Dude using heroin on the
other line
the perception to the person on the
other end of the line is that this is
you know officer Joe mcdonagall you know
what I mean like it's perception is
everything absolutely everything and
when there's a barrier there there is
some level of faith that has to go into
this
yeah and I've always felt like if you
can
mitigate Faith the more you can mitigate
faith and and get to actual hard data
the better off you are
okay I'm glad you said that okay because
just just drawing on that watch analogy
for a bit more
sure one of the other observations she
made was how it was being validated
online
and so these these quote-unquote shops
they would have Instagram accounts with
a whole bunch of followers okay their
followers were what she called quote
unquote aspirational influences people
who might didn't have like they maybe
had like around a thousand followers
each so they're not big yet but they
have they do have some visibility
and
what happens is that there's a kind of
mutualism a kind of symbiosis that
happens between this fake shop and these
quanticore influences where
the fake shop gives these influencers
more exposure and the influences also
give the fake shot exposure
and they validate each other yep the
cosine
yeah and going back to what you're
saying about perception well it's partly
a product of the internet right now
anyone can have
you can basically magic a brand out of
nothing because you no longer need
premises
you no longer need like all these like
traditional infrastructure you know
um for business
um and so you can play all these games
online because now you're just playing
almost like a pure information game
yes you can use to manipulate the
information space
that's information Warfare psyops yeah
it's in in at every step of the way it
is I mean realistically yeah it sounds
extreme but it really is I mean it's a
confidence game
um when I talk about co-signing a lot uh
I talk a lot of people ask me why I
don't have certain breeders interviewed
on this show and I try to you know every
once in a while I'll answer them and
explain it to him but realistically when
I have when I bring people on the show I
try to account for not just who they are
right now and what they're presenting to
me right now I also am I'm trying to
predict whether these people are always
going to continue to operate in this
manner and be good people because you
know how complicated life can get and
and you know someone suddenly loses
everything
they sometimes you can be moral fluid
and and the things they wouldn't do
before for money now become a viable
option we've just watched our whole
cannabis Market tanked so what I've
choose what breeders to bring on it's
normally people that I am
I'm very
very long acquainted with and that I'm
willing to in a sense cosine
a bit because I'm willing to say like if
I bring them on and have a serious heart
to Art conversation with them people
will have the perception that not only
we are friends but that I believe
everything they're saying and because I
know that perception is there I do not
want to bring on people that I don't
necessarily believe or trust and then
leave it up to the people watching to
figure that out because you know we're
just presenting something
I can't live with that and and when
people ask me about certain breeders
it's not even necessarily that I think
they're bad breeders and haven't had
them on it's just because I don't know
them well enough to put my own
my own cosine on the line if that makes
sense but it's not necessarily speaking
out against people if they're not on
it's just that safety measure and that
safety measure is there because of
perception
yeah yeah I think that's a really good
point
um
and you know just to I think just to
really really draw the point home right
a fake watch
is actually easier to verify than say
seeds right oh yeah you get the fake
watch you look at it it's in your hand
does it work
what's its quality like you can see like
it you can just do it is it yeah does it
look like it's supposed to so at least
if you bought a fake watch you know
whether or not your pinks can't
okay but I did want to say right the
point being the major point being
cannabis specifically
is even more ripe for exploitation right
and you were talking about flower before
Matt yeah imagine you're buying seeds
right and I I you and I talked about
this a bit before the recording but I
think this is the point I was trying to
make the seeds themselves are a promise
of plants
okay they
you know we've talked about genetic
variability before odds probability or
that you that comes into play right the
plants are a promise of flour
and the end result of all of that is
processed flowers so you have yet
another stage so basically from from the
beginning point of seeds to the end
point of uh consumable flour you
actually have multiple leaps to make
and it's a long time
and it's time and so what you get in a
chain of leaps like that or chain of
promises like that is deniability yeah
you know you have both you can both play
in this realm of plausibility and
deniability you if someone wasn't happy
with what you
uh what they got you could say oh but it
could have been you could have just
messed up at any of these points and
that's the way to deny like your
responsibility as the breeder or segment
yep right absolutely but even if you're
even if you're a legitimate breeder or
seed maker like this this sucks for you
as well because if someone comes to you
and says hey I didn't get what I thought
I was gonna get you have to now
troubleshoot and try to figure out at
which stage something could have gone
wrong
absolutely and that I met I imagine it
must be so crazy to have some of these
troubleshooting conversations with
people as someone who actually does care
and is trying to make sure that like
people are getting what you promise
it you know what honestly for me it's
been very um
I'm I'm constantly the bearer bad news
and I've kind of just come to live with
that you know like whether it's new
people in our Discord
um asking questions about some like
Barney's Farm or whoever you know like
I'm just gonna
have to open some doors that they
haven't heard yet you know and when it
comes to stuff like that because like
you know there are a few of us who
actually like test our lines know what
we're working with and run them out I
don't run into a whole lot of people
having issues with what I'm telling them
the line's going to be like not being
like in the end even if it's badly grown
usually there's some representation
there to where people are like okay I
[ __ ]
but the problem comes if you're using
seed banks because now you've got a a
middleman in between now let's say they
get seeds and these seeds didn't pop
well
if you're selling them direct and you
know the siege is still popping for
other customers you have them there with
you and you can pop them there yet
they're not having them pop there you
have to then think okay how are they
storing them at the seed bank was there
any problem with them getting cooked on
the way in the mail between point A to
point B or point B to point c
um how did they pop them what methods
are they using did they wash their
[ __ ] hands like any number of things
so yeah that's that's usually where uh
trickiness comes into play is uh seed
banks for me
yeah yeah and okay now that that's a
really good insight as well because I
did want to hear a bit about you yeah
that makes sense yeah but okay if even
if we move to flower right flower as a
product instead of seeds so there we can
say okay the Chain's been shortened you
it's not like the person has to grow it
out and see what happens it's like the
flower is the flower
um but even then right how we judge
flower it's extremely subjective
so you pointed out before that how you
judge smell how you judge a fix it's not
like those are
firm Universal objective things correct
so even with flower you still run into
all of this
subjective uncertainty and uh you know
you come up against the limits of your
judgment you come up against the limits
of what you can communicate to each
other
yeah and and it also again it depends on
education too
um another one of the review things that
I've been doing is something we're
starting to call Legit or not and it's I
just have no better name for it sorry
guys
um but it it was from my point of view
as I started looking into some of the
new hype Market you know looking into
these new names and trying these strains
out seeing if they are anything like
they're claiming to be or their lineages
Etc
um I've also been kind of interested in
seeing if any of the old clones that we
have kept all these years and that I
know flower up real well if I can go
into the modern Collective dispensary
Market
see that on a menu pick it out and
reliably get it like what's the
percentage you know in what city like
all these are data points to me and I'm
fascinated by it uh one of those recent
ones I did was something called Louis
the 13th OG Kush
um
and I did a review on it and you can see
that on our Channel and it was you know
I did the review on it was at least it
was a very it was an OG Kush the the
grow was decent of it the handling of it
was absolutely horrible if I was an
owner of a company I would never put
weed that looked like that in bags and
sell it like no way in hell but
because it was better than the other OG
cushions I had bought which it was a
terrible margin of of it was bad it's
Bleak out there
um
I got a second one and I got it for a
few reasons one my chick really likes OG
Kush and that was the closest one there
was and she's like I want that one that
one's helping me right now so I was like
it's ugly but all right whatever so we
got it
and I quickly to illustrate real quick
I'm gonna pop these up on the screen so
that there is some kind of um
so you guys can have some kind of idea
of what I'm talking about here where is
so here
uh can you see it is it showing up yep
okay good yep we're good so here we have
the first batch
um
it's not particularly wonderful looking
as you can tell it's
it's dark green it's been handled the
oils are smashed it's not I mean come on
you don't put this in a package but it
was actually decent to smoke oddly
enough because uh you know looks aren't
necessarily everything here's the second
batch that I got now as you can tell
this is not the same but this is not
even the same structure this looks like
a gg4 hybrid to me I would say and from
the smell of it it was kind of berry
Gorilla Glue
so at this point
my lady
I run into the the problem that I that I
was initially trying to figure out for
people my lady liked the other Louis
because it helped her headache at the
time and
I got a second bag one week not even a
week I think it was three days from the
last one and same name same batch this
is what shows up
and it's nothing like the first one from
the same batch same bag same company
same delivery service everything
so at this point I'm like okay now I
want to see how they're going to handle
this because I wonder how often this
comes up that someone's like hey you
didn't give me the you didn't give me
real Louis the 13th OG
I doubt that ever happens like where
people like can identify a strainer like
this isn't it you know like does that
happen I don't think so yeah it's always
hit a mouse about that too
I hit him up as just you know just any
random dude and I hit up the the
delivery service and actually they were
fast to respond
um and they were like okay well I need
to contact the owner of this company and
I'll let him know that there was an
issue so the owner of that company and
uh
you know I'll leave them nameless for
now but you can see it in the review uh
wrote me back and he said hi this is
blank from
our friends at blank told us that you
were unhappy with a flower purchase and
I'm so sorry to hear that
I have told them that we will totally
have them switch out the King Louie
flower bag and you can pick any of the
other flavors we did a different cut of
King Louis OG this time around because
we always package fresh to order we have
about five different in-house Growers
that we rotate flavors with based on
harvests where is it so we can keep the
same flavors in rotation and guarantee
freshness
uh it's definitely an OG but not the
same cut as before
sorry for the inconvenience we always
aim to please our patients and would
never want you to walk away unsatisfied
hope you have a great rest of your day
and and they have been notified with the
deliveries to switch it out for you so I
said
makes sense then I appreciate the
response on why medicine can't be relied
on to be consistent
I was wondering why that would be so
vastly different
as a seed maker that's an aspect I look
at I forget from the commercial
cultivation side how that goes multiple
Growers pushing to one spot Etc and the
reason I said this is because I wanted
him to admit yeah I'm just a [ __ ]
marketing guy I'm pushing other people
that are actually Growers flower I don't
know what the hell I'm talking about but
he doubled down
he said as you know
with breeding different phenotypes come
out expressed differently we try to be
as consistent as possible but there
being so many phenotypes of classic
strains some Growers prefer to stick
with certain phinos that respond better
to their formula or their growing Style
thank you for being understanding and
sorry about the confusion we would never
want patients to think that we are doing
a bait and switch
that was that
I guess I I did thank him and say no I'm
not interested in a replacement that's
not why I did this and I never got the
replacement because I just wasn't
interested and see if you'd actually
follow through with that but I was
interested in his response since Louie
OG is a cut a clone only not a seed line
there are not multiple phenotypes of it
it can't express differently but it
would not turn from OG cushion to Barry
and Gorilla Glue
just wouldn't happen that's just yeah to
me that's just some very slippery
rhetoric
um it is and it's similar to what I'm
saying
it was similar to what I was saying to
you about like uh
if you're like a scammy seed dealer seed
maker you can just pretend that like oh
it's because you missed up and at this
point of the process or this or that
this one is kind of like
I guess praying Chinese he tried to use
breeders speak on me he's like well yeah
you know type in variation
yeah but also like praying on like
ignorance no your ignorance because yeah
it doesn't make sense like to say you
can't just say it's a clone but also
it's not a clone it's actually
yeah a bunch of different uh
yeah none of it made any [ __ ] sense
so like how can he say he did not bait
and switch knowing that that's not Louis
the 13th OG
it's like literally that's what he said
specifically it's a different cut of OG
so why would you put it in a bag when
the end goal on your packaging says that
this is Medical
and that to me is like the the one
factor that kills me because the only
reason that we have ever been able in
California to be able to grow this plant
with any kind of like safety or
Safeguard or any safeness in our hearts
is because of the medical community
terminally ill patients cancer patients
people like that pushing super hard to
make this available and it was all done
off their backs and at this point they
can't even go and get reliable medicine
from these places at a reasonable price
that's done you know so to me it's just
like a
so many things have gone so wrong but
it's being carried as being done right
everywhere and people don't even know
that there are issues going on they
don't even know that there are questions
to ask they don't know about these
variables there's a lot of assumptions
along the way and if there's anything
that I if I can twist anything in my
whole career it would be to flip that on
its head and make people see it for what
it is now that we the the guy himself
has given us an insight into what his
game is actually like
um I wanted to bring it back to seeds
for a moment again yeah even though
we've talked about this many times but
the obvious analogy I was drawing with
the watch the whole watch thing right is
that in some situations these seeds are
being wholesaled white labeled by some
nameless Source somewhere
people are
getting a hold of these seeds rebranding
them repackaging them
remarketing them or sorry not
remarketing but marketing them
um and remarketing in many cases
remarketing absolutely there's a lot of
times when they're buying the bulk seeds
from a bulk seller they're not buying
the strain that they're selling they're
buying something that maybe maybe
pulls the strain they're selling and
sometimes in many cases in many
companies maybe not I mean you know like
maybe not have you ever seen Acapulco
Gold flower you know 10 weeks look like
that all dense no 60 70 days close
enough I mean
just one of many examples you know like
things that people can easily point to
and be like okay purple punch we know
what purple punch looks like it has a
very specific look and a resin profile
yeah that's not it
that's not it and like
it's just not and like but they still
list here genetics Granddaddy Purple
Larry OG so they're giving the genetics
um from from uh uh uh
oh it'll come back to me
the the actual reader can we spend a bit
of time here can you go and look at like
him come down yeah oh yeah let's do that
I think I the more I thought about it
when we when you mentioned I was like
dude we need to pull this up because
because they are funny dude the biggest
offenders in my opinion of this let's
see where's their chem dog do they not
have it do they have a search
let's see yeah they let's see let's just
do the the search for the addish mood
let's see what their search shows for
Kim dog or is it
a search
can't I should dawg that's probably the
best bet probably oh wow I'm none no
just just go chem and see what happens
yeah that's a good idea yeah
all right what do we have we have Cam
dog from blimbern oh my God look at this
thing
narrow leafed
nice and genetics clone of chem 91. what
look at this
look this is
yeah blim burn seeds so there's one chem
dog you have a a shout out here's
Bloomberg's Ken four which you couldn't
tell anything from this this is way too
early but yeah no definitely not
chem forward
Oh my Jesus Christ can we go to bindings
actually I know you I know this money is
on here but can you go to the actual
Barney's website
oh yeah see
is it still showing the search page
uh is it on that same page it's on the
same page you were on before yeah okay
yeah hold on a second I might have to
switch things real quick
um
stop screen present share screen and
where's Barney's
you know there it is sure here we go
there we go good old Barney
all right let's go chem again let's go
let's just do a little chem survey here
I don't know anything this is gonna be
real fun that's all okay Kim try that
again Kim oh there's no Kim here on
Barney's Farm it's uh Kim the closest
you're gonna get is like GMO
that picture actually looks like GMO
which is funny so I think that they're
probably like using a GMO hybrid for the
picture
what's another really recognizable one
what about the OG or something oh yeah
OG Kush is super rich see if Barney's
Farm ever got themselves a real live OG
Kush
at least in pictures we can see let's
see Bubba Kush see all results bub is
another easy one let's see OG Kush Auto
it actually looks like an OG Kush plant
in the picture too but it it looks like
a boofy ass OG Kush but yeah
you can see the shape that football
shape
yeah
you also see that in day record too that
similar shape of the bud
very very heavy and prominent in day
record except day wrecker has a more
chem 91 uh
Bud type and like has that leaf
cannibalism stuff yeah whenever I talk
about football shapes on OG that's what
I mean that
so I just wanted to interject and say
that like in cannabis it's not quite as
extreme yet I believe as the watch story
that I told like as far as I know no
one's doing Drop Shipping
yet
but it's probably not far away the way
things oh it it's very it's gonna happen
soon so the main thing that was going on
for a long time was in the 2000s a
company
in Spain started and they were supplying
Barney's Farm
greenhouse seeds
Scentsy Nirvana and several others all
the main ones that they were they were
supplying it was one company with a list
of like very femini seeds that they
could choose from uh
they're and obviously when this started
to make them millions of dollars really
fast other companies popped up that were
bigger and came and that's when
popped up and almost anything you buy
from Barney's Farm any of these guys has
come from
the past 15 years all of it was supplied
by them
um so yeah it who knows what you get me
in they don't really care but that was
that was as close to drop shipping as it
got but at some point they got lit up
um
and what was funny was not fun if none
of it's funny when people get lit up
like that but the odd part about it was
when
got hit by the span Spanish authorities
their site went down they're not cycling
down they put a warning up on their side
about it saying like uh you know this
has been
taken offline The Identical message was
up on
this website because they're the same
company
and a lot of people don't know that and
it's a Spanish company you know there's
there are good decent people who are
they own it but like are they breeding
maybe one might make some seeds every
now and then but do they is that the
seeds they're selling now that's where
it gets hairy you know like are they
doing their own projects and breeding
and into weed probably
is that what they're selling is that the
majority of seeds they're selling
and as much as I like the guys that's
that's that's the honest truth on that
and they know it yeah in the in in the
watch thing I think I mentioned that
like she basically
came to the conclusion that a whole
bunch of these different shops were
actually just run by the same person
and they just each of them had different
branding
um but it was the same same person
running all of it
and just getting it from the same
warehouse yeah yeah and you know in the
US it's starting to happen we're seeing
these big old seed makers pop up in like
Salinas Santa Barbara doing these
massive Femme pollinations outdoors and
selling these as Femme seeds for cookies
or for
that's where all those seeds come from
doesn't they're all just fem boofy
outdoor produced and these guys are
these reps of this company are nowhere
near this [ __ ] dude they don't the seeds
don't touch their [ __ ] hands
they aren't selecting
one big smoke and mirrors campaign and
like you know like I see the comments
with people right people get pissed at
me all the time because they say I have
nothing nice to say about other breeders
but I don't think I'm talking about
other breeders I think I'm talking about
people that sell seeds when I talk about
other breeders I speak with admiration
and respect because it's it's hard it's
the heart we should just we may as well
just start calling these people drop
shippers yeah realistically yeah drop
shippers they are it that's it marketing
drop shippers
um
um I did want you to look at one more
website because this one has some
personal significance to me okay I
posted it in the in the chat in our chat
here
I don't know if you can pull it out but
I'll give a bit of context
so before I've found the Syndicate I was
on a forum I'm not gonna name the Forum
okay but this forum was hooked up to
this website oh look at this website
dude it looks like it's made by Bots for
Bots these are all the the Barney farm
pictures
they're old pictures I recognize them
but look at the aesthetic of the website
dude like oh yeah it doesn't look like
it's it's for humans or that it was by
humans yeah it looks like the most
generic
um and so this forum that I was on was
basically trying to funnel these white
label seeds down their four members
throats
and you know this was like a major
sponsor saying hey you can get like
cookie s ones from weed seeds Express no
okay they ran a mild strain cool
everyone was growing these seeds and
everyone was so happy about it I just
but that's it right like because no one
that has experience was going to be
going buying these and and spending
their money here so the only people they
were going to be getting are people that
are new that are so happy that they've
gotten through their first run of
something they can smoke regardless of
quality because they're new like that
it's gonna work it's always gonna work
it's [ __ ] yeah it's preying on people
look at that dude look at that I mean
the other thing I think that freaks me
out is that this is this website is just
one example of like [ __ ] thousands
Skittles uh just as generic and as
faceless as this look what they did to
Green
crackers they chose for Green Crack
Jesus
[Music]
did they get OG Kush right they didn't
even put a picture of OG Kush under OG
Kush bro
but that but that goes to show you like
the people that are putting these
strains together and these sites
together they don't even know enough to
use a picture of OG Kush they don't know
what OG Kush looks like and that's
that's to me like that's one of those
keys it's like well dude if your breeder
doesn't know what OG Kush looks like
probably should be buying seeds from
them but if this is being shoved down
your throat at some [ __ ] forums you
know why wouldn't this be the Forum says
that's what people use right they got
peanut butter prep after all
wow
oh this poor Plant oh my God
yeah there's another one Amsterdam
marijuana seeds isn't that another one
bro there's so many man like yeah this
is the one engineering sea Bank name you
can think of probably exists
I think it was this one it was the one
that's been around like forever and is
never [ __ ] off Amsterdam marijuana
seeds these guys
Girl Scout cookies extreme uh we can't
see the tab I think oh that's why yo
Google yeah that's why let's see
but this is the one like whenever I hear
people talking about like their their
first experiences usually for some
reason they end up at uh Amsterdam
marijuana seeds and see if this is the
one yeah I mean look at that
just a horrible horrible plants I
wouldn't want to grow that
yeah the website says generic as the
last one as well yeah it's the same kind
of [ __ ] man
yeah
it's okay like I want people to have
better than this I do and I don't want
this to be the first place that they go
and get ripped off you know like for
People's First seed buying experience
shouldn't be getting ripped off
we almost treat it now like it's the
norm like if you just start you're gonna
get ripped off and then hopefully you
learn and then you stop getting ripped
off that's like with your norm and it's
sad because it is the norm like we see
it when people come to our
um our Discord now like that's the first
thing we hear is bro you don't know how
many times I got ripped off before I got
here
oh my God look at the plant on the
screen bro look at this look how Taco
those leaves are
no hope
yeah I hope for any of them
but yeah like was there anything like I
you go you go first no no no no go ahead
I was just gonna say like I think you
also did want to talk more about
collectives as middlemen within the
context of flower
um but we can also keep bagging on these
these websites I could do this endlessly
bro like it's gonna have to be its own
section on the show one day because it's
just like you can go through these sites
and and literally help people like give
them sets of logic to use like as I'm
breaking down this specific strain on
this page I can explain why all the
things that I look at that are are key
factors to me and why this is fake like
what would trigger this for me as a
person who's been in this business a
long time why would I not look at that
and see it's fake and I think that would
that might be an important tool for
people but I don't know I think a lot of
people just want their handheld and
asked like is it fake or not and at that
point again you're relying on the faith
of someone whether it's me or someone
else you're asking someone else and it's
always better to have the logic Tools in
your in your box so you're not getting
my agenda you're not getting anyone's
agenda I think we want to get towards
that that that process of thinking uh
towards the end I think you did set out
some points about it that's right but
how about we return to Flowerland for a
bit because you didn't want to talk
about
Flowerland uh you didn't want to talk
about collectives and the kind of role
that they've had as middlemen within
flower like the context of flower okay
so with the I think this is where it's
at with the uh yeah with the burgeoning
of the gray the gray quasi legal scene
we started seeing collectives with menus
of options and we saw more Growers start
in the field more availability and less
knowledge about the actual crops so the
menus have grown substantially
um uh it's just a long list of names to
a lot of people and and this it wasn't
initially the way it always was like at
the beginning of uh California
Collective summer it was like Scentsy
star Big Bud there was like seven or
eight you could get Urban Poison
blueberry
a few more white widow White Rhino
but that's generally what you would
expect it wasn't a large menu thread
interface
um and now we have a middleman between
between the grower the person growing
the crops and popping the seeds possibly
even popping the seeds because sometimes
the grower isn't even the person who
pops the seeds or sources the clones and
then we have
another middleman in between the flower
and the end user so that's a whole
another variable
and let's see uh each Collective
dispensary is working with many Growers
as the person
um talked about in that text
they said specifically we are working
with many Growers and we filter it into
one spot being the mylar packaging place
where they stamp their label they
stamped The Strain name on it all that
stuff
many Growers one spot all of whom have
individuals agenda individual agendas to
move weed from their pockets
um to the collective at the highest
price point possible
so the collective intern is also wanting
to make points on their packages so they
also have an agenda to maximize the name
value to Move It from the pockets to the
retail customers pockets
with name value
and hype and and social media Instagram
Twitter
uh Snapchat the invention of Snapchat I
mean names have gone and become far more
important in the sale than anything
except for pictures
and pictures are not worth a thousand
words anymore with with the invention of
AI pictures the invention of just you
know like people just taking each
other's pictures yeah just saying yeah
yeah it's just not it doesn't tell the
tale anymore
um let's see what else we got yeah it's
just it's there are so many agendas for
maximizing value and and getting points
off a package and and that's the term
that we use in cannabis and it's used in
many other areas you know but like
there's points on a package there's a
finite number let's say you the there's
another number of you can uh amount you
can get off this
um package is three thousand uh dinero I
don't know and and I don't want to get
flagged for something and um
and everybody's trying to get their
piece out of that three thousand so
there's a finite number of percentages
you know and everybody's trying to
maximize their value out of this so at
some point they start adding on uh
what's it called
fake value the best way into putting it
they're adding on fake values so now
it's not just three thousand let's let's
just let's let's add a different name to
it now it's got four thousand a pound
now this is more interesting to all of
us along the way right but what if we
you know
change a picture too now five thousand a
pound so there's all these different
agendas along the way and each person is
trying to maximize value at each turn
and
it's just a lot of human error and Faith
to put in a lot of people who don't
necessarily
have any reason to have the history in
mind or research in mind like none of
that comes into play when it comes to
the wallet just to be really uh bold
here you you mean like someone's grown
something but then they're like oh it's
not selling we're just going to call it
gelato instead yes and then raise the
price kind of thing well at least then
be able to move it so we can move this
at three thousand pounds gelato or uh
let's say we can move this 300 000 a
pound into screen crack okay well
there's only three thousand to spread
between us so yeah you know gelato is
kind of a hot name let's move it to that
well now there's four thousand a pound
yeah now that we call it gelato we can
move from four thousand account now
things are looking up everybody's morals
become more fluid at that point right
history research none of that makes any
sense the end user not having their
headache or not throwing up it at the
end of the day a lot less importance
yeah
that are completely irrelevant not
important just not relevant whatsoever
it never gets taken into account I was
going to extend what you were saying
earlier as well about how okay
now we're saying the names don't really
mean enough the pictures don't mean
enough even what they're writing about
what they're selling doesn't mean enough
and then it's like I think what makes
people the next thing that people go to
is
uh who's repping them on social media
yeah for example there's a big one and
like like the watch thing right I kind
of pointed out that like even if people
aren't actually happy with what they've
got there's a symbiotic relationship
here that could be at play where
the People The Growers quote unquote or
the consumers of the flower quote
unquote
um
have an incentive to still share the
product
um if they want exposure themselves from
the place they're either buying the
seeds or flour from and so they then now
have like their own entrenched agenda
um regardless of the quality of the
seeds or flour because now they they can
be promoted if they are promoting this
thing they themselves can get like
you know clout out of it but conceivably
well I mean that's to me how the the
whole
in that whole industry was built it was
a bunch of cosines off of shitty strains
not one breeder in the mix in my opinion
um it was people with big social media
accounts you know like it started off to
me like just for example with the the
example with why yeast wonderful
wonderful Dude made seeds did real
selections made real crosses and he had
a marketing guy then that marketing guy
was a better talker behind the scenes
not necessarily like physically a talker
that guy I can't talk for [ __ ] but he
was a better liar schmoozer and sneakier
so while the man doing the work was
making these pretty decent looking
strains the person that was doing the
deals on the back end was moving up the
Fuji and the marketing guy became
the breeder by just snaking his own
breeder out and then figuring out that
you can buy bulk seeds and sell them
that's how that's that's how that works
and that's how
and and the the thing that that killed
me was that I every time I saw someone
supporting that specific company after
this it happened to me it was like you
are spending money
against breeders you're spending money
against breeding because what you're
telling the whole community and by doing
this is that we prop up guys that are
marketers that put push breeders out and
that sell us [ __ ] and sell slides
that's what we prop up that's what we're
about so that's how I looked at it from
my uh perspective and obviously that's
not that's not realistic obviously
people didn't know all the backstory but
it also comes down to the point of like
who's going to tell the backstory who
wants to take all that heat for telling
the back story who wants to be the
person telling everyone at every angle
that you know and Santa's dead
this is not a fun position to be in
um you know like I always said I always
used to tell people I get mad and say do
your research do your research figure it
out and then at one point I realized
there's nowhere for people to go do
research anymore on these people
yeah just not
okay so I think we're getting towards
what we might want to recommend to
people as like a process or you know at
least generally to go through if you are
unsure about a product
but I think also
maybe I just do a little summary of what
of kind of like the conditions that we
the sub-optimal conditions that we've
outlined in terms of the flower and Seed
markets yeah so
again we're just pointing it out in the
seed Market and the flower market
there's a whole supply chain
potentially of different actors uh who
each have different agendas at different
stages of the chain
um there is the possibility of like
um
was I going to say
uh if you're a grower like I mentioned
and we're growing talking about Growing
Seeds your ability to kind of like
properly vet
uh what you're growing is really
difficult just due to the nature of the
plant and the complexity of all the
different stages that
um the plant and the flower have to go
through
um there is the issue of like provenance
there there's one other issue too
and and you kind of gesture to it but it
is the fact that there is a good
you know eight months to your period
before you see the the actual flower
from the seeds and during that time it's
eight to eight months to a year if you
pop it right away that you've gone from
the purchase like do you even talk to
that breeder anymore like you know what
I mean like will they have any
communication with you at that point is
it does it matter all that does that
piss you off anymore the you're so far
removed from the purchase is it really
worth the effort to go you know what I
mean so there's a lot of factors that
come into play about why this this scam
works
essentially
yeah many uh basically many what's a
good term for this
there are many gaps
uh uh between
yeah they're just like so many gaps in
in these like chains and and like chains
of production and Supply
um that where uncertainty and dishonesty
can enter
those gaps aren't really that well known
like outside of our Discord and our
friends and our friend group and some
seed makers like most people don't know
that you know this company is not making
their own seeds most people don't know
that this breeder doesn't even grow this
breeder doesn't even smoke let alone
grow you know like they don't know any
of that stuff
um but but it exists it does exist
okay so I think at this point people
listening in who are learning or hearing
about this for the first time might
start feeling really uh
how would I put it really disillusions
yes um about the whole thing which is a
fair feeling like it it is
dissolutioning it is really depressing
um but I also think that we do want it
to say that
you can do something about it right yeah
absolutely
yeah maybe we can start digging into the
possible ways
that you can try to verify that what
you've bought whether it's flour or
seeds
um is legitimate
okay
um
I'm actually interested to hear from
your point of view
what you've learned up till this point
where you would start right now like
let's say
um
you wanted to buy something that
had
from basically some kind of skunky
undertone
where where would you start to research
because that's a really that's where a
lot of people start it's exceptionally
hard to research skunky anything because
there are so many con artists running
around with that
man I yeah I don't know if I could
and meet uh
you're smart dude you can answer this
definitely
like what would you start so let's do
that now
I think with the knowledge that I have
now
um
number one I think I know a bit better
which
which clones or lines to look at or at
least which names to look for to begin
with you know even if I didn't have
skunk you know in my super skunk in mind
I think I would know okay
let's start sniffing around cam let's
look around diesel let's look around
diesel
um sure I can look for Super Skunk as
well I mean so there's there's kind of
like me knowing that's that's smart
basically like some strain history yeah
that's one aspect of it the second
aspect is now knowing networks of people
and knowing the people who are involved
given the history that's the next place
I would look
how did you get to the point where you
were studying the history though because
I mean you have to go somewhere sure
sure so I think the first thing was like
me trolling through all these [ __ ]
you know white label seat sites and at
least starting to get what the big names
seem to be that was like
pre-pre-learning right prede Syndicate
that's just made up of picking up data
yeah that one's more about like
analyzing frequencies of names right
imagine being like okay OG Kush is
clearly a big name chem dog clearly a
big name like that kind of thing that's
how I started
and then I think it wasn't long after
that I started getting into people's
reviews
like strain reviews on YouTube now you
know stuff like what you're doing now
but way worse yeah oh yeah um okay
because even in there I was like this is
so variable and it just sounds like
complete rubbish like so many of them
and I think that's when I started to get
towards more like long-form media like
uh conversations with breeders
conversations with um Growers
um and eventually find my way to breed
of Syndicate
um but it was around that point that
basically started getting me interested
in what the oral histories were
what what made you decide to uh
like
kind of settle at breeder Syndicate
because that that is I mean most people
you know that this these guys suck too
you know what I mean like I can
generalize here I think that at breed is
Syndicate you could actually try to
trace lines and I don't mean lines of
like in terms of like seed lines I just
mean like lines of like logic yeah and
actually get somewhere like you could
actually find a person and actually ask
them things and they would they would
tell you things yeah whereas like I when
you look elsewhere you just come up to
you just get didn't right it was like it
was like the journalist looking for the
source of the watches you would just it
would just be this endless like uh
yeah there's no way you could have
surfaces there's no way you could have
gotten to
the end of the day unless you had like
connections and connections into the
seed bank there's no way there's nothing
saying anywhere like these seeds are
actually made by you know
yeah interesting so the the other way I
looked at it was
is the person making these seats
one like a like have they published
anything about what they've done yeah
had they told any stories about their
process have they said have they
documented in any form like
um
yeah either provenance or process you
know either one yeah and often even that
criteria people fail yeah um
and then the third thing if and if not
that can I even identify a person in
this whole thing is that are they even
individual names being mentioned or is
it just a faceless organization and most
of the entities faceless yeah as an
entity
so again let me I'll recap okay it's
like
um
one is there a line of uh thought or
logic I can trace two is there any
mention of provenance or history three
is any mention of a breathing process or
seed making process and four are these
people even people that I can identify
yeah that's a big one
and so that is like outside of having
access to something like breed of
Syndicate I think that's a that's
something that you can follow whether or
not you have access to people like Matt
yeah um
but I'm curious now man what about your
opinion on like
uh trying to verify
something you're thinking about buying
or a company that you're interested in
or
that is so hard for me that's so hard
for me because I'm so biased now like
and and I have to I have to think about
this a lot
because when people ask me about someone
I don't want to if I don't like the
human
it's different than not liking or them
not being decent at their job if that
makes sense because there are people
that like I don't get along with that
are pretty good at [ __ ] making seeds
and and are legitimate and not Liars we
just don't get along you know
um so that part's that part's been
really hard for me to divide because
usually if I don't like someone I don't
support them period
um yep I mean I think one thing that I
can probably guess is really important
for you is just be able to have a
conversation with the person who at
least seems to be the responsible person
um like
if you're not happy with seeds I imagine
for you the important thing is to talk
to the seed maker and see what they have
to say
with the flower yeah I want them to be
smarter than me at this and not to say
they got to be Geniuses I'm not genius
at all I think I'm very basic at it
there's people that
you know can speak circles around me all
day when it comes to breeding but not
even necessarily smart I mean just be
able to communicate
basic basic [ __ ] like I can because I'm
basic and if they communicate with me
basically then it's great
um I was taught I told you yesterday
um I had a conversation with uh the rs11
guy
yeah he totally could talk
speak on any level about breeding why he
selected what he did how many he did
what he was doing at the time you know
like all the things around it the things
that like when you actually put the time
in and and it put in you know years to
breeding like you start at least with me
and a lot of my friends we start
referring to things in our past by what
we were growing at that time like that's
how we measure the time in our life it's
based on what our Cycles are growing
were because it's just the one constant
in our lives and when you start hearing
people talk like that then you know it's
very legitimately they're they're being
growing their being because it becomes
their basis for time in life you know so
that's one of those things I look for
and I noticed that yesterday and he's he
he's a totally different type of um
breeder in that he uses you know more
modern lines he's doing modern work and
but we're still able to communicate on
that level and I thought it was pretty
cool because it's been a long time since
I've met a newer person that can do that
yeah and I think this is part of your
larger point of actually just getting to
know these people
yeah get to know the people you're
buying stuff from this is this was this
conversation wasn't even about like
necessarily for the show at first like
it was it was because I it all started
out when I started seeing guava
the name guava pop up everywhere oh yeah
that's right I forgot about that yeah
during my era guava usually meant
startup like it was it was star dog
guava cut was in it and they called it
guava something or it was like a mango
smelling plant okay so I started going
on some a hunt trying to figure out what
guava was because I kept singing
everything including the rs11 the pink
guava so that's what kind of sent me on
that trail
and to this day like some people say
it's gelato something some people say
it's sure something I have no clue but
all I know is it's not guava e at all
but um I am interested to try the pink
guava now though after hearing uh Dio
explain it that sounds cool but
um yeah after trying a bunch of
different strawberry guava pineapple
guava none of them being pineapple
strawberry or guava it was a trip it's a
trip and that was kind of what even got
me thinking down this process was why
why this meant something else to me this
guadala means something totally
different to a whole generation of
breeders why does it mean this now and
what does it mean now and that's where
it kind of started you know this little
journey this show uh initiating
conversations with like Clearwater
genetics he was one of the people I went
and actually went into his Discord to do
research on guava because I knew that
our Discord probably wouldn't be a good
place to do research on Modern strains
you know like I'm not someone you can
ask about modern strains and I don't
know a lot of people in there that are
like that's their thing but I noticed
Clearwater genetics had used it and a
bunch of stuff so I figured I'd go in
his Discord and ask and uh yeah he said
gelato something very polite guy so you
know that was one step I took in just
trying to research it's one one data
point one person using the the line's uh
perspective I don't know how experienced
a breeding or history or any of that he
is at research but it's at least a data
point that I can take and say okay this
breeder you know a said this reader B
said this reader Z said this this person
has been around this long does this much
research more reliable therefore this
one is probably most likely the answer
that's how I kind of break down my data
and that was how I went about it with
guava
yeah and I I'll add that like that
that's a really good point as well uh
being able to have
multiple uh
multiple perspectives on the same thing
that you can help to use verify that one
thing whether it's like
um yeah I mean obviously there are
limits to that too like I pointed out
you know that example of like social
media influencers and these fake stores
kind of you know being in like the
double cosine yeah the double cosine so
you do have to be careful of that still
but I think
having multiple perspectives where you
can sort of discern that there aren't
the same agendas in operation across
those perspectives
um definitely tell you something it's
not necessarily enough to confirm
everything but it clear it definitely
helps a lot
yeah I mean it's like a like with a map
when you triangulate points or um yes or
like in in a story you know if you have
two people that are unknown to each
other telling two very unique statement
or two very similar statements some very
unique points you know like that that
stands out stuff like that you know
stands out quite a bit and gives more
relevancy and to the data I think
usually not always but yeah
because really I mean I've been scared
to use these terms but we are actually
addressing a much larger issue that you
know the world is still dealing with
which is
uh what they call like a post-truth
world uh where we have to face the
uncertainty of information almost now as
a mundane
uh issue
um and a pervasive issue
and you know one of the
it's sad though because I just don't I
don't know that this wasn't always the
case you know I just think it's become
in people's faces
but yeah it I think it's always been the
case even with our most popular most
famous book ever you know it's just like
it's never been the case where
everything is as presented
I I think that we can still point to
reasons why it's been accelerated though
or galvanized like obviously the
internet
um being able to have like e-commerce
you know like virtual shops social media
obviously specifically as well
um we mentioned the credit sure uh
Reddit did you mean do you think no no
credit like uh digital currency the fact
that you don't have to have hard
currency exchange hand to hand
yep big one
um I had another big one right the
Cannabis itself like I pointed out it
being first of all a very complex uh
process of production but also a very
complex process of like judgment
yeah um
yeah and so all of those things compound
like to produce this like
very
unstable information space
um
yeah definitely
yeah but sorry we were we were kind of
like
getting into a more prescriptive mode of
like trying to give people suggestions
on how they've actually verify
information and I think the last thing
we pointed out was like you said
multiple perspectives
uh diff not different agendas
um looking for triangulation
um
but what about something like Community
met like what do you think about so
coming back to the breed of Syndicate
right like how important is it do you
think to have a community of people who
are like oh basically looking for the
truth
it again it's like I I really truly feel
and I'm sure any parent of any group
that they build feels this way that it
is such an anomaly because it exists in
a in a vacuum of tons of forums that
have existed online since the beginning
of Canada seeds being sold online
and I have never seen a place that works
like ours ever there's never been one I
don't care there's no not even a close
comparison by any stretch the
imagination almost every single Forum
typically and I don't remember any seed
bank owners that I ever liked or got
along with that I thought wow these are
really good dudes that ran forums not
one not one and a lot of times it was
very us or them
our way or the highway
um if one of our breeders doesn't like
you you're [ __ ] dead to us you know
type thing so while
those information spaces are important
Community is obviously important when
you can do it right but it can also
be so just this bully mentality of just
stupidity and just in itself be its own
Mark pool like pool of marks to scam and
it's yeah it it's scary because you can
put yourself in almost like a cult
situation in some of these forms with
the way it turned out just shift
shoveling your money every time someone
does a drop because the Forum owner says
it's legit Bam Bam Bam Bam and like I
was actually thinking about double
cosines going on
yeah I was chatting with Shawnee about
one of these forums and um I I had it
popped into mind that these are almost
like little like feudal systems where
you have like the Lord You Know The
Forum owner the the sponsors and then
kind of like the like The Peasants the
the people who are like forced almost
forced to grow
um you know what they're being told to
grow yeah
and getting otherwise like banned if you
don't you know you don't comply
yeah it's it's tough too because even
even with our Discord there's always
going to be a kind of um attitude or
theme right that goes along with it and
ours has typically been like keeping
scammers out of our community with that
said there are people that maybe we know
or to us we have the knowledge that are
scammers but other people don't and they
come in thinking that these are good
people
and come in promoting that scammer's
agenda and get pushed out real fast from
our group you know and to the that
person's perspective they may be looking
at it like
we're just as bad as all these other
forms because obviously we have an
agenda we're not letting them push the
agenda for this particular person
so it a lot of it is perspective too you
know like
I just happen to know I came in a long
time ago and happened to know a lot of
these people really intimately in person
it's not just business to business back
then there were so few of us that a lot
of us knew each other person to person
we dealt with each other at conventions
Emerald cups all that stuff some of us
were good friends over years time some
of us were just acquaintances over years
time but got to know each other pretty
well you know so it's it's not just
business to business when I comment on a
lot of people and and like I was saying
earlier when you're talking about like
growing British stuff or uh and when I
was talking about good person versus
good genetics for me it's sometimes it
can be so hard because I'm so biased by
being so in the middle of the the social
scenario of breeding and Seed making of
course yeah
it doesn't help me for for bias you know
what I mean because but I do as much as
I can I try to be transparent in
perspective and keep perspective on that
for people when I talk about a breeder
and not liking them if it's someone that
I like their their actual gear I'll
point it out you know like I try to be
cognizant of what I'm saying when I'm
saying it how I say it because I know
some people take that to heart
you know
I'll also add that like I think having a
strong community that you can largely
Trust
embodies a lot of what uh embodies a lot
of the process already of what we were
uh
uh kind of recommending before like in a
community you have the opportunity to a
get multiple perspectives you get to
have extended conversations and why I
say extended like
um as a key part of this is that
over time when you're talking to the
same people you start to discern
patterns yeah you start to be able to
know whether what they say is consistent
reliable
and so you have having these sustained
interactions with multiple people who
all have different agendas and different
you know growing situations and contexts
it's much easier to come to you know
more reliable truths let's say because
we don't want to say that like you can
either you get perfect information or
you get uh false information it's always
going to be somewhere in between
you know like truth unfortunately no
longer is like an absolute
thing it's not like true or false it's
almost like we now have degrees of truth
yes and degrees of strength of Truth and
so if there's a piece of information
that again is verified by multiple
people and again you know they don't
have a shared agenda we can probably say
that that is
a more reliable truth than one that is
maybe spoken by one person who has an
obvious agenda right I think there's
just an obvious example yeah and so a
community again
helps you
um
definitely kind of like speeds up any of
these processes of verifying information
absolutely
um you know like thinking about it like
when you brought up Community my first
instinct is to like
push back from that because it'd be very
easy to be like yeah no our discord's
the way you know it would be very easy
to do that but at the same time I'm also
very big about like in communities there
can't be pedestals and I think um
that's something else people really need
to take into account Even in our own
Discord like I try to make try to be
very human there like people know I'm
just a [ __ ] up like everyone else and I
always [ __ ] up so
um I think that's important part of the
community too is that that it's a
community not a oligarchy or something
weird you know like a dictatorship uh
it's very important know and know the
difference between that and know what
you're in the middle of and always keep
up keep a very good perspective around
you with who you're surrounding yourself
with more importantly
I was gonna point out and I think this
could almost be his own episode but I
kind of wanted to point out what I think
are symptoms of the not very good
Community
uh I.E like a lot of the discords that I
have seen like so in breed of Syndicate
again what I was trying to draw your
attention to was having sustained
extended conversations with the same
people
now what you find in most other discords
is that there is communication but is
often really fragmented like you don't
really have the same people
participating all the time you have kind
of random one-off interactions with
random people and there's just no
continuity
and I think so if you get validation in
that kind of context I'd be much less
willing to trust the information there
because
you just don't have uh again a the
duration of interactions the the the
kind of like extended repeated
interactions
um and uh therefore you can't it's very
hard to verify what you're hearing from
them you know
yeah I've I've just been recently
learning about the discords that exist
as clone Gathering stations have you
heard about these places like the cell
phone yeah um I'm new to that
that was very new to me and one of the
guys that's a moderator and a few of
these and I were having a conversation
really smart nice dude he seems like
he's like he's genuinely interested in
collecting clones for the purpose of
getting data points to experience them
learn them you know things like that
that's a great reason to get into
collecting clones I totally admire that
it's why I got into it it's why a lot of
people do and I cannot [ __ ] on that at
all I don't [ __ ] on clone collecting
whatsoever even though I don't
necessarily do anymore but
like these clone collecting places
what I'm learning is that the people in
these don't understand that the people
holding these old clones
don't interact with groups that sell
their old clones because that's not how
it was ever these were things that were
gifted and shared and gifted and when
someone takes a gift or something that
you're sharing with them
like that's in your circle and like a
familial type thing and sell it they're
usually it s nade out like they're cut
off from the group that's how things go
over time and it's not a hoarding thing
it's just a completely different
mentality on how groups are built how
apprenticeship like how apprenticeship
Works
um friendships are built how trust is
built over time because a lot of times
if you're if you're learning someone you
share a clone with them they don't ever
[ __ ] you on that clone they never pass
it out or any of that you know that you
know you can trust them with a little
more and that's how trust and love and
friendships are built over time so
that's what a lot of these people are
missing in these cut organizations and
don't get that the people that actually
own the cuts with the provenance and the
in the good provenance that they want
aren't going to be interacting with the
groups who let these cuts out in the
community so when they're spending these
you know several hundred dollars
thousands and sometimes on these clones
that they're hoping are real and aren't
and they're wondering why this happens
it's because they're completely missing
the point
um I think you know clone trading is
great
um
I I just gave clones to people because I
didn't really give a [ __ ] about that in
the end like I just didn't I gave away
all of my clones and realized that like
I can pop seeds and find whatever I got
out of that mindset but I get it and I
think it's a sum of it is because I I
have those data points now and and
they're in my brain and they'll be there
forever and everybody I think if you're
going to take green seriously needs some
of those data points but know how to get
to that point and if you're in one of
those groups and you're seeing that go
down
um kind of have some some
Spidey senses go off a little bit of
when it comes to the provenance part
because these guys don't have access to
that they don't have access to a lot of
what they're claiming to and if they do
have some of these clones
they probably got it in Shady ways and
it's going to lead to bad provenance and
you're going to get stuck in a wall
where like you're gonna be like well how
can I prove that this is what you're
telling me and that I paid all this
money for well you know it looks like it
the best we can do you know so keep all
that in mind
I did also want to speak to a bit of a
like
I don't know Paradox is the right word
with clones but I know that one of the
one of the messages that you had for
this season was about
trying to escape this like clone
fetishization right yeah this is the
elite clone finish
but and so on the one hand it's like
yeah you know
um
uh goddess dead kind of vibe you know uh
and we're all like past that but it's
also like
clones are dead but also long-lived
clones because given how poor the
information game is sometimes if you
have a verified clone it is one of the
few
um reliable data points that you have
like it's an index it's kind of like
what you were saying so it's they're a
bit of a gift curse like I know this is
its own topic like
um
you know clones versus seeds and all
that that will I'm sure we'll get to
that probably in another episode now um
yeah but they are still extremely
important but they are also the cause of
a lot of
terrible [ __ ] so it really I mean
because at the end of the day clones are
just one or two or you know a group
selection that they feel
represents what they were going for best
or that they think the market will like
Best But at the end of the day that's
you know like who is doing the selecting
how how researched are they how how well
versed are they how experienced are they
do they are they do they smoke weed even
that's again do they smoke [ __ ] weed
even because a lot of these guys don't
how are they doing or selecting you know
do they have experience smoking weed a
lot of these guys never even have they
have no interest in it you know it just
another commodity
but yeah no I it clones are very hard
it's hard because there are good data
points to be gotten from them you know
like I recommend people run cheese and
stuff like that so that they have that
data point for skunk one or
sour okay one chemd but the it's worth
saying obviously and then this is going
to be obvious thing to say but the same
the same problems that affect your
ability to discern authenticity in flour
and seeds obviously affects clone sales
as well so absolutely absolutely and
there are you know like the one great
thing about cannabis being a very modern
like our scene being very modern is that
a lot of these guys that did this
elections some of those guys still have
those cuts in their hand never lost them
and that's like like with art if you
were going to an artist for a painting
you'd want to go to the first the person
who did it the most reliable person go
to the source and uh yeah I mean
cannabis is young enough to where a lot
of clones can still be gotten that way
you know
yeah I actually think okay actually this
is I think this is an important anecdote
from my personal Journey sure I think
early on I had given up
all
I think I'd given up on the on the
possibility of actually talking to
someone who was
who had any relationship to these clones
at all I basically just thought it
wasn't possible yeah like everything
that I saw on the internet I was just
like nothing feels like I can actually
connect to the real people behind all of
this it actually felt yeah but
it didn't also take that long to find
some people like Brita Center okay and
be like oh wow they are real people
um behind some of these things and yeah
eventually you can find them um
so I think I think with the craziest
part about the whole clone collecting
scene is is if you really break it down
like and you get really good at figuring
out who
who has done the best research who is
the most fastidious about provenance
about keeping their plants healthy how
long they've been kept alive keeping
tags right there's like
four maybe people that have this large
collection of all these clones
throughout our community that are
keeping them that are reliable for all
of their clones because they're just
consistent like four four people and
that's out of our whole world of
cannabis four that I can count and in
all of my research and I'm not one of
them to four
you know yeah like that's that's that's
scary that should be scary and very in
and people are going to say that that's
not realistic but it's true it is a
thousand percent true there's there's
four people
and we're lucky to have them very
yeah that's crazy to think about yeah
all the Breeders all the seed makers out
there tens of thousands there's four
four people
mind-blowing
I wanted to zoom out a bit and just
think about like
I think like Matt mentioned and we've
probably mentioned that multiple times
like
one of the pivots that we're making this
season
is
to help encourage people to to think
about what they are buying and whether
or not what they are buying is legit and
how they can know whether something that
they're buying is legit
and then the other major theme
is this whole tension with clones and I
think obviously we touched on the former
that that's this whole episode but I
think we'll probably come back to like
seeds versus clones like another time
yeah yeah that's fine I think yeah I
think that could be a full episode in
itself yeah it is yeah it's a huge thing
in of itself because like that for that
latter topic you know a lot of people
who don't like this show uh what they
like to say is you're kind of just
ruining our fun like does history
actually matter that much when I can
still find good [ __ ] and it's kind of a
fair point I think it's sort of a fair
criticism
um but we probably need to evaluate what
the trade-offs actually are so they're
obviously going to be trade-offs of
people who are very fastidious about
provenance and they're going to be
trade-offs with people who don't care at
all and just looking for quote unquote
fire
I think both lines of thinking are
actually sort of legit and I think we
could cover that in another time sure
and think about what the pros and cons
are
yeah
but man man I don't know we've said
quite a lot this is quite a dense
episode and I also feel like I have
repeated myself a lot but no just to
make sure that like we really really
drill these points home because I think
what men I also discovering is that so
many people somehow still don't know
this
yeah it never ceases to amaze me it
never ceases to amaze me uh a few things
yeah one so one at how many of the
scammers that continue to scam over the
years that always blows my Minds because
it's the same people but they had it
figured out early on that like there's a
cycle of new Growers always coming in
and as long as they could nail those new
people they have a constant influx of
new customers so that's one of the main
things the other thing that always blew
my mind was constantly having to explain
to people that there are bulk seed
makers
and they Supply most of the market that
part that part I I always think is gonna
like be someday be like common knowledge
because it's like that in a lot of
Industries but for some reason in
cannabis it's just like
not known still no matter how many times
it's said or reiterated
I think we did a whole show on it too
like the the worst kept secret of our
business you know yeah it's still not
that well known
yep absolutely absolutely and and like
with the watch analogy if you broaden
like uh this inquiry towards like
various forms of Commerce online you
will see the same patterns playing out
it's just that cannabis like from for
reasons I've mentioned multiple times
just is like even more susceptible
to these scams and like exploitations
than other products sure gray Market
means that there's no like real legal uh
recompense so it's going to draw in a
lot of people whose only intention is to
scam because they know that they can
legally get away with it and most people
like
especially like white collar criminals
that's what they live for you know
they're
that's their scam that's what they do
and and being in a gray Market just kind
of opens it up to people like that
that'll that'll that we're too scared to
grow but they can kind of [ __ ] around in
this room they'll get in there
and uh yeah and that's why it does it
and let me just black hat for a moment
and just and just explain like I'll
unpack this okay you want to start your
own brand it's so easy to set up
something on Shopify go steal a bunch of
pictures from someone else go steal a
bunch of writing from someone else or
use chat GPT to invent some story for
your company
um go buy some bulk seeds that are
really cheap from some random place
uh set up an Instagram account and
you're you're Gucci like you could do
this like a day or two easy you know
easy and if you're smart like you can
definitely trick people and obviously
I'm not saying this to encourage you to
do it but just showing you how easy it
actually is
yeah the one thing it's scary the one
thing that sucks though is that I'm not
going anywhere and everybody got to get
it past me and that sucks because it
doesn't happen very often and we
obviously outlined some of the steps
that we think you could take
um in your own you know in your own
searches
um but yeah I'd also be interested to
hear like if other people have other
ideas for how you
you know how you can best verify any
piece of information you know within
cannabis
um I'd love to hear more suggestions
yeah I'd also like to hear it for more
from the people that really hate what I
have to say like if you think that my
advice was kind of shitty like what what
are the steps you use to to do it better
like you know because maybe people are
doing it better than my advice and maybe
I could be giving better advice on it so
leave the comments below I'd love to
hear it
yeah because ultimately you know it's a
very complex again subjective thing
judgment is subjective you know like
evaluating these things is really
subjective so
I think we want to just like generate
more of this conversation and provoke
more of this thinking
um because that's that's what's
important it's not necessarily about
like making specific points it's about
ensuring that everyone is on this well
more people are on this journey of
excellence and so forth trying to figure
this out
yeah exactly
no I just totally get that on accidents
I was like it's gonna ramble
yeah and otherwise I think that's more
or less what I have to say otherwise I'm
just going to keep repeating myself over
and over again yeah and the same like
you know there are Avenues to be able to
do the research I highly suggest like
don't even just use breeder Syndicate
like go pick up marijuana botany go pick
cannabis ethnobotany and evolution from
from Merlin and Clark learn that and
that will give you everything you need
to know if you really truly understand
those books that will give you
everything you need to know to start
breaking down at least uh breeders speak
when people like you know for instance
this person that I wrote earlier that
said oh well you know there are
phenotypes
you can you can counter that real fast
and you'll know what what is [ __ ]
with it what is it I highly recommend
just just start there
yeah and also like the more diverse your
sources of information
um the better an idea you'll get of what
is consistent across those different
sources of information
um like going back to what Matt was
saying about triangulate like
triangulating something you know if you
read a whole bunch of texts you see some
of the same Concepts recur
that probably makes it a higher
likelihood that that is reliable
yeah and and the one other thing I'll
add is philos is not reliable data and I
should have said that somewhere in the
beginning because people are still using
that reliable data but please no no you
know what it's fine because we're going
to have an episode on the Codex where
all of this will be brought into
question again into context because it
is something that people use these data
points and I just remember like most
people again don't know the whole story
behind that and how it all broke down
and why they closed up genetic shock
Etc testing
for the Codex episode
um we can talk about Leafly strain Lee
philos seed finder we can go over all
those things yeah
yeah all right
so uh anything else you want to get in
no man yeah I don't wanna yeah I don't
want to repeat myself again
um you weren't reviewing something for
this one were you no no no reviews this
time
um yeah no it was just the the Louie
thing I wanted to cover basically but
other than that you know we have uh we
had our new high and Lonesome drop over
our righteats.com into the Appalachia
the Green Crack BX
um we had Kim dog dbx and some of those
are going to be restocked soon uh yeah
uh pack have some new uh feminized Santa
Cruz Blue Dream legitimate Blue Dream
crosses coming out soon I know some of
those are popping up on our patreon 50
tier
um as far as like uh testers going out
there and stuff so there's all kinds of
fun stuff going on
um Pico's getting a bunch of badass new
modern Femme stuff in the patreon packs
as well so thanks to Pico pandas helped
out everybody's helping out with the
patreon packs now it's getting real
exciting over there in the 50 tier
and I think that's it just keep your
eyes posted for the reviews I'm going to
be doing more of the legit or not and
just regular
um Regular flower reviews on Modern
strain so I can actually break down and
tell you what someone who's smoked weed
for a long time and has a lot of
experience with a lot of different
strains how I sense these strains what I
get from it the high the scents all that
stuff so hopefully that helps everyone
out somewhere I think we actually got a
new idea for legit or not as well as in
like another form of that same series
could also be you reviewing seed banks
right oh yes
so I think that'd be fun and even if
it's like whether it's you're going by
like today we're going to do Barney's
Farm or the alternative being like let's
look at all the different chems quote
unquote that are being sold across these
different seed banks I think there are
lots of cool possibilities for us for
those episodes yeah so if you hear that
you like that idea leave a comment below
and let us know you like that idea too
because if I see a bunch of you like
that I'll get i'll get on it and see
what we can figure out because I think
it'd be very uh enlightened for some
people maybe hopefully
anyway yeah righteous.com go buy her
spray feminized spray for making all
your own femini seeds at home it is easy
enough for you to do at home it's not
too hard this phrase ready-made
um you just mix it mixing instructions
come with it Shake It Up spray that's it
and uh for me thank you everyone here at
breeder Syndicate thank you and we love
you thousand thank you for your time
thank you very much
cheers everyone
second
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out Syndicate here.com we also have
an underground Syndicate Discord where
we get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out