foreign
er's Syndicate update not only is our
merch store up at syndicategear.com but
all episodes will remain free but what
we need from you is interaction if
you're watching the show for your first
time kick back and enjoy it if you like
the show feel free to like it but if
it's your second viewing we ask a gentle
person's agreement that you click the
Subscribe button it costs you nothing
but it helps us tremendously with the
sneaky YouTube algorithm
leaving comments telling not to his
voice lulls you into a trance works as
well we hope you take the time to do
this we try to put out the best possible
shows for you we can and want to build
this community thanks again from all of
us at the Breeders Syndicate family
[Music]
like I was connected with everything
around me
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
when it started to hit me
and I'm like wow
[Applause]
I got high
[Music]
welcome to Greater Syndicate everyone
I'm Matthew uh announcer's not with us
today but we do have Mad Jack and raho
for episode number four of the magic and
Rojo Chronicles
um today we were talking a little bit
earlier we kind of wanted to go over
some of someone that we've mentioned a
lot in in the past few episodes who is
uh are The Connoisseur and we've been
going over some of his past work and and
we all have a special admiration for the
guy and we keep bringing them up so we
thought that would be a kind of a neat
idea to to talk a little bit more about
some of his work and what we admire so
much about the man
so welcome guys good to have you hope
you had a happy New Year where do you
want to jump off at um we were the first
article we were reading was a five-year
review yes
September 1979. I start I I found High
Times I think about when it started in
1974 and
started reading it avidly and collecting
it and
once R showed up I don't know what issue
it was exactly it was really cool to
have someone who's in New York City
right in the middle of everything and
had access obviously he had lots of
dealer friends he had access to all the
strains that were coming in
and
that particular issue the fifth
anniversary 1979
was largely about the Advent of gold
when Santa Marta gold first showed up
Colombian gold
and how it blew everyone away and they
were just digging it and
over the course of a year or two
it made the brown weeds and other weeds
like uh oaxacan let's just say or
Michoacan guerreran in Mexico and
apparently he said even Thai stick it
people didn't want them they wanted
something that was gold all they cared
about was that the weed would be gold
and he mentioned a lot of the reasons
they were gold were
the way they sun-dried them or the way
they were
fermenting on their trip to the United
States in the hold of the ship or
warehousing in the U.S because they
would hold on to it and wait till the
prices got higher in the summer when
there was a drought and there was no
harvesting being done immediately and
um
just holding it at the warehouse helped
change its color but on the other hand
he said it also
precipitated the weeds that had mold
yeah it hadn't been initially dried
correctly or packaged
the thing that's so important about the
article is he's he's really documenting
one of the first
times well it's maybe the first time a
major Market shift based on appearances
was ever really documented you know and
it's uh it's swept through the United
States markets you know multiple times
over the last 20 years whether it was
moving from you know just uh just green
bud or kind bud to purple and everybody
had to have purple
and uh all of a sudden you know plants
and cuttings that had been around for 15
20 years just you know Foundation lines
that people had had bred with and kept
around for forever
um
you know cuttings got lost they they
were neglected they got pushed to the
side because everybody had to have you
know in order to sell you had to have
weed that looked like what the buyers
were looking for and that turned into
purple just like R was talking about in
what 78 70 79
um everybody you know wouldn't buy it
unless it was gold
you know so so the dealers started you
know coming up with ways to make not
gold look like gold so they could sell
it
um and uh you know it's just it's the
same story over and over again repeating
itself I'm sure it took place in in
Amsterdam you know multiple multiple
times where some new thing came in and
everything had to had to have those
superficial traits
but um
yeah that's uh you know the market
drives towards those things
um you know we we assess the product
with our eyes first
usually
smell comes next
and if you can really get a
we get a
all the different senses but you know in
today's market unfortunately I think
like that that's a thing of the past
being able to see it smell it you know
touch it feel the consistency with
um with the event of mylar bagging and
you know all the stuff at the corporate
level that people have to do it's crazy
to me that people can't smell their bud
before they smoke it blows my mind
yeah and I mean look at Art you know R
was talking about these same things in
1979. yeah right so I mean you know
people people lamenting you know cookies
and you know mylar bags that you can't
see what's in them and
you know about sticker with a lie inside
you know I mean
but it's uh
it's this is an old story it's been
going on a long time it drives it drives
breeding in in the wrong direction so
unfortunately
um so one of the other things that I
noticed about R in his in his ability to
be prophetic was his really famous
article that pissed a lot of people off
which was bam the indica
right do you remember that article at
all is bandwidth article where he in my
opinion prophetically tells everyone
that you know this thing's gonna come in
it's going to dumb down weed weed's
never gonna be the same like he was more
of the the trippy sativa you know like
he liked that high that that
clear-headed high or that Speedy racy
high and he felt like indicus was just
gonna completely come in dumb it down
and the market would be mostly Indica
dominant because the ease of growth for
for indoors and I mean it almost like
told the tale of what happened with
cookies and Kush like prophetically
yeah timing the timing on that article
is right on the money because you know
the the Affy the indicas had basically
made it into every nook and cranny of
the American Market by that point
anybody wanted seeds to grow uh an Affy
um could find him and uh there was just
so much variety you know when you think
about the various paths that these seeds
took the connections that were made you
know the it's um it's amazing to think
about that that network of of genetics
just just exploding overnight and and
spreading around the country because two
years earlier
you know it was scarce's hen's teeth you
know getting getting Indica in 19 1981
you know hard to find rare we it was you
know not maybe not in the hills of
NorCal but
everywhere else but in two years it was
turned you know up overnight just it was
everywhere everybody had their own seeds
and we're growing it maybe we can expand
on this just a little bit because it's
something I want to drive home to a lot
of the younger people because I think
and and based on
how how often I see people make claims
of having these afghanis from the early
60s and and so and even 40s in some
cases uh can we can we kind of drive
home the point when afghanis when you
both saw afghani's into the market
either one of you on that one
well for me it was when I met Rob Clark
and bought my skunk number one seeds
didn't hit Afghani number one yeah that
was the first time I had
heard of it or really seen
and I grew some
I don't remember them I just he gave me
a little free pack of a few yeah
compared to the mass of skunk number one
that we bought and I I know I grew them
uh maybe on a little side patch or
something
and it was it definitely well it was
part of the genetics of skunk number one
anyway it had Afghan in it
and the the leaves were medium sized
they they weren't these natal beautiful
long needle sativas so um
maybe it was it piqued our interest and
we were going wonder why these leaves
are so wide or I haven't shared like
that but did they smoke tanning
pardon do you remember them being
smaller plants compared to the rest and
thinking what the hell is that I don't
remember I don't even remember growing
those Afghani number ones but that's
where I first heard of them so when when
Clark told me the uh genetics involved
in Skunk number one I went oh wow so
it's in here too and I
don't totally agree with r on that
because we have the ability to have all
of them now I mean you can have land
race beautiful sativas from Nepal some
remote little you know zomia that you've
discovered and other real seed company
and then you can have um pure Afghans if
you want them and I guess was it Tom
Hill who had Maple Leaf uh or deep chunk
yeah yeah yeah and that wasn't that a
few a pure Afghani or it was like a
hybrid of a few afghanis
he uh he says it is he says it's pure
yeah yeah
the um Maple Leaf was Neville's stuff
yeah okay is it is it spread around you
know he sold it under different names
and other people got the seeds from him
did their selections and sold sold stuff
under different names
yeah that was one of the early bass
lines the maple leaf from him
um one that an Afghani that kept passing
into other lines under different names
definitely
hmm
supposedly
the uh the um
the maple leaf is the possibly
supposedly the back end of super skunk
and what is making Super Skunk so skunky
well you know you know it's Afghan T but
yeah the Afghan tea is maple leaf so in
the way the reason I say maybe is
because there are also some theories
even among Neville's old partners that
it was really Afghani one really named
Afghan T
which is possible you know especially
knowing Nev it's like very possible
because he disliked he disliked um you
know Santa's got banned quite a bit by
that point and giving them credit for
one of his
best lines when he already had half the
credit for nl5 Hayes you know
um was probably not in Neville's idea of
things he was going to let happen that's
my personal opinion and I know some of
the other partners kind of share that
Afghani one Theory so yeah
yeah
he certainly you know spoke had nothing
good to say about Afghani number one
when he was back on the forums but
exactly
um you know it was interesting the
language that he used it was very
non-specific he called it uh
toxic in a bad way yeah yeah like he
needed to say like there's that good
toxic you know right right but it's not
that one it's the other one it's the
it's a bad toxic right right right and
that goes to the point of like I saw him
like
constantly referencing Afghani one even
at points where I'm like huh why why are
you bringing it up right now like stuff
and they're talking about Super Stop the
stuff and he's bringing up Afghani one
and I'm just like it's almost like he's
guilty to me not guilty but maybe his
conscience coming out being like here's
a little hint here's a little hint for
the people actually give a [ __ ] little
little breadcrumbs that I don't know I
could be all in my head too you know
there were there were a lot of good
lines around that didn't turn into these
legends that are sought after and those
are the ones I I wonder you know what
happened is they if they would ever pop
up again but
I mean kyber right yep
um that was that looked a lot like stuff
I grew at the time and you know it was
fire so you know I always wanted to get
that but by the time I you know
discovered seeds online
um you know it was already yeah it was
already kind of the market was all
screwed up deduction totally screwed
everything up you know you know what's
interesting too a side note I just got
this in okay listen and it's something
that me and uh actually CSI mostly I
found out about it much later and we
were told about it by mustafung and it
is from the breeder of the Pakistani
chatrol Kush and it's the whole record
of the dude who bred it named isadoro
Rodriguez but it's all in Castilian so
wow it's gonna be fun to try to read it
but the breeding of chitrali is all laid
out in here in pictures and everything
so Props to mustafung for for putting us
in the right direction on that yeah now
there's a guy you need to get on the
internet oh my God right
yeah
definitely
you know Santa Marley you know yeah or
Ecuadorian or Peruvian or Bolivian uh
yeah it's true they were more into coca
but I'm sure someone there
had the ability to grow I was looking
for the article can you tell me the um
the date on it but for which
because we are yeah the fifth this one
is um September of
1979 79 79 yeah oh 9.79
and so it talks about the past five
years uh uh that he's been there and
it's in the first uh division he has at
the age and plenty of variety then they
have the the rise of the Exotics which
is hilarious considering what they
consider Exotics now you know the
narrowing of the market
we have the Colombian Gold Rush the Rise
of fool's gold and the decline of
Colombian the Advent of sin Samia which
I still think magic has something to do
with and the embryonic third generation
and the first signs of New Hope
agent plenty of variety
and I mean I I don't know if I should be
reading the whole thing but uh generally
speaking we have the menu here here's
some uh Ethiopian Emperor stash nice
little dense nuggetry there
and along with some kush some uh this is
an old picture of Afghani if it's 79
Kush smoke yeah I remember these
pictures I remember when this magazine
came out and the colors on that page
from that Ethiopian Emperor's stash the
bright emerald green and
you know it's just just gorgeous and and
the way it was kind of similar condition
to that what they call Kush smoke down
below it you know they both look like
this wasn't something that was manicured
and and you know put in a and protected
it was something that was thrown in a
baggie and carried around in a backpack
for for sure weeks you know it it looks
like that and um
but I I don't see a lot of seeds in the
in the Kush the Ethiopian definitely lit
my imagination all the all the while
back then I still think about you know
could there be some something special in
an Ethiopian line
um
I'm sure yeah especially these old ones
and it has the menu here from the week
of uh June 16th 1974 for the prices
so it shows like Mexican commercial at
200. well Hawken tops at 3 30. uh
Michoacan at 5 50. then you have the
Colombian Reds multi and gold and I
remember uh when I was talking to one of
the guys who would bring in Colombian in
Florida you would always talk about how
you had to buy a certain amount of uh
Colombian rainbow I believe he called it
which was the multi like they're
referring to here just like all of it
kind of compressed and combined the Reds
blacks both and or the the bottom end of
that and then for every 10 kilos of that
you would buy you'd be able to buy like
two kilos of the black or one kilo of
the red or one kilo of the gold I always
thought that was fascinating that there
was like some kind of Market trade like
that where you can get you had to buy a
certain amount to get the higher tier
this
looks like Panama Reds um at the top in
74 as far as the the highest priced
demand
[Music]
600 a pound whereas you know commercial
Mexicans at 200 so three times the price
of shitty commercial Mexicans moving in
all the time so it's talking about the
rise of Exotics here yes by the end of
the first year in addition to all the
goodies on that menu above almost every
time you showed up at Crosby's or
similar smoking salons and I guess they
were smoking the saloon somewhere which
that sounds fascinating for the time
um well it needs more saloons yeah right
uh new and excite exciting stamp example
of by the surprising second generation
dopes by the end of the year the menu
would include the following premium
price entries we have the Chaco Chiba or
at least Chiba uh 65 Colombian per ounce
wacky weed which is what art talks about
all the time 75 an ounce and the Santa
Barbara gold for 60 an ounce so at that
time wacky weeds killing it whereas the
tie is at 200 to 240 an ounce per stick
at 15 to 20 and Hawaiian at 160 so
significantly above the Colombian at the
time right here you can see a picture of
the the Jamaican land spread very early
picture of it
and there's the wacky weed
the Colombian wacky weed
and do you want to explain why he called
it wacky weed bro
no
I don't think uh no honestly I I never
had anybody sell me anything called
wacky weed right so yeah
um hearing these descriptions of it it I
know jaggy and I probably both are
thinking this you know sounds familiar
um but it's you know like Mad Jack's
source of the candy bar the black highly
compressed
um you know super super weed that was
you know sliced off with a razor blade
like cash yeah um you know that's
you hear similar kind of attributes or
traits to the effect to this but it's
it's definitely not the same thing
because you know there was just that one
farmer up there crafting that out and I
never saw anything like like what they
said of wacky week yeah
it's a nickname um in 1970 in Denver
there was a weed that I never saw again
that they called cartoon weed
and when you smoke this everything
you couldn't stop laughing from the
moment you took the first few Puffs and
you're just everything became a cartoon
in the sense that you couldn't hold back
and let stop laughing and it was just
fabulous more typical from when people
eat
um cannabis you know they get into the
giggles and then maybe into just
laughing so hard they have tears running
down their eye out of their eyes but
cartoon weed wacky weed you know
nicknames that I guess if you smoke
wacky weed you'd get whacked and it was
just overly powerful
yeah he he refers to in a lot of these
articles as he almost refers to it as if
he thinks maybe it's either a strain or
expression or something that can be
gotten more than once you know from the
same farmer and that it's an actual it
seems like he's talking about like it's
strain but I think more than likely it
was just highly compressed really
high-end Colombian where the oils have
really soaked in you know to that bud
maybe even hash coated like or oil hash
oil compressed
um but yeah it sounds like it just made
people absolutely stupid and and lose
control of their limbs a fellow I knew
in Chicagoland in 1970-71 had high
school kids making Thai sticks you had
the same same little
splinters of they were like bamboos
steaks little tiny ones and he would pay
these kids to sit and it was Mexican and
it was good since Samia early stuff and
he had them wrap the buds very carefully
on these sticks because he could
quadruple the money he charged easy yeah
that's brilliant though he was an early
entrepreneur yeah that's it that's an
entrepreneur a definitely an
entrepreneur
um So lately a lot of people have been
talking about the choco Chiba Colombian
especially since we uh did the chocolate
tie episode a few days ago and right
here it talks about the entrance
of the Chiba at least the that region in
Colombia where stuff was imported from
and it says while Tai was certainly the
most glamorous among the new treats
served up I think not enough credit has
gone to Chiva which for the sake of
historical Justice deserves a footnote
uh as the first high-level breakthrough
to Second Generation quality grass so
they're referring to the Chiba maybe as
a second generation type Colombian gold
or gold type Chiba hit the state shortly
before Thai and opened up a lot of Mines
to the higher possibilities of grass
opened up a lot of wallets too it was a
closer to a psychedelic uh than any
other previous grass available
breathtaking Russia's super energetic
and cerebral grass and demonstrated to
the marijuana marketers that people
would pay 75 an ounce almost double what
they were accustomed to if the grass was
like Chiba a Quantum Leap above the
ordinary chiefly established the reality
of The high-priced Gourmet Market and
after that the supply began to match the
demand and then it was talks about Chiba
followed by other Colombian specialties
like the wacky weed and the tie and and
other stuff like that coming in
uh uh and then it talks about the
narrowing of the market and one of the
first things to go was the Panama Red
and today I I know like there are people
that sell different kinds of panamanians
out there
um but as far as what a true Panama Red
is I don't know if anybody agrees can
either of you comment on Panama Red or
your experience with the red
or did you have any
um
well you know I I didn't know whether
what I got was a Colombian red or Panama
Red I like to think it was Panama Red it
was certainly an amazing plant
um the weed itself was amazing
um
you know it's pretty pretty lame
descriptive words but
um
you know
I just looked up to see if when we gave
up the Panama Canal to back to Panama I
was trying to figure out what might have
you know besides you know maybe they
just got tired of growing weed down
there I don't know you know but what
what would be the reasons why something
like that might happen sure yeah it
didn't it looks like
part of that happened during the Carter
presidency which would have would have
been a right around the right timeline
yeah
um
yeah I don't know I'm not sure why but
you know as as far as the quality of
that
of that weed
um
you know potent tasty uh unique effect
what good effects but um you know
definitely in a kind of rarified air
like you know man I can't you know I
hope I ever get to smoke something like
this good again when it happens you know
it yeah and um you know it just was so
uncommon that talking about it
disappearing
um you know would have been like what
you mean
it's true I am never gonna get to smoke
this again for the rest of my life yes I
already I already believed it you know
yeah um you know maybe maybe different
people in different circles got that
connoisseur uh stuff flowing through
non-stop like that that would have been
amazing but that wasn't my experience so
what about you Jackie what was your
experience with the Panama City
four finger baggie for 15 in Denver
nineteen seventy nineteen seventy that's
early man well 69 and 70. I was in
Denver 69 70 and 71. and it was um
excellent weed it was right up there it
was
at the Advent of sinsemia where seedless
weed was starting to separate itself
from the traditional seeded weed and
yeah less pressed from the super press
started the same you know even oaxacan
Spears in entirety just cola's uh
wrapped in cellophane pressed lightly
but you know some big bundle in your
arms might only weigh four pounds or
five pounds because yeah it would
um and true there was more stem that way
but
wow for the quality of the spears it
what didn't matter Panama Red
to me it was in that top tier back then
1970 quality wise
I don't remember the smell the aroma
but yeah
do you remember it standing out any more
than Colombian gold or anything else
I think it might have had an edge
well
it disappeared at some point pretty
quickly and and has has our
his R has
explained his gold just you know the
Columbians don't do anything small
they're very organized so they started
shipping
not just tons but
freighters
I met a guy
who brought in Freighters in like the
east coast of Florida with 200 250
000 pounds in a load he eventually
he had too many employees I mean the
just the offloaders on the docks there
was like 30 people and eventually
someone got in trouble and they they
were facing big time and they rolled and
it went right up the chain to him and I
probably bought my first ounce of weed
in Denver from
his group because they were sending from
these freighter loads to Chicago Denver
New York all the major cities
and it
I think Colombian just eclipsed the
Panama Red it along with Mexican too it
wasn't until Mexico got really
focused on high quality you know the
guerreran the sinaloan oaxacan and they
were mostly people bringing small loads
like airplane loads where they didn't
have to have them
sitting in a freighter for three weeks
while it's coming up from Colombia but
but gold the gold was a very big
presence super presence when it came
and it came big
that's why I think people wanted it so
badly you know because you might get
some one time that was super potent and
then another one next time that was
super moldy you know it was very
difficult unless you've had an inside
line to the importers themselves yeah
where you could get the tops and the the
best parts of each pack yeah definitely
yeah that's fascinating man I wonder I
wonder if because I noticed in a lot of
these old articles uh he repeatedly
talks about The Disappearance of
Colombian too at some point that that
Colombian kind of died off for a while
and you know at first was a Panama then
came Colombian and I wonder if it was
just the the
push of Mexico being so much closer to
the U.S and being that it was so much
easier to smuggle for Mexico than having
to go all the way down to South America
for Colombia move it all the way up
until they had some kind of in-route
worked with the the groups in Mexico to
smuggle up for them you know and
eventually Colombians did come back they
made a return for a little bit and he
talks about that in some of the later
articles yeah you know I I think a lot
of the the rise of homegrown in America
happened about the same time that that
cocaine started taking over as far as
what they wanted to fill their airplanes
with the smuggle yeah um you know those
two things happened about the same time
so commercial Colombian you know the
Heyday of of Colombian dominating the
weed Market
um
it it literally went away like
over it it seemed like it was almost
overnight you know it's definitely over
the course of one year it went from you
know Colombian was everywhere to who
wants that [ __ ] to you can't even find
it anymore
yeah right
um it just happened so fast with with
good homegrown showing up around the
country the the indicas show Indica
seeds showing up around the country all
around that same
82-83 1983 time frame really is when it
when it was everywhere
yeah
I have a photo here I'll see if it'll
show up it goes along with what we're
talking about okay yeah but on the share
thing uh
well I here go to presenters
it's Columbia's green right this is
an article that was
I think let's see in 2019 this was
published but it shows all the major
weed growing areas
in the cocoa Valley Cali is right up
here but at the bottom Pope Leon down
here is a famous area too so they have a
lot of famous areas yeah I guess so
Highlands Highlands let's see corinto
yeah
purple corinto that's a famous One
yep really I have not heard that no so
one of the the quotes that R has here it
says gold looks so good that people
became conditioned to the notion if
grass wasn't gold it couldn't be good
all the Glitters Is Not Great Grass and
not all great grasses gold and this to
me like as a as a person who grew up
post you know it really heavily started
smoking in the 90s the idea of gold or
brown weed to me was just like uh bummer
you know but at some point in the US
like we've talked about people really
did genuinely expect gold
um and people were trying to figure out
home Growers were trying to figure out
how to get their plants to dry gold
because it just wasn't selling for a
while
and that's kind of what this is
referring to
well you know this is this is like 76 or
77 there 79
yeah yeah this is yeah I mean you just
have to understand that it it a very
small window of time where markets
transitioning and reacting to demand for
something like like a color
right and how and how you know Growers
and middlemen around you know around the
world are trying to trying to make what
they have
sell yeah so I mean we saw it with
cookies and you know the the the wide
variety of dessert weed out there
um when cookies first came out you know
it was uh the cut was hoarded you know
it didn't exist in seed seed form you
know the people that had it
um
you know everybody wanted it but it
didn't exist so the market invented it
right just like what we were talking
about Matt the other day was you know if
you give people the CR the traits that
the product has they will change all
their labeling without without changing
the contents of the package exactly
exactly right
so I mean you know all of a sudden
everybody had cookies but nobody had
cookies right yeah and um and that's the
same thing with this gold except back
then I mean we were stupid because it
was the 70s and and you know you could
get away with being stupid but people
would do things physically to the weed
to try and change the color you know
putting it out in the sun I mean you
want if you want to know how to kill
cannabinoids that's that's how you kill
Canada right in the sun yeah all right
just stick it right out there yeah it's
gold but now nobody gets high yeah or
girdle it you know like they talk about
that stabbing the stem in the middle
yeah all that sort of uh you know things
to stress the plant and make it
make it die a particularly colorful
death
well you remember hanging a plant upside
down at Harvest was supposed to make it
more potent because the red tops
downhill from in the from the stock into
the flowers
I remember that that uh old wives tale
but if you hung it upside down the THC
would spike to the top of the tops oh
yeah gotta have the juices you know yeah
yeah so this is interesting or people
understood trichomes and oh yeah oh well
exactly this is this is interesting so
it looks like right here uh our answers
the question on if Santa Marta was the
first Golds to hit
actually looks like Chiba was the first
wave of Colombians and Santa Marta
started in 74 to 75. it says Santa Marta
was an authentic high level gold it
didn't have the Psychedelic upper
reaches of Chiba but it was powerful and
energetic a very up high more than that
Santa Marta set a new standard for
beauty that pleased the physical senses
it was pretty to see with its plump
blonde buds bursting with pollen furred
flowers it smelled delicious with the
fresh spicy pequa peppery flowery
fragrance it tasted especially good
Tangy warm and spicy on the tongue with
a fruity tinge that it tested I hate
when it does this
it had tested uh to its flowery
freshness
um so there's some pretty good
descriptions of Chloe would you guys
agree with some of those descriptions of
what you saw
yeah I mean he uh he he dances around
some of it I think um you know he hints
at some of the wood or incensey type
uh traits that are there it's a it's a
an amazing combination with the you know
The Buttery hashy citrusy kind of uh
Tangy I think is what I I read a word he
used in some of these articles
um
you know still got that to have those
kind of high notes mixed with the earthy
wooden incensey stuff it makes it very
hard hitting uh as a terp combination
you know incense with with Citrus uh
can can really can really deliver the
goods so oh I bet
well being 45 years ago I can't really
tell you I
honestly it would be a stretch but I'm
sure it did you think it was hashings
Jack did you think it was hashy tasting
I no I wouldn't call Santa Marta has she
um or
maybe those
those blacks the blacks from Colombia
could go that way but even even the
wacky weed or the candy bar my friend
had
though you had to cut it like it was
hash it didn't smoke like hash it it was
well I'll take that back it might be
equivalent to smoking hash in a joint
because my friend in Tempe used to roll
joints out of hash that he crumbled up
and they were little pin joints but boy
they were potent so maybe there but I I
don't remember
this being at all a Santa Marta being at
all ashy they it was just
a delicate
High you know it was it was an up high
maybe that's what was so special well
how can was similar at the beginning
just a super
space shot you know you just went up
higher and higher kind of psychedelic I
think that's where they applied the word
psychedelic to some weeds
though at the time most of us were also
experimenting with psychedelics so it's
kind of hard to
decide when we were accurate and when we
weren't
here's a new interesting one it says a
promising new entry in 77 for instance
was the man is Alice block is this have
you guys ever heard of this one
not by that name but I know
where's that at
well that map of the cow cut I think it
was on on in that era let me look at it
I can look it on my desktop here yeah
uh
nope
I think monizales was one of the Low
Land
um West Coast
areas yeah
I'll bring up a quick Google view
yeah that's
that's Mexican there for sure well
Hawking tops and and right here is a
picture of the Chiba for and like I said
this has been brought up a lot lately
the Chiba the choco Chiba
um I I guess maybe some seed companies
are playing with some purported jiba but
this is what uh it actually looked like
documented back in 1979 the real Chiba
right here
as best we know it's a real cheap
anyways well it's a real name yeah well
the thing is like I always try to remind
people I'm not sure about it this time
but later on High Times would use pretty
much any picture they wanted to and
insert it and just put a name on top of
it and that did happen when like they
didn't have a picture handy for
something wow so a lot of times
especially during the 80s and 90s and
and on to the 90s it became standard
practice if you look at like some of the
chem dog
um pictures like the pictures of chem
dog over the years are not even related
to it it was just stock photos so but I
think during this time these probably
are not stock photos I'm guessing no no
That'll Walk and that's that's that
looks legit I remember when it came out
thinking yeah okay
yeah
so it looks it sounds like during the
summer of 76 was the big drought like
the first real hit of drought in the
United States and just getting really
crappy weed was coming in
you know it's one thing Matt the people
get confused about this they don't
understand that the the United States
was not just this one monolithic Market
yeah right and so even though High Times
uh writes about it that way often
um because you know it's just a much
better story to just tell tell
intimately what's happening right there
around you you know instead of saying I
think it might be dry in Tucson you know
I mean yeah you know so talk about where
you are as if that's the center of the
world and and everybody else will kind
of Ride Along with you but
um you know the market was divided up
into you know thousands of little micro
markets that yeah you just you know one
place you could get one thing all the
time another place you know they would
kill to have that but they've got
everything else I'm sure um and it's
just um you can't people today they get
really confused when they read this old
stuff they think you know that's that
was America yeah right America's too big
for that for for that to be you know
it's this is just a a tiny little
snapshot of and and it's accurate you
know for for that moment in time in that
place yes but it's America's big place
yeah it was probably accurate for New
York which is where they thought the
center of the world was at High Times
Like notoriously you know right like
like a group of the 20 most famous
potheads in New York exactly right with
everybody bringing them all their best
[ __ ] on a regular basis oh interesting
Ed rosenthal's referenced here according
to the grass growing expert Ed Rosenthal
the longer grass lies around the greater
the disintegration of the high inspiring
cannabinoids into the crater cannabinoid
cannabidiols these latter according to
Roosevelt give us confused sleepy dizzy
fuzzy undertone that undercuts the
clarity of the cannabinole highs so he's
talking about early CBD and stuff I
don't know I know a lot of people say
cbd's sleepy and all this kind of CBN
degrades it turns to CBN
um manazales is straight west of Bogota
it's the Colombians uh coffee growing
region and it's 7 000 feet elevation so
wow Madness black would be
probably pretty potent yeah I would
think so high elevation probably really
dark black weed from the from the
weather yeah that sounds good might have
been yeah yeah
it sounds delicious I mean I always
wanted to go down there and visit my
friend but it was the kidnap capital of
the world at that time and into the 90s
even
um then Mexico took over as the kidnap
come but if you were an American there
was someone who was always willing to
grab you because someone would care
about you enough to pay money and yeah I
guess I just couldn't see doing it so I
never went down
yeah sorry unless they would have gotten
all your stickers too
yeah right
confiscate them right
he says uh
since Amelia is the surfer girl of dope
missing the wild trippy exoticism of the
best imported weed and the soaring
cerebral sensual reaches of Thai in
Hawaii so I I guess what he's referring
to Cincinnati here it's just a general
term for stuff like homegrown without
seeds even local homegrown it looks like
based on what he's writing around here
you know so yeah one thing one thing you
pick up from that you know it's he's
talking about basically it just doesn't
have legs it doesn't have the the depth
of power and complexity and effects but
you know that's honestly those first
couple years when when you know
domestically grown weed was taking over
that market there was a lot of stuff
that didn't that was harvested before it
was mature oh sure yeah and so when you
read what he says you know it's kind of
like this this empty-headed surfer girl
you get high and then you're not high
and it's over you know that's that think
about it for a second this is these are
new Growers their first crop or two you
know harvested early it looks good but
it's not packing the full punch it's not
because of genetics it was because of
you know Growers learning how to deal
with those with you know how to produce
the product that their customers really
wanted so yeah in their area I mean they
were the pioneers of it so it wasn't
like there was tons of books or tons of
resources to go learn how to grow this
properly or when to harvest or any of
that this is also new at that time yeah
yeah I mean it was you know just you
know bring it to maturity is is not easy
especially when you you know this is
before the full indica
um Invasion took place so there was
still a lot of Highly worked hybrids
that were just barely getting it done
before the frost you know
so it mentions even Congolese black here
which I'm kind of surprised there's a
it's something called
Tanganyika green
never even heard of that never heard of
it some kind of African grass
one of the forums that I've been on
there was a fellow from Namibia
and he sent me some seeds from the
country just north of him Angola and
they've been growing weed there for
Angola red as one of them and yeah
um I I've never grown them I still have
them but it's supposed to be pretty
potent was that the LA mono Negra Angola
red
so you got uh no it's it's actually from
a fella who lives in Namibia and got
them himself that's cool Namibia is
famous for the the
no there's like it's sort of like the
Lost Coast it's sand dunes that come
down to the ocean and for the longest
time it was closed to people because
diamonds washed up onto the shores oh
wow that had been released from certain
certain geological structures under
water or something
um yeah he's
he got them himself I I know who La Mano
Negra
um
mustafung talked a bit about him yeah
and
that's another whole show on itself like
yeah yeah it was a very well admired guy
but
um I think uh I think there may it
for people who are really anal about
things being either Pure or not that's
where some of the fuzziness comes in
with LA mono Negra but he did do some
cool stuff at least a lot of cool stuff
yes you know this this the whole thing
about the Tanganyika green there and
Congolese black and all this stuff you
know sometimes you read R and it's like
he it's like he's a travel journalist
you know telling you about these far-off
you know Vistas and and castles and and
you know Raging Rivers of you know
far-flung fantastic places
um you know that's he's he's a
Storyteller he really is and um you know
he he understood the power of evoking
this sort of exotic and you know life of
adventure around all this stuff he was
he was he was creating a a a a legend
you know for that that about all the all
the adventurous stuff people were doing
out there and he was probably taking a
lot of exotic uh license with with the
stories he told but
um man I mean what a what a job he did
you know I mean it's a great word Smith
definitely
yeah well look at the different
Generations he's inspired just sitting
here
you know like I uh many years separate
us you know and if not so was here
that's a whole nother generation you
know in there and and to this day he's
still inspiring people
um I I don't know how easy he will be or
won't be to get a hold of I do hope that
somehow someone shows him this episode
uh whether right I mean his name's out
there
um you could easily find it his name's
Ron Rosenbaum so if anybody does know
him and can get in contact with the
author Ron Rosenbaum I'd love to speak
to him all of us would so yeah maybe
this is our our way to reach out to him
foreign
you know the idea of of getting him on
the show and you know getting us to tell
stories about
what his life was like at the time and
you know what it I mean because he was
so far ahead of his time as far as
lifestyle
uh you know I mean geez man half the
people on Instagram are basically
telling their own stories basically like
he was telling the story of a generation
of Outlaws you know yeah
um
influencer
[Music]
just you know viral marketing absolutely
just like you know skateboarding did in
the 70s for
um you know for that sport this he was
kind of like this did the same thing for
uh of any of anyone like I know Sam
beats his drum and stuff but I think
this dude probably inspired quite a few
more people than Sam did or I mean
honestly yeah with his position in life
I agree with you there yeah definitely
he's a Counter Culture hero and a king
maker and uh you know the the Scribe of
of an era
really was I I I'm trying to hold back
on you know my praise for the guy
um but if we can get him on that would
be the best but it wasn't honor a tree
yeah you know I wanted to ask you
remember I wanted to ask you about what
what your um conversations with Neville
were like yeah factor in those Mr Nice
days I guess we don't have to do it this
time but I'm writing it down for the
next one yeah with devil yeah that would
be cool I mean just from a personal you
know here I am talking with you know the
real king of cannabis no bobble head
yeah and you know just like he's another
guy you know we share this passion and
it's just
I remember I remember the first time he
responded
um it was on the actual forum and it was
just like him chiming in a little bit
and responding to me directly and I
remember that [ __ ] it's it's not so
nerdy to say it now but I got this like
exhilarating feeling in my chest like
yep I just I just spoke to the dude the
dude responded to me you know like it
was that really special feeling where
you know I and for me I had spent a lot
of my my early career as you saw like
rubbing a lot of people the wrong way
with how I approached everything and to
be able to get a response from someone
like that and for him to take me
seriously not only that take the time to
talk to me and then
to to have some sort of form of respect
and admiration for each other and become
peers was probably one of the most
special moments of my life at that time
because I didn't feel like I earned it
but he was still giving me that respect
so it was special
he was very generous that way wasn't he
yeah he was absolutely he never treated
me like oh you're just some dumb kid let
me tell you how it was it was never like
that he was wanted he wanted to know
more about the American scene
um the American clones he was more
specifically interested in so while I
was asking him stuff about the old stuff
that I was interested in and his
experiences he was asking me more about
Bubba Kush OG Kush what was in those
where did they come from he was more
interested in chasing down the lineages
of stuff that he didn't know about and
trying to trace it back to his own work
yeah yeah because he was he was
absolutely positive pretty much
everything that we were coveting over
here by that point had had come come all
go gone through his hands and come back
here here yeah and you know worked and
evolved but uh I'm not sure he's
terribly wrong you know like he might
even be right still that's oh yeah the
most nuts about all of it yeah at the
time I thought he was a little nuts on
on a lot of it but um
time has proven it to be more true than
we would have liked I guess yeah I
thought it was a lot of arrogance to be
honest with you like how how would you
know how would you know you know but
over time as I talked to him I realized
he was able to see and identify traits
long before he could smell the bud just
by sight and that was something I had
never seen before someone who could
identify traits and lines just through
sight that's a special special talent a
lot of people think they can do it but
not a lot of people can do it with many
many strains you'd be lucky if you can
do that with one strain in your life you
know yeah you know for me it kind of
made me a little sad because
um you know the realization that so much
of what's around is directly related to
his work
um it makes me sad for all the thousands
of air wounds that got worked in the
hills and and the seeds never made it
out to Neville
um you know the diversity the I mean
just staggering you know and for the
longest time it I it confused the hell
out of me that people seem so obsessed
with well okay if that's that then it
must be this plus this plus this as if
you know they were in the you know
individual plants like skunk one was was
a cutting yeah and when everybody used
it they all used the same thing you know
yeah and Northern Lights was a cutting
and everybody when they used that it was
always the same thing yeah um you know
but but damn man there's just been so
much so much reuse and and renaming and
um inbreeding on inbreeding on
inbreeding and it just it just seems
like so much of what we have to work
with today came straight through
Neville's hands at one point
um I think I think I think with the
Resurgence of uh legalization
especially in areas like Mendocino and
Humboldt I'm hoping anyways and I've
seen some examples of this brief
examples
um that some of these lines that didn't
necessarily make it to Neville but
stayed in certain areas of Humboldt
Mendocino and were kept worked by these
guys who just wanted nothing to do with
being in public yeah some of those do
still exist and are being passed to
their
Protege you know is there is there uh
going to their next destination in
spiritual journey you know before that
some of them have passed it to the
Protege I know
um I know Tom Hills
um would you would consider probably a
mentor type as as recently um talking
about giving him a bunch of the stuff
you know stuff that was used to make
like ptk you know a lot of those lines
so that's going to be interesting you
know so there are little
um
little sections little treasure chests
out there but I think it's way far fewer
between than we could ever want or
anticipate unfortunately and it seems
like over time Neville really was the
Time Capsule to save a lot of this stuff
because it's the only way we still have
a lot of it yeah and look if it does
become available it's going to be
crossed with cookies and OG and Kim and
instantly you know I mean it's I don't
know I just um
I I sometimes I get depressed when I
think about what's been lost but then I
look around and see what we've got right
now it's it's pretty fantastic and
um you know the idea that there could be
some of those Treasures out there like
what you're talking about uh just just
waiting to pop up again I I hope you're
right I'm just trying to stay optimistic
and
you know maybe maybe it'll happen in my
lifetime I've been waiting very
impossible some of this stuff to happen
so it's very possible I mean we got
Treasures like you and Mad Jack popping
up so anything's possible guy anything's
possible that's the way I look at it
with a with a mustache like mad Jags for
sure exactly
exactly
pretty much go anywhere with a mustache
like that it opens every door yeah
so do you guys want to get anything in
before we uh sign off
um how did not so dog get his handle not
so dog
um so he was going and meeting up with a
friend to buy some chem dogweed and his
friend was showing him some of the bud
and he looked at it and goes this is not
so dog bro because they used to refer to
him dog as dog he's like this is not so
dog and they just kind of stuck with him
after that and it was a Kim dog it was
something else
so that's how he actually got his thing
and oddly enough it was at a uh really
well-known rest stop so yeah that's a
hidden part of the story rest stop the
action if not so
oh my God now I'm pretty sure that's the
joke there
you got anything Rojo
no no I just uh you know always a
pleasure to to be a guest here and you
know thanks for your interest Matt oh
man it's always a pleasure to have you
two with me and um yeah next round we'll
get into it further and hopefully I'll
do a little more
um setup so that I don't leave it all on
you guys to try to figure out and we'll
have some microphones too I think yeah
brand new microphone should be there
yeah that's right that's right we're not
going to be styling with new microphones
no no my pleasure my pleasure thank you
all right all right you guys we're gonna
sign off
thank you from everyone here at breeder
Syndicate thank you magic thank you raho
and we'll see you next week
okay
you want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out
breeders Syndicate update not only is
our merch store up at syndicategear.com
but all episodes will remain free but
what we need from you is interaction if
you're watching the show for your first
time kick back and enjoy it if you like
the show feel free to like it but if
it's your second viewing we ask a gentle
person's agreement that you click the
Subscribe button it costs you nothing
but it helps us tremendously with the
sneaky YouTube algorithm
leaving comments telling not to his
voice lulls you into a trance works as
well we hope you take the time to do
this we try to put out the best possible
shows for you we can and want to build
this community thanks again from all of
us at the Breeders Syndicate family