welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
revolution hey everyone welcome to Breer
Syndicate um today we're going to be
doing review news and today I'm going to
review the hash Kettle now most of the
time when we review Glass on here it's
almost always C2 because well they're my
homies and it's my favorite glass on
Earth however I've been seeing like this
hash Kettle thing online and like I've
always said we don't do sponsored
reviews right we never do sponsored
reviews so out of our own money we went
and bought this beautiful it's actually
stunning as a just a showpiece a
beautiful yellow fumed it's hard to see
uh in this video but it's yellow fumed
glass and it has a pink inside thing
where you put the snake a nice top that
goes on keeps the hash in oops and uh
yeah the that's a little pink
top and I don't know if you can see it
I'll try to put it on
here you can't wait see there's a stamp
it says hash corporation
Canada and um hasco I think it says or
something like that
anyway um yeah so I'll be reviewing this
paid for it not sponsored wholehearted
review now the one thing I learned with
these do not use like sift dry sift that
you've really like really clean dry sift
that you've pressed into hash so first
you have to make a hash snake so we've
done this um I have some really nice
from high and Lonesome of Appalachia
which that's kind of one of the perks of
this [ __ ] right like I get to have
people like high and Lonesome s is own
an Appalachia hat killer to try so but
the the requirement is is that it's
hashish with a lot of a very unclean
hashish it has to be or it won't burn in
the snake properly it'll just melt won't
smoke in the thing it's a mess when it's
too pure and I already tried that once
so this time we are going to try to
attempt it with a little bit less clean
of a sift and see how this thing smokes
and you guys are going to see it for the
first time with you so first test to see
if it's clean enough to smoke is
lighting the snake and this is part of
the process of the hash Kettle so get
the snake and you light
it I think that's what we
do there we go now it's lit hey it's
going put snake in here like
so as you can see the snake is in here
lit put on the lid here we
go yeah it's actually one of the nicest
hash smoking tools I've ever
had um don't have to put it on top of a
b with other weed to enjoy it this is a
straight up hash experience this is so
cool like how it's actually functioning
super Smokey in there see if I clear it
out hold
on there we go so there we go so you see
the hash snake burning on its own it's
got oxygen now you know a little oxygen
coming in here just enough to keep it
burning you put the lid on it it catches
it see how the Smoke's just going
downwards now towards oxygen coming
out I'm going sit here and pop this
whole damn
thing I'll probably have to edit that's
really boring just watching me sit and
smoke this whole [ __ ] thing but it's
pretty good I'm digging
it now let me see what the price on
these is let's see hash Kettle Canada
hash
Kettle can doing this all with one hand
yeah you can get massive hits off this
this is [ __ ]
great so for
140 9.95 which is actually a really
great price you can get the Hash
k yeah this is uh pretty pretty awesome
pretty Faboo I must
say um I think I paid a little more for
this one just because of the yellow
fumed part but like I haven't wanted to
use it too because it's just so
beautiful and I'm going to have to clean
it I don't want to get it
dirty I actually keep it in my display
cabinet because it's so pretty next to
the uh Clockwork Orange um dab rig which
I guess I've got to [ __ ] show off
some point I hate using my pretty glass
it's super expensive every time I mess
with it I'm scared I'm going to break it
but like this is pretty amazing the
snake keeps smoking you know I can sit
here and talk shoot the [ __ ] smoke as I
please doesn't burn up too
fast beautiful appy
has this is this is rather nice this is
great so again hash Kettle Canada hash
Co the hash Kettle and like I said
this's got a pink top pink inner side
yellow fuming so they do make it like
that um not all of them are like that
it's special editions that are released
and yeah they were super nice easy to
deal with game fast and it looks like
the the normal unfed ones are 149 95
Canadian wherever you can get just go
Google hash Kettle I'm sure any of those
places will do and one last hit Cent her
away
now be sure to check out our Discord our
patreon Discord where we all hang out
daily um we provide other reviews there
more maybe more transparent views on
other lines breeders everything um we're
there all day feel free to you know stop
in shoot the [ __ ] ask some questions and
I check out rights .c we just added Miss
Jill seed so go check them out there's
some awesome stuff up there there's some
stuff I'm going to run so yeah anyways
go check it out show your love to miss
Jill rot seeds.com
haskett this is a winner this is if
you're into like smoking hashish and
like you know this is a winner and I
think most of us especially breeders who
are constantly you know picking seeds
out of plants you know all the finger
hash Left Behind winner winner winner
ding ding ding check it
out want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it
out