foreign
[Music]
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
when it started to hit me
and I'm like wow
[Music]
[Applause]
I got high
[Music]
can't get enough of vintage strains go
check out the collab we just did Riot
seeds and suck Lord one of New York's
Premier toy makers uh we have a resin
cast toy one out of 27 only 27 made
exclusive to our uh to our customers for
the first seven days so go check it out
Link's gonna be in the description go
show him some support
so I I'm here with um Johnny uh is that
how you want to be known yep that's fine
okay with Johnny one of uh mad Jag's
Partners from the Mad Jag Canyon and
we're gonna have a little discussion
about
um The Mad Jag era and and his
perspective on everything that went down
and his experiences from his angle so
mad Jack didn't help me lean on this
because he he knows the the important
questions and and Adam I kind of just
want to sit back maybe ask a few things
here and there but let you two have a
conversation about those years because
that's what people really want to hear
so let's take it away Mad Jack
well the other day I was speaking with
Matthew and trying to give him some
history of how I met you
and
and it started pretty far back with my
friendship with
um Doug and then
Hardy because Hardy's wife
was what was her name
Amanda Amanda okay I couldn't remember
Amanda Amanda is the one who invited you
and and uh Wally and Martin right
well
um she I was in uh well to go back to
the source which is the the weed would
you believe
um I was um living in Manchester England
with Martin
and Allison whom both of whom you came
to know later
and Amanda had already moved to Phoenix
I had known her in Birmingham and
through Martin they were an item anyway
we were both studying film at Manchester
University and
um Amanda sent us some of the original
Mad Jag I think 78 and
um we smoked we saw these tiny little
joints you know and back then Matthew
you probably uh you know or maybe you're
too young
we would make spliffs out of um you know
five skin joints it was like a a quite a
operation to add tobacco in and stuff
exactly lots of tobacco you know you had
to be able to smoke you needed some
content in there with uh with the leaf
matter right well hash no no what I was
going to say was it was harsh mostly and
then we had this little present from
Arizona from Amanda in a little vacuum
pack we saw these tiny little little
joints you know so the two of us like
Martin and I and there was another fella
there who was sharing a little house in
um in Manchester and we thought what the
hell is this you know and we proceeded
to smoke the entire thing you know yeah
between two of us
and you know 20 minutes later we're in
the catatonic stage
[Laughter]
we just had never experienced you know
as you know better than I you know is um
much more different hi to the um oh yeah
you know grass and and Jim Matt Jack
there had grown the Mad Jack you know um
I think that was your year before
you did it with Doug Jimbo or no it was
with Doug right okay so it must have
been that yeah yeah
um so one year was that was that 78 yep
yep you know Jim I think it was sooner I
I think it came sooner my recollection
is that because
oh maybe not but anyway
um no I think it was sooner anyway it
was grass as opposed to Hash that's the
point and it was and we were completely
ripped you know for four or five hours
barely able to function because we
completely overdone it you know and yeah
and um anyway
um so I I have some questions for you
since you were in Manchester
um what year what era was this
roughly 70s oh yeah yeah yeah 76 77 you
know we went there in the Autumn of 76
it was a one-year film course I was
already working at the BBC and it
stopped me when you've had enough of all
this but no no working in the BBC and
then I went to uh study film it's to
advance my career afterwards and um
anyway yeah and and I spent a year up
there so we were there from 76 to June
77 Autumn 76 so that's the year where
were you raised in England I was I was
brought up on a farm in Devonshire in
Devonshire okay yeah if you know England
at all that's the southwest corner my
dad was a farmer and and we had a lovely
um childhood on a farm in Devon yeah and
then I went to Birmingham University the
teacher training part of uh after a year
I wanted to be a teacher which never
really
yeah yeah
so Birmingham great cities these if I
may Birmingham and Manchester great
music scenes I collect music from the
punk rock and Northern Soul specifically
Northern Seoul like 70 60 North Seoul
and um the reggae stuff that was coming
in during the late 70s and late 60s
early 70s to to Manchester I collected
all that stuff all of it and Birmingham
don't forget oh yeah very good yeah
sorry I've just um it's close to my
heart uh you know I had six or seven
Great years there
um and Birmingham we used to go to the
um to the scar and reggae really yeah
yep the the we got to know through my
work at the BBC we got all these
characters come in and um and um big out
there that the BBC Don let's the DJ
have you heard of him no I don't
remember say it again the name Don lets
he was an old reggae DJ yeah yeah yeah I
remember that name yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah and and of course one of the
reasons um uh Jim invited me and um
I've written a book about this about
that about you know this yeah so a lot
of that that reference to my to my time
in Birmingham was in this novel that's
actually I'm working on the last uh um
anyway it's on my bed here but I'm
working on the last uh read through it's
going to come out and um I'll be glad to
send you a copy here oh I love it yeah
anyway long story but that's um yeah
yeah Birmingham was wonderful back then
and uh great clubs too and tremendous
bands ELO and Spencer Davis that became
Transit Davis oh yeah yeah Led Zeppelin
just Round the Corner in Wolverhampton
and um yep lots of lots of stunning
bands but yeah the scar and the reggae
scene was tremendous and some of the the
Jamaican guys would take over these um
whole streets of you know row houses
yeah that you guys call them Terrace we
call them in England and uh one house
would be dedicated for the shabeens they
called them which is the bodies you know
oh wow yeah and I remember going there
the first time with three or four mates
we were the only white guys there you
know and we were tolerated I don't know
how welcome we were but when you went
when you went in you know the guy would
um hand you a a cone of um of ganja you
know as they call it you know that that
the way they grew the grass and Jamaica
yeah and you'd puffle you'd have one
each you know that's awesome you know
and and and they'd be playing that
really cool laid-back Scar and reggae
and um what a scene you know
and everybody ripped of course yeah I
would have I would have that's that's
what I would dream to have been around
for it like if I could go back in a time
machine would be to see that era of uh
England because the music the ska the
reggae scene and how many people
influenced later on yeah yeah that's
amazing yeah it was fun it was it was
great times man we were wild together or
in fact you know when I came to Arizona
Jim probably saved my life you know
because
that we would have been finished at 50
you know but yeah yeah
so
let's go ahead culture in England like
was that is it yeah
we seldom Saw Grass at least in the
scenes I was in as I say the ganja that
the Jamaicans brought in of course from
the Caribbean was the closest we saw to
any Leaf you know okay we got the
Lebanese the blonde Lebanese
sometimes and then the also the um
Afghani sometimes The Afghani was
streaked with white and I I don't know
we we used to maybe we were dreaming but
we think it was opium in it you know oh
maybe yeah I've heard about that um so I
was watching a video the other day and
there was they were showing the process
of how the hash is mixed and made in
Afghanistan and what they were doing was
bringing in they had the nice hash the
creamy beautiful stuff and they had it
all melted down you know really worked
real heavy and they were throwing in the
garbage on top of it garbage it's a
little bit of opium
oh a little bit of a little bit of uh
like the crappy hash from the air and
they're mixing it all in so that they
could sell at the higher price yeah yeah
they were mixing in all kinds of crap
just uh just to sell it for a higher
price and apparently they do this each
year and it's an old practice of mixing
the bad hash with the good hash
but yeah they also mix in supposedly
opium uh from what that said yeah yeah
yeah the streaks you know we remember
the white streaks and The Afghani was
the sought after Lebanese was okay
Moroccan was okay uh you know well fine
you know but um but the Afghani
everybody wanted that and it was it was
quite a bit more um powerful you know
and I we always thought because it was
you know really you know you didn't feel
much pain for foreign
but we always you know and it was an
education to if I may go on to Arizona
you know to to to meet the Jimbo and um
and and and yeah smoke the uh this that
would have been
um Gemini who worked for two years in
the canyon my book only Chronicles one
but
um
I remember the first meeting uh gym at
David Hardy's this guy that was married
to the English girl that's the
connection you know and smoking grass in
the morning you know I was thinking wow
you know because we only in England it
was you know you went out and had bad
pints of strong yeah yeah back and and
you were you were you know you couldn't
move hardly laugh or
Mischief with her but mostly it was you
know you just laid out right yeah but
but that was the introduction to grass
and um and how much more invigorating it
was as opposed to innovating you know um
yes the the the oxidization you guys
know better than iPhone sure you know
you know when that was the trouble with
um all sticks and seeds that came in
from Mexico right and Colombia which was
it it zonked you out you got high but it
wasn't invigorating and that's what
turned me on to
the Mad jagweed was this you know you
have a puff in the morning we used to go
and throw the football around and yeah
David Hardy had a little Park what was
it there you may I'm sure remember that
Jim but you know yeah buddy the reason
why I said 78 is that's when Doug and I
grew and yeah I only grew once with
Robert and I I didn't have I I didn't
know David Hardy yet or Amanda
so it was Doug and I our first year in
78.
well maybe I'm I'm inventing this story
to make it because that's what I wrote
about in the book but anyway
um
but I
am
I get point was that it was grass you
know in in those little New York needles
as opposed to the to the LA champagne
she used to get and we'd break off a bit
of hash and we'd heed it you guys know
all that right and then you crumble it
into the tobacco where this but the
grass that we smoked in Manchester that
year was the first real you know neat
Strong Grass it was it didn't have seeds
the ones no it did not exactly it was
sensimere yeah so that makes sense
though because the the even the Jamaican
Colombian well I don't know about
Jamaican probably uh Colombian Mexican a
lot of that stuff was you know uh dried
in the Sun so it was all just oxidized
to [ __ ] and and can be heavy CBN you're
gonna be tired it's gonna wear you out
so that's what most people were used to
when you got like that fresh grown not
oxidized not sun-dried not gold weed I'm
sure that was just so energizing yeah
yeah for sure and uh and and I think
that Jim was probably in at the very
early stages I mean I think it was um
Humboldt County of course is famous for
starting it probably in the mid 70s
right and yeah the guy the guy's
learning how to pull the males and um
and how to how to and under through the
the vital three four days after you cut
it you know how you took care of it and
um and uh that was um an idea again that
I developed which didn't actually happen
you know it's a novel what I wrote and
um and the second part is about uh going
down to Mexico in in to Oaxaca which is
the origin of the seeds you know yeah
and Jim if I don't throw him under the
bus here I think the statute of
limitations has run out but you know his
connections down there with uh with some
characters anyway that's that's later in
the story and and uh yeah it was uh
grass was was was you know opened our
minds in a way in every sense you know
the the Cincinnati green the green I
think we used to call it I'm not an
expert on these strains or anything I'm
seldom had very much after that my years
with the gym at my early years in
America I have occasional puppies but
you you were there at the at the
beginning and that's just you know what
I mean like that's what that's what
fascinates people it's not necessarily
like does this guy know everything about
strains does he know everything about
breeding it's it's the guys who were
there the the the guys who took the
risks that put their lives on the line
to to get us from point A to point B and
those are the guys that we all like
people of my generation really look up
to because like I'm I'm from a
generation where like when I started
growing real heavily it was during
California's prop 215. so it was already
semi-legal right but I was dealing with
other stuff that wasn't quite so legal
and trying to walk that fine line you
know and and I I spent countless nights
up wondering if my door is going to get
hit because you know the the plants were
too smelly you know during Harvest time
that the Harvest Time sweats you know
like so I can only imagine during an era
where it's just Draconian laws I mean
you were coming from England risking it
all over here and not knowing what your
future would hold if you got caught it's
just it's pretty pretty inspiring pretty
inspiring well you thank you I mean yeah
I mean the motive for me was of course
was was the adventure I loved the the
Southwest the dry climate compared to
you know obviously a damp wet colder
climate in England and uh yeah being out
in the I was already a bit of a rock
climber and um and um Back Country kind
of guy and um I just loved it and um and
um
I uh you know fell in love with this man
here now Kitty we spent a lot of time in
the tent together
I bet I'm sorry I'm the feeble English
jokes no no
he you know what impressed me was how
organized Jimbo was you know I thought I
was coming into these kind of uh I would
no you know before I committed obviously
we and before he committed to me we
didn't know one another in um you know
the the winter of 79 we met I think down
in Phoenix wasn't it Jim
uh at David's house I think so at
David's or or
was Doug living down there then no no I
don't think so
it must have been that David right but
but but I started to talk to Jim and um
and and and Doug for reasons that uh who
were left alone he wasn't able to work
that year yeah and and so Jim started to
talk to me about it and I thought well
what am I getting into you know just
uh that's kind of you know a bunch of
spaced out hippies and it's going to be
dangerous but Jim was so organized he's
he's kind of a neat freak yeah yeah he's
very organized much neater than me and
uh I know that I uh you know we um we
were like the these two
Paul's apart you know here's me coming
from London from working in um the BBC
and uh drinking kind of layabout you
know yeah yeah and there's this um guy
that was into Carlos Castaneda and um
much more spiritual and much more
healthy as I say he probably saved me
from an early death you know I've gone
back to London I would have carried on
that you know very unhealthy life but
but Jim was so organized and um and once
I saw all that and how together he was
you know
that that's what that's what persuaded
me you know if I'd run into this guy who
was utterly stoned all the while not to
say that we're here
taking all sorts of things and I don't
know how much he wants me to tell you
about that he had this wonderful little
house in Cottonwood Arizona cat claw on
the street was called cat claw and it
was like this little Haven of um of
safety you know because obviously our
crop was um in the mountains you know in
the canyon and um and and as soon as I
went into his house and saw how neat and
tidy he kept everything and everything
stashed away he's he's Infamous in our
circles for his little bottles in fact
here I got one right here
well this this may not be typical but
this is something he gave me but he's
he's Infamous at having all these little
tiny bottles with the various uh you
know uh rugs mostly there you go yeah
yeah yeah he's he's always leaving these
little things out
when you read the book and um when
Netflix makes the film out of it I'm I'm
Dreaming one hitter oh nice brand new
recently and saw this and you open it up
and put your buds inside and then you
hold a match and
didn't you have a a pipe that we could
toke in bars I remember we went to
Prescott that evening for the um that
day for the rodeo uh Fourth of July
Rodeo yeah Fourth of July Road Matt we
never saw a cowboy a cow a bull or
anything we were just in the bars and
um I and Jim I remember we went into
that we we drove his car across I think
there were five or six of us we drove
across from Jerome Arizona it's called
great place it was back then and um and
and we went over the mountains to
Prescott it's a big windy you know
through there
yeah and then we went into um a country
in western bar to start the afternoon
you know to get a drink yeah Jim Jim had
these m80s you know what those are the
the viral explosives yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah and he said Johnny go around the
back and uh we'll come in the two doors
you know so I thought what the hell is
this you know and I lit the uh but I let
it you know um and and I threw it down
by the door and opened the door
[Laughter]
that was your entrance yeah and then
just as they came in one side and all
the Cowboys you know with their hats and
the girl you know it was a real country
in western bar yeah and then on the
other side uh Jim dropped his and uh so
so all the heads turned to us you know
because the place was pretty packed I
mean Rodeo July 4th and then boom the
crackers off the other side and then
come the other two or three guys with
with Jimbo and um I wouldn't say we took
over the bar but you know that's a way
to make it later entrance yeah I can
appreciate that we were walking down the
street on the way there and we passed it
you know people have to park their
vehicles for 10 15 blocks in all
directions and they'll come in two days
early and park them and sleep in the
back of them because you can't there's
no place to park 10 20 000 people show
up so we're walking down the street from
where we park and there was a pickup
truck with cases of beer just piled
on each other in the back and we looked
around and we grabbed we each I don't
know I think we grabbed like two cases
and we just took off down the street and
when we got to Main Street back there um
on Whiskey Row which it was legal then
to walk with alcohol in the open outside
on Whiskey Road on this two block
section we just started handing beers to
people and Six Packs to people and we
had so much it was just funny I I hope
whoever saw that who whoever's truck
that is it would be really cool if they
were watching this
yeah sent me a bill
right no it was the wildest couple of
years of my life and that's the I'm not
saying something you know and these two
years I spent with my partner here you
know but yeah but uh that's what
persuaded me you know the grass and the
adventure of it for sure obviously the
hope to make some money you know which
we certainly did
you know we had two years the first year
we um we found a wonderful little garden
not so little maybe and we worked like
hell to prepare that just the two of us
that year and we dug a lot of holes
remember those holes Jim that we dug and
um and then this
um and then we pulled it off and it was
it was great you know I mean it was yeah
the risk was huge it was a Mormon County
Christ it was uh yeah yeah we would have
been in serious trouble if we'd been
napped you know yeah I always felt in
the canyon that you know I didn't say
that we were safe because you know there
was methods you know they had the
infrared cameras I believe in those days
you know and um and also of course even
though we wound the the you know the
garden through the we had manzania
Manzanita right Jim on one side
in in pine trees and pine trees and it
was up from the creek you know you could
walk by uh one of the things I always
remember of course in the autumn in the
in the fall when it was due was the
smell
you could absolutely smell the weed from
the creek you know so yeah so a guy
walking through here if anybody did I
mean and Jim says that in four years I
don't think we saw more than one one or
two one footstep and that was um some
hippie hiker went through there but very
it wasn't that it was so you know 30
miles from a road or anything but to get
into it you had to descend via an
enormously exhausting
um rock for
basalt it is
and and if you we tried we looked for
many other ways but they were all not
only
um virtually impossible and exhausting
but dangerous too because there'll be
Cliffs and then there'd be a scree slope
right and then another cliff and um it
had to wind your way through and the and
the the soil was loose you know there
were times I remember when we explored I
don't know if you remember Jim but you
know there was a chance you could have
slipped and gone over the edge you know
not to mention I I got spared by
um you know one of those Dreadful
agave's that have like a needle on the
end yeah my leg was swollen for uh
because they're slightly poisonous right
yeah
Agave Paras pares I remember was one the
Paris Paris anyway there were anyway
that was the only way we got we dropped
in was um through you know there was no
path it was just working your way down
these Bowlers and and when the people
came in to help us
you know with the Harvest at the end of
the year you know they were exhausted
okay utterly unused to it we were in
good shape and even so there wasn't a
trail going down you actually had to
descend Boulders and [ __ ] exactly that's
wild that is
lots of branches and bushes right
crashing through them and we very
carefully clipped just a few that were
in critical spots where you might have
to jump from one Boulder down three feet
to a big boulder and you know you
couldn't be jumping into Oblivion
without seeing it so we cut a branch so
you could at least see where you're
gonna land
right once I was stepping down with a 30
40 pound pack and I already took the
motion to move and there was a
rattlesnake coiled up right where I was
going to step and I had to throw myself
sideways into the bushes and my pack
just pulled me down and protected me it
banged against the next Boulder and
um you know we had some interesting
little experiences none of us ever got
got bit or anything those scorpion bites
we did have a friend who came down who
sprained his ankle really bad Mike if
you remember that I sure do and we uh
I know you do because you were tuning a
motorcycle with him and you had him get
on the motorcycle your motorcycle in
Phoenix and he was on it holding the
throttle and revving it and you were
doing something and he said okay now do
this and he popped the clutch and I told
him not to yeah yeah he said the
motorcycle shot up into the air and he
was flying behind it with his body
horizontal to the ground and then he let
go of the bike and it just kept going
and then he he did a full body slam boom
down onto the ground on the road he was
accident prone that guy yeah
oh well yeah Mike's a good guy he's
still alive he lives in North Phoenix
um last year
he doesn't remember things well so he
can't drive anymore
I'll be going to see him in the next few
weeks along with Robert
yep
we never got bitten no the even the
Scorpions I was convinced there was a
snake in my sleeping bag I was probably
had too much smoke that night
yeah no and um Rattlers yeah a lot of
rattlesnakes a lot of rattlesnakes I
remember climbing up um the what that
wash one you know that steep path and
and putting my hand up on something and
hearing the rattle you know and just
jumping back like Jim did throw himself
into yeah
it's such a a shock you know yeah you
don't mess around with those things and
you hear that rattle you jump right we
have them out here
area you know I think you survived you
know I've heard that you can survive a
rattlesnake yeah but of course you do
mostly you know but they do say that you
know it's it's pretty pretty yeah
36 48 hours which would have meant if we
were out there on our own which we often
were yeah
lie in the shade and hope you had enough
water because if you start to try to get
out you send it through your system and
yeah I remember Jim gave us the um Jimbo
you had those little rattlesnake kits
right
that they make you feel safe
had her in them that you're supposed to
slash at the uh oh my God
and then there was something that like a
suction thing I wasn't there that you're
supposed to pull the venom out oh yeah
yeah yeah well those came later and they
were more accurate because they were a
empty big hypodermic and when you press
down they would suck in oh yeah if you
applied them within one minute
being bitten
um it would get some venom out of the
bite site before distributed to your
Bloods unless you got struck on the neck
then you're [ __ ] crazy then you're a
goner yeah probably
we nicknamed it the salt mine yeah
because it would make you sweat so much
it was about four that was only about 12
or 1300 feet vertical only but at the
bottom end where Doug and I first worked
it was 1600 feet and all right we
that's where you and I actually went in
originally to the old garden and then we
started hiking Upstream to look for a
new garden and we were we couldn't find
anything that met our standards for four
hours or something like that and then we
sat down you take a break and we looked
up above and we said wow that looks like
a little alluvial Plateau maybe up there
there it was The Double E I think I have
already told map we called it the double
e because if you get the actual topo map
of that area which I won't disclosed you
it fell right under the word something
Creek and where the two e's were in
Creek was exactly where the garden was
so funny that's how we named it the
double e that makes sense it was a
beautiful you know that's the other
thing that uh I sort of inspired me as
well or at least the right was it was a
beautiful
you know setting you know this oh yeah
you know I was crazy action those desert
Canyons where they've got live water
whether you have the sycamores and not
too sure if there's many cottonwoods but
Alders uh you know anyway a a riparian
growth they call it you know that grows
alongside the streams of course it's
just gorgeous down there and we had a
swimming hole too not exactly you know
almost like a swimming pool that opened
up Jim didn't it after the flood I think
anyway there was a place where you we
could plunge you know and swim four or
five Strokes
um so you know In the Heat of the summer
oh yeah right down there and of course
we drank straight from the creek all the
time because Upstream you know we're up
towards the little town that we won't
mention but Upstream of us it was dry so
you knew the water was fresh and you
know we just drank straight from the and
it was safe
show you yeah it came out below the town
it didn't flow through the town right
otherwise it could be polluted when it
rained of course and it was a big summer
Sunder thunderstorm it could wash
through it if someone had driven across
it and there might be oil in it but for
it to go miles uh yeah it and us
actually drink at that moment yeah it
would be so dilute yeah
but through the summer it was pretty dry
for several miles above us and but it
somehow the the water came above surface
in our section and that's why it was
also safe because if you stood on the
rim of the canyon in the summer with all
the trees you couldn't see water yeah
there was only one or two spots that
we'd see a glint of water if you walked
along the canyon Edge which takes hours
anyway yeah yeah it was it was quite
nice and we also realized that fishermen
aren't going to go down in 100 degree
heat
1600 feet or whatever yeah to go fishing
and then have to hike out in the heat in
the afternoon no no
no so Johnny was there during skunk one
right the skunk one girl yep yep do you
remember any of the scents as you could
describe them of this skunk one crop as
it was going through flour
um close-up close-up smells if you can
remember
yeah it was obviously completely
different from the sativa which was in
my opinion a lovely scent you know in
fact Jimbo had a good idea of um of
course we were up against the legality
and or illegality of it then but to make
the the sativa into um
Ascent what do you call a perfume for oh
yeah yeah yeah I don't know what
happened with that but but the skunk was
completely different you know I mean
obviously it was just like somebody just
wasn't as bad as as you know a roadkill
skunk but it was very very very powerful
and much more
um sort of um what's the word um
accurate almost you know much more well
potent true but a more sort of uh
pungent there you go yeah yeah it was it
was not as pleasant by any means the
sativa was beautiful I can still
remember there was scoldiness to it a
second so there was a skunkiness to it
and the skunk one with some sweet
absolutely absolutely right Jimbo yeah
well greater after harvest and they were
dry because when you crush the bud to
roll it it filled a room yeah
that's wild I didn't remember much about
how it smelled while it was growing I
loved the scent of all those flowers but
it was particularly skunk once it was
dry once it's manicured and then you're
gonna break a bud but you didn't even
have to break it but if you open a jar
of that even in the house the whole
house would be oh yeah
was the sativa strain and um
um you know those blooms you could pull
them down you know obviously in the
Autumn you know and just brush it brush
them a little bit God it was delightful
it's just great
um and and you really didn't need to
brush him that much as I say I mean you
could if the wind was right when you was
crossing the creek or just walking
around a camp you know I was heading on
the far side of the um from the garden
from the blue we were plane and um you
could absolutely smell it and it's a big
thing I won't go on too much about my
book but it was a big thing in
um the close scrapes that I wrote about
in the novel uh with the with the uh you
know the have the we nearly got caught
because of the um the smell and I
remember with when we came out when the
year that uh Sammy helped us Jim yeah
this was this wonderful crazy guy that
helped us with the work um the Swiss guy
um we we we we we had that camper that I
got remember and um we put all the boxes
on the bunk on on over the cab you
remember that that setup and Sammy and I
drove it out and um we went to we came
around the anyway long story but we
wanted to have breakfast or lunch or
whatever it was we were driving out you
know and um we we of course you want it
inside the camper the smell was
overpowering but even outside you could
smell it and um and there was a scene we
we went into the cafe to get some you
know to have a meal
in this little town and the sheriff the
deputy sheriff's truck kept pulled
alongside the the camper it was like a
four-wheel drive you know with a camper
rig on top yeah and I'm looking through
the window and I go I don't know if I'm
allowed to use foul language yeah yeah
yeah you're okay yeah you know this is
dodgy to put it mildly you know yeah
half the I don't know about half the
crop but boxes and boxes of wheat enough
to put you in alone yeah yeah it gets
you put away and um I was terrified that
the sheriff would you know probably some
tea totaling Mormon oh for sure some
backwards
what the hell is that smell you know
anyway yeah suffice to say that but I I
think I've got a fairly good scene in
the book that sort of mirrors that you
know well let's let's talk about your
book real quick what's it called it's
called the year of the Mad Jag all right
you're the Mad Jack and do you have a
website or a place
I do do you like shall I send you the
link at the end I just you can say it
right here and then I'll add it in at
the end too well it's Jonathan
slater.com my full name Jonathan Slater
s-l-a-t-o-r and um maybe I can send you
the link directly to absolutely at the
end and you can Chuck it on the screen
when you edit yeah absolutely yeah yep
it's um it's won two little Awards
um it's the best one being the William
Faulkner creative writing competition
that's crazy yeah New Orleans yeah I
went to New Orleans and uh it's taken a
time of course here we are Jesus 40
years later but I I wrote it um uh uh in
the in the 2000s it took me that I I was
actually living in New Zealand and wrote
a version that was worthless so I wrote
it again when I had some time when my
children were taking care of themselves
a bit more anyway when I was I live up
here in Taos New Mexico yeah and um
anyway
um so I and I tried to get a um a
traditional publisher you know um an
agent and the whole deal but this is so
so very few of those now you know
especially for new unknown Riders you
know yeah
um you know everything's it's the whole
publishing thing is just like a film
business I've worked in the film
business it's all marketing how you
Market yourself how much money you have
to Market yourself everything yeah it's
all that well I guess my point was that
it's all in turmoil it changes every
week you know almost you know every year
you know nobody really
um knows what's gonna happen next you
know the whole shift to
um Kindles and um yeah you know the
digital and audio books so anyway the
point of all that being that as I sort
of tried to get uh many times I send it
to to 60 70 agents and Publishers and
you know got sick and tired of the
rejection so I almost gave up on it yeah
but but I decided recently I actually a
production designer on a film I was
working on Reddit and a couple years ago
and he said this is great you've got to
get it out I'm trying not to slap my arm
back too much but um it's a good story
yeah I'm obviously biased but thanks to
that man sitting on the top of the
screen there you know and uh yeah I mean
it was uh you know somebody once told me
I should write a memoir and I said no
it's that wouldn't be interesting you
know because for all the risk that we
took
um there was nothing that thrilling
happened you know we weren't chased by
the law or um yeah yeah there was you
know we were pretty organized and um we
kept no gun fights no nothing out yeah
right and and and Jim he's very thorough
bloke and uh you know I remember I've
watched a little bit of your previous
one and you know talking about
scattering the the leaves in the morning
you know we would we would always we
call it a watering Moon you know the
early phase of the moon was always the
one you wanted to be watering in because
we in the summer we would take turns we
didn't both need to go in you know
especially especially the first year
when we only had the one Garden second
year it was more work but one guy could
do it you know it's hard work sure you
get that pump going and um the Briggs
and Stratton and it was roaring you know
and you spent the next four hours
blundering around trying to keep the
hoses from you know
um
spilling over we had a like a little uh
Terrace system you know with little
walls like um like a race Patty in um in
Southeast Asia you know and uh and um
anyway the point of all that was the
that yeah we would um it was great to
have the the moon Waxing come over the
Canyon Rim we were in a nice East-West
part that we chose it
um so that we'd have maximum sun right
but of course it helped also for maximum
Moonlight and um and so
um the um the um you know the watering
was was one guy and
um that was always of course a risk as
well you know you're on your own down
there yeah Anything Could Happen you get
stuck there scorpion you just twist your
ankle and you probably couldn't get out
for two or three days you know I mean
you wouldn't have died hopefully from a
twisted ankle but you would have been I
remember you did a terrible
um twist yourself once Jimbo too I
remember you were struggling to get out
because of that and um
anyway it was it was a great adventure
that's for sure you know and again I am
it was so beautiful and and one of the
things I always I remember later on as
well was um having the um that the water
because of the um continued growth and
the drought in the southwest Jim you'll
maybe know more about this than I
because I went to New Mexico and you of
course today but the um
the creek was so depleted that guys who
went in and used our setup the next
couple of years could barely oh there we
are
that's funny yes in 1980 roughly and my
daughter who's 48 years old right now
that's amazing you guys are good shape
look at that we were in super shape look
at Jim hey you didn't go you go in and
out of that Canyon man every week you
were hard as they say yeah you could do
some you guys could have been doing some
MMA or ultimate fighting back then with
that that kind of shape and climbing
rocks and [ __ ] yeah
yeah
so so a question I I do have for you
it you know Jim even just since I've
I've met him and slowly become friends
and and learned from him I've I've had a
lot of synchronicities in my life just
weird little occurrences like weird
um things just keep falling in place
with different people just that never
really happened would never really fall
together did you did he influence your
life spiritually or anything at all
you know absolutely uh I I I'm not a
particularly I'm I was coming from the
cynical skeptical world of of uh of an
urban environment London UK is very very
atheist like I've noticed that like
watching the TV program it's common to
be atheists there whereas in the U.S
it's not you know yeah no I I am still a
very much an atheist oh my yeah
I don't think that the frankly religion
has done more good than harm in the
world I'd argue we could debate that for
a long while
um but absolutely I think what Jim
reminded and the experience reminded me
I was was uh I'd left home at 18 to go
to the cities you know I was a farm boy
and it brought back to me and again this
is in the book
um the value if you will of wilderness
and um and I've become more of an
animist because of that you know I I
don't follow the uh I I don't even
frankly have a lot of time for the um
the Eastern religions that have come
into and and Jim gave me some of that I
would say but not in any kind of a
conventional way do I think I I think a
lot of the a lot of the popularity of
the Western religions Buddhism and
Hinduism and everything
um and Jim and I may disagree on this
but you know I think it's it's very
superficial in so many ways well you
know especially in your state I would
argue you know California you know
there's a lot yeah that's a bollocks
pardon me you know that I mean Beverly
Hills Buddhists are kind of yeah
you know it's just they just grab the
the the the the cool side of it oh it's
peaceful or I mean there's nothing wrong
with meditating that's a great thing to
do but you know you don't study also the
the four noble truths and samsara and
and you know I tried it I I I I I I I
meditated up here and did the slow
walking and everything and tried to get
into it as I got older looking for some
answers but in answer your question I
think that my spirituality lies in the
natural world this is perhaps isn't very
original but you know that's my and and
those two years in that Canyon
um absolutely you know built that into
me much more took me back to my years
growing up on a farm but also the the
feeling that there's if there is any
power out there it comes in the natural
world trees the the creek the stones
even you know that that's what I believe
it's maybe a little fascinating because
like you know um through my own journey
in life
um I I've gone from so much as like
someone who's really into Satanism
because I started off Catholic so of
course as a young punk rock kid that's
like 12 13. I immediately get into
Satanism because it's like the complete
opposite right like just what is the
opposite of what I my parents like is
that what can make my parents mad right
right but after a while I got you know
of course Very as I got older and into
into science and botany I got more into
atheism and logic and reasoning and
over time I've just kind of especially
with plants learning from Plants being
around plants so long I've I've come to
realize and I don't know how much it
makes sense because I've never really
got I've never really vibed with like
the whole hippie like mother earth type
thing but I think that's probably
closest to what I believe now as an
adult that that there's a lot more
conscious on this Earth than we have any
clue just because it doesn't have a
brain doesn't necessarily mean it can't
communicate and communication is key
like to all living beings and life and
I've just kind of come to a similar
conclusion in that if there is something
existing it's probably very natural and
been here among us as in the plants the
the actual Earth and that's where a lot
of this energy is probably coming from
as best I can tell you know as a human
who can't have any answers it seems to
make the most sense to me after
interacting with all these plants and
how much they've changed my life for the
better
sure no no I agree more and to me
there's a great deal more logic in the
Life Force if you will coming from this
this natural world that's been going for
what what's the big bang 13 billion
years or something yeah yeah
than than believing that somebody walked
out of off a mountain with some tablets
with some rules on them you know I mean
that's to me that's just nonsense and
yeah very human very human created yeah
it's still missing oh that's right huh
what do they say who is it says if God
if God hadn't existed man would have
invented him right yeah right I mean I
mean it's obviously uh
1981 so at the end of 1981 I'm 41. oh
wow okay yeah yeah we both 70 are you 72
Nigel
two weeks two weeks when's your birthday
June 13th 13th yeah I didn't know that
you got the old man to cough it up
well you know also when you sleep next
to a creek and and hear it in the sound
at night in the wilderness in in the
stars were as bright as you can ever
imagine you have you'd have to go
very few places in America today to be
away from City Lights in the town that
was near us was hundreds of people so it
there was no light for many many many
miles right tens and tens and twenties
of Miles as listening to the sound of a
creek flowing by for a year or two
the time that you go every week it's
just so
healing it's a healing thing
with a poem that was translated by Gary
Schneider you know that name the um the
poet anyway
um it's I'll uh
um I walk for thousands of you anyway
it's a long story but it's uh it ends up
I'll sleep by the creek and purify my
ears that's
um it's it's from the Cold Mountain
poems of the of the I think 8th century
reclusion and Shan yeah that's how I
opened the book so that was what got us
so that you know to get back to your
thoughts about the experience and and
everything it was so lovely being down
there and I never felt like even if they
had discovered us down there the chances
of them you know and Jim and I discussed
it you know that they would probably
wait for us to hike out with something
that they could get you know they
wouldn't stake out the garden because
you don't travel down there just to get
you and they know you're going to come
back out exactly and um you know and
would they and if we were down there and
we had at least you know a chance we we
could get away from those guys probably
you know I mean yeah and they don't know
what you have down there as far as it
could have been uh you know cartel with
weapons not just cartel but you know
what I mean people with weapons anything
so yeah they would definitely wait for
you guys to come out loading pass right
well in the nearby Canyon gym there was
a there was a cartel that went to work
there didn't they and they always were
were packing heat weren't they except
that was much longer after us I mean was
it recent years in in the 2000s or was
it as late
but also we had day packs
that today people call Bug Out bags or
for for me it was like I think my
nickname was a parachute so if we knew
people were coming down into the canyon
we're above us or something crazy
um we could go down our Canyon
which led to another Canyon which led to
another Canyon and we could it could
take a day or two but we could disappear
and never be found because we didn't
park a car ever for those two years out
there
um maybe the first year a little bit but
the second year we had people drop us
off and pick us up every week because it
was too risky because like I mentioned
earlier the guys in the canyon next to
us they parked a truck week after week
there and eventually the Rancher called
the forest service they checked the
place and what do you know they're from
Jerome which was the hippie Capital so
they just waited till they came out and
took everything home to Jerome and
showed up at their house and got them
well I was going to say that was another
thing that um you know we we were
one of a better term we were pretty
rigorous about it we were professional
about it and mostly because Jim insisted
I'd say hey we could drive the hell out
there no not always but you know that we
would have a few back and forth because
who wants to hike another three miles
you know and um so when we did leave
cars we would leave them a long way away
you know and and make that extra effort
to get in there you know right um and
then as Jim says the second year when we
really have we we doubled our yield I
think or double that size because we we
took another we made another Garden the
the second year and um but anyway sorry
you were going to ask something Matt so
one thing that I know people are going
to want me to ask before we finish up
and I it it
someone asked if you guys ever saw UFOs
in the sky out there in those clear
clear nights
um well no I I didn't
Jim's got some other stories that uh he
might tell I do remember the satellites
that were mostly north to south back
then and that's 40 odd years ago and we
were the music we were right mate we
were kind of intrigued by what the hell
they were Until you realize their
patterns yeah yeah and and they also
Wink in and out with this son they only
they're reflecting the sun that's gone
down behind the Horizon yeah right you
know and of course there's some
thousands of them now right I mean Elon
Musk has got a thousand yeah tons so in
those days they were much much less
um
um you know well known and so when we I
can remember first seeing them and
thinking well what the hell is that you
know have you guys seen the darling
train yet the what mate Starling train
Elon musk's I there was one one morning
I I was driving somewhere it was like 5
a.m and it was Pitch Black outside
driving in my car and I look up and
there was a stream of Lights like dots
going across the whole Sky wow and I I
stopped my car got out in the middle of
the street there's other people stopping
their car getting out in the Middle
Street it's the first time that
anybody's seen Starling train yet and
everybody's thinking this is a big huge
massive UFO because it is just going
across the whole Sky yeah it turned out
wow they have not seen that but it's
crazy when you see it it's crazy
geosynchronous and there's over 1500 now
so how far apart would they to go around
the circumference of the earth would
that make them it was it I mean it was
it stretched across at least half the
sky wow that's how and and there were
probably eight or nine dots throughout
that half of the sky we saw great
meteorites
sure and once I was hiking out to the
canyon and I got to the edge of the
canyon near near Sunset you know in the
late afternoon and I heard the sound and
I looked down and coming up the canyon
where was a jet in our an Air Force jet
hundreds of feet below the rim I mean he
was at Treetop but he was flying up the
canyon and I just stood there and the
Sonic room was massive and at the end of
the canyon he just gunned it and shot
straight up and out and I was like wow
so they were that they were doing
training I I believe you know because
the Russians were invading Afghanistan
around that period
perfect place to fly around like
Afghanistan yeah they were doing lots of
desert training yeah
luckily that was practicing parachuting
and stuff yeah I know hey do you know
the definition of using a parachute now
do you know what that definition is so
Jim's parachute to get out might I mean
a little different now
you ever done a parachute jump
no I haven't yeah
in Australia yeah living down there I
did one yeah that's another story how
long did you live in Australia a year in
Australia and a year in New Zealand each
and uh and then another year in South
America and then sometime in Southeast
Asia after BBC
sorry mate was that all for the BBC no
no that was um no I was afterwards I uh
after uh Jim and I had our adventure I
came to live in Taos I built a house up
here I sold it and then I sailed across
the Pacific I went wow what a life oh
yeah kind of like I mean that's my dream
man sailing and just getting out just
doing it you know yeah well there's a
friend of mine just sailed from Cabo San
Lucas to Tahiti and um that's hard work
though you know blue water's failing you
know the islands are the great thing you
know yeah because the sailing's fine but
it's exhausting too you never sleep
probably and you know on a small boat
yeah we were at a 57 foot catch I think
that we were on you know and you're just
crewing all the time working you get a
few hours skip as they say where I come
from and then somebody bashes on the on
the on the hatch for for you to come and
help brief the sales of me anyway so I
said but it was a great adventure
wonderful Adventure all the way down
through Tahiti and Tonga and Rarotonga
all the um Cook Islands they're called
and but yeah I lived down in New Zealand
and Australia and and just wandered
around you know and found work in the
films while I was there were kind of
worked on a film in in Buenos Aires when
I was over that way at the slough
remember the Highlander series with uh
oh yeah yeah yeah that we did the second
one down there and oh that's cool yeah
and Buenos Aires great City lovely
lovely Town people are loyal to the
Highlander series yeah
one of my guys I I'm a location manager
you know and so I have a crew obviously
I work here in New Mexico I'm still
working I'm doing a thing for um uh it's
one of their films yeah anyway yeah why
don't they want to do a Mad Jack film
that's a real ticket
they're getting a book those boys I know
the um the assistants I'm gonna give him
a book I mean that's the story like I I
think of all the all the stories I've
seen on on
um the history of
the the Genesis of this scene of the
Cannabis scene and since I've had magic
on on these these have been the most
popular shows we've ever done like by a
large portion so I know that at least
our and this is a niche type thing to be
this far into genetics and breeding and
strains but we have a pretty good sized
audience for that and
man the amount that they've tuned into
just this story tells me that like
that's something that people at Netflix
should probably take interest in
personally like I know I would be super
into seeing that you know
yeah you know obviously that's my hope
as well you know I just would like to
get the story out there before I'm too
bloody old you know and can't and can't
do much more but um yeah and uh
I think obviously there's a there's a
certain obviously with the way it's
suddenly in a sense could become
illegalized at least since Colorado
Colorado was the first I think right uh
California and then Colorado or was it
no no maybe Colorado went fully legal I
thought it was Colorado yeah I think
you're right I think they went fully
legal first yeah they were 10 years ago
now yeah yeah so so with the with you
know I mean in a sense and this is what
I say you know when when Jim and I were
doing it and um back in those days
obviously you know I I come from a
pretty straight family you know farming
stock and my other brothers and sisters
who uh teachers and business folk you
know
even now they're appalled that I did
something so so so radical and dangerous
isn't that awesome though
what's that isn't that awesome though
like to be the one person in your family
who's like the yeah yeah that's the
awesome [ __ ] yeah I was always the black
sheep you know yeah same here you know
yeah but they even now they would they
would they just a drug dealer you know
yeah yeah yeah you know and yeah that's
what I love about this legalization that
we have in a sense we were Vindicated we
were I call it absolutely we were
modern-day Moonshiners you know we were
doing just what the guys still do in in
Kentucky in places like that absolutely
you know and um and yeah that's uh I
would like to think this story and there
are a few marijuana stories out there or
smuggling stories you know there's the
well blow you know what it is oh yeah he
just recently passed rest in peace
Boston George yeah did he really yeah
yeah unfortunately and that's cocaine
which in my view is a stupid drug he
started on cannabis in Matt Manhattan
Beach as a campus dealer yeah yeah no I
mean cocaine in my view is an absolutely
ridiculous job oh yeah no yeah an ego
drug
or what mate ego drug yeah there you go
you feel like God for 20 minutes and
then you need another no it's stupid
yeah but marijuana is I don't know I
don't go on too much but I think it's um
you know Colorado and all the other
states have proven that the system
didn't collapse not everybody's
scratching into each other on the
freeway Christ I remember driving stoned
you know you doing 25 yeah 25 and a 50.
yeah you drive extra safe
careful you know so you know and how
many people live
how many alcoholic these are all cliches
but you know I've seen so many
alcoholics in my time and and um no it's
it's it's proven that it's it's
essentially harmless but but on that
note I would also say and stop me if I'm
talking too much but um no is that we
should we shouldn't think of it as the
Panacea you know when we do need to be
careful of it because the way you guys
you know the way the modern Growers are
doing it what do we have Jim what
percentage THC did we have in the buds
eight into twelve roughly if you're
lucky right and what's it now
some say up to 35 36 40 somewhere in
there four times is powerful you know
and that's just the weed not even the
extra extracts are at 90 now 99 you know
exactly and and somebody taking that for
the first time and getting behind the
wheel or yeah that would really really
screw someone out that's bloody
dangerous you know we can and and I
think there are certain um also medical
uh mental issues with usually as well
you know oh yeah yeah some people can't
quite handle it you know
um there are there are a lot of years
where I could not smoke without it
triggering anxiety depression anything
like that and and it was just one of
those things I had to get used to
um as far as
like come to the conclusion like my
hormones in my body change as I'm as I
get older I can't smoke like I used to
like least during those years I could
it's changed again for whatever reason I
can smoke Non-Stop and not have that but
during those years it was really really
triggering stuff and it was not a good
time for me to be using it only
triggered and made it worse so yeah it's
definitely not the the cure-all um I see
I see CBD stores everywhere in
California now not just everywhere I
mean in gas stations or selling CBD oil
they're selling Arizona CBD joints you
know CBD everything Delta eight Delta 10
specifically which are extracted from
hemp
um and a lot of people don't know that
the other day I was in a cigarette store
and I about because I get pretty
autistic with this stuff like when I
hear misinformation it makes my face
turn red especially if it's something
I'm very passionate about and this this
lady was I was waiting to get Vape stuff
right at The Vape it was a vape
cigarette store and they sell cigarettes
and and CBD and everything there and I I
was listening to this lady she was
trying to get real advice real medical
advice from a cigarette store guy right
on on what she should be using he's like
well you know Delta eight Delta 9 Delta
10 they're all made from sativa so
you're pretty safe there and I was just
like
why why are you just making it up why
are you telling this lady medical advice
you know like she sativa might mean one
thing to her
and whatever she's taking might
completely trigger the opposite effect
and it could be a really bad bad
situation experience she may never try
cannabis again you know it may be such a
Negative experience and then you and
then and then it's all because someone
gave her bad info you know and and that
that ruins it for her for good so yeah
it's just constant around here and a lot
of it they're selling Chinese sourced um
CBD and a lot of people don't know the
Chinese government was paying their
people to grow hemp
um in Mass to leech toxins from the soil
in China so a lot of these were these
hemp hemp plants were grown to Leach
toxins from the soil and they're using
that sending it over here in Mass to use
our CBD market for extraction now I
don't I don't know that those Metals
make it in I don't know but that's not
what people think they're getting they
don't understand that and it's 99 of the
CBD stuff in gas stations is that
Chinese sourced CBD you know right so
yeah
and again I would say that you know to
get back to this the uh the sort of
increased strength of it now so and uh
you know I don't think that
impressionable teenagers should should
know you know take in too much of this
or uh you know maybe you know I think
they're pretty well proven it affects um
it affects
undeveloped brains right and can cause
uh what is it called emotional arrest
meaning like a lot of people that start
smoking when they're 12 emotionally tend
to stay around that age emotionally you
know that tends to happen and it's not
always it's not everyone so it's not
like a a blanket statement but it can
happen
um and so yeah like that was one of my
things growing up I had a younger I have
two younger brothers and I I was very
cognizant that one of my brothers was
already smoking pot and I didn't want
him to think that I was an advocate
necessarily of it knowing what I did so
I had to hide what I did for a living
for a long time from him and you know as
he got older he thought yeah you're an
idiot like why would you do that like I
was already smoking but at the same time
I didn't want him to think that I was
telling him that this is what he should
be doing that I think this is cool
because I didn't and he's you know I
mean I'm sure he's he's felt effects
from it as he's gotten older
yeah I mean I'm still a 12 year old so
you know same with whether you agree
that boo should be restricted to 21 or
18 or something I mean it's the same in
a sense you should be mature before you
make that decision and um yeah I think
there's a lot of uh uh you know jumping
on the bandwagon now about weed and
CBD and uh and I think we need to be
cautious as well because it is a strong
drug no doubt about it I when I first
tried some of these Edibles you know oh
clearly too much I was sprawled out for
six hours yeah what's that drooling yeah
yeah they've made me drool they've made
me drool before
marijuana in the day you know and um
yeah yeah yeah so we've got to be
careful that's all I think you know and
you know they sell this stuff for dogs
too like the CBD oil and it reminds me
of when the when me and my chick met she
wasn't smoking anymore she smoked a lot
when she was young but she hadn't smoked
for years and I was like you know my
friend sent me some CBD CBD oil she had
some back pain and I was like let's try
this but she hadn't had any THC in yours
and there was a negligible amount of THC
in some of these CBD extracts and people
don't realize that because it's not done
very carefully with some Sellers and she
took it and she went to hell for at
least like you know 12 hours she was in
THC hell you know and and it was a
negligible amount but it's just because
it affected her so much she's not used
to it and all of a sudden bam she's
taking a an extracted amount even though
it was small
it's extracted so you know yeah it's it
that could happen giving this to their
dogs people are giving this to their
kids and they have no clue no clue that
that can happen hey they're mixing LSD
with with weed you know that right how
are they doing that
I was like wait a minute you can't smoke
that I remember your story now well yeah
um in the 1980s I there was a number of
people who still believe that that
wasn't bad when they first smoked weed
that was kind of psychedelic and they I
one of my Mad Jack Chronicles is about a
Rastafarian I know in Brooklyn and he
sent us out of his house after he had
two Puffs of skunk number one and
and the next day told me was very mad
that I had given him some LSD in and he
had never smoked anything that powerful
and he was a super Rastafarian and when
we were gone he told us later that he
jogged in place for 20 minutes he had so
much energy he didn't know what to do so
he just ran in place in his living room
that's great I'll bet there's still some
people out in the farm somewhere that
believe there's LSD could be pushed oh
yeah I mean look at the the fentanyl
craze lately I mean you see this with
the the police officer saying that
they're absorbing fentanyl through their
fingers from powder and like passing out
everywhere like people that know like
you can't absorb fentanyl through your
fingers unless it's got like some kind
of transdermal jail DMSO it doesn't
absorb that way yeah and and even being
a foot away and inhaling a microscopic
amount of powder or fentanyl isn't going
to kill you or nor need Narcan so it's
it's it's we see this today with with
the um and granted fentanyl's dangerous
as hell there's no doubt about it I mean
people shouldn't be taking this stuff
it's it's unregulated it's you know
coming from China don't take it please
people not saying you should take it but
it's also the it's like the satanic
Panic of the 80s to me where there are
so much misinformations coming out with
these drugs that people are experiencing
these psychosomatic effects and it helps
spread more fear now the cops are
passing out they're so terrified to work
with fentanyl and and do these fentanyl
arrests they're passing out in fear and
and blaming it on overdosing and all
this crazy [ __ ] and it's causing more
fear and it's just yeah fear of the
unknown is is something the crack
epidemic exactly it's similar yeah yeah
definitely definitely
well
so did you guys ever think you would be
pioneering an industry that became a
multi-billion dollar industry
that's what I want to know did you ever
once think that you were pioneering
changing anything
we were just filling uh you know filling
a need in a way and there's a guy who
lives in Costa Rica but he lived up here
in Taos for many years and uh he started
to talk to me Jim knows the story and um
he said yeah you know we said we just
sort of got under weed and
he said I lived in um I think it was
Wisconsin and he said I drove down to
Arizona once and fetched this weed that
somebody was selling God it was the best
you'd ever had and uh I said oh yeah
what was it calling he said Oh I thought
it was the Mad Jag these guys yeah with
the labels and um we could we we got it
back to Chicago and it was gone in a few
hours you know anyway so so we were just
you know we would Moonshiners you know
we were providing
um an illicit um product for a market
that demanded it right and and we were
in the early days again we talked about
it earlier so uh you know we it was the
methods that Jim had learned and taught
me you know I mean what did I know and
um you know how to how to pull the males
how to how to get your product
superb we were very careful and
especially obviously those three or four
days you know we and we we had to dry it
down in the canyon you know and um we
didn't have a Cellar or a barn or
something so we use we strung lots of um
lines into the most Shady parts of the
of the um Creek Side trees and
um and maybe you know we took great
pride in our product if you will and um
and Jim sent
um something into
um to the high times he sent some um
buds into High Times
Jim on that other uh site that you
recommended that I put your book up I
see mag you know of that one Matt right
yep
um
um the the there was a little
conversation I'll send you the link if
you're interested the first it's a
chapter of the book up on that one on I
see mag and um I don't know is that your
competition anyway oh no no no no no no
no no yeah definitely check it out
anyway
um you know we got a great write-up
somebody dug up the guy was saying skunk
uh that wasn't you know nobody heard a
skunk until the 90s or something he was
trying and I said well no
we had it back in 1980 anyway you know
we were yeah no did we think of course
it wasn't gonna grow into this industry
that it is now you know obviously we
didn't know it was going to be legal
ever right yeah sure but um I mean it's
just to maybe close it up I don't know
Jim what Jim's would say but it was
there were a couple things it was the
adventure yeah it was the the the the
the the the the there's not what's the
word tipping your nose at Authority and
yeah yeah that that was it part of it
you know and uh and the excellent seed
that we had that grew this marvelous the
skunk was one thing I've never been that
fond of that you know I like this that's
TiVo was a show yeah so energizing you
know and and as I say we'd smoke it in
the morning what you know we'll just be
lying around or wasting a day but no you
you could get out I mean I don't know if
you could um fully operate in a job I
said
smoke marijuana and be any good on a
film set but yeah I I could certainly um
you know run around and chasing football
and um or played tennis I remember when
I lived in L.A we would go playing
paddle tennis anyway whatever you know I
I do all these sober myself I can't I
can never do an interview Stone not even
a little bit no my memory call sucks
during any time when I'm even a little
bit stoned so I've done every single one
of these completely sober it's weird me
too
oh yeah
yeah no it has that dissociative quality
to it that uh that's the word I always
you know you you it's perfect for for
yeah hiking or making love yeah right
yeah you know there are things that it's
good for and there are things that it's
lousy for you know and um outside in the
garden working outside in the garden
yeah you know doing sort of physical
things but but holding a conversation
about proust or you know or yeah you
know you're not gonna hold it up and
let's you know in fact I remember the
recording in you know in in my mind
conversations that I have when I was in
Jerome with people and you know a lot of
them were just very digressive very you
know nobody you don't stay on track so
well it yeah it's it's the same as a lot
of drugs you know you should take them
recreationally and enjoy it for that you
know just like being in the pub and
drinking three or four pints by the end
you're full of life and joking and yeah
next morning you feel like [ __ ] yeah
exactly marijuana doesn't seem to have
quite the same hangover no not for me
nothing like it once you're used to it
yeah no especially in that once you're
used to it I remember early on being
like feeling like I was dragging a bit
the next day but that went away so fast
this is so fast well Edibles yeah well
that's a different story I've had that
lag days Days upon some of the Malawi
carbs I've made in other people
um you the next day you wake up and
you're still as high as you were the day
yeah that's that cob you gave me holy
[ __ ] he says take please please size or
something this is a only about five or
six years ago and I was on my way up
somewhere to work and I I think I
stopped in Durango at night
and talk about being absolutely blessed
for the evening barely able to order a
meal let alone hold a conversation
that's funny
and then Stone as a dog the next morning
too you know driving through the
mountains and going I am stoned you know
12 hours later no that's it wasn't in
downtown L.A yeah yeah imagine on the
freeway or something you know at 80
miles an hour God yeah
10 miles
well is there anything else you want to
get in Jim
um not really it's
Johnny's covered
a good portion and
um like he was saying if you go
to that other
website the other put out those links I
I went I went over
um last week and posted a copy of the uh
Robert Clark's handwritten
envelope that the seeds came in oh wow
so that he could see that you know he
put for the for the 1981 season yeah
yeah made in 1980 that one you know and
yeah yeah and I posted some thoughts
about that also was that it was odd that
they used the the front of the label
said you know hash plants yeah if you're
Afghan it said repeatedly on that label
pure Afghan unhybridized I it made me
wonder if maybe they started with Afghan
number one and it was before skunk
number one or they were planning on
releasing these labels with skunk number
I mean with Afghan number one but people
said oh no the skunk number one's way
better way better so then they switched
and he he sold skunk number one
labels printed up and then they realized
oh my God we have multiple strains but
we had these nice tables let's just use
the label and put the F on the back yeah
yeah and also there's there's so much
detail that we both know
um from like even the Jerome days when
we were growing and we were so our first
year we did quite well good enough so
that we didn't have to work for two
dollars an hour which we did the year
before just to get by yeah and
it also allowed me the money to buy
three thousand skunk number one seeds
exactly I have to say thank you to High
Times because that's how I found Robert
Clark
great reading some of his articles in
there yeah and I wrote to the to the I
wrote to him via High Times They said if
you want to talk to the author or
whatever and then he he wrote me
directly
somehow we connected and it was um I
realized then that by having the most
potent most famous seed
um at that time it would be up to our
benefit oh yeah because you know what
had brought skunked to Arizona yet yeah
the loan to New York City or Brooklyn
and it turned out to be um very
worthwhile it was so new at that point
it was skunk was so new when you guys
got hold of it you guys were some of the
biggest first guys growing it in that in
that size for sure yeah and we pulled it
off so that made it even better and it
made history
all right guys but this is this is an
amazing conversation
um is there anything else you want to
get in Johnny
I'm just looking back I I you know Jim
and I still
still we we went buried to him you know
when I went my way and he went his but
it's been it was the adventure of my
life absolutely it was and if I might
have had a few you know and and that was
it was um a fabulous time and I'm always
grateful to Jim for um sort of mentoring
me through it you know because so many
people you know I've
thousands obviously tens of thousands of
people have grown weed um since you know
in in dodgy spots and a lot of them fail
you know I mean sure I I bet there's a
tremendous attrition rate of Australia
you know you know everybody starts out
all full of enthusiasm and goes out and
cuts holes into Manzanita uh you know
yeah
um thickets and and they don't make it
so you know I wanted to sit just thank
that you know Jim was the um Jim was the
man and and I'm really for the first
year anyway I was just the just the
working stiff but it was a Fabulous
Adventure and uh and I'll never regret
it no I mean and um and and again we've
sort of covered it but it's nice to have
this Vindication now all these years
later that um you know that marijuana
hasn't as as you know most of the
Republican senators in Colorado oh it'll
be the death of Colorado and you know
everybody's going to be smashing into
each other and and sprawling out on the
streets and you know and and the and
what I the other thing I'd like to point
out which is something that gets me very
strongly I'm an American citizen now but
you know this this this room this prison
system that we have in this country is
um pardon me it's a [ __ ] disaster in
my view and the number of people that
are languishing in jail for God knows
how long they're sitting on the porch
and smoking a reefer in the evening like
anybody else has a glass scotch or a
beer you know is absolutely and it's an
indictment of the privatized
um prison system we have in this country
which is which is an absolute travesty
of Justice right there with slavery to
me uh privatize present symptoms it is
slavery and all the and all the
corporations these ugly corporations
that that set up these awful prisons and
like Jim where Jim's got a lovely place
up in Northern New Mexico that I've
visited in a lot right there's a little
town called Clayton close by and it's
classic of what sorry I don't want to go
too much about this but you asked me and
you know this this um this system where
that we the taxpayer pay these
corporations to put people in jail and
they build them in these shitty run-down
little towns like this one's Clayton
where there's no business no you know
it's a dying town so all the people end
up working as guards or cooks or
whatever anyway right and it drives the
whole town and and without the
privatized prison then you're you're
driving the whole town out of money and
it becomes its own problem right and the
and the city fathers kissed the ass of
the exactly I think blue running because
it's the only trade they've got but but
it's driven and how many people are in
there for non-violent crimes you know
victimless crimes
the whole drug thing is it's the the DEA
you know we were always joking
half-heartedly or in a sense about
getting caught by the DEA that that
entire war against drugs has proved to
be an absolute complete [ __ ] waste of
taxpayers money billions of dollars
wasted billions of dollars
yeah trillions people's lives so many
lives ruined and they still are you know
the violence in Mexico and um and and
it's appalling to me that we go on in
this country you know um
financing this stupid fight on drugs
whereas you know if we at least had some
more sensible approach and policies for
it in America there wouldn't be the the
the the
terrible violence on the border anyway
that's my my only concern too is is that
legalization only brings those [ __ ]
in the corporate sector into cannabis to
bastardize it more and ruin it from the
inside out that's my biggest concern but
it almost seems inevitable because
that's what they do and then you just
take it back
yeah you know I can at least at least
it's you don't go to jail for it exactly
that's like the one the end user can
enjoy a a calming yeah I would say you
know pleasant evening without having to
worry about
um you know sure loving his door broken
down and being thrown in jail you know I
mean I think at one point there was
something like 50 of the the you know of
the um incarcerated population was in
there for the drugs non-violent and
victimless crimes yeah just because
these goddamn corporations then they
Lobby of course for more Draconian laws
oh sure yeah so so it's a it's a it's a
dreadful system anyway you asked me for
a last comment that's perfect that is
absolutely perfect my last comment is
that Johnny has climbed Half Dome oh
[ __ ] Half Dome yeah that's wild yeah
I can tell from that shape you guys
wouldn't have a problem climbing Half
Dome at all back then no back then I
don't know about now yeah my climbing
days are done I got vertigo now in fact
I'll be brief but I've just been doing
this job up in Moab and I was telling
Jim
um that um I have to go to the edges
they want these looked at uh these
overlooks you know and then and it was
just what we call a plate unit where we
shoot a clear for a canyon and then they
drop in all the CGI stuff you know in
post and I have to go to the edge of the
cliff and I've got this anyway I've got
vertigo now so my timing days are done I
feel like I'm gonna there's a there's a
magnet pulling me off and I sometimes
either lie down
with the camera
geez we'll be safe yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah well I appreciate you coming on the
show
um I appreciate Jim for having you come
on because this is a tale that's kind of
worked its way through our show and and
it's an absolute honor to speak with
someone who is one of the pioneers of uh
of our scene so thank you very much for
your contributions
well I defer to The Experts and and I
was just there I was just a muscle but
we went our own path our own ways for
many years but now we're friends and do
stuff together so it's really nice
um I'm glad you could come on today
Johnny all right my pleasure Matt a
pleasure to meet you and if I may I'll
send you some links and some photos
can't get enough of vintage strains go
check out the collab we just did Riot
seeds and suck Lord one of New York's
Premier toy makers uh we have a resin
cast toy one out of 27 only 27 made
exclusive to our uh to our customers for
the first seven days so go check it out
uh Link's gonna be in the description go
show him some support
foreign
[Music]
all of a sudden I just started
questioning everything I'd ever been
told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
when it started to hit me
and I'm like wow
[Music]
[Applause]
I got high
[Music]