ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
what's up everyone welcome to breeders
syndicate i'm here with uh our other
host not so dog and welcome
uh today we're going to take you through
a little bit of the 90s subculture both
bro and me and not so both have majorly
different experiences in the 90s uh
we're in two different parts of
the uh state and and in his case in the
country um and we were at different ages
so i think this is going to be a good
one to to rattle off about
yeah i mean we're also going to
answer some questions and then you know
since we just dropped that uh corel
interview a few days ago uh if people
have questions or clarification that
they want about a bunch of the stuff
we'll spend some time chatting about
that as well
so you know it's kind of going to be a
little bit of a wide-ranging discussion
you know and we'll just kind of freeform
it from there yep sounds good okay let's
start off with uh your 90s experience
yeah so i mean 90s experiences uh you
know we talked about in some previous
episodes we did a bunch of stuff on the
80s and the history uh you know matt and
i are not that old frankly so
uh don't have any weed growing
experience from the 70s or the mid 80s
90s is where both of us start to come
into the picture and both of us start to
have actual real experiences of what was
there what was available uh obviously uh
matt originates from the west coast uh i
originate from the midwest so very
different uh
experiences going on that and uh you
know other places talk about was your
first high like and all that i don't
think we need to spend very much time on
that because it's kind of boring to be
perfectly honest yeah but
um i will say that you know um so i'm a
little older than matt
and when i first started smoking weed in
the uh in the very early 90s
um
you know there was no internet um there
was no forums uh like i said in previous
talks you know there was some books
there was high times
uh i didn't realize at the time how
inaccurate a lot of stuff was in high
time nobody did i read it as gospel
and now i could go back and read a bunch
of stuff and be like oh my god i hope
nobody takes that advice but back then i
mean i was totally ignorant so
for me growing up in chicago uh there
was essentially two kinds of cannabis uh
there was brown mexican
and green mexican
uh that was predominantly that's what
there was
there was no other kind of import that i
ever saw
very occasionally there was some hashish
a little bit
um but brown and green dominated it uh
it was seeded
you know
the green mexican tended to be a little
bit nicer
um it was compressed the best stuff was
not that compressed and didn't have that
many seeds we used to call that 30-60
weed
because it was 30.8 and it was 60
dollars a quarter yeah uh the brown
mexican was more twenty forty weed that
was more twenty and eight forty a
quarter uh and the brown mexican
could have enormously different levels
of compression
to it and what i mean by compression is
how much they squished it to get it
across the border yes so it was squished
with stems seeds buds everything else
you had to fluff it you had to break it
up
um
you know and that's kind of that's kind
of how i started uh was
smoking
brown and green mexican yeah that's what
we had access to
um there were no glass pipes unless you
went on dead tour and saw bob bob's
non-grass the type of pipes that you
could get were stone
clay
metal
the bongs were essentially plastic
and in illinois in chicago there was no
you couldn't even buy that in the state
there wasn't a single head shop in the
entire state uh there was a couple of uh
shady gas stations where you could get
some very cheap papers that they would
claim were for rolling raw tobacco yeah
but even those places would get hassled
by the cops
so for me
uh
you know i had to drive to kenosha
wisconsin i had to drive a good two two
and a half hours away
to get to a head shop
yeah uh even even access to be able to
buy any of these things and then we had
to smuggle them back in
to our spot there was no easy access to
anything
so
you know i saw damn we were paying out
the ass for brickweed yeah i mean
the uh there was no
the amount of the amount of demand
obviously chicago is one of the big
cities in america it's a metropolis it's
got an enormous amount of people
uh
you know i um
there wasn't there wasn't a bunch of
california weed like there is today
flooding the country
uh it just didn't
at least maybe maybe there was for
certain circles but my teenage ass no
yeah i didn't know anybody and so
uh the funny thing about the actual spot
someone said in kenosha the actual spot
in kenosha was called supreme video
and what it actually was was a huge porn
shop
uh that you had to go through and in
order to get to the head shop portion of
the porn shop you had to walk through
a ginormous horn
you know i mean literally you know how
they have like the glass the glass like
push beads and stuff you know yeah
through
those they had those but dildos
yeah so you literally had to like walk
through like a wall of
you never wanted to run backwards
through it naked i'll tell you oh no i
you know generally speaking i i didn't
get naked in public but
um but you know you would go there and
there would be all kinds of metal pipes
stone pipes a few clay pipes
graphics i mean that was really all
there was um you know uh you know
getting clubs and all these high-end
papers that you have right now they
had you know the jobs the ritz like they
had all the basic there was no raw there
was no
the the papers were pretty much
cigarette papers back then
um but yeah i mean it was literally like
supreme video it was uh it was a huge
porn shop with a headshot behind it that
you had to walk through to get to it and
it was two and a half hours away yeah so
even even access to that kind of stuff
was was pretty funny in that regard yeah
zigzags uh were you know that was that
was high end you know
i mean even back then this is totally
different subject or whatever but like
the high-end beer back then was like
heineken yeah there was probably like
three micro breweries or four
microbreweries in the whole country so
even what we considered high grade of
that was pretty messy
uh you know in that regard and then
you know i mean the level of the level
of knowledge that gets spread around
right now
uh is pretty amazing back then
it was like it was a lot of rumor it was
a lot of innuendo it was a lot of stuff
you learned from some older smokers
maybe uh you know i made matt when we
were planning this episode i made matt
laugh because he had never heard of a
resin chamber
what a resin chamber is if you got like
a metal pipe and the pipe had the
smoking part and then it bent and had
the long piece that you puff off of they
would have a fat chamber that unscrewed
and you would put your nicest mexican
weed in that chamber your nicest bud of
the eighth or quarter you bought and you
would smoke that because you would be
getting free thc all over your bud
and then you would smoke that bud last
yes eventually
we skipped that process and went ahead
and just scraped the resin
and just didn't didn't smoke any bugs
inside that little chamber it was always
there i didn't know that people put [ __ ]
in no it was literally called it was
literally called the resin chamber and
so i would ruin
the nicest butt i had that i could fit
in there every single bag i bought
because i thought
that uh that was the way i was that was
the older the older cats that's what
they told me to do and that made sense
and yeah you did you know so i ruined
wheat green rocks full og moon rocks i
was also telling them a story about how
you know uh we would get all the you
know the the gla the pipes that not the
pipes the the bongs the water pipes that
we would get you had to call them water
pipes back then or they would throw your
ass out of the store immediately and
they would have big signs that say we
only sell water pipes yeah because water
pipes could be used for tobacco and thus
weren't illegal where bongs were a
specific nomenclature for marijuana and
that could get a shop shut down so cops
would come in and ask if i could buy a
bong
just to see if the the shop was stupid
enough to say something and then they'd
shut it down so
you know yeah i mean i smoked out we
made pipes out of uh tin foil using pens
to form the tin foil i smoked out of
apples i smoked out of
uh you know cans my dad still
tells everyone that every uh
every every nasty every nasty thing you
would just laugh at now but literally
the very first time
i saw anybody smoke like using glass
pipes was there is this guy he's
considered the grandfather of modern
glass pipes his name was bob snodgrass
and he was a fixture on dead tour and he
would blow pipes out of the back of his
van
and sell you little top hats he had you
know he was the coolest thing ever uh
but you had to literally go to a dead
show um
you know and so
um
yeah we would even acquiring the method
to smoke [ __ ] weed was not very
simple
you know um thank god i didn't smoke out
of too much tinfoil uh my brain thanked
me but yeah screens cleaning your
screens ripping your screen out holding
it with a pair of needle nose and then
like burning the resin off the screen so
you could reuse it with your lighter
um
you know
all that type of stuff that was like
cutting edge technology i remember
yeah hemostat roach clips of course we
had one of those too um i remember the
very first time somebody told me
that uh you could clean up a bong with
alcohol and salt
so i had a dirty graphics plastic bomb
and i got like 99 alcohol and i got some
salt and i mixed them up and i poured it
in the thing and i watched the whole
bong just crack all the way up slowly it
just ruined my bomb because i didn't
realize that that's what would happen uh
because plastic's porous you know so
there was so much resin that it like
inhibited the glass that when it started
melting the resin it started
structurally [ __ ] with the pipe and i
ruined my bomb and i was like oh
you know i had to like leave the state
to go get another one that's all i had
you know i was like oh there goes the
bomb yeah so
you know um now head shops are easy
the internet exists ordering shit's easy
um all that you know we used to i used
to take a
uh a um
a tray
right and you take your weed up here on
the tray and you angle it between your
chest and your knees and you'd break up
all of your mexican at the top and then
all the seeds would roll down the tray
and collect in the bottom lip
um and you had to de-seed and de-stem
the entire thing just to get smokable
weed
yeah you know
um you know so
uh
yeah the
i mean i don't i can't there was another
uh porn store in
kenosha that seoul also sold pipes the
only one that i remember is supreme
video uh it's still there
uh i haven't been there
in decades but it still exists i don't
know what it does now but it's certainly
it's certainly uh that's how hard it was
you know i mean even a big city like
chicago everything was banned everything
was illegal you had to go find it we
used to use um postal scales that was
the only kind of scale you could buy
[ __ ] getting a digital scale yeah there
was no digital scale available there was
nowhere that sold it there was nowhere
to find it so you would have the little
postal scale that you would clip and
you'd put your little everybody knew
that like a a baggie a sandwich baggie
was one gram and a zip lock was three
and a half grams you'd have to hold it
up you know and the buyer and the seller
would make sure because depending on the
level of compression sometimes you'd buy
brickweed and like an eighth would be
like
that and someone would be like there's
no way that way is right it can't wait
right you know and you'd have to be like
oh there's a little hanging scale but
there you go you know no it actually
weighs yeah um
you know and uh that was you know like a
lot of people triple beams triple beams
existed uh but they were hard to get the
older guys had triple beams you know and
with the you know good thing and you
move it along and do the whole big that
was the high end if you could get a
triple beam
and you had the money to grab that then
you're then you're really
then you're really doing it but postal
scales honestly as a teenager that's
what everybody was they were hideable
they were small exactly you couldn't
hide
you know postal scales were like the
standard when i was young um
just straight up and so
you know rather than talking about like
your first highs or whatever that was
the first state of weed that was weed
normalcy um i'll shut up for a minute
matt can throw in he probably has a
little bit better access because
southern california he probably got a
little bit nicer green bud tonight he's
shaking his head no uh you know
like my first experience like as it as
someone that went and actively bought
pot i'm not talking about watering for
dad or any of that [ __ ] right
because i had no interest in any of that
when i was young age so when i first got
into actually actively like going trying
to find weed uh the first stuff i saw
was you know us
high school
[ __ ] smoking out of [ __ ] cans you
know
we had just gotten into high school i
was 13 when i entered high school and
that was when we first started buying
from you know the seniors that had
[ __ ] shitty ass mets but this was all
we knew so we grabbed it and i remember
the first times not breaking it up at
all just throwing it on a can and trying
to burn it you know no one really taught
us any of that kind of stuff like how to
properly break it up or do any of that
[ __ ] um but we saw a lot of compressed
brick coming through and traditionally
most even over all the years the ones
that i remember the most had this minty
almost chocolate smell and i'm not
talking like heavy terps like whoa this
is it just had like
very low smells of that or we had what
we called the pretendica which was the
uncompressed and and usually not always
but usually it would be more red or hued
it would be full
colas and it in our area we were doing
like 60 an ounce 250 for a p of the
the max but at the same time the
uncompressed was usually 250 to 300 or
60 to 70 an ounce so it wasn't a big
difference in the uncompressed versus
the compressed
so for me i'll just throw a little ad
there um since i'm from the midwest this
we can get a little bit historical here
for a second uh obviously they they made
uh marijuana illegal in 1910 illegal in
and then they had a problem in the 1940
and that we started world war ii
and they needed
so many supplies for clothing for sales
for ropes for canvas uh army bags all
this and so they had this program called
hemp for victory right
and in hemp for victory they basically
paid a bunch of farmers to grow millions
of acres of cannabis
uh hemp act not cannabis not drug
cultivators but hemp for fiber in
illinois kansas indiana a bunch of
midwestern states right
so obviously if you're growing millions
of acres of seeded cannabis uh there's
going to be a bunch of wild seed sure so
that's where in the midwest that's where
the term ditchweed comes from uh it was
wild populations of hemp because they
made hemp illegal again right after we
won the war
so for 40 from 40 to 45 they just grew
just millions of acres of hemp in the
midwest
and then for decades after that
they paid the government the dea to
eradicate it yeah uh most people don't
know this but like 90 of the dea's
budget to eradicate cannabis was just
cutting down hemp fields in the midwest
that grew wild uh but the way the
government works you know um
you know i uh
the way the government works is they
just take the money and use the money
right so
um so ditchweed for us which we called
pretendica was i will freely admit that
multiple times i bought what i thought
were gorgeous looking ounces
of premium kind bud
green juicy frosty everything else and
paid 350 400 bucks an ounce
um and then you start smoking it and
at that point in my life i'd never even
heard the word cbd i didn't know it
existed i didn't even know what hemp was
really
and i wouldn't get high
and then we do this experiment where
we'd smoke some green mexican and we get
way higher
then and so we called it pretendica
because some entrepreneur scammers would
go out there and they'd harvest some
wild empty look gorgeous
they'd dry it and they'd sell it to dumb
bucks uh that were teenagers that didn't
know any better for top dollar thinking
they were getting the juiciest like
seven bud ounce [ __ ] looked good it
didn't look so good and so that's what
we called pretendica yeah uh because
when you got cheated out of your money
and you bought weed that didn't work
yeah no idea at the time why it didn't
work now i know it was cbd yeah you know
i was literally buying gorgeous hemp
uh but i didn't know
you know
so uh yeah i mean people are saying
ditch weed ditch weed that's what you
call it indiana illinois there's still
ditchweed kansas i'm sure there's still
ditchweed
uh it grows wild populations it seeds
itself they eradicate it it grows on the
edges of farms it grows on the edges of
forest it grows in ditches
obviously it rains a lot in the midwest
than summer so it doesn't need very much
care by humans at all to
propagate itself nebraska certainly has
a bunch
all those places where they farm you
know you farm millions of acres of
seeded weed
uh there's millions and millions of
seeds that hit the ground
yeah um and it establishes a wild
population essentially
so
um
you know uh basically you know i've
talked a little bit about this before
but like
uh when i in the 90s when i first got
into kind bud the two most reliable
places for me to find kind bud was
holland
and a grateful dead show
other than that it was incredibly hard
to come by
there the supply of it was terribly
limited the demand for it was super high
um
and
you know
so that's kind of how it was
like when i said 2040 for brownweed and
30 60 for greenweed
um anything better than mexican no
matter how crappy grown was 50 100.
yeah it didn't i mean i have some
stories of some really messed up very
poorly grown kind bug
but didn't matter it was 50 60 70 and 8
and if you didn't want it somebody else
would hop in so figure it out yeah
you know i don't know if that i don't
know what it was like in uh and where
you're from matt but that that was that
was my experience getting into cannabis
was that was what was around yeah um
we didn't really start seeing really
good [ __ ]
at least in our circle until mike
because my dad went to prison for he was
always in and out so he wasn't really
like down to hook up his connects
because he just wasn't there and he was
always getting out and getting new
connects
um my best friend his name is josh moved
back from alaska he got sent away to
alaska
for some reason by his mom in high
school he did something bad or got in a
car wreck drunk or something something
crazy but he got shipped off to alaska
and he comes back and he's like check
this [ __ ] out he opens a saxophone case
he's got a bong in there and this is
like one of the first times i've seen a
glass bomb a really nice glass ball you
know and he breaks out this weed and it
smells [ __ ] crazy i've never really
seen weed like that and he's like yeah
bro he's like let me tell you about this
most potent strain on earth it's called
matluska valley [ __ ] bro you know
and and i didn't know about name strains
at that point really it wasn't like
it was it was all a big mystery to me
and he busts out some what he called
white rhino and some white widow you
know that was our first real experience
in our circle with those kind of strains
but yeah bakersfield is is traditionally
hardcore mecca even now you're not
getting
real quality [ __ ] like people that go to
collectives you're just not seeing
quality [ __ ] bakersfield it's not a
connoisseur market it's very much driven
by low price in bakersfield
so i mean that's that's the personal
experience or whatever we don't need to
like harp too too long on what our own
personal experiences are the main reason
to talk about it was just to give people
a sense of when you get into weed
you know honestly i'm not even sure i
would have tried to start growing as
soon as i did
if i had access to a variety of kinds of
kind bud that's what we called it kind
buddy
those were the kind of the two words
that we we used for it uh commonly
um was and i'll add one more piece to it
so when i actually did
um
meet some crews that
uh
had weed so this is the funny part right
so let's say
let's say that
you you're like three people away from a
grower and this grower is growing like
three or four or five pounds or
something right
the guy who bought all the stuff that
the guy wasn't gonna keep her personal
let's say the guy grew five pounds and
he sold four
the dude that would buy the four pounds
would take the four pounds and he would
dump him out on the table and whatever
he was going to keep he would pick nug
by nugg the nicest looking [ __ ] out of
the whole thing
because every bit of it's sold
so i might have only been like three
people away from the grower and every
butt i got in the half ounces i was
buying was that big yeah like there was
no like everybody could just skim every
person that got it they just skimmed the
amount they were keeping being every
nice bud because everything would work
it didn't matter
which is ridiculous today that like you
could essentially sell smalls
uh at a premium
um but
you know the first time i heard the word
dank
um
was
uh going to dead shows uh that was the
kind of the comp kind bud or dank was
the way that you described [ __ ] that
wasn't mexican
yeah my little circles
yeah i remember
my first experience it with it was my
friends adam my friend adam's older
brother dave he he came home wearing a
shirt that said dank on it and he's like
i was like what what does that mean he's
like it means it's not [ __ ] swag bro
that was my first experience and i was
like what the [ __ ] is schwag you know
yeah what is what
you know and so yeah i mean there was
this thing where i mean you know being
frank with people like when you first
get kind bud
like you didn't even know it existed you
know yeah and then you have a situation
where you already like weed
you're into smoking brown weed you're
into smoking the green weed you like
weed you like getting high it does all
the different things to you yeah and
then you get some kind bud and like you
didn't even realize that that grade
existed yeah there wasn't any seeds
you know yeah it's a trip all the first
kind but i saw too was indoor
uh coming from the midwest uh there was
no outdoor
um yeah dirt weed swag uh you know you
cut it sometimes with the bricks you cut
it with a bread knife yeah oh yeah easy
yeah you saw it go at it you know
serrated knife yeah you'd sit there and
saw it and break it up and fluff it and
try to figure it out and
all that stuff and so
you know i mean my friends and i like we
could go to
we could go to dead shows and
uh we could buy we could get weed
you know i mean that was one of the
wasn't the primary reason that we went
um
you know i mean it's funny i didn't have
anything my parents like my parents
weren't involved in it or anything like
that i guess you could say i'm first-gen
as far as like my family getting
involved but um
you know when i first went to a debt
show
my buddy and i were trying to figure out
where we could like sit down and hide
and smoke some weed where none of the
adults were gonna rat us out oh yeah
yeah because back then it was like you
know 15 or something you couldn't let an
adult see you smoking weed you get
busted yeah my grandma and mom were not
[ __ ] cool at all with it and it goes
back to the seeds i used to get popped
every time and i never figured out how
my grandma always popped me when i was
smoking because she would [ __ ] always
catch me and later on she told me it was
because when i would smoke bowls in my
room the seeds would get hot and pop out
and burn holes in the carpet so all
every time there was new holes in the
carpet she knew i was in there [ __ ]
smoking you know oh man we definitely we
definitely got taught young
uh to remove seeds it's certainly
certainly you know
certainly you don't always do it the
correct way you miss one especially with
you you can't get them
yeah and then on top of that there's
like this paper thin seed shell yes not
the hard shell but there's like a kind
of a papery like on a garlic you know
clove or something and that's what
stripes are on that that thin paper
sleeve yeah you'd miss that and then um
yeah and then that would taste terrible
if you got that in your bowl you'd be
like oh
you know and so anyway i mean yeah my
actually my first growing
was flicking seeds out my window
you know getting
some stuff so i could go on a walk and
smoke some weed and then i'd be like
mowing my out you know my lawn for
spring in the backyard and i'd be like
oh you know and i would just run right
over with the mower because i was like i
didn't even think that that would happen
at ridgeview at ridgio our high school
anybody who went there between 94 and 99
knew about the weed patch we had going
across the street and pretty much
everybody was in on taking care of these
plants as long as we could do it you
know until the narcs came out and
figured it out
yeah so i mean like for
you know the
so that's that's just kind of to set the
tone
of like that's kind of what the 90s was
like you know in the in the early and
mid 90s there was basically mexican
there wasn't very good access the
education sucked
you know um and
you know we uh that's what started my
trips to amsterdam
um was was i was like i
they have good weed over there and i
don't
yeah you know and then you know it was
like you would meet people
on dead tour that could give you weed
because lots of people would bring
pounds to dead tour and sell eighths and
quarters and ounces
um just to like you know do their two
three week run worth of shows you know i
mean that's essentially how
you know i mean that's what keyboard and
joe brand were doing when uh when chem
dog bought his sacks
they were just you know people would
bring good weed to dead shows and hustle
it you know yeah and um
you know maybe that maybe that uh
we could talk about that a little bit
because now it's like it's pretty widely
spread
uh throughout different parts of society
and there's different there's certainly
lots of different types of people
growing weed and that probably always
was the case but in the 90s
um
it was a hippie-based group sure like
the people that were most in tune with
weed the people that were most in tune
with getting weed and bringing me to you
know
dead shows were probably one of the
greatest open-air wheat markets that's
ever existed in america
because people from all walks of life
all parts of the country new york
florida california wherever they would
buy or bring their weed on dead tour and
that's how they would fund their party
their food their hotels their traveling
their tickets their whatever you know
most people that went to dead shows not
everyone but most people went to dead
show smoke weed so it was really easy to
sell weed and get by and it wasn't
nearly as sketchy as some of the other
substances and stuff that people hustled
weed was a little mellower you know so
yeah lots of people did it
um and
you know there's some there's some
pretty famous
stuff that used to get sold there uh we
could chat about that for a second
um my buddy who you know i we talked
about him before uh i call him staten
island
uh just you know but he you know he's
about seven years older than me and so
he
and skunk va used to go to a bunch of
dead shows together um with other people
uh and you know they
uh his favorite lead on dead tour was a
big sir holy
um and he said you could buy big sur
holy skunk and you could buy big sur
holy haze
and he said you know a lot of people had
like fanny packs back then of all things
but yeah he said that like
it was so distinctive of an aroma that
not only could you tell somebody had
dank weed in their fanny pack you could
tell that they were holding on to the
big sir holy yeah and so out of
everything that he had back then
everything he had access to
um that stuff whoever was doing it was
bringing it you know chunks of it
regularly to dead tour
and so
you know the the stuff that we talked
about the the super skunk the
uh some people called that the uh you
know the skunk six on tour
um there was skunk on tour there was
northern lights on tour
um you know and a lot of people
uh that went to dead shows uh grew weed
or sold weed or new people that grew
weed so my education
um about weed was basically i could go
to dead shows
you know i could learn that with in
retrospect a lot of ignorance around my
area but i could go to dead shows and i
could learn from some old-timers or i
could go to amsterdam
sure you know uh and i could and i could
learn from cats over there you know i
mean i met
i met a guy some people call him mr
hayes i met a guy named steve
in amsterdam um i met uh simon
um
from sirius who was super nice to me
i met some other folks just like
anywhere else you know you go some
coffee shops you know coffee shops are
kind of like dispensaries they don't
really have the kind all that often
uh they have some decent stuff some of
them have some really nice stuff but
then when you get started getting into
like the collector's circles and you
make some acquaintances and friends
um you know that kind of stuff you start
meeting and getting some better read
you know so
you know yeah there was um
you know yeah they're like it's just
true it's it's dead shows were
dead shows were the best place for
because you got to realize too without
the internet without forums without
trading without any of that with
everything being illegal everywhere and
everything being super clandestine
um
you know little circles might get this
butter that bud in their local area but
not that much
um
but uh
you know um
you know the the modern big sur stuff
um i can tell you that it's not pure
i don't know exactly the mix but i can
say that some of the big stir stuff
that's out there
staten island has confirmed did smell
very similar to um we went over to
amsterdam in the 90s and we smelled the
sage
the actual like famous cutting of sage
they ran over there
and he confirmed that it did smell like
the big sur some one of the versions of
the big sur that he used to get um so
i can't say
um you know and there's a difference you
know our buddy bodhi has a cut that he
uses
uh csi has a cut uh that's a little
terpenoline based
um
you know there's some people in colorado
and other areas that has
um that has you know the the atom cut of
sage
um that's not really my my wheelhouse i
can't say which ones are more legit than
others
uh you know but um
you know i'm sure it exists out there in
various forms
you know so
um
that was uh you know that was the first
place i saw blueberry was on dead tour i
was the first place i saw northern
lights that was the first place i saw
skunk
um that was the first place i saw lots
of different things so
uh matt wasn't really into dead shows so
he doesn't really share that experience
but uh
um you know i do i will say i have um i
mean back then we were
we were punk rockers and in in our scene
it wasn't a wheat scene it was a heroin
scene it was a meth scene
and that was it killed everyone we did
we didn't have um a big weed scene and i
didn't really have the respect for the
dead or the dead scene for that matter
during those times because they were
just long hairs to us you know but as
i've gotten older and i'm more
passionate about about cannabis i've
realized how much how much really went
on in our scene and revolved around the
dead shows and as far as u.s cannabis
making it from point a to point b it's
such a major major
part of our history and it's it was it
was a serious loss not to to really open
my eyes to that early on yeah i mean
it's one of those things where it's like
it was kind of by default
you know that was one of the i mean some
of the things you know sometimes people
ask me um
you know how did you get access to all
these famous strains you know yeah and
in honesty like when i got when i got a
bunch of them they weren't famous at all
it was years before any of them become
famous so it wasn't like i got anything
that i was like oh my god this is this
you know it was just this is weed you
know um but hippies and dead and people
that attended dead shows a bunch they
traded amongst each other and i mean
honestly when i moved out to mendocino
it was because i had friends from dead
tour that lived outside of yukata
and i had an inn i had i had a person
that knew people i had a person that
could get me situated i could have me
uh you know i could get situated
with for lack of a better term now
there's all kinds of people involved in
need and it's grown much beyond it but
in the 90s
um i don't think there was any social
group that had
more access to more different kinds of
stuff than
than hippies
because being on dead tour you'd have
friends from miami and upstate new york
and montana and texas and florida and
alaska
and everywhere
i mean they would just you would gather
there was spring summer and fall tour
you're traveling with people you're
partying with people you're smoking weed
you're trading stories
um so that was the way that things
blended for lack of a better term it was
sort of the first forums
yeah it was dead shows it was where
like-minded people could gather you know
um
and uh
you know so uh
you know i i know you know they say that
there's people that have i'm looking at
stuff people are saying the cut didn't
come from adam i know it didn't come
from adam his partner is actually who
brought it to europe i believe they
brought it in seed form um it was called
the big sur holy uh because supposedly
it was grown in the back of the
monastery
uh so it was the holy week you harry the
monk full yeah so you know i mean i
don't i don't have i don't really have
any like specific ties to that except
for
um
you know except for like one of my old
friends uh it was kind of his
he would tell these stories of it you
know
uh i i used a few different big sur holy
lines i had one that came from indian
guy
or and it wasn't his creation or
anything indian guy
um he was he he got a lot of seeds from
people and he would distribute them so
we didn't really know the sourcing on a
lot of this stuff from him but it came
through him and it was a pink pistoled
version that was supposedly the
zihuatanejo purple which is in
supposedly in big sur holy weed a lot of
people refer to it as zacatecas purple
because zacatecas is easier to pronounce
than z
nail
but um that's where it is also the gambo
version which i believe is big sir holy
weed and reefer man's version bodhi had
a version um the one thing that i
noticed runs in common with a lot of
these lines was the trapinoline and
since i'm not from that area i don't
know if that is uh common trait with the
original big sur holy but that is what
ran
in between all of these
yeah i'm not i can't i'd have to uh i
know for sure that and i and i
i honestly don't remember uh but we did
you know uh
mr staten island myself bought got some
sacks from the adam and the thc crew and
the midnight in that era and he did say
that it smelled like that i don't have a
strong memory of what it smelled like so
i can't comment
certainly the one that certainly has one
comment he knows
certainly the one that uh csi uses is a
bit terpenoline yeah uh based i can say
that for sure because i've puffed that
in recent years and such and have some
experience with that one but
i don't think i've ever
personally smoked uh any of bodies pure
uh i certainly have smoked some hybrids
but i don't have a memory of bodies
either to be honest um you know
that's what's funny too is like
you know the other thing that people
should know is like you know uh csi and
bodhi are both uh
reasonably good friends of ours you'd
classify it as but a lot of breeders and
stuff they they use their strains to
breed and so some of the collection i
might have known you forever and you
might but that doesn't mean that you're
producing smokable weed of all of your
pure lines all the time where your
friends can have sacs of them either a
lot of the times the stuff you're trying
is hybrids
or s-ones or this or that or whatever
else a lot of these guys aren't growing
a bunch of
pure
you know uh females to smoke
yeah they're using them in breeding work
yeah
right well it goes back to that whole
statement of some plants or growers and
some plants are breeders and sometimes
they that's not mutually exclusive you
know sometimes
so maybe this would be a good time this
is something that matt and i chatted
about that i think is kind of it's kind
of cool
but we can throw this in there so when
we were talking to the the
on the corel interview one of the cool
things was to me
was hearing you know how they came up
with the nickname victor barne
and how they came up with beatrix choice
victor barne was like the code name that
the royal put on his bank account to get
yeah
to get the kickback skim that he wasn't
going to be traced to him yeah and
beatrix was the queen and you know that
kind of
yeah
and that kind of that kind of ties in to
like cannabis for a long time has always
had like we've had this uh we've had
this nickname game we're kind of
subversive in that regard and so yeah a
lot of nicknames about pop culture
you know and stuff like that and we use
um
we give various nicknames to weed right
a little crew gets it and it becomes you
know you you throw a nickname on it uh
for instance i'll give you a couple
examples the legend of the puck
uh is that the guy that everybody got it
from
uh you know he used to carry it around
in a in a hockey puck case it look like
the some people might remember bubble
tape that bubble gum yes it looks about
that size it literally is is a case that
holds a puck
you know um and uh and so they called it
the puck because it came out of the case
yeah um you know you know we i have the
dog [ __ ] um but in minneapolis it was
called electric boogaloo
you know um the snow bud was called
skunk five in florida
um you know chem chemdawg has been
called chemdog
uh we called it just straight dog for
years
uh then it got called skunk va
then it got called chem 91
um and so these certain strains have
names and a lot of them are funny and a
lot of them tie into various things you
know and stuff like that but
for matt and i and others it makes it a
real [ __ ]
because when you're trying to find out
like
is this nl5 by skunk one yeah they
didn't keep the real name
that they got they didn't keep the
lineage
there's a nickname
and so we put a lot of time and energy
and research into finding out like what
the real names are one second
before you get there we do have the top
voted question is in a previous episode
you guys spoke about nl2 possibly being
renamed to hindu kush when since he
acquired devil's stuff
you want to go ahead and talk about that
part
sure ties in so there's a there's a
there's a couple things there that we
could that we could talk about for one
real quick just hindu kush is a region
um and then sam skunk man dave watson uh
he brought a hindu kush that was not
related over to amsterdam as well at
some point um and lots of things have
been called hindu kush
but uh in specific this the scentsy
thing if you look back uh in neville's
catalog
basically every time he talks about nl2
he and every description from the 86
catalog on he calls it a hindu kush
phenotype yeah right he keeps describing
it as a hindu kush um there was things
that you know he called uh what he
called skunk kush was nl2 by skunk one
yeah you know he kept every every ev
basically every reference you can find
to nl2 in any of the seed bank catalogs
he calls hindu kush yeah and then when
sensei took over they renamed a number
of his things and i spoke about this
before but um they
they renamed it and l2 and one of the
clues was they also sold skunk kush
and they called it our best hindu kush
phenotype crossed with skunk one yeah
you know but you look in neville's
catalog and skunk kush's nl2 by this
yeah you know and so and so sensei just
changed every reference to nl2
um to hindu kush yeah right um and so
there's they even use if you look in the
verbiage of neville's description of
nl2 in his 88 89 and 90 catalog
they they even used similar words same
words and similar verbiage and similar
sentences
um
neville had some very long-winded
descriptions of his weed
paragraphs like that scentsy would would
shrink them down to two or three
sentences
but
it's pretty clear we've documented in a
variety of ways
they
what what if you bought hindu kush from
sensei seeds
uh it was an l2 f3 that was sold by
neville the last three years of the seed
bank catalog
and everything that they had that said
nl2 nl2 just disappears off the face of
the earth uh with the exception
that dutch passion
uh released an nl2 pheno that they
called oasis
um so
one of the things that makes it tough is
that
there's so many nicknames given to weed
that you try to trace back
what it was
and like we talked about before
um most of the stuff that was that was
coming was either from sssc or the seed
bank or scentsy because that was the
only games and that we were selling
international seed
um so a lot of their genetics are
absolutely laced
through uh
the uh are our scene
but they go by different names
and then how do you piece together you
know on
for instance i'll give you an example so
we've i've always thought that the dog
[ __ ] or i i like to call it the electric
boogaloo uh because i think electric
boogaloo is one of the all-time coolest
names in cannabis yeah um and so
changing into dog [ __ ]
definitely today
uh in modern cannabis where everything
has to be candy and evoke images and be
desserty uh there's zero chance that
anybody would name anything dog it would
be about as much chance of dog [ __ ]
being a name as like filthy sweat sock
you know
yeah it just wouldn't it just wouldn't
come about you know
um but
we've always felt that it was an nl5
haze phenotype
uh yeah cat piss would be very unlikely
um
and uh
you know if you not that and and matt
and i have issues with philos but if you
go and you look at philos okay
some of the things that
that dog [ __ ] is supposedly fairly
closely related to
um is european nl5 haze phenols that
have been you know
um and so we've always we've always had
this idea that it was that
yeah and we were able to trace it by it
was called this an organ it was called
this in minneapolis
but what was it before minneapolis
right
and then it pops up philos isn't very
good at showing family relationships it
can only show them if they're really
close yeah um but it shows relationships
to
pith
yeah it shows relationships to c5 it
shows relationships to a5 it shows
relationships to hash plant haze and
stuff
and that's be probably because it's an
nl5 haze
yeah and so you try to get you try to
get various stuff like that so there's
all these cool nicknames you know and
some of them you know i mean we know the
cindy 99 story
supposedly he found seeds and he's
laughing but supposedly he found seeds
and a butt of jack herrera yeah
so that at least gives you an indication
but if it was just cindy 99 and you
don't know that backstory part
what is cinderella 99 yeah what is the
origin
you know what is the and then it might
have one nickname in one group you know
i mean we have some friends on our
discord server and they get into battles
over it because you know the puck
the puck was called the you know hash
plan some people called it skelly
some older people say [ __ ] no one
ever called it skelet
you know no one ever called it this and
it was never that you know but different
groups get it and they get different
nicknames and then
what group you get it from or what group
you hear about it from that's the
nickname
that i can i can tell everyone that in
my crew
uh everybody that had uh the chem dog
um we called the dog
yeah it was the dog
you got the dog
you know it wasn't chem dog we called it
dog we shortened the dog and these new
names didn't really pop up until oh six
when our when our buddy uh skunk va got
on the forums
and people were trying to figure out
what the [ __ ] he was talking about yeah
and so they started calling it the skunk
va cut
you know
and uh i think canada actually named it
like canada the the health
whatever their cannabis board is there
that makes it legal they actually have a
strain called skunk va because they
confused it so much and confabulated it
so much they were trying to name it
after kim dog but they only named it
skunky i
got to know what skulk va thinks about
that
yeah you know and it was and and so
the only reason why i bring that up is
just
is uh
um is basically just because
it just shows you the progressions of
different names that different small
groups of cannabis smokers can give to a
strain
and then if you get that strain through
their crew right
um you know uh
you know
what is it so you know another example
would be you know we talked about this
in the first episode that i participated
in was about how
my buddy from staten island went to
virginia to get the skunk
and he dropped it off with chemdog when
he got the dog uh in massachusetts and
then he drove the skunk and the chem dog
west
right well there's a whole bunch of
people that call it the mss
yeah the massachusetts super skunk
right
why
because they heard about it or they saw
it or they knew about it from
massachusetts yeah it was from virginia
but they didn't know that
you know um some people called that the
super skunk that's what we always called
it in our crew there was other people
that took it to colorado that was tied
into the same virginia crew and they
called it by the name on the tag the you
know the number of the seed which was
six
yeah so some people called it skunk six
some people called it massachusetts
some people called it superstar
uh i i think some people only briefly
called it mass super skunk because what
we've realized if there was another cut
called mass super skunk proliferating at
the same time from the same crew
but we didn't even realize that for
years and years yeah yeah of course yeah
that wasn't that was that was pieced
together fairly recently yeah the point
is is that if you were from virginia you
called it one thing
if you were from massachusetts or new
york and you got it from that crew you
liked it called it another thing if you
were from my crew in northern california
you called it a different thing and it
was all the same thing you know um and
it was only recently that we started
figuring you know we were able to you
know through uh various friends and
stuff start talking to the person who
read it um and you know get actual
information on what it was yeah uh you
know and stuff like that and so
the point that i was trying to make
there when i was kind of long-winded is
that
you know we add nicknames and those
nicknames are cool and neat and funny
and all that kind of stuff but then when
you go to try to figure out the lineage
of stuff
you hit a wall a lot of the time from
90s weed
yeah you don't know what it is
because it got named dumpster
or electric boogaloo or snow or
you know or whatever it might be you
know the trinity was named trinity
because it came out of a seed of bud
that a friend gave someone that came
from trinity trinity county in
california
um so that's where uh
you know
yeah somebody you know
we do more with sssc it's quite possible
yeah guys
if you if you watch your questions to be
a part of like the giveaway and stuff
though put it in that little question
section it makes it easier for us to
read and catch it like we won't miss it
as much and you'll be entered in the the
giveaway at the end so keep that in mind
guys
yeah and so so the name game happened
everywhere um for different reasons in
america it was mostly
in the in the 90s it was mostly just
crews giving cultural names to stuff
um in holland and other areas it was to
hide the lineage that if they got it
from somebody else
you know they would change the name a
little bit sometimes and hide that
that's common now in america too
absolutely people people like to hide
exactly where they got what they got
well you can't you can't create
something magical if someone else
created it
but i mean that's that's so that's the
funny part right is that really what it
boils down to is that
you know and we we could talk about this
kind of stuff too is like you know they
everybody everybody gets to breed or
whoever wants to breed um
you know you get seeds and you get
clones and you get whatever from your
crew
yeah from your connections and you start
with whatever that was was there is
nobody out there anymore that is
collecting random mass land race strains
on their own travels for the most part
breeding them and bringing totally
unique things that no one else except
for the farmers in those regions had
everybody gets what they get from their
friends and their crew
who they know and then they start
reading and that's not a dis everyone
wants to act like in today's world
breeders have to come out with some kind
of totally unique genetics and they're
not just standing on the shoulders of
everybody that came before them
but that's a bunch of preposterous crap
yeah
it literally is you get it from
you know uh you know i mean we could
talk about maybe you could talk about
you know there's some famous strains
from down by you matt that you had
access to like um bull rider
well see bull rider was one of the few
that i didn't have access to i didn't
get access to bull riding hogs breath
hogs breath i did right that kind of
stuff you know that doesn't give you
very good clues about what the hell's in
it no old betsy hogg's breath
bull rider
no that's not very 91 no p91 yeah these
are not helpful terms we're just barely
being able to pick apart what's in p91
by its growth expressions and running
through enough s1s and s2s to see what
its parentage is just barely getting a
shot at that
yeah so you know a lot of these things
are just so they were cool at the time
and they were pop culture they were
culturally related or they were an
inside joke in the crew or something
like that you know yeah and uh
you know then
you know it uh
you know that's just kind of the way it
was but it makes it much more difficult
now because a lot of these clone only
elites
um have these nicknames yeah and
figuring out what they actually are
is tough
yeah you know because you know it would
be really amazing
i mean if if technology was different
imagine if sssc
and neville and scentsy and sirius and
these different groups have been able to
put up all of their original cuts into
something like philos or into some
something better than philos hopefully
or some kind of genetic marker group
where you can see the family tree now
has exploded from all these things oh
yeah because the names have obscured
just how much
we depended on all that
yeah in my opinion at least yeah yeah no
yeah it does
you know
so um
you know well yeah i mean someone says i
thought the p91 was a nl cubed project
that that was one of the many many
stories going around uh there's many
there's so many about p91 that it's
silverback tie across the
something else that it's silver pearl
that it's early pearl
it looks it looks super skunk-faced to
me and you know when we were also
talking to corel it was it was really
interesting to see back then that
like you know he got stuff from various
breeders
um but a lot of his work came from bag
seeds of wheat he liked from coffee
shops yeah
and you know i mean obviously we you
know we we've covered it but chem dog is
a bag seed
uh sour diesel is a bag seed
cookies is a bag seed trinity is a bag
seed
yeah you can og was bag seed uh you can
go on and on and on and on and on
apparently runts was too you know like
it's never gonna stop yeah a bunch of a
bunch of the most famous stuff is you
find some butt seed and a bud you like
and something pops out of it and
then people are like oh you know i mean
even with me
and some of these like old cuts and
people are like oh what about the maui
what about this what about that like the
reason why we called the maui is because
that's where we it was from
and i was too dumb to ask any other
questions
yeah i mean at the time it wasn't like
that you know there wasn't this like
enormous thirst
for specific lineage
like you just wanted good weed and so
that's part of the problem too like when
you start interviewing some of these
people uh you know when when matt got to
interview uh
you know seattle greg or that interview
that we just did you know you're like
okay what exactly was was this what was
beatrix choice what was that give me the
give me the rundown give me the
grandparents give me the how did you and
they were like oh you knows i took this
good weed and i had this good weed and
then there was this buddy over here that
i made from new york and we mixed those
all together and we called it that
because it was a funny thing
and you're like well
that's where that trail ends yeah um you
know you're not gonna get the specifics
of some of the stuff and not there's
this huge desire to know that
um but a lot of the lineage i mean we
should be blessed that we know what we
know
and new information still bubbles up
um you know and stuff like that so and
you know what's funny like i've never
remembered the disclaimer to run that at
the beginning but i want to go ahead and
say it here and not so said it a few
times in the middle of comments and
stuff but the history we're bringing you
is is the best that we know it currently
things change all the time people come
out of the word works that are actually
honest you know with some of these old
lines and can and enlighten us on some
of the stuff so when you guys are
watching these episodes and stuff
do your own research go out there kick
kick dirt if we're wrong let us know you
know yeah i mean we're trying to bring
you the best information as we know it
you're not catching me in anything if
you're like you're totally wrong and i
can prove it yeah great
i would love to hear something that
clarifies something some of this stuff
is our best guess yeah usually when we
present information we try to get it
corroborated from different aspects of
things
uh that was one of the really important
parts
actually of the interview that we just
did was there's kind of been this battle
between sam and neville over exactly
what happened
and then getting uh corel's you know
opinion on what he got from
from sam as well
uh and the time frame that he got it in
you start getting little pieces that add
in and it backs up one story doesn't
mean it's totally right
but
you know that's that's what you do with
evidence is you're trying to gather up
evidence and give your best guess
yeah you know sometimes people disagree
what do you do when when you know three
people are involved in the making of
something and two of them don't agree
with the other one yeah
a lot of times people try to fix like
well which person do i think lies less
or lies about what or maybe their memory
is just different
you know i mean that could be it too i
mean people like oh you said something
wrong it's a lie it's not a lie
sometimes it's a lie but sometimes it's
just people have different memories of
the same thing yeah um you know so and a
lot of this stuff
you know uh we had a big you know we had
a big chat with uh with caleb um about
breeding and goals and stuff like that
and we chatted about how difficult it is
to actually breed and you know one of
the things that's so crazy about bag
seeds or accidental pollinations
is
sometimes they're better than some
humans best effort
you know uh and that's really humbling
um you know neville said that all the
f1s he made of hayes he liked more than
all the poly hybrids he made yeah he
kept trying to get stuff that was as
good or better and he kept failing
you know and so a lot of stuff
you know some of the i think some of the
reason why some of these 90 cuts still
rule the game like
sour diesels and and cushes and some of
these a lot of these old cuts that are
still blended into things is because
they were just like two raw things that
weren't like each other accidentally
combined
yeah and that's one of the real things
in breeding that makes a big difference
is if you can cross things that are
really dissimilar to each other you tend
to get better results
so it's a hard time to sit there and be
like oh i'm going to take
you know cushman's and i'm going to
cross it by cherry pie by kush
you know or something there's like it's
it's pretty similar
you know neville found that a lot of the
pure afghans didn't like each other
at all yeah you know
you you know so you take you take two
totally different random things from two
different gene pools
and that's kind of why like i am i'm a
90s guy uh i've all i've said a bunch of
times that i think the 90s is my
favorite area era of weed
and um
you know the reason why i think that
is that that was sort of the first poly
hybrid era
right most of the things before that
were like simple crosses
and then people started taking simple
cross 2 f1s and crossing them together
and a lot of times that raw work
was really good
you know so the ak-47 the the bubble gum
the cali mist the western winds a bunch
of stuff neville was doing the sour
diesel
and the other thing about it is is
because weed was so good weed was so
rare if it was good at all sold
yeah right so the best way to keep a
bunch of diverse weed alive is if it all
sells super easy
the worst thing one of the worst things
that's happened to cannabis
is these this named this name strain
game where these different waves of
purples or sours or cushes or cookies or
skittles or whatever i've said it a
bunch of times before but
um every time that's the only thing
that's easy to sell and get top dollar
a whole bunch of diversity is just going
to get put by the wayside
because people
people are like this is hard to sell
this isn't hard to sell well in the 90s
if it was good bud it was easy to sell
yeah which meant that every kind of good
bud imaginable survived
does it all work
right
and i think that's really important for
people to understand is that like you
know if you want all this diversity to
survive you have to support it
right yeah i mean it's a it's a customer
driven market and i don't i think
that that's very little understood i
mean i talked about that with my buddy
manic quite a bit um the other day it's
a very customer driven market and what
the customer wants is
you know they want uh the new the shiny
uh what's hype what's you know they want
variety so they can select from a pack
and that really is
the opposite of what breeding brings you
know like your brain brings uniformity
working lines you know
there's a thousand reasons why it's a
customer driven market and if things are
ever to change there has to be that that
want from the uh community
to allow people to work lines for six
you know five six years to actually work
a line and not
and because it's not hype it won't sell
you know it's it's a hard it's a it's a
catch-22
yeah and i mean there's you know there's
i mean it's kind of funny in a sense but
i mean i i know we know people that one
of the ways that they got a bunch of old
strains that they have
is they had five or six rare hype cuts
and they would find old growers that had
something that they were really excited
about this guy was like oh my god i'm
having a hard time selling my herb
you know and they'd be like well you
know i can give you this blue cookies
and you'll get top dollar and they've
been so pumped
you know to get it you know and and
because people
i mean you know the name of the game uh
you got to survive yeah you've got to
find something that moves you got to
find something that unless you're
growing strictly on a personal basis and
there's zero financial incentive in it
at all
um you have to give customers what they
want and
one of the things that you know we're
not going to talk about reading very
much on this episode you know but
one of the aspects is like for
diversity's sake is that it's hard to
grow things and to take a risk
um when the public might not like it
very much yeah which is why right now
people are like okay well how many
different ways can i cross skittles
cookies and kush and find something new
yeah the problem is is that since that's
been done
like crazy for the last 10 or 12 or 14
years or whatever
people keep hoping that they're gonna
try slightly different variations of the
same cuts combined and pop something
massively new and exciting yeah you know
but they're really not and now
everything looks like gelato
because i mean it's just but for that
thing too it's like
it's not it's just there's only so many
things you're going to get out of the
same combinations of traits
and if you keep going from bad seed to
bags lead to bad seed to backseat you're
selecting in a single direction usually
you're selecting a single direction or a
narrowing gene pool regardless and the
the more it goes to that the more you're
going to see things look all the same
have similar chirps similar high
um
so
oh man
uh
so now we have a new top question
uh i don't know if we want to do this
let's head into some questions there's a
bunch of good questions yeah so the top
one right now
um is
i know natsos talked briefly about his
headband cuts but here's my question
which headband of his cuts did csi use
for his femme crosses with the d and the
tk
if i could talk a little bit about the
different cuts of headband he has and
how long he's had each one a little
background on where each cut came from
and finally which one of those cuts was
used in the two crosses by csi
uh
okay so apparently those have gotten
real popular
which is nice
um
so
uh at this point um
csi is way more prolific than i am in
terms of accessible stuff to the public
so i gave him what i call my la cut
uh which i've talked about before i got
that cut in the very early 2000s
um i mandelbrot was uh was trying to
change what he was up to and was
thinking about starting a seed company
and starting breeding and so i gave him
a whole bunch of my super dog crosses
uh i gave him my sour diesel i gave him
my super skunk and a couple other cuts
um there's been some rumors i gave him
the maui or the mendo p or the chem dog
i didn't
um
and uh and he gave me
uh the la cut which is the headband uh
so that was the first headband cut i saw
maybe explain a little bit of the reason
why white has two names in your group
because it's caused a lot of confusion
in the head yeah it's a so it's a it's
basically like
it's a terror it's it's a terrible
situation
there's uh
there's two names so when i got it you
have to realize when i got it in one
okay
um or so
uh
the kush craze had not hit yet yeah
nobody really had kush uh we have a
friend that had it yeah um there was a
few houses in la that were running it
shout out to resin long yeah there was
maybe there was there were there was
there was a few crews in la that had it
uh there was a few places in florida
that had it uh nobody really knew about
it the craze hadn't hit yet that was
still four or five years away really
uh when would you say you're from
southern california matt when would you
say like the
the kush craze really hit the rage came
like 2006 2007 2008 it was in
everybody's hands by like 2008 people
started collecting rare rare og cuts so
so you got to realize when i got this
cut it was la cush
yeah
okay which now i mean i can't tell you
how many times people have been like bro
that's not kosher if you want me to show
you what real kush is like yeah you know
but you have to realize is that like in
oh you know one issue or whatever like
nobody really see cush hadn't snuck out
yeah there was like a couple people that
had it you know it was still super
tightly held and so
and i was like well what is this and
he's like it's a headband fino
and if you go look i have screen shots
and stuff you know uh mandelbrot wrote
some uh some uh essays and stuff for
humboldt seed organization and some
other stuff and he always talks about
l.a kush and then in parentheses he puts
headband
okay
who named headband headband is unknown
unknown totally exactly what's in
headband is unknown
and i tend to believe it's a chem dog
super skunk hybrid of some type
i can't say that's all that's in it but
it has so many similarities it's a
diesel
it's not exactly a diesel uh but it's a
diesel family that's what it looks like
to me
um you know we used to sell it as sour
for the longest time uh no one ever
called me out and said it wasn't sour
in fact when uh when mean gene got it
uh in mine in my community uh way back
when and he used it as the final stage
in making his root beer which has become
world famous in the last little bit all
the rage uh he got it is sour
uh and because some people would just
call it that because that's what the
buyers wanted um
and so
um you know when he lost it he kept
trying to get sours and none of the
sours he got were it because it wasn't
it you know he didn't even realize what
cut it was until a while ago i showed it
to him and i cracked him a jar and he
was like oh my god this is it
this is the cut you know
so
um so basically what it boils down to is
that
there's two names for it l.a cushion
headband
la cush is vastly confusing because of
the kush craze that hit and the fact
that there's like 58 different cush cuts
that came out of southern california
within five or six years
and the headband most people don't have
it so they confuse it with lumpa
headband they confuse it with the bay
area headband they want to know well is
it different than
the
um
oh god what are some of the other names
matt well the 56 i mean
you know there's all these different
names and they all get confusing they
all have crazy lineage so
then i just called the la
for like it's what i put on all the tags
on it for lack of a better way to put it
um but
you know back then it was by far the
first headband i'd seen
and uh i didn't see kush until i believe
the first time i actually got a plant of
og i got the flow rider
in 0 4ish
so it was years before i saw
uh anything that became known as cush
yeah right
um
so that's that's the name the next
headband cut i saw some people call the
56 day it takes longer than that
the story is is not the greatest i don't
really like to tell it but basically
huh you don't need to tell him well but
basically let's put it real simple there
was some violence in the cush crew down
in southern california some people
took this cut and fled to the bay they
were
hiding out in the bay and they didn't
want any drama to follow them
so they had this cut but they didn't and
they wanted to grow it but they didn't
want to call it that and so
they uh
they decided to name it the headband
to throw people off the trail yeah and
then at some point a few years after
that maybe it was oh five-ish or
something like that they gave out a
mislabeled trade they they were selling
a tray of cuts to a buddy and they gave
him a tray of this
headband cut
uh instead of uh instead of the other
one and it slipped out so
if you see there's a there's a
uh old friend of mine who uh runs a lot
of chem strains uh he goes by i see you
know iccic collective
on instagram um the headband cut that he
runs is that cut
um mr bob hemphill uh got that cut
around that same time from that same
group uh that's the headband cut that he
has or the mad elite has really yeah
yeah matt elite i mean i'm just saying
like different different people see me
running headbands and and i i'll mention
this because we are going to release a
headband blue bonnet through breeder
syndicate so if people are looking out
for that that's going to be the 56
headband now in our crew
it's we have headband by not so we
always call that natto's headband and
then we have the 56
headband that i think most of us refer
to as headband had been yeah so so that
that came out i got it i got it in about
06.
it's very cush like uh it's one of the
most potent cuts i hold um it's a really
really great cut and you're talking
about the 56 correct the 56 i mean
actually to be honest both cuts i would
put both the la and the 56 in my
top five potency of things i mean
they're really good yeah they're really
really both
high quality strengths but
whatever the headband the 56 was called
before i don't know
but it's not a headband it was renamed a
headband to literally throw off the
trail
of whatever it actually is but
to clarify we don't know who named
headband so it could have been the first
use of the name headband
no because i got the la cut in one and
he said it was a headband fino that's
right um and i don't think they renamed
it until the mid to that like 2004 or
five or six or something
that's interesting um because i don't it
didn't slip out in the bay until
around that i mean you could ask your
buddy matt elite when he got it but yeah
but there's a crew there's a crew um
that got it in that same general time
it's a super nice cut
the other famous one
is the lumpa
um which is an og
which isn't which is another like push
type
yeah he's pretty sensitive about it you
know but it seems like it popped up on
the forums and the first place we can
trace back him mentioning it is about oh
wait late 0809
yep um so the la it predates that by
about eight years
um it predates the 56 by about four or
five years as far as having the headband
name
um you know there's other things thrown
out like day wrecker and stuff like that
i have no idea we can't trace the day
record lineage very far it's very hard i
can't trace it um but you know to answer
to final the guy's question
um the la
uh i gave to csi specifically because i
wanted my main goal with breeding is to
get better weed into people's hands
uh and i knew he would throw it in
various rooms and release hybrids of it
and i believe the first two hybrids he's
released of it are the tk and the d md
yeah um uh
d tk and la are some of my favorite
things
uh so i have high hopes that those
things will combine well i especially
have high hopes for the d which
uh for a variety of reasons
um but that's the headband cut that's
the story of the three main ones
um there's some guys in new york that
say they have a different one there's
some other people that say they have
this or that headband is absolutely one
of the most mysterious names in cannabis
lineage is a pain in the ass who named
it is a pain in the ass
um i'm not saying that i have the first
one but i have the first one that i
encountered yeah that does seem
encountered it does seem like those
other two popped up years after
um for lack of a lack of a better term
yeah uh
you know so
i don't know there's another question
that got a bunch of votes whose durbin
poison is the official version mel or
sam well
uh
so
i can answer that also when carell
stated the durbin was imported wouldn't
that make dp comparable to mexican brick
uh yeah so
basically you know we chatted about this
at the end of the last interview
but mel frank in either 1978 or 79 he
gave uh sam skunk man both the afghani
one and the durbin poison that he had
and sam traded him some sativas
uh
sam then later on in in 84 85 when he
went to amsterdam he brought mel frank's
uh version of durban poison to amsterdam
um mel frank had some terrible accidents
and he lost i believe all of his
original seed collection sometime in 83
or 84 as well
so
um we thought for a long time that mel
frank's version was the only durbin
poison
uh in holland and therefore everybody's
urban poison must be a derivative of
what sam brought from mel
uh but then in the corel interview we
find out that that was totally wrong
and
there was an actual coffee shop named
durbin poison that sold south african
wheat and they got all their durbin
poison from bag seed that they bought
from the coffee shop yeah so that really
widens the durvin poison gene pool
um
you know
and where people got things so if people
got durbin poison from sssc
it was probably it was from bag seed
if they got it from
um neville it was probably mel's version
and it's hard to say
other other seed banks carried uh durbin
poison other than those two and we don't
really know right at this particular
moment what their sourcing was so
um i don't know if there's an official
durbin poison
um and the version that mel is selling
now or that now mel is selling but maybe
it's todd or somebody like that is
selling um it's all claimed to be
original or whatever but i mean mel said
that he lost his collection in the 80s
early 80s so it would have to be stuff
that they got back from amsterdam from
someone at some point yeah maybe it was
from sam skunk man maybe it's
reproduction sam who knows and sold back
to todd or somebody else or
uh that kind of thing
uh who made bluedream
don't know so
the the running theory is bluegrass
seeds blue hen
which was the very
first super silver haze
blueberry cross and the sd cut that we
were all growing back in the day the
very first iteration of blue dream
uh
was very much a super silver haze dj
blueberry so that's that's
the most conclusive i've seen plus the
old photo in the can of bible is a
picture of the blue dream sc cut under
blue hen and jason king got a lot of
stuff right about that part
yeah so i mean i've heard rumors you
know um it's it's kind of hard to say
yeah um it's nothing conclusive it's a
great cut
i mean it got it people laugh about it
but when it's right you know when it's
grown right and it's not you know people
laugh at it because there was so many
people it got so big so many people grew
seven to ten pound blue dreams and
flooded the market with huge blue dream
stuff
you know if you grow it and it only
gives you four or five six ounces it's
pretty dank and and there was also the
mass influx of when blue dream got
popular uh spanish seed banks
kicking out a bunch of blueberry haze
crosses labeled blue dream and
us
u.s companies sold blue dream seats in
mass which really really ruined the
market for that actual cut now that cut
is almost impossible to find i see lots
of stuff that looks like it but doesn't
smell like anymore so there was another
were you guys able to find out any more
info about the haze a and c females
uh not really except for
there is a group of
haze collectors in holland that have
various ones have various old hybrids
and cuts
and
they call them different things
uh they have some different names to
them uh in the first part of the
interview with matt when he said he had
ac my job i hit the floor because i
thought he had the mail yeah we used all
famously and that was confirmation that
that that he had it he was going to use
it and all this different stuff and that
was pretty amazing now it turns out that
they're two different females
um that needs some more research i don't
think matt and i right now can speak
definitively to exactly what those are
yeah but the hope
would be that there's some kind of
hybrid that we didn't realize existed
uh that would be that would be the best
um
um someone was asking about sacred seeds
i did and i i mentioned this earlier
when someone asked if we were going to
have sam on i reached out i made an
offer for him to come on the podcast
just to talk about history no bias um he
wasn't very receptive but hopefully in
the future he changes his mind because
he's a very important character in all
this
yeah so um what exactly makes a real
skunk
um
so i would say two things one obviously
if if anything that comes out that
smells extremely skunky
you could call skunk and two
would be
um that's the name that that rob and
sam gave to this hybrid hybrid of
colombian mexican and afghani
um and so all the finos that come out of
that would be real skunk
the ones that smell like skunk the ones
that smell like grape the one that smell
like citrus i always i oh i never call
it skunk i only call it skunk one just
to
to never divide the two or they never
disinfect the two you know but it just
goes to show that you know you can
you know you can have something in a
strain that's quite predominant for a
while and you can breed away from it and
you can get other expressions to pop up
and then those expressions that were
once at once very common not
now you can't find them again
is anyone working with an elite super
silver haze old sog that's my favorite
personally but yeah there's good super
silver aces out there his is one that's
been passed around a long time on like
tanaka mana and other places and it's my
personal favorite it had this willy
wonka factor where when you inhale it
it's cherry and you excel it's cheese it
is really unique that way very skunk
bunny in that sense it's faster
flowering than most phases
much more manageable than most hazes i
like it what about you
um
you know i
i like haze i like sativas in general i
like i'm a peculiar kind of person i
like i like different expressions of
stuff you know i mean it's kind of like
favorite food even if you have your top
three or four favorite foods you
certainly don't want to eat them every
day um i have i i have weeds that i
would like to smoke regularly um and
then i have stuff that i would like to
like you know palette cleansing if you
will that i like to have around
uh i'll say things like even most
strains like
like for instance you know the la is one
of my favorite cuts if you smoke it
every day you get ripped
if you go a few months without smoking
it and then you smoke a fast fresh batch
it does something different to you
so there's something about terpenes and
cannabinoid content and building up
tolerances and stuff
um that you know i think variety is the
spice of life
you know
um and i like unique highs
i like sativa highs i like indica highs
i like the blends it just has to be
potent and do something to me that i
enjoy
you know yeah
there's some more questions top three
strains the dead tour disseminated it's
impossible
uh yeah like it was it was literally an
open-air weed market people would bring
all kinds of strains from all kinds of
walks of life to be sold in small
amounts to other hippies at campgrounds
and on the lot and stuff like that so
i mean my top three might just be the
people that i knew
uh you could probably ask a bunch of old
dead heads and stuff and they might have
all kinds of different stories of what
their top three was
um
you know uh
so
you know i what which headband is the
dog head from skunk va
i believe i'd have to ask him we'd have
to check to be sure i believe his is the
56th day i'm pretty sure but we have to
ask yeah i'd have to i'd have to ask to
be so it's definitely not the l.a
he does not have that one i believe
um him like i said i see collective and
and him a long time ago they've known
each other a long time i believe in that
little circle in our little circle
that's the one that got passed around
um
so jj jj said lumpa's headband is fake
um you know i know i don't know what to
say about that one except for
um
you know we think that uh the lumpus
headband is a very potent uh cush pino
i think that's the fairest
and and i will i can quote lumpa i mean
we were very good friends for a long
time he said that's just a [ __ ] og
like he even said it himself that's just
a [ __ ] og that's it so you know i
mean he's i mean i i'm not i you know
the lump of headband is a good cut yeah
it's it's
[ __ ] it's enjoyable smoke yeah um it
certainly came out later than the other
headband cuts he's pretty protective of
the name
you know um because he put his name on
it or whatever but it's a super nice cut
you know um but it is one of the later
headbands to pop up on the scene yeah um
speaking of neville and nl5 thoughts on
the basic five that is the co-parent
with skunk one and the m-39 skunk one by
basic five from
[Music]
you know that one's kind of tough um you
know we we asked one little question
about it i didn't i you know i didn't
get the clearest answer uh i do think
that they're probably the same i can't
say for sure
um
you know it's it's not clear
yeah unless unless he actually says like
yeah for sure this was it you may not
remember you know yeah it's not it's at
this particular time it's not clear i
mean that's really all i can say about
it it does seem it does seem like you're
right in the sense that you can look at
those two things and be like oh those
seem like they're similar or whatever
um but there's not uh there's not
there's not any verification you know or
of anything like that you know so
uh i don't know what to say
about that
anymore so that was uh
um
you know
that was uh
i don't know that was all the questions
but yeah do some housekeeping for a
minute and then we'll chat about some
different stuff
[Music]
if there's a legend you guys want to
come on the show i mean there's there's
a lot of these old dudes out there and i
mean we're not really bringing people on
that are like blood tenders and and and
stuff like that that are more common era
we're trying to keep this to the history
of strains you know what i mean like
that's what we love that's what we nerd
out on but if you know someone that
you'd be really into give them a shout
reach out to them tell them hey there's
this podcast you know you might be into
it send it to him yeah i mean we have
some different ideas and stuff like that
it's going to be a pretty wide-ranging
podcast we started with the the 80s just
because that's kind of like the
beginning of what most people are
familiar with
we want to do some other work we have
some pretty cool stuff planned some of
it takes a certain amount of research
and making sure that the proper people
have time we're going to try to be
bringing on
you know one of the things that's going
on with other podcasts is that they tend
to be interviews of current people
selling seeds uh which is great to get a
view into the mind of that person and an
idea of what their desires and what
their ideas are
it seemed like it was underserved and
there could be a lot of interest in the
history of what's going on right now uh
and how we got here and so
there's going to be a con a bunch of
history there's going to be some
interviews there's going to be some
different aspects of things
not just getting his only chance only
fans channel up uh oh my goodness so
yeah there's there's all kinds of
different things going on so
yeah i mean people are you know breed
like breeders steve bodie you know
people were raging about uh getting
caleb on we got him on uh we have a
bunch of network of friends and
different things like that
um you know it's all about their
availability and them fitting into the
show i mean you you know we actually
didn't interview caleb we just brought
him on to
talk about something that's close to his
heart which is breeding goals um so we
might have some people on
that we're not even really interviewing
them per se we're just adding their
voice to the larger group uh discussion
you know so
uh yeah we have you know archive you
know there's various people that have
reached out um we're going to fit them
all in i mean we want to keep we want to
keep uh doing all that stuff
uh staten island i don't know i'll have
to ask him i just talked to him last
week we'll see uh we'll see what people
say some of them are shy
some of them are busy some of them we
might want to just wait and fit in you
know breeder steve would be a good
person to bring on when we want to talk
about the switzerland era sure of things
because he was one of the big people in
the swiss era along with shanti and some
others or blueberry or any number yeah
or any number of different things so
we're not just trying to bring people on
to talk about their history per se if we
can talk about their history and combine
it with some other era that's pertinent
to them uh that makes sense too
so
uh be sure to keep your eyes out for the
notification emails we're still doing
crowdcast right now however we are
planning on switching over to twitch um
so if you have a twitch account make
sure if you don't have one go make one
very soon we're gonna be switching over
to twitch and it's gonna be a little bit
different format um on twitch i can
actually put like pictures up on the
screen as opposed to trying to hold them
up and like shakily show you
um so yeah but but for the moment we're
going to keep doing crowdcast and make
sure that you're registered on crowdcast
make sure you follow the podcast if you
want the notification
uh let's see what else we've got well
then i'll throw a couple things in here
i'll throw a plug we have a breeder
syndicate discord
that we matt and i and uh actually quite
a few of our close friends contribute to
all the time so if you want to talk
about things at length you can always
hit us up on there um
i just started doing documentaries about
weed different weed documentaries you
know we can show
cool movies we post content we post old
pictures we post old articles seed bank
stuff all that different types of stuff
uh you know yeah i do look like i'm
sitting in a pew i'm traveling right now
so i'm hearing it's really hot i'm in
this really odd chair that's not my
style but this is what i have to do in
order to get to it but yeah the breeder
syndicate there's an email uh for me now
set up there that we set up this week so
people want to ask questions
um your your questions could turn into a
whole episode frankly uh you know you
never know um there's a lot of stuff
that's you know we want to bring stuff
that's people um you know about people's
interests um but there's a there's a
bunch of cool stuff going on on the
breeders syndicate discord we chat on
there all the time um one of the things
that matt and i are doing is we kind of
wing it on this show a little bit but
the reason why we can wing it is because
this is our hobby
you know weed history learning all this
different aspect trying to like find
truths amongst this this is my life
partner so this is uh this is what we
chat about all the time so really this
is just like matt and i have been doing
this with a big group of friends for
years yeah and all of a sudden we just
turned on the camera and decided to
bring other people in
is kind of is really kind of the focus
of it and so some of this stuff is
pretty well worn paths for us
so
uh it's really not you know the the
financial aspect of it is
i mean it's relevant in the sense that
you need finances to exist yeah you
might not know but the speakeasy crew
behind this they do a ton of time of
editing and a bunch of work and a bunch
of leveling and a bunch of all this
stuff to bring this to you they're kind
enough to host this thing
so you know um purchasing seeds from
them purchasing some merch from them
uh contributing get your breeders to get
merch we got merc you know
joining
joining the joining the breeder
syndicate uh it costs about the cost of
a latte a month yeah so it's not an
enormous situation out there you know so
and in the very near future there is
going to be major discounts for seed
purchases on speakeasy if you're a part
of their patreon and our patreon which
would cost you 10 bucks a month but it's
it's insane like the amount of savings
that they're talking about doing is
pretty crazy um yeah so we get along
with we get along with you know
obviously speakeasy are our friends
they're hosting our thing they're
bringing it to people they put a bunch
of time and energy
into having us talk about a bunch of
weed nerd stuff so
um you know certainly if you want to
support them or buy seeds from them or
merchandise or get on here and chat
that that helps things so
all these lives we do these lives twice
a month and then we turn them into
podcasts they're not the only podcasts
we put out obviously but we're going to
keep this kind of stuff going you know
so if you're interested in this we're
going to keep rolling out we're going to
try to bring every relevant bit of
history over time to the forefront um
some of it takes a while to develop so
it sounds confident and we know what
we're talking about
and we can get the people that we'd like
to bring on with us on the site um but
bear with us
and uh you know uh thank you all for
listening as always we still got more to
do dude
you know well then there you go
keep going okay so we got uh i mentioned
the c drop we're gonna have a breeder
syndicate c drop with a 56 head day
headband uh blue bonnet it's going to be
me and natto's first little
adventure together in that sense um also
one thing i never mentioned and it's
super important it helps us out a lot it
helps
the podcast grow please go rate it on on
whatever platform you're watching this
on whether it's uh uh
i don't know stitcher itunes google
podcast any of it we're gonna throw up a
rating and if you don't like it tell us
what you don't [ __ ] like that tell
them i'm [ __ ] ugly whatever just
interacting interacting is awesome so
please go rate it and uh yeah that's it
yeah certainly rate it um certainly if
you want to send links if you listen to
the podcast on spotify or on apple or
iphones or whatever you know um
share it with friends you know share it
with people you think might be
interested in with it um one of our
the main goal for this is education yeah
we really want to get some of this
history out there we only want to spark
conversations amongst people we really
want to get interest in like how we all
got here going um that's the coolest
part about it for me honestly and that's
why i do it this is a total hobby you
know
so i appreciate everyone that listens it
takes a time out of you know their
friday night to chat with us
and go through it so really appreciate
all that you know yeah and and for those
of you posting old memorabilia now like
the stuff you got thank you like
anybody who's digging up all this stuff
that we've never seen like there's a lot
of stuff maybe you only have that last
issue of that magazine so so mad props
to everyone who's joining in on that on
the history search adding to the
conversation all that i love it man keep
it going
and just because you think that hit some
common history might be common to your
crew it might be rare or it might be a
puzzle piece that fits into other things
that we already know that might be a
real light bulb
so
reach out you know um and all that all
the time we're we're not we're not
elitist on any level um it's
crowdsourcing
yeah uh information and trying to verify
it and trying to get it out there to
people
all right
well it's been fun fellas
enjoy everybody's friday night peace
peace
[Music]
you