[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
live here i'm matthew owner of riot
seeds i'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
we should talk about haze sure
okay let me let me flip this around so
it's not gonna be my face it's gonna be
the haze poster and i'll try to get it
so it's um
uh nice and bright and illuminated and
clear so let's see if that works let's
see
i'm gonna aim this little light thing
down more there we go
all right
so here we start the original haze
poster now this is
my pride and joy
willing it to not so
this was the cosmic also referred to as
a cosmic boogie poster from 1976.
um
uh rl
and
crk
supposedly and the hayes brothers are
all
uh
revolve around this so talk about some
names
there you are okay
i mean where do you want to start with
it
uh let's start let's start with what
what do you think hayes c
jesse do you want to start with hayes
males do you want to start with the
original breeding of haze so like
probably like the
the the most realistic starting point
is
the mid-80s
right yep that's probably so
you know there's all this stuff about
haze and obviously haze existed in
california in the 70s
uh
possibly late 60s
and there's not a lot of excellent
sourcing
on
that aspect of hayes there's a few
people
that uh
that know a bit and they don't really
agree
necessarily so
kind of what happened is it seems like
it was a you know if you believe sam
skunk man um it was a colombian by
colombian cross
uh and it seems like because people
didn't understand breeding very well
back then
the first initial crosses and hybrids
they made
over the years were the best and you if
you look at his poster right there you
could see silver haze on one side you
could see magenta gold on another
you could see different things these are
all
named phenos that would pop up out of
their seed line
right but if you think back to the early
70s people's idea of breeding was pretty
rudimentary
and so um
you know it went through some processes
people didn't really know what they were
doing
um
and it's kind of like a mystery exactly
who the what the wh
why and where in the 70s
and then the story picks up
when sam skunk man got himself into some
trouble
in america a couple of times and it
appears that he took a bunch of seeds of
skunk
and uh
haze and then he gathered up a bunch of
other breeders work like mel mel frank
and some other people stuff and he went
to amsterdam
and when he went to amsterdam he ended
up uh hooking up with
a number of folks one of them was
neville and this is where
uh this is where the story diverges
um so if you believe neville's side of
the story
um
neville bought a bunch of very old seed
from sam
is dated from the late 60s to the early
70s
and
he
he barely got any of them to pop
if you believe sam's side of the story
uh he sold neville the exact same seed
that he sold everybody else
was reproductions that he made in
in amsterdam after he landed there
and he claims that neville never got
anything special
um there's a lot more to it than that
the neville story has never really
changed the sam story has certainly
changed from the various forums like
overgrow and cannabis world to
uh
um what's the one that came after that
after what
after cannabis world and overgrow um the
various forums sam is
i don't think his story has stayed
consistent over time
um he's claimed to have given neville
only clones he's claimed to have given
him old seed new seed this that whatever
but regardless of all that uh neville
claims he sprouted he tried to sprout a
bunch most of them failed i see mag
there you go
um
i see mag and so
um after uh
after after neville tried to pop a bunch
of them
and almost none of them came up
and he got a girl that he thought was a
piece of [ __ ]
uh and he grew it and he didn't realize
it was any good until after he'd already
killed it and he ended up with two boys
which everybody knows as a and c
um
so
that's where the story gets famous
because the vast majority of what people
know is haze
and the whole haze story
comes from those those two dads for lack
of a better term right
so
uh
everything that neville commercially
sold
nl5 haze
silver haze all that type of stuff that
was all haze c
right
um and he had haze a
he made a ton of crosses in 88 and 89
with haze a
um and then one of his workers didn't
keep a dad and bloomed everything on his
last main seed run
and so he had a bunch of seed and he had
a bunch of hybrids but he never sold
commercial stock of it
right
um and so
you know sam
sold a bunch of his haze seed he used to
be able to buy
from the flying dutchman
um
and you i believe he used to be able to
buy it from positronics too um used to
be able to buy sam's open pollination
haze
uh the different thing is that nobody
seems to have ever found jack [ __ ] out
of sam's haze lines
and
the uh the stuff that he gave neville
that seems to be where all the quality
came from
so
um
you know you're talking about two dudes
who don't get along
don't see eye to eye
didn't like each other
and they both had very different
versions of what happened in the mid 80s
uh
in a dope field that they had
so it becomes sort of a mission of like
who do you choose to believe
and what part of their story do you
choose to believe
uh
but what's undoubtable
is that all the [ __ ] that people know
about the pif the church the cuban black
haze
the a5 the c5
super silver haze mango
all those different the soma work
all that different stuff it all came
from hybrids that neville made
right
uh that that's undisputable you know it
all came from them and so
uh
you know it um
[Music]
you know like like a lot of things in
cannabis
um
uh people involved aren't the most
honest folk
and
no matter what era you're in
uh you know we seem to attract some
shady hustling and some lying and some
fibbing and some like polishing of your
story and all that other stuff so
um
it uh i don't know you know we uh
i you know
king cultivars i tend to believe
neville's story
mostly because
um
[Music]
all this fire came out of neville's
lines
and not very much fire came out of sam's
that you can really you can really
ascertain any bunch
i think northern lights five haze
probably has more elite cuts named after
it that still exists that are 25 to 30
years old than any other line that's
ever been made by anybody
uh yeah that's the goat it's the [ __ ]
goat it really it really is you know i
mean they're both on the atlantic you
know on the usa side and on the european
side it seems like from 88 to 95
people found white hot fire in that line
it's probably the most successful
cannabis hybrid of all time
uh
you know um whether he got lucky
whether he you know i mean all that you
can you know but that f1
was um you know it's got rare power and
people to this day honestly the reason
why on the west coast people don't like
haze is because the haze they know is
jack or super silver haze or some of the
poly hybrids
all of the best f1s have been hoarded
forever
uh they were hoarded in europe
uh in america the cubans and the
dominicans hoarded the [ __ ] out of their
cuts
and didn't allow it to get spread out
and so it's kind of amazing actually for
as long as it's been out most of the
other elites have leaked
and snuck out and a lot of people have
gotten a hold of them
and
you really haven't been able to about
the other stuff
you know i mean when you really think
about it right like the a5 and the c5
are in america right now uh people have
them
um those those things were found in 88
and 89
and i don't think they came to america
until a couple years ago
right i mean they were literally on
lockdown for something like 30 years
you could go to amsterdam i used to you
know i used to be able to smoke them
when i went to amsterdam they were a
staple in amsterdam coffee shops they're
a staple of cannabis breeding um but
it's the thing is is to be perfectly
honest
most of the people that think they know
hayes don't because they never got to
smoke the real deal
yeah
i mean that's just uh that's just really
the the truth uh how does mr nice fit
into the haze story
that's a little bit longer
convo but
the basic story is
um
man it's kind of a long story
the super short version
neville got busted during operation
green merchant and ended up in [ __ ]
jail
and ben and alan drunkers had money and
were willing to buy him out but they
weren't willing to buy him out unless he
gave them unless he sold them his
[ __ ] company
so in order to get his freedom and to
get out of the situation he's in he had
to sell sea bank
to scentsy seeds
and he ended up being sensei seed's main
breeder
uh one of that ended up being that since
he ended up owning most of his genetics
they trademarked a bunch of his famous
names like super skunk and other stuff
and after four or five years he wasn't
really getting along with ben and allen
drunkers and so he left
uh scentsy seeds and him and shanti
started working together and they bred
together for a few years
and that that
combination breeding
led to the super silver haze the mango
haze and the neville's haze didn't allow
arjun to get any of the seed
any of the
cuttings mom's dads or even grow any of
the flower they provided his coffee
shops with the flowers but
when they worked at greenhouse
um
shanti and neville never allowed arjun
to get a hold of any of the cuts
or any of the moms or dads they provided
him
with the seeds for sale at greenhouse
and they provided him with the flower
to uh
to sell at greenhouse right
does everybody get that
hopefully everybody got that i can hear
it okay so
what happened is is they after after
neville left scentsy
um
him and shanti worked together uh on the
super silver haze
the
mango haze and the neville's haze
project they each had a part of
greenhouse seeds
and they kept arjun out of the loop
by not giving them any cuts or any flour
they just basically gave them flour to
sell in the coffee shop and then they
provided the seeds and the packaging to
sell through the seed company and then
eventually they didn't like the deal
with arjun and so shanti left
and took the cuts and went to
switzerland
and started mr nice seeds
so that's how mr nice seeds
um and then matt can confirm this but
neville sold his seed bank era 80s era
seed collection
to shanti for a chunk of money when
neville was broke
and so shanti
um
shanti has
or had at some point
a bunch of neville's breeding work as
well as a bunch of neville's old seed
yes if that makes sense so that's kind
of how
um you know there's a lot of people that
believe in shanti there's a bunch of
people that think he's full of [ __ ]
which is pretty common for the weed
industry
um but he legitimately worked with
neville and he legitimately had access
to neville's cuts neville's breeding
parents
and a bunch of old 80 seed from neville
for lack of a better way to put it
yeah and i think he's he's probably the
main source for a lot of neville stuff
today that's more reliable one of the
most reliable sources for neville's
work today i would say
yeah and i mean you know so i mean
despite his uh
you know like but there's the thing is
is about shanti is that
there's not really a way to
cross-reference whether he has it or not
yeah no take his word for it all of it
right because
we're not in his mom room we're not in
his dad room
i would assume he's lost some things but
what it's hard to say
yeah he'd never tell you
and you know and on top of that he might
not be lying
you know yeah he might have it's it's
there we don't have any evidence one way
or the other a lot of times what happens
with this [ __ ] is um
you know
people end up believing the grower they
like
yeah yeah no that really is it
and disbelieving the grower they don't
you know
so
yeah
i hope people can hear me i'm not seeing
any more comments scrolling at the
bottom of the page anymore the last
thing i see is
all heart no hype go outside foo
oh wow yeah no i'm still seeing stuff
here i can hear you
can everybody else hear me can they hear
me are they responding that they can
actually appear yeah
yeah you're good sweet
so
um
yeah that's kind of the
that's that's the long short version of
mr nice
um he has legitimate he has more
provenance and access to neville stuff
than almost anybody
and he may still have afghan tea
he might
be you know it's it's been you know when
matt was plugging the uh
the discord server and all that
we have endless debates on what's still
alive and what's dead
so
you know um
it's uh
hard to say
yeah it is hard to say you want to talk
about um pif
piv
yeah
i think that's probably one of the most
questions i get asked the most on here
i mean
it seems like so
you know the
it's kind of shrouded in a little bit of
mystery
but what it seems like is that
there was a guy that bought
um
there was a guy that bought seed from
neville in 1988
nl5 haze
and he was uh grateful he was on
grateful dead tour
and he
found this this final that he gave to
the student florida
um
the the original guy overdosed in 1990
sadly apparently
and um you know
the piff was born
for lack of a better term um it's gotten
a bunch of names some people think it
smells like frankincense that's why the
church thing came out
and it sort of got it's it sort of got
hype in new york
um and as a result of that because there
was a bunch of money in it
um a bunch of other people bought the
exact same seed line from neville and l5
hayes and wanted to find their own pith
their own church their own heights haze
their own block work
um and so that's where
seemingly most of the phenoes come from
almost all the good phenos of nl5 haze
come from 88 to 95
right
that seems like it's neville has
confirmed that sometime in 94 or 95 the
nl5 mother died at scentsy
um and so after that the cross was never
the same
people are asking also about
cuban black haze i don't know if you
want to go over that
cuban black haze is um
it's most likely just another it's just
another pheno of nl5 haze
um yeah if if people want to go over it
things that are likely in l5 haze are
pif
heights haze cuban black haze
the dog [ __ ]
um
you know all those things are nl5 nl5
hazes
and uh in europe a5 c5 there's multiple
copies of each one uh c5 me you know
it's that's neville's notation it meant
that it was haze c crossed to nl5 haze
um a5 means it was the a dad crossed a
nl58 nl5
um so there's a bunch of f1 hybrids that
are famous that float around europe some
of them have crept over here in the last
few years
i saw people talk about you know uh one
of the
one of the old guys that used to work
for neville
um in the 90s uh
yeah
and [ __ ] dog bud no they're not the same
thing no
actually
dog [ __ ] is a sad thing because it
it got named dog [ __ ] in oregon but
before it was in oregon it was from
minneapolis minnesota and its name was
electric bugaloo
much better name which is one of the
coolest names in cannabis in my opinion
um
but for whatever reason it got changed
but it is also
uh old early 90s nl5 haze vino of some
kind
snow bud is an old afghan from florida
um it used to be called skunk 5 in
florida
i actually know the people that drove it
from
florida to oregon where it got renamed
snow bud
like a lot of things back then if you
were in eugene
oregon you called it the eugene snow bud
some people called it organ snow bud
people called it humboldt snow bud
um our buddy csi has had it for 20 plus
years
probably longer he probably got it in
the late 90s i think
um he's made a lot of hybrids with it
um it's an old
i don't know i mean it could be nl it
could be nl5 skunk one it could be any
the earliest name we can find on this
skunk five
and it got it
and it got renamed snow in oregon
and it was a very frosty
low terp
uh old afghan
kind of like the white but better
uh in my opinion
yeah
you know
um it it had low flavor but there were
some times when it tasted amazing
every once in a while you'd hit it out
of the park and it would have really
deep amazing flavor
um a lot of times though it was mild
or like the white i don't think anyone's
ever gotten it to taste good
uh it's kind of just like a
you know it's kind of just like a mild
potent afghan yeah
not everything tastes good
not everything's terpe
want more breeder syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsheets.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
so
you