foreign
[Music]
I just started questioning everything
I'd ever been told
you know by the time by the time I got
high that very first time
when it started to hit me
and I'm like wow
[Music]
[Applause]
I got high
[Music]
hey everyone so this is going to be the
uh trailer that I'm recording for the
episode with Pip it's going to be on at
a different time it's going to be
Tuesday uh January 31st at 5 PM it's a
special
um and it's coinciding with his drop so
be sure to pay attention for that the
Link's gonna be everywhere probably in
the description and other places so be
sure to check that out also don't forget
to like share and subscribe the episode
um we don't pay for advertising we don't
advertise anywhere we don't have
advertisers like we just kind of exist
so anything you do like that helps any
interaction in comments helps
um but liking sharing subscribing share
it on Reddit share it on Twitter all
your social medias with your family
friends bosses sisters mothers
uncles or what have you it all it all
really helps um go check out our merch
at syndicategear.com we have a bunch of
stuff up including the new original hay
shirt which uh was done by our artist
swings based on the poster right right
near yeah it's based on it but not the
exact same thing but
um yeah anyway that's it I just wanted
to to cut in and and put this out there
for the trailer and I hope you all enjoy
this episode it's several years in the
making and it's one of our can
Illuminati buddies uh a car carrying
table or yeah a card carrying tableman
so yeah hope you enjoy
cheers
readers Syndicate update not only is our
merch store up at syndicategear.com but
all episodes will remain free but what
we need from you is interaction if
you're watching the show for your first
time kick back and enjoy it if you like
the show feel free to like it but if
it's your second viewing we ask a gentle
person's agreement that you click the
Subscribe button it costs you nothing
but it helps us tremendously with the
sneaky YouTube algorithm
leaving comments telling not to his
voice lulls you into a trance works as
well we hope you take the time to do
this we try to put out the best possible
shows for you we can and want to build
this community thanks again from all of
us at the Breeders Syndicate family