quick uh a 999 donation from carl
bobby's got a question for you danny and
it's uh has mr sheehan personally seen
enough evidence testimony to be
convinced the uap issue is
extraterrestrial can he say anything
about the most convincing evidence
thanks amazing show thank you carl yeah
absolutely there are two there are two
specific things that have that have
convinced me the most uh one of them was
back in 1977
when i was asked by the congressional
research service science and technology
division
to be special counsel to their their
investigation of the ufo and et
phenomenon at the request of president
carter after he was elected that he was
denied access to this information and by
george h.w bush who was at that time the
director of the central intelligence
agency and president carter
commissioned a major secret study to be
done by the congressional research
service the the science and technology
division i was contacted by marsha smith
who was the director of that project
and asked initially if i could uh get at
the information that was in the vatican
archives because i was legal counsel the
jesuit national headquarters in their
office of social ministry their public
policy office
when that when we were unable to get
that information i was later asked by
marcia to
go and deliver a closed-door three-hour
presentation to the top 50 scientists of
the jet propulsion laboratory the seti
program on the theological implications
of contact with an extraterrestrial
civilization because of my position at
the jesuit headquarters
in that context i asked marsha smith if
we could get at the classified portions
of project blue book uh so i could use
that to prepare this this presentation
that i was asked to make to the top
scientist and setting and it was in that
context that i actually physically got
access to the classified portions of
project blue book and i saw photographs
not just photographs in the sky of some
bright light jiggling around or not even
a
some kind of a craft that looks like you
can kind of doctor it in the sky but
this was a crashed ufo uh saucer there
wasn't any doubt about it that had the
photographs of it i saw several
photographs that had plowed through this
field that was covered with snow was
stuck in the side of an embankment
and it was it was actually being
photographed by us air force personnel
uh in in with cameras and stuff all
around it in the photographs and i was
actually able to trace the markings on
the side on the the the dome part of
this the saucer that were nothing they
were not any kind of uh planetary uh
language at all they were a set of
symbols that were on the side of the uh
the dome of this craft and so i saw that
and so i knew perfectly well that that
was true and i bro i brought it back to
jesuit headquarters and i showed it to
father william j davis who was my jesuit
superior at the at the headquarters of
the jesuit order and he reached down and
slid opened a drawer in his desk and
took out a little manila folder
and handed it to me and i unlatched it
and i pulled it out and it was a little
uh
eight and a half by 11 black and white
glossy photograph of a ufo you know
perfectly clear that it was a ufo and i
said where did you get this and he said
well my sister dodie gave it to me and i
said well where did dodie get it she
said her husband michael gave it to her
he was the air traffic controller up in
uh seattle washington and his best
friend who was a commercial pilot took
this photograph out of the cockpit
window of a ufo that was that was
tracking his plane uh and and he the
pilot didn't want to get in any trouble
about this by reporting it officially so
he said look i'm going to bring it to my
best friend mike who is the air traffic
controller here in seattle
he gave him the copy of the photo and
michael didn't want to get in trouble by
reporting it so he took it and gave it
to dodie his wife and he said here dodie
take this and give it to your brother
he's a priest
right
so billy billability kept us in his desk
and when i showed him what i had found
in the in the art in the project blue
book he showed me that photo so that was
one of the two instances in which i was
convinced that this was real
the second one was at roswell that i had
i had uh must have been 1995 96
something like that
i was in the process of representing dr
john mack at harvard university uh who
was in this well-known confrontation
with the harvard faculty over the fact
that he had published this book called
abductions uh
human contact with aliens
etc and in that context i was invited to
go to the international ufo congress out
in laughlin nevada to do a presentation
to give them an update on how we were
doing in the litigation
uh and so a guy came up out of the
audience uh and said to me mr sheehan i
need to meet with you about something
really important and so i did i met with
him with another fellow and i sat down
with him he said look i think i have
found the photographer who took that
famous photograph of general rainey you
know kneeling down in front of that the
balloon wreckage you know the weather
moon wreckage he said uh and i had
noticed in that that that photograph i
kept saying look at what is that that
raymie has in his hand he's got some
kind of a telegram or something in his
hand and and i had thought about that
many times and when the guy said look i
think i found the photographer that they
i said look it
if you can do that find out if that's
the photographer and see if there's any
chance that he still has the original
negatives of the photographs that he
took that night on july 9th the late
night of the july 8th and early morning
of july 9th in 1947 if he still has them
i know some people we can get some
financing and we can digitize those
negatives and get them blown up and we
can see if we can read that telegram
that raymie has in his hand and it turns
out that he tracked a guy down and it
was the photographer he did have the
negatives we got the negatives digitized
and blown up
and you could read the telegram and we
actually subjected it to to a
computer analysis so it were some of the
places where there were creases in the
in the telegram that you couldn't quite
tell what the letter was in or that we
subjected it to a computer that could
tell whether it you know it was a
consonant or a vowel or whatever it was
and we reconstructed that and it said
you know take the disc to right field
and bring the bodies of the crash
victims and it said that in the telegram
that raymie had in his hand
not thinking that in a thousand years
that anybody would ever be able to read
it and the dumb guy brought it with him
for the and got the photograph taken to
him standing there holding his hand so i
said look at here are the two things
these are the two most convincing pieces
of evidence i can tell you this if i put
that evidence in front of an american
jury
the jury would conclude beyond any
reasonable doubt that the ufos were real
and that that those bodies that were
recovered there in in roswell were from
an extraterrestrial civilization uh so
those are the two pieces of evidence
that i thought personally were the most
convincing for me okay so real quick uh
andy wanted to ask a follow-up question
on something you said and then we've got
a five dollar donation that has a
question for john and i also wanted to
get john's thoughts on whoever's phone's
going off if you could silence it that
would be great no worries either way uh
i know people are busy but real quick
john let's bring you in because i wanted
you i wanted to hear sort of your
rebuttal to the the two pieces of
evidence that danny found
um
you know the most convincing and then
we've also got a a quick question here
for you
well you're muted john so we definitely
know it's not your dings yeah sorry
sorry that was me trying to make sure uh
i i laughed at at rebuttal that you
automatically assumed that i was but
i don't know that's the guess
so you're gonna uh so there's a lot to
unpack there i i'm gonna start with the
latter piece of evidence first and i'm
gonna have to ask for a respectful
reminder on the first part the letter uh
walking into a courtroom with a
uh artificial intelligence uh i would
say filling in the gaps you know to just
kind of quickly summer it
uh danny i've known you a long time so i
mean no disrespect and to say that i
would respectfully disagree with a an
attorney when i'm not an attorney uh
makes me a little uncomfortable but i
think i would respectfully disagree in
the sense that if you showed a jury that
that you had to get a computer to fill
in the blanks uh they would say you'd
have to do better um and and i think
that we would need to
really dissect uh the claims of you know
what it was about roswell but sadly i
think there are so many holes in the
roswell story at this point we've lost
all the witnesses so now we're going on
messi's second third and even
fourth-hand information of he said she
said that's challenging in a courtroom
and and i often often liken
this debate away from roswell but ufos
and uaps as a whole as stepping into a
courtroom and proving your case and i
i've had to do that
uh in foia appeals now hundreds and
hundreds of times i've done 10 000 plus
foias in 25 years appeals i have no idea
to be honest with you how many i've done
uh it's definitely not thousands though
uh just just simply because
it took me years to realize that the
appeal process actually does work and i
always recommend people to do it so i've
appealed a lot more but when you get to
the appeal process then you get into
essentially making your case when you
file a foia it could be a little bit
more of a fishing expedition when you do
an appeal process you got to sit down
and lay out the evidence of why you're
challenging a final determination and so
the
very wee little experience i've had with
that aspect of it that's just where i
would respectfully disagree about that
latter uh piece of the evidence
happy to address the first part but i'll
be honest with you uh i'm i'm just
drawing a blank on with them no no no no
no that's okay don't sweat it but let
because you're talking about the appeals
process so let's let's ask this question
here and it's
related saying
all right well there was two things that
kind of came up in the whole
conversation between everybody that just
went is um remember that there's two
different types of lies that you're
going to deal with with the government
you're going to be ones that are blatant
just to cover up some a blunder or some
type of mishap or just something they
just don't want to get out then you also
have
uh lies that are unfortunately actually
necessary for national security and
things like that and these lies are just
to as
you know counter espionage things like
that
so uh you know our job is to be able to
pick through that data find what's not
going to cause
the most horrible horrendous things and
then you know get our answers um and the
other thing is is danny said that he had
access to all the uh the the project
blue book files um along with the
pictures did you have the access to the
associated documents with those pictures
to get a clear identification of exactly
what you were looking for that it wasn't
like an experimental craft that they had
built and you know the passengers were
just you know i've heard honestly some
really horrible stories about what they
who they could actually be and we won't
go into that because a little too dark
for my taste but uh
no not mine but the public uh but it's
uh
i if i just wanted to know if you had
the associated paperwork with it and the
reports that describe the crash in
detail
yeah i know it's it's uh it was one of
those uh
mistakes i've made in the past uh one of
the things that once i got the
photographs uh and i saw the different
photographs there were like three or
four of the photographs from different
angles etc and and you could tell that
the that the air force personnel that
were all around them were kind of
stunned and they were taking these
photographs and this kind of excited way
about this this crap as i say the the
key was that the symbols that were
around the edge of the dome uh were
symbols that were were not anything they
weren't any kind of uh
english or russian or chinese or any
kind of hieroglyphics or anything they
were a completely unique set of of
symbols that were all around the edge of
this this uh the dome of this thing
which led me to believe that look this
is not any language that i've ever seen
or anywhere near anything on our planet
that's what caused me to to think that
and then one of the problems was that
once i
they told me that i was not allowed to
take any notes uh or uh or anything else
in the in the room with the documents
i did and it's kind of a
infamous story now but i had this yellow
pad with me that i had under my arm and
i i opened it up in on the inside
cardboard of the yellow pad
i reduced the the picture from this uh
film
film strip thing that i had this uh from
what they call this little machine
machine that uh that i was using to see
the the documents and what i did is i
traced the exact letters that were in
this uh
around the dome with this thing
and i closed it up and because i knew
that i
had done something that they were i was
going to get in big trouble if i got
caught doing it what i did is i i put it
under my arm uh and i walked out of the
place really fast to get out of there
because i i thought that this was kind
of just positive and i've kicked myself
a thousand times between then 1977 and
now
i should have stayed there and i should
have started taking some notes on any of
the documents that were around that
referred to that but i didn't uh so i i
had the i saw the photographs and i saw
the the letters and i copied the letters
and then i left uh and so the the the
short answer to that is i i didn't go
digging into all the rest of the
documents not only that there was tons
of other stuff there i mean it was a
whole room like by you know maybe
20 feet wide by 15 feet deep and they
had these these folding tables with
these boxes these look like big shoebox
size things with these canisters of of a
microfiche in them and it was as soon as
i hit that particular set of photographs
i it says i was able to copy the letters
around the top of the dome or the edge
of the dome of that that crap that i
just got up and left uh and that was a
big mistake is that is that tracing
available anywhere have you made that
puppy have you have you framed that
that cardboard
i i brought it back to the jesuit
headquarters and i put it in the files
of the jesuit headquarters and when i
left the jesuit headquarters i took
my files with me
and when we we left we were doing the
big iran conference case this big
case that we had
uh dealing with the the off-the-shelf
enterprise and uh there there was an
attempt on the part of jack singlaub who
was the president of the world
anti-communist league
and and green and these other guys that
were the lawyers for oliver north and
and the other guys they were trying to
get a hold of our documents so what we
did is we we stacked up our documents
from this big 18-wheeler and moved them
to california uh and actually put them
in a uh a storage facility out there
uh uh out by the inland empire here in
california and there was this huge
massive storm this sounds like one of
those dumb
excuses you'd hear there's someone on
the stand and you turned to drink oh
yeah right you know but but the fact is
that
there was this big flood and they
flooded part of the documents that we
had stored
i didn't know for years which ones they
were but when we took the documents out
of there and moved them to jackson
browns ranch where we had them for years
uh when i finally went looking for that
particular file a whole section of our
jesuit files are the ones that got
flooded out
and that the people at the at the stores
facility had just thrown them out uh and
never even told us about it they even
gave us an option to look at them
but i've concluded over the years that
had to be one of the part of the
documents that got flooded out so we
don't have them uh so jamar i want to
bring you in here real quick uh because
i haven't heard that beautiful face yet
but what i want to add to that though
is the fact that there is such a
counter-intelligence value to the uap
topic that regardless of if there is a
extraterrestrial connection or not and i
and i do believe that that's a big
possibility for a portion of what we're
dealing with
the stuff that is not extraterrestrial
connected can absolutely be utilized by
the intelligence community and
counterintelligence operatives whatever
you want to say
as a way to muddy the public perception
of what we are dealing with
and it costs the government nothing
because the general public will take
just a little tiny nugget and blow it
into something that it's not so the the
answer is it extraterrestrially
connected or not
then becomes irrelevant because the
portion that definitely isn't
they can use it and start throwing
things out there like oh yeah we're
totally we're totally clueless and i
point to the official inside
communication of the united states air
force obtained through foia
that talked about the
all with clearance holders and in public
affairs offices and so on it was the
internal communications that the navy
put out the statement to me in september
of 2019 uh that they had no idea what
those videos were first time they ever
acknowledged that
and then when you juxtaposed that with
the air force
internally and again these were not
public statements i had to fight for the
documents
internally the air force is going yeah
the navy says they're unidentified but
we're talking about uas's and drones and
the media turns it into ufos and aliens
and it really gives an insight that
number one military agencies don't
really know what the other one thinks
does or they agree with each other but
number two
look at the value of that because now we
don't know as the general public we just
don't know what to believe is it alien
is it not could it be could it be do
they have the answers do they not and
again that ci value the counter
intelligence value of this topic whether
or not it's alien is something that
they're going to utilize so that i
believe jamal if that that answers your
question that they will use that to
their advantage because in the process
it confuses russia it confuses china it
may confuse iran it will confuse all of
the powers that either we are trying to
play nice in the sandbox with or we're
not it confuses all of them to wait a
minute does their intelligence community
really not realize that that's a balloon
or that's a drone or wait a minute
that's us they're really clueless again
it's that confusion from the ci
perspective that i think is i mean is
what's going on capacity to to seek
information that is classified and they
can seek the authority to get it
declassified so they can have access to
it uh and and that this was undertaken
by the congressional research service
science and technology division at my
request
as special counsel to them and that
marsha smith who was the head of the
science and technology division of the
of the congressional research service
when i put the request to her to have
that get access to the the classified
portions of project blue book she just
came back to me
a couple weeks later totally surprised
uh that they had agreed to do this that
when i asked her to see if we could get
access to it so i could help prepare
this this presentation to the the seti
program uh at the jet propulsion
laboratory in pasadena california
we she didn't think they were going to
agree to do it and so she was surprised
that they had agreed to this and so she
simply told me yes i had a right to come
and see this
i had to bring two forms of photo
identification and i went over to the
the madison building which was the brand
new wing of the library of congress and
they had delivered
this these files and they were in this
room downstairs in the basement
of the madison building uh and there was
nobody even there it wasn't even open
yet it was brand new it just been built
uh so when i went in there were two
suits that were standing in front of the
door
uh when i arrived uh who checked out my
passport and my driver's license uh and
then i was allowed into the building and
i went down the hall into an elevator
they pointed out and went down into the
basement and there were these other two
suits in front of this room uh and and i
don't i don't know you know exactly what
agencies they were from
i don't know uh you know but i never got
a clearance that i because bob fink who
was the the chief investigator for bella
abzug who was the congresswoman from new
york who chaired the senate or the house
uh judiciary committee subcommittee on
human rights always said to me said do
not ever accept a classification
a security clearance because you can
find out virtually anything you want to
know
without doing that you got the kind of
contacts you got the kind of access to
people you don't want to have that
because what they'll do is attribute
everything that you've ever discovered
from any other source they'll attribute
it to your security clearance
and they'll stop you from talking about
it publicly
so i've refused to accept the security
clearance you know and so that i didn't
get a clearance to see that i'm going to
uh can i
just uh yeah please please john yeah and
quickly we'll go to andy
i have to ask so if you didn't because i
know judges and and attorneys sometimes
get the in-camera clearances so if you
shut that down
okay um how can crs divulge
or whatever agencies were in the hallway
divulge classified information
and that's okay
they didn't i did
well no they they brought classified
records
to you right you said boxes well they
brought them they brought them to the
library of congress they were over the
library of congress at the madison
building downstairs in the basement
and again my interview uh er part is
taking over i'm just curious then how
could they allow a civilian to go in
attorney legal background or not without
the proper clearance to just open up and
see a picture of what you said was an
alien
spacecraft from the classified files of
blue book like
i don't know i don't know i don't know
whether they temporarily declassified
the files or what they did all i know is
they brought them there uh and there
were there must have been
20 20 25 boxes of these these uh these
light green
shoebox size things with these micro
fish in them and they were all in this
room on these folding tables in the room
downstairs in the madison building and
it was like
must have been
i don't know february uh march or it was
i don't believe there was even snow i
think it must have been after march or
so of 197
uh when they did it uh and that's where
i saw this stuff
all right uh don't worry gary then we'll
go to andy sorry and i know you got a
question sorry sorry andy it's all good
uh so i just got just two real quick
questions sorry so since you actually
physically saw the symbols have you
tried to replicate them and then
without reading the documents included
with the pictures how can you be sure of
the context of the photos you know even
a ts project could make soldiers say
what they have so i just was wondering
those two things okay yeah no the the
the uh uh i'll show you that
the i was always very careful because
the the i copied them traced them
literally in the exact sequence that
those symbols were were there at the
base of the at the base of the dome
but i'll show you i don't know if you
can see this
can you see here where where am i here
yeah yeah just put prop it up there you
go yeah see let me i'll show you i'll
show you exactly what they look like but
i don't know what the sequence is i
don't remember the exact sequence they
were in but they were they were like
this
i want to see how close my guess was
because i drew some stuff like oh what
did you draw it
okay
what does that mean andy
i'll tell you later
i think i know oh what do you think it
is
well i don't know i want to give
anything away but
uh lift it up just a little yeah okay
you see this yeah a little uh you know
what let's uh let's let's hold on a
second there uh let's blow you up real
quick danny okay okay
that's that's that's what they they were
a series of of uh straight lines like
that pointing either from the lower left
to the upper right or from the upper
left to the lower right and they had
these these a series of uh series of
dots
in in little uh little uh
u-shaped things like this
okay right right here and dots like this
different sequences of dots and they
were all around the the bottom of the
dome of the of the of the craft like
this
they were they were along the bottom of
the dome of the craft all right i lied i
got one more question all right so
that's that's very that's very similar
to uh cuneiform have you have you tried
to match it uh based off of different
dialects of cubic form yes i have this
is not cuneiform it's not cuneiform it
was not it was it was these things here
and that that all kinds of physical
structures have some similarities to
other physical stretches but these were
these were unique uh they were they did
not match when i was at the headquarters
we checked it out they did not match any
other kind of of communication
andy that did that answer your question