been on a table
and I've seen something removed from my
body
that I will call a fetus
a baby it was so small I couldn't
believe that it could live on its own
I remember putting my finger in the arch
of its foot I was afraid to look at the
face I was afraid to see what it looked
like there seems to be an enormous
interest in the emotional side of this
too and the part of the aliens they want
us to hold
these odd little children these babies
they want to see how a mother will hold
in love a child things which to us are
instinctive the abduction phenomenon
begins usually in infancy or at least by
the age of two three or four it
continues all through a childhood all
through maturity and into old age as
well I have many cases where the person
is taken as a child usually what we'd
refer to as the bedroom visitation I was
laying in bed I opened my eyes and
here's a little gray standing there
looking at me and all I could really
remember were those dark eyes it is as
if that person has become a kind of
tagged animal in someone else's
experiment
and that little person as they as he or
she grows to adulthood will be abducted
over a period of time at irregular
intervals let us assume
that this is all being made up that this
is internally generated that there is no
abduction phenomenon if that's the case
then we have discovered something of
enormous importance