welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate hey everyone welcome to Breer
Syndicate so this kind of rolls in as a
hot start with me and Damen Abraham um
for those you who don't know Damian is
from the band um God I guess it's the
first minute so I'll probably get in
trouble for cussing but it's [ __ ] up
the B [ __ ] up but he's also really
well known um for his work with Vice
magazine early on a lot of the
documentaries he's he's just a legend in
the punk rock scene and uh especially
for the historical part of the punk rock
scene he's also a major cannabis
Advocate and uh yeah we've been on each
other shows now and and I really wanted
to do one with him here um it's it's not
all punk rock based which I thought it
would probably be more punk rock based
and you know I understand a lot of
people that are in Kaa aren't
necessarily as interested in punk rock
but this one applies I think to everyone
and uh I think everyone's really going
to dig it absolutely loved it it was a
pleasure recording with him and with
that we kind of just slide right into
the conversation because that's how we
roll So yeah thank you so much I'm
drinking coffee I never drink coffee is
that is that to Edge or off edge I guess
so I don't know cannabis is my coffee I
feel like I I definitely uh if I didn't
smoke cannabis after the birth of my
children I don't know what it would have
got me through those sleepless nights I
think that was the uh that finally broke
my Edge to be honest really was that it
yeah it was that it was having kids
being on anxiety pill anti- anxiety
pills I should say um having to cycle on
and off them to get to be able to write
lyrics which is a side effect they don't
they don't bring that side effect up in
the uh Preamble no they don't yeah
depletes creativity yeah like I just I
don't know what it is but I guess it
just kind of like because it
you know mutes the highs and lows yeah
um it really I guess it's hard to get to
those places creatively at least for for
me and I'm sure there's lots of people
that find
it
completely pain free to write on anti-
anxiety pills and are are very creative
on it but that's not me you know I
definitely would have to cycle on and
off them and cycled off them and and
arrived in um
we were in in Holland we were in
Amsterdam or the Netherlands now right
Netherlands right yeah yeah Netherlands
sorry and uh and uh just was like can I
hit that joint that you guys got to my
band and they were all kind of
shocked uh they said I had broke Edge
before but I had not it was it was that
time and uh took it off the joint and
immediately kind of was like oh this is
what I was missing and I experimented
with Canabis in the the dirty 90s a
little bit when you know there were like
four I guess I don't even know different
types is what we knew him as we didn't
even know him as strains or as cultivars
right like it just like this guy's got
one that's like uh it it must be laced
with Coke because it's so strong and it
was just like really crystally I guess
like looking back on it now or there was
one guy it was like oh this guy's stuff
is is definitely lace because it's just
like so purple and yeah you know so I'd
experimented with cannabis I think I've
been stoned maybe once or twice
previously like I tried acid and that
was more my speed before I went straight
edge oh really yeah I really liked
psychedelics and yeah uh
cannabis like it was just so hit or miss
what you were getting back then and like
I didn't know how to inhale I was like I
think I'm getting it I think I'm getting
it the first time style yeah well first
first time I had my first cigarette my
first beer my first joint my first hit
of acid was all one day that's a lot
yeah how old were
you 14 yeah that's a good age for it
yeah yeah I've got a 15year old upstairs
right now so I gotta be very careful
listening on this conversation yeah
right we can get into that parenting
should with cannabis later on but uh
yeah so I tried it and came back and
told my doctor you know fast forward to
when I'm trying
as a 30-year-old and was like I found
something that works it take away my
anxiety and there's no side effects on
it like it's great you're not GNA
believe it it's weed and she's like no
way that is your doctor wasn't too
receptive not at all and this is like
this is
pre like Canada legalization came you
know obviously in a lot of different
phases but I think like the the leadup
to it there was sort of this like
medical Rush that kind of started where
all doctors got on board a lot of
doctors realized he get rich running
these cannabis clinics and my doctor
eventually kind of came around just
before that but it was only when I
started losing weight like I was a
hundred or so pounds heavier than I am
now yeah back then uh I would drink a
lot of soda that was my that'll do it
dude yeah I was drinking like six liters
a day Jesus
most on tour well see you wake up like
you have a large like I would have lar
you I would have two large sodas at
breakfast because I get a refill yeah uh
then at lunch and then backstage there's
always free soda oh I'm sure yeah and
then after the show we get some pops so
yeah it was it was pretty pretty severe
but yeah Tri cannabis got off all that
stuff and went off the anti-anxiety
pills against my doctor's orders and
uh once I started losing the weight
she's like okay I'll sign your your
forms for you to get into a Compassion
Club and at that point in Toronto there
were two compassion clubs one one was
pretty strict and you know like you had
to be signed in by a doctor the other
one if you knew the right people I think
youd get around the doctor thing but
this was definitely one of the ones that
you needed your doctor to really sign
off for you at and by that point i' had
already made some connections so I had
other hookups to get it from but the
Compassion Club was great because it
kind of gave me exposure to like a whole
new side of cannabis back then like it
it it it's so recent TimeWise but it was
just such a different world right like
pre medical pre-
legalization it was like a secret
society back then so what what initially
pushed you like from trying cannabis and
LSD and [ __ ] like that to going straight
edge like was it just the punk scene the
type of music you were listening to
people no I went I went kind of
straighted before all that I just kind
of hated everyone around me at school
yeah and uh not wanting to be like the
people around yeah like I think that's
also what prevented me from admitting
that I liked pro wrestling for so long
and I would kind of watch it in secret
because I hated the kids at my school
that were into wrestling and yeah yeah
for sure and it just felt like and also
it was like my parents
both smoked weed the whole time um off
and on with my dad he doesn't really
smoke weed now yeah at all but my my mom
secretly smoked weed and she was like I
tried it once I didn't like it and never
tried it again yeah uh so I think I
found like a real Rebellion like my dad
was like really freaked out by straight
edge and oh really yeah yeah I could see
that being a little rebellious too like
from nature kind of yeah like I think it
was the dogma of it I think it was the
fact that like why are you doing this
like normally when someone decides to be
sober it's because they've got a problem
or because their religion tells them or
you know to say like I'm just doing it
because I want to do it and then to be
kind of aggressive with it like like
Xing up before I went to his wedding and
stuff
weird like things that like you know
just obviously are attention getting you
realize as you're older but at the time
it it just is like this is important and
it really makes sense to me did really
make sense to me I'm I'm glad I was
straight edge when I was straightedge
and then I came back to cannabis just
the right time like swing plate rigs had
just kind of hit and extracts and
concentrates were just kind of coming
out
and obviously the medical wave was just
about to really start hitting in America
in sorry in Canada it already kind of
started I guess in California yeah um we
even though I recently read that we
actually had medical cannabis in Canada
first but it just such a shitty
program uh that that's probably right
too yeah yeah just stunted it for a long
time up here but that's why I guess we
had such great bud out in BC is because
everyone had these really um great
doctors that were signing him then them
into this medical program that was
really hard to get signed into back then
and um yeah like so I'm glad I was
certainly I wouldn't take back being
straight Ed at all but I I'm glad I got
into weed when I did because it was just
in time to kind of see the Roaring 20s
of cannabis just before uh you know
legalization changed everything not
necessarily in the most positive ways
all the time but changed everything
nonetheless so even being like straight
edge or identifying with straight edge
you were still in a band with people
that like used pot right yeah like yeah
you so it wasn't like super dogmatic
like Minor Threat era like no you would
have a really hard time I think in
Toronto
being dogmatic about that stuff not just
in the punk scene but I just think in in
general right like it's just it's a big
city and I think that kind of like
straight edge militancy probably works
when you're in a very small town or very
small you know where you can kind of
control things a lot more um but yeah
like it was never yeah I always had
friends that smoked and drank and I kind
of loved being around people that smoked
and drank and never really had a problem
with it in sort of outside myself kind
of way and I think now in in retrospect
I probably wouldn't have had a
problem with it myself if if I had been
doing it back then but I just you know
it was
a a good time for me not to be doing it
looking at some of my friends and some
of the sort of paths they went down sure
you know and it it was pre the cocaine
Revival and pre all that kind of stuff
but yeah still there was still obviously
lots of wildness being had in the late
90s
was there a big like a a heroin surge up
there in Canada for the punk scene there
was it's kind of been here the whole way
through we actually had there's a band
from up here called the bunch of [ __ ]
Goofs The BFG about them yeah yeah
they're like they're our band they're
like the legendary band I think every
scene kind of has the band that never
got out of the scene necessarily but if
you ask anyone that's around that scene
like who the most important band is the
bfgs came I guess 84 they
83 and really into the late late 90s
early 2000s they were still pretty
strong when they were going and so they
policed the scene they had Fort goof was
was their house and you talk to bands
that came through Toronto they all have
stories about going to Fort goof and
Jerry a tells a story about having like
some crazy open wound from the stage on
his leg and some dog licking it and them
being like no no no don't worry dogs
mouths are disinfectants it'll be fine
J's like really you think they're like
yeah
yeah got a crazy infection the next
day there's like but they because they
police the scene they big stances were
no hard drugs so no crack no heroin and
uh no Nazis yeah so because of that
there there obviously were these things
in and around Toronto but you just
didn't really see it around the punk
scene
yeah major and then with the arrival I
guess of oxie and then fentanyl that
changed everything and you really did
start deaths start happening in Toronto
and and these had happened before but I
think um for our Scene It was kind of
new when when fentanyl really started
hitting or oxies before that I guess
yeah it really did make it hardcore
available for everyone I always just
wondered like with um with Heroin how it
worked like up in Canada like the actual
trade of it and how it moved its way up
if it made like like the Mexican black
tar made it up that way and [ __ ] the
whole scenes up and and killed it off or
what because it definitely happens here
you know it's interesting there is
definitely like a pipeline that's
established between out west at West is
a is heroin OB like to Vancouver will
tell you right that opioids
have uh really wreak havoc on the
population in that City and uh you
really you see that beginning in the
punk scene like people have on turn it
to punk outed certain people as being
the the conduits for heroin arriving in
the punk scene oh there is a there was a
pipeline kind of established there was
this guy for more for for weed but there
was this guy uh Rosie who's the the hash
king of okay Toronto he was bringing in
tons and tons of hash and he got busted
and he was put on trial with Neil
Young's brother
and Norman maer testified in their
defense the day after he like won an o
or presented an Oscar oh that's wild and
they got like eight years for that but
yeah Rosie's story is wild like he but
he went out west and met the guys out
west which was a lot of dudes in bike
clubs uh a lot of guys that come up from
the States during the Vietnam war and
kind of afterwards and there had been a
lot of seeds and and genetics that have
come up through Canada at that point and
Rosie kind of brought the hash across
and they had the flower and that was
sort of the exchange for a while but
there was stuff coming up from like
Jamaican cess TR a ra rather large
Jamaican population or people from
Jamaica um and around that time there's
a lot of cth around here but people talk
about how great the hash was in Toronto
and then Rosie got busted the second
time he gets out of prison that first
time they he got busted with Neil
Young's brother and gets interviewed by
some reporter from Rolling Stone and the
reporter's like let's get the band back
together start smuggling hash and I'll
be in America you'll be in Canada it'll
be amazing so tempting so they do it
yeah they were bringing in tons and tons
of hash and
eventually you know the the the law
caught on to it and and there's this
whole wild story about tons of hash
being brought into New York and them
letting the sale go the CIA or something
letting the sale go through like deep
I'm probably messing up all the details
of it but anyway he gets busted again
and this time when Ros is on trial he
gets Neil Young to testify his defense
and Neil Young Young yeah because he's
famous or like [ __ ] he was busting
with his brother before right so he had
that familial connection and Neil looks
around the room and he's like I smoke
weed every day and I earn more money
than all you put together and they gave
Rosie like 28 years oh my God so so no
young didn't like uh pulling favors for
him no that's that's the celebrity name
drop you don't want yeah yeah it just
sounds like a circus like [ __ ] it
bringing no young just because we can
but Rosie was definitely like the
um the link for a lot of that stuff
going out west and I think a lot of that
sort of connection between out west and
out out here going back to you know the
70s yeah so one thing I do want to talk
about like early on is the new video
obviously because there there there
really isn't to me like anything
covering cannabis history in any
meaningful way uh in music like that
currently especially not in punk rock or
hardcore or any of it you know what I
mean like it's not it's not a normal
thing to see so I'm stoked on it and um
it's something I wanted to bring up and
and and make sure everybody gets to see
I don't even think we mentioned your
[ __ ] band yet no I kind of just
rolled in
hot consume or no yeah yeah yeah you're
fine oh I can duck off if you don't want
yeah no you're you're fine dude yeah
they only get mad about like showing
plants for some reason hey don't worry I
wish I had some to show off but I I know
right have a post product um uh yeah the
video was was am thank you again
publicly for your help on this because
um it's something I wanted
to I think it's
just I'm I'm fascinated by history of
stuff and and and once I kind of get
into something I want to really kind of
get into it and and figure it out out
and I think with cannabis there's just
so
many false paths that you can wind up
going down and there's just so much
false information that's out there that
digging in and talking to people that
that know about the plant that have
experience with the plan and you know so
like not to put you over on your own
[ __ ] but like someone like yourself
who's actually like put in the work yeah
like that's it's like kind of invaluable
because it's not really something you
can pick up a book there's so many books
that you can pick up that are full of
disinformation and misinformation and
and to kind of like put all those pieces
together it's uh you really do rely on
people that have been kind of putting
this puzzle together before you to kind
of help you figure it out and Yeah like
it's just trying to pay tribute to this
amazing plant that I've had a
relationship with now
for like I guess 15 years yeah really
intensely but has been around for
millennia and has been involved in The
Human Experience for Millennia and it's
just so misunderstood and even when it's
not being vilified I think it's being
misunderstood like every time I buy
cannabis I get asked IND sativa and yeah
right yeah I guess it's an
icebreaker not all it is anymore yeah
yeah but like the idea that this plant
knows though this plant like as it's
growing is okay I got to make sure I
present present this trait of myself
that makes this person want to watch
Netflix and eat ice cream like there's
nothing in nature that would make a
plant want to do that to you so why is
this person thinking that that's gonna
have or trying to tell me that it's
gonna have that kind of effect on me
yeah and I just it feels like there's a
lot of silliness around cannabis and not
that our video is not silly in its own
way but I wanted like in amongst the
silliness to have some like actual real
information yeah about it yeah so what
was like the inspiration for doing it
right now versus even 10 years ago
[ __ ] up with let me like the band
finally all kind of just signed off on
it yeah the band signed off on it I
guess we have on our last record we have
a song uh called Lords of Kensington
which is about this neighborhood in
Toronto called Kensington
Market which at one point was a uh a
market kind of area for recently arrived
people from Eastern Europe and then
people recently arrived from China and
Hong Kong and Taiwan and then just sort
of in the 990s it became a place with
lots of thrift stores and still lots of
food markets and things like that but it
was a a cool neighborhood and we had a a
bunch of neat little venues in there
like um HMA or the anarchist free space
where you could kind of just put on
shows in the basement and buy records or
whatever yeahh so the song's kind of
reflecting on that neighborhood and the
changes in that neighborhood and
the fact that there was this park in
this neighborhood um that's still there
and that Park was where kids would
always go and just smoke weed and there
was a lot of people selling weed and
then cops got wise to it and would go
down and fake sell weed to kids and TR
kids and and [ __ ] up kids lies and then
in one of the kind of the grossest
displays of post
legalization uh cannabis in Canada this
the former police chief of Toronto
Julian in
fantino who indirectly probably directly
too during his time as a cop is
responsible for like thousands of lives
being [ __ ] up by canvas
laws uh putting out like an editorial
about how he had changed his mind about
cannabis finally go figure when there's
money on the table cop changed his mind
about
weed and opened a weed store in
Kensington Market and so I wrote a song
on the last record about that and um on
this record it's kind of like a a
fantasy of a kid who had been arrested
by a cop going down and watching the
cops weedster grow to business and and
so I with that song being so directly
about cannabis
and me
unrelentingly uh kind of assing [ __ ]
up for years can we do something about
weed they finally were like all right do
your [ __ ] weed
video Jonah from [ __ ] up really kind
of carried it for me because as you know
from dealing with me mant I'm a little
disorganized yeah yeah he's a nice dude
I enjoyed meeting him he's very talented
yeah he's the
uh like uh he could do anyone's job in
[ __ ] up like [ __ ] up could function
completely well just with him as the one
what band he in career suicide yeah um
he did a band called Mad Men for a while
that was an amazing kind of Hardcore
band uh he
played drum
as
well oh man I know I'm forgetting
something he played drums in and now he
does Jade hairpins yeah he also does a
band called boss with a bunch of guys
like guys from Ricks and guys from uh
chubby and the Gang it's kind of like an
international Pub Rock kind of band
that's awesome and then he produces a
lot of Records he produced that last
lexon fire record that was a big record
up here and he's yeah he's super
talented he's definitely the best member
of our band by far has he been in since
the the beginning is it like all the
members always been in the band or yeah
I was the last one to join they did
really four four shows with uh Josh as
the singer the guy who plays guitar in
the band now and then he went to
trainhop uh down in the US so punk rock
it was pre September 11th when you could
still kind of train hop AC the border
and uh so he train hopped down there in
in the states and they had three shows
lined up and they were like do you want
to sing these three shows and I sang
them
and we had fun and so when Josh came
back uh Mike from [ __ ] up was like
you're just going to learn guitar and
daman's going to be the singer now and
that's what it's kind of been weirdly
ever since I don't think any of us I
think every stage of [ __ ] up has felt
like the last so yeah I don't think
anyone in the band thought it would be
like this at all how many years has the
band been running
24 that's so long dude for for people to
get along enough to be in a van and oh
we don't get along oh we don't get along
at
all that's just how it goes yeah I it's
it's funny when we were like I remember
one of the first big festivals we played
was tea in the park in in Edinburgh and
uh rag machine showed up and each one
was in a separate Sprinter van M and
it's like oh my God like how bad does it
have to be that you can't even sit in
the same van as the rest of the people
in your band
and not that we have the means for it
and [ __ ] up but if we did have the
means I'm sure we would all be in
separate spinner bands
now guarantee that's so funny dude so
let's let's talk about um your Vice era
yeah things that you did with Vice uh
specifically for cannabis also with the
wrestlers because that's like something
I was fascinated with it was um yeah it
was wild like how did that even come to
be oh
man uh
you like you want the whole Vice Saga
for beginning yeah why not why not all
right maybe let me let me do my uh [ __ ]
my dab first and then get really into it
because this is like a like it's
interesting like the history of Vice
when you when you really start breaking
it my friend was like whatever you do
don't show your smoking setup on the
podcast because it's like the buest
smoking setup anyone's ever seen like
you know cannabis is such a headyy world
everyone's like oh you got to have
headyy [ __ ] like I I like basically am
one step above smoking out of a tin can
yeah you don't have you don't have a
bunch of trap trophies still no no I'm
I've had some glass pieces but they have
all been broken I got my one I'll show
my one rig in a second that's my like my
one cool piece but it's got a good story
attached to Vice yeah that's right
huh all right did you edit or am I this
all live Oh no you're fine you're F okay
I can edit okay yeah I just didn't I'm
sorry about that I should have no don't
worry about it don't worry at
all
okay do you use a thermometer when
you're dabbing uh no I always just ended
up using a puffco because I'm way too
lazy to my friend got my friend gave me
his old uh thermometer and it changed
the way I dab it just completely yeah
once you know you're supposed to be a
certain temperature and not just nail
that [ __ ] hot no exactly like I
realized that every dab I had taken
before had been way too hot
yeah all right now I'm
good so the uh I played in a band when I
was in grade nine and 10 called Ur in
trouble
okay and the first show the second show
we ever played afterwards we went to a
restaurant that was open super late and
walking in they would have all like the
free newspapers and things like that and
Toronto being a big city we had a lot of
free weeklys and and other papers back
then and I saw this one with a Frank
khaak picture on the cover of a dog with
a machine gun I love khaak rest in peace
and I was a huge absolutely rest in
peace someone who I think yeah we could
do a whole podcast you oh for sure um so
I was like oh my God Frank kic and they
had an article about propagandhi I
remember in that issue and something
else and it was called voice back then
and I picked it up and I'm like this is
really cool and then it became vice
really shortly thereafter and it was
still like a newsprint thing that youd
pick up and had the dos and don'ts and
it was talking about garage Rock in
Montreal and they they kept talking
about this record label they were
starting back then called SSG records
and they were going to be putting out
all these records and it just seemed
right even then super cool like it was
talking about Punk it was talking about
rap music it had cool comics in it it
was and it was really well written and
yeah there was just something about it
and so I just kind of like I picked it
up every month after that like it was
just something you you grabbed you like
you go to the record store and they're
like oh the new issue of Vice is here I
I've got one that's got like a l flexi
in it with bis the bis Marquee song that
they did with Len that came in one issue
of Vice like it was just part of like my
youth and so we start [ __ ] up like
years later and uh we get weirdly out of
the blue one day we get an email from a
guy named Andy kapper who was the editor
of Vice UK at the time and he's like um
a friend of mine told me about your band
I think you gu I like your band and he's
like I want to do something with you
guys and so Mike from [ __ ] up was like
you should put out a a seven inch why
don't you put it a seven inch on Vice
records and uh he did but didn't clear
it with the rest of Vice so it's kind of
a bootleg on Vice records that's so
awesome uh and then at the same time
Arty Philly who played in a bunch of
great hardcore bands over the years uh
was who was a writer for vice like that
was the thing about Vice like right from
the get-go there was tons of punk and
hardcore people writing for it or
involved in it and you you kind of
always knew people that new people that
were in it or this guy from this band's
now writing for him or the guy from the
space shits does these reviews or you
know like all stuff like that so yeah
Arty Philly who was writing for them at
the time and played in all these
hardcore bands hit us in career suicide
up and was like can I interview you guys
for
vice and we both sent our you know
answers back to the questions
and then he's like can you guys send
some photos and Martin from Kur suicide
never sent photos but I had some photos
that a friend of mine had taken uh of me
bleeding from the head yeah dude a show
legendary photos out there well that was
the thing you know like that was the
vice went with that photo and that was I
think what made the P yeah probably that
photo in Vice
magazine uh and then from there they
wanted to sign us and we didn't sign we
end up signing a Mador and there was a
lot of drama and it was not great for a
couple years it was it was so bizarre
because it was like something that I'd
grown up with like it would be like if
uh all of a sudden Spider-Man had beef
with you or Marvel Comics had beef with
you yeah right where I'm like this is so
[ __ ] weird and by this point Gavin
was long out of the pitcher it was more
with the other people that were left
there and it was it was weird and then
they came Vice Canada was kind of part
of the
company but like the Kinder gentler
version of Vice like the the Canadian
version exactly which is weird because
Vice is ultimately started by a bunch of
[ __ ] yeah from Canada but but still
the vice office in Toronto was
definitely like the Canadian version of
Vice like everyone was a lot friendlier
and a lot Kinder and I think if you look
at the content that they put out a lot
of it was like a lot of it had a lot
more
heart than a lot of the US stuff that
was coming around at the same time but
at that time it was still just like a
fledgling operation up here in the
Toronto office like they had just
started opening these satellite offices
and the Toronto office was pretty new
and they came to me and they were like
we want to do uh a thing about Budweiser
a thing about bands where you go around
and interview bands and it's gonna be
sponsored by Budweiser beer and I had
briefly been a VJ on much music which is
the Canadian MTV and just spent the last
two years interviewing terrible bands
about music and was like I don't drink
so being sponsored by Budweiser was
weird to me yeah I bet and uh I I also
just don't want to interview bands and
they're like well we're looking on to do
a medical cannabis documentary too and
I'm like perfect I just got medical weed
and we uh went out to BC and shot the
Canadian cannabis documentary the very
first one and it did really well for
vice Canada on YouTube that was when
Vice YouTube channel was still really
popping or just starting to really pop
and so we end up doing another four more
of these documentaries and uh it was
unbelievable the experiences were really
great I met some great friends that I'm
still super tight with today and friends
for life making these documentaries and
really got to kind of see
like the real side of cannabis BC
where and I'm sure it's still huge the
stuff but that felt like kind of the
crest like it felt like the Roaring 20s
like there was just 200 plus
dispensaries in downtown Vancouver there
was like five times more dispensaries
than Tim Horton's I think we said in one
of the documentaries some some crazy
number of these dispensaries and every
one of these dispensaries had a lounge
upstairs with where people would just go
and do dabs and hang out all of them
were packed all of them looked like they
were turning a profit like it really did
feel like [ __ ] this is what it should be
like yeah and it's weird how post
legalization that hasn't come back in
any way and there there is obviously
tons
of money being made by some people in
the Cannabis industry but it seems to be
like a race to the bottom and that
wasn't the case back then
but but I'm glad I got to see it like I
and I I I really did realize it at the
time like I remember the day
legalization happened sitting there with
a bunch of friends having aesh being
like I think this is it I think we saw
the best [ __ ] that happened in weed
because they' already the cops had
already raided all the dispensaries by
that point and you could already tell
that there was a change coming that yeah
was you know I I don't know thought it
was going to be as severe as it was but
uh and
vice by that point it already kind of
transitioned to making the wrestling
content by the time visualization hit
but they were already like we had so
much Goodwill with people on the
traditional the traditional side of the
market or the the Legacy Market I should
say yeah uh that they just kind of
eroded immediately they made a deal with
canopy to do some branded content
content
and everyone was bummed out naturally I
remember that watching the first piece
of content they made and it was not it
was like an ad it wasn't a documentary
of course and then it cuts to the end
and because they weren't allowed to show
people consuming in advertorial content
so you can see that she's clearly
rolling up like a cigarette that they
cut away from before she like puts it in
her mouth to kind of be like well legal
weed's
awesome and yeah it was great though
there was a bunch of times they tried to
get rid of me and bring in a younger
person because that's what Vice was
ultimately you know running on the blood
of the youth yeah and they'd bring in
these younger reporters and they might
be better reporters than me but by God
did they not have the tolerance and so I
one by one they would all just fall as
they'd have to go to these sessions with
glass blowers or Growers or genetics
people or just like you know people that
can smoke yeah and they would be under
the table passed out taking home and
they'd have to call me
Grandpa back yeah that was my one
natural ability that kept me employed at
Vice for so long was my tolerance
actually no I forgot there's one another
big thing that happened was um Vice had
their like 20th anniversary party and uh
was the 20th I guess it was 20th and
they flew
they're like hey uh they suou from Vice
hit me up he's like do you want to come
to New York and play at our 20th party
and this is before I started making
documentaries for him or any of that
stuff this is like the beginning of the
kind of thaw and the the Cold War yeah
and uh I was like sure sure and he's
like okay you're gonna be doing a thing
with Nick from the Yas and we want you
to do a couple punk songs and just come
down here we'll figure it out so I flew
down to New York talked to Nick and
Nick's like dude I'm overwhelmed they
got me doing like 50 songs can you just
figure out out doing like the hardcore
set with you know a band yourself and
I'm like sure so they put together a
band with Ben from Dillinger skap
plan um uh uh what's his name on drums
soft circle is his Instagram I'm
flanking on his name right now but on
drums and then Stephen McDonald from Red
Cross on bass that's so cool it was
awesome and we did we did a bunch of
arkward songs of this Vice party and it
was it was it was wild it was the day
little Wayne had left cash money and
Little Wayne was performing there and so
there's all this crazy security they're
like is baby going to show up is [ __ ]
gonna go off [ __ ] god ni Minaj was
supposed to play she didn't show I fin
yeah we start doing we do this hardcore
set and then I finish and then I look
over and there's Spike Jones on bass or
keyboards and Jonah Hill covering like
Marvin's Room on on the microphone like
sounds like a bad Acid trip but kind of
nice so nuts it was so wild uh it was
and but after that they gave me a vice
ring and I got it
here and this was like have you seen
that Seinfield episode where Kramer gets
the Tony somehow yeah yeah yeah that's
what this ring was like like I all of
sudden had this ring and it was like I
was in the Masons like I never had to
sign in for security at Vice Canada I
think it's because no one really
understood
what the ring was in Canada it was like
the satellite office so they thought it
just meant maybe executive or something
you're locked in oh it was crazy the the
amount of [ __ ] that they were just like
he's got a ring so I never had to sign
in at security that's so funny so many
weird things happen but just because you
know I Cramer this Tony
ring like when you get pulled over by
cops in the US do you just put your hand
up with the ring and no ticket not
anymore now they cut your finger off
yeah at one point gaving well actually
yeah when we first we that very first uh
cannabis documentary they gave me so I I
had so much weed like I I'm leaving the
hotel room and I'm like literally just
like eating hash just like just like
chewing raw hash like chewing edibl so I
show up at the airport and it must have
been like like pouring out of my pores
like I must have been sweating Phoenix
Tears oh I'm sure and get to the border
the first because you have to pre-clear
customs at Vancouver and Toronto Airport
before you go to the states in
Immigration so I get to immigration the
guy's like takes a whiff of me and he's
like go to go to secondary inspection so
I go to the secondary inspection the guy
gets my bag and he's like uh are you
bringing weed with you and I'm like no
he's like dude you smell like a
marijuana
grow what are you doing and I'm like I'm
going to go shoot a music video with my
band and play a show in San
Francisco and I was just making a
documentary here in
Vancouver uh he's like what what's
documentary about I'm like it's it's a
documentary for vice about weed and he's
like Vice I'm like yeah he's like will
it be on the YouTube
channel I'm like yeah I think so that's
the plan he's like oh my God man that's
awesome and he's like that's crazy zips
up my bag passes it back to me just
escorts me right out he's like hey man I
look forward to seeing that documentary
that's so cool I love Vice he's like you
the ring pre- ring oh I did have my ring
I did have my ring I don't if I had it
on me though it was just very bizarre
like the power that thing had for a hot
moment it's it's wild and I guess we're
seeing it now with Drake too like how
quickly culture can change but yeah when
we started making that wrestling TV show
The Till the End like at the beginning
Vice was a sacred word you could you
know you just utter Vice and people are
willing to help you out in any way they
could sure to when we were finished
where it was like oh I [ __ ] hate Vice
or I used to watch Vice and it's like
yeah eight
months so so was the wrestling show as
big as the weed show like with as far as
views and [ __ ] it's kind of hard to say
like I still don't even really know like
the way it went down so Vice can had
this huge $500 million deal from Rogers
which is the big cable provider here MH
and at a certain point Rogers just wrote
off the investment and said you can just
keep keep the money that we've paid you
so far and keep all your content we
don't want it which I really think was
the beginning of the dominoes falling
for vice yeah in terms of business deals
beginning to go south and everything
kind of beginning to change
so we were part of that Rogers deal like
we were one of the last shows they green
lit under that Rogers deal where they
had money to kind of spend on these kind
of TV shows so we had a decent budget I
didn't see a lot of that decent budget
making that show solid a decent budget
but we got to spend a lot of money
making that show like it's crazy looking
back on it and and that's why we were
able to travel to all those places that
we were able to travel and and do all
these those sorts of things was because
this Rogers deal which then evaporated
in the process of making that show which
left our show kind of in limbo yeah Vice
had changed directions Vice also never
really believed in in wrestling which is
interesting now with the success they've
had with dark side of the Ring yeah oh
right yeah yeah that kind of and they
were in production just after we went
into production and that also started in
Canada their production too uh but
someone ADV Vice like an executive
straight up told me like no one cares
about wrestling I'm like there's
millions of people watching it every
week clearly one of their biggest shows
yeah and then dark of the Ring became
their biggest show that was Dave zero
Maddy
Matson and uh and that I think are their
big success stories of of kind of the
vice TV experiment where did the
therapist show come in there oh that was
when we were making the wrestling show
and that came about because Andy kapper
was like Hey I'm doing this show where
you just come in and talk to this
therapist guy and I'm like okay well how
bad could that be I'm on tour and he's
like yeah we'll pay you like 500 bucks
for the two hours I'm like can I smoke
weed he's like
sure which I don't think
isal I don't think you're allowed to
give therapy to someone who's uh not
that I would ever not be yeah high on
weed but like I think on an Ethics level
the fact that this therapist knew that
might be a weird conflict but it was
very [ __ ] weird and it is so intense
and that was an intense show even
watching it it's super intense that my
mom made me cut out a lot of stuff got
an early cut of it and I sent it to my
mom and she's like can you cut out all
this [ __ ] about your stepfather and so
they really dialed that side of it back
but they got me to say [ __ ] on the
record that I never never want to talk
about and yeah and you're there and I
remember the day it aired I was in the
Congo filming in in gasa filming the
episode of the wrestlers in the in the
Democratic Republic Congo and sitting in
the hotel room the internet's I can't
stream it but I know it's airing and
just being like having the most intense
Day incasa filming where every day
filming that episode was was pretty
intense but I bet sitting in that room
and just being like [ __ ] I have this
goddamn therapy show airing was that a
panic attack in itself oh there's so
many panic attacks every day of that
experience of a panic attack like uh it
was the best year of my life Mak that
show in a lot of ways like professional
year of my life sure
because every day was interesting every
day was was cool but the amount of
travel was very intense we were gone I
was gone for two weeks every two weeks
yeah and then sometimes it' be like a
month in
Japan sometimes it was like yeah a month
in Japan bro it was awesome no weed but
oh yeah that's right I had a couple
opportunities to smoke but I'm like I
don't think I'd enjoy it what kind of
mids they got in Japan back then you can
get well obviously I'm talking to a guy
when for most people you can get Cali
quality weed there like you know
obviously shop shop level I was gonna
say for the rest of the world like top
weed but it was at the time I was told
$80 a gram $90 a gram [ __ ] yeah that's
why Thailand Thailand legalization looks
so attractive to tourists because people
are coming from Russia and Japan where
to pay for that California stuff you're
you're paying you know $90 a gram $80 a
gram so to pay $40 a gram doesn't seem
that bad
yeah but I uh yeah it was too rich for
my blood so I just stayed away from weed
the whole time actually that year I
smoked weed in Mexico a few
times uh I smoked weed in Bolivia um but
it was
it was not the greatest cannabis in my
experience the cocoa leaves though were
that be yeah yeah yeah I definitely have
never never been an upper person but uh
chewing a bag of cocoa leaves really
helped me deal with the altitude Chang
bet it was bet but yeah I'm trying to
think of other places that there would
be because wrestlers a lot of wrestlers
smoke weed so when you're around the
wrestlers there's always cannabis kind
of around um but yeah it was it was uh
it was an intense year but an amazing
year there's like so much [ __ ] there's
just obviously
like getting to see some of these places
realizing like and I think cannabis and
wrestling are the same in this way they
cross social lines in the way that punk
never really does yeah you know like
you'll see cannabis and wrestling in
places that have no punk scene or or
maybe a very tiny Punk scene
and yeah there was uh it was really cool
to kind of like think about this the
wrestling show basically it was this
sort of idea that wrestling everywhere
it goes it's going to be like a type of
music and it's going to adapt to the
local culture and that's why Lucha Libre
and Japanese Strong
Style have very little physically in
common with each other and their their
performance of professional wrestling or
the the execution of professional
wrestling but at the same time it's a
language that you could stick these two
guys in the ring together or two people
in the ring together and they'd still be
able to figure out how to have a match
with each other and getting to see that
bore out like the people in Bolivia or
the people in kinasa and the people in
ninic and everyone kind of spoke the
same language of of pro wrestling that's
so wild yeah because I'm a I'm a big
Mark for like um New Japan Pro Wrestling
like all that stuff like but mostly
because of how it intertwined with MMA
in Japan yeah and and you'd find these
people doing these uh you know
choreographed acts and then you know a
year later they're in real fights real
submission fights and just as tough as
anyone else you know yeah like the uh
uwfi and and Pancras and sort of that
and um big Japan and and
uh in all Japan and in New Japan as well
like the the way the like I think it's
Terry Funk described it in in a podcast
I think he did with Cole Cabana where
like wrestling
you know if you look at the history of
professional wrestling in Japan it's
there prior to the second world war they
think it was brought over by Masons and
it was sort of like just part of like
gambling culture like the idea of like
fixing wrestling matches yeah
performance of wrestling but it's not
until after the second world war and and
Ricky dozan this former sumo wrestler
who uh according to what I've read
couldn't uh arise past a certain rank in
Sumo because he was part Korean or had a
Korean mother I believe so kind of hit a
ceiling in Sumo came over to wrestling
and and Japan sort of freshly removed
from the second world war he realized
what people wanted to see in Japan was
Japanese people fighting
Americans and so they started bringing
in these American guys and because
they're one generation removed from
armed conflict a lot of times these guys
would get in the ring and they just
tried and kill each other and Terry
Terry FK Terry funk's like in America
you're trying to make a work look like a
Shute in Japan you're trying to make a
chute look like a work because we go out
there [ __ ] kill each other that's
that's wild but it's it's it's funny how
that became the style right to this day
that's what strong style is and that's
why Japanese wrestling so that's what I
love too is because like these guys are
going in there and they're or people are
going in there um and just being the
[ __ ] out of each other and and it's very
physical and it's very snug and yeah and
very like and then yeah at a certain
point I guess people were just like yeah
what what we fought for
real right what really happened like we
really just like didn't bother you know
deciding who was going to win in advance
and yeah what that
brings and if you look at like a lot of
the early I guess even UFC guys a lot of
them had experience or training in
Japanese proest yeah yeah and that's
probably why a lot of them were able to
kind of you know
become the Stars they were is because
they knew what people wanted to see in
the ring and they knew what they the
fans needed from their physical combat
and yeah and they also had the Charisma
you know what I mean that's like a big
part of selling yourself in any fight
yeah yeah it was uh yeah it was
interesting in kind of like going around
and realizing that there's like sort of
this Universal quality to people that
wind up being pro wrestlers like not
every not to say that everyone's the
exact same but there's and then there's
a universal quality of people that wind
up being wrestling
fans that's funny and they're not
necessarily the same types of people
yeah and it was it was interesting
because it's closer to cannabis in this
way that it is a secret thing and for
different reasons I guess maybe way back
when when it was still being fixed in
terms of gambling stuff it was for kind
of the same reasons you got to keep it
secret but you really don't like the
fans in wrestling it's not like punk
where it's like hey you kid come up here
anybody can do this [ __ ] yeah it's like
hey you kid come in the ring I [ __ ]
dare you I'm gonna break your arm this
is real
yeah like one thing I learned very
quickly is never let a wrestler
demonstrate uh a move on you or
demonstrate something on you and I knew
this going in but the first thing I made
prior to the wrestlers because rice kept
me like no you can't make anything about
wrestling no one cares about wrestling
and then I did this documentary about
Deathmatch wrestling with this director
Shaunie who was amazing director and we
went down to the tournament of death in
Delaware do you know about this thing
uhuh no T Tournament of death is this
annual I believe they're still doing it
wrestling event put on by czw on the
owner oh the CZ W1 okay and the owner DJ
Hy's parents yeah parent yeah what yeah
and we went out there and we filmed and
it was it was nuts and I kept selling it
to Vice we've been I've been trying to
make this documentary with them for
years on this thing I'm like you will
not believe how crazy this is yeah and I
brought it back and they just could not
believe how out of control all the
violence in this thing was and and that
was the first thing that sold them
because it did so well on YouTube and
and and and finally kind of like made
them realize that people actually care
about wrestling but that I still have
nightmares that was definitely the
wildest shoot ever and the most insane
people to deal with yeah yeah I I
remember seeing that episode or that
that whole thing it was nuts yeah it was
uh we did that one and then we did
another one for the series on on
Deathmatch wrestling and and it's a kind
of a separate culture
than even any other pro wrestling and
it's kind of merged because aw puts
death match wrestling on TV but it was
so maligned and when you talk to even
today when I talk to some of the guys
that are you know WWE wrestlers yeah
they'll be like oh I hate that [ __ ] it's
kind of it's got like tattoos and
scratchers you know like people
professional yeah yeah yeah or or like
um or like I I I was telling my friend
I'm like yeah you got to look at what
you're doing you're like Iron Maiden and
they're what they're doing is is psycho
sin or yeah or like Napal death maybe
even where it's it's not the same it's
but it's it's valid and there's people
that that like it and yeah it is
definitely extreme and it's it's weird
to watch because you know this person is
going to suffer for this afterwards like
permanently permanently like every
single person yeah every single person
needs medical attention after wrestling
and the the compensation for the level
of suffering is completely out of whack
yeah I makes no
sense
just yeah that was uh it was fascinating
for me I'm still fascinated by what
motivates that like I've got a lot of
friends that that are those kinds of
wrestlers or do that kind of wrestling
and uh yeah it it is such a uh a weird
subsect of a already strange culture
yeah how much do you think that came in
to inspire what you didn't [ __ ] up oh
the blading and stuff yeah because we we
when we first started playing
shows I would like hit myself with a
microphone and try and bust myself open
the hard way like Wesley Willis does
yeah did and sound guys [ __ ] hated
you I bet hated me yeah I bled very
little had massive bruising and severe
headaches afterwards and I was working
in a video store at the time and there
was this guy Glenn stelter legendary
Toronto Zen maker and play guitar and a
bunch of cool bands too and he had this
crazy VHS tape collection about
everything but a lot of wrestling stuff
and I'm like how do they bleed like that
like what are they
doing to get that he's like ah they uh
they take aspirin and and uh cut
themselves with the razor blade I'm like
what like yeah yeah yeah and he's like
this pretty
now it's all so so quaint like you just
type in how do they bleed on the
wrestling but at that point it was like
what he's like yeah yeah they take a
little blade he's like pointing one see
they right there and I'm like oh [ __ ] so
I can't remember the first
time I did
it but it bled like a [ __ ] and
it bleeds like anytime you see anything
of me and I'm just covered in blood like
yeah there's that MTV Canada performance
where just sheets of blood are coming
off my head that's always the blade the
blade is like only yeah and then I think
I also kind of tried it's weird because
they're almost hardcore specifically is
almost antithetical to like wrestling
because wrestling is the presentation of
a character and sort of the manipulation
of reality manipulation of reality
whereas I think hardcore is about trying
to obviously manipulate reality and and
you're you're definitely not presenting
fact but you're trying to be as real as
possible and as authentically yourself
as possible and you're singing about
your own life and you're trying to
present yourself as a real person on
stage L you be the Misfits or yeah yeah
or something like that right like and
that's that's kind of like what you're
trying to do so I think during the songs
wrestling definitely influences it but
in between it's like almost the
resistance
to be a guy up there cutting promos yeah
like okay yeah I don't want to be doing
that I want it to be as like real as
possible in between the songs so it's
not like some Danzig ass character that
I'm playing out there you want more let
me hear
you that would have been excellent
though to see that version of you I'm
sure I have it in me give me you know
enough time on the
road want to sit at the table with the
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out