welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate this is something that we were
talking about before we hit the record
button which was maybe seeing a trend uh
seeing more
nld uh in people's work what do you guys
think about that like you know High lome
have you have you observed like more
interest in nlds recently in like the
American side of
things uh I have I think that's coming
uh from more people being able to homow
uh it's not it doesn't seem like it's
made
any any impact on the commercial Market
uh I've I've been
in yeah I mean I've been in dispensaries
in Maine and Colorado recently and when
you ask for a sativa they'll tell you
they have Sour Diesel and km4 and it's
like you know that's not that's not what
I'm trying to smoke right now man uh but
I think with with the expansion of hom
growing in the US um a lot of people are
looking
for you know weed that they remember
from when they were younger or maybe
just a different experience um in it and
the seeds that I make and the plant that
I grow or I like the effect you know I
want I want weed that I can smoke and it
gets me motivated and makes me feel good
and you know I can I can I can get stuff
done um I like the the Psychedelic stuff
in the weed World um and I think a lot
of people do and a lot of people are
just starting to look for something
different and there's a ton of of good
work going on out there I mean the
the Band-Aid Haze thing is great um
there there's been a kind of a
Resurgence in it and I like seeing it I
wish there was more but I think
everybody should try some of these more
nld plants uh try the effect see where
you where you know it can be
life-changing if you're if you're just
smoking kush all the time or Kim dog all
the time you know and you switch and you
smoke a good mango Haze or a Band-Aid
Haze or Northern Lights Haze something
like that that I mean it it can it can
change your outlook on life you know
you're more present you're uh more
engaged it it's just um I really think
everybody should should get some
experience with it and you know kind of
get away from just the standard dull
High you get from a lot of the modern
genetics man random question for you are
there many blue or Bonnet nldd crosses
that you've done
any any plans for for some that's a good
question I don't know like off the top
of my head I think most of that stuff
was pretty Afghan dominant when I was uh
doing that work I had gotten done with a
bunch of years of doing nothing but
mostly I wouldn't say like truly narrow
Leaf dominant stuff but more leaning
that direction and I think during that
era I was I was taking a completely
different direction because the market
was totally different I'd like to see it
for sure but um I don't know I don't
know how much longer blue cono cash was
the only one I could think that's right
yeah but that one that was like uh that
plant was really weird because it was
narrow Leaf but it was short and
stocky yeah yeah the blue durb put out
some [ __ ] pretty tall [ __ ] man I 8
foot sideways that's one that I forgot
about yeah but still it's like I'm
thinking no no it went a completely
different direction that I thought it
would bar stomped it yeah yeah but yeah
I don't know I don't even know if
there's any plans or stuff like that if
there's any demand for it maybe you know
we'll
see yeah I was just thinking cuz the um
you know the blue side tends to be so
Squat and Afghan you know be it make for
an interesting hybrid
um Wally what's your take on like you
know it it sounds like you've you've
done a lot of nldd work and what's your
sense of its place in like the scene
modern scene do you see that do you see
it like kind of like uptrending now a
bit yeah absolutely it's also I was
going to say too because work like H&amp;L
is doing Crossing it with things people
are familiar with the the cam and stuff
like that and people are smoking that
going oh that that other bit in there
that I'm not familiar with which is the
mango Haze oh I wouldn't mind trying
that you know that that tends to help I
think but um everyone needs to smile
more man you know and and be more
uplifted and happier and that's what
that that's what that stuff's
for that also makes
bigger
what makes your dick
bigger oh now the SEC
out wood yeah numbers just Spike after
that spike in the
num creases the the turgent and and
girth yeah
an up surge now that's for
sure it started here guys it was this
show that started it all the
revolution just some false marketing um
well I mean we've been talking about
nlds but have you have you worked much
with um BLS in your time no not a lot
the best the closest I've had is you
know things like East Coast s Diesel and
that which obviously they're slightly
longer flowering than a lot of the more
pure Afghan sort of things I I was never
much of a fan of it but um my friend Mr
Moon he uh he used um uh Tom's deep
Chunk in uh in in one of his crosses he
made and um yeah I smoked a fair bit of
that but that dream dreamy sort of stuff
that makes you a bit sleepy and hungry
and um wasn't really I liked it you know
cuz I like weed but I don't need to be
sleepy and I could do without eating
sometimes
too that de that that MBS he made man
you just couldn't get away I was cooking
stuff you know like a lasagna or
whatever and then I'm eating stuff while
I'm cooking the stuff and it never even
interfered with the meal I was about to
have is just pegging out the the
munchies severely that stuff
that sour bubble that you worked with
was pretty decent as well I found some
good plants in the sour bubble z99 like
it was pretty D on the z99 like I know
my mate found a couple that were on um
bit more narrow and tall I think I grew
four that were beautiful stocky thumbs
beautiful cush smell big leaf on them
was it yeah massive like Jurassic Park
he yeah yeah that's that's sour bubble
we grew the like palm trees the things
so biggest leafes I've ever seen
actually on on a plan massive yeah I
think get broad yeah that was from um oh
M Ben
chicken oh I kicked him over yeah yeah
that was a good good bug line
yeah the old oh go for brother go oh I
was gonna ask W but forgot when we were
asking about the um all the plant you
working before I forgot to touch on the
L ocean um what was the L ocean the one
that you used in most of the hybrids
what was it like and uh where'd you get
that seed stock from from um a guy BLB
bad lower back and um he lives in that
Province I spoke about already UD onani
in uh in Northeast Thailand and it's
kind of like right beside Lao and um he
had some La friends La ocean friends and
he said this stuff was like the best
sativa he'd ever had and um which
pricked my straight
away and um what do you say they they br
it for a few Generations but then I
wasn't really sure if they meant
generations of cannabis or generations
of the family you know but anyway it
doesn't matter he sent me some and I
grew that and uh man that's fantastic
weed um that sort of stuff that uh you
know today's stuff you know takes you to
zero to 100 in in in like three seconds
this stuff was gentle but it still got
you there you know and um it didn't dump
you like today's stuff does where you
you know you suddenly you're not that
high but you're sleepy and you you can't
be [ __ ] doing anything this stuff you
were just sort of like well I'm not
really high anymore but you you're
better off than you started yeah yeah I
like I like that sort of thing and um on
that yeah I I I was thinking about it
because I remember you asking me
previously and to be honest I have so
much trouble describing that actual
smell um that I can only say it smells
like Asian weed to
me like I can't dissect smells like I
know some guys on the forums and I I
listen to how they do it I [ __ ] how can
they get that out of there it's like my
my nose just doesn't do that for me or
whatever but um it's I guess it's mango
I know that smell in there but I can't
really dissect the rest of it it's just
just like a nice warm
mango Asian sort of smell that like the
skin of a Tha Green Mango sort of thing
more than Sweet Mango spices yeah 100%
got that sour sort of bit in it but
um but I um I I sent some to um oh M
just trying to think of his name but uh
and he asked why I selected why I cross
it with mango Haze which I did and what
was my goal and um Euphoria because they
were both euphoric and I thought they'd
complement one another and yeah they
they did so much so
fantastic is that
mahakala yes that's right yes yeah yeah
he he loved the stuff and he does cool
work he's got a bunch of awesome [ __ ]
acid Haz agreed I think me him and him
and I have got similar sort of tastes
and so that's why he appreciated the the
um La mango and um I sent we you know we
got a lot of local guys here that grow
grow weed uh mostly sativa and um uh
couple of them that have grown that they
they just love the stuff because it just
does the right thing for them and big
plants Good Buds you know with with nice
flowers uh and um resistance to mold etc
etc and their customers they just keep
coming back from all so that's that
that's that Euphoria man you just can't
get enough of it
it's my favorite yeah CU like most
people came up around us in my age came
up on the Inda stuff but I went to um
living in Europe for a bit got up to
Holland a few times and got to try some
of the hazes but my mate's dad he was an
uh importer from back in the day and he
was always just growing all his old seed
stock and it was like never the most
knocky on your ass stuff but it was just
like you're at a party you know what I
mean like it did creep up on you always
beautiful effects yeah was that was my
um interest and that's pretty much my
whole seed collection now I got a little
bit of IND stuff but mostly it's just
you know from yourself High Lonesome
White Buffalo seeds stuff like that
bunch of stuff from Matt bunch of stuff
from um yeah morea sort of Realm but um
I got a bunch of that super La crosses
from you we have to get some over to H&amp;L
as well aric yep you know why we called
it super L I didn't actually call it
super L someone else did but it was uh a
bit of a pun uh with Neville to be
honest because he got everything was
super super silver ha super skunk and so
that was
out makes
sense I had a I had kind of a very broad
question for for both of you um and we
start with high and Lonesome which was
you know if you look back at your
breeding journey I I'm always curious
about the the kind of balance or tension
between
like how do I put it like a conscious
intentional plan
to make something versus like
reacting
um to maybe accidents or like I don't
know kind of like just going with what
you have had at hand does this question
make sense oh yeah yeah so I I always
have uh goals I always write down
projects that I want to do and then I
have this really bad habit of like when
whenever I have a little bit of
space or whenever I really just feel
like it I will pop a whole bunch of
something that's not on my schedule to
do um I right now have a lot of
seedlings that you know I wasn't really
planning on doing anything with uh but
now I I am um so I I try but I kind of
go with my go with my gut go with my
feeling uh on it you know I I don't know
I I don't know that I was planning on
doing a mango Haze project but I I love
those plants you know it's
um it's probably not the best move um
you know for the modern Market to do
something like that but it's what it's
what I wanted to do I I want to make
things that I want to smoke I want to
make things that um you know I think
other people should experience so I I've
tried the goal thing but I'm not very
good at
it yeah it's I feel like everyone must
deal with that that tension a bit of
like oh this is what I thought I was
going to do and then this happened and
then I I ended up doing this instead
right that kind of thing yeah yeah um
when I you know when I popped the mango
Haze I had I had a bunch of super silver
haze at the same time I had a bunch of
the um Neville's men Haze I had a bunch
of Northern Lights 5 Haze um and I kind
of thought I was going to go with
something like you know super silver
haze or Northern Lights 5 Haze but um
the mango Haze was just the one that I
liked the most um it's a it's a great
line I it's like we've said I mean it's
euphoric happy weed makes you feel good
and it definitely it definitely gets you
there um it's it's strong we it's good
and uh I just you know I wanted to see
that mashed up with some of the more
modern stuff to you know get people to
maybe deviate from just chasing clones
and trying out something that's a little
you know a little longer flowering but
has a completely different effect it'll
put you in a different head
space nice yeah I these are the kinds of
questions that like I want to ask more
kind of about how just like how life
impacts your projects and how like you
you know how you deal with that
basically and so yeah Wally same for you
like when you look back on the stuff
you've made and how it's all gone how
much of that was
like how much of that work is was was
you just working to plan versus you just
reacting to what you've been given or
you know what happened at at that
particular
time H it's probably 5050 but I I like
H&amp;L I go into everything with a with a
goal in mind and um it's it's about my
tastes and likes really but not
everybody has those I guess so I also
make other stuff and um so I I test
everything out but I I give it to
everyone else to test to and see what
they like you know and um not everyone
has the same taste as me so some stuff
that was unintentional and just an
accident can end up being something
that's appreciated more than stuff that
I've had a goal to do you know um my my
my like is I guess similar to a couple
of the guys here maybe all of you but I
like sativa dominant stuff and um not
everybody does but um so we have to give
them options I suppose I I don't mind
something that gives them gives get you
to sleep too you know we all have to do
that at some point
but yeah of course well what about you
Matt like in with your work Matt how how
much of it would you say it's like okay
this this was all like planned intended
I got there I didn't get there versus
like oh yeah I had no idea it just
happened I I like to think that
everything was planned but I think I
Stumble [ __ ] my way through like the
first decade of doing anything
realistically I don't know how much of
it actually met goals um a lot of it was
just simp like especially in the
beginning was simple like I want to make
a you know like a for example stealth
Autoflower or um especially during the
the era where purples weren't as popular
or at least true breeding magenta
purples uh definitely that was all
intended um but like the end yeah I
don't know how often I met goals like up
the blue bonnet stuff but that's just
because it was so easy I think like
realistically to set a goal meet it be
happy with it so yeah I think I just
stumbled through everything the most
part or I could lie and say yeah was
[ __ ] from the beginning
yeah all work out [ __ ]
Stellar I mean no I think it's really
interesting and I don't think there's
anything wrong obviously with with with
having to you know deal with some
Randomness right or chance in life
they're both valid um D I mean yeah
people make like I look at 90% of the
market and these [ __ ] [ __ ] for brains or
you know like Crossing whatever to
whatever as long as it's cookies
releasing it bam it's elite so it's a
valid way of doing things I can't really
you know piss on it for the market
they're probably making more money and
have more interest and fame than any of
us will ever get but at the same time
it's not something I'm totally into but
I get
it I guess it's you know I I I I guess
there's like a sweet spot right um
somewhere it reminds me of like making
art or making music where there's going
to be a degree to which you have a plan
and there's going to be an element to
which like something's going to happen
that you're not expecting and it might
be good or it might not
be and I think that's just life I
guess yeah yeah do you plan to return to
any sativa stuff Maddie in the future
like that badana tie um it's got a lot
of [ __ ] esteem behind it I would have
loved to get to that have you got any
like stock that you could work forward
or I have so much um just even even like
heirloom land race stuff that I've
collected over the years but like also
as I've as I've learned more it's it's
it's harder for me to pop some of that
stuff knowing it's not in the right
climate and that I'm not going to see it
as it was intended
so expression wise I don't know how
valid it would be to like run it try to
make data points off of it use it
knowing how plastic cannabis is you know
and in expression I mean you know so it
could be hit or miss everywhere I'd like
to do more but the market suck so bad I
don't know I mean it is changing it's
definitely changing I mean high and
loansome stuff selling really well um so
yeah I'd like to do more of it but I
mean I don't really do much right now as
it is so we'll see see how the next year
goes yeah we'll have to I mean the first
thing is to get you smoking again right
yeah that's happening sooner than later
I'm I'm telling you I'm snapped I'm
fully snapped on not
smoking what about yourself W how a
cheeky bong are you still on the break
for the wal no still breaking it I uh I
thought if I if I that Thailand move
that I spoke to you about that um i'
have to get like a vape or something
because you know you just got to got to
get into it when you're doing that sort
of thing but uh oh bloody o mate yeah
um I'm still still happy not in vibing
but um and I have a bong here uh for
guests and you know I'll give them some
weed and here's a bong you know and uh
you know they can get high because I
like getting people high that's
not that
fast [ __ ] I don't know how many times
I've been but one or two
times yeah just a few yeah right a
couple of times the toes in the water
it's all right
mate so we have we have a couple of like
pretty fun more like just questions
about you know uh life history the
forums you know Thailand again um but
was there any other recent work that
either of you wanted to talk about that
you've
done before we move on you got H
now um I've I'm always doing something
um I I've kind of been going back
through some of the appalache crosses
here recently um I just finished a
pollination with uh I called it Southern
Gothic it was Irene appalachin that one
was it was definitely not a Nar leaf
type I mean it's a very strong indicia
type plant but uh I hate I hate the Iran
plant I wanted I wanted something with
some of those characteristics but
without having to grow Irene uh so um I
I went through some I I kept a couple
plants around to maybe maybe mess with
some femin stuff down the road but you
know mostly just for head stash and um
while I was doing it I I made some
crossers I CED to some narrow Leaf stuff
uh I crossed to Sour Diesel so I've uh
I've started popping that stuff now and
looking through some of that uh I have a
above a hybrid I'm messing with now as
well uh I'm in a weird position you know
I I like like to smoke a lot of sativas
but it kind of drives my wife crazy when
I don't have a bunch of indicas around
as well so I kind of my you know like
for the last few months it's been a lot
of a lot of haze hybrids um that we've
been smoking and I feel like I have to
do something else to appease that side
of my life um but you know there's some
there's some cool stuff um but I do plan
on on
doing doing some more sativa stuff um I
mean I plans going out in the next you
know month or two I'll be pollinating
some of
that nice and and Wally any any anything
else you want to say on any recent work
that we haven't touched on yet yeah I
just tossed a bunch of stuff in actually
some of it was h&amp; L's um East Coast s
appala but um some uh deep chunk OG sour
z99 whole bunch of stuff with s sort of
gasolin notes and then I put in um that
um that stuff I think might be webbed
hybrid because if those things if it is
that stuff then we're just going to up
the octane of those other things by
Miles if we we make make some crosses
with it so thought i' give it a for that
one yeah I thought I'd give it a go so
because people like that [ __ ] I that was
my real other than Liker tyers that you
know high octane massive strong turps I
was all over that stuff I loved it the
stronger the better
absolutely just if it didn't melt the
paint off the wall when you blew it out
[ __ ] she wasn't strong
enough yeah it sounds like it sounds
like it smelled Death Star which I know
y'all probably haven't seen that down
there but that's a really just
offensive yeah over the top I mean it's
like it's it's an insane plant I The
Taste doesn't come through but the smell
is so strong it smells just so fouled
that's the one thing with it the taste
yeah you're right the taste just doesn't
hit what the notes hit in the in the
smell for sure the the high also I I
don't think lives up to the smell no um
I think you know it would be really good
paired to like a kimy or something if
you want like that that nose but like
taking it up a level potency wise um but
yeah that's going to accentuate the
Aromas yeah
yeah you know I like that
too you got plans to dip into any of
your old like Tha or Le ocean seed stock
well no no it's just not the right time
of year I I can't get them to flower
outside at the moment and uh I want to
see how they do
outside uh because I don't know those
sort of things they don't really like
indoors and I I can't see how they do
well enough you know I can't see a
proper representation I want to see what
they how they go outside so I'll have to
wait till the later time of year when
our hours are heading downwards because
um I got a whole bunch of stuff like um
mango thae and chocolate thae
and um couple other things I must have
like about 10 or 12 at least sort of
thae stuff I've been sent and then
several LA and um some Mull and bimy
Madness as well but yeah it's just not
the time for those and um I'll save what
I think good in in what I'm doing now
and maybe I'll hit them with some you
know some LA and stuff like that and
make some repos and [ __ ] I in I need a
bigger fridge oh I just thought of
something a long time ago I mean it's
probably well over a decade ago we
talked about the Papu Nini gold oh yeah
pan gold yeah yeah yeah what do you know
about that I mean it's not really talked
about much by anyone but I know like for
for a lot of people it's a white
whale ah I had some I lived in p&amp;j when
I was a little kid and but um I had a
guy
uh uh when I lived in Melbourne I had an
Indian friend visit up here where I am
now and he bought some back some PNG
gold and um I grew it indoors and uh it
was hard to control it was a real uh uh
whipping chair sort of thing as you went
in the doors you know back back
yeah and
um man that stuff
was amazing beautiful stuff so resinous
for like a land racy sort of thing you
know yeah and um such a strong beautiful
smell but um I have some stuff labeled
PNG I'll grow them and I'll see what
they look like but I don't know it's to
they don't have like you know seed shops
or anything over there so it's a bit
it's a bit random and you know you
probably get something called that from
there now but it may not have anything
to do with what we used to know it as
you know
yeah I think that's how it goes
sometimes E Yeah well if you find it put
me on the docket for it it's always
stuck with me you talking about it and
it always sounded super [ __ ]
interesting oh beautiful fruity
resinous
delicious you know the stuff that sticks
in your memory you know that's always
the good stuff hey and that stuff's
definitely in my memory that PNG call
beautiful stuff and it's such a unique
part of the world oh yeah crazy bit
crazy but it's a bit messed up once
bloody the
Western you know influence took a hold
of it over there it really didn't fa so
well see they having RS and stuff at the
moment that's they're having like riots
and stuff at the moment there' been some
natural disaster and yeah that the stink
bug weed mate that PNG gold you know
that stink bug weed that you talked
about no I don't think it was the same
no this was really fruy resonance okay
sort of stuff uh I GRE trying to think
when when that was must have been like
in the late 80s early 90s I was growing
that indoors but um I've got some stuff
actually here from a friend um of
overgrow who who's a local where I live
He's do living now but um he sent me
some stuff that he said it's it's it's
PNG crossed with our local wheed and um
he he rates it pretty highly especially
where mold resistance is concerned
because the area he lived in it just
rains all the time and uh um if a if a
plant can like survive there it's like
bulletproof and uh I'm pretty sure to
PNG stuff would have to be pretty rain
tolerant rain's a lot there it's a
jungle yeah yeah it's right on the
Equator so like the turnaround from
Seasons you know the I think my I
remember my mom saying was like uh only
two weeks of the year it's it didn't
rain at 4:00 every day but the rest of
the year it did you know it's like you
could set the clock by it every
afternoon 4:00 bang There was the
rain damn it have to be special for that
yeah yeah I reckon yeah but yeah save
them saving stuff like that uh I don't
really have
uh a good hope of them doing it you know
it's it's all very random
stuff
yeah even worse than
us right
I had a well booze had had a question
about um you see the state of your seed
collections the two of you um do you
want to tell us a bit about what that's
like uh while you you you mentioned the
fridge earlier you know how much of the
seed have you had to feed the birds you
know I don't know like how much stuff do
you guys
have you lost your seed collection at
one stage didn't you all like the the
main sort of one that you collected over
the years
I think at two stages or more sometimes
I don't know but uh I've I've gotten
some back from other people at times and
then you know after that you've
collected a whole lot more which I did
but um yeah I probably got um a few
kilos at least of seed I've got a whole
I've got a whole fridge that's dedicated
to to seed um but a lot of it's like
herbs and vegetables and and stuff like
that and uh it's it's it's the fridge I
don't open as much I tell a lie because
I keep the beer in there too I was going
to say not the not the bloody beer
fridge yeah it's the coldest one man so
it's the best for
it it does get cracked open now and
then
funny what about you H&amp;L what's your
stat like now it's I have a lot a lot of
uh a lot of seeds I lost mine um
probably I don't know 13 or 14 years ago
I had a fire and lost a ton of stuff um
but I've rebuilt it to all that it was
and more um I have a lot of
things from friends a lot of you know a
lot of things from breeders that I like
and then I have an ungodly amount of
things that I've made that I need to
look through um
it's you know I'm always trying to find
a
better organizational system but it's uh
it's the better part of a fridge and um
even some of the the older stuff I have
I have it in a deep freeze stored away
um which you know I've had good luck
with pulling stuff out of there and
popping it uh you know it just trying to
trying to beat time or slow down time
because there's a ton of stuff I have
that I really want to check out and dive
into but especially with some of these
longer flowering things I mean you got
to set aside half a year or more um just
to you know check out a line so I have a
pretty giant collection that I will
never get to 75% of
I think that sounds like everybody yeah
be yeah I like like Wally said kilos of
seeds yeah do you like want to sort them
in like the year that I made or the the
variety that when you come up with a why
I do it let me know that's why I need
to I keep thinking I find something but
it never really works out I have stuff
in jars I have stuff in vials I have
bags I have all kinds of things it's not
there is no standardized system in my
I'm exactly the same it's all over the
show that's why I lose stuff you go to
look I know it's in here but oh
yeah yeah yeah what about Matt Matt
what's the state of your collection like
I mean there's a bunch of [ __ ] it's it's
big bags like I don't know 10 gallon
Ziploc bags stuffed in a fridge totally
unorganized so yeah I you know me I
don't organize [ __ ] so when people ask
for certain things I'm like yeah I got
that and it'll take me a year or two to
find it poor poor local keeps wanting BR
the the C Mist the old original pack of
C mist from serus I'm like yeah I got
that I got that every time I pull it out
and go to send it to him I lose it so
yeah I feel bad it's how it goes
like is it like the first round CI
missed first drop yeah it's it's man
it's um well I don't know about first
drop but it was 2 I want to say it was
99 to 2000 when it was made I asked a
sign based on the catalog number so it's
just right there at that at that period
where it's still probably a valid pull
of it oh yeah you need to find those I
know yeah bad do you see that Cali M F2
I put in the chat no that I posted up
okay I got some old stock from a fell
from Maine um I'm kicking like 30 to shy
kids he was looking for some mail so see
if we can find something to hit to the
the old stuff but um hell yeah I've got
some I've got like another 40 I've got
more than enough [ __ ] to get to so if
you want to take them H&amp;L I can flick
them over yeah dude and give give them
to your
son get him going on it I think there's
project four or five left in the
original pack so it's like will it pop I
don't know but um the AK47 were from the
same year that were reproduced so I I
imagine they'll pop but we'll see
yeah we're going to have to leave our SE
collections in our will to to the next
poor bastard yeah I know was going to
local
yeah funny fishing law collection and
seeds pass yep yep oh [ __ ] I don't know
who's getting my glass dildo collection
but they're going to be a rich man you
promised them to
make rich rich man what are you putting
out H&amp;L this year for cuz what June at
the moment have you got a bunch of haze
Cuts in depth at the moment or what are
you planning on growing sa no in in my
depth right now it's more well actually
I do have A5 out there um but I
have some Sour some
Shoreline uh the fcut
OG uh EB a bunch of a bunch of things uh
but I do have a second round lined up uh
for my full term and that is
uh kind of all over the place I have a
lot of super silver haze I'm doing
because that's kind of a standby
probably do an increase on those as well
because um you know it's about that time
uh I popped some of the sweet
PE
um Band-Aid haze from local yeah um
really looking forward to trying that we
we went on a fishing trip recently and
uh it was a bunch of us and
um that God that the sweet pea and the
bandaid Haze were the the hits um we
were smoking pretty hard on those um
good old Rob Clark was there smoking
pretty hard on those is a really good
time uh do you like
the I do it's you know it's a bit heavy
for me it's like bedtime lead um yeah
there indicas like that I can't yeah you
know I can I can smoke them if I keep
going and smoking them throughout the
day I'm fine but if I let it lag a
little too long I just want to take a
nap yeah sure so so i' I've gotten to
the point where that's kind of like
that's stuff I smoke when the Sun goes
down I don't um I I can't smoke it all
day like I used
to um but yeah I popped all that um
there's uh some stuff from Louch the
C5 uh Destroyer which sounds incredible
um I popped some more of Wally's uh
Neville's Haze mango Haze because that
one uh that one ended up being really
really good smoke um I kind of I I dried
it and you know cured it and I put it in
jars I smoked a little bit of it and I
was like oh yeah that's cool it's you a
little Ser pentalene to it um but very
Neville's Haze leaning and I I kind of
just left it
um for probably six or seven months five
or six seven months something like that
and uh then I I got back into it
recently and that [ __ ] will I mean it
makes your forehead sweat you gotta like
you got to go out and take a walk um
that that shit'll knock you on your ass
it's very racy very strong um get a
moving weed uh so I pop some more of
those cuz uh they they did well outdoor
here um it actually it triggered a lot
quicker than mango Haye so they ended up
finishing before the mango Hayes which
surprised
me what was that the C5 Neville was it
H&amp;L no that was the nevel's mango oh
mango did you make a C5 did you make C5
nevs yeah um C5 mango Nevels yeah that's
I this them they were um but um I tell
you what I I wonder if my friend that I
grew with didn't mix some seeds in
didn't put end up with some L mango ones
in there because the difference between
the flowering on some and the others man
was like six weeks different which I
don't know maybe that's like a Neville's
hazy leaning thing who knows but just
seemed like [ __ ] miles out but uh
really good though like
fantastic but um uh the Neville's Haze
surprised me a little bit with its early
maturing and I I've seen some from
Shanty go the you know long distance but
other ones were quite early and I always
wondered maybe there was an F2 or
whatever but you know I'm not to say
anyone's the purity of anyone's stuff
but um is that one you did an increase
on I didn't I only had uh I got a little
bit of Neville's haes from a friend
online which he said he it's pre
20102 and for some reason that's a cut
off for people where they think it might
have been different after that whether
it was or not I no idea
but still a large large Cola you know
earlier maturing larger Cola not not as
satar as
some other people I've seen grow you
know what I mean but you know it's not
not really an F1 so you can have [ __ ]
a lot of uh differences in
them a lot of variation yeah we it's uh
it's we actually uh could finish most
fenos of Neville ha here I mean You' get
the frost hitting them a little bit but
it you know you could get them done here
uh pretty consistently it
was yeah than you think outdoor yeah you
find it really strong super
strong uh yeah but to me it takes a
while um like as they cure they get
strong yeah uh you know the Neville in
particular the A5 is like that too um
yeah you know if you smoke it fresh it's
okay um but with a lot of this longer
flowering uh lines I I'll let them cure
for months before I really get into them
and they you know they get better with
age yeah 100% I agree always better
those ones with
age well this has been probably one of
my favorite conversations um on the show
so far I've been really loving it um
really happy you know that the two of
you can ask each other questions and
stuff as well um obviously with plenty
of um input from Boo and Matt as well um
if you guys want I thought we could move
on to this section on the forums because
I know that both H&amp;L and Wally and of
course Matt um have all spent good
amount of time on the
forums um boo do you want to kick this
one off booze these are mostly your
questions yeah brother also I will note
I might have to say an Irish goodbye
soon but you know I'll slide Dr yeah
easy yes SL up the back door like a
devil in the
night Wally what were some of the first
forums that you were jumping on mate
because I know I think you said that
African um lady that you found was on
some Aussie Forum right or was that just
the no this thing called leaf leaf I
think something like that I don't know
how I ended up there I'd no long got a
computer man so it's like look up weed
forums or chats or talks or whatever and
um yeah it was like some something
called Leaf I think and and that's where
I met that African chick and um she
wanted to uh oh she had an ad there to
selling African weed right and so i'
I've messaged her and said do you
guarantee this stuff ever arrived you
know and she said well you so cheap why
not try it and it was it was cheap as F
so and it was Prett 9 911 too so I think
borders like you know got a bit stricter
after that but during those times um
things were a little bit more open and
um so yeah I I sent her some money and
said yeah I'll have some of your Durban
Poison and some of your swasi or
whatever it was she had and um and it
arrived and I got it and uh weed was a
little bit average but but then I said
to her do you ever get any hash and yeah
she had some uh couple of sorts of hash
and uh she sent me me that and it
arrived and
uh she was a she sent me some pictures
she was a hot chick this hot little
blonde girl and um see yeah I sent her
seeds and I sent her weed the weed never
arrived to her but she can have whatever
she wants yeah
exactly but I I did have a friend in
Africa too in South Africa there and um
he's nearby I think it was Johannesburg
I think so uh he said look I'm not that
far from this chick uh give me her
address I thought yeah yeah anyway so I
gave her the address and and he said
yeah this chick she's packing she she's
got kilos and kilos a week she's like
some [ __ ] big dealer girl you know
the dagger yeah man and um he said I I
sent her some ducks foot and he said she
has got this plant in the front yard of
her house it's like eight foot tall and
like 8 foot round with these [ __ ]
golf ball buds all over this this Ducks
foot that I'd sent her and he you could
smell it through the neighborhood and
she was she you know didn't seem to care
and um so and at the same time at this
other dude on the same forum and he he
kind of like linked me up to overgrow
and um and also to Gypsy but he was a
little bit strange and Gypsy even said
man this guy's a bit weird so yeah he
ended up exiting or whatever and and
that's kind of like how I met Gypsy as
well when Gypsy calls someone [ __ ]
weird
you know they're [ __ ] up you know yeah
yeah so yeah that's how I met him and
how I got on the overgrow Forum
initially
so my and like I said I was new to
computers it was like [ __ ] early
2000s so it's probably 2000 I I had like
the
millennial uh edition of um [ __ ]
Microsoft you
know so yeah everything was new and
fresh back then
yeah weed and titty pics
yeah
good9 yeah like these auctions back then
[ __ ] some of those auctions some of the
stuff on them you wouldn't believe it
yeah do you remember a guy called Dog
knob dog snob yeah yeah yeah that's a
yeah yeah yeah he was one of the big
buyers on those and that guy um with the
Baba Kush the first guy that come online
with the Baba Kush oh oh oh kid or
OG or kid yeah yeah I SP to those guys a
fair bit and ogre kid I he sent me seed
and I sent him seed and I wasn't sure I
sent him seed and said you know like
[ __ ] whatever and he sent me money he
said he sent me money I never arrived
but then eventually it did and and yeah
no he was true to his word there's like
uh [ __ ] all this American money in
this sachche somewhere and
dogs knob yeah he was he was cool they
used to buy up all those auctions
man dog knob isn't that Ortega dogas dog
oh yeah I always get the dogs yeah
you're right yeah yeah this is dog's
knob like dog's dick yeah yeah
yeah I don't know how he got that name I
don't know sure what he was looking at
when he [ __ ] come up with that name
he just made me cough out my bong G
[ __ ]
H what I call
myself yeah know I haven't so heard from
him for a while but I still hear from
Moon I just heard from moon yesterday
and um like he was in some trouble for a
while because New South Wales is not a
good place to grow weed and get caught
[ __ ] there down there [ __ ] K got
done down there too yeah s s Moon might
love dude he was one of the few people
on um Mr Nice that always had my back
and like even even before we were
friends
he uh went out of his way to have my
back and make sure I didn't get [ __ ]
by a few people super cool dude always
appreciated him him and smoking moose
really nice gu smok was a legend good
man he's passed on now that's too bad
yeah now he's a good man and uh Moon I
said he hadn't been doing anything for a
long long time he stopped smoking and
[ __ ] and then I I took I don't know how
many years before I went [ __ ] I'll try
this number that I've got of his and and
might be him still you know was like
years and years later and when he
answered the phone yeah it's him he's
kept the same number that's awesome yeah
and I sent him a bunch of seed he said
he wanted to get back into it so he's
busily uh growing and selecting as we
speak that's awesome yeah it would be it
would suck to lose a dude like that like
in the in the scene because he's a a
special dude and and he he loves it you
know he just just loves it so much
people with that sort of passion uh we
need them
absolutely there's still a few around
which is good like it's been a bit of a
Resurgence lately like people popping
back up or I mean you might you might
have lost contact with anyone but like
getting to meet um bucket bongs and uh
Southern Sun seed sunny and stuff like
that it's awesome there's still people
kicking around doing good Stu I'm in a
chat with them a permanent sort of one
of those Instagram things you
know and uh so I hear from bucket all
the time actually he's cool he's a nice
man
yeah he's a legend yeah I'm try catch
than some of us some of us reserved you
know we don't yeah we're going alone a
little bit but this guy he's [ __ ] an
excellent social man you know what I
mean he he could do one of these a
breeze whereas some of us introverted
sort of fellows it's a little bit harder
for us you know yeah you get used to it
you get used to it it's just a bunch of
Dick jokes bro
yeah absolutely that's all it is
[Laughter]
dick jokes and
weed titties titties yeah yeah I mean
for you straight guys
but funny did you ever have much
interaction with um the boys down in nen
like I know you said you went to the
caner cup that one year um I think
that's the Year Jason King was there
which is funny but did you ever get to
see any of Mal's gear Tony bers oh I met
Tony uh [ __ ] he his weed was really good
I had a couple of B with him fantastic
weed it was of the uh of the lot of them
the best I had down there yeah really
and
um yeah really nice man really good guy
and then that other guy
um
Cog I know there's two like a a 20 foot
tie guy do you know him 20 footer
whatever his name was him I met him and
um
and uh [ __ ]
talk [ __ ] you talk underwater that
guy guy you know [ __ ] very passionate
and um who else the uh I asked at the um
like Oasis Cafe I think it was like one
of the popular like hangout places about
um M
adman and they know they knew him and um
but they said they hadn't seen him at
that point so I never got to meet him
but um
yeah uh else say the guy that ran the
um they had like a Cannabis Cup there
thing and the guy that ran that I can't
remember his name maybe it was
that as well yeah yeah there's a German
um Cheo a German fell that lived down
there for ages too well I took some I
took some hash with me and like um
really good hash and and I so I go to
like do this entry with him and and he
says we we don't even have a
h you know a category for that and um
but we'll take it you know I said oh
yeah okay and so we get to like there's
all the photographers in that do looking
at the you know the entrance and I look
at this hash and I think it's not like
the ball I gave him I'm sure you know
it's like a gram you know and he comes
over to me and says he says I'm not
[ __ ] putting that hash that's just
Prime we're keeping that [ __ ] we just
put a little bit
in funny
Bugger I think that was the year that
Jason King was there for canb Bible 2 or
three I it was canb Bible 2 because I
remember seeing I think I sent you a
photo cuz your golden pineapple was
canab 3 but in number two there was a
pick of him in Nim with like um they had
like bunch of Mr knce so G13 hash plant
crosses they had um Tony's Blackberry
which I always wanted to see the Malay
one um and they had one picture of a bit
of hash on a table so I Reon that's the
year that you were there oh
yeah yeah know that probably is to be
honest like I would have thought that
you know it would have been the
strongest of everything they had there
and maybe it was but it didn't score as
well because I heard a bunch of them
complaining that they couldn't judge
anything after that it [ __ ] them up
and
whatever [ __ ] up the
tolerance yeah yeah I haven't been down
I used to go often like I went for years
cuz when I come back from Europe um the
only weed I could find was just that
[ __ ] pgr [ __ ] and I was like n not
smoking it like that's what I come up on
basically um from like an you know early
age that's all I saw and then when I
went to Europe they had in Switzerland
mostly Albanian weed but it was pretty
good man it was just obviously some
Dutch stuff that they were growing and
then going to Amsterdam too so then
coming back home only having access to
that I was like I'm not going to do so I
pretty much went to niman like every two
weeks for [ __ ] years just go back
down back and forth back and forth like
cuz there was always good stuff like
people rag on it but if you like know
someone down there like when the lane
boys were there they had fantastic pot
and then um afterwards you could always
find good stuff too if you know like you
going to but I haven't been in the dogs
age now but I'd like to go back and see
if I could find Tony or something
because yeah he had some good stuff yeah
the key is to knowing someone otherwise
you're just going to end up with some
rubbish to perhaps unselected rubbishy
sort of that's it's what they like they
said when I spoke with them a little bit
about it that it's just from the
tourists you know that they they just
want to make some money out of their
rubbish or whatever but
uh yeah M I think um we're probably
going to have to get his both back on to
do another one because there like we
barely even got to half the stuff we got
like four er stuff to get to as well but
I know there's one question I'll
probably let H Chanel wrap on it um that
we wanted to touch on mate uh Alie
Stanley uh who was bear from the
Grateful Dead is the sound engineer who
built like you know the wall of sound
and that lived up by you like that Ceda
Bay commun um did you have much to do
with him I know that would have been my
my my my place Ceda Bay I don't know if
he's but he lived in um uh out here at
um the Walsh River um bear apparently
there was going to be a a mini ice age
and um that was the [ __ ] the place to
be or some some [ __ ] something about no
earthquakes were going to be there but
um all the young people like
particularly my son um they all got
stuck into his ass at day and um so they
are like doing my weed and my hash and
ousley's acid at the same time and I
said to the boy [ __ ] you guys are
spoiled like no one gets that you
know anyone anymore and there you you
young [ __ ] like they're just
teenagers man they're into this uh
liquid acid on [ __ ] on on sugar cubes
and uh and [ __ ] like that and yeah man
they they had they did pretty well for
they're like a a younger version of
older people the some of the here you
know they lived a life that they you
couldn't live anymore especially that
time you know yeah lucky
[ __ ] yeah he was a bit of a strange fell
that guy I saw I'm uh I never really
knew him but I saw him at he's at M 10
all the time and I was
like yeah and uh there he is he's like a
little fell he's not a big man he was
just a little blood and I remember
looking at him and thinking this dude's
like on something and uh he's looking at
me like and I could see the look in his
face and he's singing the same about me
Fu this dude's on something you
know yeah that was that's incredible
that's
incredible he died in a car accident he
[ __ ] and ran off the road what they call
that uh
aquaplaning uh yeah kind of like aquip
plan and uh he's he had several wives
they lived in like little commune and
like you know he's a couple of wives and
and the wives like just like move next
door build a house he gets another wife
or whatever bit [ __ ] weird is his
original wife did she come over with him
did his original wife come over with him
because I think she was the chemist
like absolutely yeah that that was the
lady making the stuff yeah you know she
and she's still alive as far as I know
and she's the yeah she was the original
one but then he had some other yeah just
out the back here yeah and um I I I got
offered to buy all his stuff after he
died so I went out there to check it all
out to get it out of there man what a
mission and then the ex-wife she kind of
like wanted a fair bit or the Widow
whatever and um she never mentioned she
had [ __ ] leaders of acid but I
probably would have grab those cuz they
probably
EAS
goodness hell
yeah I said H&amp;L we got to get fishing
you me Denali we go visit
Wally hell yeah catch some bar and see
if we can find Al's
misses yeah that sounds great tsi's been
wanting to head over to Australia too
like super bad so yeah you guys got to
get yank him in on it too
Expedition us you know how to find us
man that'd be
amazing all right Brothers easy well
I'll M POS you to wrap up man but this
has just been an absolute treat for me
yeah man it's it's a it's a blast
especially being able to finally see
Wally in person and talk in
person yeah yeah yeah better look in
me yeah it's great great great talking
to you w yeah you same man same and it's
always a pleasure with h H&amp;L I love you
dude um is there anything you guys want
to want to plug uh any way people can
contact you if you want to be [ __ ]
contacted by Peoples you know any of
that Wally no just Instagram man I'm on
there Wally d2000 there we go
H&amp;L yeah I'm on Instagram and I'm pretty
regular on the reader Syndicate Discord
when time allows but yeah sure this time
of year it's a pretty big time but yeah
I'm I'm around you you can find me just
got to
look and of course you can find
everything at right seeds.com also at
gerby seeds in Australia for all you
Aussies we have right Eco Europe we have
uh our buddy at lifted lftd seeds and um
yeah with that thank you guys so much
this is G be an awesome few episodes and
uh love to have you back again Wally
same with you as always H&amp;L dud [ __ ]
yeah love
absolutely all right Che thanks guys F
want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out