welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
Syndicate welcome to bre Syndicate I'm
Matthew here with my co-host
thousandfold and today we're going to be
having a few special guests one of them
is uh a brother of mine high and
Lonesome who most people know uh he's
been on the show before and he's a part
of our crew and just one of our best
friends and uh boozy would you introduce
our other guests please other Steam
guest sitting here with a block that
needs a little introduction our mate
Wally duck um another oy Legend he's uh
done a little show before so thought
we'd get him on and delve a bit deeper
into his history in the scene he's uh
one of my favorite BLS besides being a
guy to go to about info like a mentor
he's a good mate as well so happy to
have W here
today yeah excellent so yeah so pleased
to have both of these guys on um it's
hard to get high and low someon I will
say that and I'm gonna Pat myself on the
back well no it's actually booze this
whole thing was actually boo idea I
should give Boo the credit for
that so I thought as a little Icebreaker
maybe Wally could just talk a little bit
about how he got started and then same
high and Lonesome just to point out that
high and Lonesome does have his own
episode from like maybe a year ago but
we'll get him to you know tell us a bit
more again um so yeah Wally tell us how
you got started to begin with uh like
started smoking weed you
mean yeah growing smoking bre any any of
it yeah wherever you want oh it was a
brother-in-law actually and um I was
pretty young he was a real Stoner and um
I was just sitting with him in the
lounge he's he's passed a joint to me uh
some tie stick in a joint uh I think he
he loved getting people High and um it
took me a lot though like uh two joints
and he's like sick of you know giving
weedway at that point
so um and I still wasn't High I had to
kind of like Get Up and and I I went
into another room and when I stepped
down into the next room it just hit me
all at once and um like uh complete
Euphoria you know and uh yeah I I never
looked back after
that fantastic I thought and uh yeah he
was part of me getting growing too
because um his friend had a property and
um
and we couldn't get tie sticks anymore
so we thought we we'd grow our own stuff
so and uh I was about 14 or 15 at that
point and um we grew a fair bit of weed
actually I think I was the only one of
my crew we were just young and we had
like pounds of weed and um everyone else
was still scratching around for a a few
grams you know
[Music]
so what part of Oz were you living in at
the time brother
uh
Melbourne yeah I'm I'm from melb yeah
how were you getting ties to finish down
there like were you starting at indoors
or def no there was there was no indoors
back then we just uh waited forever and
ever and uh it was all just bag seed we
grew and what year was this well like
roughly what period was this 82 83
something like
that oh actually it would be 83 it was
after like uh we had Ash Wednesday do
you remember that or maybe you're bit
young bush fires bit young but yeah yeah
it's before my time as well so it was
just after that and and all the scrub
had been burnt so um there was lots of
open ground at my friend's place so we
all stuck some weed up in the mountain
there and um a some of it took forever
to
finish and um Herm aphrodites and all
sorts of crazy stuff big couple of big
purple plants too and um
yeah it wasn't until it was into winter
where most of these things were
finishing that's crazy what was like the
import scene like at that time like I've
only got a little bit of experience
obviously I started smoking what
20 no 2011 something like that so by
that time it was just bushing Hydra but
you're saying you had like Tai and I
know me M's dad used to get Indonesian
and stuff like that what other stuff was
around at the time that was coming in as
import we mostly got Tai uh we got hash
too though Fair bit of hash all all
different sorts of hash um I don't know
who who imported it like I'm sure like
there was large Imports in containers
and that but I think a lot of the
smaller stuff was just
uh uh Customs weren't as strict back
then and people being able to bring it
with them as far as I could work out
just like um we had Lebanese gold and um
that the the larger import was I think
it was moah hadine hash there's all this
uh you know gold stamp black hash um you
know squishy sort of stuff spongy
Wrapped in Red cellophane and um but but
we we mostly only got Tai where I was in
Melbourne there but we we got the uh the
stuff on sticks for quite a while uh and
then um we got loose stuff in bags uh uh
golden golden buds golden tie golden BHA
they called it yeah which um I I think
that was the best stuff that was I I
remember that the
best did you ever get into that tie
stick book that I are the Smugglers over
in
this yeah and I I've also got those guys
they have a little group on um on
Facebook as well too one of them runs
it so uh yeah know I've seen a fair bit
of
that he was he was he was boasting that
one of the areas where I I like to go in
UD onani
that seems to be one of the places that
was pretty famous for for the to
Sticks
amazing um H LOM you want to tell us a
bit about how you got started in your
journey uh yeah so I started pretty
young as I have noted before um
basically soon after I started smoking
um I come from a farming family and it
was like man we can we can grow this so
um we were getting a lot of brick weed a
lot of Mexican weed occasionally get it
from somewhere a little more exotic
Colombia or something but uh for the
most part it was Mexican weed uh very
low quality um you know green sometimes
but a lot of it brown and just not you
know it did the trick but it wasn't you
know pleasurable to smoke so um started
you know trying to kind of cross over
some of my vegetable growing techniques
to weed and um it worked out you know I
uh I got started growing bag seeds and
um they they finish pretty well um in
Virginia where I am uh you can usually
get them done right around the first
Frost but they're area plants you know
you don't you don't have the density you
have with a lot of these modern modern
lines so you can you can get them done
without getting too much mold or
anything like
that um but yeah started from there then
I moved on to Growing Dutch stuff and um
outdoor that's a whole different ball
game um here you know those skunk one
types Northern Lights types you have
issues with mold just because of density
um so took me a few years to realize
that I was better off growing kind of
thin Leaf varieties more open open
Plants looser bud structure that kind of
thing um but yeah I [ __ ] up plenty
well I
learned is there so we've got we've got
you growing in Virginia and obviously
while they're growing in Australia are
there is there any overlap in like the
climate at all and where you guys are I
don't think so right but you both I
don't believe so
NL I don't I don't think there is um you
know Wally was a huge inspiration to me
on overgrow and IC mag I used to look at
you know his his gorilla pictures you
know his Fields out in the bush and it
was just like man like I want to do that
but um yeah completely different
environment to try to do it in so
yeah yeah d right tobacco in Virginia uh
h and h i yeah to Tobacco corn soybeans
all that stuff um it's a lot of the you
know mass production farming now um but
it's a good climate for tomatoes and you
know some of the traditional traditional
crops the problem here is the humidity
um we have such high humidity especially
um later in the summer and the the fall
so it's um it's kind of tricky you know
you gota you got to work at it to to
make it happen here yeah just when you
don't want it around Harvest time oh
yeah
yeah well can I ask uh I can ask you
both I guess what were some of the first
plants or lines that you grew that you
noticed actually
did exceptionally well in in the
area in my specific area you mean
yeah um the ERS do really well but we
had the same problem as H and now where
at the end of the season here because
we're close to the coast we that that
rain and humidity and so I I I opted for
growing in our dry season because the
the hours are still um you know the days
aren't very long still and um just
anything that would finish at that time
of year and that's how I ended up with
growing c99 actually cuz uh that thing
uh did really well here in that time of
year it uh produced you know fair fair
amount of weed the weed was really good
quality and it didn't rev you know with
the hours increasing like they were so
um that was my so I that's why I made
lots of crosses with c99 I was actually
I was not intent on on making seed for
sale it was actually seeds to grow and
then excess would end up
you know i' send to Gypsy or something
like that
so mate how did you select your c99 mate
like were you breeding it for the
conditions up there because like
obviously c99 had a pretty bloody good
run but I've spoken to a lot of people
and like people that are you know big
into Haze and stuff like that and a lot
of them rate your C c99 stock as some of
the best and I wonder if that's CU you
were breeding it for like a particular
effect or if it was strictly because you
were in that climate you likely
selecting more towards the hazy types or
what was the breeding like on that one
yeah maybe a bit of both but the
pineapple eh the pineapple was what I
was chasing because um the rest of it it
was okay but um when I found a pineapple
it was really you know it's all all nice
smelling good-looking bud but the
pineapple was just staks ahead of the
other stuff in my opinion and um so
that's what I was
chasing pineapple
weed the pineapple the c99 pineapple was
uh always one of my favorite Expressions
it was above and beyond especially
flavor wise to be able and and smell
that in weed was was
phenomenal
hash yeah
right all a f blood y that's incredible
yeah here you know like I said I started
with Mexican bag scine um that did
pretty well here um we I never had major
mold issues you know a spot here or
there um then as I kind of started
looking at more magazines looking online
I decided to order some seeds and give
it a go so I started with some cheaper
stuff some Nirvana stuff Casey brain
stuff um I tried quite a few things and
realized pretty quickly that it was not
suited to my environment there were a
few that were uh Durban Poison did well
um northern lights
Haze uh from Nirvana did well but it
wasn't like an nl5 Haze like like an A5
or a C5 it was it had some skunk one or
something in it it was much quicker yeah
um then what
really started killing it for me outside
was super silver haze um that's that's
the one that really got me you know
feeling like I could I could do
something nice outdoor here so um you
know it was definitely fenos specific
you know some of the longer ones you
couldn't finish some of the like eight
or nine weers you know you could you
could get them done but towards the end
you'd start to see some issues um some
issues with rot just because of the
density of those but um we had a cut
that we kept around that was a really
good outdoor uh really good outdoor cut
and um you know I I'm pretty hard-headed
I still try all kinds of stuff outdoor I
still Tred Bubba outdoor every few years
and um you know it just you can't
consistently get it done well here you
can sometimes but um you know that's why
I favor stuff like super silver haze
outside um appalache line I did and some
of those hybrids do well outside there
are a few cuts that do really well
outside um Shoreline probably
being one of the best uh for here you
know it gets done in time it doesn't
have any issues um you know it's
normally October 10th October 15th
somewhere in there it's done um so it
misses that kind of cool down and the
heavier rain season um but man I'm I'm
just always trying new stuff always
always seeing what works but I do love
doing Haze hybrids outside couldn't pull
off a pure Haze here but Haze hybrids
are kind of where it's at for me
yeah with I had one question about the
Appalachia real quick uh you may have
even touched on it the first time we
spoke to you um not the first time sorry
in your episode last time
um when I think of like a kimd type I
don't think of I don't think of a region
like or you know a climate like the one
you describing um did it take much work
to to get the appy to kind of you know
um
I don't know be okay in that environment
like between between like you know the
trees dog and the green crackers I'm
like those don't sound like the yeah
tell me about that okay so of the Kim
cuts that I've grown outdoor here Kim D
does the best for me um you know kim4 is
bad Kim 91 is just a nogo um they just
melt away um kimd does pretty well
especially if you can um you know keep
it dry towards the end um we've done
hilarious things over the years to keep
you know the October rains off plants um
but uh Green Crack was great because it
was always done so early it triggers
really early here right you know it'll
trigger in July in Virginia um so you
can get that plant you know harvested
before October
so um you know I wanted
to cross the two to try to get something
like green crack with a little more
potency that kind of did double duty
indoor and outdoor here um it's appach
is definitely quicker than kimd um so it
helps there um it's just just a matter
of trying to get it done before October
you
know the first or second week of
October yeah that's really cool I might
even try one of your hybrids over our
summer here later on um just to see how
it how it does is it pretty dry
there
um it's probably like 60 70 uh okay yeah
yeah I think yeah you could it could
handle that yeah you talk an indoor
thousand or Outdoors yeah it's still
indoors but I still have to worry about
it because yeah oh Oh I thought you
talking about outdoor no you're you're
fine into it's pretty it's pretty solid
it's easy it's an easy plant to
please yeah that's super cool um Boos
you had you you listed a few different
lines or cuts that we want to ask Wally
about yeah mate had a few things down so
obviously the first one um probably the
one that you're most known for besides
the c99 was the golden pineapple I
remember seeing that in the canab Bible
3 what was the breeding like on that and
what was the plant like in
general I I don't know how that even got
in
there I didn't know someone you know
years down the track said oh check this
out I had no idea but um that was just I
just had some um gypsy used to send me
seeds all the time and uh there was the
a bunch of um squish whatever lines that
that guy uh what was his name
the the weasel guy Flying Flying
Dutchman [ __ ] Mongoose that's right he
he he he made all release
those yes that's right yeah oh yeah weel
the weasel guy yeah yeah yeah he's scary
he's a scary dude I know I tried to keep
away from that guy I'm glad I did
but um now I just put some in and
seriously that was just like uh it was a
plant that was there at the time and so
it cops some pollen and um it was
nothing intentional with it but um
apparently it came out quite good so uh
and I I grew a bunch of it too but and I
I just shared some with a bunch of guys
and that's how that must have happened I
think there was a cut someone kept
around for quite a while from that as
well too
so still is
yeah I saw something pop up on the canak
banner recently I saw someone had some
golden pineapple cut they were raving
about
um see if we can time isn't it yeah
bloody mate but yeah I said I'll see if
we can get some seeds kick him over
that' be great is it I think uh [ __ ]
um Professor P messes with a golden
pineapple I don't know if it's the same
exact one but yeah
over yeah I'd Wonder I've got some
pineapple field stuff I mate um kick me
I was wondering if it had c99 in it
because it's super pineapple yeah it's
got it yeah another PPP skunk at some
point too I don't know whose it was I
can't remember but there was pineapp
skunk yeah
Green someone had some
pineapp somewhere
yeah was um the
S zaml yeah oh the double sour zaml I
remember I heard you speak about that as
well like a bloody interest in outdoor
hybrid yeah I I I love that East Coast s
diesel that stuff was awesome and um
yeah I've grown some of h&amp; L's I've got
something in now of the appala that
you're talking about east east coast s
diesel cross and yeah I thought that was
going to be pretty good stuff but um the
the Z the zaml I got that from um what
was his name purple purple flowers
Purple Rain I don't know something like
that one of the guys on overgrow on IC
mag sorry and he just sent me all this
sativa stuff uh just out of the blue do
you want this stuff I said [ __ ] yeah
I'll have that and amongst it was a zaml
and um it was Gypsy zaml originally but
I think it was a couple of generations
along and um man that stuff was a beast
it um had this like uh I I known about
it for a while but everyone said it had
a carrot smell and I [ __ ] never like
that carrot smelling
we but this stuff it did it did smell K
initially but um then it ended up with
this like tea tree oil sort of uh pretty
strong Aroma and it was really strong
weed I was really surprised
but it was like a um that creeper weed
it wouldn't grow upwards it' get like a
couple of feet high and then it just
spay down you know all over and I had
this massive Bush of the stuff I I think
I kept that cutting for quite a while
and that's what I used for the initial
um sour zaml and then I I just crossed
it to S diesel again and yeah I've grown
a bit and some other guys I I know have
done that do you know bin chicken you
know bin chicken yeah yeah on the show y
we had him on the show yeah there you go
so he's used it in one of his that
uh what's that thing he's got with the
oh doua isn't it in there I think it is
I think so or one of his things that
he's working with for sure yeah yeah I
know Sal yeah yeah we hadat a bit so and
we do a bit of swapping backward and
forward so um yeah he he really liked it
he liked a fair bit of the stuff I sent
him he said
so did y'all get the East Coast sour
diesel clone down there yeah we got it
off
um I can try to remember his name Santo
that's him yeah he sent it couple of
things down uh East Coast Sour Diesel uh
C5 that's where we got the C5 from and
uh star dog too so um yeah wow I'm
impressed they made it me too I don't
know how they don't know how they got
there but they not
only yeah I
know tried to keep that one as long as I
could and it was actually the S I kept
the sour diesel and it wasn't until
recently that that ended because uh I
had it with a friend and he shared it
with another friend of mine because he
couldn't it wasn't suitable for him
thinking my other friend would keep it
but he never did
so that's how that goes huh yeah it is
sharing's good though that way you know
you might run out of it and old mates
got it over there but it doesn't always
work
exactly always oh sorry thousand go
brother no no you go you go oh I was
just going to say quickly the sour ZL
always interested me cuz I've got this
thing for like sour and ogs paired with
these sativas cuz it's like you know
this modern Uber potent plant that like
isn't a cameo it's got a little bit of
sativa in it these kushers and these
sours so paired with um paired with a a
crazy cver I'm interested to see what
they do outdoor so I've got a lot of
Hope for the um La Kush and the sour
diesel by the mango Haze that H&amp;L did um
like 40 of each of them I'm going to do
a big pop and try and find something
interesting for outdoor because people
always said diesels do well out D so be
able to yeah find something pretty yeah
it's I have I have a really big one
outside right
now it always always does well here for
me um you you can get a few issues but
I've been the last few years I've been
doing them in a greenhouse and um I'm
depping some now they do really well
here that
way yeah
that it's a Kill ker Killer cut and it
pairs well I love the way it pairs up
with divas I'm finishing up a couple of
plants now my mate sunny Southern Sun
seeds another Aussie breeder um he got
the he had the SAA clone as well some
grow on East Coast malum Thai so it's
Sour Kush M tie cross to a k Kush mum
tie that he did so they not a [ __ ]
Speck of mold on him and they got you
know VB stby Co is so going pretty
fantastic and stoked on it hell yeah
this is kind of a nothing observation
but I just wanted to point out um it
seems like Wally's got pineapple and HL
has a lot of mango that's all I wanted
to say I do like mango couple boys in
here yeah Bo so yeah because I think I
was to you go go ahead goel I was just
gonna say you know like I think a lot
more stuff is mango than like some of
our friends like you know our buddy
local has said some of these things are
a little more like cut white grapes
which you know is pretty specific and um
I don't know um but yeah I after he said
that I noticed it in some of the you
know like the EV Appalachia stuff um you
know it it can be a little white grapy
but mango I still get a lot of mango
from Appalachia Green Crack um the mang
mango Haze was surprisingly mango on
some of the
fenos yeah very but yeah I sucker for
mango wonder if mango resists mold for
you there too oh do you think so it
could
um maybe I I don't know you know that's
something I've always kind of wanted to
dive a little more deep into but I
haven't because you know I've always
heard that t pentalene resists mold um
which makes sense to me like in some of
the sativas but then like train wreck
here if you don't take it early molds
pretty hard uh and that's like that's a
pretty terpinolene dominant plant so I
don't know if it's that or it's
something I've always wanted to kind of
dig into but I haven't I've been growing
mids this whole time
instead I wonder if size of the Brack
has something well I reckon it probably
would but I think size of the BR has
heaps to do with it cuz looking at that
Shoreline like it's pretty dense but
those bracks look quite small like in
comparison to like green crack or train
wreck or something like that and same as
with malum tires like relatively small
bracks but very dense flowers so I
wonder that if it's just you know the
the Brack itself that will um rot and
then start to rot the flow out with the
ESS no
idea um I don't know I it's hard it's
hard to say because sour can have
pretty large bracks and that does better
than you know than if you tried to take
Green Crack to the end of October that
just wouldn't work here you know you can
get it the beginning of October um you
know but it's you're not going to get it
at Halloween it's going to be just
melted away um here you know the the
thing that I've noticed with a lot of
people talking to a lot of people over
the last few years is I mean you just
have to have that plant Rock Solid going
into flower you got to stay on it um you
know we get we get
something uh saporia leaf spot uh here
and it's I see it in pictures of plants
all the time and if you get something
like that in a plant something fungal
like that it just weakens the plant so
much that it's it's susceptible to
everything else um so I I try to you
know keep my plants well fed plenty of
calcium and I I spray a lot um
I Don't Spray flour but here it's just
like trying to keep the plant as healthy
as you can going in and you'll see way
less
issues cow mag
baby so was this um
monai as well what's that sorry the MP
from Prof 77 oh is that oh yeah see that
there yeah yeah yeah what about it can
you talk some about it the who it came
from the smell flavor effect growth all
it it did it did come from prop 7 so it
came via I think prop sent it to Bushy
and then bushy sent it to me something
like that and um bushy knew more about
the the Mong part of it I don't know but
as far as I remember um prof's wife who
I I did meet them all and and prof's
wife smoker ever real real Bon head that
lady just like sit in the bathroom all
day smoking bong seriously she she loved
it and she couldn't go anywhere without
a bong we we went away uh for a couple
of days and uh she had to like make up
like an orchie bottle bong you
know brother yeah and anyway so um so we
her dad was a a smoker and I I think the
M tie came from bag seed from him uh we
initially thought he was a grow but I I
don't think he was I think he was just a
toker and uh and they knew they knew M
People I met some M people with them so
uh because I the hill tribe people you
know and um I think that's that's where
that stuff came from and uh you know I
grew some out in the jungle there and um
you know everyone says that uh Ty can
really handle rain the [ __ ] doesn't
like wet Roots much I you know wet it
died several of them died yeah seriously
I it was in an area where like it was
still on a bit of a slope but it was at
the bottom of a slope and so it got wet
feet for just too long and several of
them died but um the higher ones they
went all right and um yeah it was it was
nice weed someone uh that I gave some to
uh rated it as the best that they'
gotten off me and uh they'd gotten a
fair bit of what I thought was good weed
but they they seriously like that stuff
so obviously had a fair bit of
potential but um it's interesting that
it came from bushy or through bushy I
was going to ask you about that because
I'd seen that Kangle was growing it in
that um I don't know if you've seen that
marijuana australiana documentary but I
did I saw it and that that was it the
huge plant yeah yeah yeah and he said oh
no I think that was the oakk and mango
Hayes we said he put a Mong Tha in Lake
and so it was getting like it would have
gone 20 met or something but only got to
seven or 11 or something this year so
yeah okay would have been a big but I
wondered he because if bushy haded if it
was one of the ones that they were using
when they were doing the Outback and
that kind of yeah that's how it happened
yeah I got it through bushy and then I I
think I might have even sent some back
to him because he ran out or I can't
remember there was always a bit of uh
you know two and
fro did you ever a grow Hy tie or SE it
or no well no no one no one can have
that you
mean the the yeah yeah he's not a
sharing man that man he's not nice not
very
literate I've had some problems with
that fell
yeah I'd be like the last guy on Earth
he'd ever share anything with I reckon
yeah I'd be second At Last I would
[Laughter]
guarantee um just a random random
question here which is uh have you spent
much time in in that part of Southeast
Asia W yourself just like to visit yeah
absolutely yeah I've been at EES
probably a dozen times at least to um
Thailand and and round around too like
all you know Northeast West South and
um mostly in the Northeast where where
they used to grow the tii sticks and I
married a woman from there from the
Northeast it's called isan the area in
the Northeast there and um
each each section of Thailand's little
bit different you know the the cultures
and and the food and and even the
languages uh vary a bit and um in the
isan area they uh they eat some crazy
stuff like um frogs and um
bugs and uh frogs are frogs are pretty
good I have to say having tried frog
before it it reminds me of
poultry the [ __ ] [ __ ]
no for real it's like chicken like small
chicken yeah frog frog LS are pretty
good yeah yeah I just weird not eating
frogs missing out
dude super spicy food
though I I think we have a whole I think
booze has a whole bunch of questions
about Thailand which we'll save for
later on uh h&amp; know have you spent much
time in Southeast Asia like just even as
a you know tourist or
no I don't I don't get out much um I
have a lot of obligations that keep me
around here fair enough so unfortunately
I have't I think before before I make it
over there I'll probably try to get to
Australia hang out with these guys I got
so many jokes I could be rolling out
right now about you
traveling one not in Bangkok yeah yeah
yeah maybe one day
yeah we'll go we'll take a special trip
there
together oh man I mean [ __ ] going back
to what Wally was saying though the food
is amazing and like so cheap as well for
us um yeah [ __ ] amazing food yeah
Cuisines I do love
booze what's up brother have you
traveled to Southeast Asia nah I've been
to barley bro like every other
Australian um that's that's like the
Northeast island of Australia but that's
about it man Fiji most of my travel in D
Europe so Amsterdam a bunch um and then
like Germany and switzland and stuff but
no I'd love to get over there uh napole
probably where I'd head first I was
actually talking to a mate um looking at
the zir trips they've got some trips up
on their website like a TVD at the
moment but they're looking at going to
like South
America um Morocco and then
places like Cambodia and um I've got an
aunt that's Cambodian and uh an uncle
that lived there for 10 years or so so
i' probably looked to head over there
it' be fantastic and I think there's
still some fantastic Cambodian land
races there even this guy that's like
popped up over there I think he's the
expat that's um selling seeds so yeah it
could be a cool little venture all right
before we go any further Wally let's
talk Ducks foot like the first I knew
about you when I hit you up way back in
the day Wally and his d foot it's it's I
mean Wally
duck there's a lot of misconceptions
even nowadays like if you go online and
you hear people talk about ducks foot
they'll refer to it as like in instead
of a a strain or something that you work
they'll refer to it as like a a trait
that goes through cookies or you know
through OG Kush um can you talk a little
bit about it where you found it um what
you found working with it Etc but give
us a little Lowdown on it yeah we we we
got it loely here and to be honest I
don't know the origin but it's just a a
a trait that can be in cannabis so the
origin doesn't have to be specific you
know doesn't have to have been from
Hawaii or Africa or sure whatever um and
and and a guy that I knew um that I grew
some weed with he um he he talked to me
a little bit about it but he just said
he he knew a guy that had some stuff
that had like uh three fingers leap on
it you know which I I said look I've
seen that it's no big deal he said oh
this is good weed and um but he said the
guy wouldn't give him any and then so um
so we had to wait till the guy was
desperate of course yeah and then so
he's given us like a box of uh plants or
something and old mates made some seed
out of it and he and I uh grew some and
um we actually only had one
um one Ducks foot plant I think we
had yeah and then we crossed oh man that
[ __ ] stunk yeah yeah it did it was
skunky yeah yeah really that's the only
thing I could like in it too wasn't the
same smell as skunk but just how it
permeated you
know the distance you could smell it
from
and and so yeah it was a nice weed
little bit of hashy sort of uh and and
the tasted you get on your lips and you
could lick your lips and taste it
afterwards and um smile too happy happy
happy weed
so uh so we kept around but I kind of
didn't know what I was doing back then
making seeds and um it was a bit of a
hit and a miss thing and I didn't do
that well on the first Recreation of it
and then I had I couldn't go back
because I lost seed and the guy that uh
that I'd got to hold on to the stash he
gave him away to his uh
ex-girlfriend's new guy which I thought
[ __ ] who even GI yeah buy anything you
know
yeah but honestly the um the best out of
the seed we had there was um I don't
know maybe it was 50% web Leaf stuff and
50% just the normal uh cannabis leaf and
the normal stuff was the the better stff
and I would have used that to you know
bring back the taste and the smell but
yeah I didn't have it so um so and then
like I lost most of my stuff but um I
got some um stuff off a Hawaiian dude uh
we we spoke together and it seemed like
his
stuff
uh the stuff what I had had all the
advantages that he wanted and and vice
versa and so we swapped and that was
that Hawaiian Webb Inda yes yeah and um
it grew short like about three or four
foot had one main Coler didn't want to
Branch out huge stem huge Big Hollow
stem on it so in my idea I thought it
was definitely Inda whereas my stuff was
tall branchy you know flowered longer
and so I I this wasn't a purti at that
ducks foot but it was definitely the
type of dominant you know yeah versus
that indicate so I made a cross of the
two wow that's stuff uh the strongest
smelling weed I've ever come across it
just stunk and um but like
petroleum you know like that's why I
thought when I when I'm when I was
growing and and the people started
talking about Diesel and I'm smelling
this stuff and thinking wow it must be
like this stuff but this was even this
is even stronger than that that diesel
smell it didn't make you nauseous uh
pruning it i' prune like an ounce or two
and I'd have to stop and and and go away
from the smell it was just that bad yeah
bad bad in a good way you know yeah not
just
but um I actually got some back from a
dude recently uh and I I've just I've
just planted some this guy on on
Instagram and he he showed me showed me
a photo and he said his old man got this
stuff in blah blah year and he lives in
you know blah blah I said Fu that's just
down the road from me and I was on that
Webb Webb hybrid at the time and um and
I asked him do does it stink like this
and he said oh yeah it's it stinks so
yeah maybe it's the same one I don't
know I remember seeing a blr Ducks foot
Widow while not even that long ago um
north side of Brisbane [ __ ] 2018 2019
I remember had a Ducks foot Widow in his
garden and it was doing the the leaf
thing so this is before I was even
getting into the seed stuff I was only
just started growing five years back or
something but um well at that time
really um yeah so yeah I wonder if it's
still around in any form even locally or
if even this is might be the same blow
yeah I don't know this guy he sells
seeds this guy uh the seed packets I got
from him they they look like a salable
item so I'm pretty sure he sells seeds
so I think I remember IED okay Sor no go
ahead when I when I got interested in
the Ducks foot what I wanted to do at
the time which is like silly looking
back but um I wanted to make an
Autoflower that was like kind of um you
know under the radar but that was the
problem was that it stunk so [ __ ] bad
that if you grew it Outdoors even if you
could a little bit with the Webb Leaf
trait there was no mistaking the smell
when the sun hit in the morning like
they're just not not happening anybody's
gonna be looking for it so it wasn't
really stealthy per se yeah that was
plan not in that
regard what's that didn't one of the
Dutch companies do a auto duck not too
long ago I remember there was like a
fian duck that that uh yeah yeah yeah
but then they did an auto version of it
I always wondered if that was from W
stock Dutch fashion maybe yeah Dutch
fashion yeah yeah yeah I think I think
they were think that was
your okay yeah and there's another guy
that released some too um I can't
remember his name but there's been a few
of them
around yeah there were a bunch of uh
filial Generations released on IC mag
and the like seed server fund and all
kinds of stuff over the years I don't
know if those were always coming
directly from you or if someone was uh
F2 him or F3 him I know it was them F2
or F3 or yeah whatever yeah yeah I never
I shared some I I actually saw some on
um and and I got a reminder the other
day on Facebook and this guy in Africa
said he's got this these plants and he's
got them from a field in Africa and uh
and then they were definitely ducks for
it was like the original stuff that I
used to have and weirdly enough I um I I
one of the first trades I did was to to
Africa this this last over there and so
she gave it to some guys that were
growing larger amounts so uh it is
actually possible that that did come
from stuff that I'd sent there so you
you never know works yeah it goes long
and far doesn't it yeah it does man does
did you ever hear of the molai frost
Wally yes yeah I wonder if that might
have been in the duck's foot cuz my mate
um local bird seed grew a bunch of that
from good gear seeds and that stuff
[ __ ] stunk as you're saying you had
some taller seeds in the first um the
f1s or the f2s or whatever wonder if
maybe it's hybridized with or something
because that was super stinky we yeah
maybe because the guy that I I swapped
with he also had that stuff but I think
they all lost a lot of stuff around that
same time time I kind of like seems to
always happen with us in this trade that
everyone loses all their stuff and
line it that you were trading with the
Flying Hawaiian no no it wasn't it was
um I'll get it
ck2 okay yeah and um just trying to
think uh Puna Puna was where he lived or
or where he got the staff one one of the
two in Hawaii yeah
well booze any more any other questions
you want to ask either either of these
guys before we move on to maybe some of
their more recent work no go put the
mango
ha yeah okay yeah let's start maybe
start with high L and we already
mentioned the mango hay but do you want
to tell us a bit more about how you got
to working with it recently and what
that work has been like
uh yeah I I got some from booze um I I
actually wanted older stock um just
because some of the more recent things
I've gotten um you know the Northern
Lights Haze and Super Silver Haze that
I've gotten
recently um from Europe uh they weren't
representative of what I remembered um
yeah I I mentioned wanting some and boo
had Wally stock and I was like man I'd
love to grow his because I know you know
he's he knows what he's doing and it's
it's likely older stock um so I got
those um I don't know year and a half
ago or something popped all of them went
through them found found the ones I
liked found unique ones um I found a
mail I really liked and um you know made
a
seeds with it increased it can you tell
us a bit about uh what kind of spread of
you know Expressions you saw in that in
that pop yeah um so those plants it was
interesting to me at the same time I
popped uh Wally's Neville's Haze mango
Haze and comparatively uh the mango Haze
was a much thinner leaf plant um more
open you know what you would think of
uh with the haze plant um you know they
looked they looked more similar to the
A5 cut I was growing um then the
Neville's mango haast did uh there were
there were a lot of you know they have
this weird like as they put on um new
sets of leaves that kind of roll out um
it's a really um characteristic trait I
noticed in them um but you know once you
flower them you have you have these very
strong almost like green crack smelling
mango plants um you have some that are
like a dirty metallic mango and then
there were some that were kind of like
Savory I had one that I swear smelled
like um like Salsberry steak you know
what that is y have that
there it was like super saory it's like
a it's like right like steak Yeah Yeah
it's
like it's like a ground beef patty made
to be like it's like poor man like
probably Depression era steak um but you
know like when I was a kid we had it and
it was something you got at school and
like I had this plant and uh in the
mango Haze it was one of the later
flowering ones actually and um I just
love the structure of it it you know it
didn't throw big buds it threw a lot of
small kind of hazy looking buds through
it and the whole time I flower it I was
like what the [ __ ] is that smell you
know it's just so obscure and then one
day it hit me you know I think I was
like harvesting it and I was it smells
like [ __ ] Salsberry steak it's that's
incredible um but you know for the most
part it was there was a lot of you know
fruer Haze stuff it was more mango than
I kind of expected it to be um but
they're great plants um I've been on a
bunch of the dry sift I made from it um
I got a big jar I kind of tap into every
day did you have any that were like on
the lemony sort of kick like a Le oh you
didn't have lemon mle yeah like um yeah
yeah it's it's kind of like how uh like
it's like a more mellowed
version lemon yeah uh it kind of reminds
me of like a really wild version of some
of the super silver haze stuff that kind
of lemony hazy thing um you know that
that's cool too have you did you see a
bunch of those on your uh
increase and some kind of like incense
stuff too like we've got a couple of
cuts here like the Harlem dreams and
then my buddy's got this Aussie Outback
too and it's in that like in sensey sort
of Frankincense realm I had a couple
like that one of my males that I used so
I did uh I increased three packs using
two males and then I utilized one male
just to seed up all of my Keepers um and
that male was on the incense roomm and I
had this like I called it like a Crocs
back pattern the leaf was like Contour
ah Contour the wrong word but it wasn't
like variegated it was weird it was like
a textured Leaf very ruffle yeah yeah
yeah yep I know exactly what you're
talking about oh awesome man yeah
because I had three females that were
like that too um but yeah I had I only
had one okay my friend had this um Kina
Negra from Buffalo seeds and that's
seedsman hay Colombian Black by seedsman
Haze and so there were a few of the
mango Haze that smelt exactly like that
it was like that lemon um sort of kick
that I guess is like a oaz thing not
sure but yeah I was stoked on it because
I didn't get a lot of mango but a fair
bit of this um lemony and like incense
sort of
stuff but I didn't get to grow them
properly like they were just for seed I
um had planned to fill the greenhouse
with them but my green houses were too
chalkers to get them in cuz they took
ages to flip man like I put them in 72
darkness and then um which Sam stunk man
had said was like what you do for ctiv
is to show sex or whatever and I chucked
him outside and it still took like a
good five weeks for them to sex hey like
longest stuff I've ever um had to show
sex yeah um the ones I did outside here
triggered super late um but indoor they
don't really really hesitate I've
noticed they kind of go right to it
which I thought was pretty weird but I
had some that it was you know set
September before they flipped and I had
to I had to move uh some of the ones I
did outside you know into a greenhouse
to finish and it it's not that they took
so long to flower it's just that they
triggered way later than I mean they
triggered later than A5 did here yeah
that's crazy I told my buddy that and
he's like [ __ ] that's nuts because he'd
only grown a few as well and um hadn't
got to flower him so wow super sativa I
wonder if that's your like selection
Wally like when you got the seed line
like that's something my made asked me
to ask you what do you know what mango
Hay's IBL is like what what's is it
inbred in a certain direction or for for
earlier stuff so Shanty reckons and I I
I didn't I didn't really ask at the time
how many like Generations he in breeded
or or what he selected for but obviously
it was for earlier stuff and um I I've
grown a lot of mango ha before just the
normal one and most of what I found was
that incense sort of smell you were
talking about and uh it wasn't until I
grew this I I actually found a mango
mango Haze which uh was a bit of a
surprise it was fatter Bud though and um
it SM like um more ripening mangoes
which I'm used to sour mangoes in like
Asian stuff that I've grown and um so
then I I could see actually why it was
called mango ha prior to that I was more
like incense Haze to me never came
across a mango one
for high and Lonesome what were some of
your favorite crosses with the mango
Hayes or what you know what what did you
like coming out of
that um it's I've really enjoyed all of
them it's it's uh it has something I
like in a mail it's very I think it's
very transparent um you get you get the
mango Haze in there it's definitely
there you definitely you get the effect
from it um you know you get that
instancy back into it but it lets the
mother show through really well um you
know
the the kimd and the TK cross to Mango
Hayes are both this to me it's like it's
like zombie weed you know like you're it
completely spaces your mind out but
you're still like motivated you're up
doing things it's just like
mechanical motion it's uh it's it's
really kind of awesome I've been smoking
that every day um but then uh the the
Green Crack mango Haze it really lets I
mean it's like it's very mangoe um it
kind of it goes in different directions
as it cures kind of um but that for
flavor that one's incredible um
the um breaking hazee which is the
electric boooo dog [ __ ] whatever mango
Hayes that's I I'm a big fan of that one
um I actually have a bunch going right
now um I've kind of been wanting to do a
a EB project for a few years I've made I
think this was the sixth outcross I made
with it and I think it's the one to look
for a male to backat cross to um the
plants are
there what I wanted um you do get
variations on the mother there um there
are a few straight mango Haze plants but
for the most part it it really lets the
mother plant shine
through super cool to hear
that they sound delicious those crosses
actually yeah did did you get some of
them no just the um I don't think so
just the East Coast s diesel appala one
that I that I recall all right I'll make
sure you what did you get A5 mango Haze
mate and some La Kush mango Haze or
something like that I might have I'd
have to CH that that does seed
containers I've got Fu they're full and
I have trouble finding stuff
now it all so you I can sort it all out
but uh there's so much stuff in there
right
I've literally I can't even find what I
and I'm sure it's in there but I can't
find
it Wally did you have anything else to
add to the uh mango Hayes account uh any
anything um come to mind while H Lanson
was talking about it well some of my
first experiences with it to be honest I
um it was um mold resistance better than
anything I had ever seen I saw that
stuff go in later flower
and it was just pouring here for weeks
like literally every day all day and
that stuff um you know you fold back the
buds to to check the calaes for any
damage and and no it didn't get any and
it finished and it was uh super strong
and um really
euphoric and uh the tolerance to build a
tolerance took a long time I smoked that
stuff for like maybe a month even and I
was still getting smashed all the time
so um
yeah the the mold resistance here was
incredible as well um we really struggle
with that especially as you take plants
in the November um you know I I I moved
all of mine you know that late into a
greenhouse um and they were they were
Rock Solid even you know the heat went
out at one point and um you know was a
pretty [ __ ] piss poor run um but the
mango hay is not a specka mold on
them yeah they're Champions right yeah
incredible
FL want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most important the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out