welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
Syndicate what's up everyone we finally
hit 10,000 subscribers which is massive
for a a niche nerdy topic like this like
it's wasn't really thought possible by
anyone let alone me um with that said we
want to do a contest for everyone and it
also kind of coincides with our
Instagram page being totally knocked
down um so in or we decided we would do
like one for Instagram and one
separately for the patreon people and
that one will be a little bit bigger
because it's a paid membership uh first
for Instagram make sure you go follow
breeders.
syndicate.com and and how it treats
anything cannabis even history without
any advertising for anything other than
a show
um but we have to play that game and we
like to get the word out so please go
follow us there to be eligible for this
contest we're going to give away a free
pack from me a free pack from goat farm
and a free pack from H&amp;L for that
contest um I think we're going to end
the contest let me see on the
23d of next week so that means the
winner will be announced
on March 1st show at the beginning so be
sure if you win not to use your real
name because I'm going to announce it on
the show and stuff and that'll be fun
but I don't want to like docks anyone
either so we have that for the Instagram
people but you have to be following you
have to be following the page you won't
be eligible that's where I'm picking the
poll from and we're going to randomize
it um for the patreon and Discord people
we're not only going to have those three
packs we're also going to have a large
bottle of reversal spray which is huge
it's a big it's a big price and uh I
wanted to make it extra special I'll
probably throw in a little bit more for
the patreon people because they've done
so much to be a part of driving this
community um you have time you have time
to join the patreon it's $5 a month so
not asking a lot um we also have our 50
tier that is going to get filled soon we
do that every three months but it's
filled with threee things I'll say you
know um yeah so a free pack from me a
pack from high and Lonesome and a pack
from goat farm and uh yeah I'm stoked
for it thank you every everyone for
helping us make the 10K subscribers I do
owe a massive debt of gratitude to
thousandfold without him one there'd be
no show and I've said that before I
don't think people get that um I see a
lot of comments talking about how you
know they prefer one Coast over the
other because they got so used to it and
realistically if that was still going on
there wouldn't be a show it just
wouldn't
um I didn't have that even mindset to
push to 10K I didn't think it was
possible
um it really wasn't a goal my goal was
just trying to keep myself interested
enough to keep doing the show and for a
while I wasn't a long while um so yeah
it's it's it's special to me it's
special to him and we hope we can make
it special for you and everyone watching
um so yeah make sure you're either part
of the patreon or Following on breeders.
syndicate.com we have our show up this
week uh it's the outdoor part two go
check it out next week we are diving
back into breeding very heavily and I'm
revisiting an old episode I was really
not super stoked with um not just about
how it was produced by myself the actual
content and where it led to some
misinformation and we've always said
like if anything changes if anything
comes to light we will update it and we
will make the information correct as
correct as we can um that happened and
I'm I'm first and foremost to push for
that just because I'm anal about that
kind of stuff so we go into breeding
deeper in a in a very popular subject so
yeah with that said go join the contest
it's free you don't have to do anything
um for the Instagram one be a part of
the patreon it's a bigger package bigger
contest so $5 get you there
cheers want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
C catalogs and knowledge we hope you
join our Union of readers and Growers
come check it
out