[Music]
so
ladies and gentlemen good morning
we're going to start the day off this
morning with one of our very favorite
speakers of all time
um today wendell is going to take us on
a journey back almost 50 years
to a little-known case
which at the time was largely ignored
but with what we know now
probably shouldn't have been rather
important case
most of us do not know much about it
it's going to be a treat ladies and
gentlemen please welcome wendell
[Applause]
thank you bob
thank you ladies and gentlemen
it's nice to see so many old friends
back here
i
have a little announcement to make to
start off with i'm always asked at these
conferences why don't you republish that
picture book well it's too expensive for
us to do it we never did it never
intended to
but one has been published michael
whalen
who founded the
american figure got permission from
billy to redo it and he redid it right
from the original slide transparency and
the pictures are much sharper here
than anything else i don't have any for
sale here but there's some bookmarks on
the stage here you can pick up with an
address you can contact for it
now my presentation today
is going to be about
the bob renaud case
i don't think many of you remember that
but with
at my age with a little bit of hindsight
i can look back
and see one that we popularly threw out
at the time probably shouldn't have been
because
now we have all of the features of that
case have been repeated in other cases
and
somewhat contemporary with this case
were
the cases of george adamski
which has been
criticized
over and over again
everybody tried to call him a charlatan
and a fraud
but you know
nobody really investigated that case in
this country
the only person that really investigated
the adept case was bruce cathy from new
zealand
an airline pilot that came up here went
to mr adamski
went over all the sites went back to the
earth contact site and everything and
his report in one of his books is the
only real report on the adamski case
now the rest of them took their cue from
the lorenzens from afro
and afro was the first
world or first ufo civilian or civilian
ufo research organization in the world
after nightcaf which was not really
civilian
and
coral and jim when when the newspapers
began to report the identity case out
there in los angeles carl and jim went
to visit george adamski
now carl was a beautiful lady but she
was
had an acid tongue
and
she was not very kind to people that
they interviewed
so when they got to vista california he
wasn't home
people at the house told me he was
eating dinner little diner down the road
operated by i believe it was by his
sister or sister-in-law or something
and so they went down there and they
found george at his table eating his
breakfast
and they he invited him to sit down they
sat down across from him and
carl in her usual
way to begin such investigations
fold her fingertips like this said
george just how the hell did you do it
and he immediately
suspected that they're not there to get
facts that they're there to pin him to
the wall so he said my dear lady you
just take a hubcap and throw it in the
air
and photograph it so that's what the the
lorenzo has published in the afro
bulletin and being the pioneer everybody
else copied from the april bulletin
and nobody investigated the case after
that until bruce kathy so
this is something like that now let me
add a couple of comments here i was
inves lou zinstag in basel switzerland
brought me the meyer case
we'd been exchanging photographs and she
heard about the case in her backyard
and she called me one day and said
i'm going to be coming to the united
states and i have some pictures i didn't
want to send to you in the mail that i'd
like to show you if you pick me up the
bus station
i said sure i'll be glad to do that once
you got in tucson i did
leah and brit elders happened to be in
my house at the time when i picked her
up and brought her out to the house and
she showed us the pictures for the first
time
they were really great and
i
she it was through her that i might made
my arrangements go back in and start my
investigation of the case myself
but she was
she published the first ufo journal in
the world in german out of basel
switzerland
she was the niece of carl jung she was a
an international journalist spoke read
and wrote in five languages
and
she
contacted george adamski early on from
the newspaper reports and began a
correspondence with him
and when he was invited to come to
europe to
meet the king and queen of the
netherlands and pope john paul of pope
john xxiii
he went first to
lose instug's home in basel and she
escorted him all around europe so i know
that he made the trip and i know
that he was welcomed when he got to the
hay to the netherlands
i know that he he did get to the vatican
and
she was in the taxi when he left to go
into the vatican and she was waiting for
him when he came out and had the papal
medal which they took back to basel and
put it in zlu zinstag's brother's safe
he owned a jewelry store there so that's
i know it's all true
and i don't think that he could have
faked it
others
similar to that were kelvin rowe
orpheo angelucci
violet gilbert i got to tell you about
violet gum you probably never heard of
her she was a contactee in santa barbara
california
and her visitors
agreed one time to let her photograph
their ships
and she told a
photography friend that owned a photo
processing shop at a studio in santa
barbara what was going to happen and
what was the best film to get and he
said oh by all means we should get coat
of color because it's the sharpest
and she invited him to go with her and
so she took her handheld 35 millimeter
camera and an eight millimeter movie
camera and rolled the film
he did the same and he took a four by
five press camera with him took pictures
with that also
now the the visitors appeared on time
they took pictures of it flying overhead
they took pictures of it making an
approach it took pictures of it landing
and occupants getting out
and the the uh
contact only lasted about a half an hour
but they quickly snapped a lot of
pictures they shot all their almost all
of their film
so after this event
they rushed right to the
back to the studio to turn in the film
for processing they both went to a
five-point uh grocery drugstore that had
a film processing center there
and they turned their film in at that
time you had to wait about two weeks for
it to be processed
and sent back now they don't process
code of color
except in licensed processing
laboratories there's only five at that
time there was four in the united states
and one in hong kong
so all the code of color film had to go
to one of the licensed processing
laboratories
so when they went back to pick their
film up two weeks later on schedule
they got a u-goof slip in the envelope
instead no film nothing came back the
slip says you may have had you
taken your pictures with the lens on the
camera might have had your thumb over
the over the lens but the pictures
didn't come out and you were entitled to
a free roll of film take it to your
nearest supplier
both of them got the u-group slips now
that's a little
little unusual
and they're the the the one man was an
expert photographer
for him to leave the lens on actually he
was using through the lens camera anyway
he couldn't see anything if the lens cap
was on
so uh
when i heard about this i was visiting
out there and and guilt violet was
telling me what happened to the film and
i said
well why don't you send them to
take him to a kodak shop or something
like that
so
she took hers to a kodak shop he sent
his ups through his own channels and
again they both got you goof slipped
so she's telling me this and she said
i've got one roll of 35 millimeter film
left if you think you can get it
processed i'll give it to you
i said yeah i can get it processed let
me have it and i'll see what i can do
so at that time i was in touch with
bob beck robert beck who was the head of
color control processing code of color
film for the film studios out in
hollywood
and he said yes i can get it developed
for you i said i'm only going to leave
it with if you could guarantee me that
you could return the roll of film
process or the role of film unprocessed
but in any case i've got to have the
original film back
process to run process
he said i can i can do it for you
he says come back in about 10 days and i
left and i got a call from him two days
later and he said come down to the
office
so i went down to see bob and he had the
roll of film on his desk he says mr
stevens i can't guarantee you that i can
return this film if we process it
he said i wasn't aware of this wasn't
familiar with this but he says my lab
chief says that we have we are governed
by a classified government directive
that regulates all
code of color
licensed processing agencies again
there's only five
and they have to report certain things
seen on film and he says what you
describe on here is one of the subjects
that we have to report they'll send
somebody to take a look at it and
you may not get it back so i said don't
process i'll give it back to the owner
and that's what happened to that anyway
that was a good case she got a lot of
good pictures she didn't get much
publicity but it was a remarkable case
and there would have been some marvelous
evidence if
if we could have gotten it
the next one
that was contemporary with george was
the mitchell sisters now if you remember
george adamski said his contacts were
with venusians
and the mitchell sisters said their
contacts were with martians but in the
mitchell sister's case they had
venusians aboard the martian spacecraft
and then in the
violet gilbert case they mentioned
martians working with them
there was another case uh
halsey
lieutenant commander halsey i think his
name was
his uncle was bull halsey who he said
also had contacts
but this lieutenant commander halsey
was on
at the end of the war when we had a cut
back in money
and we couldn't return everybody at one
time the peachy boat commanders were
given grids in the pacific to run to
patrol until they could be returned and
retired
and
halsey young commander halsey was
running his grid with his patrol boat
when it ran onto solid ground in open
ocean and was lifted up in the water
he never saw this before us not on the
charts and he jumped overboard and he
jumped down onto a solid object
it kept rising and his his pt boat is
high and dry
then a cutting tower came up out of the
hard surface the door opened and the man
stepped out took him aboard
and showed him around and
told him that they had been observing
him for some time they knew him by his
first name
i told him that they they showed him
around then when they let him go they
told him that the time was up and that
they would
be would be
would see him again
and they did they came back
several times while he was still
patrolling in the pacific and when he
returned
home to california
uh told his wife about what was
happening she said i'd like to meet him
he's someone the next time he had a was
summoned for a contact he told him about
his wife's desire and they said that's
okay we consider you a unit
bring her along so he did and then him
and his wife would
meet them at rendezvous points that
would be sent to them through the mail
they'd receive a letter with a
rendezvous point at a certain place in
time and would they go there
the
venusians they said they were
met them and sometimes the venusians
came with a martian one time they came
with a martian couple and they all had
dinner and a restaurant together now
this is a little difficult to accept we
don't
when we look at venus
we see
a hot surface 800 degrees centigrade
40 atmospheres of pressure nothing could
live there
as we understand it in our physical
sense and we have to remember
that when when we look up we're looking
up through physical eyes with physical
senses
and all the instrumentation we build is
to simply extend or augment our physical
senses
the venusians explain that their life
wave
does not vibrate to the same frequency
as ours that the life wave is a little
bit finer
in
in density of vibration or density of
frequencies
and something equivalent to our lower
astral and that when they come here they
have to slow down their vibrations to
interact with us physically
since we can't speed up our vibrations
they interact with them
in their reality
their astral reality we we don't
perceive them
but that doesn't mean they're not there
they say and there are a lot of visitors
from the venus and life wave come to
this planet
they say that that their life wave
exists in a vibrational level above the
physical level that we see when we look
at venus
and someplace in the clouds and that
they have
trees and plants and rivers and flowers
mountains and everything that we have
but
in their density of reality appropriate
to their density of reality
so we have
a number of cases of
visitors from venus describing such
conditions and we are unable to test
them because we just can't see into that
and
one of the venusians offered a a reverse
situation said if somebody else looking
at the earth whose sight was denser than
the earth site and looked at your planet
and saw only the top of the molten
lava layer under the basaltic crust he
would think that was your surface of
your planet because the rest is
transparent to it and he said that would
be a river situation from between earth
and venus
so now
we
we have
getting up to the contract we want to
talk about they said
that they came from another planet also
and that they had to make a change to
remain here in comfortably and in a
physical sense
all these others by the way were
successfully put down
by the ufo clubs who are really their
own worst enemies
for lack of money and resource for
proper investigation they never could go
anyplace and do anything they had member
subscribers that barely paid for the
publication but they never could afford
to send anybody anywhere
to say a week or two in another country
or elsewhere and do any kind of
investigation
if a club couldn't own you they attacked
you that was that was norm
if they did own you others did the
attacking so that was the situation with
the case we want to talk about involving
bob renaud
so i went back through the contact cases
that i'm familiar with
and i made a list of things in common
with other ufo cases and this seems to
be
we seem to have a pretty much of a
general application here
they all
the ones that
interact with us that we are concerned
about
are human in appearance just like us
when we see them they look like us they
just
a little bit different in morphology
ears a different shape lips in different
shape eyes a different shape color a
little different but they're human
placental animals like us
they're always using a variety of
different ships they don't come in just
one type in most cases there's more than
one type
making the approach and the contact
and this seems to be a norm also
most of them speak our languages
fluently
and they before they can interact with
us of course they have to learn the
language so that means a period of
observation before the contact is ever
made
and we're not aware of that until the
contact is made by that time they know
quite a bit about us
they are also careful uh make careful
observations diverse affairs earth
affairs earth
concepts they use marvelous technologies
like ultralight speeds they can read
thoughts they use our radio and
television communications at will
they use all of our communications
including telegraph and computers as
well and we've had examples of
other forms of communication used by the
way back to the adamski case he was told
to go to that diner at near blythe
by his friends in a con
a contact
about the same time george hunt
williamson got
word from his sources to go to the same
diner south of life
and a railroad telegraph operator from a
little town outside of prescott
received over the railroad telegraph
where he had his contacts had been
coming over the railroad telegraph
regularly
he recognized the source it was it was a
practice with him that was their way of
communication and they sent him and his
wife to the same diner
south of life
and adamski and george hunt williamson
and his wife and al bailey and his wife
all met
at the diner
and decided
that they're on the same
since they've all been sent there by
their
sources
they
certainly nothing is going to happen
on the highway in front of the diner so
they got in their cars and going to
drive up to a remoter area the women had
packed lunch and they were going to
go up out of town and have a picnic and
they chose the road north towards the
mountains
they went up there a little ways and
stop for the picnic you know the rest of
the story the george adamski story by
the way the reason he had the water in
placer paris in his car is his contacts
told him to take the water and plaster
of paris before he left
to go to the diner
so
those that like to dismiss the adapsky
case
fred steckling has a table in here and
his father was the one that interacted
regularly and frequently with george
adamski
and
you can get more information from him
but
i
i have to wonder if the georgia napster
case is such a patent fraud why did the
united states government
send a government airplane to pick him
up at miramar every time you had a
substantive contact and fly him to the
pentagon for debriefing
and then flying back to miramar in a
military airplane that means that
they didn't think he was a fraud and
they they invited him often invited him
to stay in the pentagon in the pentagon
guest facilities overnight which he
always refused to do
he would leave the pentagon take the
ferry across the potomac and go to the
rotifer's home
across the river from the pentagon he
always stayed there because he didn't
know what might happen if he stayed in
the pentagon
now
the
most of the visitors use
tractor or levitation beams they pick
their their subjects up equipment also
in a beam of light that
that lifts it and they can move it and
place it wherever they want it
none of them
that i've encountered have had any money
system
like ours they their system is entirely
different they don't carry cash and they
don't have bills
most of them have
no religions like ours
all of them have intrusive observational
technologies and technologies and can
look in on anything we're doing
some of them had underground and other
water bases and what i'm going to talk
about does have both
here on this planet
many of them limited their direct
contact with humans to a very few
selected individuals and they didn't
allow it to be
broadened
i'll tell you what
why
are one reason that may be why when i
was investigating the pleiades case of
course i always wanted to meet the
palladiums like everybody else
and he billy meyer had his close friend
guido moosbruger his wife
and a couple others that he wanted to
take into the case with him to meet
samyasi
and finally he
resorted to a little trick he put
one of them over under a poncho on the
back of his moped when he was going to a
rendezvous
and in this was on a
night in january in the middle of the
night at two o'clock in the morning
actually cold as heck
and
in the forest on the way to the
rendezvous site they told them to stop
and let the passenger off
they weren't welcome or they would leave
so he put the woman off in the snow
with no cold wheel or gear and went to
meet the rendezvous he said he'd be
right back
he's in the warm ship with samyasi and
he says aren't you sorry for that poor
woman back there in the cold
and samyasi said we told you not to
bring her and he said i don't understand
this at all why can't i bring somebody
in you know is this is it what's so
secret about all this
she says no big thing and it's no big
secret she said the problem comes
when we when the second person enters
the scene she said
everybody
doesn't have the same concepts doesn't
have the same background
they have different background different
languages different educational
levels different understandings of
different things and she said they don't
all see
everything the same way
she says witness five
witnesses to an automobile accident they
already describe it and there are
details that their despair disparity
discrepancy between the details when
they go to make comparisons later she
said the problem comes when the second
third and other people enter the case
because they won't see it
exactly the same way you do and in time
they begin to group up they some will
agree and others don't agree and then
more agree and then they have more
factions she said look at your christian
religions you have 220 different
factions each one believing he has the
true source she says this is what
happens when you expand the context she
says it's more economical to us to
simply stop the context with you and
start with somebody else that hasn't
that does not have these needs in order
to
work productively so after that i kept i
stopped trying to get into context of
course everybody else did too
but
now we knew why it's not going to happen
and maybe never going to happen
the uh
oh and
for that reason all contacts
were limited to single contactees
as far as i know i don't know of any
case where except for the husband and
wife team where they more than one
contact or or contact he was admitted
into the case
they most of them spoke of an
organization of planets
of some kind
in the case of the
solar cross brothers channeled by uh
the young guy what was his name uh
who
yeah
miller dick miller
and
they uh
spoke of
an organization of planets that they
were a member of
and it included a lot of the local
planets here
uh
that the the corinthians speaking to bob
renaud described two major organizations
that are in
are
have operations in our sector of space
and they did not include the solar cross
group
they had an alliance of planets and a
confederation of planets there roughly
we'll go into that a little bit more
later
but there does to seem to be
a system of organization beyond earth
some of the visitors have bases on our
moon of course the corinthians did too
some of them mentioned well a number of
mentioned mars and venus beings visiting
earth and so do the
corinthians
and there are other witnesses involved
now the first information
if i can find the
pointer here
okay we'll
bring up a slide here
that's what i just covered that
information there
i hope it's readable
this is
the
first publication that put out anything
on the bob renaud case this is
the ufo international
put out by afsca american amalgamated
flying saucers company
uh put up by the gabriel green gabriel
green was
a young man that inherited the family
fortune
and took it to organize a research ufo
research group
and started publishing a little magazine
and this is one of his early issues
actually there were several issues
before this but what you see here
is a picture on the cover
done by a staff artist
of a corinthian vehicle that was
manufactured on corondora and
transported here by a telemetric process
it was apported here but from corridor
and we'll go into that a little bit
later
this next one is a succeeding issue
of
the afsca journal it's also ufo
international is what it was titled
uh had another some more of the story
here is gabriel greene the publisher of
the
that journal
uh
he uh
he had a pretty good well-going
organization he went to the giant rock
convention there's still a few old folks
here that remember the conventional
giant
giant rock in california may even
remember gabriel green at one time the
independent party in the united states
rely on him for as a candidate for
president
and we'll go into that a little bit
later
here is the report that i
summarized from the work done by gabriel
green back in the
in the early 60s
and this is what the cover that i worked
out for
the book that i am putting out by the
way the book is only in e-book format
couldn't afford to publish a hard copy
and the back cover of the book looks
something like this well it looks like
we've lost one
sticking slide there it is
back cover the book and
that is uh actually lost the back cover
but that's the diagram
of the ship now let me see if i can find
a pointer here
on the left-hand side you see a little
craft a board a little disc shaped crap
with a dome
that's a
one of the smaller scouts it only
carries one or two people
and it's carried aboard this other
larger scout also shuttlecraft
and
was bob renaud was eventually
shown how to operate this little craft
operates very simply and he was shown
how to operate it and
a couple of times they sent the craft to
pick him up in the driveway in front of
his house with nobody else aboard the
canopy would go up all by itself and a
voice would invite him aboard and he'd
get in
and it would fly him out to the
shuttle craft
now bob renaud appeared one time
on the platform describing his case and
that was at uh buck nelson's program
back in wisconsin i think it was
mountain view miss wisconsin in about
1967.
and
oh here we go thank you very much
and uh
okay we got one
and so
and he was attacked by the
debunkers
and ridiculed for telling his story
because there it was one of the earlier
stories of ongoing contact
and
he decided
that he his problem and trying to answer
the question is nobody wants to listen
to it a substantive answer they want to
ask a one-line question they want a
one-line answer it's hard to do
i often get those in the swiss case
and so he
he decided that he didn't have time to
educate the closed minds and he didn't
have any particular interest in it
anyway he knew his truth he had his own
facts and he didn't feel any need to
persuade anybody else to believe what he
already knew himself and so he refused
to go on a platform anymore he stopped
sending his uh
reports to gabriel green
and just kept them all to himself the
context continued but
the
carl and annie white in wiesbaden
germany
an organization they called deweest
published
the ufo not richton which is ufo news it
was the only ufo newspaper in the world
it came out weekly was about 18 pages
and it had all it was nothing but ufo
news and reports around the world so
they soon heard about bob renaud's case
and they invited him to come to germany
and tell him about it send him a ticket
prepaid ticket
he did
took his notes and went to wiesbaden and
met carl and annie white
they talked about his case for several
days and the vice became so interested
they wanted to publish his information
and he finally agreed to let them
publish it only if they wouldn't allow
it to be translated into english and
sent back the united states
so the vice published the notes that he
had and it took three volumes there's
volume one
and here's volume two
it's got a picture of one of the shuttle
craft on that one
and here is volume three
the slides are out order that looks like
that's volume one anyway
there were three volumes
that uh
were published by ufo not greekton
and uh
it included in those volumes they
included the only pictures that were
ever released
of bob renaud's
facility
bob renaud was a high school graduate
about 19 years old
turned 20 while this was early going on
he rented a basement room in his parents
home and worked
in a general electric factory in
massachusetts
and
he took his money that he earned in his
job and and collected electronic
equipment he became a ham radio buff
built his own ham radio set from a kit
and then he proceeded to build himself
a home built television set from a kid
also
you see the television set in the left
side of the picture there and his ham
radio is in the front on the little
table
and uh
he he was happy with his communications
gear and his setup and it was doing
serving him well he he uh he was being
fulfilled
by
the efforts that he was putting into it
and he was
there sitting there reading a magazine
one night and he thought he'd tune up
tune in the bbc news broadcast from
london
so he put his magazine down and went
over turned his set on
let it warm up and then tried to tune in
bbc and the closer he got the bbc the
louder noise he got
in his uh radio there was a beep beep
beep beep that was quite loud when he
got on bbc it was so loud he couldn't
really hear bbc so he tuned down to get
away from it
couldn't hear very good very good that
way either so he turned back up again
and went looking for the meat when he
homed on the beep and got it loud and
clear it stopped
and a soft boy said bob stay on this
frequency we want to talk to you we've
been trying to contact you for some time
so he was amazed that this was happening
stayed on the frequency
and they told him that if he would
make some adjustments in a shortwave
radio
he could signal them and they could come
back to him immediately on a better
frequency a clearer frequency which they
set up for it he made the modification
then he had
regular contact between him and the
visitors
so after four or five of these contacts
they told him how to modify
his home built television set to do the
same thing so he could pick up images on
his television set
of them
brought transmitted from their craft
and now he had two-way communication he
could sit in front of his television set
a round black and white screen there
and
talk to him on his radio
and see him at the same time and he he
thought this was great
and those contacts continued to develop
and they told him that they would
eventually talk to him face to face
here here's the only time that he
appeared on a convention i'm sorry
that's another picture of him in his uh
little basement studio
and here's a picture of
buck nelson's convention
from uh a book where i found that's buck
nelson in the left side walking into the
picture it wasn't a very impressive
convention but it still attracted a few
people and it attracted the debunkers
right along with all the rest
here's another
issue of gabriel green's
ufo international now he's calling it
flying saucers international
and this picture shows the corinthian
car
where they picked the
bob renaud up in front of his house
and they flew to
an area not more than eight miles from
where he lives
in the berkshire mountains descended
into a forest clearing
when they got a few yards above the
ground
it opened up like you see there
clamshell doors opened up
the car went down a shaft the doors
closed behind it
and they were in a
an elaborately excavated underground
facility that the car traveled down the
corridors
carrying the passengers with it
and they traveled some distance it was a
quite a large facility they they went
down several corridors and parked the
car in a parking garage and got on
escalator walks sidewalks moving
sidewalks to down some more corridors to
a welcoming room
and
there
his friends uh presented bob to somebody
at a reception desk and
and they prepared a pass for him to be
used a plastic pass
that had
some coded signals in it
and this they gave him this pass so he
could use it to get into the facility by
himself if he ever needed to or was told
to or wanted to
the
next issue
of the flying saucers international
showed
the first man to walk in space
this guy walked in space
on a
corinthian craft in a corinthian space
suit
eight months before
our first american astronaut
made an extra vehicular
exit from our spacecraft
so we gave a lot of credit to our first
man to walk in space but he's really not
the first one to be out there
outside the craft and
it was bobbering out
here is a little more detail
on the
the spacesuit that they provided him
it
was not a highly pressurized suit
but it contained an atmosphere or his
earth atmosphere in it
it had control buttons on the breast
there
it had magnetic boots that
stuck to the surface of the spacecraft
they were in
when he tilted his angle ankle at a
certain angle it would release the
magnetism and he could lift the boot
when he put it down again it would stay
fast until he dipped his ankle a certain
way
and
there's also a diagram there
of the spacecraft the inside of the
spacecraft that took him
out into space for that walk-in space
and
we'll come back to that diagram a little
later this cut that particular scotch
craft i believe was about 60 feet in
diameter
if i remember correctly but we get
another diagram
of it
this next one shows
a as an artist
rendition of bob renaud's departure from
his driveway and that little remote
controlled domed disc that carries only
one or two people that i showed you
aboard another craft here it's
approaching the care
carrier craft
and you see the iris port that opened as
it got closer and it went in that iris
board inside
into the hangar and bob got out and met
his his friends
there
now this is
a picture
a photograph
of the area where they parked the car
now the first time
for the first face-to-face meeting he
got his signal on his ham radio told him
to be out in front of his house at four
o'clock sharp
so we went out there about five minutes
early and
almost right on the dot headlights came
around the corner in the distance this
is dark at night
it was cold morning in the winter time
and a plymouth convertible turned the
corner
with one man in it he pulled up stopped
and opened the door
to let bob in when he when he got in the
convertible he saw that it was a man
that he worked with
in the general electric plant
near in a town near his home there
and this man had
attempted to engage bob in
discussions of ufos several times and
bob wasn't really interested in the
subject but he sat and listened and
he didn't pay much attention to the guy
until now he's driving the car
at the rendezvous time he got in the car
with him and he drove out of the out of
town and into a wooded area where
they came on this other
car that was that ported here from
corondor they parked the plymouth in the
trees right back in out of sight there
got in the corinthian car and went to
the underground base for the first visit
at the underground base
here's another
pickup point this time he was picked up
and taken to
this place in the in the corinthian car
they left the corinthian car and got
into a
larger craft and went elsewhere
this is a diagram
of
a the 60-foot diameter spacecraft
these are unmanned disks here that are
used for
remote control observations
aboard the craft and
this little disc here
are more remote monitors
like these that they launch and control
from the control panel inside here and
they do all kinds of
surveillance and observational work with
these monitored disks that are
very sophisticated can do a lot of
things
here's a diagram
of a larger craft this craft is 155 feet
in diameter
and here we see some bigger discs
that
are about the size of the other disc we
just looked at that carry monitors the
bigger discs are launched and recovered
from this
150 foot diameter
disc craft disc shaped craft that
carried a crew of about 60 people
i borrowed that one
now there's uh
all kinds of facilities here the latrine
facilities the dining facilities
everything's all
illustrated in here and it's in
the book that i've published in ebook
format all everything you see here
is published in ebook format
and you can bring it up on your screen
make it as big as you want to read the
letters it's a lot larger you like you
look at the details
and the shape of its construction there
this next one is a much bigger craft
this craft i believe is on the order of
250 to
sphere
about 250 feet in diameter i believe let
me
get back here to my
my notes
see if i can find the details i had
on it
i'd like to give you
the uh
well i should have been turning these
carefully as i went but uh now i believe
i'm getting back to where
i want to be
uh
that's the 155
before that was 155 foot diameter here
we are
the 400 foot diameter
alliance
craft spc-12 is what they called it i
don't know what that means
bob was given
printed guidebooks
for this ship so he could tell where he
was and find his way around
which he was allowed to keep the
guidebooks were printed in corinthian
but by now
they have taught him to read corinthian
script
and he found an interesting thing he
found that when he was in the
underground base in massachusetts
that all the signs in the underground
base were lettered in english and he
asked
or evolve his escort
why the english signs he said well we're
in an english-speaking country and all
of our employees here all of the people
that work here
are trained in english and they go out
and come back
and they need to know the language and
so this is just to
keep it all current they said that that
they learned our languages a long time
ago
with shortly it took them like two weeks
to learn the first language and they
chose english because that seemed to be
spoken more prominently
in what appeared to be the country with
the most advanced technical
information available
right we lost the slide again that
machine back there is not doing too well
there's a picture of
orival's space car
on the top
i've lost part of it in the screen here
and this is the garments that they wear
in the underground base facility and
also
in
the the disc shaped craft when they come
to visit
uh they
they're earth style garments but they
this is not what they wear when they
come out and mix in society they wear
clothes that they bought in clothing
stores just like we wear but this is a
comfortable kind of a uniform that they
wear
in their corindian base facilities
and there's a man here's a woman
if you didn't know it
this is the diagram
of the alliance of planets
let me get my
i got a lot of papers up here i
have to keep shuffling to keep up with
where we are there we go
a diagram of the alliance of planets
the top division there
the alliance
was formed with 150 planets
joined in a dream that had been
been
flourishing for centuries the name has
long since been called the united
world's alliance but the great visions
of our founders are as fresh today as
they were in that hallowed place where
they were farmed 650 years ago of your
time which has become a shrine that
every alliance citizen tries to visit at
least once in his lifetime
earlier i stated this is a
corinthian addressing uh
bob reloud
earlier i stated that the present count
of the alliance worlds was about 740
000. although that is the full number of
the uaws it is now split into two in the
five major divisions
of which corn doors has about
143 000
planets it's one of 143 000 planets in
its division
of the alliance of planets
this segmenting was made necessary by
the sheer
enormity of the task of attempting to
govern so many worlds under one roof the
process of partitioning took place over
a period of four years and was ended
about
september 19th of
1986 of your time the system of
government that i will now outline came
out of that conclave carried out
at this of this mammoth operation at
that time the council of elders
the top line on the chart there
the council of elders is still the
official ruling body of the full
alliance now
this is not
ruled by edict
it's ruled by
recommendation a council
deliberates on problems and makes
recommendations and they either follow
it or they don't but
they usually follow it because that's
usually the best course of action the
council is made up of the wisest men
in their society and each
unit of the society picks the wisest men
they have to participate in the levels
going up to the senior councils
they're kind of a government but it's
not elective
and it's not addictive
it isn't it doesn't issue mandates
there are five sub-councils that handle
the matters within their respective
divisions in turn these are subdivided
into sector councils that each control
about ten 000 planets in a specific
region of space
these are given
these are again segmented into
sub-sectors the lowest level of the
official alliance hierarchy
each of them handles the affairs of
about 100 worlds
in space close facial proximity
this basic diagram illustrates the new
format it was adopted in 1988
so the council masters up there has five
divisions of 143 000 each
the sub-council down here
of masters also has five
sub-councils
within their divisions and the sector
council
has about 10 000 planets in each
specific sector
and those are subdivided into
groups of 100 worlds
and these are rule the masters that
we're talking about are the wisest
people that they have in our society
they're they're they're spiritual people
they uh
they achieve mastership by knowing more
than anybody else
and because they're all telepathic this
is easily recognized
and so
when a recommendation is made by
a senior master it usually is followed
because
it's the best course of action that
could be decided anyway
and will result in the we'll get the
best result
so now where is exactly where is
corondor
this is arcturus
and about two fingerlings finger width
north northeast of our tourists as you
look at it in the night sky
right in there someplace at the head of
the arrow is a star that you can just
barely see it's it's the finest
magnitude on the star charts it's just a
tiny little dot
and that's their son korrina we don't
even number it on our charts
it's uh
and their son has several planets they
come
corinthians come from the third planet
we'll go into that a little bit more
later but there's the star chart from
the start the big star chart
astronomical star chart used by
astronomers
so the next thing we have here is
probably going to be difficult for you
to read is
a list of corinthian scientists
that have been working
in one relationship or another with bob
renaud
he's met them all
and they represent for instance just
just
to give you some idea
vern farrell the top one works in
anthropodia anthropodynamics
the other two all do also
john lahr the fourth one down works in
chemistry and the next one does
jerry saul the electronics engineer
helped bob renaud do some
modifications on his equipment
vero pollen
under that is a genetical biologist
olly soren after that is a genetical
biologist sencore is a linguist
they can learn languages in about two
weeks any language
orival is a mathematician he was the
principal contact with bob bernard
orival is the one that picked him up and
escorted him around the various
facilities they took him to see
but he was a mathematician
leonary down in the
lower middle
is a psychologist she was the first
voice that contacted him over the radio
and he maintained a constant contact
with linare whenever he was being
escorted around the corinthian
facilities she accompanied orival and
together they showed him around they
introduced him to people
they demonstrated things for him
in their parent in their corinthian
society and their base facilities here
on this planet
below the break and the names there is
han kim a sociologist
before or below him or also a
sociologist
below them the last four names are
airy lawn is a teratologist
and the rest are the other four are
teratologists tarantologists are
scientists that study
earth the particular studies of earth
this next chart
which you can't probably can't read
either
is the crew
of the spc-12 which is the big 400 foot
diameter sphere that he was shown about
given a
a
manual
guide in corinthian language how to get
around there they let him keep the guide
by the way he still has it
and the crew
was made up of
the top one is an analyst esther laurie
then the captain alaina eldrani met him
several times as a co-captain he only
met once
communications officer ken roy helped
him do some work on his gear also
there were console operators three of
them
uh
another in three engineers a flight
engineer more mathematicians and
an astrological officer a navigator
the last group
is masters
in the governmental hierarchy the
masters that he met
at one time or another
in the upper case letters are the elder
masters
and lowercase let
letters are just masters the elder
masters are elected by
the conclave of masters because of their
they they rise to a level of superior
knowledge
and there are not very many of them
now the
to give you an idea what the masters are
and what they do they all have
specializations also that first one on
the top there
is krenlor
he's from arcturia arcturia
is one it's a headquarters planet for
the alliance many records are kept there
and he
frequently met
grenoir
akinvesta
had primary responsibility for the earth
operations going on here by the
corinthians
then there was more from corinthian
corridor
okay
here's
the last group our miscellaneous
personality met along the way
and
just to characterize them a little bit
there was the first one artadoric was a
replacement
for all this is interesting art and
doric
a time came when they wanted to take bob
to view
something that was going to take more
than one day which
means he's gonna have to get a vacation
from his job or maybe lose it
his parents who he's carefully kept
his contacts from his parents because he
knew that they would be highly disturbed
that they knew what he was doing between
the hours of midnight and morning
so he never told them
he had a pet dog slept on his on his bed
put in his bed
and he
he didn't have time to tell his
employers
so
for that pickup they brought the
corinthians brought another man
with him and introduced him to bob but
he looked just like bob like a twin
and they said this is art to doric he
will replace you while we're gone he has
been carefully prepared
to
use your habits and mannerisms speaking
with your voice
and work your job at the at the general
electric plant nobody will know the
difference
and they left artadoric he was dressed
in the same kind of clothes that bob was
wearing
and he went into the house into bob's
basement room and went to bed bob went
with
orival and the rest of the team on the
mission they were taking him on at the
time
i don't see any other particular
names of interest there
there here's one
there in sin was a venusian
working with the corinthians that they
had picked up
who was from a venusian mission on the
moon that was observing earth
now
they showed
bob their language and and gave him a
language course when he learned to speak
current and read corinthian
and i'll i've got
some symbols here to show you here's uh
what the korean language
looked like these are punctuation
symbols the third column over right
right about here those are corinthian
punctuation marks
and their equivalents
are
shown out here in this column
the first one for example example is a
period
and the second one is a comma
the third one is a hyphen
the fourth one is a colon and so forth
but they had a very well
developed language system as as well
developed as english or any of the other
earth languages and in some instances it
was even more developed and conveyed
more
knowledge in the words than we
than we know and use
here's another page on the
korean language all of this by the way
is in the little mini cd
where you can bring them up and look at
them in great detail later if you're
interested
these show
a sentence
right here written in corinthian
language
which says
it's a phrase that was frequently used
as they were departing they'd say
loose enos
and that meant
go in the light and until next we meet
and this shows uh
corinthian symbols
and these are galinguan symbols now the
linguists corinthian linguists explained
that
in the alliance of worlds the hundreds
even thousands of
worlds in the alliance
in this particular sector of space there
are two major
interplanetary languages
one is galinguan
and the other is
is uh
oh boy forgot it england and solex mall
solix mall was the language system that
was described by george hunt williamson
in his books uh other tongues other
flesh
he never mentioned anything yes he did
mention galinguan in his book too but he
didn't explain anything on it this
the corinthians explained that the
korean language language was derived
from galinguan and that in
the foundation of languages that
these two major language
systems
have many derivatives it's like
on earth many languages are derived from
latin one might say that latin
was a base language for earth languages
and in that same sense galinguan was a
base language for many planetary
languages within the
the alliance of planet system
and solex mal was the basic language of
another federation of planets in the
system there incidentally where it was a
parallel group
parallel to the alliance of planets that
had
roughly the same number
of planets and they're intermixed with
the alliance planets and they cut their
allied in what they call a
there's the
alliance of planets and the
superman
uh
alliance and
confederation of planets the
confederation of planets is something
like the alliance of planets
that
does have the same kind of a governing
system
and similarly but
the
confederation of planets uses another
base language system
than galinguan i don't have anything on
that here but those two are present all
over our neighboring our sector of the
galaxy gail england
the other one and solix mall
so
when i was studying the
languages there i should have had that
up i was talking about it
here is uh
while i was doing this
i discovered another book that was
written about bob renaud apart from
what gabriel greene was publishing
and this was a book that was written by
john dean
who wrote
he was pretty well known for his
authorship of flying saucers and the
scriptures a book that he had written
before this
and john w dean
hearing of bob's renowned contacts made
direct contact with him and began a long
correspondence with bob about the
context with the corinthians
and their intentions
this was welcomed by bob as one of the
few with whom
serious interest
in with serious and interesting
intentions about
his spectacular case and a regular and
frequent communication developed between
bob and john dean
john asked many questions got many
answers
including a description of the
corinthian language and a table of other
stars with planets in our vicinity of
our milky way this part we
will share some of the profound
information revealed by to bob renaud
for john dean at john dean's request by
the corinthians themselves as originally
published in john dean's book flying
saucers close-up
and here is that book for those of you
that have a copy of it
well
i don't see the
title on the top
i don't know why we don't have that let
me back up
that should have had flying sausage
close-up by john w dean that little
picture was in the middle of the page
and this is amazing because the slide
was photographed from this page
and you see we've lost all the writing
on the slide and tell me how that could
be done
gremlins yeah
so john dean
asked a lot of questions
he was
very interested in
details that gabriel greene didn't get
about for for example about the first
moon trip
and
bob had
pretty much terminated his
furnishing of information to gabriel
green by the time he took the first trip
to the moon
and this is a scene painted by
a staff artist for the
flagship close-up book you just the
cover i tried to show you
and this shows
bob renaud and a woman from the control
center at on the moon astra laurie
riding
moon scooters you notice they're
wheelers
and they're in
low gravity or low pressure suits
for
traveling around on the surface of the
moon shows the
earth there painted into the scene in
the
in its proper perspective
so here now then is the book
flying saucers and the scriptures
published by john
dean some of you may even have that book
in your in your collections
it's not a very big book but it was a
discussion of
the biblical
reports
of contacts with
extraterrestrial beings and an analysis
of them and an attempt to explain them
by john dean
before these contacts began
now john dean
asking about the
language was the one that
that persuaded bob to get the
description of the language and the
language
uh presentations there was a lot more to
it by the way just those three pages
only showed the punctuation
and a phrase
but he got a a system of description of
the language and how to speak
vocabulary words also and how to
phrase make phrases
so
not satisfied with that much john dean
started pressuring bob
get a list of the inhabited planets in
our
near
space
so bob asked the corinthians to what
they could do
they said they would get their
scientists their astronomers to prepare
such a list
and john dean was writing his
book
that you just saw flying saucers close
up with a large section on bob renaud
and the publisher was pushing him now
to get the rest of his information in
and he still had not received
the list of planets
that he'd asked for and he was delaying
the printing until he could get the list
he was pushing bob to get it
baba's trying to hustle the corinthians
to get the list to john dean and
and he gave john gave them john dean's
address
and when the corinthians
prepared the list to transmit it
instead of
delivering it to bob to be delivered to
john dean they're trying to speed it up
by sending an emissary from the
earth base in massachusetts with the
list to go out and mail it to john dean
directly which they did and the package
arrived john dean looked and he thought
gee this is just what i look for what i
asked for
and i
i'll send it right off to the publisher
i don't have time to do anything with it
so that's what went to the publisher
so the list
included
and this is the beginning of
that chapter on the other planets in
john dean's book
and i'll read the prelude here because
it's kind of important the list will
include those planets among the 75
brightest stars known to earth
astronomers
the listings will be as follows the
star's astronomical destination
designation
as used by astronomers such as gamma
booties its common name is used by the
alliance in this chart which is nearly
always the the word used by the
inhabitants if any of its planets it's
the last register number it's this is
from us in light years from earth and
light years that is accurate to within
one light year
and further data on these stars may be
found in any comprehensive astronomy
textbook or book of tables
so these stars the 75 stars are all
listed in our astronomy books and
they're all bright enough to be seen
with the naked eye
the planets will be listed in their
orbital order
from the innermost planet out
and the names will be
those used by the inhabitants if any
otherwise names used commonly
by the alliance to designate them will
be
shown
inhabitation codes include
uninhabited
col colonized ind indigenous population
in billions of inhabitants
length of day and hours to one tenth
that's in earth hours diameter and miles
length of years in earth years
and the
allegiance whether it's an alliance
planet or a confederation planet
and there's a third federation here it's
a calaran federation that is in
opposition to the first two
and they don't allow anything to be
released to the alliance and the
and confederation planets so the the
calran empire is quite different and we
we find them in opposition to
both the alliance and the confederation
and they will turn up in later on as we
go here
this is not to be considered a
comprehensive list of planets of the
alliance but rather
intended to acquaint the readers with
only those nearby stars easily visible
without telescopes
now the first one is
alpha conus majoris
which is serious that's this
group right here there's the name
it's uh
eight light years distant from us 8.8
light years distance from us
the first one on the list their periton
is colonized
uh its population is 42 hundredths of a
million that's probably four million two
hundred thousand
the length of the day is 27 hours and
not 27 to 9 10 hours of earth time the
diameter of the planet
is
5.709 million miles
its comparative year is 64
of our year
and it belongs to the alliance of
planets
the second one down here
is
wooden
it's colonized
its population of billions is 1.6
billion people the length of the day is
19.3 hours
the diameter is 6
320 miles
its comparative year length is 1.94
almost two of our years
and it belongs to the omegan
confederation now the omegan
configuration is going to come up again
a little bit later
it's the omegan headquarters by the way
then the next one
below that does not have an indigenous
does not is not populated
and doesn't have any indeed it is
populated but only with indigenous and
indigenous population that hasn't looked
out from its planet yet is still
stuck on the planet
and the next one below that also is
inhabited
but the inhabitants
its indigenous habits not colonized by
either the alliance or the confederation
and doesn't belong to the omega the
third one also
then the fourth one vector well it's
about this
sixth and seventh vector and
right now we get
there right in there
are two planets
that are both colonized
the first one
has a population of 1.96
billion
its length of day is
31.5 hours
the diameter is 2.88
2 80 miles
comparative length of year is
7.45 of our years
and it belongs to the confederation of
planets the up the other besides the
alliance in our area
and the one below it also belongs to the
confederation
the
next one is uh
in syria just a few comments we're not
going to do all of these but i'm just
going to show some examples here
serious by the way this
let me back up to it
chart we had here this this is serious
here
and it has 12 planets on the list there
nine are occupied
and keldan the one uh the third one down
as i said before
is the omegan headquarters
the omegans are
apart from the alliance and the
confederation
the first one of sirius
is the brightest star in the northern
sky
peritum
the top one right there
has a population of forty
forty two hundredths of a million that's
four million two hundred thousand it's a
research planet for high temperature
equipment
among other things
there's another one
of import here it's damat
which is the fourth one down
right there
and damat has a population of 4.9
billion
population it's the fourth
planet out from the sun
and it's a major military system for the
alliance for the alliance
and the rest go on from there
so we won't go there's
there's a quite a bit more we won't go
into that
at the moment here
we can come back to it if
anybody really wants to
be sure we get some more stuff covered
here okay here's a
here's a good one
let me buzz down here
a little ways
these are all star charts furnished by
the corinthians
listing major stars
and the planets orbiting them
they're all in the little e-book
so you can study them in detail if you
like
i don't know why we got a break we're
getting some drop outs
okay that's the last of the list
which shows uh
a summary there
i can find my summary card here
it shows the
25 most important planets
it show that shows that 75
of the brightest stars of the naked eye
were listed
15 only 15 of the 75
have no planets now our astronomers are
having a little bit trouble of trouble
finding planets and they believe that
if we find another star with planets
we're going to be lucky
it may tend to prove that there could be
somebody else besides us
in this whole vast universe
the corinthians see
that about 90 percent
or more of
all stars have planets families of
planets
of the 75 that they listed for us only
15 have no planets
252 are of the planets are inhabited
and 165 of those known planets are not
inhabited
four there are 417 total planets
in the 75 star system
corondor
is the third planet out
from the stark arena
got a lot of papers up here they're a
bit of a problem
there's a map of corondor
again it's
seen beyond our tourists it's 411 light
years from earth
it's the third
planted out from its star corina
the capital city is right in here it's
rel city
is a capital for the planet
it's uh
over three times the size of earth
uh
it's the top scientific planet of the
alliance one of the best in our galaxy
it's the home of ndwa
and major industries the major city is
pharrell city
the
it has
more land mass for water than we have it
has about 60 percent land mass
where ours is probably less than 30 35
it's a bigger planet it's three times
the size of ours
it has uh
it has a a stronger
gravity it's a
although the planet is three times the
size of ours it only has
3.2 times our gravity
which is quite a bit for us they say
that
an earth human standing on the surface
of mars
of corondorf if he fell down he's likely
to break bones
and if he stood in a corindian rainstorm
he'd be pelted to death by the raindrops
so we can't visit corondor
in our earth bodies
very easily
so
they explained to bob that
all planets have that have evolved
life forms and most as we see from the
listing here most of them do and are
inhabited so life forms have evolved
there
that all planets
are different from each other they're
like the leaves of a tree or snowflakes
there are no two planets identical
and the conditions on
there's no identical conditions on two
planets and so
the life form that evolves the
archetypical life form that evolves on
the planet
is
it evolves peculiar to the conditions of
that particular planet
and for them to go to another planet
sometimes it's too
inhospitable for
anybody to make the trip elsewhere
so they discovered that
in the process that they use of coming
here
they
they use a something like a
teleportation process
where they step into a cabinet on
corridor
and step out of a cabinet at the
receiving station in the in the base
here before they had a base here they
had to project the base
to this planet and receive it at the
projected base
and that was difficult because it
limited what could be transmitted but
they transmitted enough to build a
proper receiving
port on on earth
and then they began to teleport their
equipment and people here directly
now they said they told bob renaud they
said we don't look
exactly like you in our native state
that if you could see us
as we live on corondor you would
probably think we're ugly as a matter of
fact we think you're ugly too
when we look at you
but
bob always saw those visitors as the
women were extremely beautiful there
were no fat ones no skinny ones
they were all pretty well stacked the
men were good looking strong hunks
handsome and he thought they must have a
planet of beautiful people there
and now the corinthians are explaining
to them when they
come here they are teleported here
and when they're received at the
teleport station here their atoms are
assembled
on the earth archetypical form it's our
ideal form for earth
in earth chemistry and so they do look
handsome they
we don't archetypically
visualize
crippled people diseased people
so they were explaining to him what his
body would look like when they took him
to corindor they said the reverse is
true when you go there we have an
archetypical form oh we only got two
minutes late
and
when you get there you they said your
body
will look like this and they show them
an image
the image i showed him was a little bit
shorter than he stood
it had
very strong neck muscles had a a a heavy
skull
strong nest muscles strong muscular
frame
stocky
torso and legs to sandy at increased
gravity there
and
it had
the body and breathed gas with less a
richer atmosphere than ours was normal
for it ours is a little weak for the
corinthians when they come here and they
take it takes the time for them to
adjust to acclimatize to our
our uh less rich oxygen
atmosphere here
and
so they invited they actually
they invited about to come there now
when i started this
and i bob
bob brown says what would you speak on i
said well i from my age i'd like to look
back
i think i have pretty good hindsight now
and i know that we threw out some very
important cases and i'd like to
talk about the bob renaud case
so he said okay
and so when i started doing the research
on he put that in a bulletin by the way
he put it out on his website that i was
going to talk about corrindor
and about three weeks ago i received an
email
and i've been looking for bob bernat for
30 years
everywhere he just disappeared from
sight
together
and i couldn't find him
and
now i get an email letter from bob
renaud
and he said that it had been his
practice
to search the web and the e-net for any
references to corondor periodically for
the last 50 years
very seldom found anything but he
suddenly hit got a hit he found corondor
mentioned and was going to be discussed
at this conference here at this time and
i was going to be the speaker and he
gave my
email address
he looked me up in the web and he got my
web page which gave him the email
address he sent me an email later and he
said
i i see you're going to talk about my
case he said you know i haven't been
putting anything out on it he said it's
not really for public consumption he
says they don't understand it takes too
long to educate them he said i don't
mind if you want to talk about the case
but he said
the case is still going on you know i
said no i didn't know that
he said i have had contacts ever since i
terminated the arrangements with
gabriel greene he said i gave some
information to
john dean and after that i just stopped
sending information out to anybody
but he said i've been making notes all
this time he said i have hundreds of
pages of notes would you like to have
some i said oh i i sure would
two or three days later i received a big
cd in the mail from bob reynolds 400
pages
of new information contact notes on his
contacts since then he'd been to the
moon twice more and he'd been to the
planet corridor several times
working there and operating there in his
corinthian body when he steps out of the
teleportation cabinet in corridor he's
in his corinthian body when he comes
back here he's in his earth body
and he he said i have
written
done a little writing on the moon trips
but he said i have written nothing on my
trips to corridor because they suggested
i not do so he said the first one was a
business trip
and the next one was a recreational trip
he said i could probably
describe the recreational trip but he
says i have never written it up and he's
had a couple more trips since then and
they welcome him when he gets there as
an old friend
many of his
contemporaries are still there they live
an average of a thousand years
time's up they live an average of a
thousand years
whereas we live shorter lives so
most of the people that he interacted
with are still there
or still here well they still have their
bases here there's one
underground in massachusetts one off the
coast of san diego underwater one in the
south atlantic and they have some bases
in other countries now also and speak
the other languages where their
expeditionary teams happen to be
they also have by the way they have
prepared
what they call
agents of theirs but
they're people that have been especially
trained and conditioned to live here
that move out into our earth
society and are maneuvered in to
positions of semi-authority and they
said they have some of their agents are
in the pentagon some are in the white
house some are in congress some are in
the senate he said they have
successfully infiltrated our population
to a great degree as well
as the governmental bodies of russia and
they said
it's
that the collapse of the russian import
and explodes the cold war
is due to in some extent to the
contribution of our agents working
internally and quietly to
tamp things down and he said we are
still trying to keep things a little
better organized on your planet with
that i'll have to give up because i'm
over time and i thank you for your kind
attention
and i
i hope that's been informative
[Applause]
thank you
bob
thank you folks
thanks wendell
okay yeah yeah
give it up for wendell
the one and only
all right we will uh keep this break as
short as humanly possible and hopefully
that'll just be 12 minutes 15 minutes
maximum for tape changes and we're going
to start right up
we're going to be rolling
standby
[Music]
you