welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate um any other any other grows
you want to highlight Kristen any other
packs that you found interesting For
Better or Worse maybe that's the other
side of it I didn't really ask you guys
if there were things that like you
really didn't like I know some of you
did mention it but H okay what I
something I didn't something I didn't
like but was I guess like market-wise
really good uh was the rainbow s S1 yeah
yeah um It produced like
crazy super pretty it had like just a
slight knuckle like structure to the
flower which is something that you know
the market seems to go for is the like
knuckly
buds um and it was po
as [ __ ] but the it the quality of the
smoke was just not so
good yeah yeah I mean and I mean it's
cookies based you know that's one of
those
things yeah
it's it looks like it I'll yeah yeah I
mean yeah there's no denying that yeah
but I I will say that if there
are there are bigger spots out here
guys who are just you know like running
you know buying you know U-Hauls worth
of oky cuts and like running them just
for the market out here yeah and you
know some of those dudes are getting it
to you know go so I would rather see
that in the market because at least it
works and it's something different yeah
definitely awesome okay well
maybe so the the next part of this chat
was meant to be about what you've found
but like I said earlier it's it's kind
of impossible to talk about what you've
grown without talking about what you
found so you guys already covered some
of that maybe what we can do instead for
this next part is actually talk about
one thing I mentioned earlier things you
didn't like uh that's one thing but also
maybe lessons you've learned and that
can that can that could relate to both
what you've grown but also like how
you've grown things if that Mak sense so
maybe have have a think about what
hasn't gone so well and what you've
learned uh from both the point of view
of the genetics and the point of view of
you're growing um Sean maybe we'll bring
it back to
you yeah um so things that I guess I did
not enjoy um
most um I grew out a bunch of dominion
stuff early like back in like 2018 2019
or so I didn't really find anything um
what I hear that accent what did you
just say what did you just say about VA
boy I didn't really enjoy much of it um
it just was just like a lot of just
citris you know like the the any like a
lot of the Screaming Eagle crosses and
um like the local skunks I I grew out
yeah some of those and it was just you
know Citrus and and not really like what
he said was on described as on the back
I mean um the only one that was like
kind
of um good
was the the one like the the the
crossroad chem um whatever it's called
um hudo yeah yeah there you go yeah
hoodoo that was the only one that was
like pretty decent um but all the other
ones you know was like they yielded well
but it was
just like a lot of citrus I mean I guess
the sangria punch the sangria punch was
actually good but that was it was like
Killer Queen
um Killer Queen Screaming Eagle so there
was like a fruit punch feno in there and
and that just tasted really well killer
Queen's dope bro it was a I think they
had the Lone Star cut of Killer Queen if
I remember correctly I believe so um and
that one that one was by far my favorite
of uh any of the ones anything I grew by
him and was like
um had like this fruit punch feno and
then they had one that was just like
Clementine tasting and stuff that I had
a friend that uh really loved and I gave
him kind of the rest of the seeds of the
pack and he popped those and and ran
that for a while he kept a cut um that
he really loved of just kind of like the
the Citrus
fenos um I preferred the the fruit punch
um it's like a really
nice um kind of more electric high but
yeah um and really long lasting um and
then I guess some of the other ones I
didn't really like the the LA lemon
tree
um I did grow out for the LA uh chds and
I just didn't really find anything I I
was hoping for and I was growing them
alongside um the Blue Sour the appy f3s
um electric Baloo appy which I forgot to
mention earlier um which phenomenal but
um the the app f3s with just like the
the couple fenos I found that were like
this chem mango Funk that was just
really um mouth coding and everything
and the taste I
just you know was like I'd rather have
have this kind of thing because it's
like a a chem you know it's got the chem
taste and then the the diesel fenos were
all right but then three of the four
were just short Stout um of the LA chamd
and and you know I I may not have you
know if I if I ranom from clone and BR
random again I probably could have did
better with them but I also it wasn't I
didn't really find anything I was
looking for like the potency wasn't you
know the best thing you know the the
Blue Sour had better potency and some of
the fenos right CSI hear the appy the
appy
F the the appies were were were really
good too and and the the electric Baloo
appy it was just I they were the the
plants that were my least favorite of
what else was going um I'm not saying
like it was bad but just of everything
else that was going they're my least
favorite um and then what else
um other than that yeah I guess that's
kind of it's kind of about it I guess
that I haven't really liked I know
there's definitely some other ones in
there I just can't um think of it at at
the top of my mind yeah I was gonna say
as well um I realized that my question
is kind of a bit Batey in the sense that
you know maybe if if some of you are not
comfortable naming specific things that
you didn't like for various reasons you
can just maybe tell us in general what
you didn't like about it without nameing
oh oh one I could I could oh also he's
um seni star like f3s or whatever and
then there's there's another one that's
a f your Saints SE a banana a banana a
banana TI cross that I'm not gonna name
but it was just like this really just
boring just bubblegum
terpinolene you know just all of them
were just boring like uh citrusy
um terpinolene or bubblegum terpinolene
just like super
boring yielded well and looked pretty
though which one which one was that uh
it was banana Tha hybrid I'm just not
gonna
name so and so yeah yeah noted noted
noted [ __ ] that guy I mean yeah I mean
it yielded well and was pretty and like
commercial wise and everything is
probably good but like just the the what
I found it wasn't what I was hoping for
and and I was kind of you know told it
was supposed to be more juicy fruit and
not not like terpinolene and bubble gum
and yeah you know like and that the the
bubble gum terpening to me is kind of
the most boring you know really like
bubblegum
tping no it was like I can't really
describe it the the best but it's got
like that bubble gum and then it goes to
like this weird like weird thing it just
not it do do do for me yeah you need to
make it move man it has to make it move
for
so it wasn't really what I was was was
trying to find
um uh it's it's smokes decent so I mean
I guess that's all right it's just it's
just not my cup of tea you know yeah
yeah okay guys I a bit awkward but I'm
gonna have to dip for another meeting um
Matt's gonna take over and yeah thanks
again you guys for um joining us but
yeah I will catch you guys soon peace
5000 I had no idea they had grinder at
the North Pole where he's from anyways
um so I think where we at like uh uh
Kyle did you go over yours uh no but I
was just thinking of what I could uh
what I which ones I didn't like uh so
there was actually one which I was
really looking forward to was grape
chocolada which was grape pie and
chocolate Thai from canado oh yeah yeah
the ones that actually uh were kind of
okay I thought the the high was just if
they were all um it was almost like you
grew them too long the high was just
boring just Bland it was just like H
well you know you got stoned but that
was it it was almost like they you
overgrown you know you grew them too
long type of thing every single time um
and then lessons would definitely be the
Isaac Hayes and that's from dampering uh
because y samies yeah yeah yeah so I
yeah I grew those inside and I
definitely got some jungly type stuff
well and I also grow uh tents in a
garage so I kind of deal with outside
environment type stuff inside it's kind
of weird yeah so I know mean yeah so
during the summer when it gets in Cali
it gets hot so yeah it was they just
they didn't they never stopped and they
were in one gallons and I they without
with the bends they probably would have
been 12 feet uh they were they yeah
around the lights and two of them were
like that uh so that was definitely
interesting so I learned a lot there and
reset everything and uh haven't had that
problem other ones wer weren't finishing
as well and I think it was definitely
the heat uh because I run stuff hot
anyway with t uh so yeah I think that
was so definitely that was
lesson big lesson right there because I
mean for why I had to completely reset
and I remember even some some very nice
people hit me up on the DMS and like hey
man your stuff's not looking too too
good so yeah yeah that was pretty funny
so so shout out to skid willly and
Denali and then yeah I grew the same
banana thae I think that uh Sean did and
mine were remade Tangi so that wasn't
the greatest thing I end yeah I end up
throwing them the jars out actually
that'll do it they were they weren't uh
yeah I don't like Tangi Citrus is
definitely not my thing so yeah know
yeah so I will actually I think part of
that other uh the part of the banana tie
it actually is more of the Citrus part
and I think that's what I got but yeah
it was really weird it was just Tangy
yeah it was pretty bad so yeah I'm not a
Ki fan either yeah and then uh yeah man
that's about it for I can't really think
of too many you know because I just I
most of them when I grow I know uh I do
random stuff so a lot of stuff sometimes
I'm not really looking I'm just looking
to learn uh stuff type of thing
especially since I'm newer uh I just
want to see uh stuff so I do
S1 especially just to get a look under
the hood type thing yeah no it's a great
way to do it it gives you a lot of
really good especially s1's from from a
reliable source it gives you uh data
points you can you can speak on things
more thoroughly you can you get a much
better understanding of traits uh you
know there's a lot to it yeah so yeah
and that's probably it for lessons and
uh stuff I didn't like that I can think
of right off the bat so all right so
from here we're going going to move on
to what else you're looking
for the
future um Sean desired strains and
traits uh what we're gonna have you guys
do you know one after the other each
grower shares which strains they are
interested in growing out next and then
uh discuss specific traits you're
looking for etc etc
etc so um I know I think later on we
we're going to talk about like things
we're growing next or whatever but um
some of the things I am excited about
and and want to try and look for like
certain traits um so sleep disturbance
the the p91 um S1 uh Blue Dream yeah I'm
gonna be running that next um I just
like the Discord and everyone everyone
talking about the p91
S1 um like I'm just really interested
and I want to you know kind of see what
that about and hopefully you know get
some fenos that are kind of more leaning
that um but just kind of you know just
get more markers on the the Blue Dream
crosses because I'm G I got a decent
amount of those that I want to run um I
ran the the montere bay dreams which I
really liked and um I really like the
Santa Cruz wreck so I kind of want to
get through more of those see more Blue
Dream yeah and and things like that so I
have um and then as well as uh the
electric Baloo dog [ __ ] um like I got
that and and blue dream I have more of
the electric Baloo ay to look at and
then the electric Baloo um mango hazee
um and I really want to look through
those as well um the the ones I got
which I think I got like the KMD mango
um green so good ones in there yeah the
electric boo and I just you know kind of
want to see both parents in there get um
because I haven't really grown any true
hazes so get some experience of that um
see things and and also just you know
try and find some really nice electric
uh work weed um which would be nice and
then also um I have some
of uh Lu's uh saene 16 Destroyer that I
really want to look through and just
find some just really something really
unique um like tpping profile and and
and high wise um just something that you
know may be a little bit trippy um and
and just the description that I've heard
of the sir 16 being kind of like a
blueberry OG that just sounds wonderful
too so like blueberry muffin cereal like
so [ __ ] good it's really yeah no
blueberry in it hoping to find something
with like that kind of tpine profile
with the the Destroyer effects um I'm
sure the saan effect uh 6 scene effects
are really great as well
um and then also his um Malibu P Kush uh
A5 backcross yeah I want to check those
out as well um and just you know grow
some more uh hay stuff stuff that's like
more unique um not really what other
people are necessarily growing I know a
bunch of people are about to start going
into H lonesome's man
Hayes but that's fine I mean everyone
should that there's going to be a bunch
of really cool stuff in there
um and you know that's what I would kind
of go to First just you know if you have
the space and and time and everything um
just no unique versus like you can go
and get chems and and everything else o
not necessarily ogs as much anymore you
can find some OG hybrids here and there
um but like everyone's growing cookies
and chem stuff and sour this and sour
that and so so like you know I'm trying
to like not keep growing that I grew out
a lot of sour hybrids I'm just and and
Diesel hybrids in general and I'm just
kind of sick of those like it's massive
Hit or Miss in those um dude it is it
really is wasted so much time um I feel
like no yeah just to find the final
three I ran of of the the sour skunk dog
the Blue Sour and the appy Diesel and
then finally found those and I'm just
like all right like those those are the
only ones I'm going to go back through
and look through if um when I do um but
yeah just wasting time trying to like
Chase certain things um that I felt
worth were worth chasing at the time and
you know it it is what it is you you
know you you live and learn um so I'm
just trying to grow some more unique
stuff um get some you know experience
growing more longer flowering stuff see
different
structures um and just learned different
techniques from seeing these structures
on how to apply to make them work for um
my space and and everything um I just
you know kind of love experimenting and
just plants in general I I work with
plants so just seeing how everything
grows and its growth structures um the
different smells it produces um it's uh
like just the strength some of the the
branches can get to and I you know I
enjoyed training at times so it'll be
fun with the haze and everything when
they start stretching to to see what I
can do with them I you know I'm just
trying to see as many things as possible
um and I try and run plants that have
the same parents at the same time so if
it is going to put out the father like
there's either going to be like a bunch
of plants that are all the same fathers
um and then just so I can you know
notice those traits easier where I could
be like well that line has this and then
that line also has this the same father
chance art could be the father um and
just kind of just narrow down and just
learn little different traits and and
little like nuances of of each little
plant yeah dude it's it's a great way to
do it it's a really great way to do it
to understand a line and the the haze
lines like you know people always say
like I'm gonna grow this Haze I'm gonna
grow this piff you know like all that
stuff but really that mango Haze line
one of the best that Neville's Haze to
me and and trying to find a good
Neville's Haze now is very hard um mango
Haze Neville's Haze are the cream of the
crop for hazes that are like
commercially viable in the sense that
most people in generally speaking most
people that are into weed will smoke
them and like them like they're not so
Airy and fluffy again generally speaking
because they're in there that they're
they're going to look weird in a bag any
of that stuff like that that they're
awesome they're awesome
yeah so I think uh that's probably about
it of of what I'm looking um forward to
and just kind of what I'm exactly
looking for it's it's more you know like
trying to see different traits and
certain um things and just gain
experience and also you know find some
kind of unique racy High that's um will
also be good for you know aches and
pains but uh won't make me too stupid to
work but we'll keep me alert
all right uh screw what you
got um yeah right now I have uh at week
four I have the skylines from H&amp;L okay
and that's what's in that the shoreline
by Appalachia sweet sweet and um and
then I just flipped some of the uh
garbage clouds from pack the um
Shoreline by Santa Cruz Blue Dream It's
a good way to see the shoreline stuff
see what it's like yeah well I mean yeah
that was your thing right like
shine yeah I kind
of I was a little bit uh uh annoying
about it but no I mean no like that was
your Chase though that's like your thing
yeah I mean I've been that was like the
weed that you know the it wasn't the
first really good weed that I had yeah
but it was the first really goodwi that
I had that made me stop buying Swag yeah
you know it was like oh [ __ ] I I'll just
spend 20 bucks you know yeah
um so and i' I've been like trying to
get a hold of a cut and uh you know just
been a total [ __ ] Noob about it for a
long time and finally I did end up
getting it yeah
um and God damn is it hard to [ __ ]
like hit right yeah yeah that's a Wy cut
bro like just looking at it it looks
[ __ ] yeah it looks like it'd be very
hard to to grow consistently to nail
every time um yeah yeah and and there's
also you know like not only is it hard
but like the flavor I don't know it's
weird it's like the better you grow the
flowers at least from how I've been
doing it better that I get the flowers
to set the worse the flavor is that's
weird yeah yeah um and it it just it's
not like it doesn't last very long so
out of those two lines I'm hoping to
find something that's a little bit
easier to nail that has improvements on
like flavor and you know maybe a weird
twist to the smell yeah the appy one
sounds like a good good hold to climb
down for that too yeah that's that's
what I'm hoping that and you know the uh
I ran the wet dream yeah um and my buddy
down here Donnie he ran uh the dream
Killers okay and it seems I don't know
the that blue dream note in there really
like carries a quality factor to it in
this smoke I love blue dream like but
like again I got to qualify that most
people like when you say you love blue
dreams are like a I hate that [ __ ]
because they never got to smoke the cut
that we all grew back in the day and um
and and or if they did it probably
wasn't grown that well you know in some
people's you know chemistry doesn't line
up with I really love that cut the high
the quality um even the flavor like even
though it's like a terpinolene kind of
Base I don't know it's it's [ __ ]
rad yeah which I was one of those people
who hated on Blue Dream for a long time
cuz yeah you know me and my buddies back
in the day sold a lot of very bad Blue
Dream yeah um and it just like poured
into here for a long time yeah by the D
but the actual you know like actually
well done Blue Dream stuff is pretty
good man like killer killer
yeah yeah there's re that cut
up yeah I I have a couple of other
Shoreline hybrids also um the shoreline
by cough by Vietnam Black Oh Yeah from
H&amp;L the shoreline by mango Hayes uh also
from
H&amp;L and the shoreline by A5 backcross
from Louch oh nice in those I'm I'm more
like looking for you know just it that's
more of like an adventure like I'm
looking for weird new you know like
stuff that
you know hopefully is just super
radically different than you know than
normal yeah that's a great place to
start for
it all right is that is that about it
for you on that
one oh yeah I mean I'm look if there's
some other Blue Bonnet I I stay steady
popping Blue Bonnet hybrids better yeah
they're good man yeah yeah I I get stuck
with it for a reason you know
like it it's very hard to find a
anything that breeds true in the first
place and that's that reliably passes
traits um yeah it's just one of those
things where even as a from a breeding
perspective I don't even really think
about it from a a customer perspective I
think about it from a breeding
perspective um it's just really really
hard to nail that a perfect male that I
I think is perfect for breeding so yeah
I I still haven't really moved on I'm
just going through the hybrids now um
yeah probably going to reproduce
bubbleberry this summer we'll see how
that goes though we see okay Kyle what
you
got all right well uh see I'm looking
forward to uh the going through the
third round of these chocolate TI
Skittles the final final selections
because uh yeah now it's just narrowing
it down to basic you know what which
ones give me the the highest basically
like it I liked it you definitely got
that that funk the earthy funk in there
and those are the ones that I like that
yeah there was some other ones uh one
was we were talking about on the Discord
the other day it was actually dryer
sheets but more of a Downey Downey like
actual fabric maybe not dryer yeah it
was really weird uh that that the high
was okay on that one it was the the the
definitely not like the that that armpit
Funk that you know you said the Skittles
Cube the Z Cube yeah yeah yeah uh then
see what else uh I got coming up I got
some uh blue dream s1s
um Santa Cruz Rex uh see what else some
black poison from the Rev uh that was
are those I'm really looking forward to
because uh I end up finding out it was
an older pack and I recently got a hold
of him through email and uh he said
though he doesn't even recognize them so
he's pretty sure those are f1s based on
you know I sent him a leaf picture and
stuff like that yeah and so I'll
probably do something with those just to
make more seeds uh because I would
definitely want to look through f2s of
those because that has uh his own
Vietnam Black and then it also has his
uh old school Durban uh what he calls
Durban Poison Bros so and then it has
Neo black Russian in it so yeah that
definitely would that sounds pretty good
to me man to look through a little bit
of I love that line dude I I I I grew so
much black Russian stuff it's unreal uh
throughout my career like early on I
focused like I do with Bonnet like a
good seven or eight years I focused on
black Russian stuff Blackberry stuff so
yeah I like it yeah and then the other
stuff uh see I got some uh super Servo
Haze s1's tribute from old hog yeah uh
and then uh some cherry Mila f3s from
the Rev too so that's basically what I
got coming up for quite a bit so just
trying to get through all
those all right yeah well now we get
down to experimental
techniques so like anything you guys are
trying to incorporate um different
techniques
Technologies um and the potential risk
benefit you know ratios um you know this
isn't going to apply to everyone like
with me I I just stick with my [ __ ] like
haven't never tried LEDs like you know
what I mean so I know that's not going
to be for everyone but um if any of you
want to talk about this feel free to
speak up like if there's anything that
you've been incorporating new that maybe
you have't other wise or uh yeah
anybody free
shot uh about the only thing new that
I've been doing the past uh probably
like year or so has been adding um
hydrogen peroxide into the bottom of my
clone
tray yeah I've been digging that but
like growwise no I'm kind of stuck in my
wave yeah I feel you there
dude Sean you got anything yeah um I'm
pretty much stuck in my ways growwise I
I have thought you know about trying uh
Coco and you know doing that a little
bit or try a little bit of more like
Sanic um approach but man I'm busy with
work and everything and and you know I'm
just you know stuck in my ways not
really trying to to venture out until I
have a little bit more space where I can
uh have like an experimental
um area and then have you know kind of a
a main flower spot um and then yeah when
I have some more space then that's
probably when I'll try out some more new
things but nothing really like new new
techniques or anything that's like
cutting age or anything like that
yeah Kyle you got anything uh no nothing
because uh I was just waiting for the
new you know rev book you know make sure
go go pick that up yeah definely go by
that book um it there's a forward
written by probably by the most handsome
um seed maker ever so biggest dick check
it
out yeah I was waiting for that and I
just do I was just waiting for more of
the um little additions that he does
because uh after that reset I haven't
been doing I was just doing kind of
plain water and now I've I've just was
waiting to now he's kind I think he's
finished up with kind of his experiment
type stuff that where he's confident I
think where he's got his grow where he
wants it so I was just wa kind of
waiting for that type thing so yeah so
real quick Kyle do either of us that you
know of have the 1979 calendar or is
that one of the ones that was missing uh
which one because actually I what I'm
finding out is there is actually the
Cannabis calendar started 73 and those
are not the Brotherhood of Eternal L
ones okay yeah no this one's the um CIA
one yeah okay now that one that one is
from KO it's from who the K yeah so
that's that's the sensia techniques yeah
and I I I have that one okay I finally
got it on the way I'm stoked yeah yeah
those are and then there is other ones
of those I think there's two other ones
of those okay that makes sense that that
would be Kos then yeah yeah yeah those
and actually yeah the pictures are some
of the ones that are in the book The
Sense Media technique okay yeah they're
just bigger which is is really cool it's
a cool calender yeah they're really cool
actually I I picked up a few I just got
another one too it's I posted the the
cover but I got to open up the package
so it's a the cultivator 77 uh calendar
oh really yeah I have that one no these
are I've been picking up a lot of
different ones I have a normal 76 one
which has a double cover it's missing
two things I have a lot of weird I've
been finding a lot of Crazy Ones man
it's really yeah we scanning them we
scanning them oh yeah they're all in
they're all in Discord and also yeah on
the thing oh yeah so yeah for for people
who don't know we have stuff like that
in the Discord
um like a lot of these old calendars
have a lot of the old I mean pictures of
the strains like the aapu gold the
Panama Red um W Hawkins Guerin stuff
that like we hear about today and um
maybe you'll see Barney's Farm say they
sell um but that's not really the case
and to have point of origin like time of
origin pictures and to be able to look
at those be able to get whatever you
know visual data points and traits that
you can see um is super helpful
especially when they describe it you
know like uh word for word like um R are
The Connoisseur used to do so yeah um
yeah that 79 has a uh has some great
pictures of Colombian in there and and
what I noticed is they have have a lot
of serration oh interesting yeah so
that's what that was that was that's
what I took away from it and I don't
know now I don't know what they did to
it but they were going I don't think
they would have just you know spent a
lot of time they were trying to hide it
so yeah for sure especially in those
pictures they're all tied down and stuff
so I don't think they would have been
cutting off serration so yeah I just
that's one thing I took away from that
so I thought that was interesting that
is interesting yeah I think someone on
the show before was saying that
columbium was also
rated yeah yeah anyway um yeah sorry for
the aside yeah we on that I know I just
nerd out on like I just just saw it pop
up on he got it um what makes a keeper
for you guys so uh
Sean this is kind of a rough I don't
know man it's kind of an on the spot
question um what makes a keeper for
you um so I do like to pick um based off
of structure but then also um so
structure it's you know how how quickly
it'll grow
um I usually don't like things that are
too slow in veg I like you know be able
to do like a if I'm doing like a quick
seed run do like four to six weeks um
and then be good enough to run them some
things from seed if I'm just trying to
do like a quick uh run to see what see
what they're about you know will take
you know two months or or so the veg and
and even running from clone may you know
take um double the time than it would
than the one that are much quicker in
seed form um so so I do like things that
grow a bit quicker um and then the
plants that like to support themselves
um not much
staking um obviously there are ones that
um you need a steak and and they're
they're amazing plants and it that's
just something you have to deal with um
but I do like um a more sturdy structure
that is is vigorous and and then um
yields not necessarily the most
important thing to me
uh sometimes it's nice but I'd rather
have the the flavor translate fully and
and be mouth coding as long and then as
long and then as well as have um the
effects you
know be what I'm looking for um whether
it's it's something for for the
daytime um to have at work or or just
you know nighttime you know try and just
chill relax um maybe just you know
completely take the the mind off of
things and and for you know just forget
and be able to zone out and and get some
good sleep um so really those are kind
of the parameters I'm kind of selecting
off of um mostly effects uh being number
one
effects and then flavor and then
structure um there have been plants that
were more floppy that I really do love
um but I do you know prefer plants that
have a little bit more sturdy structure
that don't necessarily have to stake or
um trellis too much um but I will
trellis or stake those heavily if you
know if needed like the original sin um
some of those needed more heavier
staking and things like that and you
know I love those um the the appy
diesels those were actually like pretty
pretty sturdy um they didn't much
staking the couple fenos I really liked
um they got really like nice big and
bushy um but yeah I I love plants you
know just the flavor the fla and it has
to be mouth coating um if I'm going to
keep it
for the flavor wise um there so many so
many jokes I'm holding back right
now let them go all day all day every
time yeah yeah it's gonna be uh you're
gonna put on the soundboard in a
second my yeah I think I think that's it
um you know effects and then you know
flavor and and then you know structure
after that
all right screw what you got what is
your definition to be
keeper uh I mean really it's just more
it's stuff that I want to smoke you know
cuz I only
smoke like what I grow and what my
friends you know in our little group
down here grow
um but I guess to to kind of use a a
phrase that that local said
um I like weed with character like so
whether that you know the only stuff
that I really don't like is Citrus types
honestly like everything else I mean if
if it's good it's good I came into the
syndicate with a lot of like I don't
like this I don't like that and then
just through like growing and like
trying my friends who were growing you
know other stuff found good types of
that like I didn't used to like fruit
types you know yeah that's fair you know
but if if it's good it's good
yeah all right Kyle what makes it keeper
for you uh pretty much everything that
Sean said basically I mean effect uh I
mean taste uh then structure and then
you know if it's going to be a pain in
my ass uh over time I definitely don't
want it because I noticed that her stuff
especially clones after about uh a year
and a half two that's when they start
getting kind of funky yeah and then that
that's usually when I've already ran
them about twice by then usually because
I don't usually I don't run seed I run
everything from Cuts yeah um so yeah
that that' be that for me what it is
yeah all right um if you guys want to
give any examples of any keepers that
you have um I don't know if you guys
have already done that or not like
trying to think back into our
conversation um mine would just be the
banana tie so Banana as of right now so
[ __ ] the world yeah yeah Sean what do
you got currently um I have none but of
of what just because of the work being
done and not being able to keep things
but of what I'm gonna go back through um
to look for Keepers that I already know
offand are going to be Santa Cruz wreck
um
eappi the the electri booo appy um and
then original sin and then that ation
Diesel and then I do want to go back
into the blue resin to look through that
line more as well um there's some
phenomenal plants in that um that I that
I need to just go back through and and
do a larger pop and try and find the one
I want to keep yeah there's some wild
testing plants in that line I've told
people before but I don't know um it
doesn't really stick but yeah like
anomalous anomalously Wild testing
plants in there um that kush cut from
resin long was just something else I had
one that was like blueberry cotton candy
yeah was just like and then maybe like a
little bit of earthiness on the back end
that was just like really really good
dude once you hit once you hit real
blueberry like that actually tastes and
smells like it no going back what about
you
screw uh I I hold on to a lot of things
right now um but there's some stuff that
you know I don't know I who knows how
many years I'll hold on to it onto it uh
like because I the way I see it if I
find something that fulfills that like
same role and is better then I'll just
keep that yeah makes sense you know like
I have uh I went through so for instance
like I have uh tusin leather uh number
one TUS my Budd yeah that my buddy
popped and uh it's kind of citrusy but I
guess
um I don't know I guess it's like a it's
super complex though still it's the um
and when I when I ran the uh Death in
Venice it was pretty much the same um
type of smells and flavors and stuff
just way worse yeah uh same with the
effects and all that so yeah um like
right now I'm holding on triangle choke
is something that I'm I love to death
and I've been I don't think I'll be
dropping that one
um anytime soon at least uh I I mean I
do want to go through four more packs of
it to see if you know like if I found
that out of two yeah imagine yeah if I
could find a better version of it hell
yeah um right same with uh the chemis S1
by Blue Bonnet yeah um I saw the
potential in it and like don't get me
wrong it's good it's the cut that I hold
on to is good yeah um it just the
earthiness really kind of like comes in
full force at the end and Bullies the
the blueberry and like the nasty so in
in in that blueberry there is earthiness
in some of those expressions and that's
everything I've tried breeding away from
because it is so strong in DJ's
blueberry so strong and it's just the
one thing because it can overpower the
berry part to where you just kind of
like yeah I smell the berry you know so
those are the ones I always tried to
breed away from it's it sucks and when
you cross it to something like kimd that
also has earthiness to it or chem the
chem ss1 which is like a u very similar
to KMD and it's a cannaboid scent
expression
um yeah that that earthiness is
definitely in
there yeah it I'm I'm actually seeing
that in the uh the bubbleberry that I'm
that I have at week four right now it's
like moldy blueberries not like bubble
yay blueberry it smells like has a lot
of earthiness in it too a lot like a lot
it could be very hard to work against uh
very dominant very very dominant type
strain when you cross to it
yeah all right
Kyle the keepers or the oh yeah you
already said b anai h yeah B anai for
now yeah that's that's the one I found
yeah if there's something else uh yeah
I'll keep
it all right all right so I don't know
is there anything any of you guys want
to say like you know you've seen these
episodes forever right um is there is
there anything you guys want to say like
that you've always you know if you could
have inserted anything in any episode
that you'd want to tell people uh feel
free to now Sean
anything um I would say go and grab the
mango hay stuff and and run and run some
unique stuff um I mean I I guess it's
kind of said every show but you know
don't keep running what everyone else is
running do something unique um but yeah
that's that's probably about it don't be
a cheap B uh screw which you
got uh well I guess it's something we're
going to cover over uh later but the
whole clone chasing game oh yeah it you
know I I chased one thing for 16 years
before getting it and now I'm ready to D
like I'm way more excited about the
hybrids yeah and the stuff that y'all
can find in seed is if you choose the
right seed like I totally get if you're
popping funky [ __ ] and just kind of like
getting a you know mids roller
coaster then it doesn't seem like it's
worth it and like that's all you'll need
to elevate your grow but n just get
legit seeds grow it like a normal person
don't you know do a bunch of weird [ __ ]
like we see some people come in talking
about yeah yep and you you'll do all
right yeah man the Clone chasing game's
brutal I did that with hp13 forever
forever and the hybrids are so much
better than the Clone but it was because
like back when I was young read the
canab Bible and it was like oh this is
the one so of course I'm like oh this is
the one that's the one I'm gonna chase
that and everybody was chasing it and
nobody would give it up nobody and then
you finally get it all these years later
it's like
oh that's that's cool
you know um yeah let like it's it is the
difference between Elite clones and your
own Keepers and being able to run
through seeds teaches you a lot like the
people that are selecting a lot of these
quote unquote Elite clones are doing it
from like one or two seeds in a pop in a
closet and like it's just how well they
hype it um who their friends are that
they pass it to and that makes the
difference between an elite versus your
own Keeper in my opinion
uh I don't know if any of you guys have
opinions on that and they there're you
know you have no idea how high the
likelihood that they picked that one
over you know a sibling because of the
marketability or the bag of you know
like stuff that you might not care about
as as a factor yeah yeah
absolutely I mean like do you guys have
any opinions on Elite clones versus your
own keepers Sean Kyle either of
you uh well what I've noticed from
Elites because there's certain stuff
that just doesn't uh what people think
of elite like Cam and Bubba uh those
highs for me are not what they are for
other people yeah uh they're more just
kind of whatever so cam has always been
more sativa uh High what people would
call that I hate using that word but I
know that's how people can kind of
identify what I'm talking about uh and I
think they're more breeders they're
better breeders I I found the Bubba
hybrids have always been really good for
me but I've never had good just plain
Bubba to me um maybe it could have been
the grow but I've tried different ones
over the years and that's always just
been the same uh but I always like the
hybrids so I think to me what Elite is
uh for clones is always maybe they're
better breeders they're not always good
as smoke yeah so type of thing that's
what I
found and obviously my Keepers is I'm
looking for I'm looking for good smoke
because it's all hits for me so
yeah all right you haven't had uh any
experience growing any Elite clones or
anything um like that but I say that's
Pro it's also kind of subjective um
obviously there's ones that have just
been around for a long time um that
everyone kind of unanimously agrees on
but then there's other ones you know
that have been around a long time that
um not too many people have have seen
and then like um screw was saying like
he was chasing in Shoreline and whatnot
and I'm pretty sure that's a cut that's
like pretty difficult to get yeah yeah
there's a lot of fake Shoreline out
there for so many years because the main
guy who had it dipped offline for a long
time yeah that's that's a long time to
you know Chase something and then not be
completely you know thrilled about it um
I've never been one that even try and go
and buy any clones from anyone or any of
the the Clone dealers I'm just not
really interested if you know if someone
offered me uh one of the leits or
whatever I may take it but I I don't
know if I'm like too interested in
growing like there's very few that I am
interested in growing um but I'm more
interested in growing people's uh
selections that they found kind out of
like recent recent things you know yeah
um so you know just I don't want to end
up getting someone's old clone you know
and end up
having it just destroy
everything you know that's been
my Theo thp M yeah yeah that's been my
thing also with not wanting to get
clones I I and I'm a person that kind of
likes to to do things on their own um so
I'm trying to find something from seeds
and and you know kind of then breed that
into something that I then enjoy myself
or just find something from seed that I
really enjoy and just keep that and be
like I'm I'm really happy with it
yeah now that all makes sense bro well I
guess like that's kind of I I know he
wanted me to go two hours but this is
kind of like the the end of it wrapping
it up um so with that
said any last
thoughts um Sean any shout outs anything
like that um n not that I can think of I
mean thanks thanks for having me on uh I
appreciate it and uh we appreciate you
man one of the few other punk rockers in
the group bro like stay strong uh screw
you got any final
words uh thanks for having me on and um
I guess thanks to everybody in The
Syndicate just for you know making the
place what it is [ __ ] yeah dude um and
like The Syndicate is all of us you know
like that's the thing like it's it's
become quite a uh a close friendship for
all of us like not not just like the can
Illuminati dudes but everybody that's
been a part of The Syndicate it's grown
and grown and grown and uh yeah which
also grows the Inner Circle too which is
pretty [ __ ] cool you know we get to
find the people that we really really um
I don't know connect with Kyle what you
got uh yeah just thanks for having me
and yeah man this was a good time so
that's it shout out to the doggy oh yeah
absolutely man I I'll give K him some
love for you absolutely yeah please do
dude that yeah that dog's amazing anyway
you guys thank you so much and uh I
guess we'll see if we can get this
posted Friday Saturday Sunday Monday I
don't know when it'll be but we're going
to find out so I appreciate you
guys want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out