welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate hey what's up everyone um you
may be wondering where our current video
for this week is um it aired and then it
was taken down about an hour hour and a
half after airing um it was reported um
erroneously by
can't say for sure um they accused us of
drug dealing uh which is laughable since
we're a history show uh we don't sell
anything on here um but as you can
imagine we were showing a specific seed
bank and their prices are on their
website and we were commenting on how uh
ridiculous some of the advertising was
so they use that against us however
however even though YouTube is pretty
awful um about how they're handling this
since we can't appeal it you will be
able to go
to v.com so
vimeo.com
9476229
3930 and uh you can watch a video there
and it's full unedited Glory um the
YouTube version is going to be audio
only unfortunately so you lose a lot of
the context on images um when we're
talking about stuff but I wanted you to
be able to go somewhere where you
can still like have access to the full
video so it'll be up there feel free to
go watch it and um yeah we're not going
to be bullied
like don't scam you won't have a problem
you know don't work with scammers you
won't be
highlighted simple as that um yeah we'll
always fight back and I I really don't
care like I nothing's going to slow this
down the information will get out there
um I'm not just one person anymore that
you can try to stifle like a lot of you
guys did for a lot of years there's a
whole lot of us so with that said um
yeah go click the link I'll put it in
the description hopefully YouTube
doesn't take it down because we're
leaking outside of YouTube um yeah it'll
also be up on the screen so you can see
it there and uh just enter it in your
your um I don't know address bar and go
check it out lots of
love want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out