welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to breeder Syndicate
2.0 where we explore the history of a
clandestine scene researching everything
from cannabis strain history old
smuggling Tales from the first
okay [ __ ] it um yeah neither one of
those was the right intro what just like
[ __ ] it let's go into it I'm here with
the legendary Chucky pollen um trying to
get to the bottom of this beef a little
bit see what he's up to where he's from
where he's been what clicks he's rolled
with all that good [ __ ] so uh welcome
Chucky what's up Matt I'm glad you
finally you know take a SI out your busy
ass important life out there in Cali to
[ __ ] acknowledge a homie you know
what I mean that goes way back got out
the pin you blew me up I kind of had no
choice it was non-stop you know I I
don't think I told you a mom ain't
filled you in yet but I did go back to
the PIN for a little while you know you
you gonna laugh I didn't need to steal
it bro but I did go to [ __ ] Kroger a
few years back I was already you know on
probation and [ __ ] for the other stuff
but anyways I go to [ __ ] Kroger and
like man there's these 8 O steaks this
Wago [ __ ] Bro in this the frozen section
bro and like dude I have these
sweatpants on and normally like I said I
wouldn't [ __ ] do this kind of [ __ ]
but I slipped them steaks in My Pants
next thing you know dude at the front's
catching me and anyway I try to run
steal him [ __ ] get locked back up but
that's why I hit you out I just got out
of the jail bro and I need up on wagu
charges huh bro that meat I just like
good meat you know me bro trying to
steal the dude's meat try to steal a
man's meat you're gonna go to jail Bro
[ __ ] Kroger bro stay out the [ __ ]
meat section yeah but I've been but
anyways I had time to think locked up
and [ __ ] I started rapping and [ __ ] I
did some other stuff but I was thinking
like you know we go way back you always
told me like when I you hit me up when I
first got locked up or whatever I don't
think you remember uh because you G I
don't remember but you told me if you
told me bro if I ever needed I don't
think you ever
spoke I swear bro you hit me up with
that con or whatever may maybe maybe
whatever you hit me up but my thing is
you told me like bro if I never ever
needed help just to hold my head and
when I get out of being locked up or
whatever you you'd help me out so here
we are bro was I standing in front of
the Celly connection booth and was my
eye a little
wonky bro any of that in your memory bro
I'll be honest with you I didn't have no
bread on me so I didn't go to your
booths cuz your [ __ ] was hella expensive
remember in the bathroom I caught you in
the bathroom you at the journal I was
the guy the guy with the Kim crosses and
[ __ ] I was trying to get you to do the
clab with me bro but you you kind of
like lowkey diss me bro low key I mean I
I don't know I'm not even sure if that
was you it was a man he had on it it
looked like a disguise of some sort I
don't know if you were really treding to
be super
lowkey yourself it don't it it's then
and there bro you know like I said I had
time to clear my head in jail and [ __ ]
that's right you know you got me on the
show and I before we get started I
wanted show you how much of a big fan I
am of uh like the Discord and and Denali
and [ __ ] I got the MAA shirt on he's got
he's got a shirt just like there there
you are bro your [ __ ] face bro on my
shirt I don't know if y'all can see the
sht is that a missa shirt that's a missa
shirt with my facea shirt right there
there it is Matt M good looking good
looking Matt Ms right there with the
with the blonde hair mid D anyways I
know you got some questions for me we
got some questions lined up from the
Discord some of the people from the
Discord got some questions for you maybe
me we can rock out whenever you're
[ __ ] ready pal yeah you know the
first one sent in I think the guy's name
was autog Growers only you wanted to
know when you started puffing tough puff
and tough you mean like big [ __ ] like
traditionals and [ __ ] like that
because well I ain't GNA lie you guys
you know people going to try to diss me
and A very wise man in Discord once said
uh you know people always going to
remember where you started okay so I'll
be honest I was a closet Auto grower for
a long [ __ ] time just because of my
growing situation and illegal State back
in my home state of Kentucky you know
what I'm saying so like I had to get
that little Perpetual Harvest going but
s you know as far as Puff and tough you
know uh I've been [ __ ] around I
wouldn't even consider myself for grower
bro like I'm not going to sit here and
lie and say I'mma been the grower for 20
years [ __ ] like that cuz like I really
didn't start growing till I started
[ __ ] with the autos and [ __ ] like
that but like as far as my like how I
got involved with the game or whatever
you want to call it it goes pretty far
back uh I mean it's a long story I don't
know if you want me to get into it
ramble it away please please I like long
stories like I said I wouldn't even
consider my grow myself a real a real
grower until like the last probably like
I don't know like 10 years or something
like that when I in my early 20s though
I used to hustle man you know little
dope boy whatever makes some extra
dollar here and there [ __ ] back in
Kentucky bro anyways uh you know a let
me let me bring this up a lot of people
they see me see what I'm about they see
I'm talking about Kim dog and I do it
for Kim dog [ __ ] like that they say like
you don't know what Kim dog is like who
the [ __ ] are you like dude you don't
have the D like you don't have the 91
you don't have the cisst you don't [ __ ]
around with that [ __ ] you don't know
anything about Kim well you know you
wanted me come on you wanted me to come
on here and tell the story of how I what
I know about Kim and how far back [ __ ]
but uh tell me about Kem fam Kentucky is
that is that what we're talking about
here yeah well I'm trying to get to it
goddamn it give me a second God damn
well Rambler I always like I said I
dabbled a little bit and like grown but
I wouldn't even consider myself growing
uh I'm a third generation grower bro my
my granddad uh smuggled you know a lot
of like brick weed and [ __ ] up from
Mexico on the back of Harley-Davidson
[ __ ] like that my dad he did a little
bit or whatever but so like I consider
myself a third generation Smuggler if I
G you know anything but anyway through
my connections and [ __ ] hustling back in
Kentucky you know in the streets and and
all that uh I got I made a couple
connections and one of my good buddies
bro uh I ain't gonna say his name let's
just call him Tink Tink Tink my buddy
Tink Tink uh me and him we ran around
you know like if I was ever dry I'd go
to him if I if he was dry cuz in
Kentucky bro you have like these crazy
dry spells back in the [ __ ] day bro
it was nuts like and I ain't trying to
have no real [ __ ] job you know what
I'm saying I'm trying to really live
like that and and just hustle and and
you know [ __ ] around with the girls and
just smoke big Blunts and [ __ ] I know
y'all gonna make fun of my blunts but I
like blunts you know what I'm saying sh
tobacco that tobacco in yeah yeah
anyways uh my buddy Tink tank like I
said we [ __ ] around for years and years
I'm talking like childhood [ __ ] we've
been smoking weed together on know since
like eight nine years old he's the first
guy smok cigarettes with like yeah
first me and We've ran trains on these
girls all kinds of [ __ ] dude but anyway
when you were like 10 right just like
all the time bro throughout high school
[ __ ] like that anyways long story short
to the Kim [ __ ] we've we [ __ ] around
with a lot of plans but the main thing I
wanted to talk about here because I see
a lot of your stories on your little
videos people talking about Kim Kim Fam
where did it come from was it you know
all this stuff and I just wanted to say
my PE my piece you know like I said uh
well anyways Tink Tink he's cool with
ICP If y'all don't know what I'm talking
about Insane Clown yeah jugal life you
know anything about you know you know
about the jugal life bro know a little
bit about the jugal life nice bro uh
anyways uh he's like cool with them or
something or like banging one of the
dudes like sisters or something I don't
[ __ ] really remember bro it's been
like 20 plus years ago but this is 96
right so it's like they're kind ICP he
like been around since like ' 89 but
they they're like kind of underground at
this point kind of blowing up but not
not really like mainstream mainstream
where so they're doing like House
parties and [ __ ] like that in the middle
of nowhere in these [ __ ] fields and
[ __ ] are they still wearing makeup bro
like I'll be honest I didn't even see
them bro like I just showed up for the
Afterparty [ __ ] I I don't like I don't
really [ __ ] listen to that using no
disrespect to them or whatever they're
cool uh but uh anyway so tank Tank's
like bro you got to get down here every
time I say this it's Tallahassee
Tennessee everyone every time I [ __ ]
say this they're like dude don't you
mean Florida like no I actually mean
Tennessee bro there's a bum [ __ ] town
it's like three bilings out in the
middle of nowhere and of course icp's
out there playing a show bro course they
are would they I get there I get lost
bro I don't even get to see the [ __ ]
show right I'm pissed bro and back then
bro I'm I look like I do now so like I
had weed on me but it was like up under
the underneath my truck and [ __ ] so like
I didn't smoke like all the way down
there from Kentucky I'm going out I'm D
it took like [ __ ] six hours to get
there I get lost and [ __ ] missed the
little like house party show and I get
there and you know Tink Tank's been
blowing me up I ain't got no [ __ ]
service [ __ ] like that yeah I get there
though and I randomly start getting Ser
service and he's hit me up like bro you
got to get here the the bud is crazy bro
there's girls with big titties they're
out all this [ __ ] like that yeah yeah I
would imagine Jugo
jug like I said I didn't see them or
whatever they were already gone but the
after party was going on and I I pulled
up finally get there meet with Tink Tink
I start like mingling with the people
and [ __ ] you know they got [ __ ] booze
they got beer weed like hard stuff like
these guys are going crazy bro like
titties out all this [ __ ] dude I'm Pros
had their titties out no the the you
know I don't want to get cancelled
nowadays but let's have their boobs out
bro yeah yeah and I'm [ __ ] I'm like
22 bro like just [ __ ] you know
anyways Tink tin's you know like dude
like you know get you know chill
whatever have a good time stuff so I'm
mingling and stuff because a lot of
these guys like are dealers and [ __ ] and
that's kind of my space because I'm
trying to get in you know you know you
know how it is when you're [ __ ]
around you want you always want to like
have somebody else like another dude
another plug or whatever you want to
call it somebody you can kind of tap
into just in case your people get you
know something happens like I've had
plenty of times where my people have
gone to jail so you need a new like a
new guy or whatever so always trying to
mingle and I'm thinking to myself like
this ICP like it's a ban maybe they got
like some sh back then in Kentucky bro
you couldn't get good it was so hard to
get good smoke so I'm on a mission right
I had good smoke a few times and I'm on
a mission there tracking down so I'm
going all over the place I'm going out
of state doing runs here there whatever
back to my point Tin Tin part in all
that ICP I don't see them don't really
care having a good time mingling with
some girl getting some phone number [ __ ]
like that nothing too crazy anyways you
know when you're at a party bro and
there's like a party in the party and
like when you're you be like you want to
be in there sometimes you don't want to
be in there because there might be like
like straight up dude on D banging I
don't really know it happens some of
these parties the party at the party I I
go in this this [ __ ] Shack basically
it's a glorified Shack basically bro and
these [ __ ] cats are in there smoking
I'm thinking they're smoking some hard
[ __ ] or whatever because it's like that
Vibe waving me in he's like come on in
here bro mous to me like so nobody else
sees whatever I slide in there real
quick I walk in bro it looks like a
[ __ ] a [ __ ] fog machine bro like
is gone off in his [ __ ] room right
and I'm choking up bro cuz like I said
my eyes are watering I'm thinking
there's something [ __ ] foul in here
they're doing something wrong and I'm
like what y'all doing in here bro still
I had these glasses on and I didn't
really realize it because I was [ __ ]
up it real dark in there and [ __ ]
already and like we're getting high bro
like sit down for a second I'm like all
right word so I sit down with these cats
and I'm like you know I'm thinking to
myself like what's so [ __ ] special
about this weed that like nobody else
can be in on it cuz you know they're
like shut the door bro all that dumb
[ __ ] and I'm thinking to myself like I
want the girls to come in here you right
right because it's it's me Tink Tink and
then these three cats I've never met in
my life and they're like you know got
the tray out in the rolling up and dude
I all I know I look at this weed like
it's hitting me like what the [ __ ] is
the smell the weed bro like the
stinkiest like gassiest like foul I
don't even know how to describe it bro
like it's you know 20 years ago it's
hard to even put put it in like I don't
even want to try to like you know put it
in the words but it was some of the best
weed I had ever seen at the time sure
and and um as you know start passing
joints from back and forth and [ __ ] like
that I hit it as soon as I hit I'm dying
bro and me I back then I'm [ __ ] like
borderline crackhead back then so like
for me to cough off a a joint you know I
was like what the [ __ ] I was like is
this is this [ __ ] straight you know what
I mean I'm ask like in this bro I'm
thinking like my got dusted my friend
tin Tink he's wild like these cats are
like real rednecks like out in the
middle of nowhere like with you know
Weaponry stuff and uh he's like dude
there's nothing in it and I'm hitting it
bro and like within five 10 minutes I
just feel this like like buzz come over
me bro like I'm a head buzz like a body
Buzz all that and I'm sitting here like
kind of freaking the [ __ ] out like but I
didn't want them to know right yeah
because I'm new guy guy but you gotta be
cool I gotta be cool dude right I gota
be cool like and uh and Tink Tink on the
way down there he's like dude these cats
are like big [ __ ] bro like dead head
like all that I'm like all right okay
like I didn't really know what that
meant at the time like looking back it
makes sense and [ __ ] but anyways I'm I'm
I'm hitting this [ __ ] and I'm like bro
what the [ __ ] is this and they're like
like Kim dog I said Kim dog they're said
yeah like Kim like chemical dog like Kim
dog I was like what Kim dog what the
[ __ ] what kind of name is that bro I'll
be honest this day like now it's it's it
sounds cool to me but back then I
thought it was kind of lame lame yeah
yeah I could see that and like Tink
tin's like bro this is it you know and
I'm hitting it or whatever getting
[ __ ] up and back then you know name
it's [ __ ] didn't have names back then
bro you know what I mean yeah the fact
that it had a name to us like redneck
boys from Kentucky we're like oh this is
cool you know I didn't like the name but
I was like I was joying enjoying the
weed I was getting high as [ __ ] and uh
you know just having a good time just
dudes though just dudes but at some
point like I'm kind of feeling a little
nauseous and I'm thinking like dude
there's beautiful women here like like
it's cool I appreciate y'all smoking me
out but I already had my weed with me
and all [ __ ] and the tink tank he he
gave me a little nug or whatever and uh
so I go back out to the party and start
kicking with these girls I'm [ __ ] up
for like three or four hours [ __ ] like
that go to bed next day wake up go home
hit tin Tink up like dude what the [ __ ]
did I smoke because I had all kinds of
[ __ ] up on me and like it didn't really
hit me until like the next day like that
was that was [ __ ] that was it bro
yeah dude I hit Tink Tink up like what
the [ __ ] was that and where can I get it
bro and he's like Kim dog and I'm like
yeah dude what the [ __ ] we smoke last
night and he's like you know talking
about like oh you know I can't meet
these guys and they're big deal [ __ ]
like that but yeah he said he said I'll
give you your phone number and he gave
me some [ __ ] fake name or something I
don't know a call and uh back then like
you know on the internet [ __ ] like that
Discord so I call this dude and it's
like real shady awkward conversation
talking about how I need to send him
$500 he gonna give me a zip I'm thinking
myself a zip for500 [ __ ] dollars you
know I'm 2022 bro like [ __ ] Quiznos
and hustling and like to me like like
brick weed like back in the day like 300
350 for me and like I make good money
back then from that and I was like yeah
it's a gamble but I was like I'll hit
him back I told dude I was like I'll hit
you back up and think about it or
whatever and I tried hitting him back up
for like two three [ __ ] weeks this
[ __ ] don't answer his phone bro
I'm think thinking like I done pissed
him off you know how it is yeah sure you
meet a new guy and you're like dude
trying especially when you're young cuz
like these cats were older than me and I
was like you know I don't want to
[ __ ] look like a nerd to these dudes
or whatever you definitely don't want to
look like a nerd right so I I just
played it cool whatever I I but like I
don't like that third week I'm calling
like dude I start calling a couple times
a day where finally this [ __ ]
answers like what I was like it thre me
for Loop because I've called so many
times and he f [ __ ] or something I
was like you know I sound like a little
girl like my voice crack like H it's
me he's like where you who the [ __ ] is
this how'd you get this number and I had
to spend like 30 minutes explaining no
like I've already talked to you you told
me this this price whatever now course
the price jumps up $600 an ounce damn
[ __ ] you know what I'm saying so I was
like let's do it because I at this point
I'm already in I got the dude and I was
like I might not hear from this [ __ ]
dude again and uh he's like I want mail
it to you right send me a money send me
some weird [ __ ] address I send it off
dude it like I'm waiting like three
months I think I just got ripped off
bro my mom three months three
months my mom my mom had just gotten to
divorce thank God because like she W
she's working a lot she wasn't on my
[ __ ] if I was still living with my mom
and dad like my dad would have been on
it seen it but she not talk door one I
was still living with her like hustling
out that the crib or whatever and uh
she's like there's a there's a package
here for some I forget what name I use
or whatever and I was like what it just
hit me like oh oh that's for one of my
friends or whatever and so she get you
know gave me the package and [ __ ] and uh
I go to open it bro and like before I
even open the box I can smell it you
know what I'm saying and my dad [ __ ]
with weed and hustle but like my mom's
like kind of churchy right she don't
know nothing about we so but she's like
what's that you know like as soon as I
got got was [ __ ] with she was like
what's that smell or whatever and I was
just [ __ ] with I'd [ __ ] with people I
was like it's the Kim dog mom you know
[ __ ] with her and she she didn't know
what did she have to say she didn't she
was okay with that well like she's she's
cool as [ __ ] like my mom she's cool I
live with her right now actually she
yeah she's cool but she's kind she
texted me too a few times trying to get
you on the show oh yeah yeah I thought
you were trying to joke on my moms I was
about to say we have problems but no no
she really did I'd have her come up here
bro but she's doing [ __ ] she's kind of
but she's kind of an airhead bro my
point is my mom's an airhead sometimes
and like she bro I was growing one of my
first grows ever not to get off on a
tangent but I was growing like PC grow
like in Little Boxes shoe box grows in
my closet bro when I was like [ __ ] 16
[ __ ] around I know I don't like I
don't consider myself a grower because
I've like I've started to grow so many
[ __ ] times bro and would get to a
point where it's like I'm about to
flower you know and I I be rent in a
house or something and like where I'm at
you get caught with weed bro where I was
at growing up you going to [ __ ] jail
big time so I'd freak out landlord show
up whatever so like I never really
consider myself a grower so I just
that's why I naturally gravitated
gravitated towards like the hustling
aspect of it just trying to make a
dollar or whatever anyways uh back to my
story I send the money off my mom drops
the package off in the room stinking up
the crib and [ __ ] like that like I said
thank God my this is me and my mom
living together time uh
anyways greatest experience in my life
greatest weed same weed that I had at at
the [ __ ] ICP little like party [ __ ]
and ain't no [ __ ] Diddy party either
I know people in the chat probably like
yeah they're [ __ ] around up there no
yeah it was just chill [ __ ] like back in
the day bro you know just two just guys
and girls is some orgy [ __ ] but not like
Diddy [ __ ] but no yeah but so I find a
few seeds in this jar bro like two or
three or whatever and I'm like kind of
dabbling and growing here and there and
I'm thinking like this is [ __ ] the
best weed ever and back then bro like
like some like what was like BC Depot or
something something the Canadian yeah BC
Depot bro that [ __ ] was sketchy bro I
had him knock on my door
before dude yeah any I ordered seeds
from them before from Canada bro and
like the postal people would knock on
the door and [ __ ] and my dad would be
like I use fake names and my dad be like
why the [ __ ] are they like what is what
is this [ __ ] I'd be like I don't know
like so I could never successfully get
seeds to where I was at bro so like in
my mind I'm using bag seeds and I'm like
dude this is the best bag seed I ever
[ __ ] seen in life and so I hit the
dudes back up thinking like man I need
more of this [ __ ] bro so another like
month or two [ __ ] around another
$600 and I get I get another zip and
between these two Zips bro I come out
with like 20 seeds but after I pop them
all I end up with 15 seeds bro and
that's
sometimes the 15 is what I call them Kim
15s whatever the yeah you know each one
yeah I didn't know at the time like CSI
and all I didn't know about like you
know Kim 4 Kim one I didn't know about
that [ __ ] so like looking back now I
feel dumb because like but do they
really matter those other ones that Kim
do they matter when you through 15 I
can't speak speak on them because I a
never grown them in particular but like
what like from what I was what I knew at
that point know there's no internet or
[ __ ] like that and you ain't talking to
nobody about this [ __ ] because like you
gota you know most time you got a
especially where I was at you got a
dudes that you supply to like middleman
[ __ ] right and you're not you're not
like talking about this [ __ ] to nobody
really other than maybe maybe like one
person like but anyway so I get the
seeds I call them 15 or whatever and I
start growing these seeds or whatever
and I'm taking Cuts I just learn I was
on like 420 CH or I was get like all
them I don't know like I'm terrible at
dates but like overgrow and all the [ __ ]
started slowly coming out over the years
so like yeah I learned about like
cloning and like you know propagation
and like how to you know how to keep
genetics alive and the importance of
that and I'm reading on there and then
I'm seeing these cats on there talking
about like Kim and [ __ ] and it freaked
me the [ __ ] out honestly because I ain't
trying to register to like the you know
I didn't want to really register and be
on there like that but I did like to the
self docks yeah yeah and uh so I'm
reading on there like about Kim and Kim
91 and the D and the CIS and like all
this [ __ ] and it's blowing my [ __ ]
mind because I'm like is this the same
[ __ ] that I I got or like what yeah of
course right so I'm sitting there
thinking like what the [ __ ] do I got
right and it kind of like sent me on
this Quest bro to like you know meet up
with cats like y'all and and and try the
different the different cams out and and
over the years of course I've traded
different [ __ ] you know I mean this is
about the Kim we'll get we'll get into
other [ __ ] maybe in another podcast but
you know over the years I traded other
[ __ ] so I end up getting the cist the D
the 91 you know and like I said I got
packs from CSI number one and the four I
ain't [ __ ] popped them yet
but so as I'm going through you know the
year over these you know 10 15 years I'm
like reading this [ __ ] and like kind of
you know just like I said just want to
know what's up so uh I get with a few
cats from the
Discord not too long ago and of course
everything I got legit all the all the
cuts I got were were real deal we
compared you know notes notes and cuts
and tried each other's samples and [ __ ]
like that but the interesting thing dude
is my 1 through
15 they're [ __ ] they're so close to
all you know the different cuts but
they're I would argue that they're A
step above all these because like that
would make sense well even on even on
csi's website bro if you go in there and
read about the 91 s1s and [ __ ] like that
he says Duke make sure you take a cut
because these are gonna probably be
better and can produce better Cuts in
the parents there you go so I'm thinking
maybe the 91 I'm thinking some of these
cats got s1s and or whatever maybe I
don't know because I do got a little bit
of variation in my 15 but they do have
that Kim you know that rotten just
[ __ ] tomatoey rotten flavor I don't
know how to I'm not good at uh
describing sense I I smoke too much
toback and [ __ ] like that but yeah who
cares about chps anyways but that's kind
of you know kind of where we're at you
know I've been wanting to come out
recently because I see a lot of these
guys I'm not gonna mention any names or
whatever but people in the game or in
the industry that maybe have brought Kim
to the Forefront [ __ ] like that they're
on here talking about runs [ __ ] white
runs no disrespect I saw you did your
white runs Matt I'm not ping on you I I
get it you gotta play the game to win
but but what all I'm saying bro is that
I feel like the disrespecting Kim bro my
Kim's [ __ ] I see how come to that
conclusion it ain't even well it's not
even about my Kims bro because I ain't
selling my [ __ ] and ain't none of y'all
getting no [ __ ] Cuts either so don't
be asking me [ __ ] don't be asking him
please but at the end of the day these
guys out here [ __ ] smoking M bags
booty hole runs and [ __ ] like that
acting like it's the bee's knees bro
that it's you remember when when good
weed was green bro yeah yeah used to
be these guys remember when people
talked about like Sour hazes OG types OG
typers typers yeah you can't you can't
even find the OG no more no it's really
hard well people want that now so my
thought is these cats that brought Kim
dog to the Forefront they ain't really
respecting Kim like they should bro and
my thing is I want to start a movement
where we get Kim back in Forefront bro
these guys out here talking about Kim
Auto flowers [ __ ] that you know what I'm
saying yeah that's not respect that
ain't respect no disrespect but you know
what I'm saying like yeah the this
generation coming up right now they need
to know what the [ __ ] is up with Kim bro
it don't matter if it's CIS D
914 whatever bro anyways that's I see
people we wanted to bring this up
because people are always [ __ ] on me
in my in the DMS talking about I don't
know what the [ __ ] what the [ __ ] do I
know about Kim dude and I all I want to
know is what the [ __ ] do y'all know
about him you know right I challenge any
one of them guys get on here and talk
about it they won't yeah any one of them
they won't anyways they're scared I
don't know bro but that's that's really
it I mean if you got questions for me
about it I I'll try to fill you in you
know I'll tell people all the time I
don't know [ __ ] everything bro but I
sure do [ __ ] know a lot like I said I
I joined up with y'all I'm being for
real though I know
yes you are I joined up with y'all
because I want to get better at growing
like I said I you know that's where I'm
here bro and and for the past like
probably I don't know 10 years I've been
like I said I consider myself a grower
but like really these since I've been
out and before I got locked up again I
was really going hard at it bro
but yeah that's that's basically it on
the Kim stuff well you know one of the
one of the most interesting questions I
thought since you were talking about
being a third generation Smuggler
uh we have a guy called sheets on fire
asking uh your first prison smuggle what
what was that experience
like y'all gonna call me whatever but
when you get locked up bro and you're
looking at like losing everything you'll
do some wild ass [ __ ] bro you'll put
[ __ ] in your I mean let's just be real
y'all are y'all are OG's y'all know what
it is i' dude I've loafed straight up
keered loafs of of stuff up my butt bro
I Ain gonna say
what but I've put stuff on my butt many
of times you know being locked up
especially like especially I know I'm
going in there for the weekend
bro I am putting [ __ ] up my ass bro
because I know I could go in there on
the weekend [ __ ] like dude I could
take a half zip in there bro come out
with three grand dude like 10 [ __ ] like
for real bro and they know me in there
bro the guards and [ __ ] are like yo
they're like what is it the January 7th
bro they like invite me in type [ __ ]
like let me do what I want to do bro
it's insane dude but yeah crazy I could
go on in on the weekend dude the [ __ ]
steel riders in the window Warriors in
there love me bro like I'll just say
that let's just say that yeah bet dude
people who don't know what that [ __ ] is
I'm gonna explain it to you real quick a
a [ __ ] window Warrior is somebody
when you go to jail bro and and you're
[ __ ] they they're getting you in and
you walking back to the sale bro and
there's the glass bro some jails you
know how they got the glass right there
in the getting taken back and they're
just pacing back and forth as usually
it's one guy maybe two guys and not
really the biggest cat ever either but
they're just they got their shirt off
and they look [ __ ] deranged and [ __ ]
and they're walking back and forth and
like doing this [ __ ] to their glass and
like sizing you up bro and then when you
see them in the [ __ ] you get in there
with them bro and they get out of a lock
up they get in there with with on the
floor with you and [ __ ] bro they walk up
to you like hey man my name's Steve bro
but like the hardest cat you seen ever
in the window steel Rider is somebody
that don't give a [ __ ] straight up will
sit on a steel toilet in jail you got
steal toilets bro you know because they
don't want you making [ __ ] with whatever
yeah for sure in the sale bro I'm
sharing a one toilet with 40 caps bro a
steel Rider is a guy and I guess a girl
maybe because let's not be be like that
this 2024 bro yeah you're right is there
will sit raw dog on there not even clean
it off like there'll be [ __ ] all over
the rim of the toilet
that that's how you you earn your steel
Rider Wings
bro have you gotten them yeah rer
Status I don't know maybe we shouldn't
go into depth about it but once one time
my my my buy he made some moonshine bro
sorry I'm getting hot as [ __ ] bro my see
that my my buy one time bro he made some
moonshine the dude out of like some
[ __ ] cool and some I don't know
whatever but we got we got lit in there
would you ask bro I'm getting off on a
tangent bro hey it was about your first
prison smuggling I think you covered it
pretty well yeah yeah keer bro keer
every anything and everything because
everything in jail is worth like five
times more bro in ramen noodles I hear
bro if you want to talk about some
smuggling [ __ ] in in in there like most
of us happen like when you go like you
want to be part of like uh work release
bro you know what I'm saying where you
get on the roads bro there's [ __ ]
people that will just drive up to you
bro and be like man y'all are out here
killing it in the heat I'm proud of what
y'all doing you know serving your time
and [ __ ] just hand You Like A fifth
or something bro hand you other [ __ ] too
I ain't gonna bring that up though
because yeah you know priors or whatever
but but yeah the best time is when
you're out there cleaning up that trash
on the highway bro like [ __ ] goes down
bro a cat a cat can get flatio you can
make dude what I said bro you can make a
lot of money in there yeah just even
doing work release huh yeah Work Release
[ __ ] I usually get in a fight though bro
and run that quick you know you start
liquoring yourself up getting out there
in the heat bro it's easy to get pissed
especially you got cats in there that
are [ __ ] detoxing bro you ever been
in the the pin when somebody's coming
off that [ __ ] Bro oh yeah yeah
definitely no not in the pen but I've
definitely been around detoxers I don't
know if I can get my pant leg up bro but
I actually got a [ __ ] I got stabbed bro
can y'all can you see that scar yeah
that he stabbed you in your your shin
bro I tried to kick this dude bro he be
me bro he bit you so it's not stab it's
a bite yeah anyway smuggling bro if you
want to talk about some smuggling real
quick I could get some tips real quick
to keep y'all out of out of in trouble
for I don't know maybe in YouTube land
that might not work so
well we'll get into it maybe on the I
don't want you catching any heat either
that's true I well behind me bro I'm I'm
free and clear I live in a legal State
now bro I do legal [ __ ] okay that's good
to hear yeah anyways I'm my bad
bro first prison cuddle from pumpkin pal
for you yeah bro I I don't know if
that's a nice question or unauthorized
normally I'd [ __ ] fight somebody
asking that [ __ ] bro but this is a
podcast and y'all know y'all like the
juicy details this
is only time I've ever held a [ __ ]
man in jail bro was when my cellmates uh
uh mom died bro uh while he was in there
and that's his [ __ ] baby mama got
killed too and then uh he cried like a
baby I held him and he held
me uh but Yeahs though that's good
friends when you're in there bro that
them [ __ ] are your family bro
you know so it's okay to hold each other
sometimes
I I mean dude I've kissed a guy in jail
bro like that look I swear to God look
dead up better than any girl you see I
can promise you anywhere out where the
[ __ ] you're at dude there are dudes in
there are on another level you could get
anything in there bro you want it's just
like on the street you just gotta pay
for it bro just gotta pay for it you
gotta come in with the big money bigone
jams um someone asked the first time you
had to knock a grow I don't know what
that's about knock a grow like finish
what's that mean knock knock a grow over
I think like like like get rid of it no
take someone's stuff I
believe uh well my mom I guess well let
me think about that because because you
know how dude in small towns you think
like people always I dude I used to get
into to with people they think like oh
you know you ain't from the shitty fool
like there ain't nothing you ain't you
don't know what that life's about really
but like where I grew up bro like you
had like Crews just like you got out
there but it's like way more personal or
personal because like you went to school
with these guys like every one of them
right you know all of them you know all
the dudes or whatever yeah so like it
it's sketch bro and like like out there
bro a lot of times you're meeting these
guys in like back roads like nobody
around you know pretty easy you know
what I'm saying like anyways back to
grows off I didn't really do a lot of
that cuz bro that's not really my style
like a lot of times I just hustled for
what I what I needed and did it the best
like the right way I could do for
hustling but like my my I will say the
one I could share I guess is my stepdad
well he was my stepdad my mom's
boyfriend for a while this dude I ain't
gonna say his name or whatever but he
kind of [ __ ] around or whatever and
was like growing weed back behind my
mom's like duplex or whatever and I
didn't know anything so this is kind of
dumb for me to even steal it really cuz
like it died like right away bro but he
had like some plants out there and me
and my homies he's a dick or whatever
like kind of like an [ __ ] to my mom
so I stole we stole his plants but like
I said they died bro like died so it was
dumb I don't
know
oh I was just gonna say uh you know when
I was in high school bro me and the me
and my buddies we growing next to the
railroad tracks a little bit I don't
even take credit for it because I mean I
just would be there smoking weed or
whatever but uh these other guys that
were kind of cool with us like end up
stealing our plants because this dude in
our group kind of like ratted out our
spot and uh they took like our plants
and then they started growing and then
like we found out where their spot was
and then we went and took their [ __ ] you
know kind of that's about it really bro
I didn't really steal I was I'm not a
stealer bro I'm not into all that really
you know yeah you you don't really look
like a thief I would say you look like
more like an upstanding citizen no my my
my dad and my granddad always told me
though like one thing you don't [ __ ]
do is steal you know steal people's [ __ ]
bro because it might come around on you
and man dealing with people with
addictions bro like you know I've had a
lot of my stuff stolen a lot and yeah
man I work hard bro you know I I hustle
and [ __ ] but I've had jobs and [ __ ] too
bro like you mention Quiznos bro I've
mowed grass for a living for years I
[ __ ] I've I've modeled a little bit
at a time I can see that you're doing it
right now looking good I'm trying to get
these sponsors to hook me the [ __ ] up
man like yeah dude but they for weed you
know I see these guys trying to make it
come up off the weed game all the time
I'm saying thinking like dude I need my
piece too bro like I did my [ __ ] I did
my time like what the [ __ ] right right
you know you mentioned that in the texts
as did your your uh relative who kept
texting me blowing me up to have you on
the show bro I appreciate you you
finally giving me the nod like like
really I I thought you were bullshitting
me I I kept telling the mom like Matt is
coming through bro bro just like that
answer the Kim back in the day like I
got impatient you know I got a problem
bro you do you have a little problem
with the the patience I got AC or what
ACDC or whatever it's
called [ __ ] like that but yeah bro but
that's my Kim story bro uh and smuggling
as far as smuggling I've done a lot of
smuggling you know U yeah we'll keep it
at
that all right well if since we're live
if anybody has any questions from the
audience for Chucky get it in there
right there um ask away and U I'll keep
my eye on that you got any of the
Discord questions
loaded Logan my name ain't Logan
chucking Paulin bro my real name ain't
Logan get it right let's see here it's
not I don't want to say your real name
on the that's all good uh so we got a
question from scrw scrw what's he want
he's got three questions all right first
question is can I touch your butth hole
I'm guessing he's talking to you bro I
think he's talking to you that was this
was actually for you the only time
another man ever touched my ass when
he's helping me ke something right
before going in bro yeah going in on
accident and you got that one friend you
can call
that will help you because he's been
through the same [ __ ] you know what I'm
saying yeah that one one guy he says
have you had have you had any
experiences harvesting something earlier
than
usual I'll go first ahead yeah lots of
times bro when you're making seeds
especially uh you know some people like
to take their clones you know but some
people like to start with a seed grow it
out clone
it you know and and work from that uh I
like to do it a little different I like
to I'll take a plant the seed
plant and I'll grow it out and instead
of taking clones immediately and just
scrapping the mom plant I I kind of want
to see what the mom's going to do just
what the buds GNA be like what she's you
know what she's about and then I'll I'll
go ahead and take that when you're
working with RS especially I'll take
that opportunity to go ahead since I got
the mail usually right there I'll go
ahead and use that opportunity to hit
hit them with something so I get some
kind of seed out of it so now I'm not
only I going to have clones but I'm
going to have uh you know seeds of stuff
too so um as far as you know taking
stuff early for sure if you're doing a
seed run sometimes and when you're
making uh seed for yourself especially
when you ain't selling seed and you only
want so many if you do it early enough
and you don't the bud maybe the bud
isn't what you want it to be or maybe
whatever you know you can run in
problems pest maybe even or even you're
outside and you you don't want to run
into certain weather conditions I mean
there's a times where you do it but
mainly for me like I've taken [ __ ] when
I just want to get the seeds I I I check
to see if I got enough mature seeds that
I want and I'll go ahead and take it and
just have my clones going or a r or
whatever but yeah I mean there's times
you could do that for sure I don't know
what about you Matt I mean you you
pretty much covered it I'm just watching
your your blunt rolling skills here and
seeing if you really I could roll a
blunt in about 26 seconds but but this
[ __ ] weed I got right now uh is kind
of like real fluffy like Haz likee you
know and it and it uh I'm trying to pack
it thicker than I probably need to fam
but what was that first thing you smoked
out of was that was that food that you
this fam bro I was about to munch on
this [ __ ] sandwich
dude my mom got me some sandwiches and
[ __ ] but then I got to I was about to
hit that and I was thinking like damn
like maybe I shouldn't eat on the
podcast or whatever my mom treat me good
dude my momat oh my God like what the
[ __ ] what kind of is that a bagel
sandwich what is that egg bagel it's a a
steak uh grinder or what do you call
them bro up here in Michigan bro they
make the subs up here bro I don't know
what they call them I'm from Kentucky
bro I'm red I don't know what the [ __ ]
this [ __ ] is I know I know a website
called grinder I think I Subs Grinders
all kinds of sexual [ __ ] no it's a
that's a sub bro that like Grill it's
got steak and cheese and peppers [ __ ]
like that sounds delicious dude it's
fire how do you that that that figure
eating stuff like that bro it's from
[ __ ] working on these plants all
goddamn day bro I don't work out on
nothing at all bro but I'm I'm pretty
I'm do in the pen like you don't get
your sets in I did in the pen but now
like I got so much [ __ ] going on it's
hard bro trying to make a dollar bro
like that's the main focus like working
out is one thing but making a dollar but
let's jump back to the question yeah go
Chan says besides blue stuff what
hybrids are you most excit excited about
looking through and
why I don't know if that's me or you I
think it's probably you but I think you
like blue too I think you are a blue
Champion I got blue bro I actually got a
I got a few jars of blue a couple jars
of blue on me uh I got the blueberry ex
I got three of them on me I was gonna
pull out at some point if we had time
nice I should have rolled that in here I
didn't thinking about it didn't think
about it you that [ __ ] seated though I
did SE it with the males the so it's
like you know I
got but uh but uh for the answer his
question besides the blue stuff what
hybrids are you most excited about
looking through and why so I mean for
blue I mean he said besides blue stuff
but blue stuff the blue resent I think
is probably my next thing or maybe the
uh was it Blue Sour yeah stuff just
because like I do like uh I do like that
blue flavor man like the like the but I
want something a little bit more potency
I will say U my particular Expressions I
got I like them the flavor is great on
the ex but I think like I did hit that's
why I hit them because I figur I would
have to hunt them a little bit and also
like I did get some really nice color
but not the color I wanted so like yeah
I made enough seed to like hunt through
them you know what I mean but um most
hybrid's most excited for bro I did I
mean I just cut down my Rank Stranger
from H&amp;L high and
Lonesome I had two of them outside bro
and somebody said it is it Gojo or Mojo
the orange hand uh hand cleaner stuff
that's kind of gritty that mechanics use
it's not real orange smelling but it
does have that orange Citrus kind of
smell to it but one of the plants one of
the rank Changers got that like
chemically like uh like orange kind of
like hand soapy kind of smell bro not
soap so much but that I think it's Gojo
is what they say somebody in disc but
I'm excited about smoking as far as
growing [ __ ] bro um I'm growing a lot of
lot of stuff from the guys from the
Discord I mean I'm excited about
everything I'm growing dude I only grow
[ __ ] I'm excited about you know I mean
I'm not why would you waste time doing
anything else yeah like what the [ __ ]
yeah I mean I'm excited about it all bro
I mean yeah I mean I don't know if I
anyways we can jump to some next
questions I'm let's do next question
list list a bunch of [ __ ] off but uh if
you could go back to one line you made
and start a new project from it what
would it be from
Sean I'd probably do the
the strawberry cream stuff again which
isn't which is still Berry
because I guess I guess that's where I
reside did you like I know you've talked
about a little bit here and there but
from years of doing doing drugs bro my
memory is terrible when when what what
is that name just the name to get people
to to to buy or does it does does it
have like a strawberry cream super super
super strawberry super um cvf got it um
I think it was a a Strawberry Cough S1
from a lady named golden eyes I think it
was that you know it's the internet you
don't really know but um golden eyes uh
was on the forums back in the day and
she did some strawberry cough
s1s that had males um so yeah that's
where it came from but it did it did
carry a much stronger uh
strawberry expression than even
strawberry cough and flavor was there
yeah have you i' probably go back and do
that that's cool bro uh have you have
you the M question from me have you
messed with csas uh s1's of of the cough
no but it would probably be a good
almost a better place to look because it
would be more pure like I think that the
golden light stuff was probably a pollen
contamination with all the males in it
word okay yeah I think I picked some of
them up or a pack of it up I missed that
one when I locked up bro for a while
yeah that happens just hopefully mom
grabbed you some yeah yeah Mom she don't
really you say Mom yeah your mom
hopefully she grab you some she don't
smoke really that much but she will go
buy seeds for me I ually use her money A
lot of times you know because especially
when I first got out you know gotta help
a gone take EBT right now for is it
seeds does anybody take EBT for seeds
bro I wish
man oh I do got a uvt card but I don't
even use it bro because I'm like my ego
and [ __ ] because like I can't just like
accept that you know what I'm saying
like I I'll [ __ ] hustle my [ __ ] up
bro you know I mean I hustled you on the
show so like we're here bro right now um
you did so let's jump into some more
questions I guess yeah go ahead uh dogs
and trees says what was the line
cultivar that made you decide to go all
in on breeding I'd imagine the the
Bonnet stuff but maybe it started before
that oh yeah know it was um Hogs breath
Hogs breath the old San Diego Hogs
breath that's where I started really
learning about breeding breeding
um yeah Clockwork Wars is the fem the
best fem stuff that was when really
really tried to nail down a line but the
Hogs breast stuff from from
Jimbo that's awesome it's cool hell yeah
dude what what's the Hogs breath life
like bro like the turs the like can you
talk anywhere from cheesy I've seen
fruity expressions in the s1s um foot
Funk
just it's hard to explain but like even
how Shoreline can go through those
[ __ ] different I don't know trying to
reference another old rare clone is kind
of hard for most I think I know what
you're talking about though like that
kind of like it does some of the [ __ ]
I've been [ __ ] with recently got this
almost like
um a fermented oceany like smell bro
that's like a I don't know uh the Irene
s1's from CSI I just did uh I only had
three to make it I mean the packs for
like 300 [ __ ] dollars so I only got
one pack but uh I I I had one that came
out like that bro
uh I I would pull it up here but we get
like [ __ ] YouTube strikes us every
time we show any kind of weed weed
plants but yeah I'm actually got got
clones of them and uh anyway my point
was it had that like funky like only
thing that I can maybe you know maybe
that's what it is basically
yeah it's um sweet funky the actual
clone that was foot funky cheesy foot
funky okay but not like cheese the Clone
gotcha okay yeah it was own little
unique indicia thing do you do you still
have any of the the work that you did uh
with that the last stuff I had I gave to
Bitter and he has it was the master Hogs
coach it was SoCal master um which is
like a Bubba norn lights type um uh OG
Kush and Hogs breath that's cool [ __ ]
yeah shout out bidder OG B bitter bro
he's a real one salute him
you know uh I
think you know I can't really comment on
that but I think one of the first packs
that I popped bro was from
CSI that made me like want to dive deep
in into just learning more about weed
bro you know I think I don't know man
yeah I was just sitting there thinking
about that from not really a Breeder's
perspective but just wanted to know more
about the plan so I popped uh I think it
was like Girl Scout cookies Cali
o something else that had gotten in a
trade that was CSI stuff bro and when I
popped them you know I've been [ __ ]
with Autos a lot at that point and when
I popped them I was like damn dude like
these are cool and uh I just remember
the Girl Scout cookies were cool because
I grew them like four or five of them in
a small like two by two with like a 100
watt light bro and there was like from
of the densest like it grew so well in
there under that low light it just
worked great dude and made me kind of be
like damn this shit's cool bro but you
like the cookies huh you're a cookies
fan well at the time you know when
you're talking about Autos when you
[ __ ] with mainly like Autos uh and
Kim's the only other thing I got I've
had really that I I've been you know
kept this long so it's like I love Kim
but I over the years I've tried stuff
you know because you know how it is bro
before the internet and Discord I get
ConEd into buying all kinds of [ __ ] bro
I like these cats out here telling me
like this is the new [ __ ] this is better
than than Kim and all [ __ ] I try try
this [ __ ] I don't get high bro anymore I
go to the dis I went to the these
[ __ ] dis dispos or whatever up here
bro and they're talking about like the
dude you know what I mean dude out front
like bro you trying to get a free join
joint on it of the run and I try it I'm
not gonna lie I smoke bunk bro you know
[ __ ] we all do but yeah I mean just
[ __ ] ain't nothing like good Kim or
OG
sour hazy type [ __ ] like you know I'm
still learning but
anyways what else we got well y'all got
remember I locked up a lot of [ __ ] so
when I get out some cat might say like
yo this is fire I try and this anyways
so we got cranky Dany says if you could
travel back in time for one year what
year in in time for one year what year
are you choosing where are you going and
what are you bringing back with you who
bring back I was thinking about
traveling to
to to I don't know um bringing back I
bring back real blueberry now and but I
I'd probably go to Humble
1978 or or even the the Pacific
Northwest 1978 to see the early uh
Afghani infestation see what that sh
like I'd probably go back to when Rob
Clark I hung out with Rob Clark oh yeah
are you guys
y good friend yep good friend shared a
fishing trip together dear friend that's
true this is true yes
he my point is I love to go back and
meet him when he was my age back then or
you know what I mean like a 20 year old
dude yeah be cool just hang out with
them smoke some go back and see the
early Pearl that'd be nice yeah
col yeah all that Stu be cool bro yeah
be fun my bad I forget this is you
usually thousands job y'all yeah I know
he's asking me qu this is supposed to be
about you but yeah yeah well you know
anyways we we'll making it work H we got
a question for you from uh I can never
digid Dobe or whatever I can never say a
[ __ ] right uh have you started smoking
again yes yes I have very slowly very
slowly trying to
reint um uh someone sent some of the um
I think we called it Swampy blue in the
end which is the the white cross to Blue
Monet and then some of the blue and
cross too hell yeah slow starting slow
making sure I can because I had a few I
had a few close calls at the beginning
where I was like I'm not sure man I'm
starting to get sick and pukey so well
yeah it's okay again it's okay again I
just might have been nervous I'm I'm
glad you back amongst the smoking uh
peoples you know
yes but yeah um so we got
uh am I you know I you know your boy's
always smoking I'm smoking
always we got another one from dogs and
trees that says which settings for age
location preferences Etc should I put my
grinder on for the best chance in
matching with Matt
guys you I mean I settings for the
grinder
I don't know like the website you got
you got Matt the blueberry [ __ ] King
on here right now you're talking about
[ __ ] grinder bro grinder what is
grinder anyway that's my bro you don't
want to know bro don't want to know I
haven't heard of this site this is
maybe
connections maybe I'm on it I don't know
maybe I don't know see anyways we got
one from Bittersweet the OG
King all in timing in regular breeding
difference in like short flowering and
long flowering on how it affects seed
production that's a great question it's
a great question so um you know like
usually like in my brain I put it
between 10 to 14 weeks or actually 8 to
10 sometimes seven which is rare as [ __ ]
the 7 to 10 and then 10 to 14 and then
you got 14 to 22 kind of um you like
Ping to hit usually usually at four
weeks for the for the Afghani dominant
type which is almost everything we'll
see you know unless people are going to
smoking like Haze hybrids like real Haze
hybrids uh 10 to 14 are some of the more
hazy hybrids like we're talking about
like um like even the mango Haze stuff
the the electric buo mango haze from
High lome stuff like that H seven six
range and then longer than that dude you
can hit it 10 11 12 cuz that shit'll
just flower forever once it goes longer
than that you know I thought this was a
good question from from what I had for
H&amp;L and maybe you can speak on it too
but you know something I didn't realize
was you know or it's not even the
question I guess it's more something you
could speak on but I didn't realize that
if you're growing outside and you get
Maybe by accident or on purpose you get
seated Bud that you know that can cause
like Bud rod and [ __ ] man like oh yeah I
didn't even like because you know you
think like this is a natural process
like kind of in a maybe not natural but
you know but yeah I never I never knew
that that that was a thing and I talked
to H&amp;L about it and he's like sure yeah
dude like you could get Bud rot or rot
from just the seed in there or like you
said before the [ __ ] seed will grow
up out of there sometimes or
whatever looks like alien Bud bro when
it has a bunch of uh the tap Roots
flying out all over the Bud white yeah
yeah I've never seen that but that's
that is wild dude yeah it's weird
looking yeah as far as you know uh Auto
pollen maybe people care about that
we'll speak on some Auto [ __ ] this
podcast dude your boy you're the auto
king you know at one time but as far as
Autos I mean dude some of the male
especially like your more like you were
saying the more indicate types I guess
you call them or dominant varieties yeah
shorter shorter types or shorter flower
and period Autos if that makes any sense
uh uh there I mean dude males are
dropping anywhere from like day 21 to
like like I'm like serious I've had [ __ ]
yeah like real fast dude we week three
to week four uh and then you know your
females they usually can take around
there too like maybe a little bit like
week four for sure but I mean and then
they're they're just like your normal
plans as far as the time it takes to
mature for the most part right I mean
they yeah you just let them run as long
as they need to weeks yeah yeah long to
and I do what you taught me to do bro uh
you know you've always told me growing
up back in the day bro don't check the
top bu check the bottom ones bro because
you know if the bottom ones you if
they're mature the rest of the plants
probably yep top one's always first and
there's inner knuckle elbow ones I think
they called primordial seeds yeah those
are always done first so they're tricky
you see those come out you're like oh
nice and brown nice and you know sturdy
and then the rest could be all immature
yeah something I thought was kind of
interesting bro and you know what none
of your audience probably us a [ __ ]
about this but I thought it was cool I
had some Autos bro that I that uh Chuck
some pollen on right and I Chuck some
your blueberry onto a blueberry Auto
right nice and what would you say the
primordial [ __ ] like the the pre I hit
those with the auto pollen right yes
sounds crazy because guys in the chat G
contamination contamination but I got
the answer for you fu
all right go here let's hear it when you
you could do some cool [ __ ] like that
though because you
take like I said you hit the Autos or
you could do it I did it both with both
let me let me let me simplify this so if
you got an auto blueberry you got the
and thex blueberry right you could take
you could do it either way but I took
the male blueberry ex and hit it to the
female primordials right yeah so every
one of them which she ended up being
like $50 100 yeah is a hybrid of that
and then I hit the uh rest of the top of
the buds with the a male blueberry Auto
right yeah and it's just as simple as
like I'm not selling seeds so
contamination [ __ ] don't matter so much
so what I when I'm popping them at the
end of the day I'm just popping you know
if they start flowing early as [ __ ] I
know they the auto yeah that's true
right it's and I'm doubling up on two
have you ever done anything like that
probably not because I know y'all not
not with blueberry to to Blueberry Autos
but it's because that's actually two
different U traits you're working at the
same time breeding for blue and breeding
for
autoflowering it's uh two observable
traits so it's not it's not super
complex but it's also pretty cool I I I
even think that's a good idea to do and
you can tell which ones are pure and
which ones aren't just based on how they
flower you know something I appreciate
about you dude and working with the RS
and stuff especially man is like you got
around all the time I see Cats though
cut them down soon as they start seeing
and like for me bro like it's so easy to
just to separate a male for you know if
you got this space right some got this
space but if you can separate a male and
just do some brushing bro like why not
dude why not get some seeds out of that
[ __ ] dude you know you know I tried
keeping the Bonnet mail for uh years and
I actually gave it away to radio Ridge
so they can pass it to other breeders
that want it to work with but um I don't
know that they ever did that's the thing
bro you keep Cuts Like It's good to keep
a cut bro as soon as you [ __ ] get
locked up and your homies like got an
infestation or something bro your shit's
gone that's good to have a seed of some
kind maybe you don't get that particular
expression back the way you want it but
at least you got a jumping off point but
my badget we got question for you does
Chucky have bottoms
on
fam who bro you better watch out bro I
SW out here fam
what are you like 610 I'm [ __ ] big
[ __ ] bro you are a big
[ __ ] that's right but uh so we
got you have nails around you all the
time from uh the dawn Don is on I've
been to the DA's MAA parties he should
be well he's well aware of having males
you know he's a good guy I like d d is
bad right he's the [ __ ] man dude
don't ever you know if it wasn't for D I
wouldn't be here right now
you know what if it wasn't for D the
Marines wouldn't say simpy fact hey de's
bailed me out of
jail D gave me advice when I needed when
I got divorced yeah taught me how to be
a better father yeah how to be a better
grower how to respect people better you
know what I'm saying because you know
hustling the game can can [ __ ] turn
you embrace it bro make you I don't know
bro turn you into a hard ass
[ __ ]
anyway I think H Lon had a question for
you too if I remember make sure we get
that in find I find it in the Discord
it's somewhere in there I [ __ ] get
lost I'm going
through yeah here it is here it is has
Chucky ever grown an auto that Stacks up
to Top Shelf traditional flower see this
is a tricky question 100% transparency I
[ __ ] around give yall jokes all the time
but I say it like this bro if you take a
pack of RS of like traditional rag pack
right or F whatever like most of the
time I don't know if you can speak on
this but when you pop a pack of anything
really there's always going to be a
plant in there or two maybe for the most
part unless you're cookie fan you get
everything's a [ __ ] winner dude every
time every time but in a pack bro you're
gonna find a plan or two in there that's
not the greatest right yeah I look at
Autos like this in a pack of Autos if
you pop the same
amount sometimes you got pop a few more
than like you would a normal pack I'll
be for real but you will find the best
auto in there will be close comparable
to maybe the worst plant you find in a
traditional pack do you see what I'm
saying yeah I see what you're saying I
see what you're saying and I also will
say this you know they are definitely
comparable to like cookie stuff bro like
or wreck weed you know I've for sure now
you are you going to get weed that
you're you're he the most headiest weed
that like you know some like H&amp;L or
whatever is going to be like this is it
bro probably not because that's there's
not enough work in them they need people
like H&amp;L and people like that to work
them further you know just he should
start an auto company is what he needs
to do next bro yeah he he could speak on
that yeah yeah he uh but but yeah I mean
your worst your best auto is gonna be
like your worst plant you probably you
know what I mean but I this like I get
surprised all the time by them bro when
I when I did [ __ ] with them I I would
get surprised on a regular basis with
them you know anyway oh [ __ ] we're
dropping the weed bro anyway dropping
the weed that's party P let's hit some
more of these questions nothing about me
uh if you have the option S1 F1 BX which
and Y pros and cons why regard or with
regarding with regards to breeding so
maybe I could speak on this a speak on
it preach so BX and s1's is when you
want to lock something in right yes f1's
when you want to move forward mostly yes
correct I mean that's all I got really I
know learn I mean that's that's yeah um
I'd say s1's for making the money seeing
recessive
bx1 for making better money than f1s and
then f1s if you want to kill your
company GRE yeah so there you go Autos
if you want to make a bag bro yeah if
you want to make your money back autos
on all the new
Growers there you
go yeah I mean basically here you go
here's a good
question Chucky what do you think of
Kentucky going medically legal I mean
it's like anywhere right like you're
still looking at years of probably
waiting around and them [ __ ] you
around for you know whatever I mean I
think it's great dude because like it is
I think it's 21 or 22 illnesses or or U
I'm not good at this kind of
conversation or you know talking about
medical Pro long as for sure like if you
got cancer terminal illnesses things
like that uh you know you can be on this
list I think it's kind of silly though
last time I checked you had to have a
care you or your care provider has to
drive out State and can bring back up to
eight ounces legally you gota have you
know all your proof of everything so
like it's it's like what you know these
people are like dying and [ __ ] and you
know they need it now and not tomorrow
or in a week or and you're literally
just driving over from what I understand
and maybe I'm wrong in this guys but
from what I read that it's literally
you're just driving to I guess a medical
facility and just picking up and it's
literally driving back so it's like why
can't we have some medical system to
[ __ ] to it people are buying th seaweed
or whatever be [ __ ] like bro I mean it's
a joke bro but I I think it's great but
for me and what I came from in my
background it didn't really you know I
mean it's not really any affecting like
what I did or would have affected what I
did at the time I don't think all right
Let's do let's do one more question and
we can save the rest for the next one y
That's cool all right if we bring you
back I don't know we'll see we'll see
see how your mom does with uh bugging us
well let's see what we got a good one in
here first uh maybe while we're we
looking for a good question do you got
any cool projects coming up do you got
what you I know you're doing this big
overhaul and doing a make going
different
direction a big overhaul yeah you know
but maybe you can speak on that a little
bit any plans any drops coming up um so
we have we have some seeds that Miss
Joel just sent in we got we got the the
space queen stuff from her there's some
pretty cool stuff in there um
what else we got coming in I don't know
I mean we still have the blue and cross
stuff um there the sale is still going
on right now so go check it out um when
I get un lazyy and get back to doing the
site stuff instead of clean up my house
um maybe I'll put it back up to the
normal price but I haven't really
remembered yet um what else do we got
yeah um I don't know I'm gonna have to
do some fem work next because I mean for
years people Associated me with fem
stuff and then I started doing regular
stuff
and nobody wants regular stuff so back
to Fem stuff you know um I don't know if
I'm going to do blue fem stuff because
like really I'm just burning it to the
ground with blue but um [ __ ] I don't
know I think you should get risky man
you should try some stuff I'll be honest
I've tried some some Modern stuff that's
all right I mean you could if you find
the right you know the right stuff you
could do something cool you know I don't
know bro maybe me there's some good
stuff I mean I just don't like the taste
of a lot of cookies and like sherb stuff
but like the sherb cream pie stuff that
that spindle had was really good so we
used that and some stuff
and yeah like I don't know I'm
particular maybe maybe back to
Strawberry I don't know need to do F
stuff though whatever you're doing I'm
for it bro I mean people want if you
want a chance to get in on some of
Matt's new drops coming up his new work
or some of his old stuff and you want to
save a dollar or two join the Discord
there's a $50 TI in there for all you
guys and gals out there that want to
save some money every two to three
months Matt takes that monthly payment
and does a big bundle and sends it out
where you get a lot of his new stuff can
Illuminati drops from Pac H&amp;L a bunch of
a bunch of other guys in the Discord and
it also if you want to go check out Gert
by seeds if you're in Australia you can
check out uh what is it Riot seeds in
Europe rco Europe yes gold cut gold cut
he's GNA have some um uh uh some of uh
pack um goat farm and high and Loan some
stuff too soon out Europe and great by
seeds is getting some more of the blue
and cross stuff too yeah don't forget
lftd seeds if if Matt's may be sold out
yeah he carries a lot of other stuff too
so yes please check him out he's good
lftd genetics or lftd I always get it
wrong I think I think he even made
another account because I kept screwing
it up he's like I
that I mean and if you're interested and
any of the stuff that hnl or poac and
them were working on man they got them
in the Discord bro they're always
talking about stuff and and you know if
you want to get in on that early that's
the place to be bro yeah I think even
bitter made some um Strawberry Cough uh
blue incross stuff or maybe it's blue
bonnet I don't remember blue incross so
yeah so that's going to be available in
the Discord somehow someway we'll figure
it out y y I always forget about konzo
tooon in there yeah go check him out
it's I think what is it a pick a
lick.com I always get it get it wrong
bro I don't know I'm bro I don't even
know how to F I barely got on here with
you and this podcast I it took a while I
don't know how to I don't know how to
spell I was on Hooked on Phonics didn't
complete it you should be ashamed that
your mother had to come do the
connection for you though and click link
it's not that hard hold on one second
she's yelling for me right now just
pizza Rose
[ __ ] damn little Goos [ __ ] BB anyway all
right last question guys yeah yeah let's
pick one here real quick
um we've already answered the goals uh
let's see [ __ ] or Dino Gro I can't
whatever [ __ ] man where to find info on
certain strains I'm growing some Sub sub
Rob and some Matt Elite I'm not finding
any info besides your YouTube videos
from the 420 promo I didn't see anything
in the Codex either thanks yeah so the
Codex is all the old strains and it's
like a list of that so like we're not
even putting my stuff in there um that's
just for old clones and I haven't worked
on it in a while and I really need to
because it was built for that purpose
and it's amazing for it um as far as the
the Discord you can there's a search
function you can type in subro and
there's a lot to talk about it there or
mad Elite same kind of thing both I mean
sub Rob isn't that underground you can
also hit him up um uh C trip Rob cpor
Rob I think or maybe it's just C trip
Rob on Instagram hit him up um Matt
Elite you can't hit him up he's a hidden
man um he's a kept man but uh yeah no he
has some of the best chem work that's
ever been done and I could speak on both
of them real quick if you want go ahead
pleas growing them right now I guess and
uh so the for for for yeah Matt's right
robs is a great guy
he he's not on like this oh I'm a
breeder [ __ ] if you have questions
talk to him he's in the Discord he's on
Instagram I'll talk to him on both on a
pretty regular basis uh he's a great guy
he'll get anything you need to know um
as far as uh skank dog in particular uh
that thing is [ __ ] amazing bro if I
was a breeder I ain't even like
bullshitting if I was a breeder one of
the Expressions I found out of one pack
like dude I'm hitting this to everything
bro or hitting stuff to hit whatever
it's I can't describe it because it I
would the best way I can describe it is
a runchy rancid used coffee ground smell
that's got a skunk maybe a little skunk
to it little tiny bit of mint and it's
just kind of like this sharpness to it
and maybe that's the you know the sour
coming through this the skunk all I
don't know bro I you know it's been
years since I've smoked some of the that
kind of [ __ ] so it's like hard to really
wrap my brain around it but and they all
kind of exhibited exhibited those
uh flavors out of the Packa pop uh the
structure is where they varied um and
the ease of grow I would say the one
that I had is super dense some of the
you've seen some of the pictures maybe
the beautiful nugs uh beautiful like
under 100 let me let me put it this way
I grew it under 100 watt light for about
basically its whole life until about
last four weeks of its life and I put it
under a big dog big light but great
plants and even the ones after I I I ran
out of that I got a little bitty bit and
I'm sending some samples off or giving
some samples away uh but I want to crack
those open and smoke the rest of it
because I like it so much but yeah bet
the uh and I can't speak on the SSH or
whatever sssd yeah he Rob's been talking
about me with that one a little bit but
I I ain't grown that one but uh and then
the other one what was the other one he
was talking asking about the uh it was a
SK do oh thead Elite so the mat Elite
you probably not going to find a lot of
conversation on it in the Discord
because it was such a limited drop that
prior to that it was it was like seven
eight years nine it was a long time ago
yeah when when it was all made a limited
drop so there could be very well most
the people that bought it weren't even
in the Discord for starters yeah I'm not
sure was a thing shout out herbs SD and
a couple other people I think are I know
herbs is is either finished or run of I
think the resurrections the Kim Kim one
the kimd one yeah um I'm not sure I know
me personally I got uh the both the
Resurrection the mobile one and the Kim
D going I lost the majority of my uh Kim
uh the Kim ones they dampened off a
little bit I it was my fault I think you
know I [ __ ] around High [ __ ] around
with this chick big titties but that I'm
growing them right now and they're
looking killer dude I haven't smoked
those yet to that one but yeah I mean
it's you're not going to find info on
them bro because honestly there's not a
lot of people to got hit me up in the
Discord I'll I'll answer anything about
it there yeah smoked a lot of it grown
some of it yeah yep yeah bro well all
right well [ __ ] it did you do you think
you'll get a mod modeling contract out
of this is it possible I'm [ __ ]
hoping somebody sh like lets me like
sees my passion bro I got so much
passion bro he's got passion unleash me
on these guys bro I'm [ __ ] coming for
everybody dude I don't need y'all's
godamn this year year next year now next
year now whatever bro yeah you know I
don't need your [ __ ] Cuts I don't
need your money just support us bro let
us give us what we need to take over the
game me and Matt and crew everybody else
thousand F shout out everybody we're
about to change the game the landscape
it's going to another level bro sponsors
Galore it could be it could be sandals
Crocs dildos shirts dildos whatever you
got glass makers who now make dild
shout out spindle bro we don't have yeah
shout out spindle That's my boy yeah all
right all right man I
appreciate pleasure yep all right until
next time hopefully next week I think we
should be next week we'll see how see
how it goes yep all right peace Brother
later want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out