welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey into finding my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies we are the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smok and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis underground this
is the
revolution welcome to breeder Syndicate
I'm Matthew here with my co-host
thousandfold and today we have local and
farmer Dan with us thousand let's hear
about the show and this is our season
finale yep so we finally get to our
Skittles episode and we have Dan and
locco both because they have had an
interest perhaps different angles of
interest uh into the Skittles green sh
keine pie question um both have some
experience uh either with the cut uh and
or with the uh
s1s of either the Sher or the Skittles
uh Dan has worked with it commercially
if I'm not mistaken Dan in some
degree yeah pretty
extensively yeah okay and also we
initially plan to do this with uh CSI
but he's been too busy so we have his
Blessing and also a little
representation of him right
there there he is right there there he
is just about how
the so a little bit about how the
episode is going to be structured the
first half is really just us unpacking
um what uh we all know and have observed
and not me so much as these three uh
whether in the cut itself or the
s1s um and then the second half of it is
going to be about hypothetical breeding
projects we won't be going into origin
stories per se uh as we have for
other clones so we're not going to be
talking about like the people deci side
like who did what when I think that's
less the priority today that's just a
cluster anyway so yeah yeah I think we
want to stay away from that and you know
to be honest I've always been keen on
and Matt I know has always been keen on
this side of things where you actually
work to find out what's happening yeah
traits yeah so without further Ado we
can step in I think to talking about
some of the traits of the Skittles
clone
Dan do you want to start us off just uh
and we Matt obviously jump in at any
time local jump in at any time um but we
may as well start with what I think is
its
most uh notorious uh attribute its scent
right yeah like it scent is something
that like blows people's minds if
they've never smelled anything like that
in cannabis and so especially for like
people that are kind of like I don't
know touring a facility or something
it's like always a treat to be able to
be like oh you don't really smell weed
very often like come smell this plant
and like to me it's kind of like this
like Cherry Lemon grapefruit thing you
know like somewhere in between all of it
with like this creaminess that's like
really pretty mild compared to some
other Cuts but like also it's there and
it's distinct um but like it's it's also
like a dwarf little mutant that grows
super super slow and has just an
absolutely terrible root system that
like it I and the roots are there they
just don't work well for whatever reason
like maybe it has like a naturally low
respiration rate or something like that
but it's um it's a pretty hard to work
with plant like it's hard to clone it uh
um yeah like you can veg them for weeks
and weeks longer than everything it's a
pretty short flowering plant like we
like to take it at uh between like 50
and 56 days um before that nose
disappears because it will and just turn
into cardboard um but yeah that's kind
of my little my little summary of it
it's a nice plant though all
green a realistic picture of Z right
here yeah dead on Photo realistic photo
realistic it's not the most impressive
plant Matt what's your take on the scent
um is it the same as dance or do you
have a different opinion for me like
when we grew it it was um extremely I
can't I don't want to say Citrus in the
sense that it's like orangey because
it's not to me it was like the essence
of grapefruit and and the flavor lingers
like it it gives you the the lip
smacking thing where it's con it stays
in your mouth for quite some time after
and it's just it it hangs in my mouth
like Tangi and Calo do so yeah that
that's why I have a big association with
the Citrus Parts but yeah um grapefruit
is where I lean most
to and locco have you have you tried the
cut local I can't remember if I've asked
you this um I haven't tried the cut
specifically but I've tried a few uh Zs
ones from Caleb that he
grew um and those were honestly kind of
all within the range of what Dan and
Matt both described uh really heavy kind
of
like citrusy like kind of candy thing um
it the the smoke is like really
transparent too like the way it tastes
and and smells um it's almost damn near
identical but yeah it's it's really
tasty I like it a
lot yeah this thing does translate to
flavor uh yeah yeah that's obviously a
big deal as we've discussed um what is
the sense in terms of effects
potency low
nothing I mean I weed I I definitely
built up a tolerance to to Z and the Zs
ones and the sh best ones um extremely
fast extremely fast and but it wasn't
like there was ever like a whoa this
deep you know I never never hit there
even uh at first
smoke is it like uh how does it compare
in that sense to like other cookie
derivatives or
hybrids you say less less potent than
average oh wow okay you know because
there's like decent potency in modern
you know like gelato Bas lines and stuff
it's not always there but um you know
with just like a little heterosis from
outcrossing you can usually bring stuff
into the i20s and get you know like a
decent effect but yeah Skittles like I
think you're pretty hard pressed to get
high off it I like to blend it with
potent weed that may not be the most
flavorful like a a nice camon OG or
something and then like add that fruity
element so you got like the skunky
earthy you know what I mean with the
candy so I use it as like a flavor
modifier in
Blends you know one of the things that
like I think when we talk about the
Clone being kind of like a kind of piece
of crap I think some people do agree
like growing it it's not the most
friendly plant um is the branching and
when we try to talk about the branching
it it has even to me it has even more
bendy limp limbs structure than say an
OG and because it's not as tall and it's
more short and squat it's very odd
looking almost like a train wreck Style
just to where it just flops all over
itself it never had good turgid
structure for me yeah and it it also
like doesn't really have like strong
epical dominance like you'll never get
like a tall lanky
clone it's always this little ball
plant like that yeah without without
topping yeah without topping it does
that yes breus Syndicate 3.0 is coming
at you with props guys hope you ready
right I wanted to ask this kind of a
random question but like in your minds
are there any other kind of cuts or
lines that are comparable in whatever
fashion like does it remind you of
anything else for whatever reason
whether in structure or smell or
anything or no it's quite
unique I think it's like sweet pee and
grapefruit just along not the exact same
but the the the TPS are similar enough
and unique enough for what SPG was at
the time to have made the same kind of
impact I think that's why I associate
them so much and the grapefruit part of
it maybe one thing for the people who
are not in the US especially like when
did it come into the market this isn't
in my outline but I just kind of came to
mind when did it really like hit the
market and how much of an impact would
you all say it has had relative to
something like gelato 2017
2018 yeah um is when it really impacted
the market I remember the emerald cup
where they were trying to sell every
seed form of it possible yeah I think it
was like I think it was I think it was
spring 2017 when the dookie Bros dropped
their trades in Humble because that's
what I remember I was still in college
but I think it was my senior year or my
super senior year something like that um
and uh I remember ditching class and
going because like they had announced on
Instagram that they were you know had
limited quantities of it and I think I
got the last one that was on the tray
and it was like the least well rooted
and like I didn't know how big of a
piece of [ __ ] it was but yeah um we
actually didn't end up keeping that cut
long term because the hype hadn't built
yet and um it was still spell like the
candy too there was no Z's involved and
um uh yeah I couldn't get anyone to grow
it because it was a bad router it was
veg so slow just like those growth
traits nobody really wanted to grow it
because that hype hadn't built up
yet and as far as the impact it's had I
think I mean just look at the Modern
names on the market everything's got a z
in it now whether it has actual Skittles
in it or not its actual impact has been
that everybody sticks Z's on [ __ ] now so
yeah I think it and GMO also are like
single-handedly responsible for the the
whole rosin revolution in extracts
because Z actually does have I forgot to
mention that earlier it does have really
nice resin traits for washing and they
those tricomes just fall right off and
so um those were like I think the first
two that were the earliest I think that
ended up being washers that have lasted
to this
day I have a cultural question here is
the Z responsible for the term zah or is
that from something else I would bet
yeah I don't think you get zah without
the Z revolution in like Matt was
talking talking about a second question
if I call it Zed what will people think
you think that you're British just like
you are yeah you T totaler yeah
um in terms of like this crappy growing
like this kind of uh you you know you
have mentioned multiple times how bad it
is is there anything else that grows as
poly or that grows like it maybe
urle yeah ask actually
yeah yeah yeah that's kind of like what
I would compare it to if I was like
being like hey you've never grown this
but like here's the reality of it and if
they like knew their purple oh yeah I
see I don't have experience with that P
very similar yeah yeah not as leafy uh Z
is not as leafy as Puck obviously but
yeah no same kind of structure slow
growing shitty RS
yeah another thing that came to mind was
like have there been any
notable outcrosses uh with it
historically yeah tons like it just
depends on um what you consider notable
you knowly what I was going to say I
guess 201 2018 I don't find anything
notable too much but at the same time it
has had a major impact on the culture
and notably like yeah I mean there's a
lot of just like I said the z's are in
everything so I mean yeah definitely I
think it's honestly I think it's been
more of like a marketing Revolution than
actual like number of plants that have
come from it kind of thing there you go
it's like Skittles and then like maybe
moonbow kind of thing and rainbow belts
those are the only like three like big
names and they weren't really that
widely distributed and I don't think the
first iteration of rainbow belts was
like super well received and so what's
the lineage on that I think I don't know
about rainbow isn't it Dosey
Do [ __ ] Skittles I thought that was
moonbow but um I could be wrong on all
of it I don't know yeah me too yeah you
might be right that is moonbow what was
rainbow belts bro I'd have to ask I
don't know but I've seen stuff that
looks like rainbow belts come out of
like some classic combos of like Z OG Z
headband stuff like that sometimes you
get those dwarf little guys with the
really chunky
buds yeah um zcube was the one that I
had the first experience with before the
moon bows and all that stuff um how much
you pay for those $500 a pack yeah
that's what I remember too and I
remember I think it was Shiloh from
Fields no I bought them from Shiloh and
Shiloh charged me $500 a pack for I
think I spent 6K and 500 to pack all the
way up no breaks yeah yeah every time
I've met Shiloh at like events and stuff
he's been a really nice guy he's nice
super nice businessman for sure yeah
yeah the one I get out of all those
dudes all those dudes the only one I get
along with yeah yeah Matt since you
mentioned it Matt what was it like
working
with Z or the
zcube um there the the zittles smell is
not consistent in zcube despite it
supposedly being a
bx3 um and that was bx3 yeah could old
bx3 um a very fast bx3 I might add
meaning like it was made very quickly
yeah like a year and a half exactly and
the other thing I noticed was despite
buying many different kinds of the
Skittles hybrids that everything except
um the
Ros Rosé types were identical like not
in and not that everything was
uniform but everything looked like the
same Expressions coming out of different
packs no matter what the parent was if
that makes
sense so it was a lot to spend to see
something I could have seen in one pack
um with that said the outcrosses they
could definitely outcross Z dominant um
I like the structure better on
zcube um the crosses it's just it wasn't
consistent for the chirp so I had a
really hard time calling any of its
Skittles unless it was uh dominating
that particular cross but it didn't
really bring much in that in that sense
um it could have I think it could have
been done better relatively speaking
like what was the what were some of the
more successful results do you think in
your opinion um we had a a Dosey dose
NorCal IC mag cut cross to the zcube
early on called do Skittles which is
essentially similar to moonbo but it was
a few years earlier and people really
like that one a lot but again it's like
I didn't love it uh my favorite was the
the Skittles Blue Bonnet and I I work
that further but but that one was like a
a merging of the the graef fruit and
blueberry which to me reminded me a lot
of like um blue satellite you know so
and I like blue satellite what' you call
that Skittles Bonnet I didn't I didn't
think he did that I never released it of
course I only I only uh ran them and
then used it in the blue Skittles
blueberry Mac one send them to me yeah
you want I might have sent the last them
to D actually I don't remember what
happened to them yeah they were all
white they were all shitty seeds so I
was just like I can't sell this they pop
it's pretty it happens a lot even with
like a really healthy expression of it
that you get a pretty fair portion of
white seed in there yeah I mean they
were they were like modeled gray but
just like not full brown tiger stripes
so I knew there's no way I can sell
these because people would just like
flip out so yeah yeah it definitely has
like its own unique seed morphology too
I've actually used that surprisingly
successfully as like a predictor of uh
like those TPS you know and in my line
it's like a a limey kind of smell um but
once I fixed that like they were all
like really consistently limey like I
had one run where I like was doing a
breeding project I was pretty stra for
time and I didn't take as good of notes
as I should have and so I was kind of
just like smelling these like flower bit
and the Shu seeds off to the side and
like um I was kind of just like well
that one looked really similar to the
mother seeds you know what I mean like
oh I'm gonna I'm gonna try that and like
when I grew them they were just like
amazing you know and so I actually look
for that now and I've kind of noticed
that's interesting yeah that's
interesting I yeah like it's not
something that people ever like look at
but um I'm actually kind of obsessed
with it to a certain degree um cuz when
you know a line you know what its seeds
look like like yeah chmd seeds are like
little dark brown circular like
spherical balls you know what I mean
like that's what I've always kind of
seen from them and uh um I don't know
yeah Z is kind of like these little
dinosaur eggs with these like few but
like pretty specific looking uh uh
modeling on it I think is what it's
called um those tiger stripes but yeah
they look like dinosaur eggs that's what
I always call it you know because they
look different you know what I mean than
the average
seed funny little OTE I had like a buddy
telling me in a trim room one time we
had some seeded weed on this outdoor and
he's like you can't tell the difference
of these seeds and I'm just like let me
look at them and like I'm looking at
these five cups of seeds and I'm like
mix them all up you know what I mean and
I separated them perfectly and told them
exactly what they were you
know yeah I mean if you've gone through
a lot of seeds and you've made a lot of
lines and you just you know sorted seeds
a lot like it it becomes very evident
like oh this came from that this came
from that like train W has own type of
seeds you know like there's all kinds of
strains that that really have
distinctive seed types yeah yeah I was
working a bunch of s ones and so they
were like distinct separate a bunch of
Caleb stuff yeah I mean it's the same as
if you were like a I don't know a wood
worker looking at work uh wood you know
like you can see a lot more than someone
else could just because of the time
spent with it
um I'm glad you mentioned the oh you go
man I was just going to say like for
that comment uh me and someone else were
talking about a
mutual I should call them an
acquaintance now a mutual acquaintance
that it seems like what they were doing
and this is very typical in the weed
business was taking someone else's seeds
looking at what it was and was thinking
oh let me think this has skunk one Haze
and something El and and and I'll five
in it let me say this is you know uh a
Thai Afghan something you know like and
we'd see him move these things around
but the problem was like if people knew
those lines well enough that he was
confabulating for the others it's still
just as obvious because traits or traits
are traits and that's the one thing a
lot of people Miss if they aren't able
to see it themselves they don't
understand that other people can see it
they don't get it but it is
there yeah and I think you know that
should be a strong implication of this
whole episode you know the way we're
exploring this is through traits and
through observations not
through uh yeah not through a you know
as I mentioned like a historical lens as
much absolutely which I think I think is
a really interesting um way to go for us
as well even in terms of the show um I'm
glad Dan mentioned the s1s obviously
we're going to dive
into yeah thoughts on Skittles s1's sh
say S1 someone say
S1 it's the S1 master
um can I ask locco before we jump into
the S1 was there anything else I know
local doesn't uh mention that heat may
not have as much to say about the Clone
itself but local was there anything else
you wanted to add before we went into
the s1s um not at the moment that's cool
yeah okay if well we can just like
briefly just so like people can like
understand my kind of experience with
the plant in general and just like the
timeline so like we mentioned like the
Dy Bros um breaking up with like I don't
even know what their group was called at
that point right it wasn't Dying Breed
yet it wasn't turp Hogs yet like I don't
was it third gen or you know what was
that it might yeah I don't know I
remember I remember the the KY kushman
Shiloh thing but I don't remember
anything what what it was before then I
wasn't as keyed in to like the whole
like IG like I was just kind of getting
into it and figuring out like who
everyone was in California like I was
hidden away for a while but um yeah like
they do that in 2017 spring I get the
Clone couldn't get anyone to grow it
drop it um I come across it again or the
the kind of family in La that's when I
get the green shb and the sunset and we
do run I was telling you about this I
think like a week ago but yeah like we
get the sunset we get the green sherb
and um we run them side by side and
we're like well [ __ ] this green thing
you know what I mean the sunset's the
way to go it's purple it's gas it's
creamy it's like you know yeah um but
like I saw a plant that had like pretty
good modern structure like pretty full
um pretty unremarkable in most ways just
like lime green like a little fruit
basket kind of bouquet um and uh like I
I forgot about it for another year or
two you know until I got a cut called
Skittles quote unquote from a buddy in
Oregon and um that cut was more similar
in structure to the green sherb but it
smelled like the keyme pie yeah you know
and so I bred with that for a couple
years and now recently you know know
since I've had my current job for the
past year I've just been like crossing
Skittles to everything and doing tons of
Inc Crossing or outcrossing work a bunch
of different inbreeding projects and
stuff and so um it's been interesting to
see it all it's just like it's a like we
were saying earlier it's those traits
don't always line up the way that you
really want them to yeah that's for sure
yep yeah no that's great and maybe local
can say a bit as well I know it's
obviously not on the same scale and not
not trying to you know Mak him feel
awkward or anything but logo head you
you've run some sheris once correct yeah
I ran two packs from Caleb in the past
um and then I have another six going
right now I had one damping off so I'm
I'm just down to
six um but yeah I mean relatively
speaking they're all really nice plants
um what I've kind of found it that was
cool um
is that I know people [ __ ] on the
structure of Z A lot um that's one thing
I did not notice um in the the shb best
ones is is there is like No Lack of
vigor uh so to say um you got some
pretty nice like you know decent
yielding plants nothing you
know out of the ordinary or like you
know spectacular or whatever um there
was some color on the leaf but not much
of it really faded to the bud um but
then again my room wasn't the
coldest um and then um I was showing
some pics to Matt the other day and he
would pointed one out that looked kind
of like a like what you would see in
cookies um which I thought was really
interesting um what do you mean by that
uh so like the the nug structure and I
think it would be like the interner noal
spacing like the the way you kind of see
them spaced out from each other it's
pretty kind of obvious like now that I
look at it again
yeah um but I don't know like the smell
is just really nice too but I don't
think it's as strong as like the Z S1
smells but they are like the exact
same theme if that makes sense I don't
know also I wanted to I wanted to add
here like we haven't been able to um
verify that key lime pie is the exact
same cut as green Sher there's never
been a time when anyone that I know
personally has gotten them both sourced
from really good sources at the same
time to run them side by side so I just
wanted to add that caveat actually yeah
we should actually really explicitly
signpost this because I don't think we
actually spelled it out but the
speculation is that green sherb keyme
pie Skittles are either the same thing
will have something to do with each
other very close right no no Skittles is
something different what's the Skittles
is is is defitely a different clone than
the keyme pie and green Sher but um
keyme pie and green Sher it's definitely
debatable on whether they're related I
don't I don't really know I like I
describe I describe keine piie different
than Dan does for example because we
didn't have in the same environment same
room all that um how how Z is related to
Green sh like that is definitely
speculation but there's a lot so much in
common that it's hard to ignore I would
say okay so there's speculation
basically that they are that these three
are at least Loosely related yes I think
that's fair to say okay yeah gotcha
gotcha I mean if we were taking we were
like placing bits then what would your
bit be just I don't
know I mean I still don't know that's
kind of like why it's such an
interesting topic is that um I still
don't think anyone's found a Dead Ringer
in a green sh S1 but I think a green
Sher bag seed is definitely part of the
equation you know because like for those
traits the the way that I've seen the
traits break down and how they outcross
versus when you self and stuff is that
like the structure and the resin
qualities are really dominant and the um
Aromas are really recessive and so you
only ever really see them when you cross
it to things that it's kind of related
to already which is sure you know and so
you can actually get some of those Z
turps at low rates to pop up by even
Crossing like Z into gelato stuff you
know um but it's not very common and
like as far as like the percentage
breakdown um so I would yeah go
ahead no sorry you finish oh yeah I was
just going to say like I think that
green sherb like a green sherb double up
on some of these traits that being like
in an S1 I think is like a necessary
step but I also do have a suspicion that
it was out
cross so we've kind of piered the
conversation with this already but Dan
would you tell us like uh in terms of
these Zs ones like what did You observe
so I grew 45 of them and um I got 35
jars of flour out of it because some of
them hmed and then some of them were
just like literally so unworkable and
dwarf and slow growing that like it just
wasn't going to happen you know with the
pace of our work and so um what I saw
was like
90% Skittles like dead ringers of
Skittles and its structure and its uh
expression but just with cardboard turbs
you know like not good at all like
almost aromal less you know what I mean
and then the other 10% was eily similar
to cookies and and uh Sunset sherbet it
had a very sherb look to it and um they
were also completely aromal you know um
but there was a handful full I think we
had four Keepers out of those 35 um that
were all notable for one reason or
another you know some of them had better
potency some of them had a more true
Aroma but I personally didn't see any of
them that I was like this when I smelled
this and real Skittles at the same time
like that's the exact same Aroma it was
all like how local was saying it's in
the same ballpark which um I call like a
mixed Starburst you know what I mean
like if you had like a cherry a lemon
and an orange Starburst like all right
there on your hand that's kind of like
the closest thing you see um even in the
s1s and so I do personally think that
like um Skittles its Aroma and profile
is a very rare trait combination or Gene
combination in that pool because I Haven
seen it pop up yet just to clarify and
the s1's that you you ran uh you saying
like 90% of them were aromal less no
like 90% were like Skittles expression
like if I showed you the flower and a
real Skittles plant like the Clone side
by side you'd be like yeah that's the
same
plant like yeah it's a different
individual yeah morphologically yeah but
there was some nice smelling things like
what is that four out of 35 you know
like that's like one in seven has like a
pretty nice Aroma you know so it's not
like non-existent it's just like not
very high prevalence you know like when
we're working lines I like to fix traits
towards like you pop a pack of 10 you
have like a few to keep you know what I
mean that are in that same range but
you're just going to hone in on what you
prefer specifically you know so did you
did you run out sure best ones as well
or no you haven't you haven't seen no I
haven't but um I really want to I'm just
so limited on my like personal space and
I don't think it has like a purpose for
my work um at my job you know what I
mean they don't really care about like
the lineage and uh you know what I mean
like the mystery kind of thing that's
more of a personal project and so
yeah that makes sense you know like I
don't see msos really giving two shits
about lineage they just you know what's
already hyped what's marketed what can
we hype better things like that yeah
like don't get me wrong they want that
profile and some of those traits and
other things but it just doesn't really
make sense in some regard to like be
like oh let's go buy seven packs of s1's
run them find something that's like you
know I mean like I've already kind of
figured out other ways with just the
Clone to kind of get those expressions
bumped up a little higher percentage
wise and so um I actually had a little
side tangent do you know anything Matt
about the um the zprite cut no nothing
yeah that one is honestly even more
mysterious than Skittles itself in like
its whole Origins because like it just
like appeared no one can really tell me
anything about it the Bri yeah yeah yeah
and it's actually I think a another
little side tangent off that same
profile but it really does smell like
Sprite and I [ __ ] love it and I think
it has a better a better High to it and
so like I've worked with it I don't know
if it's like the real cut but it has
like you know the namesake trait yeah um
and so um that one is honestly even more
mysterious to me because it's it's cool
it's obviously related you can get some
of those zprite combos to pop up pretty
easily when you cross together and so
well if anybody in the comments uh or
that's watching this leave in the
comments if you know who the came from
or anything about it
please also ask real quick let me let me
chime in on this because Caleb the one
thing that I did or inspector the one
thing I did get him to comment on right
here was on the the prevalence of Z chps
in the zs1 and that was I think that's
the one thing that he took um like a
different take on he felt like
popping a lot of these Zs ones that he
found that TP in there um a lot a lot
but not the ex exact dead-on turp but he
said that the the scent profile was
there but in in abundance but not that
same exact clone with that scent profile
if that Mak sense yeah well and I've
been kind of thinking about this too
because like um you know I got that
feedback you know was that a couple days
ago or something like that um and I've
been kind of thinking of it because I'm
just like man maybe I didn't phrase my
like question or like wording right but
I think what it really comes down to is
that like we have very very different
cultivation Styles and like the work
that we're doing and he's doing those
like living soil organic beds you know
um which is like more what I would
personally do if I was doing this for
myself like he is um but it couldn't be
more opposite from what I do at work
yeah in our cultivation style which is
like small pot cocoa drip line direct
injection you know what I mean and so I
bet you he's actually getting a higher
prevalence just because he's growing
weed in a way that like that plant
probably prefers more than what I'm
doing you know I also noticed this too
in a similar way with the bubbleberry V2
like when I first popped you know a
handful of them I saw a lot of very
blueberry dominant smelling plants in it
but when the larger population got a
hold of it like when I sold it and
people got packs of it I was finding out
it the the blueberry trips were the
least
comment Expressions it was really really
bubble gump dominant and it was weird
because I felt like I had a pretty good
representation there and it just like
different rooms different styles you
know what I mean there's so much that
goes into it that really doesn't get
accounted for on variables like when
customers ask me hey what am I going to
expect from this is it gonna you know
help my anxiety etc etc there's so many
variables involved and it's really
impossible to explain unless you give
good examples like these yeah yeah
there's definitely so much difference in
how dir different people are going to
grow weed and so like you kind of have
to take an average of those and so like
if I even only have two data points it's
like well the the reality is probably
somewhere in between you know what I
mean like um you know maybe the way he's
doing it is literally just like perfect
for those expressions on this plant
whereas like a salt diet in Cocoa is
just like not really going to bring it
out because like there are other cuts
that I breed with that I get routinely
upset that I'm like well we didn't grow
it well so like how can you judge this
expression yeah you know and so I was
definitely kind of thinking about that
for the last few days where I'm like you
know what I think I could be really
wrong about that um based on our
cultivation style or not wrong but like
that our cultivation style is so like
specific to production and not like like
best turpine expression you I think I
think the way you qualify it isn't that
you're saying that this is what
everybody should expect and the only way
it goes down it's just like you're
saying this is how I ran it so I don't I
don't think it's necessarily wrong I
just think it's a completely different
run and take that it's
notal yeah yeah but it makes me want to
like slow down and change some things if
I could ever like do that at work you
know what I mean because I'm like I've
been like I've talked to you guys about
my frustration with OG too you know what
I mean like it doesn't like that
cultivation environment that's like very
prevalent now and so like how can you
really judge a breeding project if like
the expression you're getting is the
worst possible one I wonder if that's
why everybody thinks OG is just gone
despite every [ __ ] OG hybrid out
there still
oh I I think I really think it is I
think there's a lot of stuff that people
like renamed for clout like um I was
telling you before like the ghost OG
that's going around right now like
people have I've heard many people say
that it's not the same ghost that used
to go around of course and I'm pretty
positive that it's like a chmd OG based
on the structure and the expression and
the potency and like passing motor
breath around yeah yeah man but like a
way better cut than motor breath it
actually is a really nice cut if you
guys can get your hands on it um called
just it's just called ghost now it's
just called yeah ghost OG that's what
it's been going around as um but it's
actually really nice man I'm I was
really pleased with it when we r in it
so that's cool total s um I wanted to
come back to Dan's questions for Caleb
even though I know that Caleb didn't
really get an opportunity to answer them
Dan I
wonder I wonder if Dan wanted to at
least tell us about why he wanted to
ask these question some of these
questions um in the outline I don't know
if you guys are looking at the outline
but the second page has some of Dan's
questions okay um Dan I don't know if
you just wanted to tell us about why you
thought of these or like what what you
what what kind of outcomes you were
looking for yeah well I mean that that
first one I feel like we already covered
and that maybe the second one too
um your overall strategy yeah oh I mean
the main reason that I was like I've
been so so curious about this is that
like the cut does have nice traits but
when you outcross it to just like any
and everything like I kind of been doing
the last year um you don't see the
things that you want as much as the
things that you really don't like the
dwarfism some like slight hermaphrodism
like it's definitely not a Herm bomb
like um I've heard some people describe
it as but there is some hermaphrodism in
it um but like the main thing is is that
like I would cross it to all kinds of
stuff and I never got even a semblance
of the knows and so like that's
partially I think due to cultivation
style from like you know our previous
little anecdote but um at the same time
it's also just that like I've heard
plenty of people say that you know that
it's just like you don't end up with
that Aroma and outcrosses which leads me
to believe that it's some like very
recessive combination of traits that
actually make
it and express the yeah or some link tra
I mean the link traits like the aroma is
definitely tied to the dwarf is as far
as I've seen you know um but um I I try
and stay out of like the linked trait
whole thing just because it's like
SOC theortical
theoretical almost impossible to prove
at this and I mean even talking about
the aroma as like recessive it's like
well it's probably like dozens and
dozens if not hundreds of genes like
yeah that all need to be correctly
aligned in the proper way to like
Express that way but um what I've
actually oh go ahead reminds me a bit of
like uh Matt talking about Crossing two
super skunk types yes yes yes yeah yeah
double recesses and whatnot well and
that's kind of like what I'm getting to
is that like so maybe Skittles like
let's for Simplicity sake let's call
that a Roma profile like a double
recessive if it was a single trait so
like the only way to like really ever
get that expression then would be to
find something else that also has a
double recessive you know and that's
kind of honestly like the success that
I've had in like upping the um the rate
of expression for that really nice Aroma
even the ballark of it has been from
using two children of Z that both have
those traits um and or children quote un
quote like one of them being like the Z
Sprite and one of them being rainbow
belts you know because rainbow belts do
smell similar to Z but it's definitely
not as like pungent or is nice you know
sure it's um yeah it's just good you
know but um I actually had to pretty
decent rate of uh you know zerbs pop up
and so um that just means that you have
to like only incross it really like
weird types of incrosses cousin to
cousin kind of thing to be able to ever
um maintain that profile in a line and
so St yeah it's it's challenging to work
with in that regard because like you can
only really cross it with itself to get
those expressions out and I don't think
that like I think other people talked
about like using s1's and like maybe the
S1 will pass it better and I'm like no I
really don't think it will because
you're going to break it up again yeah
let me pause you here because I think
that's going to I think we're going to
move straight into um possible
directions projects Etc just to wrap up
this kind of like your your and and even
locals observations on the shus ones
like um but actually wait now what am I
saying sorry your your experience with
Skittles s1's what do you speculate its
lineage to be based on what you've seen
I know that like again don't hold down
to any of this this is just like go what
is it Dan well the only the only clue
you get right because if you see 90%
Skittles types is the sherb expression
and so it just leads you to sherb which
is still kind of like not really an
answer either you know what I mean and
green the green sh I tried but that's
what's funny is that it look the ones
look like
sunset you know what I mean I didn't get
it really much of anything that reminded
me of the green sherb cut or the the key
lime pie and structure and so um it's
all just Skittles you know um but that's
kind of the whole confusing part to me
you know it's definitely not a child of
sunset but like it shares a common
ancestor you know or like a shared
lineage with the green you know like
that's why it's so I mean we can talk in
circles for hours about this kind of
thing because like there's only enough
info to ask questions but not enough
info to ever have an answer you know Dan
you're so keyed up on this dude I can
hear those like sharp intakes of breath
like yeah where you're like you don't
even end your sentences yeah yeah yeah
local did you have anything to say even
just based on your like distant
experience with this just on like
speculation like got you
know I mean there's some kind of
relation like obviously between like
Sher and Skittle of some
sort um yeah based on what I saw I mean
some cookie look alike I mean maybe that
would be some kind
of thought on what it could
be not it's like 100% but you know maybe
that's something in there but yeah I
really don't know what it is well I
think there's another like conflating
part that makes it equally confusing is
that like the only difference between
sherb and cookies is the supposed
outcross right of pink panties well what
the [ __ ] is pink
panties you know that was yeah yeah I
had experience with it in running it
it's kind of a [ __ ] plant but um and a
[ __ ] breeder at that too I mean it's
better than it's a better breeder than
it is a grower but actually looking at
F1 derb I would be quicker to think pink
panties is related to F1 derb based on a
lot of the same um traits it has a lot
of the same stem traits and stuff and
and the way it sets the plan up um yeah
but like I've looked it up it's supposed
to be like what Burmese or Burmese Kush
maybe cross to [ __ ] I forgot what the
other part of it was but none of it made
any sense to me um yeah I think they say
like burmes to OG yeah something like
that something stupid it's not and
there's no possible way yeah it's not
it's not a good cut bro it doesn't have
the same scent profile does not have the
same tur profile whatsoever not even
close kind of fruity not not all it did
was kind of beef up the sherb whatever
it was yeah it's it's I wouldn't go with
pink panties I really really wouldn't
and and I know Sher sherb says that's
what's in it and you know he seems like
a nice guy but I I after growing that
cut I just am very hard pressed to see
that um oh by the way rainbow belts it
looks like it's a a skittles cross to
moonbow number 75 so it's like a g bx1 I
think that Fletch did okay yeah that
makes sense you
go yeah which actually may get you
farther away from what you want than you
know what I mean yeah um the other thing
is like we aren't going to go too much
into history but when I think about the
people working with that cut and the
history basically that it came from some
dude's girlfriend's dad in a tray blah
blah blah was labeled
cookies um and I think about what the
third gen dudes were growing they were
growing a lot of Sweet Tooth in
something called Adonai and and uh
Russian Kush there were a few other
things that were Staples in their crew
and when I think about sweet pink grap
grapefruit and I think about like sweet
tooth and stuff like that I'm like hm I
wonder but it came to them supposedly by
the story ready so maybe that's just
like a a red herring but yeah I just
don't know it's really hard that is a
very confabulated T it's gotten much
worse since third gen Dying Breed and
the the other dudes um broke up and stop
being frenzies it's gotten even worse on
the on what they say things are and who
did what where it came from less
consistent I should say so you don't
subscribe to The Grape Ape grapefruit
crop you know it's funny like I I say
grapefruit but like it's not like
obviously that's not graping it's there
though I I remember tasting some early
extracts like some BHO of Skittles and
it was like pure grapefruit it's very
grapefruit and that's where like a lot
of my Z stuff is extracts I that I smoke
and it's like this is [ __ ] grapefruit
this is sweet pink grapefruit like I
know what this is and um but I don't
know that that's why you know I don't
know if the the cuts in it and I I
basically I I really doubt it because
sweet pink grapefruit was a robust big
huge healthy plant but um yeah whatever
like the process was to make Skittles I
think it involved a lot of inbreeding
and s1's and not on purpose yeah exactly
like most [ __ ] right like just a lot of
accidents and re relabels and renames of
clones and trays and just [ __ ] like that
yeah someone got super lucky on that
like one in a thousand one in 10,000 bag
seed you know
like otherwise I think we would see
sisters to it you know what I mean like
if it wasn't so obscure and rare and
recessive I think that you would see
sisters because if you get a bag of bag
seeds or like the way I keep bag seeds
you know what I mean it's like I got
like you know like ideally like 20 30 of
them if it was really seated yeah you
know so yeah I have to agree on that but
trying to find out even guess what could
be in Skittles other than like there's
cookie type Sher types yeah like the
other Factor would be really really
shooting in the dark I think yeah that's
why I want to eventually go back to the
green shb s ones and like actually run
through those it's just like I don't
have the like capability of doing it at
the scale that I would want to like I
want to do like
120 you know I'm glad we're here because
this is where I think we pivot towards
looking at it its potential um but
before we do that I guess it's like so
the question is like what is the future
of Z before that I want to ask like who
cares do we care do you care does Matt
care um how far can it be taken um
and okay Matt so Matt I doesn't seem
super enthusiastic about its future why
is that Matt um just the future of the
Clone in general even talking to Dan
like the fact that they're having to do
all these go to all these Mees to keep
it alive to be able to reproduce like I
can see it being kept alive in other
lines but as far as that clone goes I
think that there is going to be a day
where that clone is gone because of how
um sickly it is not necessarily with hlv
but I mean just like its natural
structure is very not not good it's been
in a lot of shitty rooms before it made
it up to a bunch of us and it's just not
Hardy I don't see it living as far as
like it's not widely held either yeah
exactly like people couldn't keep it
they couldn't root it they couldn't you
know what I mean that's why I don't have
it I couldn't keep rooting it um yeah I
just I I don't know like I think because
it's an inbred type plant but it's
recessive I don't know what kind of
future it would even have in breeding I
mean people are going to keep doing it
whether it should be done or not or
whether it's making better [ __ ] because
the Market's determined by names and it
doesn't really matter how good it is as
long as it's hyped so in this kind of
Market maybe it'll last forever in
hybrids who knows because i' I've
actually heard from Dan his excitement
um that he just kind of cares about
solving the mystery if I'm not mistaken
Dan you don't actually I don't even like
it that much yeah yeah yeah I think it's
flavorful but I think it's a really
shitty breeding tool unless you want
resin traits that come with a ton of
baggage so like me sour essentially like
I I don't I don't love sour better than
anything else but the mystery of of it
has held me for so godamn long that I'm
not going to drop it until I figure it
out for sure yeah it's it's like the
whole like murder mystery kind of thing
like I'm not really into that stuff but
I can get hooked on it if I get that
introduction of the story you know what
I
mean murder mystery game yeah like what
happens you know what I mean I got to
know what what happens you know and so
like I've just been around it a lot and
had like experiences but like I don't
personally like it that much and I hate
working with it because it never does
what you want it to yeah um but like
going back to that whole like
theoretical like recessive thing you can
actually have a recessive trait like
that that's in like dominant and a or
dominant prevalent in a population but
everyone has to have it you know what I
mean because like over Generations if
like there's even like a handful of
individuals that don't those are going
to be dominant over the recessives and
eventually take over at like a
population scale over time you know and
so like I think it's kind of a doomed
tool be because of that you know what I
mean like there will I think it'll be
around and like people will hold cuts of
different crosses or like s1's or
whatever because like it is really tasty
and it makes delicious extracts but like
as a breeding tool I think it's like
next to useless honestly unless you love
breeding for resin
traits I want to Pivot to local here
because I know local is looking at some
shest ones as he mentioned and maybe I'd
like to hear from him like what he
thinks might be possible or what maybe
first what is he looking for in the s1s
and then if he does find that thing you
know what what does he think he could do
with it
later um honestly bro I'm kind of just
looking for some
zah that's really it um yeah I mean I
say Z like I need some cultural context
like what oh um
like you
know it's like tasty flavorful exactly
yeah that people would eat up right
yeah because even though it's low
potency people [ __ ] love it like low
potency isn't always bad you know but
what else local like is there something
that you want to do with it as well um I
don't know um I don't think I like it's
really nice like the flavor and
everything but I don't know if it would
make anything particularly worthwhile in
my collection like it's not something
that I would go back to and like dig
through extensively again or no but
you've talked to me about like having
some ideas for potential
outcrosses oh um yeah I mean I don't
know if I'd ever get to them um but I
mean there's some really nice U mango
gummy bear tasting eie appy uh plants uh
that could be like maybe a cool outcross
your sheret like thing I don't know
increase the legs a bit um keep like
those candy notes in like intact
possibly I mean I really wouldn't know
how to pan out fun enough I'm pretty
sure Matt might have mentioned something
like this in that I don't know one of
the weird cookies episodes that we did
about like how you would try to
Counterpoint cookies with something and
I think we did mention appy as like a oh
probably yeah like hearing um that would
be interesting yeah I guess just from
the point of view like oh sorry you got
M yeah no just I remember trying to
think about it it was like um trying to
add speed a better high and all kinds of
stuff my first idea was like c99 and I
was like wait a minute I have something
way better than c99 that accomplishes
all that and is way more dank and way
more pungent that's appy so yeah
definitely yeah yeah because I guess for
me this this section is interesting like
more or less all of you have said that
you don't get that much about his future
which is funny so I'm trying to force
you to pretend that you do uh so that we
can have can kind of like tease out some
like possible hypothetical directions
maybe can pass it to Dan now Dan I like
the I like the appy idea but the problem
is is I think it would take a minimum of
two steps oh easy yeah like guaranteed a
minimum of two steps where it's like
you'll have to make the cross and the
harder part will be like well how do I
find the plants that to double up on to
get the expression and the aroma that I
want out of it you know you're kind of
just picking at random we don't really
have that type of genetic phenotyping
yet and so um it'll take a lot of trial
and error I think but I think it could
potentially be really awesome you know I
went
with yeah I like that angle I I think
blueberry Z would be [ __ ] awesome I
think I had a what was it the blue
Skittles clone yeah um and I I I never
really knew what that was cuz like the
Dying Breed one was blue Domina Skittles
or whatever but like the one that I saw
was kind of like a squirt grapefruit
like super nice easy to grow you know
what I mean like I've never actually I
wish I still had that clone because it
was if it was what it says it was like
lineage wise it was actually like a
really nice expression what was it
supposed to be lineage wise do you
remember well that's what I don't know
is like I just got it as blue Skittles
but like it could either be the one that
you made or the one that Dying Breed
made I'm sure it's the one they made cuz
I me mine came way later than gotcha
yeah yeah yeah and I didn't I didn't
come across that honestly though until
about like 2019 2020 that sounds a about
when it showed up I'm pretty sure that's
when it got real popular I remember 2018
Emerald cup a lot of people were smoking
on blue Skittles there and I really and
thinking this is not fairy this is not
blue what the [ __ ] are they doing but uh
yeah no I think uh space B Invader kept
clones of the the main blue blue Z pop
that we did from our stuff I think he
kept it CL yeah there was some good
breeding clones in there too that was
still not pure Z but in the outcross
with the Mac one there is one that looks
like blue bonnet with Mac with Z turs so
that does exist it's just crapshoot yeah
that's kind of where I'm at with like my
work with it too is like trying to push
those boundaries of like well what's
closely related enough to like get the
right expression but like not just gonna
be boring and Z only you know and trying
to get away from those morphological
traits you know yeah um and I've had
some mild success but you know they're
uh um you know it's you I still have
never come across a Dead Ringer it's
always just
ballpark yeah and the zcube stuff too
like I said it was very unpredictable it
was
wildly not predictably Skittles like you
could find him in there but you'd be
finding a lot more other stuff in there
like I know um when when Dying Breed and
whatever they called them Platinum
Skittles I think they called it at the
time broke up um they one of them had a
Z3 which was the Platinum Skittles guys
phony meno and those dudes and uh there
was a
uh like zcb so I'm not sure that those
were any different they said that they
were after they broke up they're like
ours Hindu Kush ours was with this but I
saw a lot of Hindu Kush what I what I
recognizeed Hindu Kush stuff inside of
the um zq so I don't know which is which
I've had some later iterations of uh um
bx2 of Skittles um I won't name who
they're from because I'm about to talk
some mad [ __ ] but they were [ __ ]
terrible like some of the wor like like
imagine if you had the shittiest all the
shittiest traits fixed perfectly in a
population so they were all dwarf they
they were resin lless somehow so they
lost the good resin trait and they were
all cardboard yes and like I ran a lot
of them and I was like what the [ __ ] is
this trash how is this group so popular
yeah doesn't surprise me so all you have
to do is go type in who made Skittles
bx2 you'll figure it
out
yeah well you're welcome we may well
have a shorter episode today uh we're
kind of like come to the end of like at
least the structured questions that I
had for us um so we can talk about
whatever really at this point um if we
wanted to start wrapping up
um any you know any kind of final
questions or thoughts from everyone um I
knew that we wouldn't get to you know I
knew that two hours is quite long for
Skittles show sure yeah yeah there's
only so much to say you know right that
it's like um the plant is cool but it
also sucks you know what I mean and so I
mean I'll be honest with you in many
ways the plant was really just a foil
for us to talk about looking at traits
and what you learn from looking at
traits like that's really I think what I
care about more than
anything yeah yeah no honestly that's
kind of where I'm at too is like I've
been really getting into like
visualization of data and like looking
at the inheritance rates of these things
and like trying to quantify it and make
like visual aids to like assist my own
work with it and so it's been really fun
because it's been a challenge you know
what I mean and which is forcing me
outside of the box of where I would
normally hang out like I was never
really a data guy I was always like
breeding and selecting plants on
Instinct and my little handwritten notes
like it's given me an opportunity to
like really expand the toolbox to more
like
analytics yeah that's cool you know me
and local have been talking a lot about
traits lately privately U mostly
revolving around Super Skunk um the
different looks of it um you know I talk
a lot about like privately not even
privately like on the server about the
dog tongue traits inside of Super Skunk
um and and I've given examples of it I
think there's probably examples of it in
another episode even is that like a
single bladed Leaf yeah the little it's
like a little leaf that looks like a
little dog Stone but it's Absol it's
rounded and that's a very specific point
to it because there's a lot of stuff
that has those little pointy leaves you
know um yeah yeah but no I that's what I
look for in like as a sour trait exactly
and that's and it's in jel it's in it's
in p91 it's in uh clock Orange it's in
it's it what I've come to realize over
all this just by observing not just that
trait there's other traits inside of
Super Skunk that I don't really talk
about much that I've talked about to
local um that I kind of keep back
because I I don't like other people
using those traits against the plant if
that makes sense yeah you'll see it on a
strainly listing tomorrow exactly
exactly like look it has this tra and it
won't and then I'll be pissed so um but
the one thing I've learned is I think
just because of looking at traits and
nothing but traits I do think that and
and this goes along with what Neville
said one of his highest selling seeds
ever was super skunk and it looks like
super skunk proliferated in the early
90s throughout the United States and a
lot of different groups picked it up ran
with it found their specific cut and it
became like a local Legend in a lot of
different places uh under different
names and a lot of the the history on
it's gone like the history on p91 is
just so obscure but the one thing you
can follow is trait and traits just
don't lie they really don't I mean there
can be times where like um maybe a trait
isn't just standard to one line you know
what I mean and that can pop up and be
like oh [ __ ] well that means nothing to
me then it's just another data point um
I guess I was wrong but in this one I
haven't really seen that specific trait
and it's not just the dog tongue it's
how it's the pattern of that's laid out
on the bud um specifically that that
denotes the super skunk trait for that
one uh yeah so like following traits to
me I'm slowly learning over time traits
can be a lot more honest than trying to
untie people's stories and go back talk
to these people get inconsistencies talk
to them three years later get more
inconsistencies that just leads to you
spinning your head but really really
understanding traits and breeding traits
can take you so much further when you're
trying to figure out what stuff is in my
opinion
yeah does that dog tongue trait appear
in the like the original sensey Super
Skunk yeah yep in the original picture
of ciny super skunk you can see it
gotcha sorry D yeah I was just gonna say
I had this thought earlier is that um
when you're a newer grower it's like
pretty easy to like look at the
landscape of like what's available for
purchase or like collecting and think
that there's this like infinite
diversity within the gene pool and like
what my experience over the last you
know like 10 11 years has told me is
that like honestly there's really not
you know there's a lot of stories but
there's not that many traits and so like
I recently saw like an argument on IG
about like Lemon Cherry gato you know
what I mean not like the most desirable
plant by any stretch in my opinion um
but I did S1 it and I've run through a
bunch of hybrids of it and um one thing
that popped up at a really low rate was
lemon
tree the exact like not dead on but like
the mouth coat
yeah the basement version the the the
Stanky version you know what I mean like
a must musty version of [ __ ] lemon
tree and so like to me I don't give a
[ __ ] about what any of those dudes on IG
were talking about it being an a renamed
assai like gato 47 or like you know
being a renamed runs all that and I'm
just like bro like it's got lemon tree
traits in it yeah like it's not a really
high prevalence but like it's it's in
there you know what I mean and like it
didn't come from out of the blue you
know these combinations of traits that
give you that expression like they're
less common than you would imagine being
a newer grower you know what I mean like
if you smell lemon tree the chances that
there's Lemon Tree in it regardless of
what anyone says like it's probably in
there man and for me I smell lemon tree
and I smell lemon G like that it's like
a hard burnt rubber lemon peel that's
just offensively lemon yeah it totally
just yeah that that reminds me of that
one so much
yeah now that's a whole another clone
that's actually taken my interest in uh
the last year or two is that um I've had
lemon tree under like four different
names yeah but it was all the same exact
plant lemonade and all that lemonade
lemon are people associated with that
one I don't know yeah so um yeah there
are people associated with lemon tree
one of them is a complet lunatic like
anti Semite so and he's the one that
likes to talk about it the most so it's
really hard to get the actual back
history and know if it's correct but in
the end none of them know what it is at
all or have any clue so
yeah yeah but I've got lemonade and
lemon tree myself yeah I've got lemonade
lemon tree organ lemons and um God it
was like a Le play on Lemon Tree
um uh like maybe it was just lemon trees
with Z or something I can't
the top of my head it's all been the
exact same PL yeah
yeah um but honestly I try and stay away
from that stuff because it is like
really dominant you kind of get the same
thing dominant yes the same thing over
and over it's definitely not something
that I've tried uh you know down here um
but I'm a bit scared too based on what
you guys are saying the way I just some
people love it some people really love
it they do some people love it I
describe it as picture a lemon coming to
life growing legs and a ballsy dick and
pissing in your mouth like pure lemon
lemon Flor cleaner but not like L but
like just pure like actual cleaner and
that's what it's it's very much like
that lemon man pissing in your mouth you
can get it to be a little sweeter to
where it's just like a really potent
lemon candy but that that cleaner side
of it's always kind of there where it's
like offensive you're like
oh co your mouth lemon G is the hard
offensive part of that to me like it's
just same mouth coding same everything
and it's it's one of those where like I
I know it was super popular in Ohio and
I'm like how could people smoke this
[ __ ] over and over for years it is all
lemon it is Wild Well when all the weed
just tasted like burnt [ __ ] before that
they were like this is delicious yeah
probably right when we say cleaner in
this context like is there any relation
to kind of like OG soapy type cleaner or
totally different yeah like like like
pinea pungency but like not Piney like
lemony so like I don't know lemon
cleaners are pretty common like Goan and
like any of those like
Limon Pine yeah Pine is like a furniture
polish in OG is very furniture
polishyellow line that makes that
because those cuts aren't even that
particularly high in
line yeah like I think today I actually
just saw like my first test where I like
I saw over one and a half percent limine
and I was like holy [ __ ] like Jes that's
a [ __ ] lot of lmon like most on
anything specific um I can't remember
off the top of my head I was doing a ton
of data entry today and so like I just
noticed [ __ ] that like is abnormal you
know like when a canono profile like
you'll get like a total total THC or
like to you'll get some cannabinoid
total cannabinoid and then total THC and
they're all calculated slightly
differently and so when there's like
large discrepancies between some
cannaboid and total THC like more than
10% of the potency I'll go and kind of
like dig in the cannaboids and be like
well where's all that extra percentage
coming from because it's got to be
something like CBG
CBC um is CBG 1% CBG common to find in
stuff or
1% is very common yeah up to like one
and a half or 2% because like CBG is the
precursor for a holster of cannabinoids
right yeah CBD and THC included and so
um when the plant is not quite finished
you'll see an abnormally High CBG
content but for me to notice that like
10% threshold like average difference
between those two metrics is like 5 to
7% and so when I see like 10% or above
I'm like oh what the [ __ ] is in there
and yeah it's usually CBC and CBG but
it's like that's like kind of one of my
next Avenues is uh trying to get like I
have one plant that's like pretty high
in CBG but it's also very high in THC
and so I can't I haven't quite figured
that one out yet because it doesn't like
really make sense like that CBG would
probably all convert to THC if I ran it
long enough like 11 12 weeks but like
when you harvest it at nine weeks like
it's done and it's like you know loaded
with all these accessory canono and so
interesting I'm wondering if I can like
if I find another one I'm like oh I'm in
the money you know what I mean I can
cross these two together maybe it's due
to the same kind of like genetic play at
work you know what I mean yeah but
that's all like guess and check work
it's like you just got to find two
plants with the same trait and hope that
it's for the same reason and cross them
together and see what happens like
that's kind of where I'm at with my
rosin work you know um because at least
it's an easy to test for trait I don't
have to to do like analytics I can just
go wash it real quick and do a test
watch you know yeah but
um I have no idea where we're headed I
don't know either man you want just talk
about
weeds yeah I mean we could probably tie
it up whoa is that Dan's household oh
that's my little boy let letting his his
real shrieks
out that might be a sign for us to to
wrap it up here guys
yeah fine for the first time in a while
we have a on Hour episode usually when
we short it ends up just being two hours
anyway but today two and a half you have
NE on telling my [ __ ]
right so I don't know I think we take
the we'll take that as an opportunity to
have a more chill day um is there any
last thoughts from any of you local then
I know sorry local I know you didn't
probably didn't have enough like much
space in this cono but but
yeah anything from
anyone any shout
outs yeah um shout out to our boy here
Mr Mr inspect Mr inspect shout out for
him showing up to the episode and
helping
out thanks Caleb he's got pretty pink
legs bro I needed him here we might do
if he actually ends up being available
we can do a followup yeah for sure with
his what he's found yeah
yeah yeah no just a hard one man no I I
got nothing I mean just like shout out
to the homies on the server and I
haven't been around much I've just been
busy and [ __ ]
exhausted now you're fine dude
especially after you you had you needed
a break after that one week where you
recorded like three shows as well yeah
yeah I've been joining the like the
Sicky club that we have on our server
too where I've just been like not
feeling good this week so just I think
now too
yeah I'm passing it off to all of
you through the mic yep wipe down those
Discord voice
chats shout out to Coma what else do we
got local you got your shout
out loc um not this time
no shout out to Call of
Duty shout out to [ __ ] bon bonss in
your mouth while you're saying
that um I'm I'm eating a payday right
now oh it's it payday okay yeah I just
ordered inant
cart Loco has to Loco you got to send me
some junk food from over there man for
sure bro all right okay it's a good idea
actually will they allow
that yeah yeah anything that's kind of
like commercially produced and like
packaged is fine just like no live bio
material and nothing that's like open
yeah I've got to start thinking up all
the greasiest tastiest crap we have how
am I going to get that to
you well all right everyone uh all right
Matt you wanna you want to wrap it yeah
wrap it up like a a sheep skin condom
um sorry I just had that picture to my
head and had to finish it off um yeah so
check out our Discord you know that's
where we hang out and she [ __ ] and act
like idiots and have fun um we talk
about strange stuff all the time
theoretical non- theoretical help each
other grow help each other grow in life
sometimes in many cases um go check out
right seeds.com we have lifted seeds
lifted genetics.com I can't remember
which one he goes by um but he's on
Instagram he's carrying a bunch of our
dude stuff we also have uh who else do
we have uh right Eco Europe and Maddie
booze at G byce seeds in Australia so
check all that out and I think I mean if
you guys have any comments leave them
below um I always like it when the
comments get blown up with a lot of
people's opinions and uh counter
opinions to anything we say it makes it
a lot more fun and interactive so yeah
please New Codex entries Matt oh yeah
there's New Codex entries that's right
we added F1 derb I'm gonna be adding ABC
soon or did I add it no that's still to
be add you add though as well yeah and
we're gonna have some more info on ABC
soon too which is I mean for there's
only a few of us that have chased it you
know 15 years plus and we're finally
getting to the bottom of some stuff so
it's really cool and I'm stoked about
that same with headband um yeah we got
the headband entry in too that was very
interesting yeah one thing was that so
this is the end of quote unquote season
9 but we I think we've got some exciting
stuff lined up for next season yeah um
some cool interviews coming amen
yeah and no one's even breathing hard
yet and with that we thank you uh we'll
see you next week thank you everyone for
showing up thanks everyone we might have
a week break maybe we'll see I'll talk
to B yeah yeah okay all right cheers CCH
[Music]
you want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it
out