foreign
[Music]
episode of do or dab we've got two
contestants today
both Kelly and and the Cana Queenie
how you guys doing are you ready for
this [ __ ] I am so ready
what do you guys do to prepare for this
I want to hear a little bit about the
build up uh coming to do or dab
friendly competition
happens a lot of a Dying you know just
good enough
there's a lot of things into this we've
got Mr Pink tank joining us today too
backing up his girl you guys are gonna
go [ __ ] down
that believed in me yeah show everybody
your shirt there that's [ __ ] awesome
don't be a [ __ ] in the Discord don't be
a [ __ ] in the Discord
she has to be reminded
you're gonna show why it was wrong
talking [ __ ] already prove those
[ __ ] wrong Queen he prove those
[ __ ] wrong whoever the [ __ ] lied on
me whoever the [ __ ] lied on me this is
for you it's on number nine I'm not
Galaxy
but that's okay [ __ ] pink came
through he kissed my boy my life forget
it all right
here
I think we should do a friendly game of
rock paper scissors to get it started
between you two all right let's go she's
on that [ __ ]
ready
Rock Paper Rock Paper Scissors Shoot
okay hello scissors go again
[Laughter]
you can't hear me
no I just stopped I figured I'd let you
guys go on now
so you gotta give my ADHD brain okay
okay ready ready
Rock Paper Scissors Shoot
okay we got Queenie Queenie starting
okay back to the do or dab board so
Queenie starting Tink pick a number man
yeah
44.
we're gonna go straight to 44. number 44
says
take a red hot Banger dab Charlie Brown
you gotta heat up your Banger until it's
red [ __ ] hot like glowing
or you can pass take a regular dab but
you don't get the point what a way to
start the game
right that burns
what I'm gonna do Queenie we can do it
we could just pass the point
I know that's for her and it's like the
first the first challenge of the game
what's the motto
it'll kill me but that's all right I got
steroids
oh yes
so we're taking it
[ __ ] yeah
awesome [ __ ] yes
it's red hot
I should have thought about that
yeah it might burn the fingers a little
bit
picture of glove
I'm reading the comments
Friday since it's easy
good job
one point for Queenie my turn all right
kellyanne
I'm gonna pick number let's say 14.
seems like a good number
first person you see on the screen tell
them I love you and that's about as real
as they get
like in real life I have to do that a
real life
uh and so I have to take you with me
am I the first person you saw
I love you and it's as real as it gets
a boy for kellyanne
all right go ahead
25. number 25 says
Rhyme Time pick a word in rhyme the
loser dab
so you're gonna pick a word
and then kellyanne's gonna have to rhyme
with it to begin with oh
worried can somebody grab a [ __ ]
dictionary I think that's cheating here
I thought the term was
supercalifragilistic Expialidocious and
I'm pretty sure that's not in the
[ __ ] dictionary
okay I'll give you another word
calisthenics what is it calisthenics
yes
Alex
ah Queenie gets the point
[ __ ] you too
[Laughter]
number seven says you have 30 seconds to
roll a joint if it runs you must dab
do you have any flour whose turn is it
your turn it's my turn 30 seconds to
write roll a joint s
and it can't run when does my time start
as soon as you got the the uh Bud ground
up and it hits paper
terrible picker at the numbers okay
I'll pick the worst ones apparently yeah
and you can't go off past you or dabs
because I rearranged everything again
and there's a ton of new questions
okay I'm taking the last of this four
grams I
just got smaller none of them
in advance I apologize for none of the
new oh it's so hard
all right go ahead
start the timer
okay hold up choke it down pleasure
ready go
it's quite the episode isn't it
come on Kelly you got this
50 more seconds
no pressure
Panda says I'm already having flashbacks
do our dab cause the PTSD oh time's up
are we rolled up
I'm rolled up let's see it let's see it
okay keep going under the camera oh
she's got it
you've got to light it you've got to
take three long drags off of it and if
it has a run you don't get the point
glad you guys like the grid format this
is easier for me to edit from
yeah I hold it up to the camera
that's not running
[ __ ] hey
hell yeah kellyanne that's my girl
all right tank
that's how you do it 22. going with
number 22 number 22 number name three
sex positions or dab Queenie
oh she's got this reverse cowgirl
missionary
doggy style
um
we're just gonna start describing [ __ ]
now
all right kellyanne you want to pick a
number 45
45 says
list five terpenes in 10 seconds man
can we do it did I
can probably write them better
peninnaline
um
yeah
I know I know oh this is too hard that
is hard unless you really know your
terpenes
all right we lose a point there go ahead
tank
[Music]
21. number 21 number 21 says
free pass
got a free point for Canon Queenie
there's two more free passes on the
board right now we are at kellyanne two
in Canon Queen E4
yay
just talking I love the energy love the
energy Panda yeah what's going on here
oh
Panda's eating mushrooms too
I'm just saying oh my God
I just got a point
oh [ __ ] what was the last one that we
picked free passing going away either
no I'm stuck on that [ __ ]
what number was the [ __ ] 21 21
this was not the day to do the mushrooms
thing tank
that's when you told me
all right we're good we're good
okay okay where are we at we're on
Killian kellyanne let's go with uh let's
go with number 20. number 20 says
guess the color of your opponent's
underwear if you're right you get a
point if you lose you must dab
she's not wearing any underwear
are you free Bob and queenies
hell yeah we're gonna ride like this
doesn't have any underwear on
all right all right
uh let's go with number two
number two
low numbers who says red hot Banger dab
again ah damn
um I thought it would be a low risk
you're earning this Queenie you're
earning this
wait let me take off my cat this time
she's going command she sees this
free fact about Queenie
that's my favorite Banger of yours
I'm already feeling that stream a little
bit
as a banger
we have the Banger no he needs to God
damn it China
God damn it
already stealing it all right Stephen
the [ __ ]
I'm so happy with that shirt that's
[ __ ] awesome Queenie
thank you Sam Julie made it it's all
good just crank it up
and just let the heat go man I mean the
other [ __ ] are we doing here
cranking out the big boy
[Laughter]
the wax
I will work on some don't be a [ __ ] in
the Discord stickers for sure you do
stickers still yet yes I do oh yeah
we're definitely gonna talk
I have a sticker supplier right now but
I would be happy to trade that shouldn't
support one of our members
I do stickers and I just started an eBay
store selling patches cheers
[Music]
badass oh [ __ ] oh my God Queenie please
be careful
[Music]
that was pretty bad
I think you you like
burn it all off
all right kellyanne we're gonna go for
number 34.
number 34 says do your best yodeling
impression
sounded Indian
I was gonna say what the [ __ ]
yeah
it sounds like like a Native American
that got lost on a pirate ship
laughs
oh man what the [ __ ]
you said to my best
um I don't know does that count you said
do my best I that's a technicality yeah
yodeling is not like that yeah
thank you
that was a good one that was a good one
I loved it all right go ahead Jake
number eleven yes
what was that that's my favorite number
number 11. all right number 11 says good
sing the first Michael Jackson song that
comes to your mind for 10 seconds
still got three seconds
[Applause]
there we go
[ __ ] yeah Queen good job
[Music]
full on in character shrooms and doer
dab goddamn
let's go with the higher numbers let's
go with number 30.
number 30 says animals take turn naming
animals that start with the letter s
first one to mess up loses any living
Creature Counts we decided this last
time anything alive works
foreign spider
a spider is not an oh you said that was
any living animal okay I watched the
doer dab that said that a spider was not
an animal
right but you just hesitated by not
answering back Elliot okay that's fine
oh no
Saint bernadoodle it's okay
yeah go ahead Tink that's why we changed
it to anything alive Anything Goes
yeah
okay that's the wrong family it doesn't
count
wrong Kingdom wrong Kingdom actually get
it right um
go ahead dick five number five number
five going low number five says best air
guitar solo winner gets the point loser
dabs Panda's got this one
give it to me okay you start off
go ahead Queenie
oh wait let's get something better how
about this
[Music]
[Applause]
try to compete with him
[Music]
that was [ __ ] awesome all right so
what we're gonna do for that one
um we're gonna ask our viewers
oh you did the better guitar solo that
pole is going to be upped in the chat
you guys get to vote
I feel it I feel it I'm already feeling
my dad
all right we got the pole open there you
guys go vote on that one and here after
a couple more questions we'll reveal it
and the loser will have to dab and the
winner will get a point
okay we're back on kellyanne correct
yep yep okay we're gonna go with uh
number nine number nine says juggle
three random objects for 30 seconds if
you drop one you lose the point and you
must dab
clearly I'm not going to be able to do
that
are you going to attempt it okay that's
Spirit of the game I'm
finding
I'm going to Jekyll I'm gonna head down
to it I'm just thinking do I do I just
give up the point or and just take the
dab
don't be a [ __ ] in the Discord
don't grab anything glass please
I don't know if you needed that tip but
it's there I have a lot I have a lot of
glass things
pens
easy God you're telling me is there
something terrible we should look out
for
something easy
how good at juggling do I have to be
yeah
but you gotta do it for 30 seconds
okay here we go I'm an [ __ ]
oh yeah
did you drop it I left
oh no
Oh wrong [ __ ] soundboard what the
[ __ ]
[Laughter]
[Music]
okay yeah you know that is a cruel one I
should change that to like a good solid
10 seconds but
I wasn't trying to be nice KW okay and
the 30 seconds and stuff all right go
ahead Tink
oh you gotta take a dab by the way 31.
that's what I'm doing
31 says
open your front door and yell I love
anal or you have to take a half gram dab
she's in the middle
I know
I'm good
I said have you walk out to the road
y'all ready for this [ __ ] I only get one
chance you can't go
good job good job now let us know if
anybody comes knocking yeah
all right we got another point right now
we've got Kelly Anna before can aquini
at seven
kellyanne catching up on the dab there
we're going to give you number 26 number
26 says staring contest stare at your
opponent the first one to Blink takes a
dab so you got to get your eyes right up
to the screen stare at your opponent
the first one the blink has to take a
dab you know when we start
but if you win kellyanne you get the
point
okay ready on your mark get set go
oh they're locked in
ah Kelly yeah come on
I have a brain disorder that one's
really hard
we gotta get you caught up here Kelly
come on come on I believed in you we all
believe in you
can't you all put your money
straight in my face forever I'm not
worried about Tink he gives me hell all
the time
all right go ahead
it's my job Doc it's all out of love
um
37.
over here number 37 says y'all look like
rookies steal a point
oh
Kelly Ann loses a point and Queenie
steals it there is one more of those
so you can grab that point back but
right now we went down we're at
kellyanne three don't even [ __ ] eight
don't even think about it
all right Killian
what are you thinking should we go low
numbers High numbers what are you
feeling
I do not care whatever you want okay
we're gonna go 47.
47 says
steal aboard
[Music]
what's the [ __ ] chances of that
that's badass
back to back baby
right back to where we were
Kelly
was seven
okay
maybe it's more intense I guess I'm not
sure I have no
damn that went hard man
yeah literally
what are the [ __ ] chances he says one
in fifty I mean
you want to get technical we can take
more off the board you know
okay we're we're at Tink thanks choosing
where the [ __ ] are we
yeah I'm not gonna lie I asked you guys
if my voice was echoing thank God it's
not for any of you but it is for me and
I'm getting an echo back into the
headphones so I hear myself twice and
now I'm on shrooms I was like
okay
what are we going with I think
. we're gonna go with 29. it's just
getting real for me
there we go okay number 29 number 29
says
take a fat ass dab okay all the harsh
dab ones I'm so sorry
that's the ones that get you in the true
Spirit to do her dad that's a badass hat
the true Spirit
um I
I think those red hot bangers might
really kill your spirit okay everybody
we're gonna reveal that pull here in
just a few seconds if you haven't got
your vote in yet down by where you can
typically ask questions there's that
pull click on that vote
who did the better guitar solo
just taking a big old fat ass dad
all right the pull is closed and we will
publish the results Kelly and the better
guitarist solo
60 of our viewers here said kellyanne
got it 40 said Queenie very very close
thank you
all right and we are back to Kelly and
Kelly and I'm gonna give you number 16.
number 16 says
oh take a dab and say how much wood
would a woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck
could chuck wood if you succeed your
opponent has to dab if you fail you have
to take another dab you have Tink here
to thank for that one
take your dab as soon as you exhale
you're gonna try to say how much wood
could a woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck
could chuck wood could chuck wood are
you gonna put that back up there do you
not know the saying by heart listen I
have a brain condition I don't remember
[ __ ]
the woodchuck would
you
I could make it harder
fun way to the doctors the other day
oh [ __ ]
that's a bad thing to get lost do you
I'll throw it up there I'll throw it up
there as soon as I see you pull away
they all throw it back up on the board
if he can find it
all right so can a Queenie did we take
that dab
okay
it's a good one too
you're not dying like I thought you
would you're doing really good you guys
did practice
well I hit it with some Claritin D
before I started
clear off that check how much wood could
a woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck could
chuck wood
get it get it
all right go ahead Tink
15. foreign
number 15 says what does CBG stand for
[ __ ] I don't know
I don't uh
I don't know
nothing
you don't want to take a shot in the
dark
you never know you might get it
gravity
take a dab
we'll see it can a bigger what does it
stand for
canopy girl can a big girl
can a bigger all
right
all right
kellyanne we're gonna go with uh let's
say number 17 that one's sticking out
number 17 says rock paper scissors best
two out of three winner gets the point
loser dabs
[Music]
am I warming up my hands like I'm about
to play
[Music]
you know how you feeling over there tick
I'm feeling good my knees are tingling
my surroundings are shifting
I'm getting to that front right there
yeah
more with you
really got tired I'm good
all right we're about halfway through
right here okay
all right we on kellyanna are we on
Queenie
yeah the rock paper scissors you're
right yeah I'm way ahead right now
go ahead
that's two out of three ready oh
who's saying it I am two out of Rock
Paper Scissors Shoot
oh rock paper breaks
scissors
Rod break scissors I got me in my head
okay ready that's two out of three
Rock Paper Scissors Shoot
I break scissors on the other end okay
we're one and one
Rock Paper Scissors Shoot
is that paper or scissors paper what's
going on there paper that's paper oh
Kevin kellyanne
good job Queenie
I have to die all right Kevin you also
dab
somebody's got to be in control here I'm
not I chose it's team's turn to pick a
number okay I think
13 [ __ ]
13 but I don't have a 13 [ __ ] I
have a 13. throw that one up number 13
says name a word that rhymes with Tokyo
you have 10 seconds I gave you that
challenge yeah
Tokyo
[ __ ] yo what the [ __ ] okay
they're like those candy they're called
Tokyo
Google hockey
is that it buggy yeah
Tokyo
yes I love it I love it you almost adapt
it cleaning it
[ __ ] yeah oh [ __ ]
I mean you were close you could have
said like Pinocchio
oh
my god
oh [ __ ] clothes
things sitting here when you're put on
the spot right exactly
I can't remember [ __ ] right now
I'm definitely towards the peak right
there
yeah okay
next time I say we're gonna do we're
gonna do this tank just be like remember
last time man you remember that you
remember how hard it was the function I
needed it the first time to be able to
say that so yeah
was doing
all right Killian we're gonna give you
number 33 number 33 said
balance on one leg touch your finger to
your nose and hold it for 30 seconds if
you fall you must dab
[Music]
one leg yes
okay 30 seconds starts
[Music]
three two one good job oh yeah
Killian gets the point
we're at Killian six can of Queenie nine
all right Tink go ahead buddy
42.
number 42 says
using no words or objects communicate
how to pack a bong and smoke it okay
calyx gave you this one so you gotta use
body language to tell kellyanne how to
properly load her bong and smoke it just
just the body
just body language
this is going to be heterosexual get
ready yes
[Music]
did you did you put your weed in where
you're smoking from what's going on here
you're breathing in ground but what
kind of contraption is this [ __ ]
foreign
[Music]
laughs
oh my God this is awesome awesome dude
I'm loving it okay Queenie Kelly
let's go 28.
[Music]
28 says
Simon says your captain is Simon lose
the challenge lose the point I being
your captain you've got to do what I say
for one minute
we'll put that on the clock
kellyanne go grab yourself some water
yes Captain take your time
oh never mind it's right there
I'll go get some
Gilead Simon Says chug it
we can't see you
she wants to get the water well you told
me to go get water
okay Simon says stop
some says act like a chicken
like a chicken
oh
Simon didn't say
but you're Simon I know
I've Gotta Throw one in there just to
make it there
I didn't know that you had to say Simon
all right have you ever played Simon
says kill yet yes 27 years ago no 30
years ago it's like riding a bike didn't
you
okay
sorry
I'm the worst coaching coach ever
okay go ahead take
what's up buddy number 39 says if you've
never run a scrog take a dab if you have
take two
you've never you've never grown indoor
have you
yeah you're good you just gotta take a
dab
see
ignorance is bliss just live a peaceful
life in this situation absolutely
dick magician says we're losing it
bro I'm [ __ ] up and I want to say KW
said something
the universe
and I was staring at that [ __ ]
comment for a good few seconds [ __ ] up
I look over every once in a while
chicken all right
we're gonna go with number 18.
number 18 says
take turns naming curse words whoever
hesitates and repeats and loses and must
take a dab
this is a correct one go to the room
go
come on
all right
just making sure it's kid-free yeah you
just know it you just start saying cuss
words
okay are you ready are they gone
Queenie are they gone
[ __ ] yeah everybody's good though
let's see
[ __ ]
damn
I already said that oh she repeated
she repeated kellyanne gets a point
we're at seven for kellyanne 11 for
cannaquini come on kellyanne we got this
okay and we're we're back on tank right
no it's can a Queenie yeah Canon Queenie
you're picking the word 32.
you get to pick the punishment she's got
to be the one acting out
all right mechanically you got number 32
number 32 says free pass
ah damn it
this is [ __ ] us up there should be
one more in there kellyanne
that better not get stuck on that pretty
fast
[Laughter]
there's too much [ __ ] moving and too
many numbers gone I'm gonna have trouble
coming back from this one
it's easy when it says a number up there
like number 18 I can just go back and
reset it
right yeah
sorry guys your host this [ __ ]
tripping balls uh dank Magic Man
's 36.
I didn't pick that number
no I know he says he said I said Thank
magic man says
please dear God number 36 says [ __ ]
that's 537 oh no
we'll get there take a 10 second dab and
blow it out your nostril if you can't
take it
another one
wait wait
I don't I don't right now I'm having
troubles
this is a bad idea
no it's a great idea take a 10 second
dab and blow it out your nostril if you
can't take a 30 second dab
s not holding on to reality comes back
foreign
so you just gotta take a 10 second dab
breathe in for 10 seconds and blow it at
your NASCAR
[Music]
[Applause]
we're gonna run this uh show 15 minutes
later because it took us a while to come
back guys but you guys still got a
little while to do or down but no
worries
we'll always do that whenever if the
start time is late we will run it uh
that amount of time over
give everybody a free shot about one
hour
[Applause]
[Music]
and then you plug your nose
and blow it up the other okay that works
good job good job
[Music]
her internet connection is kind of going
to [ __ ] on us it's a good thing it is
Queenie starring Queenie yeah
all right go ahead
17.
yeah 17. did I stutter I'm sorry it's
it's the you gotta realize I'm hearing
double everything and it's like [ __ ]
War I'm seeing triples of everything my
man
ah why is it showing up the eyes
what do you want dog you're over
stimulating me you look like a
terrifying monster trying to eat me I'm
not gonna lie
doubt
we'll get this back
pick an animal Whoever has the worst
animal noise loses okay
yeah which animal you want to make a
sound of a horse
a horse okay let's see your best horse
noise
kellyanne can we get you back on screen
here
oh no I'm gonna have to play for
Kelly yeah come back
I can't finish this right now
we promised them 15 minutes
I mean I won't give her the [ __ ] but
then what's the point of me doing it
she ain't getting any points for it
gonna say number 27 number 27 says iron
lung
both players take a hit and hold it in
last player the cough wins
oh should I do the horse noise can I
play for
what are we doing here
we're supposed to I picked up
the horse
what you think what you think
who did the better one dude go ahead
go on
[ __ ] pregnant
would you guys think in the chat who did
it better [ __ ] things
yeah I am keeping track I have kept
track of the points onto here we're good
right now we are at Kelly and seven in
Canon Queenie 12. okay Killian's back in
okay you can do your own horse noise
there we go
yep okay best horse noise
thank you let's throw it up let's throw
it up in the pole I like it I I like how
you took my lead on that one
go ahead take
number
40 no 23 do [ __ ] 23.
going with number 23
number 23 says do 10 push-ups then take
a dab
who you
oh it's my turn yeah
oh [ __ ] okay are you gonna do the
push-ups
oh what a badass um why not
people always go out on that one nobody
wants to do the push-ups I mean can they
be broken in the in the don't be a [ __ ]
teacher hell yeah 10 of them
one two
three four
five
six
seven
eight Echo second nine
ten good job
[Music]
don't we gotta take a dab too just say
take a dab at the end
yeah oh now you gotta take a dab damn
okay we'll wait on that did the Dome
[Music]
I don't know yeah you gotta take a dab
then you get the point
that was badass push-ups alone I already
gave you the awesome correct buzzer
and we already gave you the point
because we trust you
all right kill yeah
let's go with number four
number four says
do 19 spins in a chair then take a dab
Funtime grower gave you that one are we
gonna do it
yeah
a lot of spins in a chair
[Music]
foreign
Chileans I mean they spin by yourself
hi hi
[Music]
I like that chair that's just the
executive
I hope you're counting because I'm not
he's like only like three four
[ __ ] hey thank you panda for having
our back here
how many of those did you have to do 19.
19.
that's not as easy as it looks good girl
Panda said you got 15.
yeah well Panda's wrong
now we say 18.
that's okay we'll we'll do a leniency
here because I was [ __ ] up
all right take a day out there
oh it's been someone in hydrate girl
I trust you take the dab we got you she
did it
all right Tink
number three
number three ooh we're going low those
are usually the new ones
number three says
do your best celebrity impression candy
Queenie what you got
let's hear it
no no you don't have a toast
I've never [ __ ]
anybody over that didn't have it coming
to them I only have two things in this
world my words and my balls or I don't
break them for nobody
oh that was like a dope I love it
Scarface baby hell yeah
we got Queenie with the point we are at
kellyanne with seven Canon Queenie with
13. we've got five minutes left to the
game oh [ __ ] oh you're gonna have to
bust ass here Killian
welcome
all right let's go let's go with number
eight number eight says say the
alphabets
backwards in 60 seconds so if you fail
take a dab I gave you that challenge I'm
sorry
the y x w
v u
I don't even know the alphabet four
words
u t
s r q
you get stuck on the pee
this is [ __ ] you deck magician
let's look at Doc's face right now I'm
trying not to look at me
at all on that screen
does not exist
all right we are back to Canada Queenie
go ahead
got four minutes left of the game
number six
number six he says number six says
sing the first song that comes to your
mind you have 15 seconds
[Music]
[Applause]
all right Killian
we're gonna go with number 35 for you
number 35 says take a dab through your
nose and blow it out the opposite
nostril
I've been waiting to see this one too
this is the classic one Tinky all right
over there
jellyfishing on me man
feeling great bro my eyes are amazing
I'm like I want to cry
beautiful
I'm just vibing like I'm here
I'm with you barely
[Music]
starting to lose reality
I'm amazed I've done so well before
especially in the with the Techno
technological fuck-ups
I don't want to listen to myself
no Canon Queenie you guys don't really
understand what's going on but we
decided we were gonna collectively take
uh would you end up taking take
about five ten or fifteen what the [ __ ]
is going on
y'all too [ __ ] up
dude I've been
uh five and a half broccoli did you do
five and Jesus Christ I said I'd match
you oh no
[Music]
well you called me I originally said
five so I went back on it I thought
that's what we were doing I had to be
about
dude
we got a minute left
I can't hear you you just look
like what
the [ __ ] what are they called Oompa
Loompas
what'd you say dick what number
24 24 okay there it is number 24 says
lonely
smoke your Banger like a pipe without
the rig
so you gotta take you got the Banger out
of your rig and you gotta heat it up and
smoke out the end of the joint
yeah yep
okay hold on I gotta be safe
yeah it takes like I've been waiting for
this [ __ ] dude I've been confused
you're gonna spray me with it why the
get that [ __ ] out of here I don't want
to be sprayed with a water bottle
what the dogs are spraying you
pay back [ __ ] no my girl just
go try to spray me with a water bottle
don't know why
she aimed his name
where's my
damn it
foreign
yeah
don't even remember what the question
why this video you [ __ ] did
oh man that was awesome
congratulations to both of you this was
an epic [ __ ] episode to do or dab uh
if you guys want to we'll probably have
an after party over in the voice chat if
you don't want to don't worry about it
um but awesome [ __ ] episode to do or
dab because I'm out I'm disconnected I
probably will too for at least a little
bit uh you guys are [ __ ] awesome
thanks for joining us uh Kelly Ann you
ended up with eight points can a Queenie
with 14 leaving Canon Queenie the
ultimate winner of this do or dab
competition let's give it up to her not
only that but you guys won some seeds
too
uh
at this point
we're gonna have to we'll do the drawing
on a voice chat later for the for the
patron member but we've got three packs
here that you can choose from some seeds
from our man boogie chunks that we just
did uh interview with yesterday you guys
can pick from one of the three all right
so you get to pick
first can a Queenie do you want the
skunk Tech sour with the lemon G and the
GMO fuel
do you want the Lesotho which is a like
a land race from Africa crossed with the
cam de la cam
or you can get the flow Screaming Eagle
OG across the dumps uh 88 or the
dumpster hash plant Screaming Eagle OG
I'm gonna
I'll let you pick doc
they'll make me do that right now don't
make me make decisions
just pick one pick one
do it
one two or three that what what Vibes
with you more like hashy indica
uh or like sativa sour
uh
hashy Indica you got it you got it all
right and that leaves kellyanne you're
gonna get some seeds of the skunk Tech
sour lemon G crossed with GMO fuel
awesome good job ladies thank you for uh
joining me for the Stewart dab it was
[ __ ] epic Tink thank you as well
brother for joining me you know physical
and Spirits
yes so I can take got it kellyanne we're
gonna have words later
that make me think
yeah you did good you get did good I
mean there's no no telling how the words
are gonna go but uh I appreciate y'all
and we'll catch y'all later this is an
awesome door dab don't be a [ __ ] in the
distance
[Music]
[Applause]
you know we got what you need baby
[Music]
I said we got what you need
come on
wow
[Music]
come on
come along
[Music]