good morning everybody and welcome to
the khaled crew podcast we have an
amazing episode for you today we've got
canna queen genetics on the line all the
way over from the east coast a female
breeder that's here to promote herself
to talk about some of her genetics her
history with the plant in her history
with breeding cannabis before we get
into the episode i want to give a quick
shout out stoner days apparel you guys
can go over to shop.stonerdays.com
and use code calyx that's all caps
c-a-l-y-x
at checkout for a whopping 20 off your
order shout out stoner day's fit
[Music]
now
let's just jump right into it we've got
canna queen on the line how you doing
canna queen
hey doc i'm good how are you good very
good we got a beautiful [ __ ] day over
here the weather is starting to heat up
it's amazing outside got some chernobyl
in me this morning did you get an
opportunity to smoke
yes absolutely i always make time for
that nice and what were you smoking on
this morning
the queen way hayes i've heard a lot
about the queen white ace i know what
wisco tree fire was telling me about it
you sent us over a pack of it i'm stoked
to pop those but miss c got in on those
zombie unicorn right off the bat oh yeah
that zombie uniforms uh there's one
other garden growing it's definitely um
more in the testing phases but it's a
fun stream
nice
so i wanted to talk to you a little bit
about your history with this plant when
did all this come about when did you
first start smoking
um i think i first started i actually
remember the very first time i smoked or
smoking on like an abandoned school bus
in like this fishing town
and
yeah everybody was like all like you
know their eyes were [ __ ] and like they
were giggling and i was just like what
is wrong with these people
so you know i realized that you know i
guess maybe you know
that first time you don't get high i
don't know maybe i just didn't realize
that i was high i don't know
but just
i didn't get high my first time either
yeah yeah like it's a common thing i
think but then it's like how can you not
like what is
it's like maybe what is wrong with you
maybe your endocrine cannabinoid system
is like so empty because you've never
you know fulfilled it that that first
high goes straight into your receptors i
don't know it's kind of crazy to think
about yeah or those receptors don't know
how to react to what's going on for the
first time you know
yeah could be it could be yeah so my
first time nope didn't get high second
time i
uh slept for like 18 hours
nice
do you remember what you were smoking on
actually back then i was just like it
was like the [ __ ] or you know um bc bud
or you know what i mean so we never
really know we're spoken but it was like
right in the air where the cannabis
started changing from like the mexican
brickweed all the time to like actual
like christmas tree buzz and the mango
stuff and you know that's when it
started like really blooming that's
about the time that i started as well
like when you start going from green bud
to actually having some names like white
rhino and stuff like that um i remember
when we actually started calling it
names other than oh this is chronic this
is mers you know
and i i think the west coast merch is
the equivalent of the east coast
uh would you say [ __ ]
yeah like the crippy the
yeah was that
hydro or
iconic you know what i mean there was
just like a blanket name for him
yeah we called it either hydro or
chronic that whole that whole [ __ ] thing
the crippy that seems to be an east
coaster i'm just not familiar with it
but i'm here yeah i was born and raised
in florida so uh it was definitely more
of an east coaster thing but a lot of
people it started moving you know it
started moving everywhere to new york
and um california and stuff like that so
nice all right so how old were you at
this point
i think i was probably about
15 turning 16 something like that okay
okay
so
at what point did you go from smoking
cannabis to saying i want to grow this
for myself
so i do have to rewind a little bit a
little bit after i started smoking
cannabis i started realizing that some
things were changing as far as like my
brain chemicals i wasn't i wasn't as uh
i don't want to say sad but like i had a
pretty tough childhood and i went
through a lot and it wasn't the best
home life and so every time i smoked i
really felt like it was doing something
different like it was touching my soul
and like i just i didn't smoke for the
same reasons everybody else said yeah
like i was gonna like be around my
friends like yeah we're getting high
like let's get high but like really i
knew it was doing something different
for me so the minute i had the chance to
uh pop a seat i did i think it was like
14 when i popped my first seed and tried
to grow it outside in florida i don't
know if you know about florida but
it's uh it's humid it's hot it's you
know hurricanes and so uh you know the
winds blew really hard blew my little
tree over and i was so depressed and sad
about it but
that was my little first experience and
then i married when i was about 18 and
we moved away from florida and we
traveled the entire country so
um i
yeah so i kind of like put that on the
back burner but we ended up landing in
colorado
at fort carson and he actually got
kicked out of the army for testing
positive for cannabis
so
he got a general yeah it really sucked
because it was our livelihood we lived
on post
um
anyway long story short he got kicked
out we ended up staying in colorado and
i'm like oh yeah like i'm gonna start
growing so
my friend's husband he was a military
veteran
and uh he was like he was already
growing so every time i go to her house
i'm like can i see it can i like just
see it i just want to look at it
right and uh finally she was like i
don't know you know he's not here he's
really protective blah blah blah
so finally one day he was there and he
was like hell yeah come on
so he took me in there and i i've never
felt such joy in my entire life seeing
what i saw in that that garage that day
so
nice what were what were some of those
first ones that you grew
so yeah so i ended up seeing his grow
room and i was like yep that's it i'm
growing so i linked up with a local guy
there
and he had a bunch of seeds reserved
saved up from his you know his dad from
like 80s to the 90s so we had like
elephant stompers strawberry cough and
wi-fi
og
ak-47 destroyer
um there was some really good classic
ones in there
and um so yeah that's a blue dream so
yeah that's like the strains that i
started up with my first row
very cool so you're growing at a young
age um you started smoking at a young
age how long
did it take you while you were growing
until you decide you know i want to make
the step in making some types of
cannabis that work for me
that i can produce for myself under the
name canoquin
so this isn't a story that i get to
share very often this is a story that
it's actually literally what sparked
my joy to do more than just grow and
i'll try to like make it short it's kind
of a long story but my neighbor he was a
retired not retired but he was he was
medically discharged from the army
he had ptsd and he had a lot of pain and
he had epilepsy and so he was having
probably about seven seizures a day on a
good day
and they were 25 years old and i just
watched this and him and his wife and
like they were trying to start their
life out and they were just stumbling
and falling and
um they were smoking spice at the time
which at the time was you know it had
been killing people
and so i'm like he can't be smoking that
he has epilepsy what's wrong with you
like
that's probably why he's having seven
seizures a day you know
so i grew a clone from that said uh
military veteran
that was my friend's husband it was ace
of spades and
i realized that it didn't get me that
high but like i knew i knew what that
meant you know like that it had some cbd
factors to it
so i offered him an ounce from like one
of my very first harvest
like real good harvest like i had a
thousand watt raptor eighties like
flying fan like i had the whole shebang
name drop
i remember
well you know that was at the time like
that was those are the [ __ ]
yeah
so i handed uh his wife an ounce of the
ace of spades and i said
tell him just to smoke this like put the
spice down just give this a a chance you
know
and it probably took about a whole month
for her to come to me and be like dude
he quit smoking the spice he started
smoking the aces you know the weed she's
like he's been 43 days without a seizure
i'm like
no way like literally that i knew that
wasn't my strain but i knew i wanted to
have that pride from something i created
it would be a medicine that you created
for a patient so
it doesn't matter
it was medicine that you produced that
you made and you helped somebody with it
that's
there's nothing better
yeah it was the most amazing feeling
that i had ever had so yeah he he ended
up you know getting a quality of life
back unfortunately they divorced and she
went on her way but there was a lot of
damage done between you know before he
he healed himself which you change you
know and things change but he i see him
today and he's he's healthy and happy
and it's just crazy so yeah that was
that was the fire that got started in
canada queen's soul
and uh so was that one of the first
plants that you bred with
actually no i didn't agree with that um
i got picked up by a state uh breeder in
spain
i'm not gonna name drop but like he he
saw my pictures on instagram and he
wrote me and he was like dude he's like
that's awesome and i'm like no it's not
a dude it's a she and he was like what
he was like i want you on my team he's
like he's like i ain't never seen a girl
grow like this before like what so he
was like i want to teach you how to
breathe and i was like dude i just got
you know good good at this growing thing
and you know i don't know if i'm ready
for that and he was like i'm backed up
and i just need you to f2 he's like i'll
help you make the selection but he's
like i need you to have to
uh this cbd straight and i was like oh
here's my chance you know it was like
destin you know like that is the cbd
strength a foot in the door for sure
yeah absolutely uh long story short i
did the breeding project i made three
little men gails that was my very first
strain it's a three to one cd
it has 11 to 18
it is um harlequin times tsunami or sour
tsunami times an unknown west coast
stream he he had it listed as unknown
west coast strain and i i think that was
his way of protecting it at the time
um but he had it tested and um
yeah it tested that you know three to
one so
i was like
he got half the seed stock and then i
got half the seed stock and you know he
made a good chunk of money off of it and
we parted ways and he hooked me up with
another breeder and then i realized that
i you know these guys were using me to
breed behind the scenes for them
with no name and i was like nope this is
my time like i'm gonna step forward and
i ended up you know
partnership with
the other the second breeder and then
canna queen genetics was born in 2018.
that's awesome and at this time when you
were getting into it what what was some
of your main intentions on breeding
cannabis was it all cbd related
actually no that was really my only cbd
project i started going more towards a
very high thc
you know what was what the hype was i
was trying to go like towards the mark
where the market was going and
i had already bred
under a different breeder's name a bunch
of really killer strains so
ended up when we broke up i say broke up
because it was literally like when our
partnership broke up like we had to tr
you had to split equipment down the
middle and and all kinds of stuff it was
literally like a breakup
but i got the babies and he got half the
babies and then you know we we went our
separate ways
and so that's when uh queen hayes was
born
so that was the first staple strain that
made canna queen a name yes that is my
legacy strain for my company and what
was the cross on that
the cross on queen my haze is autoblanco
by bodhi which is the white times wookie
times miami heat which is exotic i mean
yeah exotics genetics and it is triple o
g times miami haze
oh very nice it was true to my roots so
you know i just knew that it was going
to be you know
originally it was supposed to be like a
white version of the black cave but i
really brought it more towards the og
side so it became more an og than i hate
but i would tell people in the beginning
the f ones and the f twos it was an og
haze all the way you'd find ogs you find
hazel you find og's with haze high and
you find hazel's og high it was kind of
cool
right and you know when i first heard
the name canna queen that was the first
strain that was for the first type of
cannabis that was thrown out there um to
represent you was everybody was saying
grow the queen white grow the queen
white grow the green light and uh i'm
going okay well maybe i'll pay a bit
more attention to this gal she's
obviously got something going on that
people love
what what's the flowering time like on
that you said it lean closer to the og
right
yeah it does lead to close to the og and
the flowering times are i mean i've seen
one harvest at 56 days
64 days 70 days um but mostly between 60
and 70 days is your sweet i feel like
cloudy half amber 20. definitely yeah
definitely leading towards that og side
that's a beautiful flower
it is it's so frosty like she definitely
lives up to her name like everything
about her except for the haze but the
high does come out and some of the
phenos the haze high but uh yeah
especially she's definitely more of a
heavier high and then like i sing on the
cake the um the trichomes is the icing
on the cake because when you press her
she'll give you a 30 or 32 return like
every time
every time yeah that's beautiful and
what's the terp profile like on her
so
i have f1 f2 f3 v2 and bx1 but when when
you get to the x1
it is i locked in that piney
lemony like um like it's like almost
like murphy's oil there's some that have
like a like a burnt rubber tire um terp
to it so
yeah it's pretty big
one of the things that i like asking all
the people that i interview or all the
breeders i should say that i interview
um
is what top three to five strains best
represent your company and what you're
trying to accomplish obviously that
queen white haze you said that is the
staple of canna queen uh genetics is
there any others that just you're really
trying to promote and put out there
so i'm just gonna say like as far as
like crowd favorites um the crowd
favorites are definitely definitely
queen white haze number one uh lemon
delight number two
uh blue tree stars probably number three
uh three little nightingales
oh it's so hard that nightingale was one
that you made with the breeder over in
spain yeah the three little nightingales
with an f3 of his strain the nightingale
so you recreated that
and took your i made that train out of
my selection yeah and i changed the name
because i don't good i don't think it's
right when you stomp on and i say stomp
on but you could be making it better or
making it worse you don't know until you
you know into the progeny but
it deserves a new title like i always
stay true to the strained lineages it's
somewhere in the name you know so
what about that lemon delight what's
the lineage on that one
okay so lemon delight
is uh it's a queen's treat actually
that's what i named you know that's what
the name is about but it's lemon right
now by swamp boys which is
lemon tree times gmo tk skunk
that's nice yeah it's very nice yeah i
would i would have to say that if you
like a longer flowering one she's you
know for you she's probably a 12 to 14
weaker just depending on what female
we're all about
yeah but i'm talking like lemon tree all
day long like fresh lemonade stand grind
like i don't know she's just phenomenal
but there's also like a gmo pheno that
they love
lefty's farm
uh did a collab with me
um on operations bro season two they did
a blind girl and they found out what
strain they were growing halfway through
so it ended up being the lemon delight
f2
and lefty had at the time was doing um a
phenomena of the tkno5 haze by ak
beanbrain
and he hit his best lemon delight with
the
tkno5 haze mail
oh wow well yeah so he sent me almost
all the seeds that he had made which was
a bunch
and something kept telling me to pop
them so i did
and i guess i would you know i guess you
don't think about this when you're
trying new strains that you've made
you're just like yeah i'm about to you
know smoke it and taste it
but i actually did it live on instagram
i smoked a mess up and it was it was
phenomenal it was amazing the smoke was
great i was sitting there i'm like yeah
i feel great
it ended up being called
oh oh sorry so menage a delight is the
name of the strain and then we had to
nickname it mess up like like that
matches
like you know i feel really energetic
i'm gonna go get some stuff done and
i'll see you guys later see you next
time whatever so i get off the phone and
like 10 minutes later i kid you not my
heart was beating out of my chest i was
like
did you hear that like did you hear that
like something's outside it's like broad
daylight i'm like oh my gosh so i have
never in my life had to smoke cbd to
come down from flower ever in my entire
life so i knew something was up at this
street i didn't touch it for a whole
month after that so
it was caring and i was telling all my
people i'm like nope stay away from that
that's messed up that strain is messed
up you know
and so it kind of stuck you know and
then they all wanted it they're like we
want to grow i'm like no i just need to
come with a disclaimer like if you have
heart problems this strain is not okay
for you i feel like it's
it sounds like tyson trying to say
messed up
yeah yeah definitely
it's funny that you brought that up
about taking cbd to bring you down from
a strain um a lot of people have their
you know
withholdings about cbd and its efficacy
but one of the things about cbd is it
needs that thc with it in order to
activate in order to touch those
receptors and be effective right
so yeah the entourage effect you know
the t the cbd piggy backs on the thc and
vice versa so they don't really work as
well without the other um but there's a
few things you can do if you get too
high
you can chug a beer because like alcohol
is a depressant so if you're like really
really high and you you're freaking out
because you know a lot of people
aren't used to this medical grade stuff
you know what i mean like they're like
what what'd you do to it it was fine
before like it's too strong that stuff
hits different now
um so you can chug a beer or you can
smell pepper
pepper does something to your brain
where i i can't really under i'm like
i'm like not a scientist it must be that
karyo filing it has to be so
yep pepper and then um
cbd and people just they just shun cbd
like oh never nothing without pepper
yeah definitely
you know what's funny about that
we're doing an event in seattle at
hempfest and there was a booth there
that sold cbd
like i don't know if it was isolated or
it would said full spectrum um but
hipfest doesn't allow you know any thc
over there but he had these cbd dabs and
then he had extract terpenes so you
could add
whatever flavor profile you want to the
cbd
and right before that miss c and i had
we were passing around this big old one
ounce joint that i had rolled um and we
were sharing it three coved days and we
were just high as [ __ ] it was amazing
and i was with my brother that doesn't
smoke cannabis at all like he's never
done a drug in his life so we're just
ripped on this one ounce joint and then
we go to this booth and i said well i'll
try the cbd dab we sat down he had a
little e-nail on it we put the isola in
there we picked my terpenes i think it
was peach or something like that but i
took just an enormous rip and it was so
smooth
that i just kept puffing on it kept
popping on it i was fine and then i
stood up and he's like well what do you
think
and i said
it sucks
and he goes what do you mean it sucks it
looks like he enjoyed it i said i'm not
high
at all i smoked a one ounce [ __ ]
joint and you just made me waste it
so that that's my testimony to how well
cbd can work it's just how you use it
yeah so i just looked it up real quick
about the pepper and it says it's not an
old wives tale
if you're battling a bit of thc induced
anxiety paranoia your body suggests
sniffing or chewing on black peppercorns
a few sniffs immediate effect while
chewing peppercorns could provide a
relief for about an hour
so that's really cool oh wow
up to an hour that's actually
sniffing some pepper
very nice all right we're gonna take a
short break
for on a short break i want to give a
quick shout out to diamond cut company
you guys can go over to diamond cut
company and use doc minus 10 for 10 off
your order
since making the switch over to diamond
kit company i have not
wanted to use anything else they meet
and exceed every expectation that i have
in a trim so there's some of the most
beautiful trimming scissors ever they're
like a piece of jewelry
and they keep their edge forever as long
as you keep them clean they have tons of
different models the classics which i
use to chop up my buds i prefer not to
use a grinder when i'm rolling a blunt i
prefer of course to grind so i use the
classics to chop up my butt they also
have the 6'5 which incorporates the
finger loop and it is spring as well i
use those as my general handyman
scissors they also have the pros which
have a rounded and grip and a heavier
spring and i can actually use those for
physically taking down smaller plants
anything from like a one to three gallon
they usually seem to be pretty well with
um as well as de-stemming before the
trimming process
my favorite model though is the
harvester they come in both gold and
silver they're springless so you can
trim it as fast as your hand will fly
and since there's no resistance against
your hand it also means less fatigue and
longer trimming time
miss c's favorite model is the artisan
the artisan does have a spring and it's
very comparable to a lot of the
top-of-the-line models
that most companies use but i find that
the artisans have a lighter spring which
again leads to
less canned fatigue and longer trimming
time
as well as a more comfortable grip and a
sharper edge
so one last time shout out to diamond
cut company you guys can go over there
use doc minus 10 that's doc
minus 10 for 10 off your order
all right let's get back with canna
queen genetics
hey everybody and welcome back to the
calyx improve podcast before the break
we were talking to canna queen genetics
about her experiences with this plan at
a young age her experiences getting into
growing and how she got introduced to
breeding
we also talked about some strains that
best represent her company and she was
shouting out that lemon delight sounds
delicious the queen white haze everybody
has recommended that to me so i'm stoked
to pop back in here with canna queen and
talk more about what she's got coming up
in the future
what is going to happen with canada
queen community
i
i can't say what didn't happen with
canada queen genetics but i would like
to think that
we will be operating somewhere in a huge
field of dreams with warehouses full of
magic
everybody wants that
exactly um but for now
i'm just forwarding working these lines
like really just putting in the putting
in the work and um eventually you know
my my strains would be my talking for me
and we'll see where that takes us but i
am actually explaining
the triplex candy and the xxx candy was
a special project i had gotten some
pollen from a friend
of the doll forbidden candy is
aficionado aficionado strain it's a
skittles times royal kush times highland
afghani super hashy super fruity
beautiful plant so i hit
the x18 times the white by white buffalo
sea company with it and i created the
xxx candy
the male was the most impressive
impressive plant i've almost ever seen
he was
he was covered in trichomes he was
colorful he definitely had more of a
skittles leaf trait but i didn't really
see that come through
as that as much on in the f2s because
they favor the x18
nice what colorations were you getting
in the fade oranges and burnt umbers and
reds and um plums oh it was just
phenomenal actually i have it listed on
my ig
keratin doesn't get enough appreciation
everybody loves the the dark purple the
black fades but i've always had like a
special place in my heart for the
oranges and reds
i actually have a special place in my
heart for the males they do not get
enough appreciation they don't get
enough
face time they don't get enough credit
um yes we need females i think they're
obviously important but i think they're
not funny that you say that as we're
talking to a female breeder
the males do not get enough respect
and what's
is the females in this industry it's
vice versa with with like physical life
and this community and industry the
females just don't get
the credit that they deserve um and a
lot of females just don't even stand
stand up they don't stand for it because
uh they're intimidated it can be very
intimidating to be in a sea full of
it's definitely a
dominated industry yeah
yeah
no it's okay it's okay most men are
[ __ ] we can throw that out there and
it's not me sticking up for the females
here
i can be an [ __ ]
yeah
everybody can be dazzled
not not so much [ __ ] but like
they're
when i decided this was going to be my
job i was like hell to the yeah i don't
have to deal with all these you know
any women like hating me because you
know whatever and then i get that same
thing that i i thought i wasn't gonna
get here
yeah it's just hard to we face a lot of
adversity and i'm not i'm not like a
feminist i don't know i'm not like power
to the vagina but if you guys would just
give us half a [ __ ] chance and you
would let us work with you you would see
that
we bring something to the table that you
never could we were creating it's
definitely something that shouldn't be
gender related at all especially when
women
naturally
pay more attention to things than men do
it's those fine details you know that
comes with that that whole nature versus
nurture um where i might go into my grow
room and say you know oh well you're a
little soggy you know i'll give you or
you're a little droopy i'll give you a
little bit of water and i'll catch you
later
miss seal actually like go through and
look at him make sure everything's good
um she's kind of like my second pair of
eyes and she's a little bit more
detailed than i am and she catches
things that i just don't catch
and that you know on that point a lot of
people discredit like for me me for
instance because i'm more of a
intuitive instinctive type grower and
breeder like even though i'll see two
plants and i'm like yes seemingly you
guys are perfect for each other you have
everything but like there's things
under recessive things that you cannot
see that you could bring up so like even
though i do pick the two best plants you
know in my opinion as far as breeding i
also go with my second choice that's
like in the back of my head like you
should hit those two like they're not
perfect but you know what i mean like
and nine times out of ten that second
cross i make that version 2 that i make
is
is the one that i end up going with
so
i definitely
agree with that i think there's
plants that when you smell that terpene
profile it hits certain receptors in
your brain that
when they turn you on they make you
happy and they make you feel good and
you have a good feeling about that plan
that's definitely something that you
should investigate further because
obviously there's something about that
whole makeup
of that cannabinoid profile in that
particular phenotype that's just saying
it's calling to you
yeah i think too with a lot of breeders
they're breeding more towards like their
own their preference only and that's i'm
a firm believer in making three versions
if you need to of the same cross if if
you can if you have the selections i
definitely encourage making more than
one version because one version could be
for you and one version could be for
your mom and one version could be for
your sister it's like
i just don't want to single out just
what i want and i think that a lot of
breeders do that and i'm not saying
that's bad i'm just saying maybe that
makes me a more thorough breeder when i
hit more than just what my selections
would be right right i feel like there
that is or few and far between um but
there is a couple breeders
that like isolating oh yeah absolutely
i'm for that too
i just really love variety so much and i
have a very
a very uh dependable test team so they
love it when i send different versions
of the same strain
very nice very nice who who all do you
have on your testing team would you like
to give a quick shout out
i actually have about 19
of my gardening team i know i know it's
grown over the years i've really built a
like a little family
it's really awesome
and i'm gonna forget some so i hope they
don't kill me but um smurf and the stone
uh wawa canna girls tulkas
grim smurf banks
dubs
i just have so many and they all bring a
different factor uh and they're all over
the country too so i have some in
scotland i have some in south africa uh
shout out delta nine um and and shout
out forbidden high teledai farms in
scotland so it's really cool to see the
different um phenotypic expressions
especially the south africa he grew the
women delight and it i mean
black the leaves of the queen i mean the
women delight were completely black
it was it's just a stunning plant
cool cool and what do you got that
you're working on right now
so yeah i kind of got off base but yeah
i'm doing the triple x candy
f3's i'm doing the queen white haze back
cross
one with the smurf and stone cut
smurf in the stone won the dylan queen's
grow off which was my
my third grow off that i had run on my
own
and he won with the queen white haze so
i used his cut to back cross
at f4
yeah so that's what i'm working on right
now
very nice and what was it about that cut
that just did it for you that you said
this needs to be the backdrop so
honestly i wasn't i wasn't that sold on
it just because of how she looked but
she was
every time he grew her he grew her like
different so he grew her in a greenhouse
and she hit she was like rainbow like
her fade was just rainbow like her bugs
have this purple undertone underneath
the leaves is purple
um super frosty super dense um but every
time he grew her it was
better and better and then the the last
time he grew her she
um had like this merlot
like almost like a brick red color like
oh my gosh she was magnificent i said
you know what smurfs center to me
she's been screaming at me for three
years now just said her to me and we'll
we'll collab on a back cross oh wow it
took three years for you to agree on
that one huh well i wanted to see what
else you know there was a lot of people
growing her and there was a lot of
different phenos i mean i was seeing the
same ones you know throughout the mix
but this was the one that was just like
maybe
do you keep your lines pretty open or
are you more into bottlenecking into a
certain type it sounds like that you
like your variations so you're trying to
keep your lines a little bit more open
but you're giving the people that want
the option of the best
you know type in your opinion to be able
to select for that too
yeah so uh for a long time i only had
about 14 strains released and
behind the scenes you know every time i
was flowering i was breeding so i have
about 50 or 55 strains that i've
actually created
um and i just released 47 of them so
these are strains that some are f2 some
are at f1 somewhere at f4 or so you know
what i mean it just depends on what
strain it is but um everybody there's
something for everybody
nice very nice what else are you working
on that you're you're really stoked
about
i had gotten some seeds from a friend in
the emerald um
i didn't want to call it murder mountain
emerald triangle
and he sent me some double energy and
i'm literally like i i love og so i
popped those i found a male and i found
a female of the double og so i did a
binary cross i did
a male double og to the female queen of
haze and then i did a female queen white
haze to them
vice versa because like i'm dyslexic so
like my brain flip-flops it for me
anyway i did binary so whichever you
know i flipped it with the other cross
and so i'm excited about those those are
that we just named the strain it's
called lorena del sur which means queen
of the south
very
very that sounds beautiful yeah yeah i
thought so too so
this what made you decide to work with
uh the purple wookie oh man i actually
have just to like
i just have to say this i got the me
body i got to tell him that my signature
strain was made with his ore blanco i
was like are you bringing some more back
like where are they they just
disappeared you know it's now
now it's like my second top strain i've
ever grown and bred with um
one of my strains i've actually replaced
it but i got to talk to him i got to
pick his brain i got to show him um some
of the phenos that i had and
so you know he did pull the wookie and i
absolutely was dying to work with some
kind of skunk some kind of you know
roadkill killstones but not from
certain people
so i saw bodhi had the roadkill unicorn
and he crossed it to the wookie and i
was like oh you know i like lookie too
like he knows the way to my heart
through his trains
yeah wookie's almost in everything that
i have like literally it's somehow well
obviously if the queen went hazelnut
wookie's in it you know so
i i had heard about the wookie for a
while
um and then that name kept popping up
wookie wookie wookie and uh
i'm going a lot of people a lot of
people think that it's the white times
cookies which it's not
it's lavender
times appalachia and a lot of people
when they say the white times cookies
i'm like ew why would you do that why
would you even think that
but i get it like if you just take the w
and you put cookie you know what i mean
i get it but maybe there is a wookie
cookie but you know not
not wookie
right right
yeah we got
to try for the very first time i think
it was the purple look that's what it
was um and i said okay well i finally
have the opportunity to try some lookie
and
i didn't know what to expect out of it i
didn't know that much about it other
than that name kept popping up and after
we smoked the purple wookie i was like
this is something i would grill this is
beautiful
and the high isn't scamp either like oh
yeah it's a nice even high
so okay so purple wookie is roadkill
unicorn bookie but if you break down
roadkill unicorn you got roadkill skunk
then you have blackberry widow so that's
where you get all those berries you know
undertones and stuff from and you
definitely get that widow too like that
i call it halitosis that's the only way
i can explain it to people who can't
smell it but it's like bad breath like
that's what widow smells like to me
i always thought
to me widow was very like
muskie earth
yeah i think yeah that could be it could
be chalked up to earth yeah i guess i
just i really get like a
it's not really gmo bad breath
yeah that's true yeah yeah so true
that's what i'm saying like i just
explained it exactly like if it smells
like a porta potty cake i'm going to
tell them it smells like a quarter body
kit because
how old are they gonna like yeah
yeah so your perception out there no
matter how bad it is and honestly i'm
one of those people that if the worst
you make it sound the more i want it
yeah or the more you can relate oh i
know what a bunt rubber tire smells like
and i know what lemon smells like so if
i put those two together yes that's
something that i would like
yeah for sure
i remember i remember being a a younger
punk and uh stealing some of my mom's uh
vodka
and we took a swig off of it and my
brother goes well what do you think it
tastes like and i said well it tastes
like [ __ ] tastes like oil lamp oil
and he goes how do you know what that
tastes like
i don't but that's my perception
so yeah so then when people say that
like how do you know what that smells
like dude how do you know what it tastes
like it's like because you can your
smell can translate to taste that's how
that's why you're given those senses
like
absolutely absolutely
well we love talking to you canna queen
thank you so much for coming on the
podcast um before we end this is there
anybody that you would like to shout out
sponsors
um what have you
uh first of all thank you so much for
having me on i really appreciate that
you're giving me a little
stand for my voice and and that's super
important to me so i really appreciate
that i really um had a great time and um
i did shout out my carson but one more
time they i wouldn't be where i am if it
wasn't for
their thorough testing and growing for
me so thank you guardsman and uh also my
friend johnny nuggs will be vending at
any can
uh beanstalk and beancon
at the fish [ __ ] booth so shout out
fishit and johnny nuggs that can logic
inc and
also my soil is so very generously
sponsored by bio365 my rap bio 365 tim
amazing people
very knowledgeable backed by science
check them out
i've seen great things with those that
soil
beautiful beautiful work
weren't you also doing a
a contest for people that were growing
your your types oh okay so uh yeah in
april i'm having the first annual canada
queen cup it's actually a private sesh
for the first annual just to you know we
can iron out some kinks and stuff but uh
we're doing a blind judging everybody
who's coming um has has grown uh some of
my gear and we'll be blind judging that
uh we'll have prizes we've had some
prizes sponsored by what the [ __ ] wisco
tree fire for the slaps and some i like
how you say that too
what the [ __ ]
yeah we have to definitely give him a
little spotlight and i didn't mention
him in my garden but is it it's not
actually what the [ __ ] though is it's
just wtf
right yeah oh yeah so yeah i guess
that's just how i read it every time
that's how i read it yeah every time he
pops into my life i'm like what the [ __ ]
was go tree fire and he added that later
and i was like oh it stands for wisco
tree fire but i still to this day call
him what the [ __ ]
yeah he's just a solid solid solid guy
good friend and um definitely make some
amazing
um slaps he prints so
definitely check them out
so at this cup that you're doing the
first ever
cannabis queen cup
is that the name right
can a queen cup yeah
what is the is there some kind of
incentive is there prizes for somebody
that wins this
yeah so we're gonna have all kinds of
prizes
going to be playing all kinds of games
uh there's going to be like a joint
rolling competition uh i don't really
want to give away all the details but
there's going to be prizes that we're
buying instead of like a trophy we're
buying like dab rigs and stuff for game
winners and um the some of the
competition winners and stuff so
yeah very nice 365 was actually
yeah bio365 was actually so generous it
sent me a 10x4 banner with like their
logo and my logo
awesome that's very cool
so anybody that wants to get into this
can of queen cup over on the east coast
what are the credentials like what do
you have to is there any rules to it
otherwise it's gonna be a traveling
event i decided that we didn't want it
to be a stationary event um this year
it's obviously in michigan um and next
year we're planning on it being in
oklahoma and then possibly new england a
year after so it's gonna be a traveling
event yeah and um yeah i mean you
definitely have to grow we're gonna do
an overall best cannabis of the entire
weekend so
it doesn't even have to be my gear but
we're gonna do two separate you know
competitions so okay one can of queen
only genetic
and then one whatever you want
right right yeah so you know people who
maybe didn't get to grow or didn't get
to harvest in time you know they still
get to bring something and get to
compete
just a good time very cool sounds like a
fun time i always love a good joint ruin
competition hell yeah
all right thank you for coming on cannon
queen we appreciate you and we
appreciate what we what you're doing in
cannabis yeah thank you so much and uh
you can check out my check out my
website pianocleangenetics.com
and you can um hit me on my email for a
full menu at canon mafia420 gmail.com
you're also on
instagram correct instagram you've got
canna underscore queen underscore
genetics underscore code
very nice very nice well thank you for
coming on we appreciate you so much
[Music]
and that's the show everybody i want to
thank canna queen again for coming on
for sharing her story who she is i urge
you guys to go over to instagram go over
to her website check her out pick up
packed seeds
and see what she's working with this is
a female breeder that is putting in tons
of work
that wants to get her name out there and
rightly so deserving it some beautiful
plants i've seen coming out that queen
white haze absolutely beautiful some
lemon delight i've seen all kinds of
pictures from tons of growers that are
growing her genetics yet her name just
isn't getting out there which i find
absolutely astonishing shout out to anna
queen i hope we can get her back on the
show one day see what she's up to in the
future before we get going i urge you
guys to share the show with a fellow
grower is the lifeblood which is going
to keep the calyx and crew podcast
pumping your support means the world to
me
also don't forget to go check us out on
patreon and discord our membership start
at a mere 10 a month with membership you
get access to our form our discord and
we have 24 7 help there for you
i'm joined by my amazing team guys we
have grow green daddy over there helping
us with content creation we have husky
genetics who's going to be doing the
ever hilarious do or dab with us as well
as a synthetic cultivation class called
why so salty we also have my good friend
farmer fly over there doing the wake and
bake wednesdays with us
very very excited and we hope we see you
over there thanks for joining us thanks
for supporting and watching listening to
the show over all these years this is
doc alex saying good night
you