good morning everyone and welcome to
another exciting episode of the calyx
and crew podcast i'm your host as always
doc calyx i'm very excited to introduce
that we've got an east coast breeder on
the line today my good buddy maddie from
solo farms is on the line he's going to
be talking to us about some of the
cultivars that he's got in stock
his plans for the future and what he
does as far as breeding for hash
returning cultivars it's going to be a
very cool one before we get into it
though i want to give some love to an
affiliate of the show coconut sensors if
you guys want one of the best
environmental sensors for under 100
push to app notifications available in a
ton of different languages for anybody's
growing style go check them out at
coconut.com that's
k-o-k-o-n-a-u-t dot com use code calyx
that's all caps c-a-l-y-x
for 10
off at checkout i would also like to
give a quick shout out to all my patrons
over on patreon their subscription is
really the backbone behind what keeps
this content going which has me creating
new episodes putting more out from
building the discord the patreon and
everything that we do bigger and better
it's been awesome it's been an amazing
ride so far it's really picking up steam
and i've got nothing but love for these
guys they are my a number one they get
my full attention anytime they have grow
problems i'm over in the discord helping
them they get q and a's with podcast
guests behind the scenes content that
nobody else gets to see do or dab where
they win seats we had duke diamond on
there last week and he was giving away
some of his genetics awesome genetics
from an awesome breeder great experience
great time if you guys are interested go
check it out patreon.com forward slash
stock underscore calyx one more time
that is patreon.com
forward slash doc underscore couch
simple ten dollars a month you get a
show support for one of your favorite
podcasts
all in the meanwhile getting a ton of
extras ton of exclusives that nobody
else gets
now let's jump right into the episode
i'm really really stoked to talk to
maddie over here at solo farms
all right we got matthew from solo farms
online how you doing maddie i'm doing
good man how are you good good it's nice
to hear your voice nice to get to
finally talk to you for all my followers
that have no idea who solo farms is why
don't you give them a quick introduction
to who you are and what you do
okay
just matthew from solo farms i live in
maine
i
grow cannabis
as a caregiver hell yeah i also uh breed
genetics for cannabis
it's been
a huge passion of mine as far back as i
can remember
and that's why
i still do it i just love what i do i
enjoy it man
and we gotta do like small batch stuff
unique
cash makers and
extremely beautiful flour
with older things things that are unique
to just me or my area
of the country
and
put a different swing with some
familiar things that people know from
all over the country try to put my own
little twist on it hell yeah when were
those beginning phases when did you get
into growing cannabis
oh so growing
uh first time growing
uh i want to say that was
it was outside
and i want to say that was 1992.
just me and the buddy
had some seeds we found in bags you know
i mean that's what
you had seen back in the day and i was
like man i'd really like to see if we
could grow our own
and
during those years in the summer time it
was always a drought
so we're like well i'll take some of
these seeds and start growing
our own maybe we could supplement at the
end of the year you know
yeah just kids
yeah just young guys just playing around
and seeing what we could do
and i guess that's kind of sparked it
man because
we ended up
you know actually doing okay and first
time doing it like oh wow this is so
cool you know
and we just back then all you would see
is coming in a bag or a brick
and then to actually see the plant
looking like something we used to see it
in high times magazines
was just crazy to me
for sure
yeah what were some of those first
cultivars that you fell in love with
oh god
some of the first ones i want to say
like playing around with as far as like
like back then it was like mexican
indicators sativas you know
land racy stuff and then
we had some buddies that
up north in northern new england that
were doing it
a little bit longer like their dads were
or their family were
like my own
and we ended up getting a couple cuts
and stuff
and
you know through black market getting
seeds from different various ways
just
unique things i'd say rock bud was one
of them
from soma yep new york city diesel
and just so many god blood i mean
an adult vida
was that somas nycd
yeah that was a good one new york city
diesel
which i did earlier work with
unfortunately we never i took it to like
f2
and
because of that chem family
it just always seemed to carry
some hermaphroditic traits yep so we
just kind of left it alone
you would find some really nice things
but if you weren't adamant enough or if
you went away for the day
and came back and something happened it
just you know it was just something that
we didn't wanna and back then i just
didn't know enough to really
say hey stress test these things in
different ways you know and all the time
reading about it
obviously friends like
chris
helping
in so many different ways just dropping
these little knowledge bombs every once
in a while
on me during conversations
helped improve that and then asking
questions and then just going for it too
man yeah breeding cannabis is definitely
for looking for certain things is so
much different than just like growing
cannabis only for flower absolutely
so many different components to it
and you know hopefully i think a lot of
people when they get it if they crying
into it or even just like a novice just
home grower saying man these two things
are really nice and to be honest with
you everybody out
there that was that is a breeder or
upcoming breeder
we were all in that same spot at one
point
and just saying man these are really
nice
and
you know i think back then too a lot of
people were nervous about
ordering seeds online it was sketchy
yeah years ago i think certain people
were just making their own having
something that stood out in their area
and said hey we did this
you know and over the years obviously it
just has gotten so much more intricate
when i do it
i look for
depending on what i'm using and what the
i guess the end result
at least of that particular project is
as far as like a goal like an end goal
stability of male what does that male
and lineage bring to the table
it's
not just because of the strain that i
like
it has a lot of different components
medicinal value
everything like that man uh
is it a short growing plant that i'm
going to try to put it with and pair it
with as a female and this male
has a lot more vigor and i can open it
up and maybe get the
veg time a little faster you know
all those little different intricacies
yeah for sure yeah
the cool thing about breeding is i find
it's much like art like every breeder's
got their own little flair their own
little fling that they kind of throw on
things and that's kind of what attracts
us to these certain people i'm still
kind in those beginning stages still
learning about breeding
and one of the things that i've
definitely picked up is that when you've
got a project in mind you have to have
your goals right because you have to
have those boxes that it meets those
expectations and anything that doesn't
automatically make those expectations
it's gone right
yeah you can't waste a kid you don't
want to put any more energy and time
into it
absolutely so i wanted to ask you
for you what's your artistic touch what
are those boxes that you know every
project is going to have some a little
bit different is there anything that you
find that box is consistently going
through
all of your cultivar cultivars
everything that you're producing are you
going for terps are you going for
resin return
just so
always resin return
and terps
pretty much the the most important part
the medicinal part of that plant
don't get me wrong i love an amazing
flower
looking at amazing boutique
or artisanal style flower
especially nowadays in this new market
with so many stores
and people
it's so much easier for them to
go in and look at something pretty
versus you know catches their eye
it's beautiful yeah
the biggest thing for me with
let's just say the skittles blissful was
a product project that i did
that mail
just added figure
stack
that mail just stacked really well
um super resilient
to pests
lighting heat stresses
cold stresses
food stresses like
overwatering underwatering all those
different things just kind of chugs
right through not super picky
but the biggest
thing about him was adding resin
just really packing in resin in all
those little areas where
certain strains because of the
head size or the
just what it is
it's there it looks beautiful but you
know there's certain ones that just
really back in
right
that's really my biggest thing like i'm
growing for
cash
that's what i want
and hash
i love tasty beautiful
good producing
cash
that people are going to enjoy
and that growers want to grow because
they can actually get a yield
that was really something and just
because i paired them with certain ones
even though i
with all testing and then growing these
all out and then doing washes on
everything
doesn't mean that that my mail even
though i put it to it's gonna always
link up
right you know it's not a guarantee
nothing's guaranteed
i think
my
intention had some what to do with it
and then just
man it was a you know just putting in
the time
and really watching and and then also
picking specific
females that just had excellent
properties already and it's just like i
said i'll say it again it doesn't
guarantee you anything
but it's definitely a good step forward
and to
the end goal
i don't know man i wouldn't downplay it
too much i grew that mountain wizard
from you
and every single one of those females
was a resin hog
even at the end of the day that you
could get the best of each combine them
sometimes it just does not work right
like chris has told me so many times
like man we have all the right
intentions
and this is what i remember from this
one and then when you pair it up but
sometimes they just don't think well
yeah and
by the grace of god and a little bit of
luck
and with some foresight i guess and a
little help
man it just worked bro that's all i got
to do
and
the positive feedback and i guess you
know another thing that maybe helped too
is
before even
releasing these projects and showing
people
on the solo farms page like hey this was
the great buy this is this this is this
and showing them and then working with
those
products and then having availability to
them you know to keep people and
getting it out there so people can
actually try it and then know
and then i think
coming out with a product that i made
myself with some of these ones that they
were already enjoying
just kind of paired well man it just
worked out
brother
it just really did
i think about it a lot and i'm just like
wow you know
at least with that particular one
because
i did enough work with it but like i
said it doesn't guarantee you anything
now if i was talking about
maybe the grapefruit work epic
there's been so many years of that
since 2010 i mean i got me a buddy got
the seeds in 2005 for those
out at the uh amsterdam high times cup
and
i think around 2 000
9 10
is when we started playing around with
them
we did them inside outside
found some really nice things
found a nice nail
did some preservation where we could
keep more of the genetics and goats to
go through
uh for further work just because it did
so amazing
up here outside
it just seemed like man this thing's so
strong she's
super healthy super vigorous
man let's try to i think this would work
really well with some other stuff that
we have
you know at the current time
and
so we you know i think we brought it up
to
2015 we had about five years of work
with it
every year we did some populations of
inferior amounts
finally came and narrowed down to f2s
in
oh god i want to say we finished that up
in the fall of 2014
and then
chris had come out in 2015
for a mmcm show and
you know we were doing the seed booth so
he came out for the weekend and
just funny story he was like yeah i
brought this up let's try this and it
was charlotte's web
and one of his buddies
that was actually doing the extraction
had a cut of this grapefruit from steve
and it was amazing
so he was like hey instead of
me running mine separately why don't we
just put ours both together i think it'd
be super tasty and
really medicinal from the
charlottesville christmas like yeah sure
cool
so friday night we get out of the
show we smoke some and we're smoking it
all night
then saturday comes around and there was
a bunch of us
in the hotel room just hanging out and
we're smoking and i'm like man this
would be just kind of crazy
because i'm like you have the showers
yeah uh the charlotte's web and he's
like yeah i was like man i was like
you know as far as bro wise obviously
not medicinal wise
so he was you know giving me some
backstory on her and how it was for him
and
he was like man you know i'd almost
think about getting that cut and maybe
doing something with that i was like
well
here chris i got grapefruit f2s that we
have
and i'd love to put some in your hand
let's do like
let's do some collab work and maybe
hopefully end up finding something and
then read like let's make this straight
it's super delicious and it made us feel
good all weekend absolutely you guys
knocked it out of the park on that one
i'm really glad you brought that up
i think
one of the things that is my like
paintbrush to the canvas for me
is
a couple really good friends with
knowledge
me obviously having some heirs to listen
but my eye man
and i don't know where i got it from i
just have it
some people got it
an eye for cannabis man to watch how
these girls grow
and i guess i i i guess they can't kind
of came out of
necessity because in the building in the
beginning
when i first started doing this
having like you know smaller children
being super discreet limited spacing
yeah really paying attention to what i
needed and what i could use
so i guess that kind of help narrows
down those easter eggs quick when you
gotta get [ __ ] out because you need room
right
yeah and it just i think it heightens
certain senses more than others because
at least that's how i feel and
i think that's a
probably why some of it and then just i
love this plant man this plant is just
no matter what from a young age always
helped me
and so many other people around me
and i'm like man and obviously you know
as young kids
like mid 80s and through the 90s looking
at high times and you're seeing all this
and these guys are like wow they're so
underground and this is so cool like
we're getting brickweed back here but
these guys on cali are crushing it and
just seeing all those
different all the different expressions
of this this plant
and i'm like man i'd
i'd really love one day to be able to
say
i've found some unique things and then
things that are familiar to people
and i can maybe hopefully make
some of that for not only myself but
maybe to share
and then in sharing
um that's how it all started just like
making some beans super early projects
knowing what i'm looking for but
maybe not having a super end goal just
open expressions but knowing what's
there is really good
passing out a lot of free seeds it's
almost like paying your dues when you're
getting into breeding right
yeah and just like putting them into
people that i look kind of i looked up
to and then other people in my same
position or people that maybe you're
just starting out and saying here man i
know it's tight during springtime you're
gonna spend money on this and this this
this and this here's some seeds go try
some of these they've done really well
for me
hopefully you know we're in the same
climate and area let's see if you like
them too just adam you know just a few
of something different
and uh
i don't know just with that it just kind
of worked out really well you know
yeah just kind of fell into place i
guess little bits at a time it
definitely takes time i've been
extremely happy with everything that
we've grown from you and i don't want to
quite get off i could praise you forever
on the mountain wizard and we we're
definitely going to get into some of the
other stuff that you're working with but
i want to get back to that grapefruit
really quick
you
and p had completely different
cuts of the grapefruit right
what made what happened there
well chris ended up taking finding uh
an amazing male out of the f2 style
that i gave him
because at the time i was
building my new building and everything
and i said chris i got to kind of take a
backdrop of this but if you want to you
have an amazing eye and if i was going
to trust anyone
with these i would you know my brother
yeah
and um
and chris has that eye plus
so i knew that i was more than confident
that chris would take it to the next
level really and definitely do it
justice but keep in mind
of where i was going to
and keeping it open a little bit
and i think in the beginning chris he
kept it open and then you know seeing
some really cool
things that he had in his table like
that durbin
some of the older stuff and you know
with coming out with that new relic line
it just seemed to kill
it was just the right timing everything
just kind of in it and now you're at f4
right
um f4 is uh working i'm i actually
went back in on f2s
okay doing a large population
and f4s
and going back through now
hopefully we'll see how things are by
fall i should be able to start getting
the
f5s into testing is the
goal
whether
that completely works out is all on what
we're finding now
from those f2s to this f4 that you're at
now
what's changed in the in the phenotypes
and the or i should say genotype so
what's changing the genotypes are we
seeing more
like the sweet pink grapefruit are we
seeing more of both the sweet pink and
the inbred line type of stuff what's
going on so like when chris was doing
his
he had a certain
flavor that he was looking for
and he had a really nice sweet pinky
grapefruit
and he knew that's what i really liked
like
with like a little bit of funk in it and
i think chris was looking more of that
sour like
yeah funky grapefruit like
more gassy
and so that's where
he wanted to take
his part of the work
too
thus the relic grapefruit
using a
that same cut
that was in the oil that sparked the
whole thing up went back to that
mutual buddy and ended up doing some
work with that cut which was
thieves cut of the grapefruit
and i mean it all comes from that same
lineage even my seeds it's just i've
used stuff that i find
and what we enjoy right
when it came time to
do the f4s
i've only released
the a
uh version so i have a through d
on the f4s
and
i basically did it so i wanted to keep
my expressions open i didn't want to
bottleneck it into just one thing
because i want to
get these out there and see what
now i know what i like
but people that are grabbing my gear
they might want that open expression
because they've seen it
my version of it chris's version of it
and then obviously multiple hybrids
so what when i was
pairing females with that male i ended
up taking a sweet pink grapefruit that
was like short and stocky more
indica growth
and then a more sativa more faster
vigorous
female
on the sweet side
and
use those two and then
the other end of the spectrum that more
gassy
new york city like
diesely
red grapefruit look like a little more
sour
with the same stretch a short
indica stat with like a more stacked
internal spacing
and then something with
a little bit more of a stretch
and a little bit different of a spacing
so i could keep everything open because
as far as further project you know at
that time i'm like i don't
want to just make this one thing
like
this is how i'm gonna really find it
when i find it i'm gonna know
yeah i think that was a good approach
too because they all
like they were all great in their own
right that's for certain
yeah and you know and i just
i feel like
if i don't do if i didn't do that then
i'd be kind of
limiting myself and then other people
too oh absolutely and i want like i want
everyone to enjoy just the way
you know that these things caught my eye
i mean
and it's so funny the way it's trending
like the way cannabis trends
in the markets go like we've had these
for so long and smoking on it but then
everything went through with
cookies and then all the other different
hybrids and don't get me wrong i love
all of it i appreciate every strain
there for what they are so i'm never
gonna bash on one style
of breeding and or
kind of cannabis
like they're all they all have their
purpose
i agree
i think the grapefruit and me starting
to open up into breeding
and
i just felt like i should definitely
keep that going and keep it open because
it's kind of unique to
me and this other guy
he since i think he ended up selling all
his share
of his seeds from that season
and i wanted him for preservation i knew
what i wanted to do
and it was just like i don't ever want
this girl to go away
because i mean how many strains have
been lost because of not we know without
hindsight yeah and that's one that's got
to stick around i gotta say that's
probably still to this day one of my
favorite smokes of all time
yeah and i mean she's been around for a
long time and i think people kind of
like oh this is so good but then
you know some new things coming oh wow
this is so good too and it's natural
instinct
everyone's gonna i mean variety is
awesome it's the spice of life
but i also like something i can go back
to that's reminiscing yes and it's just
a flavor can take you back to a memory
in a good time you know
so it wasn't just about the strain it
was about those memories
it was a collective thing i i feel
and i think i would have been doing an
injustice of not keeping it around so
that's why
when i chose someone when if i was
anybody was going to work with it with
me would be chris like that's my brother
i love him
and
you know he loves that plant and i love
chris and i have the utmost admiration
for him because he he stays in his own
like he made his own way
yeah absolutely
everything that he has is so unique to
him and he doesn't sway
and don't get me wrong he's worked with
some stuff that's familiar with other
people too
because it's smart and to be honest with
you those very vanilla cookies and all
this cookie strains that platinum
cookies is fire oh fire as [ __ ] it's so
different than a lot of the other cookie
hybrids that are out there so still even
then even doing cookie strains like you
know learning from chris on those modes
like he's stayed so individual and true
inconsistent
super consistent
taking so many pages out of his book
and just dinner after dinner and
event after event with him and just even
just phone calls just
taking all of that
info end and just
getting that vibe too you know just you
could talk forever
so easy going so humble so open with
information too
but he's not scared to share whereas
like you know in the early years no one
wanted to tell anybody anything oh you
got to learn that yourself
and i think we've all gone through that
if you're
within a certain age i mean if you're 40
years younger you've definitely felt
that
oh yeah
for sure it's good to have somebody
around like him that's you know willing
to
willing to help out and he's always been
one of those people that he's over the
top he was one of the first people the
the first time i met him he put my kids
before anybody else he wanted to make
sure that they had juice they had drinks
they were ready they were happy before
we even started talking and it's like
god damn that
i mean it shows the character quality
you know
oh he's he's a genuine dude that's why i
love him man
he's such a good guy so i've taken so
many things with when i think of those
kind of relationships and then
working with my own personal stuff
i keep all those things in mind and it's
like i can't let these guys down because
they've never let me down
and i would be like kind of doing it
just justice if i did i think like
that's how i feel like
i can't do that like
and he was super supportive even before
i even decided doing anything
after the collaborative work you know i
talked to him and i said hey chris i
said
you know man i said now that i've done
what i've had to do with the building
and
all the caregiving stuff is well on its
way and all that stuff's kind of
whatever you know i'm really thinking
going back in on the true passion and
really doing some work with this
breeding and
i just want you to know that i'm gonna
definitely start going back in on these
grapefruits
and but i want to ask you and say
something to you because i know that
we've done some collaborative work and
you've already
released some things
and he was so good about he's like are
you kidding me why you do whatever you
want like you gave me these like yeah
and that's just the person he is but
me being the person i am i have to be
transparent i'm gonna ask right and if
he felt away like i said maybe we'll
just keep working on them
maybe we do some more collaborative work
with it or
maybe i had a different ver you know
vision for it
and no that was not the case
not at all
which made me even want to push even
harder with it good i'm glad you did
man i i am just so happy and grateful
that i'm getting
so much amazing feedback from everyone
brother like
and everyone's really enjoying them and
being supportive
and for the most part like anyone that
follows us like
really just is like hey these are just
amazing like
wow is everyone's like the buzz is going
around and the photos are coming out
people are actually getting to enjoy
some of the extracts and the flower at
their local dispen you know stores or
person and then obviously their own
personal experiences either growing in
their garden inside or outside it's kind
of just built itself and now that it's
going it i don't even know man i i still
i'm like man we just had this and we
were enjoying it
and no one really knew about it like we
all knew it was like true cannabis
enthusiasts and
that grapefruit was around but to have
like a strain and then work on it
locally
and then just like people locally like
you know that's it it's okay like and
then some people really enjoying it
but we really just loved it and it
wasn't just
and to be honest with you the f2s
super terpy
huge blobs
assurance the time on anything
that's figure like a
you can't believe
you shorten the time on it
oh it's short the time like anything
that that grapefruit touches shortens
the time they were already short when i
grew
so which ones did you have again
the relic grapefruit really great for it
the inbred line was a little bit longer
but the sweet pink i mean that that
stuck out like a sore thumb you know
that thing was just stacked up bushy
[ __ ] yielded like a mother
so i think when chris was doing that
relic i think because chris loves sativa
yeah it's his true passion and to be
honest with you i love sativa too
i'm the same
and
i think
that gassier one
of what i've seen out of populations
the gasier more acrid sour citrus
phenols are a little more stretchier
with a little more spacing
a little more
still having nice stacks though
beautiful stacked flowers but definitely
more stretching and i think that has to
do with just
that particular
version of the plant that you're looking
for that's what he likes so i believe
when he read it
you know certain characteristics just
remain
more dominant yes like i've done some
like my buddies have had even out here
there's been a lot of god what is the
fat
the hell is the name of that
male my buddy used
oh it's like it was a
kimbo kush
okay
and this kimbo kush no matter what it
touched
just was so that kimbo kush male was so
dominant that's all you would 95 of the
time that's all you was getting this
gimbal bush
whereas on these grapefruits
you're gonna pretty much see i mean
you'll even you can get some different
turf but pretty much for the most part
that is citrus
it is sweet pink grapefruit oh for sure
orange peel
and then that salary a little more
fuelly gassy like that soma
i definitely
found exactly what you were saying my
inbred line phenos they had huge inner
nodes we're talking like two three
inches but they have these rock hard
buds on them
now here's a funny story for you i'd
already been growing for quite a few
years by this point i already knew how
to take clones and everything but that
was the one that really told me take a
clone of everything because
the sweet pink was then obvious like i'm
taking a i'm taking a cut of this we're
going to test it out we're going to try
it out some more and you know see how it
reacts in different environments the
inbred line i wasn't as interested in
because those long inner noses like oh
god this is just a mess of a plant you
know but it smelled so [ __ ] beautiful
i was interested and it wasn't until
after i cut it down that i was like oh
my god this it's it's that
citrus sour that and not just citrus
sour not like a lemon sour it's got that
grapefruit [ __ ] beautiful sour you
know that's so i guess
that's the other thing so like when i
say hash and terpenes
and i kind of get this from like me and
chris share this
i'm a terrapore i love flavor i love
food i love just the smell things i love
to taste the different things
and just like with uh unique meals
and
you know they pair well with a bunch of
different ingredients that just
sometimes you look at them and you're
like what the [ __ ]
there's no way that's going to taste but
when you layer those flavors they do oh
yeah for sure so i guess my point when
i'm going with this is like on that
mountain wizard just to
say one
my hope
with the skittles and then that mountain
crop
was just getting layered flavors
like you're tasting one thing on the way
out and when you on the way in and then
when you blow out it's like what the
[ __ ]
dude that's so different like it's two
different sides
oh yeah going like bob ross on his
painting and saying happy little
accidents well there's that happy little
accident i guess that was a damn good
accident
you know and i said well all i got to
say man is
it was amazing genetics i paired them it
just worked out dude and with
definitely with some effort and i'm not
going to say that it wasn't
but who knew that that layering
that was my wish and what i was going
for as far as the therapy profile
and it just
hit it on the head
and it was just one of those like yeah
you know you take your fist and you
bring your elbow down like yeah i did it
like
it was you know and i'm usually not that
guy i'm like super like i'm just not but
man that was like yes
so we you know we rolled one up
obviously and
he took the first couple hits he's like
what the [ __ ] it this is like sweet
candy orange
it goes but when i blow it out it's like
a whole bag of skittles and
i didn't get it
but it could but it coats it
honestly one of my favorite ones that i
found out that madden wizard came out
it had such an interesting profile
a lot of them were happy heavy in that
orange
but i got one that had like a floral
soapy fresh mintiness to it it was
amazing and that one that one [ __ ] you
up
i believe in it i believe it so see
there's where those
that's the other thing that's super nice
about regular beans and with some of
these things the way they pair together
but
all of a sudden you're like oh where did
this off you come because like 80 85 of
the time you're gonna get like
one of the skittles all of the skittles
the orange the combination like
depending on the color you'll get very
different variations of color
maybe a little bit on calyx production
box failing and or like heart like some
are a little bit hotter
some are a little bit you know because
of that mountain drop like minecraft's
not a super hard blood but it's open and
it's a great hash maker
and the terps are just off the chives
yes whereas the z whiz was a really
stacked bud that was a lot more denser
with even more resin population
and then this super unique terpene
profile off the male just on the stem
and then made i have f2s in that as well
i did a limited release of those
and i still have i had eighth
oh god i had three of the females
and i you know kept those expressions
open too for further work
just to kind of keep aside and then i
wanted to put a few into some people's
hands and see
what they were finding before i go any
further
nice man
what's your idea behind pairing some of
these up you said you work with some of
the older stuff you don't mind working
with the newer stuff you're no shy to
that obvious
but what is it that like when you're
going after something where do you go
well
i think that's going to pair good with
this okay so
oh so let's say you know every you get a
clone or you
you smoke some flour wow this is really
amazing and i've been seeing it out
there people growing it
you get it you grow it
and
i don't know it's just something that
held tight to me it's just like caught
my eye like man she's really nice
and i think it would pair well
what i'm trying to do and i think
i consider myself a pretty
good judge
of what people like
i'm pretty picky and i
i know what i like it and everyone else
enjoys it so i'm like man if i i put
these two flames together
even though some of it's already been
done and there's you know there's a
bunch of tropicana cookies out there and
crosses but
not this
and then that's okay
i just liked them i enjoyed these and i
was like well let me while i'm playing
around let me make my own version
and i guess some of it was as a
caregiver
in the state that's
recreational as well and having so many
different stores and all these different
things coming up with so many other
caregivers growing
i wanted to have my own genetics
that were familiar so if someone oh
that's dropped stuff i smoked that but
not this one
because
i'm the only one who has it
and
i guess that was
some of the reasoning too just having my
own unique genetics so like when people
are looking for a certain thing like oh
i want that one i like this but this
one's man i just like this one better
just it tastes a little bit better
when i grow it it's just
more of what i'm looking for compared to
this one
basically trying to improve
things that i liked but you know even if
a great pie let's say for instance
grape pie is an amazing plant
and super tasty let's be honest it grows
like [ __ ] and that's super small but
that's how is what i was going to say
about the trap you know so like all of
them really just not a producer so like
i'm trying to make it so it's similar
but it's a better producer
yeah add to it add a little more figure
to it add more structure to it some
strength
blood size
more hash population
just always
trying to improve on it not taking
really away from it but definitely add
and influence it positively you're
finding cultivars that you really like
and you're making them better you're mad
yeah just trying to make it
like
seeing the flaws
and pairing the mail with it that i
think
at least the males that i have my stable
and
using them to their benefit not just
making it just to make it and don't get
me wrong some of them in there were just
really nice emails and
some of it i probably will never release
but some of it i've added in
to it just to say just have a different
off you like man this cheese is really
good
but these kind of girls like [ __ ] too
so like it's all small buns but the
[ __ ] weed's amazing it's got this
really great high
it's reminiscent of good times that i've
had my friends in the past
pain in the ass and pickle some of them
are like
picky on feed
some of them are super stretchy some of
them just aren't stretching at all you
can veg them forever so i guess like
when i did some skittles work like
skittles is an amazing cultivator ugly
flower super tasty flower though
if you get you smoke the real skittles
you know as well as i do as good as from
the first hit all the way down to the
last
because she doesn't really grow super
well so she takes so long on veg
so some guys like oh you know it's a
nine week strain it is a nine week
stream but if i didn't add
this to it it would have been longer
yeah you know like
always trying to make it better
sometimes the female's only bringing
color and hash production other than
that she's not bringing anything else
maybe her name because people are known
for her and i'm always going to keep it
transparent i'm going to say yes i use
this this is what it is and some people
are like oh man i drew that green pie
[ __ ] it didn't give me well it's like
this one this is why we
cross these things
and try to make them better because it
really does have some amazing quality
that's good to hear i've never did get
to get to grow that great pie but i was
going to say that about that trop you
know you definitely improved on that
i've always loved the taste of the
chopped cookies but every every time
i've grown it or had a phenotype and an
outcrossing of it that leans heavy
towards the trop side it's got beautiful
beautiful flowers it smells amazing it
tastes great the potencies and and the
yield [ __ ]
yep yield [ __ ] it's kind of wispy a
little
they're not very dense buds they're not
rocks by any means and small just really
small bloodstains
yeah and i definitely did not have that
problem with the mountain wizard at all
i was getting phenotypes that expressed
that flavor but with the skittles yield
the beautiful
bag appeal the buds i i love the bud
flower shape on it
honestly yeah
that's kind of you know and really
trying to influence that butt structure
make it so it's a little bit easier to
trim like so when i say like in a
positive way like i want guys to not
only get the yield
but it's better trimming
so like if it's better trimming that's
more production it's more productive
means that you can spend less time doing
that kind of work and more time where
you need to be
so you would say that's one of your
goals as well as that brack to leaf
ratio
yeah i want that i i definitely are
always thinking
thinking about the grower and the
caregiver and just even down to the
patient making it
streamlining
every part of that
whole process
hell yeah but giving them something
that's like oh well it's familiar damn
man this is pretty damn close to what i
was seeing but i get look how much
better it is like and i think a lot of
guys want to do that
that's my main goal though always trying
to make it better that's why i like that
grapefruit is amazing anything it
touches it just turns it to go the mail
me and chris was sending back he was you
know telling me i was like oh man this
f2 male is like i can't let it go
it's just so nice you know and
i'm like well did it grow like this and
this and this because i remember from
projects in the past
this is kind of what i was looking for
and then sending me pictures and
so when i went into my population going
back in to do some further work with it
that's kind of what i was looking for as
well
super fast in fact that male out of all
of them
my god
it would eat anything you could throw to
it
not picky at all
it's not that it's a super heavy feeder
it's just not picky yeah you could have
really had a hard time as far as like
the nutrient regimen with it did you no
not at all so that's another thing all
the way down to that and i don't get me
wrong some of these just like some of
the chems and the older strands like
some of them are just like i want food
like you need
me
but at the end of the day
especially with cost just rising
electric bills just rising soil
and
nutrients and just all of those things
that was
i was always trying to shave cost myself
in a smart way
i mean that's part of business
so if i can
shave off either some bench time because
i added bigger but yet still kept
the same quality that i was looking for
and the end result
there's my influencer always looking to
definitely make a positive
influence so that way it's just a better
product easier to work with
um yet simpler
in the entire time you're putting you
know like you said the caregiver and the
patient in your forefront of what you're
breeding that's pretty damn cool maddie
yeah
like i'm a patient myself so
i put the care into it that i want for
myself that i put into it for everyone
else
amen
all right before we get going to break
here really quick
you have a seed bank that you're running
over there on the east coast right yes
what's the website for that let's shout
that out really quick oh that is mainly
merchandise.com
it is spelled m a
i n e
main l-y
merchandise m-e-r-c-h-n-a-n-d-i-s-e
dot com
mainly merchandise dot com guys i carry
uh
you'll find all kinds of good genetics
there i have
stuff from relic and dynasty i have
stuff
um i did have some other guys on there
i kind of taken off a couple of the
breeders
for no specific reason other than
i'm just wanting to do more new england
based
and then people that i've been working
with which is chris like i've been
working with chris the longest out of
everyone
and have the utmost respect for crystal
i will always
do that and
as long as until i can't um for sure oh
yeah and then my other buddy from
vermont
inspirational seed coach too so
good deal yeah just yeah check out the
website guys you definitely i would love
for you guys to do that right now
unfortunately there's no payment option
on it
but you can leave a message on there we
can figure out all those details no
problem
awesome all right we're gonna go to
break really quick we'll be right back
with solo farms and we're going to talk
more about some of his old other
cultivars that he's got going on
[Music]
[Applause]
what is up everybody while we are on a
short break i want to give a quick shout
out to a sponsor and affiliate of the
show coconut sensors
if you guys have ever been like me you
probably bought a 10
crappy ass sensor that you're throwing
on the bottom of your tent
checking the environment from a place
that isn't going to monitor where you
want it to be monitored you have to get
into the tent just to check on it which
disrupts your environment as is
no longer have to do that with coconut
you guys can go over to koko
dot com that's coconut dot com use code
calyx at checkout that's all cap
c-a-o-y-x
to get a truly portable wireless wi-fi
device that brings climate insight into
the palm of your hands
push notifications directly to your
phone keep you in
dial with your environment data 100 of
the time go check them out at
coconut.com
[Music]
[Applause]
all right we are back with solo farms
we just had a smoke break we got to talk
about genetics a little bit i am now
smoking on a very orange fino that i
pulled out of the mountain wizard we
were talking about that before the break
the mountain wizard the grapefruit i
want to talk about some of the other
stuff that you're really proud of that
you made
what has popped out where how many
different strains now quite a few
you have a lot on your website that's
for sure oh there's so many
but out of all of them which one stuck
out
so the
oh god the god of the pancakes
how do the pancakes work uh stuffed
strawberry crepes
that the pancake the london pound cake
on christmas eleven times the strawberry
cough from
cal cushman
just an amazing plant all the way around
inside outside works really well up here
to be honest
the strawberry cough
you know another one of those that was a
really tough
super long vegging plant and just no
stretch whatsoever just like nothing
yeah
but yeah and
just took forever just ever just keep
going super coughed on it
which i don't mind as long as i'm
actually at the end of it
it's worth that time enough one way or
another right right it was no don't get
me wrong it was always worth it one way
or another especially for the tariffs
she wasn't always the prettiest looking
flower
so
the pancakes added a little bit kind of
like a makeover
as far as visual appearance
a tighter nugget structure easier to
trim
uh better caleb's the leaf ratio
shortened the flour time
added
a different
high to it
definitely a different
depth to the flavors
um what was nice is that
on that particular strain everything
that we found
and everything that everyone else is
finding
is that it
i was so grateful that the male didn't
take away from that strawberry cloth
like when you hear strawberry you're
looking for that
berries at least you know that kind of
red berry
and
it's just tried and true
the best part of it was that it added it
took away the bench time
gave it a better spacing while keeping
the buns the buds
good size
and
overall weight you're getting a yield
now
better hash production
better bag appeal
a better overall i think
feeling than effects from it
didn't just
limit it
to
that
sativa
as it is a sativa dominant hybrid but
you will find
certain uh
phenos of that
will lean a little more towards you know
the strawberry end of it but that was
really one of my favorites out of that
super nice
the other one that i really like out of
those were
the
boot camp breakfast as well
super nice they paid they just linked
together just amazing
the colors from both ends that was the
other thing that what was the cross on
that one so that is the the london pound
cakes on food mints the pancakes male
times
military chocolate which i phenotyped
from seeds i got from only see go
okay i found a really nice pheno of it
that would out of all of them that just
stood out out of all of it
super
chocolaty earthy
just
the most resinous out of all of them
nice blood structure
not super huge buds but they were rocks
and
res is cut of bubba times the tropicana
f2
oh okay so that that's what makes up the
military chocolate
and
so the cookies added that hardness to it
obviously the
resin to the bubbler i like the bubbler
for the
medicinal value
obviously the bud size you know nice
girth to it
and then the colors
you know that's the other thing that i
failed to
mention with the
stuffed strawberry crepes
is the you know you'll get colors coming
out of all of that
pancakes mail definitely some beautiful
colors coming out of those
so that's another thing to look forward
to that
anything from purple to reds
so then you add that to strawberry and
it's just
instant bag appeal and visual
there's so many terpenes man just really
nice
good deal man good deal
i know two of the ones that really
caught my eye that i picked actually
actually there's one that we can't even
ignore now that we've talked about the
grapefruit for so long is that new one
that i grabbed from you the strawberry
grapefruit bananas
tell me you've gone through that i want
to know more about this i'm excited
about it so the 14 are cut is an amazing
hash cultivator
and
amazing terpenes
she's always not the best as far as like
flower yield
so then my hopes with the grapefruit was
to just add the girth
go fish and shorten the timeline while
keeping the hash there
add another layer of flavor
super nice like i mean strawberries
bananas grapefruits like it's just
fruity super terpy
i feel like there's so much gas out
there that fruit
that is a hash producer but with a
different
level of citrus onto it that influence
is just something that will be unique
yeah for sure yeah
so that's kind of what i was looking for
to improve on that straw mana while
keeping like
definitely all the unique
characteristics of it and the positives
from it that people enjoy
he really is an ash producer
and that's one of the things that i
appreciate about you maddie is uh
a lot of people know me for like hunting
through land races or [ __ ] with true
hybrids or heirlooms and things like
that and i i'm just not into a lot of
the more modern stuff but one of the
things that i constantly tell my guys is
if i'm going to [ __ ] with modern
genetics like it's going to be maddie's
he's already impressed me multiple times
and now you're taking
my [ __ ]
the one i love grapefruit and i'm not so
familiar with the straw nana i have
smoked it a couple times and i love the
terps on it but i did grow the
strawberry mamba number four for quite a
while i don't know if you're familiar
with that one at all yes i've heard of
it for sure i've never um
i've never played with it myself
it's really similar
very similar to like the straw nana
flavors with less of the banana more
focus on that strawberry but a very very
similar strawberry taste nice
and i've grown that one
so much just because of the flavor on it
and i cannot see that match up between
your straw nana and the
and the grapefruit going bad in any way
i don't think so i think everything that
we've seen
is just
wow
wow man well here's another one
it's just another one yeah you know
and that's one well i'm in that stage
right now where i'm really
i'm doing a lot more dabs my wife she's
a huge dabber so concentrates has been a
big focus in our garden lately and
that's like you said this is one of the
things that you kind of breed for is
hash production terpenes
yeah so
taking you know in a lot of those old
cultivars they don't
have a return like some of the more
modern ones do the resin populations
just weren't as bred in at that time you
know nope they just weren't
so it's nice to have some things that
you're putting out there like this that
are more modern get that hash production
so we can really enjoy [ __ ] around
learning hash oh absolutely and then i
just love to see it
there's so many other things now that's
why i'm trying to get it i've been
getting them but you know always looking
for
new hash companies anybody that
is doing really
amazing work
with sovereignness extractions
and or hydrocarbon extractions that
solely looking for those type of things
love to work with them i've worked with
a few and am working with
guys that are doing that
and i think it's an amazing combo
oh yes i've always enjoyed that the most
don't get me wrong i'm a flower person
i've always smoked flour but
i think a healthier
way of consuming the cannabis is
cash i think i believe it's super
enjoyable
the one good thing about modern cannabis
is the testing and all the good things
so there's a little bit more
transparency on products that
patients are able to receive
so that to me is definitely a plus
side on
modern cannabis as well
um and everything ever changing in
the markets it's
you know making sure that everything's
transparent and
to be honest with you when you're
dealing with patients you should be
putting the utmost care into everything
that we do because at the end of the day
this is their medicine and if they're
not capable of supplying their own
medicine or they're in a state that
maybe they can't yet
these genetics and or
ones like it
in the right hands you know their
caregiver or someone else that can do it
for them
with that availability to that is just
amazing and thus it should be we have a
responsibility
to these people
i mean i feel like if you're gonna put
the time and effort into something that
it should be an expression of you so not
i'm not just selling or
telling people about what i make but i'm
also telling them about me
and
that's just as
it's an important part of it because
that's why
in
what influenced what everyone is seeing
now and starting to see and has been
seen
yeah you know and just it opens up every
day to more and more people
and i'm you know i'll go right back to
it i'm never so ever grateful
and just humbled that i'm still able
to keep doing what i'm doing and put
smiles on people's faces
that's the biggest part to me and seeing
people get relief because at the end of
the day when i started this i did it for
that i was a patient
and someone that
it was easier for me for me to be a
patient to take the street element out
of it and do these things for myself
that i like
so let's get a couple quick fire
questions in before we get going here i
had one of my patreon members cue ball
had a couple questions for you he wanted
to know
what have you produced which one of your
cultivars
is
the strongest on the nose which one's
going to pack that in your face what's
the first one that comes to mind as far
as your nose
anything with that the the
z-whiz male
everything with that z-wisp
and then the grapefruit
grapefruit is just
that's what she is
yeah
they just do it it's uh it's just so
prominent no matter what it touched it
wasn't gonna you can't water it that's
the reason why keeping all my
expressions open
so it doesn't get muddled or
bottlenecked into just one thing
that was my biggest fear i want to keep
the drugs alive and the terpenes alive
because i can always improve on
for sure
he also wanted to know how you went
about your pollinations when you
find a male that you want to work with
is it you're sticking it in a room with
everything that you think it might pair
up well with or are you more
taking the role of the bee and hand
pollinating
so no to be honest with you
i like to open pollinate so i like to
have the males in with the females
and throughout the process i will
collect some pollen and the only reason
that i'll go in and touch certain things
is just for consistency throughout the
plant
for the most part i let it do its own
natural thing that's that's all it's
supposed to be
good deal do i help influence that a
little bit
i have
um i have gone in and say like if it's
in the corner of the room even though i
rotate the plants
if it's like
in the middle of the plant and i feel
like it might not get as much
of the pollen as i needed to i'll go in
and hit a couple breaths just to ensure
but the biggest
my thing is over pollination i open
how do you limit yourself on how many
males you'd use in that room
obviously you're taking females with
different expressions that you want to
that you want to put forward in that
next generation but
how do you know it's going to be two or
three you know or how do i get it down
like on one strain how do i narrow it
down to one or how do i
is that where you're doing one male with
you i'm narrowing it down to each yeah
so each uh
each train that i've picked the mail
from
is the
the biggest things are stability
resilience
as far as stress it can handle all the
stresses that i'm
and then
on that positive note if it passes those
tests
it has something to bring to the table
it's always going to make whatever
female that i'm
uh pairing with it later it's always to
make it cool
okay so you're looking for something
that's not going to pass on any unwanted
straights but still keep the genetic
lines open enough where there's enough
possibilities from all over the board
within that strain that makes sense
that's that's awesome
that's my biggest thing that's what i'm
looking for in a male and then i choose
to keep them
you know
on the grapefruits in the beginning we
used a couple different males and then
we just kept the mail
and then
due to unforeseen
circumstances wasn't able to keep it so
then moving forward
going through a huge building project
with the building
i just didn't have the time to either
keep played
didn't have time or space to
play games with
doing that at that point so that was you
know the reason for
talking with chris
to keep things moving forward while i
could
and also to him
i knew he would love them just because
he's a pure sativa citrus tropical fruit
person who
remembers this grapefruit and
enjoyed it just as much as all of us
have
oh hell yeah
it's definitely a good icebreaker strain
when
i talk about the grapefruit i can always
tell some of the guys that have been
growing a little bit longer because
they'll break out and be like oh yeah
man i remember the sweet pink you know
i used to grow that outdoor
cause it was it was a tried and true
yeah for sure
i feel like she was like one of those
that fell between the cracks
like a bunch of other amazing
cultivators as well but
well wasn't it it was originally a skunk
phenotype
that's right sweet tooth
northern lights
originally came out of british columbia
there was more in it than just the c99
that is what it was the sc-99 that's
where that's that citrus came from yep
at least that's what's documented anyway
of what i understand well yeah there's
only so much that we can know if you
weren't there
yeah i mean it's a little deeper than
just that but
just for a basement like a basic
that's kind of like
the founding right there the building
blocks so to say
for sure so
did you have any shows coming up i do i
have uh
oh god we have uh the bonfire coming up
in april
which is down in lebanon maine
we also have
a mmcm show coming in august
in augusta maine
for that will be a two-day show
and then we always have
every two weeks we do a show here
the local people
and just to get you know all these guys
with a bunch of you know they get to
meet a bunch of different caregivers and
guys like myself as well
so they get you know some of these
genetics in their hands whereas you know
without those they wouldn't be able to
oh yeah now with the website open that
gives so much more availability and
obviously social media as well
that's cool that you're still taking
time out for the locals though oh that's
the most important part i mean if it
wasn't for those guys i wouldn't even
have
gotten those genetics in my hand to be
honest
that's awesome yeah really i mean that's
always always to those roots because
that's where it all started that's
that's what it is i mean
i was one of those patients before
anything so
always keep it there never forget
never ever
upcoming sale
next month i don't know sometime between
the beginning of the month and
valentine's day
i'll be dropping a spring fling sale is
what i'm calling it it's coming up soon
and
yeah be really soon you know trying to
get
some more of these packs into guys hands
with the upcoming season coming up and
some new things maybe into your garden
if you're a caregiver
trying to diversify defies yourself as
far as being in
dispensaries or your local shops and
having something different so it's not
all the same
keeping that market open and
regular instead of just everyone
always doing the same things i think
that's the future and keeping things
like this and from other people that i
work with is a good way to start
that other like i said that release that
three pack
release that i did of the sorbet the
savory sorbet and then that strawberry
the strawberry grapefruit bananas
i'm going to
do another drop of those
like 50 packs
and i'm just gonna run it till they're
gone and
depending on when i started it'll
probably run to the end of february
good because i'm going to do it and then
the following month up until now to like
july i'm going to do a different
seed sale every month coming up so that
way wow wow if you did happen to
miss out on the february sale there'd be
one up and coming so that way everybody
gets a chance
that's awesome man yeah i just want to
make sure that the availability is there
and give people a shot
good i was definitely
trying to give other people the
opportunity to get some of the
strawberry grapefruit banana for you and
not hoard them
[Laughter]
i'm glad you're putting them back out
there because i still want more
the other one that really went like the
sorbet went i think once everybody sees
it the ones that went out once everybody
start seeing those but the uh
the savory sorbet that aside berry uh
gelato onto the cushman's 11 times gmo
awesome you did send me some of those no
brainer
i never grew the cushman's i've never
even seen it honestly so like i said i'd
smoke so much old [ __ ] and that's what
i'm on to all the time it's pretty you
know other than you and professor p's
gear there's not a lot of modern stuff i
grow what was so great about the
cushman's ah the vigor
it was like i like this particular
gelato hybrid it
doesn't have it's not like like the 41
is good my personal opinion
i really
enjoyed the flavor
of the 33. i hate the veg time on it
but the blood structure the effects from
it are medicinal as well also adds i
mean obviously a beautiful color
without
influencing the flavor in a negative way
and so
my
obviously again trying to make it better
had
less bench time to it
the male had
amazing color to it and then it was just
like
creamy doughy
gassy heavy resin populations
amongst the calyxes just really super
dense
so another reason why i wanted to use it
basically the same reason why i wanted
to use the
z-whiz
but to have a different flavor and then
add it to
similar things and or different things
as well
i mean i made f2s of those and
and then obviously a multitude of
hybrids
everything she touches
as far as a gelato like she actually has
that same blood structure as the 33.
more denser
from the cushman's
really harder like definitely harder
buds so you're going to get your weight
and then
like
such a dense resin population now
the thing i didn't like about the gelato
33 unlike the 41 is that the 41 had
better heads
it more resin
the 33 had resin
super nice high but as far as extracts
it really wasn't a great yield
so i'm like man i'd really like to get
this terpene profile
possibly maybe even draw some color out
of it but i'd love to pack some more
resin in this thing
and that's what that mail brings to the
table
nice
that's good to hear that's exciting man
yeah man they're really nice everyone
that's been going through those are just
super excited definitely
happy about all the results they're
getting
and yeah i can now they like there'll be
some more future work with those too
so yeah i look forward to that as well
just seeing what everybody's
keep on hearing what everybody's saying
about them keep getting them out there
so more people get them and start really
looking at bigger populations of them
and
i love to hear all the unique things
that come out of a manner you know just
like your story with the
with the mountain wizard
that was so fun
that entire hunt there was so many
expressions and none of them were bad it
was just a pleasing hunt all around like
you said they were really really
resilient to everything stable beautiful
bag appeal was off the wall some more
than others but all of them were good
every flavor every smell every hive was
all good
i did not have one complaint throughout
that entire thing
thank you i appreciate that man that's
what that's what i did it for go in and
hit a couple breaks just to ensure
all right before we get going here we
got to ask you some of the hard
questions
oh boy
our lead content creator this one of his
favorite questions for me to ask you
guys uh grow green daddy over there on
the podcast
he always wants to know
what
we try to get three if there's only one
there's one it's a hard hard question
but
at the end of everything
when you're gone
what do you want to represent your name
which strain are you like or which
cultivar which type are you working on
where you're like i think i put my most
like most of my passion most my energy
into this one this was my pride and joy
easy just like that bo
the other ones are amazing don't get me
wrong i love them all but the grapefruit
like hands down
hands down
if you had to name
a couple more that you thought were
really close to that is there any more
you're like i think this represents solo
so
ah god
i do have an answer for that
it's a hard question
it's a super hard question
so
i'd have to say that
that zewi's work is definitely i'm proud
of that work
i really am because of
the time it took to pair everything that
i put in to pair with it
with that intention
knowing that it would pair well
um
i guess
the other one i really like
that's a part one of that sub this is a
sub part of that second part okay
the one that i'm really second most
proud of is just still not available to
anyone
oh
as things come
forward in the future
you
and a few other specific people will get
those in their hands
for
so many reasons and
first off is just
the amount of passion
love and dedication
that you put into it among
a few other very select individuals
that i really want to get these into
your hands because
i know at the end of the day you guys
are going to do
the best work for
yourselves and myself included for the
common good for everyone else
somebody
i just i can't see what it is yet right
now but it's
something that definitely something that
i'm super proud of
dude i'm excited i don't even know what
the [ __ ] it is this is not something
you've told me before you just dropped
this on me during the podcast
so maybe something to keep
everybody looking forward to i know i am
i'm so looking forward to it
hell yeah are we working with the time
frame here
i would say that i'd say by 2024
they will be
yeah
yeah i'd say like maybe the end of 2023
to 2024
just depending on
how everything works out it's just
really it could all within a three
to six month of that i would say that's
that's the best guesstimate that i can
you know that's a good thing though that
is a good thing if you're already
excited about it now and you've got that
much more time to work with it because
no one knows about it
and you got to keep it that way i got
you i got it
like there's i can't even fill up on one
hand how many people know okay and or
are involved
yeah so
this right here is gonna be another
testament
i'm hoping
for fall
late winter like maybe early winter
for f5 work
we'll see we'll just see how
on the grapefruit
yeah on the grapefruit f5s
and i'm looking forward to those as well
and i know
i just want people to keep enjoying
these that far's
don't think that
the f4 is going to be like the f5 it's
not that it's not going to be a better
version
it's just going to be
i'm using a different expression from
the original expression the f2s
and then
going into another like you know i had
the a b c and d
i'm going into another one of those
because i
it was just a few different reasons and
i think it's really just going to end up
because the end goal for me
is to i always want to keep that
expression i'm not going to be selfish
and say
all you get is uh sweet pink grapefruit
that's it
i don't want anyone to ever get that i
still want everyone to get and find
those unique ones that make their garden
stand out
really helps them out
individually i want everybody
to
experience everything grapefruit has to
offer
well yeah exactly kind of like
kind of pick your own version of it that
you like because everybody's taste buds
are just a little different
yeah and what i smell
doesn't necessarily mean you do or taste
yeah same plant but everyone can
get that taste but you know depending
like if you're a cigarette smoker you're
going to taste it different if you're
this you know
there's too many variables but yeah i'm
trying to definitely keep it where
it's open
it keeps everybody kind of like wow yeah
there's that well there it is but then
wow what is this
holy you know
awesome dude i'm very stoked i'm very
lazy
with the f5 project people can look
forward to
which i think with the f4 is i kind of i
mean
for the most part everything that i'm
seeing and hearing and everything that
we've seen all the blood structures just
the good size flower sets
and nothing too crazy but i think if
anything
out of all of it is going to be getting
some more maybe more uniform
not so much of actual structure
but size
depending on the cross and or the
some could be more fox tailored than
others and vice versa so
good so we're starting to see a lot more
uniformity in the population yeah i mean
a little bit more but then also
my biggest thing is to keep the terpene
profile
open but yes yes
awesome dude
well i wanted to thank you for taking
this time with us maddie i appreciate
you
thanks for sharing so much information
about what you got going on and what you
have in stock right now you guys can
find maddie
solo farms over at mainly merchandise
dot com that's maine as in
m-a-i-n-e correct
yeah
m-a-i-n-e-l-y
merchandise
dot com
hit the instagram at solo farm solo
farmstead co or and or solo farms 2.0
awesome and we got a big sale coming up
soon you said at the beginning of
february
thank you for taking this time with us
maddie i appreciate you and i look
forward to those beans whatever they are
you got me excited you have a good day
yep you too thank you
[Music]
what is up everybody your boy doc alex
here before we get going from this
episode i wanted to ask you were you
aware that we have our very own private
discord server
that's right we have our very own
private discord server you can check it
out entirely free at discord dot gg
forward slash alex crew podcast you will
be limited to the general chat in the
reception area you can kind of talk to
me if you can see what's going on with
your grower you can just share some of
your experiences and growing it's a
great community probably one of the best
platforms that i've ever dealt with if
i'm not coming across too cocky we've
got a great team of people in there if
you want to unlock a little bit more if
you want a little bit more of the calyx
crew podcast experience you can check us
out on patreon at patreon.com forward
slash doc underscore calyx we have two
different tiers in there we have a five
dollar tier that unlocks all of the
discord we have a total of got like 161
channels in there everything from
growing showing off your glass showing
off your joint art tees brewing teas
integrate pest management pretty much
anything you can think of
we've got a team of specialists that are
just [ __ ] killing it and they're
really helping me out teaching guys how
to do stuff that even i didn't know i'm
learning [ __ ] in there every day so i
want to give a quick shout out some of
those guys that are helping me out
shiggity flips our very own sip
specialist if you guys aren't familiar
with sip it's a sub irrigated planter
it's an awesome way to do organic
growing in an organic and growing
environment he's also on instagram you
can check him out there tk geico our
scrog specialist you can find him on
instagram as monster scroggin always
killing the skog if you want to learn
how to scrog that is the boy to go to go
check him out tinkle turp is our host if
you come into the discord he will see
you right away grow green daddy our
league content creator that helps us out
with all of this you hear him on the mid
rolls my funny australian bastard friend
i love him to death and then my other
australian friend harshi83 who's in
there moderating our discord awesome
dude we also have a 10 tier if you guys
want even more behind-the-scenes content
we just had an awesome one with duke on
the story of tommy two dicks uh we also
do q and a's with our podcast guests we
do game day giveaways the infamous do or
dab that everybody's heard of you get a
chance to come in there play games win
free prizes
build a community an awesome [ __ ]
community it's worth checking out at
least completely for free jump in there
see if you like it and we'll go from
there
love you all appreciate y'all thank you
for supporting the show and i will catch
you on the next one this is doc alex
saying good night and grow red
[Music]