[Music]
good evening everyone and welcome to the
calyx and crew podcast
i'm your host doc calyx
today we have a very special episode for
you we have my buddy gas from swami
organic seed on the line he's going to
be talking a little bit about his
history and both growing and breeding
this plant he'll be touching some spots
on roadkill skunk as well as the nine
original plants given to the brotherhood
of eternal love we'll be talking a
little bit about some of his famous
cultivars what he likes working with
what his methodology behind breeding
these different plants together is
and what he's hoping to achieve as well
as a q a from our followers
before we get started i want to give a
huge shout out stoner days apparel you
guys can go over to shop.stonerdays.com
use code calyx at checkout that's all
cap c-a-l-y-x
at checkout for a whopping 20 percent
off your order
[Music]
now let's just jump right into it
guess how you doing today my brother
hey good man how are you i'm doing
pretty good i got all of your chocolate
thai inbred lime i got a hundred percent
germination rate on those and i got them
planted today so i'm stoked for those to
take off is that the uh the to the
pakistani chocolate thai yep
those are good
then you cross that back with the
chocolate tie right yeah yeah those
those are good man i saw you post about
it the other day it sounded awesome but
i
figured it would be a good like dig my
toes in before i hit the actual inbred
line you know
it's pretty good you know the inbred
line is is the uh
throttle line you know
yeah
it's just two two lines from you know
from like snow higher and like whoever
else had it that gave me it way back
when i just finally got a hold of them
and opened them up combined them again
you know
but that that wasn't the darwo line
yeah yeah
that was real brown dirt warrior
oh no that chocolate tie is different oh
okay
that's like a bag seed from from one of
his buddies in canada or something oh
right on nice so for everybody here that
doesn't really know you or hasn't
introduced themselves to swami why don't
you tell us a little bit about who you
are and like what you do
well i've been doing this forever you
know but i i started out oh probably in
my mid-20s you know as as far as
breeding
plants goes or crossing types together
you know back then we didn't really have
a lot to work with if you wanted seed
you had to drive hundreds of freaking
miles or go to amsterdam or take your
chances with whatever mail order service
you could get right you know
in 96 i drove
[ __ ]
200 miles to
vancouver and bought seeds direct from
mark emery you know for two hundred
dollars a pack for for uh you know a
pack of blueberry and uh what was it
bubble berry and uh
oh you know all that stuff back then and
it was good
you know we we liked it we worked with
it
everybody bought it everybody loved it
yeah it's amazing how times change now
you can just get on the internet and
order some seeds with your credit card
the trading scene alone is incredible
you know when you get into the trading
aspect of it it's the greed aspect of it
just kind of falls away and now we don't
even count seed anymore we're just like
oh here have some of these right you can
have some of those have some of these i
noticed that when i planted all those uh
back crosses i
just automatically figure like 10 to 12
seeds a pack and i don't even know what
you threw in there i think there was
like 18 all together
well there's a method to my madness man
and that's my success is your success
right and that's that's that's what it's
all about you know it's best that i
give people a lot of seed so they
actually grow them and get the phenotype
that they're after you know when they
order the seed
right but then you're giving more people
more seeds for the same amount of money
well yeah you can't have that
well
it doesn't bother me right you know
you're doing it the right way
it's it's it's about getting people
what they need
absolutely you know they want specific
things so they
select these types for the specific
trait or these combination of traits and
they want those they want those results
you know or they want that
experimentation they want to they want
something different right you know we're
supposed to be different yeah absolutely
um
so we're talking about late 80s when you
started breeding
oh yeah when i first started throwing
pollen around it was probably 88 or 89
you know
just whatever we had with you know
california indicas and mexicans and
stuff like that and we were so young you
know yeah you never really see anything
through to fruition when you're 18 19
years old you know yeah well that comes
with learning patience with the plan as
well
right and i you know i grew up reading
high times for my parents and everything
so i was all my nose was always in the
ask ad section you know
what's that what's it got to say today
you know
i miss that i really do even some of the
revs articles in skunk magazine early on
were pretty good
it was it was all we had you know if you
weren't if you weren't buying the books
that were what they were out you know
yeah or whatever it was you know a
dollar 75 you could go down to the
7-eleven and buy a copy of high times
and and get some weird grow advice you
know yeah absolutely
and we talked a lot about that like
magazine culture this day and what
people
you know expect to get out of a certain
product that they don't even need
well it's that it's the gray area in
cannabis that's always been you know the
the legality aspect of it so created
this subculture of word of mouth
right you know
so you know just the craziest
non-biological stuff that ever happened
you know was was
somehow accepted as common practice
right
like everybody threw their soil away at
one point in the game i remember
throwing my soil away because it's no
good anymore
yeah and i can't tell you how much i
appreciate some of the knowledge that
you've instilled on me as far as reusing
that soil and the the results that you
can get from it
well yeah you know back in the 90s when
we were doing this and throwing the
stuff away
we got tired of trying to hide it in
dumpsters and weird places you know yeah
we started putting it in our gardens
mm-hmm you know you know all the growers
i knew that's what we were doing oh yeah
i was the same way so we started
noticing that our gardens were like hey
we're doing good
so yeah and then and then people started
picking up the recycled soil thing you
know and
and figuring out that it was it's really
just based in mythology
the whole cannabis grill culture you
know right
so
even aside from breeding you're saying
that started late 80s mid 80s
but you're also a lifetime cannabis
grower right you actually come from
generations of growers
well pretty much yeah
you know
let me ask you when you were getting
into this there wasn't as many people to
idolize as there is today but when you
were getting into it who did you look up
to who was like this is the seeds that i
want this is what i need to go after
well my parents you know in 82 they i
remember bundling and playing with the
real roadkill skunk you know i got crack
when i was 13 years old i did two weeks
in juvenile hall because i took some
skunk bud to school
you know
it was no joke you know one bong hit
wrapped up in a baggie stuck down in
your your pocket sitting in sixth period
blew up the whole freaking room man
you know
and there was nothing like it you know
people say oh it smells like skunk well
yeah but it
it it smells like cannabis too you know
all right it smells like good cannabis
oh it's probably the loudest thing i've
ever smelled you know
but you know i paid attention to what
was going on in the magazines and stuff
and i remember reading the old seed
catalogs that my parents had and i was
processing herb by 11 years old
so
you know we we just grew up around it
you know they had all that stuff they
had high times and all the little the
catalogs and everything laying around
and as kids we read that stuff you know
like the fabulous furry freak brothers i
remember reading those too
nice
and they were associated with bikers you
know
so they got the stuff they got the cuts
they got the seeds they got you know
whatever that those guys are running up
and down the coast and what was that at
that time
oh just whatever they had you know i
just i couldn't tell you this was before
there was uh metal halides and
stuff like that people just grew with
fluorescent bulbs and they and they had
just all these weird designs of
fluorescent spectrums that they thought
would do good and
people go to this one growth store in
seattle and that was the main source for
all the stuff you know right but at that
time you know fluorescents were a step
ahead the old
oh yeah i mean that i still vividly
remember these fluorescent tubes growing
roads kill skunk you know
that was one of my first gross was uh
actually the very first girl that i ever
had was with a whole chicken's heat lamp
thinking that would be a good idea and
then uh after that we shortly moved to
this uh the t5s we went to t5s when
those came out
but you know as i grew up you know
regionally wherever you were
you kind of sourced the best stuff that
was around you know
to grow you know whoever's growing this
hey i want a cut of that i want to i
want to grow this stuff and most of the
time we never knew what it was
you know and then
sometime around in the game people
started paying attention to what things
really were oh this is blueberry
that was really the biggest
you know
wave that started changing everything
was blueberry
i'm i'm talking like mid 90s now is is
when this stuff took off and and the the
fruity names the bubbly names started
popping up you know
what are you working with now that
you're excited about
oh just everything man i have so many
things going on i do
everything you know i'm not really in
one magazine culture methodology of
breeding oh we have to do f1 f2 f3 and
then select out you know i do that with
some type but
that's not my gig man you know there's
not a there's not a certain profile that
a type has to match to catch your
interest
well i kind of do that i kind of put
things together based upon what their
similarities are
or what they're what their their lineage
is
you know
right one of the one of the things i
like doing is taking older afghanis and
combining them with their ancestry you
know
with newer collections with older
collections and stuff like that
okay so
i had a really good question from a
viewer here
how many plants of a particular strain
do you grow out um when you're choosing
a new breeder like say
you want to work with uh dj shorts for
the first time how many seeds are you
gonna oh god
as many as possible man if i have a
hundred i'll crack a hundred you know
that's a good way to be
it's a it's critical
it but if i only have five seeds of
something
then
you know that really narrows your window
so if i have five seeds or something and
i don't get any males well that's a dead
end line
unless i figure something out so what
i'll do is i'll i'll go through
everything i have and say okay what's
the best thing i have that's gonna made
up with this type that's gonna you know
enhance its its characteristics
i actually have a personal question for
you um
so you have thousands of seeds you have
all the seeds that you need at your
disposal how many
would you consider to be the minimum
amount to be a proper final hunt oh i a
hundred is good
i know okay i i like a hundred because
you're not going overboard and it's a
pretty fat range of expressions in there
and it gives you the ability to call out
all the weaker stuff without having to
worry depending on what you're working
with you know if i
if i have
two parents of unrelated genetic origin
say a thai and an afghani who've never
met each other before and i combine them
together
and i get my f1s what my hope is there
is that they have heterosis bigger
right
that
they express traits and characteristics
that are better than both parents
and that's generally the case with with
working with unrelated genetic material
so why not why not do that and give
those to people so they can really have
some fun you know what i mean and that's
what we love about you man i've got
another really good question from a
follower here it says what three to five
strains best represent your work and why
oh probably mazar guillero because i've
worked the lion so extensively you know
taking the two land races combined them
together and and really selected out the
parents over a long period of time
to uh
get the traits and the expressions and
everything that i wanted out of the line
without boxing it in
you know because you're i'll you'll
still get some i i
like to keep the lines open a little bit
so that people that
don't like a lot of indica can select a
little more sativa if they want to right
that's a good way to be
it's it's it's reality man
so you know i i personally like the
heavy indica as our 7 76 chiaro myself
but some people man just really just
throw on the couch and they're slobber
and they're passed out they get up and
they go raid the fridge and they go back
to the couch and it's it's really
non-productive for them right you know
and what what type of strains do you
prefer do you prefer the more productive
stuff or is it a good mix of
both throughout the day well i use it
you know as a human being so
i'll do the sativas in the morning and
the indicas at night right you know have
you ever noticed people that react to
those things differently
um generally
um depending on what you give them you
know like if i smoke a
haze dominant type with somebody who's
not used to smoking like sativas dude
you know like eight o'clock in the
morning here have a cup of coffee and
hit a haze
they'll be luke
missy has a couple friends that have
given some really really heavy hazes um
i we even smoked the moose and lobster
professor p which has the cali mist in
it and we gave that to her friend she
was down she said she was tired she i
was like wow really
that's interesting man a lot of women
really like the cali mist right
that was really successful with the
women i'm just wondering if it's not one
of those things where they use um like
methylphenidate for adhd kids and it
actually has the opposite effect you
know there's so much going on here
everything is different right that's the
most incredible thing about it all is
every single one of these types
everything that i do
has a different effect or a different
result
so you can really narrow down what
people want in their medicine you know
so a lot of my customers they're like
tell me what i want
this is what i need so do you find a lot
of people coming to you asking you
um
what do you have that's going to be good
for my ailment
yeah and that's been consistent over the
the last 10 years that's awesome and you
actually have a
type that is good for ptsd correct
yeah that nigerian sunshine is another
one of those top three lines i don't
want to dig into that so bad
and i said i've worked extensively and
then isolated a couple phenotypes you
know
but i like to keep that one open too
because i don't really i don't want to
lose that 76 nigerian expression in
there you know right that's awesome that
you do that and especially in a day and
age where a lot of people are cubing
their stuff or they're bottlenecking it
in one form or another you know
and i do that too you know i have my
back crosses in my cubes and for the
people that are going after and it's
it's it's uniformity you know they want
the uniformity so
it's it's easy to do there you go
so tell us a little bit about this blue
orca that i see you crossing with
everything
it's the sister of the one
you know um there were there were nine
cuts in 1983 that were distributed to
nine brotherhood of eternal love members
and they all had names
right uh the one
was the one because it had
the narrowest leaf
yeah it was the one that looked like
that yeah
it was tie dominant and
so they named these and they gave them
to those nine members blue orca was
cootes
uh there was mary poppins was another
one and nazis cut was another one uh
crystal flowers was another one i've
heard that name but most of these are
lost nowadays
well
there's seven lost sisters that nobody
knows where they were or what or i mean
what happened to them or where they are
you know yeah they're probably extinct
or there are there types nowadays that
people just don't even know
but for example
you know when i grew out the i forget
which chem it was chem d or something
some years ago the first thing i noticed
was how
much it resembled the one in blue orca
and there really wasn't anything out
there that matches those profiles like
that oh wow you know
if you've had the the afgui
yeah
it's been a while but
some gooey breeder it's kind of like
that you know an afghan and a thai
dominant kind of thing it's just greasy
as sweet as hell you know yeah
you know yeah jinx was doing some work
with that after
it was good it was you know it was just
kind of loose
so tell us a little bit about the story
behind the blue orca going to mexico
oh that was that's not the blue orca
that was the roadkill skunk oh that was
the roadkill skunk and then that was the
one that was hit with the european
yeah this guy
he you know took a bag from humble
which was the road kill skunk and 85 to
mexico to his sister
who live there and they're heady as hell
you know so
she gives it to her favorite local
farmer who happens to be you know
in the export business and grows a
european type and that was just the drug
cultivar over in that area right yeah
and then they're supposed to be pretty
good
from what i hear i i've never smoked a
period pan so i wouldn't know the
the mexican farmer hybridized it into
that type for 30 years
wow
it's a 30 year roadkill skunk mexican
nice and you have that
no
no you done
well she we only got a few seeds in and
we split them between two guys and he
got the females and i got the mail oh
man
and
i sent the pollen and it didn't hook up
so was it a sterile male or was it no
you know just how however the pollen got
there maybe it got too hot during
transit or something like that
it just didn't work out that's too bad
but you do offer other rks crosses
well i took the males and the first
thing i thought was oh i gotta save this
stuff
you know what am i gonna do so
naturally it was the one blue orca and
cherry bomb since they were the oldest
and out of those three crosses which one
became your favorite
oh i like the blue orca
by the 85 mexican what is it about that
blue orca that just does it for you
it's uniform you know like when all the
offspring are uniform
okay so it's just a very true breeding
right and it breeds truer than the one
the the one
it's it's f1's are always they're kind
of all over the place well you said it
was more thai influence yeah unless you
made it with something that it likes and
it'll go down that line you know but
mostly it's a blue orca has has the
stability and the uniformity that that
you need as a grower you know and the
early finish time and for a finish time
what is that looking like
uh blue orca itself is uh 56 days
56 wow that's that's always a fun
harvest when they come off fast like
that why i work with it so much and you
know and a lot of these landry's
afghanis
they go 75 80 85 90 days man
yeah that's no joke so that's something
that you're typically breeding the blue
orca with is the longer flowering
cultivars and trying to knock them down
and and keep that heterosis bigger and
early flowering times and high resin you
know nice very nice all right we're
going to take a short break we will be
right back
while we take a short break i want to
make a quick shout out to coconut
sensors you guys can find them on ig at
coconut inc that's k-o-k-o-n-a-u-t
or you can find them over at
www.coconaut.com
you use code calyx to check out that's
c-a-l-y-x all caps for 10 off your order
if you buy a sensor from coconut not
only are you supporting a small business
but you're
buying a sensor that's competitive with
all the top leading sensors on the
market right now without the price it
monitors my temperature my humidity my
vpd and i heard from anton coming up
here soon it is actually going to be
able to monitor co2 levels as well and
we're talking a fraction of the cost of
the leading brands right now the
original mitsu the original coconut
sensor is retailing for 69
pick yourself up maybe one or two check
them out and tell me that i'm wrong
they're amazing and i absolutely love
the one that's in mine i can check it
anytime on the app on my phone
see where my conditions are if
anything's out of whack and if anything
needs to be adjusted and then i'm not
sitting there worrying all the time i
know what's going on in my tent i know
what's going on in my environment in
that room and i don't have to worry as
much it's amazing huge shout out coconut
huge shout out to anton appreciate them
go get yourself one
now let's jump back into the episode
with gas
what is up calyx and crew podcast
listeners before the break we were
talking to gas over at swami organic
seed and we were talking about some of
his uh practices and some of his
favorite cultivars now i wanted to get
more into those brotherhood of eternal
love some of those afghanis that were
originally passed around and what made
the afghanis so special at that time gas
can you give us some insight about what
it was over in that area that just made
some of those different types so
desirable at that time
all unique and that's what's really
special about them you know because
well i guess before you know the soviet
invasion all that each family had or
tribe had their only their own type of
hatch
so they cultivated their own type of
herb you know
so like
a bulk afghanistan is some people might
consider it a mazar afghanistan because
it's in the same little area as mazar
but it's really quite different than the
mazar afghanistan
you know even though you could it's like
just a click down the road
right
it's it's it's quality is far superior
the hash is like food grade it's so like
just creamy and nice and
just every afghan has its own character
yeah isn't that amazing these little
micro climates can influence the plan so
many different ways
and it just depends on what those
farmers were doing too
you know what were they doing with their
with their herb were they taking it to
market were they exporting it what were
they doing what was their objective how
educated were they in in farming and and
everything you know
right
because if you if you're a shitty ass
farmer you're here you know you're
probably not going to be a very
successful in market
right
that's where the herb speaks for itself
right so like when i went through these
uh jahalabad
you know i went through like 200 at once
and i saw so many different things and
these were fresh out of the field
you know the next pass over from kyber
pass
oh is that where it is
yeah
and uh
some really cool stuff man i think that
was one of the coolest things i've ever
done and ever seen was opening up those
200 um jihad you know out of all the
land races and everything that was just
so cool to see
yeah i'm growing a jalalabad cross by
farmer fly right now and
one of the things that i've seen from
that is a lot of vigor and i see these
gigantic fat fingers leaves
oh man there were so many expressions
there were index indica expressions
there were sativa expressions there were
both there were ones that were just tall
there were ones that were super short
wow ones that were loaded with resins or
ones that smelled like skunk body odor
gas fuel
um ones that just smelled like [ __ ] you
know
and you know
such a range such a plethora of uh
untouched stuff you know yeah that
that's one thing that i've noticed with
these is they are very very stinky and
they have a lot of vigor i can't really
put my nose on it yet because it's our
first time going through veg but uh
definitely very very smelly fat fingered
plants on the end that i got they're
definitely um
hindu related there's some definite
hindu uh hindu-esque features in there
right right
so what what else are you working with
that just really gets you go
oh man you know i love this uh you know
five haze stuff who doesn't you know
it's it's you know it's one of the best
hybrids of all time and everything
everything you do with it is just
incredible
so
that work is really interesting to me is
just to go through these nl1s and l2 and
l5 and hazes and stuff
and experiment kind of continue on like
with what neville was doing and those
guys were doing with those combinations
you know
like like you know one by a chocolate
tie kind of thing you know what i mean
yeah have you done that one
probably
probably i like that that's your answer
but you know everything is put together
for a specific reason this is this isn't
just random throwing pollen around right
right but you've been doing it so long
you've been at it so long and you're
working a lot of the same type
well i can identify treats and plants
really easy you know and identify origin
pretty easy too
so
after you've worked with everything for
so freaking long man you just you know
what you're looking at you know we've
talked about that before too as far as
like neville having the eye for thing
and you kind of have that eye as well
yeah if you don't have the eye man
you're not gonna make it right no if you
can't select you know
easter eggs correctly it's i don't know
you know
i'm with you
but you know a lot of the things i do
and everything has intention
so like the oaxacan ibl by the chocolate
thai for example i want to combine that
with the velvet rush i want to i want to
make a mock blueberries just because
because i freaking can't
yeah absolutely let's talk about that
for a second that a velvet rush that you
have that's basically like
your version of the old juicy fruit
right well it's the first dj cross you
know the the 79 kabul afghani number one
and the 76 77 highland blue tie from the
brotherhood of eternal love
right and this was long this was uh how
many years before blueberry became a
thing
well i think he did the cross in 79 but
tj has always been
you know
not really forthcoming with his
information so we don't really know or
if you said it i never [ __ ] heard it
but
it's the highland blue tie was only
imported for 15 months
oh wow
that's what makes this particular one
unique and by 1976 77 the scouts that
had went and got it they knew what they
were looking for
you know they're heady as [ __ ]
so
i have some bluetooth why the blue line
from the highland that the that's the
blue line and everything
you know right
so that's why any any blue cross that
has that highland blue tie in it is
always dominant
that is that's ex wow
that's intriguing
so you're telling me that the blue tie
was what expressed a lot of those
blueberry flavors that that's why where
it got its name from
that's why man that's the basis of
everything blue wow i thought between
the red
tie the blue tie
green tie was just associated with the
the bud color on it and maybe where it
came from
well yeah they were different regions
too
okay
different tribes people
did different thing so but it wasn't
just the blue coloration it was actually
the flavor as well
yeah that's amazing
yeah it was the characteristics of it
everything you know yeah it just all
made sense
it's basically just those two
you know i think the first line was
juicy fruit
so what was that uh i don't know 81 82.
i was going to say early 80s yeah
and then in 86
at a brotherhood of eternal love
barbecue
uh mel frank gave this the velvet rush
back to coop and you know the other half
of it anyway
and told him and said hey these are
velvet rut
so he took him
and he gave them to his associates
who took them to san cle in the hills of
san clemente and did open pollinations
with big crops for like five or six
years
and the plants were you know they were
like 20 feet tall they said they
exhibited every color in the rainbow
they had flower from the top to the
bottom when they took it to market which
was you know la and orange county
they
you know it's always the same that's you
always hear the same thing it was the
best around
you know
so
that's the story behind that
and that's where when back in 1990 or
yeah when two got the seeds
back from them in 1990 he did a breeding
you know
okay
he um crossed him to his 88 nl5 hey
which is you know the one i have
right
and he had all those packs man somehow
that guy was hooked up and
he had everything
you know
somehow yeah
i i can't even remember but i i saw you
know 88 g hash i had that but i i think
i gave it to somebody you know because i
had so much stuff that i was just all of
a sudden had this responsibility for him
like oh my god you know
you've had that g13 for quite a while i
know your wife showed me some pictures
of the early grows in i want to say the
early 2000s that was barney and or
reaverman's airborne g13 by original hey
all right on
and it was good man everybody liked it
but as soon as i did blue orca hey
that's that [ __ ] was out the window man
you know
yeah everybody that i've seen grown that
yeah is really really appreciated
well it's it's it's for real
you know
it reminds me of uh cali mist is tame
compared to blue orca haze but they have
that that uplifting kind of everything's
cool feeling you know
right so similar effects but
much more potent
oh god yeah oh god yeah
but it's not is
is uh
debilitating his nl5 hayes itself
right right
which is you know if if you know
anything about nl5 hayes you know that
the real [ __ ] will put you in a [ __ ]
fetal position
right
i i've definitely been there it's not
it's not a pleasurable thing
you know
we'll just go light on it
well yeah if you enjoy that kind of
experience
generally younger guys do i enjoy that
[ __ ] you know but at this age man i'm
like i don't dig that [ __ ] i want to
keep my head straight
right so like blue orchid haze is the
cleaned up version of 88 and 05 hey he
could still function and and you know
be a psychonaut at the same time you
know
get your [ __ ] done and enjoy your high
exactly very nice
i'm definitely gonna have to grow that
one out um one of my followers asks what
is your favorite get things done smoke
since we're talking about your hazes is
it that blue orchid
you know that's a good one that worked
for me i like the nigerian by the punto
rojo
who for getting stuff done
very nice nigerian sunshine by punto
rojo that was great
did you get to grow out any of the
pierpontorojo
yeah yeah
but you know the hybrids are better so
right right
that's not but that's just not a type
that a lot of people get
a hold of
right so i'm going to crack some punto
rojo this spring i'm going to do cbg
you know can a biogen punta rojo and i'm
going to do the uh
i think the escobar
rojo oh wow
i'm gonna do them all at once man
and do you already have something set in
mind to put that with
well i just kind of
i have projections for what i'm going to
do every year you know what i mean i'm
going to work the mexicans this year i'm
going to work the ties this year you
know what i mean
no teasers
last year it was the afghanis i opened
up all the afghanis and did a bunch of
afghani work you know
right right now now this year i need to
repopulate some things like you know the
panama the guillermo and some stuff like
that
you know just to freshen up those seed
you know once they get past four years
old they start i start getting nervous
why is that
because their viability goes down you
know right around five years
you know
i didn't realize that was the start of
degradation if you're if you're well i
have them in storage too you know so
they're protected but what i also have
some that i bring out and i work with so
the jars are open they're in a space
you know they're sitting there because
i'm packing seed all the time right so
how do you feel about people that are
refrigerating and freezing their seed
it's a good idea
but you should really insulate
insulate the containers that you put
your seed in or it'll damage the enzyme
good tip right there
don't use rice and any of that dumb [ __ ]
just really just just really insulate
the container well
you know put some cotton in there and
then wrap it in a sock and or and then
wrap it in some tape or something like
that if you're going to store your seeds
in a regular
right give it give it some buffer so
it's not direct cold right because
you're going to lose power
and weird things like that are going to
happen and there's big temperature
fluctuations between
cold and heat and things like that it
really takes it takes a toll on the
enzyme in there
yeah just between freezing and room temp
you're gonna have some breakdown and
that can only happen so many times
before it just it just like screw you
buddy you know wow
that's a hundred dollar attempt right
there
we had a we had one smart ass follower
ask will you be working
with runs
no no runs man
no
not not doing any runs i don't even know
what it is you know what is it oh gee
kush by cookies or it's it's runs man no
i'm so out of the loop on any of that
[ __ ] i can't even keep up man
you know
it's just it's just it's absurd to me
when did everybody start naming their
stuff after candy
well i don't know i think it's more they
the taste that they want to market they
want to market it like candy because
that's the target group that they're
hitting you know
and everybody's just candy anymore
uh i don't know
when you know when you guys are saying
stuff like oh this smells like
rotten dirty gym locker socks that's
what gets me off that's what i'm looking
for
well i'll give something a name if it
then if the if the uh genetic breeding
is just way too long to say you know
right like matanuska thunder [ __ ] by
shipburg afghani by alaskan thunder [ __ ]
by 88 nl5 hayes
but even at that point you're just
abbreviating pretty much
well so why not just go okay thunder
[ __ ] ace
right right
you know right but you're not calling it
exotic
uh cheated dumb banana cream
very nice um what do you have planned
for the future is there anything that
you've always wanted to get your hands
on that you haven't been able to touch
actually no man i i really have just
everything and
you know i have a lot of ibl's and um
land races you know
so i basically have everything that i
ever need to work with there's like oh i
wouldn't mind getting a hold of the puna
bud
that's one i haven't had yeah we talked
about that one man that that one's a
hard one to find
i've seen cuts around man but they don't
look like the cuts that i've seen that i
want that's what i'm saying yet
they look kind of
wispy compared to the chunky ones i've
seen
the puna bud that was
basically just the old uh
kona
um it's
rumored to have lineage to captain cook
okay
that's all i know
i i remember my dad having a shoe box um
or telling me the story about him having
a friend that came over with the shoe
box and opened it up and there was just
a big freaking cola the size of your arm
in there
back in the early 80s and mid 80s that
was that we were kids the in the pacific
northwest we were getting some hawaiian
stuff
it was incredible
you know
um one of them was buddha bud
it was just it was just incredible it
was like wow
where'd this come from
you know
what was it that about the hawaiians
that just stuck out to you right away
it's probably just the soil that the
types were grown in
okay you know rich rich nice good
tropical kind of environment you know
so and only the types that could make it
made it
so anything that got mold or was weak it
just kind of faded away you know right
and then there were different uh
microclimates to the islands and you
know some heads took them to other
islands some heads took them on the
other side of the island where they
developed sativa traits where they
developed indica traits like the molokai
type um
that was really interesting it was
really the most indica dominant hawaiian
type that i've seen
you know and you think why why why would
they select this indica dominant type
down there and uh whatever well i was
gonna say that was one of the few that i
experienced where the buds on it weren't
as beautiful as some of the other
hawaiian type oh they were ugly as hell
too man
i thought oh it's a it was a leopard
colony
you know they were probably selecting
for high cbd if their if their relatives
had anything to do with it oh wow
because that's what people tend to do
where they work with plants they'll
select for what they need
right you know
for what feels good to them yeah that's
one that still hangs around to this day
if you go over to the islands and you
ask for molokai frost they'll have it
like the mazar pck by the mazar i put
together it's one of those two you know
it was tested on old people and people
with pain problems and things like that
so it was just basically put together
for them and as a solid indica base to
do sativa outcrosses with
right have you
done any work with uh very many africans
yeah actually
what are some of your favorite africans
um my favorite one is the trans game
really i have some of the
it's pretty neat man i like it
i like you what about it was different
just the effect
yeah the effects nice and um similar
structure to most of those well it's
like any other kind of wild sativa you
know but it it uh it was loaded with
frost
most of those african sativas actually i
i don't know if this just my experience
or this is how it is but they seem to be
shorter sativas compared to some of the
others
it just depends on you know where they
were and what everything the swaziland
uh
those were short
yeah and that's that's mostly what i've
worked with is more of that coastal
region off the cape there
and the the congo it's you know that was
out of control like a like a vine long
super long over 100 day flowering time
and all that you know
fun
but um
the durbins are uh they're pretty nice
you know
but those were also more
inland correct they're good they're good
but you know you
they have that thing where you just
can't really smoke a whole bunch you
just get wigged out you know yeah yeah
especially women and people that aren't
used to smoking uh
sativas you know
so what would you say would be a good
intro sativa that you have produced for
people like that
oh it's what you're working with right
now like a pakistani in influx into a
chocolate tie you know something that's
not predominantly indica but it has
enough indica in it to keep them kind of
grounded in case they aren't used to the
effect or something you know
right
i appreciate stuff like that
good even all day smoke
and then you know it just depends as you
explore this stuff
and you explore region and you explore
uh hybridization
you start
coming to note certain thing
about effect you know
right so like nigerian has a lot of cbd
in it well so does the punto rojo
so it was like
duh
you know
that's why it works you know
do you have any types that you work with
where you're actually selecting towards
that cbd side
yeah yeah
a lot actually
you know mo i did a lot of hash plant
work let this last year
that's basically i was basically putting
uh
hash plants together
you know for resin production
and what were some of your favorite hash
plants that you found oh you know the
blue orca by the black kandahar
you know and i put that to the
gym dog or the one by the turkish gummy
or uh
i didn't know that you were working with
that turkish gummy
the one by uh the nl2 is another
another one you know where the resin is
just going to be off the hook
you know
did the turkish cross take away from
that slender conical shape
oh i don't know these are fresh f1s man
you know i have a great background
myself
there's the ones that i want to do
i want to get into the one by the nl2
myself
just because of the similarities between
the two and the potential the potential
for the effect and the resin
absolutely
i i think i was talking to dash earlier
about that nl2 or it might have been you
he was put it was put together in canada
um over 30 years
by some canadians
who had the
advantage of a lot of space so they
could do a lot of numbers
and
they selected it out really so
everything that i've used with that nl2
comes out in l2 dominant you know which
isn't surprising
but um yeah just most of the stuff i do
is is hybridized for a certain outcome
so
you can put these planets up next to
whatever
and they're gonna out-compete them
what is your top criteria in a smoke
like are you the smell the taste the
high itself bag appeal what's most
important to you
it sounds like you're going more for
effect over anything
does taste or smell have any play into
it
it does a little bit you know that's one
of the first things that you can select
for is scent and that gives you an idea
you know what what the taste is going to
be but it doesn't work that way all the
time and you can't rely on that right
you know but i do that i'll select for a
certain characteristic dominant in that
type
you know
right
but over everything else effect is
number one
it's that's probably the most important
thing or preserving the genotype
you know how do you feel about the taste
and smell portion of that are you
looking for something that correlates
like the taste relates to the smell or
does it not matter that much as long as
it's good
oh
it's so it's such a plethora dude you
know there's so many things that
it's an endless rainbow
right if i want to make banana i can
make banana if i want to make orange i
can make orange if i want to make lemon
and it goes on and on and on right so
you're saying it depends on what your
goals are
and what you find within
while you're doing that you know just
what hits your fancy what takes all
those boxes
and the same thing with making pretty
pot too
you know
the the nice fluorescent purple
kind of stuff that everybody likes to
look at you know that takes really cool
pictures and
and uh that's really easy to do too
you know
i've always said that some of the best
stuff i've ever smoked to look like hell
generally uh
you know
it's it's gonna be the landry sativas
that are going to rock your dome the
most you know
it's not to say that uh
a pure afghani hash plant isn't going to
rock your dome just the same but in a
different region of the brain you know
right right
and we're looking for that up
clear-headed fun
get [ __ ] done
it depends on who you are and what you
do
you know everything's humans are so
unique that's why it's so big it's
critical for me to offer such a uh
you know so many choices
because everybody wants something
different everybody wanted something
that everybody wanted to run suck man
yeah
well i thank you for coming on brother i
appreciate you you've given out some
really really good information where can
people find you
um you can send me an email at swami
gear
swami.gear gmail or you can get online
you can find me on instagram you can
find us on instagram
uh my better half miss green dreams she
runs all that
all the social media and networking and
stuff and i do i'm a hands-on guy you
know right we appreciate you coming on
brother like i said um i look forward to
having you on another podcast where we
were going to talk about some of your
methods with living soil correct
yeah yeah that'd be that'd be a good one
that would be awesome especially for
people like me that are um already
practicing k f and kind of working
towards that no-till style i'm gonna
save you a lot of headaches and a lot of
money absolutely and i i can't tell you
how much i appreciate the some of that
knowledge that you've instilled on me
brother like
it wasn't just me you know there was
there was code and there was tim wilson
and we we had quite a group for quite a
while
that explored all these avenues
didn't really push the envelope to take
everything into the next hemisphere you
know right but you were one of the few
people that i personally got to interact
with you know so well i i appreciate
your character you know
it's just i don't know everything just
naturally worked out how it should i
guess you know
but you're doing the good work and
in a day and age where there is a lot of
filters that shouldn't be there um
you're putting forth information that's
correct true honest and
is tested with time you know
it'll benefit the entire planet every
everybody gets on board you know amen
regenerative farming practices and
things like that
so you know you don't really have to go
buy anything in a damn hydra store you
don't have to buy a damn thing to grow
[Music]
wow wasn't that an amazing episode i
want to give a huge shout out to gas for
joining us for the very first episode of
the calyx and crew podcast it was an
amazing episode hacked full of
information gas is always a great guy to
talk to and i'm looking forward to doing
another episode with him where we were
going to talk about living organic soils
which i am personally stoked for before
we get going i want to give one more
shout out to diamond cut company the
best trimming scissors on the market
hands down you guys can use doc minus 10
at checkout to get 10 off scissors
they're beautiful they look like a piece
of jewelry and as long as you keep them
clean they have a sharp edge we've been
using these same models of scissors over
multiple runs greenhouse outdoor indoor
and they've stood the test of time i
wouldn't use anything else and i have no
want to
i also want to give a shout out to my
family without them there would be no me
other half mrs calyx without her there
would be no dog
and of course i want to give a shout out
to my crew husky gardens country green
thumb real green daddy farmer fly
they'll all be joining me over there in
discord to help guide you in a community
of growers that wants to see you succeed
if you enjoyed this podcast and you want
to support the show i urge you to follow
us over on patreon at doc underscore
calyx we have tons of more content over
there including weekly giveaways game
day giveaway shows with grow green daddy
synthetic cultivation tutorials our
strain reviews with mrs calyx
and hopefully soon we'll be back to
mapping cannabis with country green
thumb
for our founding members we created a
single tier at only ten dollars a month
it helps support the show it helps make
all of this possible we appreciate it
and we'll try to make it worth every
penny so lastly i want to thank you all
the podcast listeners whether you want
to join the patreon or not whether you
want access to the discord and all the
giveaways all the shows with all the
guys
it doesn't even matter we appreciate
your support just for listening i urge
you to share the show with a fellow
grower that might appreciate it
we have podcasts lined up and ready with
sun leaf seed company and canna queen
genetics stoked for both those that came
out amazing both amazing people
and we have tons of more guests lined up
covering everything
from soil
microbes
to cannabis history it's going to be
amazing i'm excited for it i'm excited
for what the future holds and i hope you
all join me for it until the next
podcast or until i see you over in
patreon
this is doc alex saying good night
and grow right
thank you