[Music]
[Applause]
good evening everyone and welcome to
another exciting episode of the CX and
crew podcast we've got a very notorious
guest today none other than the man
himself her be is on the show how you
doing TP what's going on dog I'm so glad
to be here thank you this was actually a
reschedule we had scheduled this in
February and I had some surgery and some
other stuff that I had to deal with so
thank you so much for putting up with me
and having me back and we worked it out
thank you I'm glad that we finally got
you on here man what you smoking on I
see you lighting something up over there
so this is chaita
berries uh it was originally a chaita OG
cross to I mean a a chaita bananas cut
cross to
a it was some sort of like cookie
berries it's from a 209 Stone City
genetics and I went into it looking for
something banana and I found anything
but it was burnt match heads bad perm
like this this I mean just a complete
opposite but in the best way like you
know I went in looking for one thing and
what I found wasn't that but it was so
much better you know it I didn't go into
it looking for something kind of on that
funky really almost burnt nasty end but
it yeah it's so awesome and it it kicks
it kicks really good would it be fair to
say that you're kind of into those
offensive tpin oh we can have a whole
discussion about the pooping fetish this
has become a a very a very hot
discussion topic lately um we've we've
probably discussed it on six or eight
different podcasts um the growing fetish
of describing just how nasty and foul
and odiferous your weed is and just that
become a whole subculture now of the
more spoiled rancid rank the better you
know and uh yeah it's it's becoming a
new thing of just there's a whole
subculture of people that hit me up and
it's just like what's the nasty you got
anything it smells like a old diaper
that's been out for two weeks I'm like
yeah I'm sure I got something for you
man like well you know they don't call
me tur for nothing we'll definitely put
you with a flavor um but that's become
like you know it it kind of became one
of those things like we all kind of do
it a little bit and then we started
talking about the fact that we all do it
a lot and we're like yeah I'm looking
for that like burn burnt perm wrapped in
hair with some skunk and you know a baby
diaper and uh yeah it's it's just the
the descriptions descriptions and the
descriptors of of rancid weed has become
a whole subculture lately I think a big
part of that is the shock value attached
to it like right you know if I say hey
I've got something that's super
blueberry turine you're going to be like
okay there's a lot of
blueberry but if I'm like okay well you
know what you got R Hill skunk you got
your tennis ball and everything but I've
got this Pakistani chocolate tie that's
[ __ ] tastes like you're sucking on
the wet stuff that's at the bottom of
your garbage trash you're gonna be like
oh you know it's the shock value it's
what lot a lot of other artists a lot of
it's kind of been on the back of like a
lot of the chem strains I found like as
those of GMO and stuff like that as
those kind of strains have become more
popular you're starting to see a lot
more of like
Savory you know stuff that's not just
simple fruit turps right and the people
that love it love it I mean love it but
there's a lot of people that go I don't
know if I want my weed to smell like
diarrhea and the truth is it's it's a
niche that's why I kind of call it the
pooping fetish is it is very much a
niche thing and the people that love
those funky nasty turps that's what
they're looking for they don't they're
almost the sort of people that don't
want fruity weed you know you have to
appreciate that everybody's got a flavor
everybody's got a C everybody's got
something that they're really into you
know so it's like I've always said my
whole thing from minute one was to try
and cover all the bases so anybody that
hit me up and said I want a flavor I got
something for you and it really doesn't
matter what corner or niche of the weed
Market you're into I try to focus on a
little bit of something across the board
so any customer hits me up and says hey
I need a I need a gassy strain I need a
fruity strain I need a strain that's
just TPS beyond anything anybody's seen
I got you I got you okay let me get
personal with yeah you've got something
for everybody uh what's for T FEI see
that's where it comes from man so it
comes from a I have tolerance issues
I've been smoking for a little while so
there's a little bit of the thing that I
found to deal with that the best is to
constantly keep a different strain on
Deck so I have real bad add with any
strain in that I'll smoke it and then 15
minutes later later it was the greatest
thing I ever had but I'm over it now and
so a lot of it comes from just my desire
and my need to find stronger strains to
find strains that fit particular niches
and anything that'll kick through that
tolerance issue of like you know look
man I'm I'm traditionally a Dabber like
90% of the time I'm I'm smoking hash um
I found it kind of easier to smoke flour
on podcast so like it's one of those
things that you know I'll puff a couple
joints but yeah I mean really in my
pursuit of flour it's always been flavor
unique and something that'll cut through
something that's going to get you know
past everything else and that's usually
the jar I grab it's tough to say what my
favorite that a little bit
more which part they cut cut through
what do you mean oh so yeah so like I'm
just saying like I'm looking for a
strain that if I have eight jars on the
table that's the one that's going to
kick me the hardest so that's the one
I'm going to grab like I always say it's
the jar that go bre SE barrier yep yep
Goa and see the big the big problem that
we have one of the big problems that I
feel like we have in cannabis right now
is kind of the
misconception that high THC is the best
and that's it so when you walk into a
dispensary when you're buying weed it's
just what's the THC
content that is not the best way to buy
weed and quite simply because the
highest THC isn't always going to be the
one gets you the highest I know that
sounds funny because your immediate
thought is 18% is not going to get me as
high as 30% weed the truth is 18% with
high mercine levels will get you higher
than 30% weed and I know that sounds
funny but we have you know we have a ton
of discussions all the time about uh
anary tping about you know tping in
general and how they modulate
specifically mering and we've known for
years and years mercine helps THC cross
the blood brain barrier so that's why
for years you heard the joke about eat
some mangoes or you know chew on some
peppercorn peppercorns you ever chewed
on peppercorn that's some that's
hardcore bro a heavier cararo filing or
is there a significant amount of mercing
there's also significant amounts of of
mercine and so with with those higher
elevated and that's generally why mercy
and in most of my strains I like that to
be the first tarpine on the list the one
that has the the most turps of all the
others because quite simply you're going
to get higher now what I've seen this
from is I'll take strains that are 18
20% but with higher mercing levels and
I'll have people come back and say I
can't smoke that like I've had people
literally tell me like my customers are
afraid of the blackout truffle just
simply because it's a higher mercine
strain you know 20% 20% plus THC so no
slouch but it's like 30% THC usually
comes at the sake of sacrificing turbs
like there's only so much room in a tri
so if if in that triome the predominant
oil is THC the predominant chemical is
THC there's less room for other stuff
and so we're you know there there will
always be a market for high THC strains
like that's just it's the marketability
it's easy to sell your average customer
says THC yeah but as we go down the line
more and more we start to realize that
heavy TPS and the right turp Blends
matter a lot more than 30% tpps I mean
30% THC and so that's why I say for me
as much as I love flavors and I love
different flavors and I love you know
for me it's the variety for me it's the
chase for me it's what haven't I seen
yet because I've seen some awesome
strains you know through 20 years plus
of popping seeds like I I've seen I've
seen the evolution of weed As We Know it
you know I I started growing in the in
the late
90s um to be honest there weren't
genetically there weren't a ton of
options back there back then your
options were either mark emer's
catalog Amsterdam maybe go to Canada I
that was that was about it in general
there wasn't nearly the flood of genetic
diversity that we have today um and then
not only that but the the problems that
we encountered trying to acquire
genetics or even having them in our area
limited that pool even more for
sure and that's something that we were
talking about the other day is some of
those old strains you know you get a
nice Panama Red or something like that
that's only testing what 15 to 18%
that's not what it is it's the canabo
profile and it's how those canabo
interact with each other to give you
that high that's the most important
thing absolutely absolutely and the
thing that we're seeing kind of
now so back in the 90s when I started
growing there were still a lot of those
very basic profile strains so it was
either piny or it was skunky or it was
Berry but back then it was kind of rare
that you would hit a strain and you'd go
man there's so much going on here I
can't really describe all of this you
know and in the world of poly hybrids in
the world of you know everybody with a
closet can be a breeder and can make
their own seeds um we're we're really
now seeing the TR diversity of the gene
pool oh yeah because it's there's more
people breeding now more people growing
weed than at any point in history um the
sheer amount of weed that's being grown
because it's done legally in so many
places now is far surpassing anything
we've ever seen and the Beautiful part
of that is we're seeing the expansion of
the genan pool at such a rate
that it's it's really tough to tell you
what what tomorrow holds in the simple
fact that we're also seeing along with
all these poly hybrids and all these you
know multi crosses we're also seeing so
many people going back to some of the
older stuff you're seeing people
reworking old stuff you're seeing people
who bust open seed collections after 10
15 years and really just start to pull
out stuff that you know it it meant
something to them they collected it um
but the tragedy of that is you know we
keep getting into this discussion about
W without kicking up a bunch of mud
skunk for instance skunk's one of those
profiles that everybody talks about it's
gone it's gone we lost all the good
skunk we lost all the good skunk well
why like why do you think that's the
case and the answer is usually because
those older plants didn't adapt as well
to indoor cultivation they were
specifically bred in whatever region
they came from largely to be outdoor
plants grown in specific environments
and as everything moved indoors you know
plants that didn't keep up plants that
hmed too much with skunk particularly
plants that grew 20 feet tall and didn't
really yield all that much weight those
plants didn't make it long term and so
that's why I tell people all the time
what's really important is if you love a
plant make more seeds of it find a way
to make more seeds because that
guarantees that whatever profile you
love whatever plant you're in love with
makes it to another generation and it
can be tomorrow's favorite strain too
you know we don't have to get there and
be like you remember that one strand in
the day I wish we'd have kept it you can
do that you know find find two seeds and
breed them find your two favorite
strains and breed them together you know
you really be surprised man and that's
what makes sure that those favorite
strains that you loved from yester year
make it on to the next generation and
make it you know to somebody else to
talk about down the
road isn't take much work to do a
preservation effort and you know it's
something that's extremely important
especially for the future of cannabis I
remember talking to a patreon member
just like yesterday I think it was um
about how back when I started smoking
almost everything tasted like Pine like
heavy pining or heavy mercing there
wasn't a lot of genetic diversity maybe
when we started getting some orange butt
up from Cali or from Nevada um but
almost everything tastes the same but it
had kind of a different look or it was a
little bit heavier in this tpine than
the other one you know but uh about the
time of like white widow White Rhino BC
bud and all that Northern Lights like
that's mainly what it was right um but I
think an important thing to note like
you were saying the genetic diversity
that we have we have all these uh tping
that you just don't find in cannabis
showing up more and more often uh the
more breeders that are out out there the
more people that are breeding towards
these different traits than we've ever
seen before not only that but like uh
when I did the Egyptian land race this
Sinai uh I always say siai say it [ __ ]
up but that was one that was very heavy
in granal and granal I was looking at
because it was apparently the turpine
that was responsible for like stone
fruit and Peach flavors but that
tpine doesn't just Express as Peach it
can express multitude of ways along that
spectrum and that's not just that one
tpine that's [ __ ] how many is there I
don't even know right so kind of what
you're what you're knocking on here kind
of goes back a little bit to what we
were talking about uh in the the kind of
the early to mid 90s as you started to
see more breeding specifically in
cannabis right it was generally for high
THC they were largely breeding for heavy
Tri comes heavy resin but at that time
most people weren't breeding for tur
beans so in that push to breed higher
THC and higher THC strains you generally
phased out so many ancillary turpins so
many of those turpins that maybe only
appear in smaller amounts and so as
we're seeing now the other thing that we
see now is the rise in testing so we now
have more access to testing turpine
testing cannaboid testing than we've
ever had before it's still not perfect
like you as as a person on the street
can't really just take a 100 samples and
send them to a lab and get TP tests but
all of the dispensaries all the legal
entities that are running grows right
now all have access to testing of some
sort so what that's doing is we're also
we're starting to see all of these
strains that we've had for years and
years and years being run out documented
with test results right right and now
we're starting to see that there are
other turpins there that we weren't even
paying attention to and whether it's a
concerted effort to actually breed for
specific turp flavors or it's just an
effort to we're not as concerned with
high THC now we're willing to breed for
other things like flavor and for you
know cont other content other than just
THC so so with so many breeders you
might have a favorite flavor and it
might be some strain that's really high
in some unique or odd tarpine and I say
really high really high in comparison
right some of these TPS that you're
mentioning and especially some of the
ancillary TPS that are kind of there in
smaller amounts when I see these turp
wheels and it's like this turp smells
like you know lavender and this turp
smells like it's so tough because in
that triome is a soup of different
Tarpin uh you know thigh of there's all
kinds of flavor molecules we still don't
know what all is there yeah because the
best labs are only testing for turpins
and cannaboids most of them aren't
testing I haven't seen at least full
spectrum tests of everything that's in
that resin you know that's that's in in
the triome and that's the real kick
right now is we keep bringing up every
time we talk about turps somebody brings
up gas somebody brings up gassy turps
and THS and skunky tpps and th we still
don't
know what all is there yeah because it's
not something you can really just call
up a lab and say Hey I want to test for
THS in my cannabis those places don't do
that that's not to say they can't but
I've never seen a full write up of every
single thing that's in cannabis resin so
it's like we're still only seeing a
small piece of the picture you know
we're we're seeing the part that we're
looking at and there's still so many
other things going on there that we
still don't really we we're either not
capable of testing for or we just don't
understand I think that's a big thing
about you know it's not federally legal
so there's not as much testing that we
can do on it but I'm really glad that
you brought that up because you're
you're right there is so many turpins
that we know of already I don't remember
how many anymore is it right under
something like that the other side to it
is it's all commercial based so it's
like all of the testing that's generally
happening happens for one of two reasons
state
regulations or marketing
curiosity right that's kind of all of
the Cannabis Testing that happens you
have to test for things like pesticides
and THC in some states some states
require tpine testing some don't um but
the truth is those are all done because
it's not in a scientific method you know
it's not because we're just curious
about what all is here and we just want
to look and see or you know it's just
that's not why it's done it's all
literally done to either pass
inspections
or because you can use it to Market and
say oh we have you know High TPS in this
and high TPS you know but most tpping
testing is is it's not done as in an
exploratory way you know what I'm saying
it's not can we figure out what all is
here it's just give me something I can
use to Market my strain better when I
put it on a shelf to somebody you know
yeah I'm glad that you brought that up
though like I was going to say not only
like we talked about can one turpine
Express you know variety of different
smells um but how it interacts with
other tpping as well is going to change
that profile so I might inbred line uh
this granal tpine within my Heritage so
much where everything's is expressing
Peach but the minute it comes in contact
with a new chirping that's not used to
is really going to change that profile
to where it doesn't Express exactly
Peach anymore right
right pretty amazing uh Jesse harle
wants to know in terms of
say he wanted oh guys if you have
questions throw them back up I [ __ ] up
the
Q&amp;A um but he wanted to know if had any
problem fuing seeds if he fued seeds oh
no no no no no no no no and I'm kind of
glad this came up because this is
probably one of my three or four
favorite topics to talk about so I'm a
firm believer in open source
genetics if you purchase a pack of seeds
those seeds are yours to do as you
please if there's male plants there and
there's female plants there you paid for
those plants those plants belong to you
and how you use them is up to you um if
that means you F2 and and and sell them
that means you F2 them and give them
away to everybody on the planet it's
your prerogative man um I I I'm a firm
believer that if you're selling regular
sex seeds you paid for all of those
seeds they belong to you and what you
want to do with them I have no control
over I always tell people I always
appreciate a pack if you shoot me a pack
just so I can throw it in the bin and I
have a pack but it's not required and
it's one of those things that I tell
other people ask your breeder that
question and see how many of them tell
you no I got no problem with it because
there's a lot of people in the in the
seed industry that will get super angry
about that will throw fits I had an old
man try to swing on me mons and it it
it's the
funniest you know the the ego and the
amount of like it's mine I'm gonna
control it you sold it to somebody and
you why you trying to fight nature 10
seeds they paid for all 10 of them yeah
it's there was nothing on that pack that
said you got to throw half of these in
the
garbage you know and it's the truth
is we all eat well it doesn't take a
dollar out of my pocket if you sell f2s
of my seeds people know that I made the
original and if they want the Next
Generation they're going to come to me
and the reality is I can't control it
anyway so why would I get angry to the
point where I want to fight somebody or
yell at people online I've seen so much
over you know people F2 and seeds and
then getting their feelings hurt and the
truth is
a lot of the people that get mad about
that paid stupid money for their Cuts
because they're usually suckers and
that's why they get so in their feelings
about it because they've paid a premium
to have the cut or the only cut or you
know and I don't really work with cuts
I'm I've never paid anybody a
significant amount of money for cuts
like I bought cuts at a dispensary once
years and years back but like I've never
paid somebody thousands of dollars for a
cut of weed nor would I um I'll just
wait until you cross it and then get
those and and make my own seats right I
hate to I hate to say it man but like I
believe firmly in open- Source genetics
I believe that you know you buy them
from the person that made them because
you love them and then what you do with
them is is you I mean that's you know
I'm not in every grow so I can't I can't
do anything about it even if you did but
I fully support people that do I always
joke these are all just crayons and my
my biggest desire is that one day
somebody takes one of my crayons and
paints a
masterpiece and in that we can all share
there's so much to go around there's no
lack of genetics if you really think one
cut is the end all be all cut pop some
more seeds because there's there's other
stuff out there there's better stuff out
there every time somebody shows me the
cut to end all Cuts I just go I hope you
didn't pay a lot for it man there
there's just better stuff out there and
it's not there's so much like I said
there's so much ego in like do you have
the cut is that the cut from such and
such like are you sure that's the only
cut can you verify that that's the I
don't
care I don't I don't care I don't care
to even have that discussion you know
like I would rather make my own
something amazing and sell it to you as
something amazing then just rip off
something somebody else is doing and
just say man I chased down this one cut
I paid $5,000 for it and now I'm gonna
pimp it out as hard as I can I just it's
not my thing I'm kind of old school I
like seeds you know like I said when I
came up there weren't a lot available to
me so once I could make them I literally
just thought of myself as like Johnny
apple seed like I just want to make all
the flavors and I want to try all the
flavors and I want to try and I want to
spread them as far as I can
and so I've always tried to keep my
genetics affordable we do tons of
giveaways and freebies and you know like
ways for people to to to get tons of
good genetics for reasonable prices and
so many people now they just assume
because it's an expensive pack of seeds
it's a great pack of seeds and I've I've
popped them all man like I I've popped
your six s $800 packs of seeds and I've
popped the stuff out of Joe's
closet nine times out of 10 I'm going to
go with the closet guy there's only one
or two people at that top Echelon of
price that I would spend my money
again and you know let's be honest like
most great genetics shouldn't be
expensive you know unless you're like I
said you're paying 10 grand for a
cut why let's let's throw a range on
this what do you think is an acceptable
and moral price for a pack of seeds uh
minimum to
Max if we're talking about anything
under an
F5 right 100
bucks you know is that Max yeah $100 is
the top end of what I you know and this
is as a buy listen man this is as a
buyer I'm not necessarily saying this is
somebody who eats off of seeds I'm
saying this as somebody who's spent 20
years collecting yeah yeah 20 years
colle collecting um you know 20 years
hoarding my own flavors and my own seeds
and you know and so for me if I'm buying
seeds and it's over a hundred bucks a
pack it better be something that I can't
live without which is real rare for me
like I said I don't I don't get attached
to strain so like there's nothing I've
ever had that I wouldn't just say I'll
find another one right you know I found
this one you know and
so if we're talking about something F5
or
higher then we get into like how big is
the breeder how well-known is the
breeder how well-known is the pedigree
of the genetics that we're talking about
if this is some stuff that they've been
growing in in Northern California for 40
years then you can usually guess that
this is of a pedigree that's a little
bit higher genetically than just a
somebody did in their closet you know
like there's it just depends on what
we're talking about but anything under
than anything under an F5 I'd have a
hard time paying crazy money for now
there's two brands that I would I would
I would kind of make an exception there
they're both kind of Legacy Brands out
of
California um and they're on the kind of
the upper
end um and I would I would buy their
seeds again in a minute let's be honest
man anado and dying breed are the only
two companies that I would 100% vouch
for every seed that I've popped was
worth every nickel that went into it um
I've been in a weird position like just
having an Instagram page and I had
people hit me up and just go man I got
all these seeds and we went to a cup and
we spent a bunch of money and now I'm
scared to pop them because they're so
expensive I feel like I'm G to I'm just
going to screw it up you know and it's
like so I had people come to me and like
trade me my seeds for stuff that they
had picked up at cups and couldn't you
know couldn't bring themselves to run
and so I had stuff kind of fall in my
lap at one time and I was just like I'm
going to run it all and see what's you
know what's worth running what's garbage
what's you know I'll never touch again
and in that price range there's a couple
other brands that you know I won't talk
negative on anybody um but there's a
couple other brands that I would I would
say or maybe not worth spending that
kind of money on unless it's just
something you can't live without you
know you're allowed to have your
opinions man yeah absolutely yeah
absolutely but if you don't know what
you're buying right if we're just
talking about the average seed buyer who
sees a a three to $500 pack and goes is
that worth my
money do the research really heavily at
that point you know it's one thing if
you buy a 6070 pack of seeds and you got
got 10 shots to find a winner and let's
say nothing comes of it that's a whole
lot different than when you've invested
$500 a pack and now every seed needs to
be a winner in your
eyes right you don't have the margin of
error because you've invested so much
this is I'm talking about your average
seed buyer I'm not talking about the guy
that's got 180,000 square foot in an
unlimited seed budget you know I'm
talking about your average collector
who's they been in it for a little while
here's these bigname Brands and then
goes what expensive it's got to be good
you know why would they charge so much
for it because they
can that's that's the only reason like
those genetics aren't super special
nobody's ever had them you know like
once again that goes back to the open-
source nature of
genetics there's in a ton of
[ __ ] several years ago um when I was
talking to two different breeders uh one
of them you actually named and we were
talking
about that cap that I just asked you
about and what's morally and ethically
right to charge for a pack of seeds and
we were talking about there was a couple
packs that a breeder had put up but they
were asking thousands of dollars for 10
seeds and I said that's it's not worth
it and I had another breeder that was
involved with that breeder hit me up
really go on the defense right away and
say well you don't know what you're
[ __ ] talking about these are you know
been held for so many generations and
everything I said at the end of the day
what's going to come out of that is a
plant albe it maybe an extremely inbred
well-worked beautiful plant it is still
a plant and I
can't being worth it at the end of the
day let's be honest okay deep filial
inbreeding is only good for
breeders right so as a
grower I would never I would never pay
that money for that ever exactly as a
breeder and that's why I get back to if
I'm paying you that kind of money I'm
paying you for the fact that you're
selling Legacy strains you're selling
pedigree genetics and I am going to use
them to breed with because that's the
only reason somebody would pay that kind
of money for those names as a grower
it's irrelevant like there's so many
hype strains out right now that like and
it's been a couple years I feel like
since we've had like a really big this
is the hype strain everybody has to have
you know I don't know if it's a little
post-pandemic lull High Times hasn't
been doing as many events to tell people
I people are nishing out more especially
you know with you me everybody kind of
moving towards Discord all right
Instagram shoving us off there
cancelling us out um YouTube's taking
down channels like Discord is I think
it's the future and I think people are
going to Niche out like that because I
don't have to follow a page of [ __ ]
and scroll through trying to find tur's
post today I can just go to tur's
Discord and check all that out I don't
have to just choose t i can choose tur I
can choose you know CeX and crew podcast
or whoever I follow and have multiple
Discord accounts that I can pop between
and find exactly what I'm looking for
you know and I think that's important to
note right now but like you said as well
um sadly from a Growers perspective I
think a lot of people nowadays like the
hype boy cut keeping guys uh are doing
that like you said equating this is a
high price this is going to be good for
me you know or this G to be something
extremely special and usually I find
that those people are basing more how
much money can I make off of finding a
really good one and selling cuts of it
than keeping it for myself the truth is
if we've run enough seeds if we've all
run enough strains you've
seen the most amazing top tier of
weed let's let's be honest dank weed is
dank weed like at at the best top point
of
cultivation then it all comes down to
flavor there's so much Frosty weed and
there's so much it's beautiful and it's
just gorgeous nugs but what does it
taste like that's what really has become
the deciding factor and I think that's
why we're seeing so many little
niches right is that it comes down to
flavor and and taste and people come to
realize well it's like hype doesn't
always mean it's the best hype usually
meant it looked pretty in a picture and
somebody posted it on the internet and
somebody else went I got to have that
you know or somebody in a marketing
company at one of these large brands has
essentially said now we're pushing out
XYZ strain we're going to have our
rapper WAP about it we're going to have
our marketing team hit every social
media hard with it it's going to be the
next thing everybody's talking about
that's usually what we're talking about
there is branding and marketing more
than just the most amazing strain of
weed um usually don't get me wrong
they're usually gorgeous but if you sit
down with 10 of the greatest growers in
this country right every one of them
have Frosty dank nugs the one that's
going to walk up from that table and
walk away being the one that knew they
had the Dank was the one whose jar stank
the most because we all have jars of
stank you you know like any great grower
has jars of stinky weed but the one
that's going to get everybody is that
flavor that makes all the ogs go what is
that I gotta have that the jar that goes
the fastest that's how we always joked
about it if we all sat down and threw
our jars in the middle of the table and
you could smoke anything you wanted all
day long the jar that empties the
fastest is going to be the best
one and that's almost never just the the
most resinous one it's always the
dankest flavor patreon member dank Panda
wants to know I have a pineapple
meatball F2 and veg that smells of rank
feet and vomit will it hold or get more
putrid and
flour so if you haven't gotten the
pineapple flavor on that yet like so
some of those kind of go both ways
there's kind of a funky pooping uh I
heard people say Italian meatballs it
get really weird and savory meat um and
then there's some that have more
pineapple and then there's some that
kind of have both it sounds like you've
got the more meat breath leaning
feno um and yeah I would I would expect
that one to make your friends kind of
run like that one you bust that one out
in the car and somebody's going to think
they [ __ ] themselves um yeah and once
again man like that I in my selections
I'm not sure you said F2 um when I did
the f2s and the f3s my goal was to work
with plants that exhibited kind of an
even mix
because I think that strain really
shines when it's got both the kind of
funky rancid stuff but it's also got
this candy pineapple thing on the top
and it really does kind of remind you of
like a a burnt ham with pineapple rindes
on it or something like it's it's really
unique and Meaty um but but my favorite
ones are kind of an even blend of the
two um I've also selected in that line
away from what I I like to call the
mutant Leaf Fen knows of meat breath um
you can usually tell them about you know
a couple weeks into veg all the leaves
just throw this ugly mutation and you
just go what's wrong with this and it's
just it's it really just is a leaf
mutation but I found those plants don't
tend to be as vigorous as you know
profile typical as I like those tend to
have just a boring cushy profile as much
as I love Kush like that's not that
wasn't my goal with that line that line
in general all those pineapple sorbet
crosses just unbelievably complex and
unique um and that meatball yeah you're
probably stuck with the funk on that one
I hope that's what you like if you need
to we're going to start a uh we're gonna
start a group essentially you know a
support group we we'll figure out where
um we'll just call it poopin Anonymous
or pooping fetish Anonymous um and we'll
just we'll just have a forum where
people can kind of talk dirty to each
other about the the the rank of their
weed and whether it you know they can
argue about whether it smells like feed
or you know bad little sub threads G
really there really there really needs
to be a place for these people to gather
um that guy seemed like he might have
had a little bit of it and been looking
for a place to find other likeminded uh
pooping heavy individuals I've got an
appreciation for a little bit of
everything uh I I do love my pooping I
love some nasty [ __ ] uh I just feel like
those ones whatever is going on with a
lot of those style heavy ones just get
my head right that that high is the high
that I typically look for not always um
but in general another one is Dynasty
genetics I grow a lot of their gear and
he mostly does like sweeter Berry stuff
you know um but yours is one that I've
definitely been looking at as well I've
never grown own any of your genetics but
I really want to it's very you already
sent me some SE okay I I mean I'm giving
them to other people but if you don't if
you don't have seed around I'd be more
than happy to pay for it man that's that
that is morally and ethically correct uh
you know I've gotten seeds from breeders
before uh but I always always offer to
pay and I still do even you know I'd
never have to pay for seeds uh from a
lot of these people I could just ask for
them but I still pay for them just
because I think that's important you
know if you got a homie that has a
business like that you you don't have
like I have one friend that started up a
restaurant it's like a festar restaurant
it's big money like to go in there it's
going to be an expensive meal yeah but
I'm still going to go in there and I'm
still going to spend money I'm not going
to expect a free meal because this is my
friend and I want to support them you
know I think that's what's important
with we're still even like how many
times that's happened to us and we go in
and then the friend still comps the meal
you better tip that waitress 20% on top
of what the meal was going to cost and
that lady just had the best night of her
life like you better still leave that
money in that business because that's BR
that's the truth of it is that you know
so much of us that that run businesses
on our own um it's it's so much bigger
than any one facet right you have to be
the marketing team and you have to be
the you know the the grow and you have
to be you have to do it all yourself and
especially in this business the ones
that are still doing it now even people
that love it because the 2020 boom came
everybody had those stimulus checks it
was easy to be a seed vendor for a year
and a half there and lots of people made
money but the last year year and a half
man you know it separated a lot of those
people that were just here for a quick
Buck um so many of those quick seed
banks folded and you know that's the
business I've seen so many of these bust
and Booms to the point where it's like
it's not uncommon for people right now
to not be in this industry in a year and
a half you know it's easy to do weed for
a year year and a half it's a lot
tougher to do it for 15 20 years plus
because you have to change with the
market you have to realize that the
market is changing you know if you were
selling flour 14 15 16 you know you had
a hard realization the market changed
drastically when all these huge legal
grows came online in in legal states the
flower market changed probably
irreparably at this point like I don't I
don't know if we'll ever see some of the
the high water marks of you know what
people were getting for for flour there
and it's like so many people have
shifted now into seeds because once
again there's there's still reasonable
money if you know how to Market yourself
and but yeah it's it's you got to love
it you have to love legalization there's
still a market for craft cannabis I
think that's really important uh just
you know if we're going to compare uh
different drugs uh then we should be
comparing this to alcohol if that's how
you're trying to regulate it then we
should compare it to that and there's
still a niche for those Craft Market um
and at the end of the day with more
people getting into cannabis um you're
not going to see that big money Rush
it's just like any other industry when
it starts up when it's limited there's
big money in it after a while you're
going to notice it's still agriculture
you know farming agriculture is tough
yeah yeah it's farming that's what
nobody tells anybody that gets in the
weed industry nobody ever straight tells
you farming it's a farming it's indoor
farming which is very unnatural like for
90% of the people who aren't growing in
you know Open Fields which I I don't see
too many commercial grow grows like that
yeah it's unnatural you know and we're
trying to play God and we're trying to
create you know environments that are
perfect and we're trying to you know and
I don't know man I keep saying that
every business that's in business right
now as soon as it goes federally legal
within three years we'll get bought out
by a bigger company and once again all
these people will be pushed out of the
industry who were largely just here to
make a quick Buck funny enough it's been
de de ad since weed was a quick Buck you
know if you were growing in the late 90s
or early 2000s and you were brave and
you had a decent sized Black Market grow
you were probably eaten okay but the
overhead and you know it's always been a
tough business and the notion that
you're just going to make a bunch of
quick fast money like I've seen people
make decent money just moving packs like
just middlemen but like I've never known
an intensely wealthy grower
you know like even the people that run
most of these large cannabis companies
aren't weed people they're people who
made money in real estate who made money
in some other facet they've got
investors most of them aren't people
that spent their lives in a cannabis
grow and most of those people are still
just growing on their own because
there's really no money working in
another person's grow making you know
what amounts to for some people people
McDonald's manager salary or less you
know like they're not throwing tons of
money at Great Growers and that's why
you've got so much mediocre weed in
dispensaries is because it's grown by a
coary of who just got off the bus 22 23
year old kids who just love weed and
they will work for nothing just to tell
their family back home they're working
in a weed grow little do they know that
job only lasts about six months to a
year because once a year they do
cyclical firing get rid of everybody
there and bring in the next set of
20-year-old kids who can do it for less
money than you just
did pretty s that's why all the weed and
dis if you want a quick fast on why all
the weed and dispos sucks that's it
right there before we move on to some
more questions I wanted to ask you you
said you started growing in uh the 90s
early 90s mid late 90s late 90s okay uh
what was some of those first types that
you were grow so the first handful of
plants that I ever grew were bag seed
you know and so you kind of you kind of
mentioned before we started about
chatting about some things that kind of
was into so at about
16 156 I did my first fish
show uh fall
97 um from then like that opened my eyes
in a huge way to weed in general because
I had you know so much more access and
so occasionally you just get some great
weed with just a sprig nugget here just
a seed here or there you know kind of
set those aside and once we finally got
to a point where we were like let's just
try it let's just throw some plants in
the woods and let's just give it a
go I had some you know I don't even
honestly probably didn't even know what
it was it was bag seed from fish tour of
some
sort and then at some point um I got on
to probably IC mag was the first Forum
where I reached out like I spent a lot
of time lurking on early
overgrow uh we had a computer in our
house in like the late 80s so like I saw
the entirety of the internet Bloom and
Blossom and so as you know overgrow
became a thing and then got shut down I
did a lot of lurking there uh you know
probably picked up my first BHO tech
there um um tons of you know subcool
super soil stuff and you know stuff that
honest to God was was so valuable and
just teaching me um because back then I
felt like everybody wasn't an expert
that's been my big beef with like forums
for a while I always joke it's just
experts telling experts how to be
experts now nobody's ever just like I'm
learning something like I'm here to
learn a lot of it is just everybody
wants to boss and say no that's not
right you're absolutely wrong that's not
the way to do it um and so for a long
time I just lurked on these forums and
sucked up as much as I could and I think
it was around IC mag probably in the
early
2000s um the 2000 2001 2002 that I
finally reached out and was just like
hey look I got these seeds that I've
kind of played around with on my own and
I can trade them for something else and
I started trading with people um and
that was probably the the very
beginnings of just getting my hands on
stuff
now some of my favorite stuff from back
then uh there was a a haze number one
cross cut that came around or a flower
that came around really heavily that was
through one of my good buddies that was
super unique um and really gave me like
kind of the essence of what Haze was uh
there's there's so little Haze these
days that like it was it was one of
those like perfect very typical samples
um as far as stuff that I grew early on
that I just absolutely loved uh I had a
double purple Doge of Mental Floss from
a cat called like Outlaw grower Outlaw
breeder maybe um from the seed Bay days
that I fell in love with uh deep chunk
is one of the the first strains that
like really hooked me got me into cush
got me really into like heavy medicinal
mercing heavy
strains um and then I run a deep Congo
which was another you know odd beautiful
sativa indicia pairing it was a one that
I got from from across from a friend
online um but that just you know it was
my first fouras into kind of digging
into what's out there now it really
wasn't
until you know probably 2010 and later
that I really had a a super access to
just anything you know and really got a
full Taste of everything that was out
there you know spending years in
Colorado um just with access to every
dispensary and everything you could have
access to working in you know tons of
commercial facilities running most of
the gear that they ran you know when you
work in a facility Cuts tend to make it
into everybody's grow so you're all
growing whatever you know whatever the
grow grows um and so through that man I
had finally access to just all of the
flavors and it was literally like a kid
in a c candy store because I finally had
for so many years it was just whatever
came bought you know you might get weed
from your buddy or he might have two
different kinds if you were like me you
were on tour you might rent into four or
five people with a couple but it was
kind of uncommon to get a
selection you know to get eight or 10
different kinds of weed and all of them
be
unique and it wasn't really until I
started growing my own heavily and and
getting access to seeds and and just
popping whatever I could get my hands on
that I finally got to that point where
I'm like I still don't think I know
everything that's there but I have a
much better understanding now of of the
possibilities you know because so many
of those earlier strains like I said
were so one note that now we're seeing
these beautiful combinations of
different things and different flavors
in different ways it it's just
unprecedented um so when did the switch
occur
between growing and deciding I'm going
to breed my first
plant it wasn't they weren't far behind
but back then it was purely
necessity like it wasn't with the air of
I'm GNA one day be selling seeds I you
know I wish I had that sort of
foresight because it really it wasn't
until maybe 25 15
2016 that I really went at breeding as a
full-time thing and as a as a passion
and is something that you know I wanted
to work on
wholeheartedly um I'd always just been a
grower and I bred in little small
projects on my own largely because like
I said it was two strains that I loved
or it was something I knew I was going
to lose for some reason or couldn't keep
up with had to shut a grow you know
whatever the the situation was and so it
was back then it was more more of just a
necessity I didn't have access to all
the genetics that I have access to today
um and so it was just kind of one of
those things where if I had two strains
that I loved I'd breed them together so
that I you know I had something and when
I started breeding full-time I had some
of these projects that I had worked on
but to be honest it wasn't ever at that
point with an eye towards I have a goal
like I want to breed a strain with
flavor or I have a you know it was
almost always just two strains I love
both these strains I want to make
another strain that's you know across of
these and keep them around or if I had
access to F1 you know enough seeds I'd
do an F2 um but yeah back then
especially when it was just you know
stuff that I had gotten off of forums or
stuff that I had worked with um just
here and there those were just I wanted
to try other stuff you know because I
didn't have this great access I mean I'm
from the the East Coast we had whatever
came by you know we generally lived in a
bubble and didn't really have
until you know like I said maybe the
early 2000s finally had access to just
other stuff that we could get maybe know
a buddy that had a cut um I ran a couple
of I got I got spider mites twice for
the same Purple Kush cut I gotta be
honest with you man I'd fight again to
get her back like it's one of the few
that like got away that I don't know if
I've seen in the exact same condition
since the last time I saw her and I'll
see if I can get you one that kid gave
me mites twice and I knew I knew the
second time I was gonna get him and I
was like I gotta I gotta have it I gotta
have it I uh my well I everybody knows I
grow up a farm kid uh but not a lot of
people know I also grew up up uh you
know involved in a motorcycle Community
I'll say won't shout out names
um but I still know a group of bikers to
this day that have the purple cush and
like because it had unmistakable leaves
right like that was a defining trait of
it and one day one of them came or he
just grew plants you know he got clones
every year from his buddies and he just
grew them out that's all he did and uh
he goes can you come over over here and
kind of like show me how you're he he
want he was an old school grower that
never really done anything like I said
just water his plants uh but he saw some
of the things that I was doing he's like
can you come over and kind of show me
how to like strip them and like
defoliate them a little bit where I'm
going to get my bud production where I
want it to be like yeah absolutely man
and he started shouting out some
different stuff you know and this a few
years ago so there was like some jack
crosses
um I don't remember all what he had but
it wasn't all like super old stuff and
then right at the end of his garden he
goes oh and I got a purple cush over
here and I was even being a smart ass
then and I was like yeah we'll see you
know like we'll we'll see and I walk
over the Clone and I see it and I see
that long middle leaf that slender
pointed shape and I was like that's
[ __ ] purple cush and he's like well I
hope so my guys have been [ __ ]
growing this for like how many decades
now I'm like holy [ __ ] dude I haven't
seen the first time I got that I grew it
one time oh wow out in a greenhouse and
it was just strictly production and I
fell in love with it but I fell in love
with it afterwards I like the plant as
is it's not a commercial producer like
it's not one that you're just gonna you
know grow shitloads of weed of but it's
it's very typical and it's one of those
that when you see it you know it I miss
her so much it's the only one away
that's the only one like people ask me
all the time about like what strain of
all the strains that you had what strain
would you you know is there one you
always wanted or it's probably that one
she never came
back oh I'll see if I can get a hold of
that one yeah and uh I'll I'll keep you
in the loop with it magician wants to
know why don't you have pictures of your
stuff on your
website so we have been
through
uh three PayPal accounts two venmo
accounts a cash app account and three
credit card
processors okay anybody that's tried to
get a credit card processor in the last
couple of years will tell you that the
few that are legitimate credit card
processors that will even have a
conversation with you if you're a seed
vendor are very particular about what
you can
put um so what we originally were're
going to do was put pictures of all the
strains put descriptions put you know if
we could get THC contents and stuff like
that and so when we signed up for this
most recent credit card processor we had
to go through the underwriting process
which is normal of any proper banking
situation and they were pretty much like
look the less info you put on there the
better and nothing about like THC
percentages content Turing profiles so
what we're working on doing and once
again anybody that's followed me for a
while now knows I'm on my fourth
Instagram page I've lost about 60,000
followers um I've probably lost 15,000
pictures of my of my strings um I put
eight years into my first page and it
got shut down with 30,000 followers
broke my heart but what we decided to do
was to start redistributing all of our
advertising of of all kinds so now what
I'm doing is all the weed pictures are
on my subreddit which is RT F genetics
um what I do still have is there and as
I get more pictures we're leaving them
there now instead of Instagram so that
when they get taken down I don't lose
years of my work you know that's my
fault you know it's my fault like when
you do everything when you do it all
yourself you kind of get into this like
it's easier to just have one social
media page so I can just oh so I can
just do everything you know in one place
and I don't necessarily have to have six
different pages you know it's like you
said with Discord there's a really
healthy community on my Discord now um
you know those guys share tons of
pictures of my work um and for me I kind
of am completely hands off with it in a
sense that like I'm not over moderating
it I'm not like telling people if you
have a problem with my gear gear please
go tell somebody like tell me you know
I've always said if you have a problem
with my gear I'll replace it happily you
tell me what your issue is we'll talk
through it I'll figure it out you know
seeds are living things and it happens
but um the reason I don't have any
pictures on my Instagram page now is
because I'm tired of getting them shut
down um I'm really kind of sick of it um
and so I'm not putting any more weed
pictures on Instagram for the time being
until we can figure out how they can
stay there
um yeah how about on your Discord oh
Discord yeah Discord anything goes there
I mean that's one of those things that
like I I need to start getting more
active in like posting there but I also
don't want it to be one of those thing
I'm really weird about the
self-promotion [ __ ] man and maybe I'm
just old school I I kind of joke that as
soon as they're dead air I start
plugging but like that's something I had
to teach myself to do it's not something
that like comes supernaturally to me of
like I just need to I want everybody to
see everything I'm doing 247 so it's
like once I get into a habit of this is
where I'm sharing weed pictures man I
forget there's six other places I need
to go post that same picture you know
right that's kind of tough man like I do
have other things going on like I I do
weed my day but like I do try to have
some semblance of a life as well and so
it's like one day I'll pay somebody to
handle all of that social media YouTube
run my podcast like we're just not there
yet you know a lot of us are
bootstrapping our our our our our
businesses and a lot of us started with
absolutely nothing and have built names
and brands that people recognize to some
degree and that just comes from being
persistent um I've put hundreds how long
have you been public with turine
genetics 17 I'm sorry 16
2016 t genetics yeah 2016 was when it
became like fulltime yeah yeah and that
was after a few years of in the
commercial industry doing a little bit
of everything I want to I won the first
ever rosin competition with a with a
hash company um you know I I worked in a
bunch of large commercial grows did it
on my own for 18 years on the other side
of the law um and that was really 2015
was probably the beginning of me
starting a social media page the
original t fiend page that's now long
defunct and reset um and I did that
until 2020 when they shut the first one
down so it was like six years or
something like that that I had built
that first page um and then after that
like I started doing the growcast uh
Jordan is an absolutely awesome dude um
he was one of those people that like
when they shut down my Instagram leveled
with me and was like you shouldn't have
relied on them so heav heavily don't do
it again it wasn't like that but that
was exactly the point was he he was
essentially saying like get a website
diversify make sure you've got you know
all this the other thing back to the
original question now I remember what
started all this we are also trying to
get my strains put up onto seedfinder um
we we just did a huge batch of them um I
have a few strains at this point so
getting them all logged in and and all
of that into seedfinder has been a chore
the goal is eventually to have that be
more of a repository for the actual data
of like photos and tarpine cannaboid
percentages and whatever other
extemporaneous data we could put
together um but once again man it's
being a Onan show it's like my wife
helps me a lot and it's the two of us
but that's you know I don't I don't have
a team I don't have a bunch of people
that do things you know we knock out
everything that has to get done and it's
one of of those things that it's a
passion for me I love what I do if I
didn't I probably would have given up
ages ago because there's there's so much
that's not dealing with plants in this
business that is the tough part like if
my worst problem in a day is plant
related it was a good day but you know
most most days it's dealing with
somebody who's pissed off or somebody
who's angry about something or you know
and it's it's one of those things that
that's the part of the business that I
understand why so many breeders dump
their gear onto seed banks and just say
I'm not going to handle it I'm not going
to deal with it I don't care so the
Breeders that go above and beyond to
have that connection with their their
their the people that are growing their
strains not only is it rare but those
are the ones that you should support
because those are the people that love
what they do they're not just a face a
brand with no face you know it's not
just a marketing team that's running it
all it's somebody who loves what they do
and who's passionate about what they're
producing and nine times out of
10 these social media companies don't
want us advertising without paying them
large amounts of advertising money so
that's really the big difference between
you know your big Brands and you or I is
that they probably have a $10,000 a
month marketing budget that they're
putting straight into Instagram's
Pockets whereas if you're not paying
them ad Revenue they look at it as a
burden that you're making money without
giving them their Fair cut I guess you
know I remember you saying you had a was
it sorbet I just dropped a sorbet line
we just did another sorbet line it'll be
the last one I'm working with this line
um eventually I'm going to go back and
work with some more of the original f1s
and just see what else is in that line
um the sorbet line that I've had now has
been worked with by a handful of other
breeders it wasn't mine excuse me it was
an effici and auto strain I found and
worked with I don't see him working with
it heavy we've worked with it a lot um
you know Leo's told a few people that
the cut that we worked with was better
than anything he had ever seen from
those um I know mantis worked with it at
some point um Leap Frog genetics has
worked with it a bunch um and so it's I
did I did what I needed with it um I
want to go back and see what else is
there but my next
line I've noticed that you know once
again in these conversations that we're
having somewhat repeatedly I don't have
enough
pooping so we're going to go back and
we're going to dig in some just some
rancid
rotten just poop and we're g to see what
we can find um you know I hear the
people when they speak I will say that
um I I've never been one of those people
that you know isn't a part of the
community I I talk to Growers all day
long um anybody that has a question a
grow question a breeding question
whether it's about my genetics or
otherwise I try to answer them all
because I remember being a young cat who
didn't have access to you know the
resources that we have today or being
overwhelmed with the information that
was out there and not having anybody
that I trusted that I could go hey man
how does this work like what's your you
know what's your what's your opinion and
so I answer all of those I answer every
question I can
and I hear people I hear you know we
don't have these conversations in a
vacuum like I hear you talking people
want nasty funky poopy gassy you know I
hear it and I have a problem with like I
I will I have a tendency to run fruity
profiles just because I find that like
as far as the diversity in that I I
found there's there's just so much there
of like the different ways that kind of
mimic mix other fruity profiles that we
associate with but yet in its complexity
of how it you know it can taste it it
can a single strain can smell like five
or six different things and you just go
yeah that's you know um and I find in
the fruity kind of category there's a
lot just to dig there but you know I
definitely listen to people and when
they say like we want the funk I'm
like we got to have that funk then let's
find it you know like let's see what we
can do let's I wish I had that on my
soundboard right now you know let's dig
let's dig in there and see what we can
find and I'll meet you on the I'll meet
you in the support group I guess you
know hell yeah yeah so next it's poopin
um
fiveyear man that really to me I want to
hear more about the sorbet line okay
yeah the sorbet line what's funny about
the sorbet right from the minute I
started working with it everybody that
messed with any of the f1s mess with any
of the f2s any of the crosses that we
did of it has told me it's one of the
most
complex strains they've ever worked with
and when when I first ran
theal um so it's
got It's I named one of the one of the
crosses that I did with the storb I
named nog Champa right everybody asked
me does it smell like the
incense no but it reminds me there is a
lot of incense there like incense kind
of turbs but the thing that I love about
it is it's so
complex that it reminds you of incense
in that there's so much going on but you
can't almost can't point to say like it
reminds me of that right so it's one of
those strains that the more you smoke it
you just want to hit it again just so
you can pull that flavor and try and put
it together of what that note is that
you're tasting so the pineapple sorbet
that I originally worked with it has a
lot of candy pineapple but it has this
like incense on the beach type of thing
where you almost get like a
coconuty uh lots of fruit you know like
just assorted fruit type of thing but
it's also got this I always say it
reminds me of like rum punches on the
beach you know all of the tropical that
just goes with that it's just a level of
unique that I you know I had to work
with it and so the thing that I found is
that anything you hit with it kind of
takes this even amount of this overly
complex fruity in sensey thing and then
kind of marries that with the weird so
that's kind of like with the with the
pineapple meatball that somebody was
asking about earlier you know I never
thought meat breath and pineapple sorbet
would work like when I put it together
it was one of those strains that I was
just
like this is weird but I'm going to
throw it and see how it happens you know
and it's been one of the top
four strains of mine that people have
resonated with the most like it it
washes well it's it's a hasher the
profile is super strange and unique you
know it's just it's a it's a box
Checker that sounds delicious uh So
speaking of growing your genetics I said
I hadn't grown your genetics yet but I
had wanted to for a couple years now
I've been watching it I just you know
I've had so much [ __ ] going on I really
haven't had the opportunity um but you
mentioned Lee frog genetics earlier
they're both good friends of mine um and
they sent me a bunch of seeds that they
did from your work of that Champa Rose
that's one of the ones that I really
wanted to grow out see what they were
doing it looked really really good um
and then the other one that I didn't
have seeds of was the orange Head
Rush do you still do those yeah so I'm
going to get back to the that's those
ended up being some of the heaviest
yielding strains that I've made those uh
the 501st OG deep chunk the ones I
called The Head Rush those are actually
from eclectic Elegance seeds and I think
he ended up what's funny was I wor he he
gave me those way back when I asked him
if I could work with him I made some
seeds of my own and just one of those
where I put some stuff together I needed
a name so then later down the road he
does his own thing with them um and and
probably still sells them amazing seeds
um but those ended up being some of the
chunkiest crosses that I worked with
like out of everything that I've worked
with so far um and so yeah I'm going to
get back to that I always joke that like
my goal has always been to get people to
smoke more Kush so like if you kind of
look at through 80 85% of the work that
I've done there's kind of a prevailing
theme and it's just if I could get
people to smoke more Mercy Kush ween
heavy Kush I think we'd all get a little
higher um that now the counter to that
is that most of the poopin I feel like
most of the heavy pooping most of the
funkiest profiles tend to be Southeast
Asian in origin um tend to be kind of
more sativa leaning strains not to say
there's not that in the you know in the
in the indicia profiles as well but I
feel like a lot of what we associate
with these days is like the GMOs and the
chem 4S and the you know the really
stinky stinky stuff a lot of those are
Southeast Asian strains they're mostly
sativa strains so why they take 11 and a
half weeks and they're still not done
you know it's why at 11 weeks they're
really starting to put on their true
show you know like they're just not
strains that not great strains to grow
indoors you know most of them will have
some hermaphroditic Tendencies if you if
you stress them a little much you know
but that's where we get all those like
awesome stinky yucky profiles from you
know is Those Old School Ties those old
school Vietnamese
strains uh the Cambodian you know
there's southeast Asia effect for me
yeah no absolutely absolutely those
trins are devastating too like they are
really heavy but for somebody who
doesn't have a super tolerance like
there's a little bit of like they can be
overwhelming oh yeah [ __ ] put you on
your ass um but I that's what really got
me and then why I shouted out the
Breeders that I did I'm interested in
working with some of your gear uh I do
work with Dynasty I even work with solo
uh and solo does a lot of you know like
modern short week heavy TP stuff um but
I think it's important to take these
This Modern cannabis that we have now
and for the people that are willing to
do the work to go back to those you know
old ties and stuff like that and find
that one that's stable find that one
that as unique which might be one in
1,000 you know uh but still taking the
time to do that and work it back into
modern medicine so we can kind of open
up that that genetic profile again yeah
one of the problems that we're having
right now with that with the numbers
game there um I don't know how many
people I could tell you said man I found
these my dad my dad gave me these strain
these seeds my dad gave me these seeds
I'm going to start a skunk project I'm
about to pop all he gave me bags of them
I'm going to start a skunk project we're
going to resurrect
skunk right then everybody runs into the
same problem seeds that are older than
95 are probably going to have less than
a 1% germ rate if that right if you're
talking about strains that are 20 seeds
that are 20 plus years
old other thing is the 70s specifically
70s 80s where a lot of those strains
those old School strains that people
remember right the skunk and the you
know the original lineages of those that
was a long time ago that was a long time
ago so unless somebody's sitting on cuts
of that any seeds that might be from
that era are long since worthless so we
really get into like a if you're talking
about bringing stuff back from old stuff
you better have hundreds of thousands of
seeds to be able to start with so you
can just get a couple of plants that
work you know but if we're talking about
something where people are going and
finding land race genetics and finding
these you know small untouched areas
where there's or or lineage you know uh
Legacy genetics where people have
actually been breeding these particular
strains and they're not overly
hybridized with American stuff or Dutch
stuff you know that's what we need
like we need to grab as much of that as
we have access to as the community and
just so that that's the sort of stuff we
can still be infusing in once inevitably
modern genetics get all over the planet
there's still only a few places in the
world where you can find seeds that
aren't just you know Dutch Old Dutch
strains or that aren't just you know
modern American strains and that's you
know that's the beautiful part about
those people that still going out there
still hunting stuff down in these little
pockets of the world because that's
where the I don't know is going to come
from it's not going to be from overly
banging together stuff we already know
what it does it's going to be going back
now that we have the analytics now that
we have the capabilities to do testing
to go back and find in these you know
somewhat older genetics Old World style
genetics not old seeds um that we're
finally going to see you know what else
is out there that we don't know about
yet so we got you gave us a bunch of
seeds uh to give away to our patreon
members we're going to be doing an
episode of do or dab tomorrow I don't
know if you have any time but if you
want to come in and see your seeds be
given away during a game show H it's a
lot of fun we have two new members
coming on right on and taco with axe to
go head-to-head on do or dab which is
like a game where we have two players
that go through a game board uh random
selection style they get a number it
comes up it might say do a one G dab it
might sing say something like sing
Bohemian rap city for 30 second you just
never know right um so they get
questions like this and they go
head-to-head at the end of the game
everybody's super high everybody had a
great time and the winner gets to pick
uh a pack of seeds from you while the
other one gets a random pack cool yeah
absolutely absolutely man yeah uh what
time that's going to be about the same
time about 5:00 P PM okay because I got
a 9: tomorrow we're doing another I got
a podcast tomorrow evening at 9: uh we
do two and as much as I hate Instagram
at this point I'm just it's where my
following is at the moment yeah I'm
doing two podcasts a week uh we do dank
talk on Wednesdays with me and the real
Mac Blunts and then on Saturdays I do
the OG sesh um which is usually just me
and another it's it's this it's it's
usually me and another grower another
breeder and we just in an hour we s sit
and we shoot the [ __ ] off the cuff and
it's all off the top of the head and
it's really just the conversations that
so many of us have when it's just us
Growers or just us breeders or you know
the industry people and your average
listener probably doesn't hear so much
of this kind of stuff where these are
the kind of just conversations that we
have so often when we're just sitting
around and just you know puffing whether
it's about grow Styles or or whether
it's about you know it's the life it's
just there's so much that I love about
what I do so I don't ever think that
it's 90% of my day is just talking weed
with people and then I just figured I
might as well stick a camera in my face
and and you know let somebody else
listen to it because it works you know
what I love about it is I always enjoyed
getting with the homies sitting on the
couch smoking weed letting the
conversation go wherever it goes um and
now with you know all of this technology
that we're using right now to connect
with people all over the world that do
all these different niches within the
Canabis Community I get no more pleasure
than getting to meet new faces um and
find out those people that I Vibe with
it's [ __ ] cool man like a
gigantic constant going cannabis event
yeah like speed dating it's even better
because so many of the Cannabis events
have either gotten shut down or wrapped
up they're not what they were we don't
even even have Seattle hempest they were
talking about doing it this year and if
you go on the that was the biggest event
that was one of the biggest events in
the United States you know Seattle
hempest one of older ones too I want to
say that like the the hash bash um and
Ann Arbor I think were two of the ones I
remember way back in the day raing about
in High
Times yeah but if you go on the website
even this year it's like not confirmed
they were talking about doing the event
and who knows you know yeah there was a
long history there of Cups and them
being really awesome and then there was
a point a lot of it had to do with the
the legalization end of it that when it
was kind of in a gray area in some of
these places then it was one thing but
now that it's legal and everything needs
to be within a very specific framework
of yeah have to buy the weed and
dispensaries and you can't just open
smoke and all of a lot of things changed
you know they quit doing the Denver cups
on 420 like those were some of the
biggest events on the planet I mean you
would have 30,000 people a day by three
days and it was just you know it was it
was Open Season it was literally like we
did a few Cali cups where you especially
those couple chalice the first couple
chales where you could just walk up and
purchase slabs on people's tables you
just walk up and buy pounds you know and
it was that that all ended 15 16 and you
just it's just not the same without the
vendors and without being able to show
off and bring whatever you want and you
know it's yeah I really don't have the
time like I used to to do shows anymore
because I've got so much of my own stuff
going on uh do you still participate in
shows quite often
n man I did a few I did a couple runs um
man it just came down to a it's an
expensive lifestyle B doesn't always pay
off um
C once again I grew up on music
lots and it's just a hold over it's the
exact same same thing in a different
parking lot it's just people hustling in
a parking lot and like I said now it's
not quite as Open Season so whatever
you're selling it's just not as easy to
make as much money on them um I never
really had a passion for the the weed
circuit um there's some people that were
just made for it and it was I always
looked at it just like a concert if they
weren't doing shows they would just be
doing you know weed events and they
would go to City to City to City to city
and you'd see the same people on the lot
every single time same people paid for
the big booth same people are in the
back like it was you know and it's all
politics it's all I don't know once
again I got other things to do than
travel around the country smoking weed I
love it you know if I can drop into a
cup every now and again it's still a fun
time but it's I it hasn't there's just
this era of like it's not the same you
know a lot of it has changed there
really is no big cups anymore like there
used to be and so now so of it is like
everybody's desperately trying to buy
for the same amount of dollars whereas
when you make your money online it's
just how many people can you get in
front of whereas if you're making your
money in a parking lot it's how many
people showed up today you don't control
that so there's a little bit of when you
have to pay money to go do those shows
you have to pay money for advertising
you have to pay money for banners to pay
money for entries if you're entering the
cup you have to you know and it's
just it stopped being fun or profitable
and I think for a lot of people once
they had access to the internet in a
little bit better way so many people
were hitting you know Instagram for a
long time and just crushing it that yeah
it didn't make sense to go
fly especially post pandemic how much
flying are you trying to do like I you
know you just want to spend your whole
time in an airplane and in a hotel for
not a whole lot of money yeah you could
get a McDonald's job and make more money
than you're going to make TN around the
country and it's just it's a little bit
of
like I've always appreciated being the
kind of breeder that like people find me
and when they find me they love what
they end up finding so it's not one of
those things where you saw me in a
magazine or you saw me at a hype event
and then you got stuff home and then
it's super expensive and then you run it
and you kind of go I don't get it you
know know like the people have always
found me and despite the fact that
Instagram keeps shutting us down it
doesn't really affect much because now
we've spread out so much and the people
that find us are almost always word of
mouth it's almost always a friend of a
friend told me you had something that
was different than everybody else and
like I said that's why I try to keep
something for everybody I try to keep a
a flavor for every palette but at the
same time I'm my pickiest critic whether
it's my grow whether it's you know my
seeds so if I see something and it
impresses me I usually assume that's the
that's the top and and generally
speaking when I show that to other
people regardless of it's my own work or
something I'm running from somebody else
if I usually say this is shocking try
this and it's usually something that
other people are going to pick up on and
go yeah that's that's something special
so a good one a good in a good for
instance was the blackout truffle right
so the blackout truffle was a cut that I
got from a dispensary I was working at
and when I left the veg manager hit me
up and was just like hey if there's
anything you want let me know so we had
this bio chem cut from 303 seeds it was
a chem4 sensy
star and it is probably one of the
strongest single cuts that I've that
I've worked with like it's tests high
and it's got a ton of turps which is
super rare and we crossed that to the
white Cherry
truffle and which is another chem heavy
you know chem cross and it is it's just
ABS that's the one that I've had people
come to me and go my customers are
scared of it and I'm like you need
better customers but beside the point
like it's it just I think people think
it's a marketing thing but I've had
multiple people come to me and be like
it's too strong for me I can't like I
can't run it I can't everybody that I
give it to it's too much and it's one of
those that for me I've seen tests on it
most tests of the Cross aren't in the 30
range the mom was a dispensary cut so it
regularly tested in the 30s at dispose
like no problem um but the crosses have
all been kind of high to mid 20s but
just lots of mercing and once again
that's that kind of comp combination
that just makes everybody knock out and
it's it's almost like a cheat code mer
heavy mering levels is almost like the
cheat code to to high potency because
most people can't tell the difference
between high THC and something just
makes them so body high they're ready to
pass out like that's that's what high is
to so many people right unless you just
smoke sativas and and just literally wig
out the that's generally when people go
it was too strong for me it's almost
always because it made them go to sleep
it knocked you just off your ass that
tends to be those heavy mercing strains
whether they're super high THC or not
out of everything that you've made what
would you say would be the number one St
strain at this
moment where if you were gone tomorrow
you would want that to represent the
work that you've done with cannabis
blackout truffle blackout truffle for
sure hands down yeah and I think there's
strains and I think there's strains that
I've made that have been more popular
like that other people would probably
argue with me about like the NOG Champa
is one that you know so many people have
come and told me it's I tell people it's
special and I think people think it's
marketing hype um that would probably be
the very close number to uh the NOG Chom
is a special special plant but the
blackout truffle for me is a level of
medicinal that like it's that cut
through plant it's that one that like
when I got jars of everything around
when I hit the blackout truffle and even
if it's from a a friend who doesn't know
what they're doing and they beat their
plants up and they were struggle looking
and they didn't get a good feed on it
it's still the gorgeous one it's still
the one that just Wows everybody for me
it's the profile it's got everything
that the chemline has
right it's got a heavy mothball spoiled
Thai food thing going on but it doesn't
take 11 weeks to finish it's almost
always finished in like eight to 10
weeks no
problem um and it's heavy like it's like
I said it's the one that I've had other
people tell me their customers don't
want because it's too strong I've had
other Growers tell me they had to cut
back on running it because it was just
too much for them but like for me with
tolerance issues it's it's the one that
like if you ask me the desert island
question because that's the other one
that I get like on a lot on the you know
when I'm talking to maybe non non-
breeder people it's always the like
what's your strain three strains that
you live on a desert island with and
that would have to be that would have to
be number one for me because every time
I have something else and I go back to
that one it's the one that always works
you know like I build tolerance really
quickly to strain
um most of them depending on T profiles
and certain other things you know most
of them I'll build a tolerance to within
a couple days of just puffing it
regularly but that's the one that like
it just always kind of kicks you where
you need it and it's like it's almost
the one where you have to go it has a
special place like I can't a little too
much in the middle of the day will still
get you you know like I might have to go
have a lay down um yeah that that's
that's that's that's the one that I
think if you asked me the strin that I
think represents you know my favorite of
the work that I've done it would be the
blackout trule but the NOG Tampa is a
second is a close
second what if I asked you the same
question but about somebody's genetics
other than your own oh that's a good
one ask me the question
again what was the what was the whole of
the question just so I'm specific if you
were on a desert island you could only
take one strain with you and it's not I
got I got your own
work gotta be somebody else's
work man I got to go back to that purple
cush cut
man you know I got to go back to that
purple kush just because it's the one
that got away it's the one that I
haven't had in so long and it's the one
of the you know once you have a strain
like it's in your grow and you can run
it as much as you want and you can fill
jars up with it then it's easy to get
over it real quick you know like the
even the most amazing looking strains
once I can grow it for myself and I can
just fill a whole room of it if I want
then it's kind of like I don't know you
kind of get a little jaded on it right
so it's like the stuff that I've had
access to throughout my my history of
growing
is always the stuff that I'd be like if
it just never came around again it'd be
okay you know even the best stuff that
I've ever grown or run at the end of the
day you just kind of go man if I had
jars of it at one point then you know
there's other stuff out there but that
the ones that got away the ones that you
didn't really get as much as you wanted
the ones that you didn't really get your
fill of you know you didn't get sick of
those are the ones for me that I think I
I you know I'm gonna be stuck on a
desert island man I I really want
something that Got Away something
something that reminds me of the day you
know do you keep Cuts very much or do
you strictly work from SE yeah but
mostly once again it's mostly like the
Legacy stuff that I've that I really
love like the N Champa stuff which one
stuck around the longest n Champa of
somebody else's work oh of somebody else
oh
yeah that's tough
because I don't keep man I don't I don't
keep I just don't like I just don't I
don't covet Cuts I wish I had earlier
because when I was working in commercial
dispensaries really heavily like I had
access to so much stuff and there was so
much stuff the sour diesel deep chunk
that we used to run orange ghost from
obsolete from back in the day there was
a an orange Legends OG cut that he put
out that they used to have they had a
Tiger's Milk cut that was just
stupid stupid and you know it's it's I
wish I I wish I'd have thought earlier
on like this is going to be full-time
for me I'm going to do nothing but seeds
and genetics because there was so many
genetics that went through my hands that
at the time I was just running flour you
know I was just running grows of flow so
it made sense to just you know run a
tray of it run a couple trays of it till
you're sick and run something else um
yeah I don't know man uh other people's
stuff that double purple Doge and Mental
Floss got away from me back in the day
and here's what's funny I'm not a big
sativa guy it was more leaning on the
sativa
side but as a hash maker it was the
first strain I ever saw that had purple
tricomes which made purple sift and so
the first time I sifted it and I was
looking like I had done something wrong
it's like it doesn't even look purple
you know what I'm saying like the first
time you sift purple trikes it looks
gray and when you're used to seeing like
white and like crystally white it's a
weird thing the first time you see
it So eventually I get the scope out you
know and I'm like scoping and I see you
know you can see the pigment go up
through the Tricom stock and then fill
the Tricom head while they're
maturing and then it all made you know
it was one of those early like like
you're just in your grow and you don't
really realize once again this before
the internet so super macro pictures
back then were not common you know
people they weren't they weren't
everywhere you didn't see these like
amazing it pictures yeah of like two two
Tricom individual tricomes you know and
so uh yeah the first time I saw that it
was a double purple DOA Mental Floss
cross from Outlaw grower and uh it it
kind of It kind of you know it's you
have these points along your growing
career where you see something new and
you know we all may find it on our own
but to you it's a new kind of thing and
it pushes you that little bit more uh
you know into the minutia of growing and
it's one of those things that really
once you've realized something on that
level that you didn't know now you just
have that thought of like what else
don't I know what else can I learn like
what else small things am I missing
because I you know the first time you
see purple Keef and you're just making
Keef on your own and it doesn't look
like the rest of it you're just like
whoa whoa I mean now we've all seen a
purple Rosen drip or we've all seen you
know yeah they're out there it's not I I
don't know if everybody has man there's
some people that just I've met through
doing this uh we've got patreon members
from all over the world love of cannabis
is intense but there's a lot of people
that really don't do social media that
just like oh well I saw your podcast and
I came on here and yeah we grow weed
like that's awesome it's [ __ ] awesome
that's awesome I love those people
because they're not jaded by all of the
things that you maybe you or I are Jaded
by because we see them 18 million times
on the internet like I made a meme that
the worst headache you can have is
watching what's wrong with my plant
posts on
Reddit
oh oh the level of pain like you do it
for five minutes and just go scrolling
through and look what's wrong with my
plant here's a single leaf what's wrong
with my plant oh oh it's so bad and it's
like people that don't know all of those
cliches and the things that we've all
seen a million time those are the best
because let's be honest they come from a
place of like weed the love and it's a
plant and that's it Yeah Yeah the more
calag joke is is we we beat that one to
death too though but that is the funny
thing about the more calag joke is how
apt it actually is because it's twofold
right the joke is just add more Cal Mag
it makes everything better there are
literally people that are using cowm mag
as some sort of a crutch or that it's
it's got to be in everything or you know
and here's the funny thing calcium and
calcium and magnesium are both
micronutrients so your plant doesn't
need a ton of either one of them I mean
it needs them but not in these massive
amounts and the joke is that like more
micronutrients isn't going to help your
plant one iota but it's the duct tape of
the weed World something's wrong with
your weed more cow mag in two more weeks
and you're good we do have synthetic
Growers we've got Sanic Growers uh but
what I do myself is no tail living soil
so the amount of times that I recommend
caleg most organic gardeners would know
mag was you yeah you shouldn't see it on
the Shelf I mean if you really need to
get some oyster shell or something like
that in there bone meal work it in top
dress it you know that's just kind of
like being aware of you know your soil
and re amending it but the amount times
I've needed to add caleg no you probably
don't own a PPH you probably don't own a
EC PPM meter either yeah no you wouldn't
need one you know it's it's it came from
the commercialization of the industry it
came from the fact that now every town
has a large scale grow store and those
guys make money selling you stuff and so
when you go in there and you don't know
what you need they're going to sell you
anything they can and that makes them
more money I mean that's why most of
those nutrient lines are broken down
into 12 different bottles they could
sell you all that into two bottles they
just can't charge you as much for it you
know you don't really need 90% of that
stuff and then you go in there and
you're like I don't know what I need can
you hook me up like I need you know
they're like you need cow mag I'm gonna
talk [ __ ] just because I was the scer at
one point so I feel like I get to talk
[ __ ] about my old self here yeah but
most of those bottled nutrient companies
I feel like those balls are 90% water
and that's not just because that's the
popular way of thinking but I like doing
uh I practice knf and making my own
nutrients for my soil and I can make
nutrients for my soil at a fraction of
the cost and by fraction of the cost I'm
talking about what I would have been
paying with uh a seven part ball system
for one bottle I'm doing like one2 200th
of that it's a trillion dollar industry
and per dilution rate I'm using way less
than what's recommended on any bottle
yeah that's the trick that I tell so
many new Growers is like whatever you
pick whatever you start with you
probably need half of whatever's been
recommended to you you know like for a
lot of people uh the way that you grow
is very much a passion it's the sort of
thing that you find at a certain certain
point and it's a very beautiful niche of
the market so many people that get
started the thought of having you know
Vats of stuff rotting around their house
to make nutrients to dilute it is such a
foreign concept that you know so many
people go into the grow store and just
like I need a bag of something I need a
bottle of something and I need a
light you're lucky if that's you know
and that's that's pretty much the grow
store is like oh we got you we got six
or seven bottles for you we got fans you
you're not going to believe it we got
and it's a trillion dollar everything
you need yeah it's a trillion dollar
industry if not more and there's so much
just snaker in that and it's like it
it's overwhelming now because when you
go into a lot of these huge Grow shops
there's so much stuff that even as a
seasoned grower it's it's shocking at
first because you're just like good Lord
I've seen all of this and I've never
seen half of this you know like you guys
got stuff you know I always joked about
the in the late 90s early 2000s there
was always this it was like a lamp mover
but it was essentially like a bladed fan
with like 15 blades and they just had
like screwed in hiid bulbs and it would
spin just like a like a Fanwood and I
never saw anybody buy them but for more
than a decade every time I went into the
grow shop they had them on display and I
would always think to to myself like
it's the same amount of light it's just
going in a circle like it's not like a
proper light mover where it's moving you
know four feet away and you're covering
more canopy it was the most useless tool
I could ever think of they were probably
hundreds if not more dollars each and I
guarantee you there's somebody out there
running one of them things still today
you know and swears it's gotten them
increased yields but it's like there's
so much junk there's so much just
Foolery but wait there's more yeah
almost like the the As Seen On TV level
yeah so cheesy and it's like they two
$29.95 yeah they make money selling you
stuff so like don't listen to anything
those guys say like figure out what you
need ahead of time figure out what your
Niche is in the market you know if you
just want want to grow Organics learn
about Organics if you want to grow
synthetics learn about Hydro learn about
synthetics but it's like the last person
you need to go take your grow tip advice
from is the guy that makes money from
your
failure that's a million dollars worth
of game because those guy and not to say
I haven't met some awesome dudes that
work at the grow shop but their whole
business is on you needing to spend more
money whether that's on more bottles of
n more pots more lights more fans they
make money when you have to spend so
like going to them and asking them
immediately what do I
need you need all of it we got the best
lights you can think of we we're g to
get you on the 12 bottle system it's
super easy don't even worry you're going
to use them all at the same time it
doesn't really matter it's all the same
[ __ ] yeah and I mean I don't know like
as we see more new growers in more legal
states right there's a million new the
joke is the reason Blue Dream will
always be somebody's favorite strain is
because a new state is about to go legal
soon and there's another couple million
people that have seen Blue Dream in High
Times and they heard everybody talk
about blue dream and now they can
finally get their hands on this mythical
magical
strain and so now there's a million new
people looking for a blue dream
cut and it's the same thing with all
these you know how do you feel about
blue dream bless new
Growers but you know just know what you
need because there's somebody out there
willing to take you for a lot more than
you should be spending to get started in
a
grow how do I feel about blue dream how
do you feel about blue dream now that
you said that
so what's funny about Blue
Dream It's the only strain that I've
ever seen a documented three a light
in a thousand in thousand watt bulb
grows it's the only strand I've ever
actually seen pull three a light so I
can't argue with why it's popular right
it's it's a beautiful
strain when it grows huge
buds lots of
resin got kind of a generic blueberry
muffin profile it's not going to get
anybody out there too high
never have to worry about that you know
how do you feel about it it will never
be in my
grow okay it hasn't I I've never this a
long running joke that you don't know
the backstory on oh okay I need to ask
you believe me you're not you're not the
you're not the first to have a blue
dream joke I actually another I still
have it I still have the good no this
joke it's this joke has one more layer
of Comedy to it so I actually did start
a Facebook group you can still go find
it today it's called the closet Blue
Dream
lovers and the joke was you can now put
your friends who talk Blue Dream up
amongst themselves and and have the
whole argument about it's so why it's so
amazing and they go and you can just add
them to the Facebook group The
clauset it's still it's still out there
floating around it's never been very
active but it's once again man I'm
starting up groups to bring people
together that have common interests
pooping fetishes Blue Dream fetishes you
know whatever it is man I'm here to
support the bringing together of just
like-minded souls and
individuals yeah sounds like my group so
what's now I gotta know what's do I feel
bad for being in it what's the blue
dream
joke oh uh it's not a blue dream joke so
yeah I still keep uh the Santa Cruz cut
just because I agree with everything you
said it's got a very generic taste uh it
is an impressive
yielder I I like the bag Appeal on it
too I think it's just a goodlook bud um
but the plant structure too it's a
strong plant and it's really good at
holding weight you know um so i' always
when I started getting interested in
making seeds for myself it wasn't that I
loved blue dream or anything it was like
it's a strong plant it's a solid yielder
is this something that I could increase
the potency on and give a better flavor
while still retaining that yield or not
taking it down too much you know still
retaining those base traits um but I
have not bred with it yet and it's just
kind of been something that was
nostalgic for me that I kind of kept
around to see if I could do that one day
um but it's nostalgic for me because we
used to we have you ever heard of rad
boarding I'm not sure okay so it's this
like country boy redneck game it's a lot
of fun but we all go down from the deep
I'm from the Deep South so try me okay
so this so dangerous uh but if you do it
and you're good at it and you figure it
out it's a lot of fun but essentially
what we do is we take this rad board and
it's like
this not cra Moon not d-shaped but
somewhere in between just slightly a
truck or a bulldozzer
neither okay so we tie a rope to a tree
and then to that rope you tie a bungee
cord and then you attach the bungee cord
to the board and you lean on the board
and ride it out into the current of the
river and if you lean the board back the
current pushes you back and it stretches
out the bungee cord and then when you
get up on it and you start to lean
forward you can surf in the river like
that gotcha yeah but if you like if you
mess up and you land in front of that
board it's on that bungee and it loses
tension yeah it's scary but it's an
awesome sport it's a lot of fun I've
done it quite a few times but I've seen
people get messed up from it too um but
that there was this dude that used to
run it down here in our area and he just
he grew all kinds of blue dream that was
like the only thing he ever wanted to
grow just because it was such a
production plant you know and he could
get tons of yield back then and you
could get decent money for weed you know
so we we have this it's the conversation
that's it's it's cliche at this point
right because I I joked we were gonna do
an hour just about blue dream and we
were just gonna steal man on one side
and and and Devil's Advocate the other
side and we're just going to have the
conversation that you and I have
probably had 100 Times by now about the
one side says it's the production strain
it's immune to PM it's you know it's got
all these beautiful traits and that's
why we run it and then the other side
goes yeah but nobody's getting ey on
that [ __ ] so after about the second
joint nobody wants to smoke it because
it's kind of just a generic Bland
profile and and the other problem is it
is such a production Workhorse so so
many people have beat it I mean just
cloned it and run it and clone it and
run it and clone it and run it and so
back when I would see it heavily
like you know years back it was always
in the most gross amounts you could ever
see a point where you just go nobody
wants that amount of blue dream why did
you grow so much blue dream like and
it's not that really that they grew that
many plants it just yields that well and
so it just throws these like super
symmetrical for a sativa it yields
really well you know for a fairly sativa
leaning plant um but yeah I worked in a
dispensary it was like 180,000 foot
indoor grow and they would grow six and
seven8 foot tall blue dream buds uh
plants and it would literally have arm
siiz single colas on the top of everyone
and I mean yeah it's the only grow I've
ever seen documented yielded over three
ofite you know three pounds per thousand
watt I've never grown that much BL green
I FL I flower out a plant here and there
just for a nostalgic taste y it's on the
tur Okay so
let me move on to the second part of
that before everybody forgets though how
do you feel about purple
punch uh I'm a lot more positive than I
am about blue
dream here's why here's why here's why
and this comes from a resin guy point of
view right so blue dream does not make
great hash the funny thing about it is
it's got tons of resin it doesn't it
might throw down in the wash but then
it's got really waxy tricomes so when
you go to press it there's tons of stock
there's tons of wax there's tons of loss
it doesn't make six-star melt I've never
seen Blue Dream throw down pure true
six-star amazing melt right now purple
punch is a different story when it comes
to wash when it comes to resin purple
punch is one of those strains that as a
breeder um it's going to make amazing
crosses with amazing resin and the
beautiful thing about purple punch is
that it's not that loud of a profile so
what you can do is you take a really
turpy daddy and you hit it to a purple
punch and now you've got something
that's worth talking about it's kind of
like slurricane nobody's ever going to
be like I got 10 jars of slurricane
you're never going to get enough of it
but it makes amazing crosses amazing
wash crosses amazing hash crosses um and
the Beautiful Thing is with both of
those strains the resin tends to break
really evenly from the triome stock so
that's why people love to Hash them
because though they're by themselves not
the most turpy profiles they're great
for making crosses with yeah and and
it's another one that like I don't run a
ton but I have made some purple punch
crosses that were just amazing amazing
hash
strains but I don't run either I don't
run either cut why is purple punch the
blue dream of the 21st century is that
the implication I'll go ahead and say
what hasn't been said in this one I'll
address the elephant in the room I I'm
that I'm a I'm stubborn about it I
defend blue dream in those things like I
all agree with you it's not what are
your thoughts on purple
punch my thoughts on purple punch I have
nothing against purple punch at all yeah
um I think I love the taste of purple
punch just like I love the taste of Blue
Dream um but it's not I don't know that
I love the taste of Blue Dream now it's
not
that it's not that it tastes good it's
not that the turps are high on it it
it's just that specific flavor it's
nostalgic for me it brings back good
memories that's why I said out plant of
it here or there just to have like a
little bit of it just so I can reach
into that jar and like roll it up but
that was the other purpose of it too was
can I use this as a base to breed
something special that I find with right
um to improve the potency improve the
flavor take what I like about blue dream
but make it better you know in my
opinion can I tell you the funniest part
about this conversation with you right
now yeah is that I sense a little shame
in your
voice not at all as you and I I think it
may come from it's because I hear it
over and stigma that you know exists oh
yeah there is a little bit of like I
love it guys and it's shame at all I
know it's unpopular opinion you know but
I also have you ever bred with blue
dream no why I've never even had now
purple punch I've had in main because
have access to a more like never worked
with it at all yeah but you have access
to what your favorite thing is which is
those heavy turp obviously you're going
to go I don't I don't fult you at all
for having a strain that you love even
if it's an unpopular strain you know and
and I think the thing about blue dream
is that has it has become a cultural
thing within the head weed Community
right it's it's not your shame doesn't
come from you not feeling right about
the fact that you love a strain what I'm
saying is there is a cultural thing of
like shame towards people who love
specifically blue dream if anything the
tiny amount of shame that I felt there
was because me and my buddy we have this
funny long running thing like he'll make
fun of me like yeah you're still you
still got that blue dream but he's got
purple punch and I'm like you're still
running purple punch there it is said I
just said it first I get it I get it I
like I said purple punch is one of those
things I I equivalate them the same
because purple punch does not get me
[ __ ] up I think the flavor is way
better on purple punch like you said the
resin is better and I think that's a big
part of it it's heavy oil glandula
better oil to wax ratio and the triome
yeah and it's a decent yielder too it's
pretty it looks good but they're kind of
in that same ballpark you know good
yielder they've got their own original
flavor even if you don't like it or you
do like it um On's got a heavy yield
quality the other ones got a heavy taste
quality and neither of them are really
going to [ __ ] yeah do you remember Sweet
Tooth yeah I love sweet to the reason I
didn't like blue dream was because it
reminded me so much of Sweet Tooth I ran
a ton of Sweet Tooth in like the late
90s early 2000s and the profiles are so
similar it's kind of like this just
generic
site is you how I usually described it I
mean like I've seen some blue the thing
about most of the Blue Dream flower I've
seen is that the blueberry profile that
is usually inherent to the flower
doesn't always transfer to the finished
weed so like with blue dream a lot of
the Blue Dream flower that I see is just
kind of a generic you know sweet kind of
profile it's almost rare to see one that
like you get a lot of that blueberry
complexity that is there on the flower
like when you grow it it smells nice it
just yeah it just
doesn't did you ever grow the blueberry
muffin
not blueberry muffin I've run a few
fenos of blueberry years back and
Through the Years here and there from
different seed Pops from DJ
Short okay but no I do remember a strain
back in you know late 90s early 2000s
that they used to call the Blueberry Yum
Yum that was super heavy around Atlanta
ludicrous wrote a song about it yeah was
that not just
blueberry uh in
depends on who you ask and what you're
talking about like yes I don't think it
was an entirely unique strain but I'm
not sure if it was a DJ Short Blueberry
pheno but it was it was one of those
that was just it tasted like
blueberry you know just candy like
blueberry almost Blueberry muffiny
Blueberry candy you know the best of the
blueberry
line oh man I don't know if I want to
get into a hot take deep into two hours
here man but I got it I got I got it I
got it I got it man the guy that wrote
the book on
breeding while we're talking about
blueberry the man who wrote the book on
cannabis breeding has also contributed
one of the most hermatic strains in the
history of cannabis
genetics there that was a safe way of
putting it there are so many problems in
blueberry that anybody that's ever
worked with those that strain in any
capacity whatsoever
would really go like it's so funny when
people ask me about Herms because that
guy's been selling that strain for 40
years now and every seed every seed has
a very high probability of having
hermaphroditic traits and he's blamed it
on the tie he's you know but in 40 years
I feel like that's kind of fair you know
I haven't apparent I think he took that
from the blue tie and I haven't grown
the blue tie to say for specific but
grown a lot of ties and they're known
for her her mafism right so I think
that's kind of a fair blame but at the
same
time when you've been doing it for a
long time I feel like it's not only a
goal but a responsibility for modern
cannabis to test your genetics and make
sure it's stable for the homeg grower
that can't afford to waste time for
their medicine growing out in stable
genetics well see here's a big issue
right stable has changed what stable
meant through the late '90s early 2000s
meant that if I bought a pack of 10
seeds those 10 seeds would generally all
look the same that was the term stable
when I first started buying
seeds as of late stable means they're
not going to
hm this is tough man because one of my
biggest pet peeves is the notion that
we're going to solve the hermaphrodite
Problem by over
inbreeding so the notion that if instead
of there just being all these f1s and
f2s everywhere if we had started and
just done nothing but inbreed every one
of these lines to an F10 there would be
no Herms anymore the notion is that if
you just work that line a little bit
better there's going to be no more Herms
this is a plant that wants to breed
you're never going to get rid of it
natural inclination when it's stressed
especially late in life is to
breed so the notion that you're going to
over
inbreed and make that problem just
miraculously disappear inbreeding is
great for making a stable line of
breeding plants they look alike they
breed
alike right we only have to look to dog
breeding to realize what over inbreeding
does to a gene pool
right there's certain breeds of dog that
you can't have around kids because they
were bred to be white dogs with black
spots and nothing else so if we only
focus on every filial generation of an
inbreeding line we're getting rid of the
Herms we got rid of the Herms but now
we've created something nobody cares to
smoke because while you were focused on
not having
Herms you weren't paying any attention
to all the other 150 other things that
you need to look for in breeding a
modern cannabis
strain so it's like that's one beautiful
thing nobody wants people to lose money
because of
Herms but we have to be better about
explaining to people that the notion
that that's ever going to just disappear
that any breeder is selling seeds that
produces an absolute 0% Herm ratio it
doesn't exist it yeah it does not exist
I'm glad that you went more in depth
with that absolutely but that's not to
say that you can't breed for more stable
genetics absolutely absolutely and it
should always be you know a number one
priority in any breeding because that's
what the market dictates as necessary
you want plants that aren't going to
throw female you know male flowers and
and Herm a whole room and ruin people's
money but the other side to that
is if I pop 200 seeds from from assorted
different
breeders I could probably make every one
of those plants flip male
flowers oh yeah every every one of them
which means that not necessarily you're
lucky if it doesn't happen to you but
what I'm saying is at the end of a plant
stage you have to just be diligent
growing this plant indoors like it's one
of those things that like we're doing
really unnatural things with the way
we're forcing them to grow the spectrums
we're using pruning techniques with with
training techniques with indoor lighting
so like the notion that you can breed a
perfect strain that's going to hit every
box isn't going to hm you know it's it's
it's going to wash 5% you know it's
going to be all resin and no wax
like man you know and it's one of those
things that like as a breeder you think
about all of this you want you know you
want to make perfect selections you want
to do the right you know the right
selection and make sure every and when
it comes down to is just having an eye
it's something you can't really teach
it's something you can't really tell
somebody how to do from looking at
thousands and thousands of plants and
finally having an eye to be able to see
what you're not seeing to see the
potential in a plant male plant female
plant you know that's going to bring
something that you haven't seen
before and that's you know once you've
seen 100,000 plants I always tell people
biggest mistake a new grower will make
is keeping around a plant they should
have gotten rid of because they haven't
had that thing yet of not every plant's
a winner you know even in a large enough
selection you're going to kill some
plants off you're going to get rid of
some plants any great grower has killed
a couple plants along the way you know
both intentionally and
unintentionally and you know one of the
things that you have to do is you just
have to say look if this plant
struggling it's probably easier for you
to start another plant or to have
started 15% more plants so that you can
account for the fact that you're going
to have to kill some of them thank you
you know and so many people drag those
plants into flower and they're like you
know maybe it's just genetics maybe it's
just it doesn't like your feeding
regimen you know but just having a less
Discerning Eye about plants and just
saying you know what some of them are
going to die and if they're not healthy
sometimes it's easier to get rid of them
than it is to drag a sick plant into the
garden into flower and now you've
brought all kinds of other issues and
pathogens and all kind it's a sick plant
you know anything can attack it now
thank you for saying that I know uh we
were talking about that the other day uh
you really become ruthless when you're
doing a big hunt and you're looking for
something very specific um or even just
trying to pull things apart you don't
have time if you're going to find that
something special uh to be going through
these and putting up with the runs or
putting up with the heavy mut
that aren't worth a [ __ ] in veg and
can't keep up with anything else you
know it's I popped a 12pack and I had
two that were really runny and I just
pulled them out right away and
everybody's like why didn't you see you
know they might have been females I'm
like I do not have time for that [ __ ]
anymore because at the end of the day
what I want is I want that plant that
excelled you know that's the one that
I'm going to keep around not only is it
a great smoke but it's got to grow well
too I don't care care how good the smoke
is if it takes me [ __ ] four months to
veg it out n I'm good y there's so much
of that man that
like as a as a grower who's done it a
few times you kind of come to understand
that what you want is a plant that from
the minute it hits water it has the
healthiest and most beautiful life it
can right so I see all the time because
I work around hash makers I work with
hash Growers I work with breeders or you
know other breeders who focus on hash um
I ask people all the time
like what's important to you in your
grow right is probably not going to be
important to somebody else in their
selection so when when I'm picking for
what makes a great hash strain it's
almost never what somebody else is
thinking it's almost always like what is
what what what do I feel like what am I
the most passion about because if I'm
putting passion into every selection
into every thought into everything that
I'm doing in the garden at the end of
the day the results are going to show
from that and the plants that people
pick up and run are going to be grown
from minute one from what I thought was
the best that I could pick all right
that's about all the time that we have
for today tur thank you so much for
joining me man that was an amazing
podcast we got so much information out
there we had a giveaway during the show
uh Big Bad John and stone stew from our
patreon membership won two packs that
you donated block knocker ice cream man
grape Sunday crossed with Lucky Charms
congratulations guys and then we will be
having do or dab tomorrow hopefully tur
can join us I will send you an invite
tomorrow man gonna be about 5:00 P PM if
you can make it come in if you can't no
big deal but we will be giving away the
rest of the genetics that you hand us
and I know I'm GNA be hitting you up
later to get some seeds off you as well
um where can everybody find your
genetics right now uh if you're looking
for seeds t.com
www.t RPF I3
n.com um the best place to find weed
pictures is on my Reddit subreddit you
can go to my Instagram which is at the
moment at T RP fi3 n d TP fend um and
you can find my link tree there that's
got all my podcast links and uh if you
didn't get enough hearing me talk
tonight we'll be doing another one
tomorrow night we do two a week um but
yeah seeds go to turf.com still running
a 420 sale through the weekend thank you
so much I vibed with you I love how much
detail you into everything and uh I
appreciate your view on cannabis for
sure thank you so much man I appreciate
you having me till next time guys have a
good
nightow come on
[Music]
I say it
baby I know you're on the
road sweet
on let's take it real
[Music]
soon you know we got what you need baby
so take it
[Music]
Al I said we got what you need honey com
and
grone come
on roing on that
[Music]
high
come