podcast listeners and welcome to another
exciting episode of the calyx and true
podcast
i'm your host as always doc alex and i
want to thank you for taking time out of
your morning come join us
we have a very exciting three hour long
podcast with the legendary breeder
himself ak mean brains
we're gonna break this down to a couple
parts so you don't have to take on all
the brunt of it at once
this being part one
aka is here to talk about old super
sativa sea club lines some of his
favorite blueberry types semi-auto
flower genetics and how to keep them
and even share some stories to make you
laugh so whether you're a grower a
breeder or you just want to have
something to sit back and listen to
while you poke on your joint you're in
the right place
if you want to get more involved with
the crew come check us out on discord
that's right i have my very own private
discord server entirely free
whether you're having problems with your
grow or you're just looking to build
community and network
it is the place for you
come check us out in discord.gg
forward slash calyx crew podcast you can
find that link in my bio on instagram as
well
now before we get too long and drawn out
we'll pop right into the episode
all right we are on the line with ak
bean brains
how are you doing ak
oh doing pretty good
how's the weather up there you guys are
starting to get some light right
uh yeah the lights coming back but we
are uh
we are in a kind of a freak though at
least 10 degrees above our norm
but we're thawing out
and uh it's kind of floody icy we have
you know quite a bit of snowpack about
four pound four feet of snowpack or
something that was there
so uh lights coming back but it's a it's
pretty bad
right now for weather we call it break
up when it normally happens in uh march
20th to you know april 10th around there
we got some hardcore breakup but it's
happening a little early
good deal it's it's good for our tourism
industry the only thing you can do in
the winter up here
is called for a rendezvous and it's uh
you know old-time
per
crater celebration thing that turned
into a modern day events and
it's going on starting tonight for the
next two weeks and it's like they have
dog mushing races so much crap goes on
but it's uh
on the first saturday and march is the
iditarod so this kind of kicks off the
old dog mushing thing there's a lot of
sprint races but they do sit where's not
there's not a lot to do in alaska in
anchorage in the winter especially you
go snow machining or
outdoor activities or skiing
lots of skiing and uh
[ __ ] like that and uh
activities very little but they have you
know fun [ __ ] right now ice bowling
snowshoe softball tournament
uh running with the reindeer where these
fools all run down our main fifth avenue
uh downtown
in different waves uh with
with reindeer
pretty uh comical all of the little [ __ ]
that's going on but yeah that's
kind of wild timing did it happen
we're interviewing today and have a big
fireworks and
i think we're just pretty boring so
that's our big snow bowling eye
yeah snow blowing yeah they clear
through the ice of uh all the snow and
ice bowling they call it
what are they bowling with
no just regular bowling pins and bowling
balls it's just on ice out on a lake
right at one of the main establishments
here in town one of the big
bar
a sports bar kind of big sports bar
place doesn't
there's little events all over like that
but we're we're that po down um that's
our big deal there's people that do come
tourism wise people always want to visit
the winter if you didn't come this
weekend or this and there's a big snow
sculpture
uh competition too which is that is
pretty cool there's some real good
sculptures but if you didn't come this
two weeks or three weeks in the winter
it's pretty damn dark and cold with
nothing to do unless you just have a
friend that has a cabin
in the middle of nowhere and good snow
machines and then you can go just tear
it up or you you know if you're
targeting a skiing or something like
that that's that's an attraction but
other than that
there's
i don't even remember we had any
concerts this whole year they don't send
us a whole lot
it's [ __ ] yeah it's been kind of an
off couple years anyway that's cool
though yeah thanks for doing that on a
normal year
we get the least out of anybody on the
normal year so
right right there's a lot of live music
events going on over right the next two
weeks too and a couple good comedy guys
come up here they're all targeting this
whatever tours of money is available
but yeah we all get a we get a sense of
relief all alaskans this is like
we realized about
about uh
valentine's day
most alaskans see the difference in
light coming back because we started
gaining about
four
three or four minutes a day by then five
minutes a day almost coming back so
you kind of get a different attitude and
see a review of
the sun coming back it's like a renewal
of life in the new season and after the
last two years
everybody
you know being a different mode
it's going to be like a brand new fresh
year and nice this year
good deal it'll be good for us to come
down and go fishing this year
uh yeah there was two years ago i didn't
go fishing one time because the town
that i go fishing out of whittier and uh
it's one of the entrance to prince
william sound
they have massive restrictions the town
has a tunnel to get into that's like the
longest tunnel in north america and yet
they built it in the 40s army corps of
engineer did it for army purposes but
there's a fuel depot over there all the
fuel and anchorage come through that
and
they closed down a lot of restrictions
and it included the launch that i went
to you had to have a
covered pass to be able to go into the
industrial part of the town which is
where all the fish processing is and
they had these you know the fall meat
houses and fish crossing around america
was really getting
uh infected on that first wave and there
was hundreds of people sick and they
couldn't take a chance of losing the
fish industry on all these salmon that
was coming in so they basically blocked
the town and i didn't get to go fishing
i didn't go i didn't go at all and last
year i tried to catch up and
things gotten away you know last year i
was almost normal but little [ __ ] got in
the way i kept [ __ ] shrimp puller
wouldn't work bilge pumps and emaciator
bumps i do have more maintenance than
fishing
but the boat's tight
right now yeah man i'm we're going to go
out here it's it's still winter
full-blown but
march 31st we can shrimp i mean not
shrimp but
we can catch a snow crab and breadcraft
right
so we're fixing to get the boat in the
water early this year
yeah i don't know about you but i get
super antsy if i don't get
out fishing within a certain amount of
time
oh gotta have my i've got to have my
therapy
i'm antsy right now because that is my
de-stressor
[Music]
getting over there in the boat and being
in prince william sound it's a special
place if you make it up here you're
going to just like go wow we're going to
make it we're going to make sure of it
it's wow the place is worth the visit i
kept trying to get uh
professor p to go fishing when he came
up here on this one like a four or five
day visit uh
two or three years ago but he wasn't
like wanting to go jump in the boat and
if it was i know if it was you sure we
just probably went to the cannabis cup
for about eight hours and spent about 40
hours on the water you wouldn't have
even had to tell me twice i'd just jump
in that [ __ ] oh yeah i could do that
your choice high times cannabis
and or uh
i might
be there i mean i'm going there for the
event i'm going to check out the event
but you know if we can
spend one day there and then [ __ ] go
fishing the rest of the time i'm cool
with that you know
yeah our events up here aren't quite
like
the ones i've been to i've been able to
i didn't go to a lot but i was able to
go to a couple high times and
the san bernardino south southern
california was pretty
pretty wild event every big uh
vendor was there and
uh you know how they are the big big
shows was great that's crazy that was
almost like a i guess that's in between
or near coachella and all the other like
what was the chalice and all that you
know so those people are like geared up
i mean it's not our style up here
like five speeds lower up here
speaking about being geared up let's get
on some cannabis talk here you i was
talking to you yesterday and you said
you wanted to talk about some of the
original sssc
trains that you're working with
yeah that is uh something that people
hadn't
i guess there was a void of it for a lot
of time and
tried uh
genetics were dried up or missing and i
know there are a couple of real
uh
cuts around of some of the original
stuff and people were wanting it but uh
one of the things that i was able to
bring back a few of the strains a friend
of mine who was a big preserver of that
uh original drops of both
seed bank of poland and the sssc
he's uh
he was collecting just about everything
there was and
he'd grow a little bit of it but froze
all of it
and uh would take it out and
check it out or reproduce it one
forward generation and put it back up
properly and freeze it
through
uh through a younger guy uh
blue pass skunk board he's on ig he was
friends with this older guy
or had met him through the forums which
i wasn't involved in at all i hardly
ever ever got on forums or
i didn't really want to deal with that
but uh i'd work a little bit and check
stuff out but he was offering it
years ago
i don't know i went back and did find
old posts
he went by old detroit on some of the
forms i forgot if it was ic mag or
whatever but they they come up if you
search them and he was offering people
the original ssd
right out of the manila packs just years
ago and nobody
you look at the thread
it wouldn't it wouldn't even go nowhere
nobody was taking them up on it they
were just like their offer was out there
and
people just probably thought it was fake
i don't know about that maybe it's just
like
not enough knowledge about it it's just
hard to believe why there wasn't or
there wasn't some kind of
want i know you gave it to a couple guys
maybe a few of them i think for even the
people that are interested there's a
certain amount of skepticism when
genetics have been gone that long you
know the real deal it could have been a
buried thread that wasn't popular to you
the threats that you come up when you
google them
i don't know how that i'm not
super familiar with you know how the
that whole
system worked i just like get on find a
little bit of information and then go
away again and uh
but he did have a lot of strains and
then he had offered williams wonder and
beatrix choice and m48 which was uh
m48 was the last thing that ssc
ssc had produced they did have some
unreleased strains
that went higher than that number of m48
and they never did hit the market so
there are people that did get those and
it is even available and around today
i know of another person that has an
entire collection of sssc2 and they're
reproducing it right now so what was the
m48 do you remember that yes yes m48 was
south african and hayes
and uh when i i know carl
and uh he's
the
originators of the
of the sssc keys is the son of carl who
was the original
reader and owner of it and
[Music]
through years ago i had kind of been
collecting the
uh some of the
it was from original purchases really
the seed catalogs from both the seed
bank and sssc and i had like five of the
original ones that i had from
88 89 90 and
somebody else that had some different
years
we got together and he gifted me him i
reproduced them and uh
i
had gotten a hold of sssc
through
like different channels because it was
daz at mafesto got a hold of his buddy
in europe who runs that side of it
mitch mitch knows keys real well because
they hang out
and i had them
i asked if i could reproduce because uh
there was copyrighted
issues that i had gotten a hold of i
asked if i could reproduce them and get
them back to him and he gave me full
permission to
go ahead and do it so i went and made
some real high quality reproductions of
them and ended up with about five or six
sssc
uh catalogs and
even the a friend of mine
american one
on uh he's on ig
and he's on different chats people know
him uh he's a good collector of uh
old
cannabis uh super cool [ __ ] he has the
old cannabis trading cards i mean still
in the cellophanes are our foil packs
like old bubblegum trading cards the old
cannabis line of
i mean that's crazy because he got about
case of him and he still gets those
things out there vintage but he he had
the original
copies of uh both neville's first year
in business and ssscs like handwritten
black and white tight
explanation of business first year in
business how the success is doing what
lines are coming and they'd have a
little list of what the available
genetics were
the next year in 86
they like hybridized it almost made a
catalog they actually made that you know
seed bank did make the catalog neville
made actual catalog in 86 and then uh
the first uh real catalog for sss is 87
and then i had those uh
i had those all the way through like 91
i think is the last one that i had
whatever it is but there's they're like
books they put in a ton of information
for grow information that's very very
very technical and there's about
15 pages of information on there from
everything from step one to end product
i mean and it's got cool vintage [ __ ]
like sea of green 144 cuts at a time of
one single strain and
it's got a ton of cool information
but uh
the
m48
is
the last one on that whole list and it
was a supplemental flyer it had i think
uh
i'm sitting right around here i could go
look at a little flyer that had the m48
on one m47 was i think uh
what is it
m47
is how many glasses do you see what it
says
uh super indoor sativa nm47
and that was on the flyer with that m48
the haze south african
and they had m46 was on that flyer too
super indoor indica
that you know
these are a little bit of things that
people don't really know unless you
bought those and the super indoor indica
looks exactly like afghani one and they
originally were
offering that afghani one it had the
branded sacred seeds uh logos and [ __ ]
right on it but but so did the
other producers at the time uh neville
did the same thing all of the first
catalogs were all branded with the
sacred seed stuff
because that skunk one and from
cultivator's choice
i made about 16 i ended up with like 16
of them bodhi
cody's friend
i mean i met bodhi and got lucky and met
this guy down in emerald or something i
don't think i'd ever contacted him prior
to that and uh
i think i had these catalogs and i
gifted him so many uh
maybe a couple of them or something i
don't even remember just like it wasn't
a major deal but he had the his friends
a photographer for the 1990
uh catalog where neville goes and visits
the hash factories in the tiber pass and
it's all the front cover of it is the
the actual guys you know shows them
holding the afghan
seed stock shows the hash they're
smoking a
pretty wicked looking water pipe and uh
and his buddy did the
it wasn't touring a little bit too
it's very great information but his
buddy did all the photography work and
had like a dozen original uncirculated
copies of that seed bank catalog and i
was uh
i was blown away somebody would have
originals he gives me an original and uh
he had about
four others i think
and um i asked if i could copy him and
he is on his way to just a
few years back he was on his way to
mexico to do that land race hunt i think
i forgot who he was going with but they
were all geared up to go to um
mexico and regional areas to
find a bunch of real good stuff i think
that's when he brought back the mia that
uh build the
rustica tobacco from
maria sabina
and a bunch of other cool [ __ ] but
anyway he's going to the airport
he told me he would send me the catalogs
and i was like well don't go out of your
way
i know you're you're going to be busy
for months he's going to be doing that
stuff for months on the track
and uh he did he had his he had his wife
go bring go to the post and send me
those the four or five copies he had
so i was like super honored and i copied
them i was able to set i think i
delivered them back at emerald and
delivered him back with copies that's
what i did
remember he's getting so bad but i uh
he got all the i that way it increased
the whole a lot of the catalogs to like
13 or 14 then i got some of their
more rare ones after that
but there's their info you it's if you
don't have them sitting there
just go to and look for reference it's
better than the internet it's faster
it's the original
all this info has been downloaded and uh
formatted for the internet phone
yeah no
i'm the same i like a written copy in
front of me
i i've either gifted or uh there's
there's times that so you know sell seed
combinations only the only way you could
get them was with seed combinations so
the people um some of them
reposted that information
in public forum so it is very readily
available i know
nice yeah i'm going to have to grab a
few of those copies off that off yeah
yeah it's essential information i don't
care where you keep it at the toilet at
the [ __ ] coffee table piss the wife
off and leave them just out off the
coffee table
that would bring a lot of memories back
for me
everybody had a story dude everybody
it's it's crazy everybody that got him
had a story and knew the exact moment
that they lost him it was a flood of
fire an aunt a dad a mom
a fbi that i mean i heard every [ __ ]
incarnation of how the catalogs could go
away in boston history and i'd joke back
and say well you know how to get him
back
i've never had any i i gotta look
through a couple of them but back when
those came out i was more of a consumer
than interested in growing or breeding
like anything like that i got a handle
on those in the 87
high times they were advertising the
1988 seed bank of holland magazine
seed catalog and that's the one that got
him busted that's the one that brought
the green merchant [ __ ] out and i have
never i've seen that i've seen terrible
black and white copies i've seen other
people holding the original color copy
over in england um but it wouldn't pass
it to me
the copy and uh that's the that's the
unicorn right there that's probably the
best uh
best photo cover of all his [ __ ] or it's
one of my favorites um but anyway
anybody that has that uh 1988 c bank of
holland catalog
send it to me i'll copy it and send back
my full collection of them to you i've
offered that to a couple of guys that
have way larger collection of these and
they kind of like hold them too tight
they're
i don't know why
kind of strange if somebody has that
copy get it over to ak bean brains and i
will personally give you a handful of
[ __ ] i am sending
you know i'm buddies with irizing and uh
the indian land race exchange and uh
oh two or three of those guys and they
you know that that uh
i'm spacing out the name of it but they
have that library way up in the [ __ ]
elevation uh that they
they have been building uh up in nepal
and uh a set of these are going over
there to that uh
to be housed inside that thing and it's
like
it's crazy if you see the thing it's
built up
in the [ __ ] middle of nowhere rocks
and it's a library that's awesome
and uh it's nuts another set of them
they're really lucky to
friends with uh
he's uh he was on ig for a while but
that was oh you know d friends
oh yeah but you know he was best friend
he had a lot to do with neville and he
knew everything had a lot of stuff but
uh because neville's sister
was applying for recreation
uh for medical permitting
in
uh byron bay australia they had they'd
already gone right away through the
permitting and they had all this set up
and uh they are going to be growing all
of it a lot of his legacy stuff the
outback haze and everything that he had
left will be brought back and uh but i
was able
to get
you know three or four sets of these
copies of uh
i sent him the all of the ones i had you
know just for general information but
his original specific stuff went right
back to devil's sister and she yeah
and went to his sons and his daughter
and that's the ones that are rough and
you gotta run the whole entire operation
but you know she put them in the office
she framed them put them in the office
it's a
pretty pretty uh [ __ ] that they got
that stuff back the diaz mcd is one that
made it happen so
in fact he had another good deal i
wasn't aware that you guys knew each
other
yeah he is
he sent me a bunch of stuff to play
around with but uh
i wanted you know some nl2 ish kind of
stuff but he sent me like nl2 and
lowrider original stuff and uh oh man
it's really cool but he told me it was
going to trigger at
16 hours and should finish you know
because
where he's at it would do this so
he's just so much off of our system in
our life so
we uh
and i've grown it outside it's getting
killer and beautiful and come down to 18
hours was getting excited no sexing at
all not at all and then 16 hours come
down and no sexing at all
man 14 hours come down and no sexing at
all and it's turning dark and getting
purple because our weather is already 40
degrees and going downhill quick the day
that we hit uh about 13 hours where a
plant will trigger it's already freezing
so
i'm looking at these things and it it
was a late on come for fall so i just
left them out and there it is about 13
hours he's [ __ ] near auto half auto
from pure low rider find the trigger
i've seen the first males and females
and then i had to move them inside to
finish them
so it's not a uh it's not a photo auto
usable thing that's what we're kind of
targeting for autos up here don't work
uh real well outdoors
the weather is just way too harsh 90 or
or not uh you know weather resistant
they have arthritis or asparagus or any
of the natural fungus or molds are going
to hit them and just
they're done and the rain will win
if you got to grow them you know
in an open
there's a lot of like things that aren't
going to work you don't have like this
have you tried any of the original like
siberian root or alice well um
yeah from neville's original stuff in
1990 we did grow they were
they were way harder and did finish and
then you'd get a hybrid
one and four just like skunk or pure
indica like that he had crossed them to
but they were smoking like cardboard it
was super high cbd cvn
and it just like the uh there's very
valuable [ __ ] now because that's the
meds i've got some if you want it i'm
circulating
i don't have uh i've got a ton of them
in old
uh
film canister the old 35 millimeter just
the ones that went in the freezer that's
how i froze
almost all of my old stock went to those
old 35 millimeter film canister but i i
have one and my partner has one and they
both just say rudy rudy's on it so we uh
we cracked it open and have gone into
multiple times it does just instantly
grow them single stocky
past
cardboard
um
it's it's interesting [ __ ] though
no not the none of them that have been
frozen they'll talk every time but
you're near 100.
he had a string of um
wicked tough
siberian cross [ __ ] from uh original
just the photos and the only photo that
neville
used that were not his own was from dee
and it was the photo in the 1990s
uh seed bank catalog and that was
advertising his uh root oralist hybrid
crosses
and that thing was uh a full a polar uh
polar graph from
e
so uh
it shows
just
at the back of the catalog shows a uh
let me see what the offering was i
thought it was the
[Music]
indica root or alice in it i think but
um he said he has the original stock
he had the original stock it's a
reuterella skunk and the picture shows
uh and it says it too rude or else
polaroid snapshot from canada but so
he's been growing this this exact stock
since 1980s
this is the 1999 1990 catalog and he
told me he had been inbreeding it and
just growing it and it finishes and
kicks ass and is potent and is good he
said originally it was just sleepy weed
but they had geared it now towards taste
effect
still got the super resistance and
durability and he said he was going to
send me some of it but he sent me about
10 other things and not that and then he
said he would resend it but i'd lost
contact with him
he disappeared off ig and i don't even
i don't know how the hell i guess we
were talking only on ig
but regardless he has the ruder ellis
and this the auto that might work up
here photo autos are the only thing that
do real well up here you can get
something like a
colombian photo auto with the fastest
best uh
indica it'll have the phosphitis
resistance and still finish it about
75 days
that's the thing you got to target if
you're going to do with that [ __ ] right
everybody does light yet but if you're
going outdoors up here there's only a
couple choices you know autos that don't
do well you can put a roof find like a
greenhouse with screened walls just
screen them in so it has ton of airflow
that'll finish your autos
or you um
everybody grows autos in here indoors
it's so [ __ ] silly 18 hours of light
indoors wasting all that time energy and
space yeah this crate crazy world
somebody's gonna get offended
uh no it's everybody can do their own
thing i'm not against any one form but
also one thing people do up here is
growing in the windowsill like if you
got a good sunny window that'll get you
by what's modeled so you can finish off
yeah
it works so it works pretty well because
we have the you know 18 and 20 hours of
sunlight and those things are just
jamming in your window
um
pretty impressive that's a good way but
they are you know so protected
environment of your house it's like your
house plant
right that's funny that's a good thing
about that auto triggering blueberry
that i have fast blueberry it uh it's
one of the lines of blueberry you have a
root restrictive root zone restriction
uh flowering response so if you just put
it in a solo cup all your males and
females
and you want to sex it
keep it in that solo cup and by the
third fourth week you're actually going
to see males showing and you can just
separate
it's not a dead locked in trait but it's
pretty damn accurate and pretty heavy so
that's interesting
you can almost just pull all your mails
if you want to kill them kill them if
you want to do you know keep man solos
put them somewhere else because they're
going to continue to flower at that
point
um you know do you just deal with them
but you know what your females are so
you just repot them up and you get these
just killer females and even if you want
a male you just repot it up it'll just
go back into full veg it won't be
blowing out balls everywhere that's good
but
outdoors it's about 10 days
it's weird the strains like a photo auto
it must be because if you don't uh shave
the legs completely strip it the auxins
are going to make this thing go into
flower but if you strip the legs and put
a huge root ball
root give it good root zone it's going
to go to full veg and veg only and just
be a regular 100 normal plant but if you
want to root bind a good female
you can put it in your window seal
and it'll act like an auto so you'll get
a very nice tight smokeable killer
blueberry and you can smell the thing
growing the whole time um they make a
house plant an auto house plant so the
fast blueberry is really an indian it's
an interesting screen
and it triggers outdoor maybe 10 days
faster than your regular
outdoor blueberries which finish fast
anyway but this little
people have told me they finish it in
like
middle of september and they can get it
done before october weather starts to
hit so
wow that's really important that's good
area that's oh yeah that's a really good
thing up here
or hybrid i heard that the iranian autos
were like that too i don't know if it's
in the genetics or if it was just got a
little bit of the
you know the auto root oralist type of
genetics in it or i know there's there's
probably about 10 variations of
cannabis between the chinese the
you know root or alice's the sativas and
then there's gonna be
through evolution i think they have made
photo autos of their own which are just
a slight degree
the expressions i would agree with that
definitely they lean in one way or the
other you know your expressions will
tell you that i mean i've been asked by
some pretty
thoughtful people they're just like
they're like putting a lot of thoughts
in their head and they tell me that they
actually think that cannabis is a
perennial because it is one that
you can grow forever
it could be biennial annual or or
perennial and it's thought to be the
only
annual in the world out of 6 000 annuals
that has a male and a female to it minus
the fact that i think a radish
is very similar
and um i know ed rosenthal had uh
brought up some stuff on that that that
cannabis
is not the only out of 6 000 but other
people have
argued that that's not true so i don't
want to get into that [ __ ] cannabis is
very very special for the fact that
out of every annual you think about it
they're they're all asexual and cannabis
is like that one expression alone and
then you
look at all the different uh lines
through thousands of years that have
come down for whatever purpose they were
using it for uh so they've and
regionally too it's one of the best
things in the world cannabis is it's got
every single expression and then
through development this can it's going
to go to crazy places i think that was
undeveloped natural occurrences
happening to do what it does right now
very little human intervention you know
we just now hit the same humans
that weed has been around they have
prehistoric [ __ ] you know marijuana
[ __ ]
fossils
you got my mind rolling here thinking
about all this weird [ __ ] with our you
know our our 20 hours of light up here
it's so hard to
we don't get a fair chance on
you know america they all have these
plants they get them vegged out make
them to huge bushes and baby them and
put them in you know 600 gallon pots or
in real outdoor ground or
whatever the case and then it starts to
flower or start to show here's june july
and
we're at 20
right 20 21 hours of light
up here so
it's
we just kind of get ripped off
i'd love to grow some outdoors that just
did auto trigger and
a regular photo
photo
cannabis without doing light depth
are you having trouble in your grill
maybe your plants aren't looking as good
as you know they could be any
experienced grower will tell you that
the number one thing that's going to get
your plants growing to peak performance
is keeping a stable environment and
staying within vpd range
and if you're anything like me you can't
afford a two to three hundred dollar
environmental sensor well coconuts got
you back
now for the low price of 6942 you can
pick up your very own coconut mitsu
humidity temperature and vpd charting
with real-time push-to-app notifications
will send notifications directly to your
phone keeping you in tune with your grow
24 hours a day you can go to coconut.com
use code calyx for 10 off that's
c-a-l-y-x for ten percent off
don't let your grow get the best of you
get the best your grow
with coconut
now let's get back to the podcast
i really want to get into those
blueberries with you because that's a
big part of what you do too
but while we're talking about the
original sssc strains you said you got
permission to reproduce these is this
something that we can expect here in the
future no not the strains i had actually
uh those came from old detroit all that
is freezers all of the ssse and i gave
him back you know a good portion of
seeds like a thousand of each one after
i did the reproduction and
he's a super good old guy he's like 73
or 74 running a medical uh co-op type of
dealing right outside of detroit
michigan he's been there the whole time
i mean he's like he's in it for the long
haul
he just did that nigerian kandahar and
last year now it's about a year and a
half ago he had just brought that out of
the freezer
did a huge grow out did a huge
repopulation of it and then put the
stock right back in the freezer you know
everybody once a bunch of people were
looking for that nigerian kandahar
in pure form
and that's that's good [ __ ] that he can
just break it out if he wanted it yeah
both of them on their own are great too
i had permission to reproduce the seed
bank catalogs that were copyrighted that
is that's what i was talking about so
but you have some of those original sssc
types too
reproductions i have forward productions
of a bunch of them yeah i have durbin
dthf which i got from
the flying fish farms
and um but durbin had for a [ __ ]
goddamn month of sundays and uh
the
those other ones i've only recently had
for a few years the beatrix and the
william plunder that's something that
people should check out the williams
wonder grows a
beautiful like afghani uh
dark green stout thick tough gross just
killer nice frosty buds they're huge
those good outdoors indoors can get a
little botrytis because the buds are
yeah even if you don't even
try the buds will get huge so
you have air movement or a roof over
them son of a [ __ ] just uh i did a lot
of cold weather resistance testing up
there's all i can do and uh
the [ __ ] will rot
yeah i never did
throw that williams wondering
but i recently i've got a couple people
that i just gave them
give it back to you where they're going
you know that was my thing and that was
my favorite and this and that you know
what's interesting about the williams
wonder is
the man who invented not i'm going to
say invented but bred the williams
wonder
is um
nobody really knew him or knew the story
i mean carl says that they got the
strain in new york
the originator of williams wonder
made it in
williams oregon in the late
70s
and uh he used to live in uh santa cruz
and he was like 18 in santa cruz he
moved up to williams but he brought all
his santa cruz stock
which at the time was like mexican
imports and uh you know you're only
going to get so much [ __ ] that was
coming in
but uh
he met a grower
in williams who had a solid line of
afghan and that's all it was called
was afghani and they crossed what he
said was o'hawkin that he brought up
from santa cruz his original mohawk and
chickadee i mean i've seen the pictures
of this [ __ ] cat at
18. you know how people look
he's a badass [ __ ] um you know
he almost looked like a
santa cruz weed pirate or something he
has pictures for it was the real deal
and then
uh such an honor to meet all cats he's
like 75 now he's still growing i had to
meet him his name is dave stanley he
lives in [ __ ] williams wonder i mean
over in williams oregon still you know
he's tough [ __ ] chopping wood uh snow
gets deep as [ __ ] it's it's he's a tough
sum [ __ ] but he grew the williams again
because i gave it back to him
first time since he'd lost the seed
stock he'd go to
he'd go to hawaii in the 80s you know
he'd go to hawaii and spend a couple
months over in the islands and bring
like a suitcase of weed go to the condo
chill out
during that time
[Music]
you had the seed stock in a jar and
[ __ ] mice got into it killed it all
one of the last trips to hawaii but
prior trips to that when he was still
super into it and having the seed stock
in production
he met willie nelson over there and
[Music]
him and willie nelson got it got you
know got together hit it off
they both have [ __ ] suitcase full of
weed trading out their [ __ ] but will
willie nelson
really like david's weed
they gave him a shitload of seed
and um
the next year when they met up in hawaii
[ __ ] willie nelson had a suitcase
full of [ __ ]
weed and they
break it out and laugh and he this is
what i call willy's weed and
he was [ __ ] the williams wonder seed
reproduced from [ __ ] directly
direct connection to [ __ ] willie
nelson that's right out of dave
stanley's [ __ ] mouth he had a tongue
story i love talk to these old guys i
can get on the phone
i can get on the phone and talk to him
and um
the honor to [ __ ] hear any of these
old stories and get some information
from the old guys because they're not
going to be around for very long if
if i didn't hear it nobody would say
[ __ ] his son
owns ziploc seeds and he'd say that my
dad invented william's wonder and i
don't think anybody ever [ __ ] once
heard it
you know my my biggest experience with
it has been the crosses that p did with
it
with the williams wonder and he did a
great work with that
chick cross is good oh yeah
it's some of my favorite [ __ ] i've grown
from him
i just remade a couple of crosses the
williams wondered in my uh vintage
blueberry it was kind of like the
opposite of what you know um he had made
a blue magoo dj shorts blueberry and
williams wonder i did the opposite male
to female
backwards deal but it was the sssc uh
f3
i used
my vintage blueberry so
it is
damn good weed it's different it's come
out different i grew this blue magoon
it's really killer weed it grew a
certain way and did a certain thing mine
does something else but it's it's uh one
of the ones i think should be grown
that's a really nice one
beautiful and smokes good i promote the
blue magoo back cross twice a lot and i
think you would be happy about this but
chris told me the other day that he's
about to release the or maybe he already
has the back cross three
and he said that bat cross is way
heavier on the williams wonder side it
really resembles my brother he's always
working so he puts in the work and you
know i know i know for a fact he did get
some of his blueberry is the same
blueberry i use so when we get into the
blueberry stuff
because the best blueberry that he's
ever found and that's what he claims the
best sweetest blueberry he's found is
the uh kenneth goose bay blueberry it
came from
a friend of mine up here his name is uh
greedy
oh ak legends
ak legend
yeah he had the
you know about 20 years of that connect
games bay blueberry it's right where he
lived is his house right there connect
news bay
and um
it became pretty good uh brand name [ __ ]
even though it was black market days
it was a sought after brand name
people went for kgb
bgb has always been a thing you know
killer green but that [ __ ] kgb is a
[ __ ] term that's been locked in up
here
for a long time
some people call it gooseberry but
there's i've heard that there's a
canadian gooseberry uh blueberry q so
it's very confusing it was probably a
local blueberry in canada
it has got a lot of blueberries yeah yes
they do in the east coast
i've heard the goose bay i've heard just
regular canadian blueberry
i know blueberries over there like the
mother of berries was basically down
from like a good blueberry
oh there's so many good berries like
that
i did cross the mother of berries tomato
sorry i made a shitload of that mother
of berries and uh 907 blue jeans and 907
blue jeans is the connect gooseberry
blueberry to my vintage blueberry it's
probably
my best great uh go-to sweet blueberry
that 907 blue jeans you can just get a
handful of girls out of that every time
that are going to be
you might have to go through five of
them and flip a coin and have a couple
people smoke out on them to get a one
because i revenge four or five every
time i think like oh well those that's
one for sure but these four are right
there with it so [ __ ] it we'll rerun it
and see what happens
that mother of berries is real
interesting it
grows full of big old nice fruity big
donks and it has green leaf and in the
calyxes
in about six weeks they start turning
purple inside so the bud turns colors
this is on the vintage
no mother of berries
just to be straight that's a you know
it's weird how certain plants have some
purple some will have purple
and they turn purple like um
anna um or say gooey breeder of the the
guy
can exotics i mean uh he
he'll have purple cord buds that just
are naturally purple that start up at
two to three weeks in and these
[ __ ] turn purple from the coron
up and then
other ones have purple
in different ways and they'll have
purple uh patio purple uh vein down the
middle of the leaf vein and then
have um
start to purple up that way later on and
somehow purple leaf and then you know
green inside the hole but it'll be a
purple exterior from maybe
photosynthesis or cooling and those
purples express one way
it's so weird how the purple there's
probably four or five different
expressions in purples some have a
purple underskirt some won't have any
some will be a purple top and green
bottom some will have [ __ ] purple top
and purple bottom
so many variations
that's the best thing about the cannabis
i get i get crazy about
combinations and wanting to bring out
the expression so my mind's like going
i'm gonna do this and i'm gonna do this
and
oh man i can target some [ __ ] but um
[Music]
it's uh there's so much more can be done
oh yeah
yeah i think one of the best
ways that i've ever heard is when it
comes to breeding it's it's an art
and you're the painter and you're going
to create it you know within your vision
of what you want i got a good handle on
breeding because
my whole life i didn't spread animals
i'm at a very very early age i see sixth
grade i had meat rabbit breeding
uh
project that was making me money because
you know i was a kid i was pretty damned
enterprising i worked i worked and i did
[ __ ] to make money but that was one
thing i learned was breeding rabbits
right quick on but then through future
farmers of america and vocational
agriculture courses you know in
in school i learned a lot about breeding
animals and learned how to cast great
pigs and you know we did that [ __ ] right
in class castrate [ __ ] pigs everybody
got one chance at it and you don't want
to bleed your pig to death you gotta do
that [ __ ] right and then i went and did
judging
you know a little bit of judging as
apprentice judges like a different state
fair uh playing around with it and i
learned you know learn all of the cow
breeds all of the chicken breeds all of
the pig breeds and back then there was
like
40 cows 30 30 [ __ ] pigs or 20 pigs
and 30 chickens now there's like
hundreds of [ __ ] each
stupid so you couldn't keep up on the
breeding but i did american bulldogs
from 87 on i i crazy i was i saw my
first in like 84 saw
a guy called american standard pitbull
biggest baddest [ __ ] dog i've ever
seen and it wasn't a pit bull terrier
there's no terrier in these dogs and
he's in oregon he's a native guy a
american indian and uh
yeah the wicked [ __ ] brendel and
white
badass patched up bulldogs and it's like
i thought five years i was thinking man
that's the baddest dog i've ever seen
they just call it american standard pit
bull
and um
89 i got into researching them in 87 my
my
one original girl my partner's cousin
he has one of these dogs he had a couple
of them called suds and scratch and suds
and
he's gonna go over to hawaii
did construction work he just like moved
his
he sent his [ __ ] bike over there his
hot rod camaro 68 camaro and take all
his tools he'd work over there six
months at a time he left me as dogs
i thought they were they were something
else so at the end of that year i went
to
i went and targeted american bulldogs
and it's like they're called
american standard
it was once called bully the johnson
bulldog line the american standard or
allen scott line and then there was old
southern white lines and then there was
country bulldog lines and i realized man
they're everywhere they're all over the
[ __ ] place for the johnson bulldog
has english bulldog in it
they're a hundred and
at the time 140 pound just like
bird machine
and um the the other ones are working
bulldogs they'd be catching uh doing
cattle
cattle herding pig catching uh straight
up utility farm work of every [ __ ]
base shape and farm
and then the country bulldogs there
there's cracker bulldogs down in [ __ ]
florida that uh you know
did they do work with these dogs fear
salads got to return the originator of
the standard bulldog you do
like wild cattle roundups on islands
down in florida swamps and
use these bulldogs for that but
i get the dogs and they're a [ __ ]
mess
there ain't one of them that's healthy
they have bad hips dysplasia they have
entropic eyes
ectropic eyes bad elbow mange both
demodectic and scarpotic and uh
oh my god they're a [ __ ] mess
and some of what you understand about
breeding
[ __ ] throats like the frenchies and
the
and the english bulldogs and um some
have clear throats and oh geez sorry we
weed through this [ __ ]
and have every expression of a dog
coming out and uh
it was like poly hybrids of poly hybrids
of poly hybrids like the current [ __ ]
scene that is today in cannabis and we
try to get some normality of it i
started doing a massive amount of
testing for hips and uh
yeah
we got a lot of long weight we went with
10 hip which is university of
pennsylvania and the ofa orthopedic
foundation of animals
my vet the hillside wellness center here
she
took my money for a lot of times 200 to
300 tests i think i've done 60 70 tests
and i'd get to be involved with it
because i'd be the one that would
describe the extract you put the dog and
esta size them
put them on a ventilator
uh you got to extract the panhip is
actually a pop that you displace their
[ __ ] hips and you do this with
hundreds of pounds of force you spread
them on the table pop their hips out a
[ __ ] joint measure it then you
another one where you press them in you
put their hips together put your knees
together and press in
and then there's another one where you
stretch them out lengthwise and that's
an ofa view so
through all these combinations of
[ __ ] views and calculations and four
or five different bets determined that
the dog's got a rating so i it's pen hip
rating
and ofa does rating two there's all the
excellent [ __ ] there's only like one or
two american bulldogs ever made the ofa
excellent rating so
anyway i was i got them up good enough
to where i produced ofa excellent dogs
and there wasn't many of them i produced
one i got the ofa rating
from like 80 percentile which was loose
as [ __ ] 80 and 90th percentile loose as
[ __ ] dogs gonna be crippled from
dysplasia
so we got it down to the 10th percentile
and we were [ __ ] jamming on that
thoughts we didn't have no more [ __ ]
ectropic eyes entropia
um and i was still inbreeding i did
[ __ ] grandfather to granddaughter i
did brother half brother to half sister
i i inbred his only way i could clean it
up right um i inbred fresh where i
didn't want to [ __ ] you know you
don't want to do straight father a lot
of the
table terrier guys that have winning
champion dogs they are they do father to
daughter and do a ton of in breeding and
ton of it and they lock that [ __ ] down
but you're gonna lock down any of your
issues so if you had a perfect dog you
could do that but you're gonna [ __ ]
do that with the dog that has issues you
want to
keep us somewhat fresh but anyway i get
a coefficiency on my dogs
where i like them
i'd carry them down to
you know big confirmation shows or um
the confirmation show would have
protection tournament testing and
training and uh certification and all
this for working dogs there's something
called the working american bulldog
association and they did titling and
testing and
there was tons you know shoots and there
was a psa these are all protection
sports that are hardcore
um kna there's a ton of these
[ __ ] so i'd go down there dogs
right off the couch from alaska and go
wild boar hunting that night because it
was in regions like
you'd have the show at watsonville
california and salinas is right there
that's right the main center of wild
boars in california i have friends that
are
true dog men
and they're in books about this [ __ ]
they're [ __ ] famous true dogmen they
take me on the biggest ranches in
california still to this day i got i got
invite to go on on billionaires [ __ ]
properties to hunt these pigs i mean
this guy's got gatekee and key codes for
places where the it's insane what he can
get into to go big huh i remember you
telling me about that guy
i'd go on those ranches and pig hunt at
night and show up at that confirmation
show i'd hunt all night
and uh we smacked some pigs and i'd get
the dog boxes like a rental truck
perch rental truck or whatever you know
i'd put the pig on the dog box put the
stick in his mouth where the [ __ ]
tusks are sticking out i'd roll through
the dog show at about
11 o'clock it's already rolling start
maybe about 10 getting very active
already doing confirmation and all this
[ __ ] protection and just shows and
all this crap's going on i roll through
and every one of the [ __ ] have
to turn and look at that bar on the back
of my deal and then i'd run back to the
ranch put that thing in the meat cooler
run over to the i never once slept i
don't think ever oh we'd show back up at
the show with the bulldogs that caught
the damn pigs
so
we've made our mark in the whole thing
they've called me that [ __ ] from
alaska because i'm
not like
in an [ __ ] i'm just louder and more
i'm on coffee and i'm like
unfiltered
unfiltered you know
so we we hold we put our mark and i go
down to texas and they
might about get your ass phone kicked in
texas bunch of guys down there a little
bit tougher they ain't take it like
california guys so i'd get mouthy down
there and i'd have four or five guys in
the talking together in a group and i'm
not thinking i'm gonna have to get into
a fight with [ __ ] but i'd hold my own
i'd steal a couple of their confirmation
points where they couldn't champion
their dog out and go back to alaska i
did that saying
multiple times so i did grand champion
dogs out there i met dogs that were good
i improved them enough to where i made
dual grand champion dogs i won seven
best in shows with one female
you're beating the other strain of dogs
the bully dogs that's your class
you're beating the next class you then
you meet beat the best male in that
class then you beat the best male in
that show
you [ __ ] man best in show with a
female seven [ __ ] times in a row
you're you've gone somewhere with the
dogs this is like
a lot of work though but that gave me a
straight up idea how to give me a lot of
help i'm doing cannabis the whole time
besides breeding pigs too a lot of
[ __ ] pig breeding i go to straight
semen farms just get pigs do all my own
ais so alaska alaska's big stock sucked
did you ever hit up that guy i told you
about
i tried to yesterday that uh it didn't
come up i'm gonna say i'm gonna send you
that profile
i put in the farmer underscore fly and
nothing came up there's like the fly
farmer and the flying partner
oh my god i'll send you his profile i'll
make sure you guys can come right down
the rabbit hole of looking for this guy
yeah i gotta get me some damn shetland
chickens he's he's a good friend of mine
he's a good good guy you guys are
getting appreciated just lucky as hell
because that's a near-extinctive strain
of chicken um my main interest in
breeding cannabis a lot of it is a
one-time thing i happen to get my hands
on somebody collected it and [ __ ]
whatever some of it is very rare like
the guy's collecting [ __ ] in the fall in
77. i get my hands on it i'm gonna
[ __ ] preserve it if it don't come out
pure to itself i'm gonna cross it to
something they would express good with
it or whatever but that's how i am if i
hear
shetland chicken is almost extinct in
the world it's a blue egg layer which
genetics originally comes from south
america by way of spaniard conquistadors
going up into
northern europe this this genetics
finally ends up because the only blue
acres in the world is the shetland
chicken and the [ __ ] cream leg bar
and that's like a sussex england
um but yeah
you're hooking me up if i get me as if i
have
gatlin chickens this year i'll probably
have my chicken fix
i'll be done with chickens for i don't
know exactly what he's got but i know
his his main focus is chicken and
chickens and pigs and when you said that
name the other day i've heard it before
and i think he'd be the only person that
ran that by me
yeah i ordered up 15 [ __ ] cream lake
or opal leg bars this morning that's the
one of the i mean they just came into
america in like 11 a lot of these
chicken strains have never come to
america they had been banned from
importation and a lot of them are
[ __ ] dutch german english and
green fire farms is one that brought in
most of these really killer lines the
french marines and
the leg bars now they're getting
distributed everywhere it's kind of like
the elite cannabis
but one person finds it develop it gets
the word out and uh it spreads out each
person that
gets it it's not on lockdown they do
whatever they want with it so some
people would
bootleg it at quarter of the price or
give it out or
whatever so the chickens have come that
way you know five thousand dollar
chicken a few years ago is now uh
you can get thirty dollar set of
hatching aids on ebay
[ __ ] funny as [ __ ] yeah
well let's reroute really quick back to
the blueberry because i don't know about
you but i'm about to light up right now
i'm gonna finish that [ __ ] other half
of my blueberry joint i never asked is
that what you were smoking on
and which blueberry was it
an older blueberry
oh yes yes the one that we can yeah
gotcha
gladly send it to you you'd [ __ ] draw
it and love it dude [ __ ] yeah
um i am about to light up right now one
of the collaborations that you did with
uh
it's the goose blueberry crossed into
that grapefruit we were just talking
about oh my god yeah yeah that's
wonderful
he made a couple of cool crosses like
the uh
that
gooseberry blueberry to his um cheese bx
so that [ __ ]
looking through it right now maybe it'll
put off that blueberry cheesecake oh
because this cheese is really good [ __ ]
i know that he worked hard to get on and
working on
that blueberry is a gift blueberry is a
gift you [ __ ] get that [ __ ] it's
sweet good ass blueberry that [ __ ]
tiny gooseberry blueberry you're not
gonna
you're not the [ __ ] around you can
target it
it definitely added to the grapefruit in
a good way
i'm curious because that like the
grapefruit web of his was a super killer
grapefruity uh
deal and uh when i crossed it
to grapefruit
badass from ice river genetics
they um
it's a [ __ ] killer plant still
not as 45 day fast for 50 days fast as
the
pure grape fruit web but it had [ __ ]
double that grapefruit flavor so
this one still retain the grapefruit but
that blueberry added so much bag appeal
and color to it
what's happening juice i'd like to think
it add a juice flavor to it yeah well
and that's the other thing is that
blueberry didn't get rid of the
grapefruit
but it did accent it like it's
definitely got a heavy blueberry there
but it's playing along with the
grapefruit really nice got to be more
grapefruit like what i was saying
earlier i'm gonna be uh this afternoon
i'm gonna go grab a [ __ ]
20 year old cut of uh
pure island sweet skunk
oh yeah you're talking about that
the grapefruit web uh
grapefruit badass crosses that i got all
uh
or the oh you know bx a little bit on
the older i had that island sweet skunk
one time
it was a
hard to manage plant
it grows six inches a day i actually
grew in the greenhouse for at first when
hit the eight foot mark i realized i was
[ __ ] so um i flowered the damn thing
to nl1 trying to
control these genetics on that runaway
ditch and uh they don't want to
generally squat everything or put 50 or
more in that category it'll like it'll
show its influence really strong it's a
fairly well inbred afghani so the island
sweet skunk it over ran the
nl1 so wow started by 25 seeds two or
three days ago of that island sweets
volcano one
it's been a while since i've encountered
it wasn't that island sweet skunk pretty
[ __ ] short plant to begin with but it
branched out pretty bushy
i don't know about that this is old
original um genetics here and it's
yeah beyond my time it's
it's uh
it's known he's saying it's the probably
the wildest thing he [ __ ] houses
other things that were like that for me
were really good was uh
like oh seven i got a hold of uh space
jill that um i grew also chocolate the
original d line that was it was labeled
on that line i had [ __ ] space jill
and d-line and i'm indoors growing this
[ __ ] and i read the right outside that's
one of the few times in the world i'd
get on those
forums you know i i've researched this
and i go man i gotta have that then i'd
go grab it and they were warning that if
you don't the chocolate it was like they
said four foot
minimum height and don't grow it under
lights or you get over running [ __ ] so i
started at 18 inches it's gonna be great
well it's solid went to four [ __ ]
foot it is a serious big long cola
biomass not out of control but man it is
what they said 100 but the space joe did
grow six inches a day if you had it
tuned in and it was feeding and had root
zone
you could dwarf it for sure and kind of
keep it a little bit slow but that's
what i call a biomass producer it's
almost an out of control [ __ ] indoor
plant you
you have a heart and she's funny she's
trying to reproduce right now or go back
to any
of her original space jail closest she
can to vic high's uh gift that that uh
they had picked up so she's running
through her um
was um
a few packs of it actually left i used
to wholesale for them and i've bought
hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of
[ __ ] packs of i was just running the
[ __ ] out of their gear just because i
was getting it
you know at wholesale and i could just
run through it
she's trying to reproduce her original
space queen or space jail right now the
space bomb that's what she's going
through taxes baseball which was at the
last
jail production so if anybody has
original
ace jail
hacks or original old old old [ __ ]
space queen
you know kick that [ __ ] to her
that that'd be uh
probably helped her out a lot
man that's good we the original space
channel was [ __ ] damn good
you're looking for space shield not
space queen or is it the same thing
either one well most you know the space
dude the male version of space queen
that's what [ __ ] like all of his
breeders produced everything came out of
that one [ __ ] deal the original
space drill seeds i got was like the
[ __ ] f1 right off f1 ish or whatever
this [ __ ] was fire it was like different
you know weed changes and everybody
breeds it you're gonna get a slightly
different expression two or three
environments later it's not the [ __ ]
same and they never kept a clone ever
all they would do is grow from seed
every single generation because they
didn't have room to keep the claims
so
it definitely had no i'm not going to
see generational shift but it's [ __ ]
changed so
original space jail was a [ __ ] good
product that's some of the things i
crossed
back in like 0.7 and 08 was like i made
tropolop which was
you know just d-line and space jail it
was like
that day we
ain't gonna
like you know really good strong killer
up
tasty look good
nice i would love to go through that
that chocolate trip some of those old
boys like that the chocolate taco looks
like you're saying i'm gonna [ __ ] get
your mic you want to catch a fish you
put chocolate on that damn hook because
there ain't enough chocolate in the
world i tried that escobar's uh
chocolate was that the chocolate trick
was escobar's somebody sent me a pack of
that my [ __ ] friends
it went germ for me it was really old i
was just so disappointed i'm doing some
chocolate thai right now i mean i gotta
i have a few pictures of it i'm sure
that's what i'm getting mixed up is the
chocolate thai we we did go through the
chocolate tie i never got to grow the
chocolate
yeah there's not enough good chocolate
time if chocolate thai i want one that's
like the one when i
i smoked a lot of pot when i was very
young say uh
10 years old because
there was no there was a guy around
back then people were just so different
and killed it was like
people on the radio with like the eagles
and [ __ ]
people were like chill it was so much
different but a guy was
getting a bunch of ounces we didn't call
it ounces of weed they call it lids he's
buying lids so we'd have a meat dc to
de-stem it and roll joints for him and i
was like at like 10 years older very
nimble fingers very [ __ ] good at it
he would give funny he was using those
the old zigzag wheat papers which were
yellow he would he would tell everybody
that
nobody nothing causes cancer except the
paper and
the thing and he would say that wheat
papers didn't cause cancer this [ __ ]
guy
so anyway it's five dollars a lid and
ten dollars a lit for you know uh import
weed which was generally brick some of
it wasn't super compressed some somewhat
but they um i would roll the [ __ ] out
and where was it coming from at that
time for you i think
at this point that was in oregon so
okay
i don't know where the [ __ ] it would
have been coming from when i was in
washington a little bit i could direct i
knew where it was coming from there was
a lot of mexican imports straight
through the columbia river when i was in
oregon i don't know where that important
came from i was right at
when i started getting into it i was
right at that time where most of it was
mexican but we had just started getting
some like good green but some kind yeah
it was different well we never saw that
back then this was the pure original
[ __ ] paraquadish type of old [ __ ]
[ __ ] mexican you have that dirty had
some crap in it and it wasn't good but
it was cheap it was like yeah when
this was like gotta be eight eight
seventy eight or something is and i was
smoking it i would here's what the deal
was he'd give me like two joints if i
rolled up like 30 and i'd get about
get about 30 joints out of a out of one
of them lids so i was rolling the [ __ ]
he'd like go grab his 60 joints and go
give me a couple of them so me and my
friend would like go smoking it was such
poor [ __ ] weed
i don't even know that it really got us
hot you get about as high as [ __ ]
tobacco because i got super i got spun
out from tobacco at that point hard so
i'd say it was equal to some tobacco
height and i didn't enjoy it i've got to
ask you a question
back then
way beyond my time
were you smoking the seeds in your
joints
no i knew to clean it out that's why
that guy was having me rolled this
because he didn't want to deal with the
[ __ ] amount of work it was to [ __ ]
deseed a lid of that weed you know right
no seeds were seeds or give you a
straight up [ __ ] headache and they'd
be
you know popping and fizzing yeah oh my
god no i tried to smoke talking seeds at
one or two times desperation as a child
thinking after i already knew what we
was without a weed thought i could go to
get high off the seeds and try to smoke
it that's how you know at 10 11 it's
like i realized that oh my god it's like
oil pure oil and bark right
you can't do it but i i had been smoking
those crappy joints and
my babysitting funny and so this is in
about 80s in about 78. i babysitting my
mother's friends children
and i think we're about 12 years old
maybe i'm about 12. yeah um
but they had some i know they're not
their bikers and um
back then bikers were pretty hardcore
people but they had some weed
i can call a tie bud and it was on a
[ __ ] stick it was like on a actual
literal bamboo stick laced with like a
[ __ ] string from the whole
length of the
main stem the
the um apical
stem there's like ham stirring basically
and that's what that [ __ ] was all bound
up with so
they let they tell me i could smoke some
wheat they knew i was smoking my mom was
pretty liberal because she
that's how i ended up it was her friend
that i was rolling all the joints from
and then you know they would go out on a
saturday night go to some live jams with
some country [ __ ] bars and [ __ ] and
she's like well you can smoke a joint if
you want and
[ __ ] would just never get me high anyway
i'm babysitting to these people they say
well here's a little bit of um what if
you want to smoke it so
untied it i untied the [ __ ] i crumbled
it up i rolled the [ __ ] joint
about three hits and it hits me is but
one the first thing hit me is the taste
it was original real chocolate thai it
actually had [ __ ] like
licorice um
chocolate leather
it was [ __ ] a delicious just almost
like an incense type of a flavor um
and then that weed hit me i don't
remember two to three hours [ __ ] of
the whole [ __ ] event i should have
never been
um taking care of [ __ ] these people
are crazy if they let some [ __ ]
oh
watch my kids
i lost three hours aliens could have
[ __ ] grabbed me that out that three
hours i don't know
but i [ __ ] never then i got high you
know from then on that trigger it
triggered in me that weed made me high
after that so i knew what levels of of
the strength was
but it's weird some of the times at
first if you smoke it really does not
affect you
though the first time i smoked i didn't
get high at all
but a long time ago it was said [ __ ]
weed i think if a [ __ ]
sixth grader gets a hold of the back
right now i think they got high
right
i think
[ __ ] one hit of that [ __ ] [ __ ]
school they
went to the shed and they found him
sleeping in the shed if i can you know
that's that's the difference in what
we've had
that little bastard just looks in the
eye and says i didn't feel nothing man
oh funny
no i the the whole reason i asked behind
that is because uh one day we were
talking about i don't know
i don't even remember who was involved
but my old man was around
and i said i remember
some of that first stuff that we were
buying it was mexican stuff we'd call it
marsh
and uh we'd put it on a paper plate
grind it up you know and
just kind of tap the back of the plate
and let the seeds fall out from the
weight
and my old man he's about your
generation he goes [ __ ] we just rolled
that [ __ ] and smoked it
holy [ __ ]
yeah
god damn man
oh it happened yeah we have so much seed
weed that me and my partner
is a running joke with us that we miss
one and uh if you take the dragon you
start to know it's starting to burn
you'll instantly know and you just like
get it puffing just a tiny bit more and
make sure it's like scorching and then
just pass it to that [ __ ]
yeah you're about to get that
firecracker
that's too much
true story here listen to the 17
bernadino my buddy falcon falconer is
showing me around and meeting new people
i don't know i don't know anybody about
industry or strange or nothing and he
brings me over to [ __ ] jj and [ __ ]
mr soul we're sharing a booth i didn't
know jj and didn't know um sour diesel
or nothing he knew jj that this guy this
guy bought a hundred thousand plus worth
of [ __ ] packs from all of these
breeders he'd get like pre-drops and
[ __ ] so he brings us me and aka rizzo
and over to uh
jj's booth and introduce and he's like
oh you want to smoke a joke he rolls
[ __ ] join a sour diesel and about and
we're hitting it we're like you know
four of us five of us and uh
but the second round man big old pop
goes off the [ __ ] seed
bursts and like a volcano and it's like
adam you all laugh and this kind of [ __ ]
you know and
he's like
oh my god i'm sorry about that guys let
me roll it i was like no no
no
i got to
[ __ ] did that [ __ ] we walked off and
we were laughing a little bit and [ __ ]
and just like super comical but one my i
don't remember if it was [ __ ] falcon
or a [ __ ] result was pop dog
oh damn this is funny but i had never
smoked that sour diesel before that
[ __ ] 17 right then and there we've
got to smoke his so
i didn't know [ __ ] about diesels before
that that's awesome
i smoked a few different diesels i've
tried a bunch of taco and ajs and
albany uh
what the [ __ ] might have been another
one
but i had never been a big diesel fan
before but it's pretty good if you have
a
have that as like 1 or 10 or 15 in a jar
say you're going out fishing and then
you smoke like five or one type and then
you just want to go off a whole
different scale you break out a diesel
joint it's a whole different thing
diesels are by far one of my favorite
types i just the way that they affect me
um but it's kind of a trade-off because
a lot of diesels can grow like
[ __ ] too so so
they're a [ __ ] yep i don't know if you
ever got the chance to try peas
huckleberry diesel
who which one chris is huckleberry
diesel no no no um
that was amazing
amazing
like that half a dozen things of his
pineapple fields the caramel all that
was it caramel haze caramel cough oh
caramel coffee yes that's why i meant
haze because it had the [ __ ] coffin
um you know the blue magoo he gave me a
bunch of [ __ ] when we first met i i grew
up the best thing i grew i think they
liked a lot the most was the
the milkenberry cookies the original the
platinum huncle cookies
very original [ __ ] incarnation i got
one that's so ogkb
nothing like any of the others in the
packs you would get that out of the f1
for sure you'd get a good one
if you found it it was a good one and it
changed a lot after that a lot of people
did different selections that's so weird
how
one pack can put off nine of one
expression and one of another that guy
keeps it in that whole line this that
line and the other go do different [ __ ]
[Music]
like the one i keep right now we call it
the kirkland and uh
uh because it's [ __ ] my buddy captain
kirk [ __ ] new house is it all the
time but it's a [ __ ] mainstay go-to
for
[ __ ] at least five years it's
a [ __ ] such a consistent good
plan i was down there carry that [ __ ]
down to emerald and it'd be one you know
i might carry three types there's all
the whatever a time period in the world
it was with gorilla glue [ __ ] wave or
og wave or cookie wave or gelato wave or
something whatever whatever it is today
you would walk through that smoke cloud
it's just calming as [ __ ] so emerald
about 18 or whatever i'm carrying that
purple uh it's carrying purple hindu
kush
the good one that uh
i got from uh
i'm from the nature farm it's a [ __ ]
killer old shasta
old old old mid mid 20s old kind of
purple indie kush but
that would hold its own and that uh
this is [ __ ] platinum uncle berry
cookies it hold its own [ __ ] i'd roll
out of pre-roll joints that [ __ ] and
we'll be meeting strangers being super
social good like being at some phone
drop or whatever and everybody's over
there doing their thing and we'd be like
sitting down chilling smoke a joint a
stranger come along we're just meeting
and talk to them and they take a rip off
that [ __ ] and they look like oh what
what is that that's not like everybody
else it's not the [ __ ]
they said no that's chris is fighting
marvel great cookies it has that just
that really unique certain taste i'm
sure there's slightly different
variances because he we used to
two or three years later got a v3 pack
of the same thing and then he told me it
was
like way slower veg
way faster but way more huckleberry and
he was right the slowest fed in the
[ __ ] world we got a bunch of like
trifoliate type of growth out of it so
it was like
a
super squat
biomass pig if you didn't like take off
leafs and take off leaves and we ran
that thing two or three runs and they
were all the same
super slow super fast
um
flour and
it wasn't nothing like the original that
we keep it's so good though that thing
there the people up here that are
friends of his the
east uh frog botanical gardens
i think they consistently run a super
killer cut of that
that uh platinum wickleberry cookies of
his also
if they have a wreck market down in
homer it's a little
down 240 miles south of here at the end
of the
kenai peninsula
and a real small community and that's
one of the places they grow and uh
have dispensaries so they got the market
handle growing christmas [ __ ] that's
almost all exclusively what they grow
really really cool that they do that and
then
this homer has a lot of [ __ ] dynasty
here i can [ __ ] honestly say that you
go to a dispensary at home or you're
[ __ ] buying chris's [ __ ]
oh yeah that's the end of the road
that's like the capital halibut of the
world this [ __ ] town is known as the
capitol hall i mean the halibut capital
of the world it's called the end of the
road or into the spit because there's
like
it's the end of the [ __ ]
peninsula there you drive right out to
the ocean to the on the spit towards
just straight water but i don't know i
hadn't been to their uh i hadn't been to
their uh operation i know [ __ ] sure
the husband of the couple that runs it
he's a boating fool like us
the
hunting fishing ocean killing tools
oh yeah
so
a lot of my patrons have been asking
about your skunk cabbage do you have any
new plans to do anything with that
yes and no i've done it for a long time
i think i made that straight up in 08 so
it's what is now like [ __ ] what is
that 12 years or 14 years or something
[ __ ] i've had it a long [ __ ] time but
i i did just break out some recent
frozen uh
frozen seeds that actually didn't have
skunk cabbage written on it it still
said uh
[ __ ] crazy train
and d-line so
they're one of the first generations
i don't know what it is that's something
i don't even know what the [ __ ] it was
but they're prior to five i know that i
started calling it skunk cabbage at five
and um
i used to call it a1 but i already had
too many a1s you know when i'm doing 50
or so
beats i'll go a through z and then one
through whatever and then when i find
the phenosearch i have all that [ __ ]
written down
uh classify them as what's best one
through five and [ __ ] funnier than
[ __ ] but two or three times the number
a1 ends up popping up as being the best
keeper final so
you can't keep calling [ __ ] a1 and [ __ ]
there's other a1s in the world the body
has maybe a haze
you know but bodhi i think has a haze
called a1 or something so people confuse
mine and they go what where'd this and
that that no no my a1 is [ __ ] this
it's just a it was a number
but number six runs in my [ __ ] lines
too i've got four different things that
ended up being number six you know my
americana
the um
[ __ ] ice afghani
the gst which was um
originally i call it jackson skip
originally strain i got from a
83 year old dude here he's still alive
he's in bad health right now he got
into a car accident and uh spent a year
in the hospital with a broken back and
then
now he's wheelchair-bound but he's still
growing the [ __ ] gst the guy that
originally
produces with his old crew
pretty uh pretty tough old cat but he's
he's going downhill i'd like to think he
doesn't [ __ ] uh
if he can pull out of the [ __ ] his goals
to get out of that wheelchair
hell yeah
uh he's a good he's a good old cat him
and his guys just like us would have
been with uh your little local crew they
had a local strain and they [ __ ] went
through it and they would decide
what was what and they they picked that
thing after breeding for years and they
all stuck with the number six that's
what he called he just calls it the
number six i got it can you get me a cut
of that number six and
like yeah you know what i bring one over
in a [ __ ] second four year old jack
so named al jackson but i call him
jackson
yeah he's he's a good old guy it's like
if you don't hear some of the old
[ __ ] like that
it's gone
he told me a bunch of cool [ __ ] about
anchorage um
retro grow days
because him and me he's 35 [ __ ] but
they're full 30 years older than me so
he's seen some [ __ ]
[ __ ] yeah he went through about
everything
those 83 year olds if you're still doing
it and got a clear mind and [ __ ] they
can tell you what was what
right
went through some hard [ __ ]
and some and some good [ __ ]
one of our patreon shitty flips he
wanted to know how is your big skunk
and is rks still on the planning list
big skunk i haven't um
do tons of [ __ ] with big skunk i have it
preserved in a couple of forms and it's
available pretty much pure big skunk
just like it was um
it was a commercial type of strain you
know some of them older [ __ ] was made
for uh
original commercial it's not going to be
super strong and you can find killer
ones in it
some of that stock that was older
freezer stock uh
or five years ago sent that [ __ ] to uh
jackson to mean jean and he reproduced a
bunch of it outdoors
and he the way he's so meticulous he
listed
you know when he breeds he'd grab all
the
ones he liked
male wise put them on whatever females
which were going to be whatever but he
listed what their preferences were for
uh
exhibition of [ __ ] and uh one or two
were like he said pm was everywhere [ __ ]
just stick some plants other strains and
and even these
bad pm but one or two
wouldn't even get pms and then he you
know noted that [ __ ] for me so i was
able to breed another generation out in
my greenhouse from the ones that said pm
resistance
and they were man i made a hell of a
difference because big skunk was a pm
pig if you grew it indoors i'm not pm
but [ __ ] you petritus really easy you've
got a big thick nice bud and it's six
weeks in you're happy as [ __ ] and eight
weeks into [ __ ] wilts a little bit and
browning and you realize it's a sloth
right off the [ __ ] plant before you
even kept it so we'd kill it at seven
weeks early
every [ __ ] time we just had to kill
it early but yeah big skunk is just like
in mainstay it's in a cross that i like
a whole lot of americana which was their
our original nl5
and i crossed the big skunk in l1 that's
americana's [ __ ] killer because i
worked with it i don't know we had 15
000 [ __ ] seeds of it and still have
my partner still has a jar of the
original 1990 f1
americana he's the one that named it
because it was like a joke it was a big
group of 300 of them [ __ ] seeds and
we called off all of the uh males so we
had about 150 or 120 i'd say real nice
females told every male we're just
trying to make a nice room of [ __ ]
killer weed
and uh you know the story five weeks in
start seeing seeds every [ __ ] where
was like what the [ __ ] looking for herms
uh no herms get about you know 50 plants
back there's a little shorty that
[ __ ] grew up right next to [ __ ]
one of them girls a little spindly
single stalk [ __ ]
male that came in late did his [ __ ]
thing polluted every girl of 120 of them
[ __ ] or something so
when we just shucked it out we got the
killer ash and uh
it was really [ __ ] good hash too
because i have photos of the hash and um
i was able to share it with jack hair
[ __ ] steve hagar and [ __ ] jack
hair up here damn that's a good story
listen here's a good story i'm going to
try to not [ __ ] talk about 1 million
hours on this but they're promoting that
emperor wears no clothes
um
i mean a book that jack had written and
uh steve hager the editor of high times
and him are on tour promoting the book
and they have a symposium up here even
at our at our uh performing arts center
downtown this full-blown [ __ ] and uh
everybody went down and [ __ ] got to
listen to the show and listen to him
talk and explain the [ __ ] how bad we
have been [ __ ] on him and from the
beginning uh how the whole thing went
down the the benefits that him could do
the world like he's selling this [ __ ]
and we knew already we're like we are
nuts dude we're like
we are known we're pissed we're like
revolutionists about this [ __ ] back in
[ __ ] the 80s so we are um
we're all behind them anyway
this is like 89 in the summer of 89 and
uh
they get to go visit different gardens
and [ __ ] play around and anyway i
give them a half
ounce of the hash which was near bubble
hash of that that production from the
americana crop
and
[Music]
we didn't call it americana back then
but he uh
he went on his deal a couple days
meeting other people we met him up about
the third day and he's like
i didn't think he'd ever smoked that
[ __ ] it was super expansive and it's
super [ __ ] strong so i thought it
would last the whole time and he's going
to smoke other people's weed he comes on
the third day we met up he's completely
out of it asks if he can get any more i
don't know how he [ __ ] smoked that
[ __ ] because it's really it was that
strong but his tolerance was
truly [ __ ] insane because he smoked
all the other [ __ ] best weed that
people were displaying for him
and all that i gave him of that [ __ ]
killer hash and uh
it was amazing but we got to uh
there's a there's an initiative to
illegalize marijuana in 1975
what happened was a
lawyer named raven
intentionally was arrested with a couple
joints
to go to jail and then fight this in
court that he had the right to smoke pot
so this big battle goes out he wins in
local court goes to the state supreme
court and wins
and because of that
what the deal was they they ruled that
alaskans have the right to privacy and
it would override a privacy in their own
home this is
it would override a suspected illegality
the right to have privacy in your home
would override the fact that a cop
thinks you're smoking pot indoors so
they write it in the constitution that
it is legal to
[ __ ] possess marijuana and they wrote
it up as 16 plants and four ounces in
your own home you can do this in 1975
that became a law here so
you couldn't transport it so you still
get uh
not no felony [ __ ] for transportation
but a misdemeanor fine wasn't an
infraction it was a misdemeanor so uh
it's still pretty big trouble you could
get like [ __ ] 30 to 90 days or
something a thousand dollar fine it was
pretty hairy [ __ ] so
and bigger the worst and anything over
16 plants and 4 ounces was turning into
trouble
so
in 1990 a bunch of really stodgy
people that are starting to move up here
from the other places
decide it should be illegal to have
marijuana they don't want the [ __ ] and
they think you know they don't want
their [ __ ] children there so they get
a initiative going
alet initiative enough people to sign it
to
outlaw marijuana in alaska so
yeah we're as patriots you know we all
have tri-cornered hats and we're like at
the time you look in the 80s late 80s
high times this is going on in ann arbor
michigan and [ __ ] there's all these
people that are like protesting
and let's make marijuana legal
everybody's wearing tri-cornered hats so
that was like our symbol and kind of our
moniker and uh
jack is up here promoting his book
emperor wears no clothes and he decides
to help with um
you know
that kind of help with the fight on the
initiative which was going to be in uh
the november vote
to make it illegal to vote but uh i mean
make it illegal to smoke
but at that point in time
uh
we were all rallying there was a group
of guys from the states which did more
harm than good because they were all the
type that wanted to use wheat paste and
post flyers
vote no on the initiative and uh they
did this [ __ ] around town on private
property on walls on electrical you know
uh
electrical boxes that are like city
owned and uh fence posts and fences and
posts like light posts they're wheat
paste it's impossible to [ __ ] get off
but they did this excellent they're like
doing almost uh
environmental uh terrorism [ __ ] damage
more harm than good
the people go oh look at this they're
yeah i'm gonna vote no well the owner of
that [ __ ] fence that tried to scrape
the [ __ ] wheat paste flyer off his
[ __ ] is pissed [ __ ] off
so
yeah it was super it became negative
more than anything so but
during that little rally point we
all of us is a huge group got to go down
to the denny's there's a there's a
there's a couple of denny's up here but
there's one on virgra street it's still
there today it's like you know regular
denny's they have a [ __ ] big main
like area and in the back convention
room and uh
we got to go
have our meeting or whatever the [ __ ] it
was in the convention room and somebody
at one point decides to [ __ ] start
smoking and uh it turned into a
full-blown [ __ ] smoke fest in the
denny's restaurant they they served us
not we kept oh no
they kept ordering our stoners so we
ordered every [ __ ] thing on the
[ __ ] menu and
they kept just letting us do it and it's
it was crazy it's like the first known
indoor smoke out that that's probably
ever happened [ __ ] up here for real
a dangerous story for you to tell no it
is it's so it's so normal and good no
but at one point though it was leaking
out you know every time they entered
through the conference room doors the
smoke was just belching out into the
[ __ ] main area and at one point after
about three hours
customers were complaining that the
[ __ ] smoke was just [ __ ] them up
and they shut us down on the smoke so
but it's the it's an epic [ __ ] thing
that happened right there we were
rallying and it was all like for the
cause
we ended up losing the initiative [ __ ]
in to end the story
it goes illegal 1990 the [ __ ] [ __ ]
goes illegal illegal to smoke marijuana
after [ __ ] since 1975 we've always
had the right just to do it to grow your
own and smoke your own so
it's it's like super illegal at this
point and [ __ ] snitchy ass neighbors
and people that know what you used to do
are going to [ __ ] turn you in
right the eea's up here thick as [ __ ]
this green merchant just went off and
it's still fun going on they're embedded
like hell so it's scary [ __ ] times in
alaska
and uh somebody [ __ ]
use
that it is illegal to change the [ __ ]
constitution
with an initiative ballot that goes to
court and [ __ ] they reverse the
initiative
so
we party we rally [ __ ] alaska is 100
[ __ ] legal again to smoke and just
shut those [ __ ] whiny you know people
that were basically
hockey moms and call them now they were
like soccer moms from scotland
they came up here and you got to call
them hockey moms when [ __ ]
but it was the
that's who made that initiative and just
like evil marijuana evil marijuana [ __ ]
it's a normal [ __ ] non [ __ ]
harmful thing besides the
medical aspect is insane
so
weird though how the evolution of
of alaska has gone
that concludes the first part of the
epic three-hour podcast with ak bean
brains i hope you took away from this as
much as i did you'll learn something
along the way and he had a lot of fun
listening
if you're a fan of the show you want to
help support it
come check us out on patreon for only
ten dollars a month you can get behind
the scenes content
extra bonus content from past previous
and future episodes game day giveaways
seed giveaways and more
come check us out on patreon you can
find us at www.patreon.com
forward slash dot underscore challenge
i hope to see you there and we'll catch
up soon
until next time this is dr saying good
night
and grow right
i'll catch y'all on the next one
[Music]