[Music]
[Applause]
what is up everybody and welcome to a
brand new episode of Meet the breeder
I'm your host as always doc CX and we've
got a very special guest today we got
big mace from Masonic seed company
coming up now before we get into the
episode I want to remind you guys if you
are not in membership uh go check it out
we give out free seeds every [ __ ]
month guest of the show that sponsored
the show uh we've got a million [ __ ]
giveaways that we do for free members
and paid members so either way come
chill out with us uh but we got a bunch
of cool [ __ ] going on we've even got an
art giveaway going on right now so if
you're artistically inclined pretty easy
to get in on that and uh win some seeds
membership is only $10 a month it also
allows you to interact with me and my
guests and ask the quickfire questions
right at the end of the podcast so I
want to thank you all for tuning in uh
we've got somebody that I think I'm
really going to Vibe with here we've got
big mace from Masonic Seed Company how
you doing today brother right here man
this blunt gots me like a on on blunt
mode I'm I'm all [ __ ] like this and
[ __ ] I'm not nervous from the cast trust
me it's this [ __ ] nicotine kick over
here yeah you do your own podcast too
right so you're kind of used to this man
I'm [ __ ] I'm I I live on my phone man
I'm always on the screen like a bird in
a cage man that's what it feels like
sometimes oh no hey you got to make time
for yourself but I see you doing that
too um before we get into all this [ __ ]
you know some people here are aware of
you uh aware of some of the controversy
that goes around with Masonic SEO we're
going to dig into all of that today um
with with your gu and you know if you
don't want to talk about something you
just let me know uh but we're going to
get into some controversial [ __ ] but
first off I really want to get to know
who you are you know as a person so why
don't we just start off with the easy
[ __ ] like how did you get into cannabis
what was your first
experience uh smoking weed um like like
in ninth grade smoking weed I I enjoyed
it when I smoked it and uh just kept
smoking every day never stopped and
then kind of like played with a seed
here and there from a bag seed throw it
in some dirt see what happens all this
like at age 15 16 and then finally when
I turned like 18
uh I decided I wanted to grow some pot
to try to emulate the weed that I was
smoking so uh I ended up growing pot
because uh I had a habit that I had to
sustain fair enough fair enough you
remember what some of those first types
that you ever smoked on were so I
started a smoking weed like I grew up on
a in South Central on a on a street
called Avalon well like the it's 111th
in Avon it's like kind of ghetto there
you know and uh the the weed we grew up
on was stress that's what they called it
it was brick weed stress is brick weed
usually weed sends him from Mexico super
compacted because they had to like hide
it and in you know during Transportation
whatever which way and this weed would
be full of seeds so you would get your
$5 nickel bag and you would break it all
down and we would smoke it in blunts cuz
it didn't taste that good in points and
then blunts lasted longer that was our
our rhetoric so we started with stress
and blunts up up upgraded to like
chronic Kush OG and then start hitting
the medical dispensaries uh like we'll
we'll have a big homie go like hey you
know or a big homie would be have his
card and we'd always go cop off of him
ironically today when I was at the post
office uh I ran into like one of my
first plugs from when I was like a kid
and and and I I recognized his his wife
because she used to sell the weed for
him too and I'm like that's her and I
look up and he's there too and I'm like
hey what's up create he's all he looked
at me like CU you know we're in the
we're the we're in the we're in the post
office in Watts like ghetto as [ __ ] and
he's just like like on his guard I'm
like you don't remember me like I used
to buy weed off of you almost every day
and he's just like and then it clicked
and then he just had this big [ __ ]
eating grin on his face and I'm like
yeah dude I'm like it all paid off
because that's that's all do now doing
now
[ __ ] and then I just left and
and that happened what like three hours
ago maybe so that's how I grew I grew up
buying weed on the streets of South
Central Los Angeles and upgraded my way
to the dispensary and then it all just
kind of unraveled from there from ghetto
to ghetto uh respect for sure uh we had
the exact same thing we called it MCH up
here instead of stress but it was the
same [ __ ] [ __ ] bag ass [ __ ] from
Mexico uh I see that you're still
smoking on the blunts do you have a
preferred blunt
WP uh so those pearls are good the ones
from uh Paxton pearls those guys do good
work they're they're fairly new but uh
most stores don't carry those so like
I'll find these graas right here these
graba leaves that's what I'm smoking
right now there's a big ass green one
that comes and it's like this big this
one comes with two nice chunks that are
kind of already cut out for you so
that's what I'm smoking right now I like
smoking leaves man so you'll see me
smoking a leaf every now and then hell
yeah I wish I could say the same I don't
think we got that [ __ ] around here I get
what's at the gas station
yeah back in the day it was a Popin man
like that's the stress right
there [ __ ] you know what'll be
healthy getting some of this paint off y
so you start growing this like fresh
Year we're saying say about nth grade
yeah dabbled dabbled like pop a seed put
it in the dirt water just just for
funsies always grew like a seed on the
side but started growing for like cash
crop put some pots in the backyard like
uh somewhere around 18 years old you
know okay right after uh High School
when my pops had bought me a pound of
Sour Diesel because I graduated high
school as a like a congratulations gift
and uh I didn't necessarily re up I just
kind of smoked most of it and bought
dumb [ __ ] and I was just a kid you know
and and when it was all gone I'm just
like what am I gonna do you know and my
dad's like talk to Ry Ray Ray knows
about growing so he ended up
Ry convinced my dad to go buy like 10 15
gallon drums and like a bunch of dirt
and just throw the Clones in there so
rats ended up chewing that and and even
then I wasn't like I was just like ah
whatever I just want to smoke weed I
don't really want to grow or like what
is that I don't get it yet you know it
wasn't it wasn't a concept that I
understood yet and then finally the fire
was getting hotter under my ass where
the the sour diesel pound started to
deplete more and more and you know
another pound wasn't going to come
around that was a one-time gift you were
supposed to figure it out you know and
uh I'm just like I got to grow weed just
like my dad was about to grow weed how
we were going to but the rats ate it so
I little by little just started buying
dirt putting bag seeds in the ground any
random clone that you know me or any of
my family members would get at a clone
from a firsttime patient deal or
whatever whatever uh bring it over here
let's grow it you know and next you know
we started with six plants and then 12
and then 24 and then [ __ ] let's fill
up all the space you know is that is
that how it goes now it's just whatever
we can pack in there that's kind of how
I uh do my grow and now it's it's even
hard to pack in the space now cuz it's
just I move so so much it's just like
[ __ ] that's already done we got to fill
it up again [ __ ] like it's just it's
it's it's becoming a whole ass job and
it's cool like I'm not bitching but yeah
like filling the gaps filling the gaps
like like I'm not worried about you know
we're doing it how it's always been done
and I'm just like just filling the gaps
you know whatever happens
happens okay so leading from growing
into breeding growing kind of came out
in necessity
uh how did you make that transition from
growing to breeding like how how long
was it and what was a why so I've been
growing I graduated high school in
2010 probably started found out what
making seeds was in like
2016 so I I was growing for like six
years cash crop blasting it all selling
it to the dispensary smoking it just on
top of the world just smoking my own
[ __ ] Backyard Boogie not worried
about nobody's [ __ ]
and uh eventually I find Instagram and
and I was never on forms I didn't know
what a form was I did kind of find this
one form but I was like ah this ain't
for me like I'm just I'm just gonna grow
weed and make slabs you know I did know
about you know all the seshes that were
happening around me all the the
dispensaries like that's what I did know
I knew real life and uh I went into
Instagram and I meet some people and and
they know all these this this
terminology all these clones all this
jargon all these breeders and I'm just
right there like cool first breeder to
kick me a
bone uh was uh Harry Palms Harry Palms
sent me a bunch of seeds uh and and he's
all like have fun and at the time I'm
still growing for flower like I'm a
flower grower or or a B maker and uh a
lot of people started saying that
goddamn a lot of bringing back memories
of that backyard [ __ ] you know this
[ __ ] bad ass [ __ ] yeah a lot of
people start noticing that I'm growing
some killer genetics and uh I I uh at
the time that I'm growing these these
genetics it was the Tropicana cherry pie
Tangi it was the Cherry Pie Tangi
hybrids bloom had or Harry had a cherry
pie Tangi line at the time godamn this
story is like deja vu so you're good
brother I remember this out and uh at
the time that I'm growing him out it's
the same time that burner and jungle
boys were having a collaborative effort
and one of the strains under the the the
the the brand that they were launching
the Exotics brand was a Tropic Thunder
Tropic Thunder happened to be the
Tropicana Cherry pangi so I wasn't
necessarily growing the same clone or
feno or whatever they were they were
hyping but I was growing the same seed
stock and and me I'm just like cool like
I I hyped myself up I'm just like yo
that's dope like I got that too and
everyone that followed me is like yeah
you do got that too you know and and I'm
just like cool well well dope you know
still not thinking about making seeds
and I I get some mels and I'm just like
cool I got some mels uh maybe I should
make some seeds with them and I'm like
but I I don't want to jeopardize my grow
so I reached out to Instagram I was like
yo who here in soal wants to help me
make some seeds with this killer stud
that I found uh we'll see what happens
sure enough somebody reaches out and uh
they go they make the seeds they bring
them back to me and uh and it's just
like I'm just like hey who wants to buy
some seeds and people are like boop boop
boop boop boop and and you know just
like nowadays I wasn't charging what
people charge back in the day 150 bucks
200 a pack I was like give me 60 bucks
give me 60 bucks 60 bucks sold agent
orange Tropicana cherry pangi and
plushberry Tropicana Cherry pangi all
those sold you know uh people started
growing them everybody loves them cool
we made seeds so I I understood the
concept of making seeds all the whole
nice like oh you take a picture you put
on your page everybody ah it was back in
the day when when it was more like you
know damn look at this picture you know
and nowadays it's like yeah whatever
dude uh look at Oreos uh but whatever we
post the pictures everybody goes crazy
not everybody goes crazy but I kind of
get a following as a seed maker in in
the sense and and then I'm like you know
what that sold pretty
well I I uh I didn't have to use that
much space
I didn't have to dry all this weed I
didn't have to package it all that felt
good people respect the vision I didn't
understand that I was just kind of just
rolling with the punches like damn like
I can make seeds like that's allowed and
while I'm while I'm doing that not too
many people knew who I was or gave a
[ __ ] right only the people that followed
me and then eventually I end up getting
like the the tools to make Wilson and a
couple other varieties on my second
visit when uh Onie and Harry came to
Adelanto in California like two hours
away from Los Angeles and I drove my ass
down there to go meet Harry and he gave
me five papaya fem and a Tropicana F2
and I took that back home grew them all
out and made some dope ass crosses and
that's kind of how it all unraveled you
know for the most part that's the ab
bridg version for the most part I
appreciate that [ __ ] re
bro uh guys just a reminder if you've
got questions for
big mace uh we're going to do a rapid
fire at the end so members you guys can
get your questions in I opened up the
Q&amp;A already uh so whenever you guys are
ready throw them in there but it'll be
like the last 15 minutes of the show so
you're smoking on a blunt we didn't talk
about that at all what you smoking bro I
uh so I have the I live like 20 30
minutes away from capulator uh shop that
he does his work at so I went to it's
called laade piece of green so I went to
piece of green and I bought a couple of
flavors I bought uh Mac one because
that's his [ __ ] you know his his his cap
cut or
whatever they had some rs11 at 20 bucks
in eth I was like give me two of
those I bought some Sunset Sher because
I like Sunset sherb and I bought his
Sher Banger 22 because I wanted to see
what his Sher Banger 22 tastes like
grown by their facility and I bought
some uh the Strand that they dropped
with SE Junkie
I I actually got this clone as well it's
the uh biscotti gelato 41 it's really
nice I like it a lot and they had some
other [ __ ] there too but that's what I
went for I'm a I'm a sucker for you know
Candy and gas and [ __ ] like that they
had like some hazy [ __ ] and you know
some other [ __ ] um that's cool and all
respectably no no disrespect but
anything but like I'm trying to smoke
some flavorful stuff right now you know
so if I had to ask you like you got a
top strain of all time
yeah man uh I guess it changes with the
times but right now it's Skittles is my
go-to I heard you saying that one that's
and that's not too new at this point no
it's not that's pretty cool that that's
stuck around for you what is it about
the Skittles that you like it's got the
perfect amount of
like it's like a it's like a it's like a
it's not gas like sour or or like you
know like headband or or GMO or like
anything one might perceive as gas right
but it's its own type of like cush
chronic gas like it's and and that I
know I'm just describing like a strain
like Kush like it's like its own type of
dope weed you know like when o came out
like everything that was just kind of
related to OG you wanted to smoke well
Skittles is the same thing every hybrid
and derivative of Skittles I'm like yeah
that's good you know it's the same thing
that happened with OG because there's
like all the planetaries there's the sfv
the sky Walker the Fire OG the the sour
diesel and they all I know Sour Diesel
and and OG they're kind of like you
could separate them but they all fall in
that same realm because they're not piny
they're not to me like as a as a smoker
and as a as a seed maker and breeder
whatever like this is how I look at the
plant this how yeah your answer is your
answer brother you don't gota [ __ ]
explain it and I know how people are
they like that's not sour gas what are
you talking
about that's more of a fire and I'm like
gas fire yeah gases cause fire same
[ __ ] what's this smell like [ __ ]
smells like dirty monkey ass like you
never smelled that one what yeah gmo's
more funky but you sometimes you find
that nice derivative of it that's got
some some gas in it you know I've
definitely been finding some like I do
another show called The Washington weed
review because I feel like no matter
what you guys all agree on there's
something that we can all agree on
that's [ __ ] medic and hom grow is
always going to be better than
dispensary like nine times out of 10
so but because of that we wanted to go
out there and we wanted to tell some of
the guys local around Washington like yo
you are going to go to the dispo like
this one that I'm saying is pretty
[ __ ] good you know so we have been
trying out some hype [ __ ] and I've been
finding some stuff that I do like I
heard you talking [ __ ] about the Oreos
why don't you like the
Oreos uh I don't like the okay I Oreos
for not that I don't it's just like
don't like hate those are like tough
words for a plant like the plant didn't
do nothing to me it's just the plant it
just exist you know so I wouldn't say
that right I just don't like the the
Fanfare behind it right the the yo look
at this plant it's the best and you're
like yeah it looks nice pretty hey hey
it even smells cool it's got this neat
smell but that smell you will never
taste no matter how well it's
grown I've had it five or 10 times from
different Growers and different shapes
and forms and I like the smell it's like
damn this smells nice [ __ ] what's what
is this I like that smell and it just
don't it don't translate it it doesn't
do the the the job and in hash form and
in weed form I've yet to grab a Oreos or
or or hybrid of it uh that's that leans
Oreos that's like okay I get it now and
and I'm not there's some strains that
took me a while to get privy to but the
Oreos I I I can't accept the the the
Fanfare behind it the like the other day
I seen uh I think they're still selling
that one strain zero gravity as as like
a as a thing I seen you know no no
disrespect I'm just calling out names
but I seen uh they just opened a
dispensary somewhere and they're like
doing this whole ad about how they got
this dope ass drop on this or Oro strain
called zero gravity and they made this
whole video for it and I'm just
like that weed
sucks I'm with you I'm with you bro okay
so since we're already in this realm
right here least favorite strain of all
time unless it is Oreos n i don't that's
a hard question uh least favorite strain
of all time [ __ ] you know it's got to be
one that you're just like I would never
smoke that
again oh uh anything that's like uh like
perfumey whatever that means yeah you
know I I I love I don't disregard any
strains even the Oreos it's hard for me
to be like Ah that's the worst strain
because hey man you might be able to
breed with it I don't know one day I
might try it and I might like it but so
far the 10 times I've had it from cool
dudes n but I can't disregard a strain
like that man it's just it hurts which
one's not good good for big Ma's
body don't put no train wreck in my dab
[ __ ] you know I'll smoke it when I want
to smoke it but don't come over here
telling me train wreck and Jack hair is
the best turp in the world and I get it
it's like a old school thing and some
people really love it but don't tell me
it's the best thing it's the best thing
for you yeah yeah I'm with you I'm not
I'm was never really huge on the jack I
like the effect it's kind of uplifting
but like the flavor I think a lot of
people that worked with it call it Jack
turps for a reason you know like it's
like that spicy kind of weak kind of you
know I'm not crazy about it either
so what if we took the Jack hair and we
bred that [ __ ] with Skittles would big
May smoke that yo find a skittles leaner
with nuances from the jack it might go
down the [ __ ] throat nice you know
but find find a complete Jack leaner
it's just another Jack it's like you
could you could CR whatever you want to
it if it leans Jack heavy like 60% or
more it's like hey bro you just just
like any other strain another GMO
another Jack another [ __ ] this like
there there's strains that have been
coined and and go find something new you
know so you haven't found a skittles
cross that you don't
like not necessarily I found
Skittles uh batches that I don't like
like uh the way it was grown and
processed it's never necessarily the uh
the flavor cuz yeah in
mind quality right I smoke quality and
and it's like there's some flavors I'd
rather not smoke but quality Skittles
and and most hybrid forms they check out
[ __ ] yeah okay so we got touch on it I
know a lot of people are wanting to hear
about it some of the controversy behind
big mace
uh what do you refer to yourself as do
you consider yourself a breeder or you
doing Ma thing when when uh when when
dudes call themselves breeders and and I
I just feel like you know I'm very
confident in in in where I've put myself
right and I see a lot of like even to
this day like covid [ __ ] breeders and
covid Growers and no disrespect but it's
like I never seen you [ __ ]
outside and and and and and yeah you
might be inside but it's like a lot of
echo chamber [ __ ] going on and and and
and and just see myself as me but if I
have to put on my breeder hat and be
like hey man [ __ ] you guys like I do the
same [ __ ] you do and if you call
yourself a [ __ ] breeder well [ __ ] I
guess I'm one too [ __ ] you know
but whatever you want to call me but
make sure [ __ ] put the big on front
of it first I'm
just fair enough good answer good answer
man uh so let's talk about your breeding
practices a little bit
uh how do you go I know you've got a
whole book by the way guys go check it
out do you still have that available
yeah I got I got all that stuff
available it's all any I got the
breeding book selection guide the
pollination guide all shout out green
pine logo trees it's a concept that uh
he's an artist and and a [ __ ] teacher
out in New York he's a college professor
of some sort he teaches art and uh he
does uh some logos for some of the guys
in the Cannabis scene and uh I reached
out to him I was like hey man put this
[ __ ] on paper for me because uh you know
it's it's something that feels right for
for for the people you know no one has
done this before or and if they have you
know [ __ ] I want to do it too you know I
don't think anybody's done it the way
that you did it it's pretty damn cool
that you used your influence because
obviously you know you you've still got
that same Vibe you got the Pokemon the
[ __ ] Yu-Gi-Oh like I think it's dope
man because I'm into that [ __ ] too not
so much to Yu-Gi-Oh I saw you playing
that earlier I never really got in that
but like Pokemon like some of the old
cards from back then [ __ ] yeah dude that
[ __ ] was cool as [ __ ] like that's what
we did we never really played the games
back then it was more about collecting
cars but it was still [ __ ] fun you
know even the [ __ ] Game Boy games and
[ __ ] that was my jam like that's the
vibe I grew up with uh so that you took
that influence and brought it to
cannabis for a breeding guy and like
made a comic book thing I like that I
like that Vibe a lot and it was
something that you know people had done
but not necessarily in the way that you
did it you definitely brought your whole
[ __ ] new thing to it so go check that
out guys if you do want to learn more
about uh Masonic breeding practices his
selection guide all that uh I know a lot
of people know you for your Wilson
mail like we were talking about earlier
you got something proven uh you
definitely want to hit that on some
proven Fe females and if you got proven
lines on both that you know what you can
kind of expect from each one uh that I
mean there's not
really much margin for error you know uh
what what would you say is now current
Masonic seeds what would you say is your
breeding practice you say you do pick
out a lot of females and you kind of try
to pack as much space you can is it all
Wilson still or are you doing multiple
males I uh so i' I've spread out my
tentacles a little bit uh it used to be
solely Wilson hybrids all I did is
Wilson I'll do a couple side missions i'
pick a m From Any Given seed pack that I
popped and if I deemed it special or
worthy I'd reach out to X people and be
like yo go make some seeds you know give
me half at the end and you know call it
a day and whoever did that you know all
power to them and uh so i' I've done a
couple hybrids besides the Wilson lane
and then I time started to
unravel uh I just I I have a whole
different thought process and as of last
year I uh I just let the MS go like
we're just we're just making seeds now
like uh and and in that way and and so
I'd like we pop x amount of
seeds we're we're scratching our chin
thinking about what Mel we're going to
breed with n we just leave them all what
do you mean just leave them all just
leave them all but just leave them all
people grow them just like any other
pack of seeds get great weed on to the
next one and are we talking about
multiple males from the same line like
almost like an OP or different lines
different lines it's just okay so if I
get a pack of like a papaya cross from
you it could be a papaya this papaya
that Pap papaya cross to if like if you
know all these Ms or hey man just grow
some [ __ ] seeds you know yeah grow
some weed you bought seeds from this guy
grow them like oh you want a a a vision
well then buy the [ __ ] Wilson
one
that's you want F buy the Wilson fem oh
you want you want F2 F3 they're sold out
oh you want you want you want back
crosses we got a few back crosses so
that's like that's my my rhetoric it's
all like we we did that we did that we
did that we're doing this now and this
this now is like a lot of people are
like scratching their heads but but why
but
why go smoke some weed and then come and
tell me but why come smoke with me come
like come come and and and like there is
no Wizard of Oz [ __ ] here so just come
to Oz or whatever and just see what
we're doing here you know and and and
very confident in my craft to the point
where I bring [ __ ] you know the who's
who's breeders around and show them my
dick you know and I mean that in the
sense of like come check out my grow
look at my grow look how clean I keep it
look how cool it is and they're like
damn you're like a crazy person but I
know exactly what you're up to and I'm
like yeah [ __ ] yeah I do I I have much
respect for you and I told these guys
before that too it was like you know no
matter what kind of controversies around
big mace he doesn't [ __ ] sugarcoat
[ __ ] he just tells us yeah exactly how
he's doing [ __ ] and there's no back like
back door [ __ ] talk about it like
this what we're doing you want it or not
you know I and for the people that are
talking [ __ ] on you you know [ __ ] them
really no one no one above you is ever
gonna talk [ __ ] about you no one that's
like sometimes like they they get in
their moods and I'm like what why am I
in your [ __ ] mouth guy or or why do I
even think that you're talking you
really know me why why do off you yeah
[ __ ] yeah shout out me you know I
remember like uh I want to say like four
years ago when I was doing my first
Wilson blast one of my first Wilson
blasts where I just hit it to everything
I was like counting my eggs before they
hatched and I posted a story I was like
yo check it out guys future cross is
coming like I literally posted all the
seeds that I popped cross to Wilson and
I think it was like jungle boys are
capulator they like they post and
they're just like look at this guy you
know I'm like let's go you know f look
at me now people are like yo I'm like I
don't they're sold out gone you have
different categories of your seeds you
got the fem you got the B crosses F2 F3
are sold out sorry uh and now you're
doing this kind of thing with all the
different males is there different
prices that reflect those different
categories or is everything about the
same so I'm still doing single uh Mel
pollinations in between you know we get
like three four seasons over here so
like I'll do I did a honey banana Wilson
that's my other stud that I created the
Willie be so I did align with him I did
a light dep with two tunnels and just
hit a bunch of things with the willieb
and so I squeezed that in before the
full term and the full term now uh I
mean the price points reflect on the
scarcity of set pack but I don't I never
like to reach like 80 is where I'm like
all right cool we could both leave happy
for untested varieties right and and
I'll throw in some pork barrel where
where like you get an extra pack and
some or not because I totally believe in
that product right or or uh or
everything else like [ __ ] you make a
million seeds in your backyard I'm not
I'm not you know trying to make a
million dollars I'm just I want to get
by and make some I'll I'll meet you guys
somewhere around 2530 sometimes I'll
make some bundle sets where it'll
incentivize the sell where in instead of
like them spending 25 to 30 on a pack
they'll come with four packs and they'll
level out to 15 to 20 a packs so there's
like like I'm the I'm the breeder and
the seller so I got to find ways to
incentivize and put my product that I
stand behind in people's hands and and
it's and it's and it's a you know it's
and and and I I know like it's like
driving the masses around like I'm just
like pulling teeth sometimes on trying
to like explain to them like I'm the man
I'm the man it's like first place look
guys first place and they're just like
this guy's crazy but hey man [ __ ] you
got to be crazy to do what I do that's a
fact that is a fact uh okay so there is
a little bit of price difference but no
nothing crazy especially with today you
know with people that are working lines
constantly and they're selling their
[ __ ] [ __ ] we all know who like I got to
shout out names but there's
[ __ ] out there with a $500,000
$5,000
packs $10,000 we saw the other day
[ __ ]
godamn ridiculous like you're saying
this is exactly what I'm making price
reflects that let's go you know I
[ __ ] Mass respect to that uh I know
everybody wanted me to bring it up mace
we gotta talk about it why do you hate
white people bro drunk mace hated white
people that one night all right and and
and
that I don't know I guess it's just
uh of you know growing up as as as like
a Mexican in South Central LA and not
understanding white people that's the
that's like my Abridged uh version and
and like they there I didn't grow up
around any of them and and it was a easy
target that night and and and I went for
it you know that's I don't hate white
people by the way I I I love white
people I have a half brother who's white
and I I love him dearly and and and I do
business with white people a lot of my
demographic they're white as they come
and and I and I respect them and I know
them on the name to-name bases and and I
hope that they know that I don't hate
them because I I don't it was just I was
at a low point in my life uh drinking a
lot every single night and I just I
lashed out and somewhere deep inside me
I convinced myself that I didn't like
white people that day fair enough and we
talked about that before there's plenty
of people here uh that definitely found
solace with cannabis quit drinking with
it you yourself quit drinking with it I
know I've said plenty of [ __ ] dumb
[ __ ] being drunk back in the day but
that's exactly why I don't drink anymore
uh and you yourself you quit drinking
too how long's it been now I'm going on
a little bit over three years so
ironically the day I went to visit cap
shop today that's the day I stopped
drinking I was like I was on top of the
world lost in the sauce oh yo cap
invited me to go you know parlay with
him at his at a c drop [ __ ] yeah some
dude gives me a tall can with the
[ __ ] devil imprinted on it I go home
that night I get hammered and and start
[ __ ] off the whole world on on
Instagram but you know that happened
August 23rd three years ago and and and
[ __ ] that's how long it's been it's
been three years and a couple days that
I just I don't drink no more it used to
be a thing where it's like hey stop here
let's grab a sixpack let's grab a 12pack
I I need to drink every night and then
like some days they'll be like Oh I'm
[ __ ] throwing up [ __ ] I'm I'm sick to
my stomach I'm I'm I'mma slow down I'm
not going to drink for a day and then
back on the [ __ ] train and I'd be
blackout drunk engaging with my
customers selling seeds playing Call of
Duty getting first place [ __ ] in a
Lobby full of Instagram patreons and and
I just thought it was normal and then
one night I I drank the wrong beer with
the [ __ ] devil on it and the devil
came out
Y is that what we're going
[Laughter]
with it was that [ __ ] that brand of beer
[ __ ] that that brand of beer and and and
yeah man that was the last day I drank
and it's the best thing that ever
happened to me shortly after I stopped
drinking uh a lot of dope things
happened in my life and I'm I'm in full
control of my life now you know I just
kind of had to reflect on the outside
looking in I looked at it was all on it
was all on record there's videos of it
you know some haters over there holding
on to it for dear life and uh like I
seen it all over the Internet plastered
and I told my constituents I'm like I
made a social contract with them I was
like I'm not going to stop I'm I'm GNA
stop drinking and I'm very I'm a
shameful guy like I'm a man of my word
so I stopped drinking it's it's it's is
that's how easy it was hard but that's
how easy it was like I made a social
commitment of course I did it for my
family but I also did it for the people
that help me maintain my family which is
my constituency all my followers all my
people that buy my seeds and support the
brand taking care of your people ain't
nothing better than that man I see you
guys going off in the comments tell of
you guys congratulations mace
congratulations all you guys I I got
nothing against alcohol uh luckily I can
control it where at a point there was
definitely a point where I couldn't uh
but now I can drink like a scotch you
know every few months or whatever just
for the flavor and it stops there cuz
like there was a point where I was going
to work we were talking about old jobs
earlier uh there was a point where I was
going to work and just [ __ ] throwing
up all over the [ __ ] floor but you
know back then it was like that you come
to work and you're GNA drink like a
[ __ ] man you know you're gonna work
like a [ __ ] man now yeah so I tricked
myself and making it okay like I'd read
dumb [ __ ] like oh these guys Dr like I
drink too I'm like them or or or I don't
drink in the morning or or or like I
don't drink before noon it's one and
it's just like yeah tell yourself
whatever [ __ ] want boy you know tell
yourself whatever the [ __ ] you want and
yeah I just had to stop yeah some of
those things man they just become
self-destructive Behavior but I'm glad
to know that you don't hate half of me
that's nice to
[Laughter]
know all right guys I see you popping
off there in the questions we'll get
around to that in just a minute
uh Sonic uh you do a bunch of live
auctions of your seeds we were talking
about you letting things go you know for
a price that ain't nobody going to
complain about I picked up a few packs
from you because I definitely want to
see what your gear is about you know
that's how I judge breeders ain't by
like what everybody else is [ __ ] pay
attention everybody in chat right now it
ain't about what everybody's saying
about him stay about the [ __ ] drama
find out for yourself like let the seeds
speak for themselves now there's some
people that uh that I just could not
support or even care to try their beans
but you are not one of them those are
mainly the people that you know talk
about burning their plants [ __ ]
Holocaust style and yes that happened
guys uh I don't even think I'm gonna
release that yeah I'll release it as
bonus content for you whatever uh yeah
podcast gone wrong that's what we'll
call it podcast G wrong no doubt there's
some [ __ ] you just can't say or don't be
like bragging about shooting people's
houses up like I ain't trying to get
involved with all that you know that's
SC man I'm you know miss me with any
type of drama I used to be the I wrote
the book on that [ __ ] you know back in
the day I used to who who wants it you
know Meme Canon's pointed your way you
know I can't do that [ __ ] more like I'm
getting too old youin got time for it
you know you're working on your success
and like you said ain't nobody going to
be bitching at you from the top yep
great up so desert island question
here top three strains for the rest of
your life you ain't got nothing else
I'll take uh
Skittles
OG
and I'm going need some I need one more
and I hope I got this one right but
maybe I'll take a papaya with me just
for for for for for fruit sake you know
switch it up a little bit's got some
good flavor is there sir no G or it like
original [ __ ] give me sfv I'll be
good you know sfv all right [ __ ] yeah so
Taco I'm going to shorten the [ __ ] out
of your question here buddy oh my god
let's try to keep it to like one sense
guys have you ever had any this like
another show that we do too we like
doing conspiracy theories and like
getting all [ __ ] high and just like
wondering you know yeah um have you ever
had like any Supernatural
experience uh one time me and my wife
were driving and we seen like a object
and then it left that's as close as it
happened that's is and right when I
wanted to take a picture of the random
object in the air as soon as we passed
the freeway underpass it disappeared and
this happened uh on our trip to in
December when we went to Fresno I think
and and and I'm just like there's so
much alien [ __ ] that happens nowadays I
was like whatever it's real I was just
like whatever I guess I guess they're
here you know like I'm not even gonna go
on Instagram and tell nobody but like
that's the only time it's happened and
happened this this year that passed in
in December and that's as close as like
I've had to weird [ __ ] around me who
knows it could have been like a [ __ ]
plane or something but to me that looked
like a very still object and then it
disappeared and then we just went on our
merry way that's as close as I've been
to some freaky [ __ ] like that no Ghosts
no paranormal [ __ ] nah I've had I've had
dude dudes uh come in my
house like real
guns not ghost
[Laughter]
though let just cut that part out right
there it's all good that's going oh [ __ ]
so T all right Taco I got you homie so
when the aliens finally show up do you
think they have their own version of
cannabis and do you think it's like here
where the aliens have the Cannabis
culture and they have pictures of humans
on the die tapestries what the [ __ ] kind
of question is that bro God damn big dog
that's a long one do you think they'll
have their own version of cannabis n
just go with that I think they'll be
Beyond cannabis I think they'll be here
for you know other purposes you know
cannabis is probably Beyond them and
[ __ ] if they're cannabis enthusias well
[ __ ] we're on top of the world big DG
yeah we're good then you
know unless they [ __ ] [ __ ] phos our
ass yeah man straight up thank Panda
wants to know what's your favorite plant
that you've
lost uh so I've come across like some
Elite strains that I I've never been one
of like oh we we got this and you know
keep cloning it and keep it around it's
like cool we got this nice like that's a
nice tool damn that's a nice Cut damn
that's nice and then as time goes by
you're like oh like that was a pretty
nice Cut like I don't like asking people
for anything and and and now it's gone
and and and and that's that's an
inconvenience so like a lot of cuts
right that I've come across that just
kind of left like bwiz 32 [ __ ] you
know real animal mins real real uh
kushman's rabbit hippie and just like
everything that's come across and and
it's not that I lost it it's just a
matter of like uh how much space I have
and and the creativity that I'm pursuing
and and I'm a seed popper like I that's
cool like we could do motor breath and
papaya and the whole [ __ ] Elite
catalog every [ __ ] time to a new mail
but I'm looking for brand spanking
unscathed new and that usually requires
a seed pop and and coining turps that
have not been coined and looking in
places that aren't Elite clones and
going to [ __ ] Canada and Europe and
[ __ ] land race varieties From Any
Given seed company and just looking
under stones that aren't those Elites
but yeah I feel bad when I lost every
clone I've lost to this day but it
wasn't CU I lost it it was just cuz
that's just how things had to be because
of my space and I'm not one to be like
my my Greenhouse would be full with just
that catalog I'm I need to do seed Pops
I I because that's how I look at stuff
and if if hey man if it gets lost [ __ ]
it man you know just make sure the
Wilson mail's always around and we're
good so that's the one that you just
can't lose not that I just can't lose
but like in this Unwritten book of
[ __ ] it will be it will feel good in
10 years 20 years from now to be like yo
I got my same mail [ __ ] you know like
what do you got you know like oh you
don't got your M that [ __ ] everything
that's whack you know that's just
like that's how I look at things and
that's how kind of I was taught right
like you were taught to go hunt to M
when I stepped on the scene from the
people that I looked up to you go hunt
to Mel and you build a line and you keep
your Mel around that way cross it back
to the Mel and just just do true
breeding and that's how I looked at it
and uh that's why I kept my Mel around
because you know that's that's part of
my legacy speaking about males uh Big
Bad John wants to know male selections
what do you look for
so so like when you're making a cross
you're making a
cross if you're basing it on structure
I'll power to you I don't base my plants
on structure it's just kind of a given
right like hopefully it has enough
structure most of the time they do so
that's cool and all structure is fine
biomass is fine but flavor turps that's
what we're after so if we're trying to
make a hybrid of for me for instance I'm
trying to make shishka Berry hybrids and
honey banana hybrids and and headbanger
hybrids so first thing I would do is to
grab those tools and I would go grab
head banger seeds shishco Berry
seeds X X seeds whatever you grow those
out
visually some will grow better than
others right that's cool that's fine but
some of them will start to
like Mel's right visually you start to
choose oh that's a run that's a run
you're left if you pop 12 seeds you're
left you got six seeds two of them suck
you're left with four then kind of you
know start stem rubbing start look at
the females if you flowered out the
females you kind of notice like if
there's two ways to to lean like I'll
give you an example barbera's pie I
popped a regular pack of barbera's pie
um some of them lean towards the train
wreck [ __ ] which is not my selection
right like that's not something I would
want to encapsulate and sell to you
knowingly like yo not knowingly but I
mean it in the sense like I'm not going
to sell train wreck to you I'll sell
train wreck to you but I'm going to tell
you it's train R right yeah so Barber's
pie you're growing your Barber pi or
whatever [ __ ] selection you're aiming
for and and you elude the this is just a
way of doing it you elude that stem rub
from that female leaning you know
[ __ ] feno or whatever and you kind of
go look for that in the MS but you got
to keep in mind when you're doing
selection you're alluding to your bar
what is your bar your bar is your
experience what is your experience your
experience is how many seeds you
physically tangibly grown yourself
that's all you know so like your
selection is this most of the time
because a lot of people haven't popped
let alone seen that many things not
saying that you haven't but that was my
process going through the ringer it's
like oh as I went by now I know what
bandid Haz is now I know what A5 is now
I know what C4 is now I know what Dosey
is now like I know what all these things
are because I grew
them so that's all part of your
selection process is like what you know
and just kind of narrowing it down and
and finding that flavor and making
hybrids with
it I got to ask you this really quick
before we get back to you guys'
questions uh because we talked about
this not too long ago you seem pretty on
par with about what I do too how do you
feel about some of the people that like
some of the runs are some of the best
ones cool they might have some of the
test
[ __ ] that's not your thing hey not your
no not that it's not my thing
like sometimes you find turps that you
won't find in a big plant on a small
plant look at Skittles and [ __ ] right
when we did the blue Magoo back cross
twice uh I did a big old hunt of that
which I didn't know at the time I really
didn't have to do that big of a hunt uh
but we did Big Old Hunt of that and we
had some runs and I did keep them just
because we had the space uh and they
were [ __ ] crazy Frosty and they were
[ __ ] amazing and I actually kept the
Clone off the one uh but like selection
breeding wise that wouldn't be my [ __ ]
because I'm after that Vigor like that's
a big deal for me if the
TPS the [ __ ] high are on point and
it's a vigorous [ __ ] like that's what I
would want to breed with you know yeah
and I'll [ __ ] take that amount and
pull that down to like what's the best
of that fits that description that's
going to be my that's going to be my
[ __ ] so steal says I heard about Masonic
from a pack of Chile Riano Chile veric
cost with Wilson is there anything else
you have with the Chile Verde still have
my chile verde seed stock uh but I never
Revisited the Chile Verde clone it was a
kind of just I did what I had to do with
that and I don't see me revisiting that
line until maybe later on in life where
I run out of Chile Verde seed stock I
might pop some more of my chile verde
Wilson find a nice CH Verde leer and
some other stuff and just repopulate
those lines it's a good question Dan
thanks for bringing this up I didn't
even think about that uh where' the name
Wilson come from so Wilson is a cross
between uh a string called castaway and
Tropicana Castaway is banana OG papaya
uh so it was a play on words uh I I
didn't name Wilson Oni named Wilson when
I made the strains for Onie uh that's
how it's easier to sell seeds when they
have a [ __ ] name so they named them
and uh I just kind of stuck with it and
it turned into a life of its own and I'm
glad they [ __ ] called it Wilson
because Wilson is super [ __ ] like
culturally relevant every time I turn on
the TV the name Wilson's there every
time I open a book there's something
about Wilson [ __ ] Tom Hanks this
[ __ ] uh Forest Gump that so it's
always like this proximity that always
ties back to the greatness behind the
name and it it just the universe blessed
me with a dope uh Flagship strain name
for
sure uh dank Panda wants to know
favorite cross that you've ever
created um maybe Wilson uh as as time
has gone by Wilson itself as as like the
F1 or like any of the generations or the
hybrids of it it's it's special in its
own way that it's not another
regurgitation of the strains that were
used to make it so it's not necessarily
another papaya or another Tropicana it's
its own tropical mix that has stood the
test of time since like 2017 till today
that is like d like I did this cool like
I'm proud of this train because it's not
just something someone else did it's
just something new it's it's a it's a
breath of fresh air and and I'm very
proud of the Wilson and what I've done
with it for
sure fair enough answer uh Taco wants to
know is there a cross that you would
love to
make uh I'm working on all that stuff
right now I'm all the stuff I love to
make is all kind of happening right now
there's there's uh people always ask me
like wouldn't you like this clone and oh
like nah there's no end all Beall for me
i' I've gotten to the point in my life
where if I see something that I really
like I can go grab it or reach out and
uh everything that I want right here
like I'm very confident in and what I
learned and and and and and that I push
on you guys so like you know everything
that I that like I'm wishing for like I
I got the tools to do it and I'm already
doing it Taco says I like the chicken in
your logo what's the story I'm uh I have
a chickens I raised chickens i' I've
raised chickens for a little over 10
years I got [ __ ] so many chickens at my
house we get eggs and they're like pets
and they give us eggs so they they
fertilize a little bit they do their job
they fertilize and then you use them
kind of like it's part of your IPM huh
I mean they there ain't no slugs at that
place you know I ain't got no snails or
nothing like that like I'm as far as
Critters on the ground we're pretty
clean man hell yeah they [ __ ] clean
up nice IPM sure we always had chickens
growing up too but yeah never did have
them around my [ __ ] weed plant
like I think we'd use some of the
chicken [ __ ] to grow with and everything
but never just had them like free
roaming around the plants that's pretty
cool seeing like some of your pictures
you're growing [ __ ] and they're just
like wandering around [ __ ] feeding
them and [ __ ] that's pretty smart too uh
all right well where can people find you
man like if somebody wants to look up
like what's masonics let's see some of
his plants like we're going to find you
on IG you got anything else yeah so I
got my Instagram Masonic smoker 4.0 that
more is like a lifestyle page where I
kind of just post like stuff that I'm
into my family and then I got my backup
page which is the Masonic 2099 and
you'll see me showcase some of my
growing talents there sometimes and uh
besides that man uh that's that's you
know I got my YouTube if you want to
look through some old videos that I've
done and I had I have a podcast that's
on Hiatus we'll be launching back a
little bit sooner than later on YouTube
but yeah YouTube and Instagram is kind
of where you'll find keeping up with me
you know I got my website but we just
sell [ __ ] on there we don't necessarily
post blog logs or nothing like that what
is that where people get seeds yeah you
go to Masonic seeds. that's where you
[ __ ] go look through that there's a
never ending list of selections there
for sure there you go guys go hit it up
and you do some uh like live auctions
and [ __ ] on your Instagram live
sometimes yeah well not auctions I just
like to engage with my crowd and and do
like a [ __ ] I'll incentivize a sell
you know you know buy this pack you
might win this pack type [ __ ] so you
never know what Shenanigans I'm up to
I'm always doing some Billy ma
[ __ ] see and he wouldn't make that
reference if he hate white people Billy
May white as he
gets no for real though uh guys go check
him out I picked up like three packs
from Big mace the other day three packs
I think I paid 60 bucks we can kind of
see what's going on with that there's
some fire [ __ ] in there like the LA Cush
cake there's some papay [ __ ] like I'm
stoked dude cuz I love the papaya too I
I'd like to work with it the flavor on
the papaya is probably one of my
favorite fruit flavors and weed of all
time only thing I never liked about the
papaya that I'd like to improve for me
is that [ __ ] knocks me the [ __ ] out I
could smoke that [ __ ] first thing in the
morning I'll be tired like I'm G want to
take a nap
afterwards but like everything else
about it the flavor the
yield I love that
[ __ ] I love getting ripped man I love
getting ripped that's for
sure any flavor as long as it's good and
it's not train
wreck it's not train rck all right man
mace thank you so much for taking time
out of your day to come talk to us kind
of [ __ ] reiterate some of those that
[ __ ] that's going on in the
community with the talk and the [ __ ]
haters and [ __ ] fuckum thank you for
coming on here speaking your real really
appreciate it and I'm looking forward to
going through your seeds uh we got to
get you on if you got time again I don't
know I'll hit you up but we're doing a
game show on Sunday if you'd like to
help me host that it's fun as [ __ ] it's
like an hour of people just dabbing
constantly like doing handstands and
[ __ ] one G dabs and all kinds of
crazy [ __ ] and then we give away some
seeds for so if you're interested in
doing that we'll have you on then go
check him out at Masonic seeds. thank
you big dog hell yeah till next time
this has been with crew podcast saying
good night
[Music]
right come
on I say it
baby I know you're on the
[Music]
road s on
it let's take it real
[Music]
soon you know we got what you need baby
take it
along I said we got what you need honey
come come
on on the
high
wow come
on