[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
all right today guys we've got an
awesome interview for you we've got none
other than the man himself dragonflame
genetics in here uh he's going to be
talking about his new lines that he's
coming out with some of the past stuff
that he's done we're gonna have a smoke
session as well so let's introduce him
without further Ado what's up dragon
slam how you doing man
[Music]
hey pretty good man thanks for having me
so let's talk you said you were working
with smaller canopies now you made the
big move from Hawaii to Oregon so you're
a little bit closer to us you're in the
Pacific Northwest now obviously the
climate's got to be a lot better to deal
with especially when you're doing indoor
um Oregon can be tricky still Oregon can
still be tricky
yeah especially where we're at
um we kind of went back to where we were
before we moved to Hawaii so we're back
in the Willamette Valley which does have
a you know fairly
it's nicer than Hawaii's growing season
um but it's still I mean it's certainly
not the Emerald Triangle we still get
you know some months or some years I
should say this season will be you know
October 1st and that's all you get and
some years you know you get lucky and
um usually a lot of rain and a lot of
fog and a lot of gray days
um whereas Hawaii was the endless
humidity that's all you get is the
humidity
um so it definitely were
we're kind of just in a rental right now
but uh we'll be getting a farm again at
some point but in the meantime we're
we're just doing some indoor
um you know kind of micro I guess you
could say we've got two five by five
flower tents and a two by four flower
tent so it's considerably smaller than
what I would usually be running but
that's just the sacrifice we had to do
to move
yeah yeah you gotta sacrifice some
things just to keep growing the plants
sometimes life changes and the plant
just keeps going
yeah what are you working on in those
rooms man what's new with dragonflame
genetics what's to come
so the big projects that I'm focusing in
on for probably the next year or two
um is going to be my mackberry moonshine
lines I have one tent that I just
um reversed the modified McBerry
moonshine so that's the GMO to the
macberry Moonshine was that original
um cross and so I have a keeper out of
that that was found by can Essentials
here in Oregon they're a wreck farm and
on their first run it was at like 4.6
Terps and like 26 THC and then in their
second run it uh went over six percent
Terps and almost 30 percent THC
garlic skunk notes
um crushes here in Oregon they uh they
Run Greenhouse
um like light supplementation
greenhouses all dialed in but still you
know still an organ Greenhouse you still
have the humidity um and it's a cut
that's been proven out for them and it's
uh it's everywhere right now in Oregon
pretty much uh they're hitting every
dispensary
um here and people are loving it so it's
one
um this reversal didn't make as much
pollen as I was hoping I will make some
seed but I am going to have to reverse
it again
um to really make the commercial size to
be able to release anyone
um so that'll that'll happen again
um and then the next my next reversal
which that cycle is vegging right now is
the blackberry moonshine bx1 reversal so
I'm gonna make
um s1s and then I'm also going to make a
feminized version of the Holly moonshine
line as I call it which is the
blackberry moonshine to the modified
macberry moonshine so it has the Mac
Berry on both sides just you know
different moms but the same dad on both
crosses so it should be
more consistent than like a normal F1
you know it'll have more of the same
traits from having the same lineages but
it'll still it should still have that
that Vigor that we all you know that we
all want
those are the
yeah those are the big ones for the for
the next year anyway
that aioli looked really good
and I'm definitely expecting to to get
some concentrate off that that last one
that you were talking about
the Mac Berry moonshine that sounds
delicious
yeah it is it um generally comes out
with like a tangerine candy or like a
tangerine kind of uh
sweet Funk kind of going on
um it's generally how the macberry
Moonshine that itself is
um and then the blackberry moonshine bx1
has more of the fuel sour
um raunch kind of to it and then the
modified has that garlic from the GMO
and like some skunky you know Sour Notes
it doesn't have like the Thai food side
of the GMO which you know some people
love GMO some people hate it
um it makes it great crosses and get
people love it for concentrates
um but you know not everyone loves the
terp
yeah absolutely speaking of nasty stuff
I've got to bring it up because there's
so many of my followers that have been
growing it we've talked about it before
and how much I love it uh the garlic
stash man is there any new plans working
with the garlic stash
um I it won't be this year but I do what
I want to do with that line is I want to
find a male out of that garlic stash and
I want to hit it to the modified
macberry that's that's my short-term
plan and at the same time I probably
will when I hunt through the line
looking for the mail I'll probably look
through females as well and you'll see
see if I can find a good uh breeder mom
that I could keep to you know maybe
reverse someday but I love the garlic
Terps I find them so
anti-stress you know that's a big thing
with the I find with the garlic is it's
really good powerful smoke that you can
function and you can get through your
day and you know there's a lot of crazy
[ __ ] going on in the world so there's a
lot to get stressed out about and it's
just one that it just kind of helps melt
that away so I definitely you know I'm
I'm going to be putting more garlic into
more of my lines especially for the next
year
that that's a good news man because
back when you first made that one uh are
you familiar with okay calyx at all
we've had him on the show before
um somewhat
somewhat personally but I've you know
through social media and such
he he grew that uh garlic stash for
quite a while and the constant trade-off
that was so freaking beautiful man
there's
quite a few cultivars out there nowadays
that have or they claim to have a garlic
chirp but I have not come across
anything quite like the garlic stash
where it was like that even GMO where it
was that overwhelming [ __ ] garlicky
oniony nastiness and I love it I love
that yeah
yeah I'm a big fan and I think like the
GMO I I like it by itself but I actually
prefer it in crosses I like to get away
from kind of that that that cookie side
of it and get more into just a straight
sour the straight raunch
um because with a GMO you still have
that under bite of
Thai food and kind of cookie-esque
um note to it it's one that is
especially depending on how far into
flower you take a GMO can be a pretty
you know GMO to eight weeks and GMO at
13 weeks you wouldn't even believe it's
the same damn plant
um so I mean it could be pretty
different
where do you like to take it down
where's your Harvest frame on the GMO
um pretty much as a blanket statement
I'll say I take everything way further
than most people do
um I smoke pretty much from the time I
get up to the time I go to bed I have a
[ __ ] up tolerance
um so I mean I'm I'm an all-day heavy
smoker and so the the early Harvest just
doesn't have enough potency for me I
like the I like to I like it really ripe
uh generally like I hear people say
eight weeks and 10 weeks and I'm like
I'm not really even looking at shopping
at eight weeks unless I'm outdoor in the
you know the weather is forcing me to
but
indoors I don't pull anything usually
under 10 or 11 if it's something for me
to smoke and usually more like 12 13 is
usually where I take things to you
really get the the full term profile and
the full potency that you're going to
get out of the line going deep
that takes a lot of patience going that
long man congrats on that one uh are you
seeing any different in the outcrossings
that you're making with like the
mackberry Moonshine is that Harvest Time
a little bit sooner is it about the same
um most of my selections have been done
in tough climates so generally just by
that fact I'm usually taking the faster
phenos
um that's just you know that's part of
how I have to select when I've been in
tough climates
so generally the longer I work something
the faster it's going to flower just
based on how I select plants
um and especially in Hawaii because the
days are so consistent and because it's
tropical and so close to the equator
especially in Hawaii things just flower
so much faster
that's for sure
um you had a ton of challenges going
over there in Hawaii you told me about
that last time would you like to tell
our followers a little bit about what
makes growing in Hawaii so [ __ ] hard
yeah I mean if you take just a simple
fact that it's 3 000 miles away from a
land mass and everything is shipped in
um so across the board everything is
three times more expensive
um you know like a bag of soil here on
the mainland you know 15 bucks for a bag
of box Farms on in Hawaii is 35 to 50 if
they even have it and then the actual
climate itself fights you at every step
of the way
um like at our spot we were at 900 foot
elevation uh we were about six miles
away as the crow flies to the ocean and
at our spot 300 to 500 inches of rain a
year is pretty average and normal for
that climate zone
um daily the humidity would usually be
no lower than 80 percent most days it'd
be you know closer to 90 percent in the
day time
and and then at night 99 humidity every
single night there's no Frost so there's
nothing no snow nothing ever resets your
pest pressures and your fungus pressures
so everything can breed year-round
fungus uh you know from mites to
I mean every every pest basically can
grow unchecked and also because it's so
isolated most of the things that we
would consider to be beneficial that
would
somewhat put a pressure back onto the
pet doesn't exist so it's a it's a real
recipe for a petri dish effect where
um you know you're in the jungle and
every single if it if it lives in the
jungle it's going to be in your garden
then there's no preventing it you can
deal with it as best you can
um but I mean I would find I'd have to
run you know 300 seeds Hawaii itself
would kill the first
[ __ ] 200 Fino is just from mold from
septoria from stem rot
um you know with in that kind of in that
kind of Zone it's it's
it's really tough really tough to grow
and then on top of that even if you you
know the stars align you how you you're
on your game you know you get stuff to
the Finish Well you're in a zone that
the humidity is never less than 85 so
then you go okay well how do you dry and
cure flour off grid
when it's 85 humidity and there's no
easy answer to that except for you know
boatloads of infrastructure and money in
order to overcome the climate and then
like even let's say you're with your
buddies and you got some fire and you
roll a joint and you roll it too slow or
someone starts talking you know and then
you go to light it well it's picked up
all the humidity and now it's not gonna
you're not gonna be able to smoke it
because it's too damn wet
um so I mean it's
as a grower and as a smoker it's a it's
a really goddamn challenging place
yeah that's I mean a lot of people don't
even consider things like that with that
kind of humidity it's going to be hard
to spray anything keep anything you know
uh pest resistant at all or you know
kill off the bugs that you already have
that's pretty [ __ ] intense man
yeah it's a tough place and then on top
of that you add a culture that
I'm an outsider I mean I'm I'm according
to them I'm the epitome of what they
don't like they don't like
people that come from the mainland buy a
piece of property you know it's
according to them it's their it's their
Island it's their you know it's their
spot they don't want people there
and when you're on a and when you're on
a rock in the middle of the ocean
there's no hiding
um you know everyone knows your business
everyone knows who you are everyone
knows if you're not a local everyone
knows and that makes you a Target
um so I mean from security Community
Vibes yep
yep you uh you know it's a
you have to absolutely love it it's it's
the most expensive state to live so you
have to [ __ ] love it and we didn't I
mean that's what it came down to for us
is we didn't love it enough to
to deal with it and we are so much
happier to be back here with family and
you know you don't know what you have
until it's gone type of thing and we
didn't realize how how big it would be
and then the pandemic hit so we weren't
even able to travel off the island for
[ __ ] 18 months
um so I mean it was it was a it was a
cauldron of of of stress and you know
trying to figure it out and trying to
overcome these obstacles and
um you know we're happy we did it we
learned a lot I [ __ ] especially about
cannabis and
um and my genetics in particular
um I learned a lot I learned the
exactly like exactly the threshold of
what cannabis can take and what each
line itself can take
that's awesome man yeah there's no way
to really learn that unless you're
thrown into it right
oh yeah I mean I I was humbled really
quick I thought you know I've been
growing a long time I was like oh figure
it out you know how hard could it be we
got this yeah I got this little you know
I'll have a rough Runner too is what I
figured and
you know and I get there and you know
it's it's constant pain there yeah being
over in that environment that obviously
had some Play Into You breeding towards
you know uh moisture resistance and the
high humidity and rot uh botrytis and
things like this
um is that something that you think
you're going to continue breeding for
being an organ
um yes in the long term yes
um at this exact this year of my life no
just because I'm indoor only
um you know indoor I can't like if you
don't have the pressure you can't select
for it so for the next year I'm going to
be focusing more on feminized lines and
lines that are
um I hate to use the word hype or you
know exotic or whatever you want to call
it but more
um show body type lines you know more
indoor type stuff is going to be what's
coming out for at least the next year
nothing wrong with that man nothing
wrong with that at all
um we have a question from a follower I
think it's one of yours uh course says
any chance you ever plan on doing a
one-to-one
yeah I actually have
um two or three that I've made
um the big one that you know I pretty
much pass it to anyone that wants it I
don't charge for it I call it the
dragons remedy it's the uh sour tsunami
cut to the dragon stash and it's pretty
easy to find the one-to-one stuff and
then you can also find
some some more like 15 to 17 CBD and
like three to five percent THC Pinos as
well and that one it has a nice chirp it
kind of has that Sour Diesel
esque with some berries or some Citrus
coming from the dragon stack side
um and that one you know I've got a lot
of C that I made a lot of them and you
know anyone can DM me and I'll send them
a pack of the dragon's remedy
that sounds awesome man that's something
I definitely need to get into he's been
pushing me to to smoke more of the CBD
Heavies to get off cigarette smoke
so that might be something I'll be
hitting you up about pretty here
um yeah pandas says which garlic stash
do you prefer the 13 or the 21.
um I personally prefer the 21 the 21 has
more of the GMOs garlic side more of the
skunk side more of the um
you know more of the parts of the GMO
that I like the 13 is more ogkb heavy
and comes out more garlic cookie forward
it definitely has more of that dough
side that you know cookies is known for
um the 13 flowers much faster like most
people are seeing you know most people
like people that like seven to nine
weeks and then the 21 is more in line
with the dragon stash GMO side which is
you know 9 to 11 is generally where I
see people pulling the 21 so it really
comes down to your preference
thank you
GGG wants to know will Jeff continue to
expand the land race heirloom
preservation in unique crosses he's done
in the past
yeah yeah I don't know which ones I'm
gonna do next
um
probably I think the next one I'm gonna
do is I think I'm going to continue my
panamanium line which is the Panama Red
to the bengi haze I took that
yeah it's a really fun one
um I've got some photos too it gets I
was able to do one out in California and
I mean [ __ ] massive
um 18 foot tall 30 foot around monster
plants um and it has that
um kind of incense ammonia
kind of lemon cleaner side like the
Panama has with um the the bangy haze is
like a faster flowering
subcompact Haze you know that one's like
you know made for made for the shorter
season is where that baby Haze went
um so it kind of has something that you
can do outdoors in the Panamanian like
most Growers would be able to finish it
and so it's not so exact or so thin leaf
that you know it takes a Madman to to
try to do it
um I'm probably going to take that one
to F3
um that'll probably be the next one and
then I also want to get
um I want to take the Vietnamese black
one more step
I feel like that one I it needs uh I did
I already did an open pollination on it
and now I want to do my next one I
actually want to select I want to go
through and I want to find a find the
best email that I can
um but that will probably be
now a while down the road at least a
year I'd say
I don't think I knew that you did an OP
of that uh Vietnamese black that's
pretty awesome man I've been wanting to
grow that one for a long time what'd you
find in that uh heritage
yeah we did a Vietnamese black and then
we also did a Vietnamese a lot in Hawaii
and so the black is more like swamp
Terps
um there was like some cedar wood
Sandalwood kind of Terps in there
um there was some like Pine Saul
um we had one that was like um kind of
like geraniums kind of like that herbal
tea almost
um and then the lot was more like sharp
Citrus and sharp lacquer like really
more nose assaulting
um whereas the black was more like
Pleasant it's kind of I don't know if
I'm conveying what I mean but
um they're both really racy uh really
long flower
um growing them next to each other you
would believe that that they are both
from Vietnam but they are a little
different
um that's a lot uh will go more colorful
especially towards the end of flower
whereas the Vietnamese black is more
like straight black
so is that something you said would say
it was true breeding for is that black
color yeah
that's impressive how about the high off
of it what was the high like
heard mixed reviews
um well I mean if it depends on if you
like thin leaves
um it's it's definitely [ __ ] potent
um if you don't like if you don't like
thin leaves it's gonna be uh really
overpowering
um it's pretty it's easy to overdo
there's no ceiling like the more you
smoke I mean it's pretty soaring
um I won't say it
um some people find it paranoid I
personally didn't and my wife didn't
um I know some people though some people
just get paranoid off of thin Leaf so I
can't really say on that I didn't get
paranoid
um but it definitely it's a racy you
know nothing like modern genetics
um there's absolutely no bag appeal no
you know it's really wispy
um long flower I mean it's
you're not gonna You're Not Gonna Fill
rooms with it I mean appeal means so
much to people these days it does some
of the best smokes I've had are from the
worst looking buds oh I almost guarantee
it you know 90 of the time the only time
I've ever found it not to be true was
the dragon stash
um and that's that was pure pure dumb
luck the the redfinos end up being the
terpiest
um every other line I've ever seen you
know usually the green Fino smells
better it's you know usually the way it
goes
tips straight from Dragon slime genetics
because hey it's big in the market
though right now I mean people want the
fast flowering and they want purple and
they want gas I mean that seems to be
and they want hype and they want Femmes
I mean that's that's what I hear anyway
from everyone that bends my seeds they
all ask us all ask the same questions
yeah and you've really been getting into
the Femmes I do want to talk about that
quite a bit what was it that calling for
people asking for your genetics
feminized that made you get into it
or were you [ __ ] around with it
um it actually was more so because I
wanted to preserve cuts
um Hawaii decimated my library nearly
every everything from the last six to
eight years that I've hunted Hawaii
killed it
um I have a few things that I put into
tissue culture with node Labs that I'll
be able to get back but
um I pretty much crop after crop watch
more of my mom's die off and so I that's
why I wanted to get into Femmes
um I reversed my orange dreams keeper
which I no longer have so I'm so so
thankful that I was able to reverse it
before Hawaii killed it
um so that's that's why I got into
Femmes is because of
the understanding and especially now
when I first started growing and when I
would be buying seeds I would never buy
them you know usually if I'm gonna buy a
seed line I'm looking for males as well
because I want to continue I want to
work the line
so and then on top of that most of the
Femmes that I had run that I had seen
run you know the early process that a
lot of people used through like
stressing or through root cutting
there's all kinds of crazy ways that
people have huge stress to make uh
feminized seeds it's only more recently
that people have been doing it more like
with you know sprays or STS or the elite
spray which I just I just think it's a
better process
um you know anything that's doing the
like the root manipulations to me that's
a stress that the plant should be able
to overcome like I'm trying to breed
stronger lines and so I've personally
always kind of
not been too impressed with Femmes just
because of the process of how to make
them
um so it's been more the longer I've you
know I've been in the game and the more
I've seen the more research I've done
and the more people I've seen doing
feminism doing them right especially you
know my mind just kind of opened to them
but I do know Market wise that's what
people want more than regulars so I mean
it's kind of
it's kind of both really it's you know
serving the need and you know doing what
made sense for me at the time
absolutely man
um you said you you make your own spray
right your own reversal spray
yeah these every time I've done it I
have I think I think I'm gonna try next
time I'm gonna use the pre-made Elite
spray this uh last one well actually all
three of them really like the orange
dreams didn't really want to reverse
either it did
um
and I you know I did get a good amount
of seeds of a few of the lines
um and then the Mac Dragon reversal that
one went really well but I also sprayed
12 huge plants so I had
you know back up the backups I had a
whole Army of plant matter that I was
that was being sprayed so just by the
sheer size of what I was able to do I
had enough to pollinate the greenhouse
and then I tried with the
um GMO cut and it wouldn't reverse for
me and then I just did the modified and
it did like it made male pollen sacks
and a few of them did have pollen but
for the 99 of them were totally pollen
free
um so I think the next time I'm going to
try the elite
um stuff and see if you know if I can
get a better reversal out of it
so do you think the amount of pollen
that comes off of these females is it
directly related to like the type of
reversal spray that you use or the
compounds that you use on it or do you
think there's some genetics that the
females just just like males there's
some that just naturally don't make very
much seed or drop very much pollen even
though they're great
yeah I
I it's both factors some females are
just really hard to reverse
um
you know and some like the orange dreams
the thing with that one is that one was
it was making a [ __ ] ton of pollen but
the problem was it was so dense and so
thick I mean that's what that line does
is it makes huge football colas and so
it was actually so dense that the pollen
sacks wouldn't open properly so all the
pollen that I was able to get and what
actually seeded was for me
literally manually opening pulling
everything apart because anywhere that
the pollen just would stick to the
cluster it would mold really fast like
within two days you'd go out and not be
moldy and you'd look and you'd
investigate and pull it apart and it's
like oh well there is a big old glob of
pollen that fell out that just stuck
right there on the plant matter and
molded
um and then some plants you know it's
just some are finicky
um you know as soon as just the nature
of farming it and it's
um you know it's how much effort you
want to put into it like the like the
modified I'm gonna get the damn thing to
reverse I'm gonna make seed off of it it
might take me a few tries but it's gonna
happen
um so I mean it's it's it's farming is
always it's always a pain in the ass I
mean there's always there's always
something it's still like always
something
I mean like the perfect example like the
and even males do this as I guess my
example like the last cycle in Hawaii
that we did
it was kind of funny we had already
decided that we were going to put the
farm up for sale we hadn't decided time
yet and I so I had a crumble cake mail
that when I stress tested it it was
[ __ ] phenomenal solid beautiful
took way more abuse than what I thought
it was going to be able to especially I
mean that's a cookie type line
um and so in the stress testing it was
solid and so I had a whole Greenhouse 12
by 30 foot Greenhouse I mean beautiful
plants huge mail I would have made
mountains of seed and um it through
female parts it didn't do it in stress
testing but it did
and what should have been the cake run
you know it was getting fed everything
was a quote unquote on track
um and so that's actually because for me
if if a male throws female parts it's a
wash like that's not worth breeding with
so it was like I chopped the garden down
and I went up and told my wife and I was
like well I think we just got the
[ __ ] sign that we're out of here
because that cycle that we were waiting
on just
maybe that was The Universe telling us
to get the [ __ ] off a rock I don't know
but
um anyway that I mean that and that's
with a male that already had gone
through stress testing so I mean it's
that's farming
so I have a huge question to ask you
here you mentioned males throwing off
female parts I've actually talked to a
couple breeders where they said they
prefer
males like that because they hold that
female genetic and The Offspring are
more likely to produce feminized uh
progeny what do you think about that
I think that's gross science I think
Herman's Herm that's all I think um
instability is instability no matter how
you slice it if a plant is willing to
harm and you use it you are passing
along genetics that have the propensity
to harm
um and for me this is uh This is my
legacy this is what I leave for the
[ __ ] world right so for me
you know I try to do the absolute best
work I can and I personally people don't
forget when you see that one of their
rooms they do not forget that it has
something that you know uh leaves a mark
it does it does
um you know [ __ ] up someone
yeah oh it's never their fault it's
always it's always the breeder
so just to play devil's advocate here
you're saying absolutely no instability
is instability how about
males that throw resin that are heavy on
resin that's usually typically a female
you know trait uh males always have a
certain amount of resin but the ones
that are overly coated with it
I love those males those are the ones
that I tend to look for
um if a male has grief then I usually
The Prodigy will have grease and I
shouldn't even say what people want to
do with what they're going to run for
themselves have a happy like some of the
greatest strains in cannabis history are
accidents I mean that's that's the way
you know what I mean so
it's more just
it's understanding that if you're
passing that along in your genetics and
then you're selling those genetics
that's
friends and even still if you have a
male that does that that does throw
let's say it throws a few hairs let's
say it throws a [ __ ] hundred hairs I
mean let's go to both extremes
if you run through the genetics yourself
you actually test those seeds and you
stress test those seeds and you see oh
well they're solid the male might have
had issues but if that didn't get passed
along but that's where stress testing
comes in and that's where you know
running those seeds and you know
everyone has their own different
standards you know this is every time I
open Instagram there's 100 new breeders
so I mean this is everyone's different
standards everyone has their own
paintbrush so to speak for me I don't
want to grow Herms I don't want to sell
Herm seed so for me from for my
collections a Herm is a kilt
that that's a solid Point that's
something that I get behind for sure I
find it very important to uh do stress
testing on any genetics that you're
providing there's a lot of people I mean
I'm not going to say names but there's
one guy in specific that drives me
insane and he always talks about how
cannabis naturally has that
hermaphrodite trait because of its uh
ability to reproduce itself even if it
doesn't get pollinated to carry on those
genetics
so his claim is that you don't have to
stress test any of these seeds there's
going to be Herms and everything how do
you feel about that
that's an interesting standard to have I
mean if we're going to go off of that I
mean think of all the plants that we
have made
off of so I mean that
that's our job as breeders in my opinion
is to push the line forward and to make
the line better for the for the next run
um and so for me yeah there are a lot of
lines that do that it is a
self-preservation tactic that is a
hundred percent true it is a
self-preservation tactic and it's our
job as at least for me anyway it's my
job as a breeder to minimize that to
remove it from as best I can from lines
and if it's present like perfect example
I made the peanut butter breath orange
dreams
about 30 of them harm that's like I've
you know 20 30 that's probably even
higher than what it really is it just
sticks out in my mind so I always over
exaggerate for in my mind
but the ones that don't harm are
phenomenal and so I've had people that
are like oh bro you know I got this from
this person or that person and it was
phenomenal I want to grow it and I tell
them well I don't sell those seeds
they're they harm this is their you know
their rate I've had people that are like
well I don't give a [ __ ] I want to run
them anyway
you know everyone can make their own
their own choice for their garden and
you know
some people a lot of people have
actually come out of that line which to
me was a wasted project like once I saw
that that rate was that high to me like
it just sits in the back of my fridge
and
C'est La Vie you know maybe I'll use it
for a seed Sprout tea someday but that's
you know that's about it but
yeah everyone that I saved mine for and
I didn't see a big uh I didn't see a big
jump over like a corn SST so yeah we end
up just being food
boil them shuck them put them on salad
we're good yeah so what would you say
was an acceptable hermery
um
that's a very varied question
um and something that I release I don't
want to see more than one or two hearing
reports and um for those Herm reports I
want them to have a reason and I want to
be able to find the reason
um but generally you know I my standard
is I expect that everyone that popped a
pack of my seat is going to find
something terpy something that they can
finish in their climate zone something
that has resistance
you know that's great smoke in every
pack that's basically where my standard
is and if they can't if that can't be
done then you know
like my fridge is full of lines it's
ridiculous it's easy to make seed let me
just say that it is really easy to make
seed but making sure that it's actually
worth something and you know worth
growing because I mean I know how it is
for me I only have so much space what I
put in that space matters and I know
that that's that's more of the norm than
oh well we go ham you can pop whatever
the hell you want so
you know that's what that's what I try
to aim for
absolutely I I appreciate you saying
that man definitely you can breed for
stability that's absolutely
um doable and these people that are
telling you you know it doesn't matter
it does they're just not willing to put
in the work as far as I'm concerned
so let me ask you the hard question now
out of everything that you've ever made
let's say top three what would be the
top three strengths so far that you go I
want this to represent what I've done
well the first one would be easy dragon
stash
um that is the sum of
um
you know all of my time growing and
breeding has gone into making that
strain
um and it's going to be one that I'm
going to continue working in fact I
actually just ran out of
um the F3 Green version so it's probably
going to move up the list because that
is our Flagship line
um you know the so I've got the red
version and I've got the Green version
F3 of the Dragon stash the red version
tends to go like blueberry fuel
um blueberry funk you know generally
those are the words that I hear
um when people describe the blue are the
the dragon stash red Fino the green is
more like a citrus Kush
um or like a sour Citrus
um and not like that Tangy type terp
like the actual true citrus peels like
actual fresh Citrus not that artificial
like candy Tangy turp
um
and so the number two would probably be
probably the modified mackberry
moonshine
would probably be number two
yeah it's one I'm I'm really happy with
um
you know it's a it's it's it's a damn
good one and so far everyone that's
tries that loves it
um I'd say probably number three would
probably be the Missy stash actually
um which is so that's my wife's favorite
Congolese Kush to my dragon stash so
it's basically my wife's favorite strain
to my favorite strain
um combined into one and that last I
heard anyway I don't know if it still is
but it has set the terp record in
Massachusetts and their legal system at
like six point like 6.7 is what they had
set it at
um and it's you know it's one that's
been really special because obviously
it's you know one of my wife's favorites
and one of my favorites so that's
probably
those those three
um
the blackberry moonshine probably would
also like that's probably a close tie to
Third
um
yeah I think I mean there's I've made a
lot of I may have a lot of lines over
the years
um you know so it's really hard to
narrow them down but I'd say those are
probably the tops
so let's hear a little bit about what
made you decide to make your own strains
what brought you in where you going I'm
gonna try my hand up reading
yeah so I grew up in California and
that's where I learned to grow I was in
like the amateur Calaveras County Line
area
um and in that area you could pretty
much any string could go out in a 200
gallon pot and if you could keep it
watered
you'd you'd see put the potential that
plant was you could pretty much finish
anything
um and then I moved to Oregon after a
divorce and I brought all of my
California genetics with me
and that first season in Oregon I got my
ass handed to me with mold and
at that time when I was looking around I
could not find people in my area that
were breeding that were making outdoor
seeds and so for me I've always like I
do indoor I love indoor but what I my
passion is is the Outdoor the full term
monsters so that's generally where my
focus goes indoor you know just dial
your rooms in but outdoor That's
genetics that's what your plants can
take
so when I had that year when everything
molded on me that I brought from
California it was like okay well what am
I going to run next year and then it was
like well [ __ ] there's there's not much
that I'm seeing so it was like research
you know okay well this feed line has
good you know if people have said okay
well this does good in their climate in
Canada or this you know oh they're this
guy's breeding out in Maine or just you
know it was like trying to find these
these strains that I heard about that
you know oh someone said it did good on
mold resistance so I ran you know a [ __ ]
ton of all these different lines trying
to find okay well this one and this one
okay and then it was okay well now I
need to make seeds combine them
and run them the next year and I mean
that's pretty much how I started was was
for myself like I
I would have never predicted dragonflame
genetics like I would have never
predicted selling seeds or
you know anyone even giving a [ __ ] about
my seeds to be honest
um so it was you know that's just where
it developed and then you know word of
mouth and you know people hear about it
and you know I was at that time I was
selling a lot of pounds that's pretty
much what was paying for everything was
um flour so it was
you know just all of it combining really
how DFG and breeding started
oh yeah man what's been some of your
favorite smokes that you didn't create
oh
um
well I'm a sucker for a gray OG uh TK 92
OG sfe the the the classics
um death star is another one of you know
one of my all-time favorites
um
the old Super Skunk cut I think that one
comes to mind a lot but I think about
um and then one of my buddies
um Hemlock was what his handle was back
in the old days on the forums
um and he gave me a [ __ ] ton of seeds
one of them was a dream Lotus Scentsy
star and he called it Fubar and it's
still to this day what in my mind what I
compare everything potency wise to I
mean True to this day still one of the
most true one-hitter quitter I mean at
that time I was moving pounds like crazy
I was had a roommate we were both all we
did was moved pounds and so we saw a
[ __ ] ton of flower we were in Sacramento
at that time so I saw a [ __ ] ton of
California Flower really great flower
and had access to it all the time and I
remember rolling that joint and I I hit
it and I handed it in to him and we were
trying to play Call of Duty and we
passed it back and forth and we both
were both just going down into the
[ __ ] chair dude why are we dying so
much you know oh man yeah I mean and it
was that was some I mean although
honestly a lot of a lot of hemlock's
lines had that were really phenomenal
he's probably
out of anyone unknown especially I mean
if if he had marketed and branded
himself he'd be he'd be a pillar in his
community but he didn't so he's an
unknown person just you know [ __ ]
some pretty fire for it some people just
get their genetics out there and are
happy with that yep
so is there is there any breeders that
you truly respect
that you would look forward to
yeah yeah
um
two-tone genetics is one we've done some
collabs together
um great great palette high standards
um great breeder great guy
Matchmaker genetics out of Hawaii is
another you know passion
first in breeding
um he's you breeding in Hawaii as well
for tough climates
um two dog seeds is here in Oregon
another great long time grower very
passion forward in his work meticulous
about sourcing and you know doing it
right
um he kind of has a bad rap for Rick for
naming things but hazeman I've had a lot
of great work out of Haven's lines but
you know you kind of got to be careful
about
what's what sometimes
um but he's you know he knows how to
select males I'll say that for sure he
knows how the plant works and how to how
to make nice lines
um
the um Lucky Dog Seed Co is one that
I've you know I'm like digging through
their packs and I'm going to be digging
through more of their packs looking for
some of the old school chem type stuff
um El Jefe is great as well old school
you know old school guy
um
but I mean I think I think it's pretty
much for me it's the people that that I
gravitate to are people that are doing
it for the passion of the plant not for
and the people that don't you see it you
see it real quick yep they might wear a
mask for a year or two and then boom
it's out there
it's funny I've always heard the saying
if there's a test of a strain but time
is a test of a breeder and you know
you're around long enough your
reputation comes out you know who who
you are what your standards are what you
are putting out into the world
you can't hide that [ __ ] forever people
figure it out exactly so what have you
been smoking on the most lately
um so I picked up uh from can Essentials
I grabbed a uh half I think of the
modified macberry when we first landed
um so I've been smoking mostly on that
and then going to the dispensary right
now now sadly
um you know just grabbing what I can
find that looks decent enough
um and I have my first cycle coming down
I'm week six right now so I'll have my
homegrown oh I'm so looking forward to
my own nothing better than your own girl
I mean you know the way that you like
your flowers so there's just nothing
that compares to that I want to thank
all of my followers for coming in all of
your followers for coming in and
checking out the stream this was an
absolutely great interview and I look
forward to having you on sessions I
don't know if you're willing to smoke on
camera but if you are we'll have to
we'll have to get you in for an episode
of sessions oh [ __ ]
we're having our smoke session now
people
how's that for the answer I can't let
you do it alone brother
we got to get a dab in here was that
that mackberry moonshine
yeah yeah so this is what I've got left
what a jar yeah
no they I you know it's funny it's one
of those things it's so surreal to go
into a shop and see something that you
made on the Shelf
but to see something that like they grow
with love in their plan and you can like
ride toward their Farm
I've been to a lot of [ __ ] show Rec
facilities let me [ __ ] say that I've
been to a lot of them I don't vouch for
very many like I can count on one hand
how many I will vouch for and they are
one of them
um everything I've grabbed from them has
been
you know truly truly done well and so
it's really awesome to see someone
that's I mean they're filling
greenhouses with that cut so it's it's
really cool to see someone that's you
know using one of my strains that does
it right that's always such a great
feeling
do you mind uh mind sharing a Horror
Story
um I think the biggest one that I my
wife and I still laugh about
um he was down in Grants Pass
and it was one of those facilities when
I walked in my wife and I looked at each
other and we like
what could we do with this [ __ ] spot
like it was gorgeous so it was right on
the river and they had I mean it was
probably 50 acres
and they had this crazy like octagon
two-story building and then on one side
they had huge warehouse space and then
right in front it was like picturesque
next to the river they had a they had
the permit to do a tier two here in
Oregon and I came down in the Consulting
row to try to help save their grow is
basically what my
um meeting was for and I got there and
they had I think they had nine Growers
working there
and my wife she's not a grower
um she's a nurse she came with me and
sure her not being the grower she's just
exposed to it because of me she walked
into their warehouse and was like what
the [ __ ] are you guys doing and they had
literally every pest they had russet
they had rude aphids they had PM they
had them all they had shelves of avid
they had shelf of Eagle 20 and four bed
and everything you're not supposed to be
[ __ ] doing yeah I mean hundreds of
lights in their warehouse and this was
like mid-june July so in my mind my
plants at that time were four foot tall
already so I'm going to this Rec Space
I'm expecting to see a field of [ __ ]
plants they have anything planted yet
and they were making I think they said
like twelve thousand dollars was what
each grower was making a month there and
I straight up looked at all of them and
I was like y'all [ __ ] robbing this
guy because their Garden was I mean
straight up everything you weren't
supposed to be doing and the the owner
was here and he had been in a motorcycle
accident or something and he literally
pulled out his bike and then right in
front of my wife and I and started like
crushing it up and snorting it and
looked at her and well you're a nurse
you should be okay with this and we're
like dude you're [ __ ] crazy like no
you're like and then he got a call from
a dispensary that they were like are we
need those clones that you promised us
and he was like oh yeah I'll bring him
down I got some moms for you and I
looked at him I was like I just told you
all of those plants should be [ __ ]
burned like start over just burn them
like they are not they're [ __ ]
infested and you've been using every
chemical so now they're they're [ __ ]
immune to Avid like you're not gonna go
put that on a [ __ ] shelf to give to
patients this was in the you know very
early days of wreck when they still had
medical like you could go to the
dispensary and if you were a medical
patient you might be buying that flower
sprayed with [ __ ] Avid and I was like
oh man I was it still pisses me off to
this day and he did I mean he ended up
taking those [ __ ] cuts to The
Dispensary to put on the Shelf [ __ ]
russet mites rude aphids braid with
[ __ ] everything and
obviously I didn't end up taking the job
because if you're going to be that like
that's your morals when you can go [ __ ]
yourself is how I feel no [ __ ]
those russets man just those alone are a
[ __ ] nightmare rude aphids on top of
it
oh I'll tell you it's an insane story
man yeah I'd take rough it might any day
over the week over rude aphids rude
aphids are like there I've never had
married Avis so I can
and I will never [ __ ] forget it like
oh man [ __ ] those pets
and you had the russets too
oh I've had Restless a few times over
the years russets are he used wettable
sulfur pretty easy to knock out russets
um you know those
for a while they were really a pain in
the ass but once once figured out
wettable sulfur they're pretty easy to
get rid of
so I feel that every one of these
obstacles that you face in agriculture
is a learning experience because once
it's happened it's already there you
might as well learn from it instead of
getting into that State of Mind where
you're just crushed and upset about it
you know and just kind of giving up it
everything happens for a reason and that
builds that knowledge of how to deal
with that Pest of how to deal with that
situation
so when I first got russets I did not
take it seriously I took it like most
pets that I have met up there we're
gonna try a few different things we're
going to start with like you know the
lowest chance and uh kind of build up to
it I've already lost this crop I'm not
okay with flowering these out you know
they're damaged they're stressed out so
we might as well see what works on these
[ __ ] so I actually kept the russets
around in an indoor environment for like
six months it was [ __ ] because a lot
of the lower end products like your your
natural like uh insecticidal soap and
[ __ ] like that they weren't really doing
anything to it and uh yeah if you don't
kill them with that they do become
immune to it they burrow into your stems
some of them won't even get touched by
it you know
so the only thing I found at the end was
heating up my room because that was kind
of keeping them out of the out of the
stocks and the stems of the Clones
and then using that wettable sulfur and
spraying that down and you got to be
consistent with it but yes it's not that
hard it's just a matter of uh
work ethic and consistency being on top
of them for sure yeah oh that's that's
farming 100
um there's no replacement for the
gardener Shadow I mean that's the way it
is the more work you put into it the
better your crop is I had one guy that
he had multiple tents in his in his
warehouse and he had spider mites like
crazy
and so his garage was like hoarded and I
kept telling him you were never gonna
get rid of spider mites until you clean
this garage out because you might spray
your tent they're in all of that right
there behind you too and he had his dogs
that would come through his grow and I
was like
until you keep your pets out of the grow
you're like they are bringing them in
and out they're not in this Barn anymore
they're on your property they're on the
trail that every Trail your dog takes
they are on just waiting
um but that's I mean that's the way
farming is is yes I mean I know a lot of
Growers that let their animals into
their growing it gives me a heart attack
every single time I mean yeah like you
said especially with dogs that are
running around outside and aren't house
dogs you know and you're not regularly
washing them or you just took them for a
walk they've got [ __ ] there's gonna be
[ __ ] even if it's just dust mites you're
gonna have a problem yeah yeah I mean
it's something that I struggle with too
I mean I have I have animals that are
part of the family
um so I get it
um you know and I you know I've been a
hippie Outlaw like I the idea of wearing
like lab
suit type stuff doesn't really Vibe with
the idea of a garden
um
but especially indoor I mean just my
logo man yeah
on the indoor
actually
because is is everything
um clean rooms are much much much easier
to maintain and you know the cleaner you
can keep it the less problems you
generally will have
is that part of your sop going into your
grow
uh most of the time yeah I and I try not
to wear the same clothes I don't do the
lab coat
um I probably should
um yeah I I don't go that far but I do
go in with clean clothes and um I never
go from one to the next it's like if I
go if I work in this Garden I don't wear
those same clothes I go take those
clothes off I take a shower before I go
into another Garden just not only for
the pests but also because I work with
pollen that I don't want to take pollen
where I don't want pollen to be
um and it's so easy to do that so it's
you know it's all just part of part of
what you just have to do to do it you
know really well
yeah absolutely so what would be one of
your best tips for beginner grower
oh man
um
well I think when I was a new grower I
think what I tended to do was over love
the plant and over overdo it like it's
so easy to over water it's so easy to
over love when you're when you're first
learning
um and so I'd say that's probably
probably the the biggest thing is to
start learn like the biggest process
about growing I'd say is learning to
read plants learning to understand
is what what they want what they look
like when they're not getting what they
want and how to fix it I mean I think
those are that's the underlying key for
for success I would say the faster you
can learn to read plants
you know the the better the better adapt
you will because happy plants make Happy
Flowers that's just the way it is stress
plants you're not going to get what you
want out of a stress plant exactly
definitely a good tip right there over
watering is probably the biggest problem
with most beginner new Growers
um and over loving like though more
water does not equal faster growth nope
it's all about those dry down times and
cons or consistent uh water so great tip
on that thank you for everybody coming
in from Dragon's flame side and my
followers this was an awesome interview
man
um did you still want to donate some
seed packs for a giveaway yeah
definitely awesome so our patreon
members have that to look forward to
some dragons flame genetic seeds going
in I would love to give those out what
we do is we typically give them out
during our monthly game show
okay so we're going to do a do or dab
next month in October have you heard a
do or dab yet I haven't it's a game show
that we play where two of my members go
head to head they get to pick which
packs they want out of whatever you
donate and then the rest that we we give
to random patreon members but the two
that are going head-to-head they get a
pick which packs they want right off the
bat and they basically play Truth or
Dare but it's extremely [ __ ] up and
they end up extremely [ __ ] up by the
end of the hour but it's an awesome game
and we would love to have you come in
and be one of the coaches for one of our
uh are contestant
yeah that'd be cool yeah I could throw
some packs and then I also have a stack
of uh books I could donate a um signed
copy of um
by Larry Livermore
um oh my God I'm totally brain farting
the goddamn name of the book
uh but anyway it's
um
now it's gonna drive you insane yeah now
it's gonna drive me insane absolutely
[ __ ] insane
[ __ ] memories
that's the book
memories awesome
um so Larry Livermore was the uh guy who
found Green Day the drummer for Green
Day and it's basically uh his story
living on Spy Rock in Mendo uh during
the prohibition area era I it's it's a
book I love I got a ton of them
um from him they're all autographed by
him
um so I mean it's a it's a cool thing
I'll throw one of those in too
that's intense that's awesome we'll say
uh
say the winner of do or dab whoever wins
do or dab can get their pack seeds and
get a book
from Larry Livermore that's [ __ ]
badass man how'd you come across that
big Green Day fan
um no not really actually
um but I am
um so we did a season in Mendocino
um on pigeon Ridge in uh it's outside of
kovalo which is
Outlaw uh grow country basically
um murder mountain-esque but it's in
Mendo not Humboldt and so spyrock is
the if if the Emerald Triangle is the
epicenter of cannabis spyrock is what I
would consider the epicenter of the
Emerald Triangle it was
um in the height of prohibition you were
invite only
um there was armed guards blocking
spyrock you did not go there if you were
not a grower and if you were not invited
so it's you know Outlaw country
basically that where this really you
know where this movement that you know
we're all a part of now
you know I would say was the heart of it
um so I mean it's it's something I've
always it's always fascinated me that
area
um you know especially especially the
year that I was there hearing the OG
Tales
um you know people that had to hike a
kayak and Hike every literally
everything in
um you know really far into the into the
Into the Wilderness to to grow this
plant and how spoiled we all are now to
have it in our houses so
no [ __ ] it's gotten a lot easier that's
for sure yeah it has
awesome man well thank you for the
amazing interview thanks for joining
this I will hit you up later with the
details and we'll try to get you in on
the day of do or dab as a coach that
would be awesome I think you really
enjoy the show
awesome will do all right thank you
everybody for tuning in thank you
dragon's flame for joining us and giving
us so much great information on
feminized seeds some of the lines that
he's working and what's to come out
check out Dragon slim genetics if you
haven't support our friend here doing
the good work breeding stable genetics
I'll catch you all later until next time
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign