[Music]
[Applause]
all right good evening everyone and
welcome to a new episode of Meet the
breeder we've got red scar Seed Company
joining us today how you doing brother
I'm doing
good hell yeah so I was lucky enough to
get a catch up with you make sure Vimeo
worked with you and we kind of talked
about you know what we had had in common
with grow Styles and whatnot uh why
don't you let everybody know that isn't
familiar with red scar Seed Company uh
what you're about and what you're trying
to achieve with your company yeah um you
know I'm just a small dude um organic
grower uh like a lot of dudes you know I
do a lot I have a lot of uh use a lot of
Korean natural farming inputs uh I don't
stand on my soap box and preach about it
a lot but um it's just kind of the way
I've been doing things for a lot of
years you know probably the last decade
or
so um yeah so I I kind of started off
just to preserve um and to create seeds
for myself and my friends uh it never
really was supposed to be a business um
initially it was just um making seeds
because we didn't have access to the
seeds and that that's pretty much how I
started off and uh just kind of Grew
From there um organically so to speak um
some years past you know I was kind of
in and out uh of the scene for a while
um being from Kentucky we didn't when I
started growing you know there was
circle of Growers didn't exist there
were no other people that I knew that
cultivated I didn't know uh really any
other grower in the state besides at the
time I think um I don't want to call him
out he's he's a Senator Senator now in
the state of Kentucky Dan [ __ ] who is
running uh do we have to noral no you
don't have to believe that you know he's
he's good uh he I'll just say he knew
some people uh up in the Louisville area
but for me and my buddies we didn't know
anybody so I was pretty much kind of on
an island by myself so getting seeds was
hard it took a long time you didn't know
if they were going to show or not back
then so it just the natural thing to do
is just create your own seeds and and go
from there
um some of those first types that you
started
preserving let's see you know it's just
I'm gonna be real bag seed we would um
if I'm going to go way back it was like
the we would collect the best back seed
you know all all off season and then in
the springtime we would just randomly
pop everything we had and there were
times that we found things that were
just absolutely abolutely remarkable
grew with the resin of the old school
White Widow but just absolutely rre of
garlic um way back before anybody had
garlic butt or anything like that and
these things I suppose were just mashups
of who knows heirlooms from Mexico maybe
some California genetics tossed in of a
true grab
bag exactly any brick if it was light
green you better believe we were keeping
seeds out of it that was the the
criteria back then is it light green if
so the seeds are probably worth keeping
yeah did it smell of anything other than
mold if so then we might have kept it
and grown it you know oh yeah man so how
did you originally get into cannabis
what was your first
experience uh just smoking with buddies
um then I I guess uh few years past you
know started smoking in high school
nothing serious just you know smoking on
a oion then um I saw my first plants I
guess like up close when I was about 17
and that kind of stuck with me a little
bit uh it's a little bit older than most
people but again coming from
Kentucky um it's like to see anybody's
plants at all was pretty pretty
miraculous so um an old buddy Roger
cotton rest in peace this old dude would
grow 10- foot plants back behind his
trailer in Kentucky
and um his sons would always take me
back there and be like hey man check
these out and we'd go sniff these plants
and it was just like that's when I knew
that's what I wanted you know I needed
more of that in my life um and I wanted
to explore the Aromas and the Aesthetics
were just too much to pass up so um from
that point on I think I started trying
to find we found a some old magazines of
his and there were all these old Afghan
pictures and [ __ ] like that and so
that's kind of when I initially fell in
love with the Afghans is is seeing those
old fat wide leaves on the Christmas
tree shaped plants and big chunky buds
that that's really what got you know
drew me in then a few years later um I
lost my financial aid and scholarships
for a half a gram of weed so from that
point on I was like well they took away
my education I can't get a bik it's too
expensive for me to go to school now
because I have nothing so I'm I'm going
to grow and that around 2002 is when I
decided I'm going to grow and that's
what you know that's the direction I
went in at all at all cost I was going
to
grow between the time when you first
started growing cannabis uh to breeding
it what was the change what made you
decide that you wanted to breed and how
long did it take after you saw your saw
your first plants come out of the ground
till you were like I'm going to start
making some of these myself it was a few
years you know we made some mistakes
along the way um trusting people was
number one I got robbed a few times by
roommates or friend of a friend you know
you slip up and tell you know your best
buddy he tells his friend all of a
sudden those guys don't like you so much
they come take your [ __ ] things like
that um I guess for me sometime around
like 07 I started messing around with
like some reefer man genetics uh gypsy's
kiss and and things like that Big
Thunder I think was one of them and um
petrolea a lot of petrolea head stash
crosses and um I guess losing those
plants and then looking back six months
later and being like oh I wish we had
you know some of those Gypsy kiss seeds
but we have none that's when it clicked
like you've got to preserve this [ __ ]
you have to start creating and you know
you're going to lose your favorite play
forever if you don't yeah
absolutely so what was the first plant
that you worked
with um it was the big it was a big
Thunder plant it was the M Madusa
[ __ ] cross um and that was one of
the first ones it was some random pollen
off a mail that I didn't know what it
was and I think I ended up with about 15
ripe seeds and that's about it um but
from that I took those with me down to
Tennessee and and ran a bunch of them
ran 15 and then ran those for a while
and then made some more off of that and
then took a took a small break and went
out west for a while and um tried naive
I was naive and thought I could just
like oh I'm gonna go out west I'm gonna
get a job on some mountain and that's
gonna be it and um that's the dream yeah
that's the dream and it's just that most
of the time it's just a dream so when I
came back I came back with the wealth of
knowledge and um new genetics
and and that's kind of when I just stuck
with it and kept making seeds and
breeding hell yeah I know the one that
I've seen you work probably the most on
I don't know if this is the one that
you've worked the most on but I've seen
you do a lot of work uh with that GMO
fuel even be even have problems with
other people using the GMO
F yeah she's she's popular uh with with
the boys in the yard um
it's nice um I liked the GMO I didn't
like how it extracted I thought that the
turps didn't really carry over in the
flavor um that a lot of times it might
smell really rancid like garlic or onion
and just skunk ass or death but then
this the flavor is going to come across
as I don't know sometimes it depending
on how late you took GMO it would the
extracts would almost come out like an
attic or Grandma's perfume and no matter
what extractor I got it from that seemed
to be the like like I don't want I don't
want that on my mouth so me being the OG
head I'm like well let's smack it with
with a nice OG and at the time I had a
really nice Rocket Fuel mail from
archive and always been a big fan of
their gear um politics aside or you know
can can of poit TI aside I've been you
know always been a fan of their gear and
always found good stuff so I just
smacked them up and the first the f1s
came out terrible I couldn't release
them the seeds were mainly pale and
immature um a lot of them cracked I
would say 95% fail rate on that first
project um so I didn't release a single
pack of the
f1s and then made then grew those out
and made some f2s
and it was growing those out that I
realized this is really special and so I
released a small amount of the f2s and
that's kind of when it took off okay so
was it just a uh a low bearing seed
plant no um it it produced a lot of
seeds um and I still have this problem
even with the
F6 um it's just a really finicky seed
producer it reminds me of some like ogs
that just don't really produce a ton of
viable seeds it have produced thousands
of white immature seeds and maybe a
couple couple hundred or so like really
mature
seeds and I've seen a few strains kind
of do that throughout the years and I me
being a perfectionist I'm like well my
room is [ __ ] right now it's not dialed
in like it should be I Mish hit the
timing but then I've got another strain
that's just crushing it you know
producing these big black vible seeds
with the tiger
stripes so you know some genetics just
don't you know want to produce seeds for
you like others and that's just the way
it
goes right and you actually I told you
earlier we got uh those packs from you
uh so Red Scare seed company has donated
three packs of seeds uh to our patreon
members here a GMO fuel F6 like he was
just talking about uh I've heard you
work with this one quite a bit too and
it's been interesting I want to know
more about is the luden's cough drop
F2 let's touch on that for a sec and
then he sent a pack of curvature uh 2.0
we want to hear about both those as well
that luden's cough drop uh is this like
a cherry like the classic it is
everybody knows that or what yeah so
back in Michigan I had a pack of cherry
Tahoe from
inhouse um and I'm never really ran a
bunch of In-House stuff a lot of their
profiles don't really suit my needs you
know the slur cane and all of that but
the Cherry Taho was one of their earlier
packes I
presume um so I popped it and the it was
amazing the Taho really came out with
some like bright uh Cherry
undertones uh sweet almond cherry with
just that earthy forest
floor and the resin stocks on it were
amazing it was just so coat it just
dumped with sugar you know so you guys
hearing this yeah so I had to take um at
the time I was running a bunch of coffee
F3 from uh Pacific Northwest roots and
picked the the what I thought was the
nicest representation of that out of
like 20 or 30 seeds I forget how however
many I kept um and then yeah and then
cross those up and I I kind set him on
the back burner for a long time and
never really messed with them they just
kind of sat there for a few years um and
that happens a lot as a breeder you kind
of you work a bunch of stuff and some
things you don't get to right away well
I handed them off to my buddy uh city of
homes horiculture up in uh Massachusetts
and about a year later he hits me up
with some pcks and he's like hey I
finally pop these I'm like oh [ __ ] you
know good luck man and as the pick start
coming in I'm like oh this is this is
incredible I got to work with this and
then he sends me um some samples
and that's when I was like this is it
medicinal uh effects were on point Aroma
flavor everything was just really on
point um that
earthy it's like the coffee intertwined
with the uh Sweet Cherry and forest
floor it was just rich and robust it's
like the best cup of coffee you OG cush
you could have so
um being EP somebody for those ones yeah
right the flavor and and the aroma is
one thing but it also has to carry a
medical aspect you know because I have a
lot of neurological issues um and it
checked all the boxes easy to grow good
yields um narcotic smoke but not just
gonna make you lo you know you're not
GNA pass out you're GNA enjoy yourself
um one of my it's it's jump the ranks
it's one of my
favorites put that one on the other side
of the table no I got I got you on a
pack I got you on a pack dude I would
that sounds amazing I wanted that coffee
from pafic Northwest roots for a long
time and that was one that I
just they they were pretty expensive
when they came out and it's definitely
worth coming from them you know what
you're getting uh true story just
deluded me I didn't have time for it I
went to the cup in Michigan and at the
time I had a fever I had to wear a mask
I was sick uh didn't think I was going
to make it um but really really wanted
to meet a few people and wanted to snag
a pack or two I was so sick I didn't get
to smoke with anybody I didn't get to
take a single dab I was miserable I
stood in line for the uh coffee Pik it
was the only Pik I bought the whole day
um I think I gave away all of my seeds
bought a pack got home a month later I
go to popet I open it up and the inside
of it was just full of confetti with no
seeds and I was like what is
like there I don't know I had to mess it
was just an accident with the packaging
Department yeah they just they just
forgot to put the seeds in so they ended
up having to send me another pack all
good in the end at least they did it
yeah yeah I was so sick and then I get
there I get home and I'm like great pop
the seeds a little bit later after I
recover and I'll look at the seeds and
there's no seeds in there just a bunch
of bunch of mulch I'm like get out of
here I need my
seeds get really high I don't know I
I'll still plan it
[ __ ] yeah if you guys have any questions
don't forget you can hit that Q&amp;A down
there uh and interact directly if you're
a member of our patreon so shout out to
the patreon gang for supporting this
thank you panda uh for setting this all
up man uh redcare we got a common friend
there farmer fly I know that you were
growing some of that Haze that he was
doing how'd that come out very hazy so
old school it yeah it reminded me of
some of the first herb that you know I
ever grew um really good stuff it
honestly
um it just had such a heavy um Mexican
feel to it it was it was really nice
everybody enjoyed that one so you sent
this uh curvature 2.0 I know nothing
about that I don't think I remember you
talking about it can you enlight me a
little bit yeah um I had some fun with
Gage green back in the day um and made a
made a curvature pack those dudes are
pretty hardcore flat earthers um so it's
mle breath across to GMO fuel F3 so the
2.0 is pugs breath F2 which is
technically AO breath F3 I believe
um cross to GMO fuel F5 so it's just a
new uh version of
that very very limited release I think I
might have released nine packs of
it no I'm all over that luden's cough
shop though I'm fighting one of you guys
for that
one hopefully we can get you on later as
well the anybody that sponsors the show
with seeds to give away to everybody uh
we like them to come on during the show
um and get a watch it if you're down for
that I'll let you know that date later
on it um it's a ton of fun we either
play do or dab or we do like can of
trivia do or Dab's the most famous one
but a lot of people are afraid to do it
it's like it's I don't know what you
compare it to you do a challenge or you
got to take a dab or sometimes the dab
is the challenge it's like a one G dab
or whatever and these guys will just go
head-to-head trying to get this the free
seeds you know it's a great time
everybody's laughing you know you can't
like walk away Los from that show
everybody everybody's win when one gam
dabs go down yeah you're just a winner
no matter
what sounds like Doc versus Farmer for
do or dab [ __ ] farmer wants them too
uh you sent me those black tiger nld I
know our patreon member Big Bad John
wanted to hear a little bit more about
it uh I acquired those from you uh where
was the sourcing on those and did you
work it at all tell us a little bit more
I have not worked that one um can't work
everything you know I wanted to um those
are sourc directly from
bistan so direct from the fer there yeah
yeah doesn't get any uh oh you didn't do
any preservation work or anything that
was something from your
stash yeah yeah exactly oh damn thank
you man yeah so that was from uh the
Indian Land race exchange drop uh I
think two years ago maybe last year gets
a little hazy they've had some fire
drops you know it gets the lines get
blurred there you know and that's one of
the ones that I wanted was their black
tiger but then again it's like money
versus how many seeds I have you know
I'm already at the point where it's I
can't grow all these I have to give them
away and I do all the time or we do
auctions cating my number of years left
to strains to grow you know it's like
right I'm sure you you're really OG and
you grow a lot like that then every once
in a while it's like I need a break I
need to do Haze or something a little
bit higher you
know not me I for MCL Haze was the first
Haze I've grown in probably five years
true story I just don't grow a lot of
haze and and with the land races yeah
with the land races you do have to take
a break you do you get burned out it's
like oh yeah you end up wanting the hype
[ __ ] you're like hold on I want some
hype like I just want something to look
good for yeah I'm not going to say the c
word because I don't want any cookies
but you know it's like you do end up
wanting some hype like somebody was
talking [ __ ] about Ron and I was like
Hey runs isn't that bad you know it's in
the scheme of things it's not it's not
the worst people get you know kind of uh
emphatic
about uh preserving things and and then
you get into your purist and they're
like you know [ __ ] all the hype hybrids
you know but I I like them all guy
there's there's I used to be that guy I
used to be that guy hardcore and and now
it's like no there's room for everything
there's room for everybody abely
something I've realized as I got older
even if it's a a type that bag appeal is
off the chain resin producing is off the
chain but it doesn't have a lot of
flavor it's not that strong you can take
plants like that and mix the traits in
that you're looking for uh if you do
enough work you know try right with a
few different things that you like that
are heavy resin producers great highs um
and work it in see what you find exactly
and on the adverse of that you can take
something that um like isn't a heavy
resin producer and then cross it with
something that is and then like for
example the Maru fored we were talking
about the you know the preservation and
whatnot so so that's another uh
Pakistani
selection um and that asbach region and
one thing that they all carried was this
rotten flesh Aroma a lot of them had
this nasty foot
odor um moldy cheese dead body
smell then when you cross them with
something I ended up
multi yeah dead body corpse yeah yeah
and we've found this in a few times
swamp boys had layer cake c and a lot of
the layer cake fenos that people choose
are kind of cakey layer cake we found a
corpse feno and then we crossed that
with our GMO fuel F3 back in the day and
that was crude cake that [ __ ] was like
digging up a corpse it was nasty not
that I know what that smells like that's
some weird [ __ ] it's what I would
imagine it smells
like so oh my God back to the red
back to the red Maru no matter how gassy
or nasty The Strain you hit to that
marof is it turns it
tropical it's goes directly 180 away
from the dead corpse and all of a sudden
you're talking guava passion fruit
pineapple like star fruit the most
tropical [ __ ] you can think of all of a
sudden that's that's all you're getting
anymore more it's it's
Wild Desert Island
question if you could only take one
strain with you out of anything that
you've made that other people have made
what would you take with
you man I'm I'm gonna go with the GMO
fuel you know yeah I think I think a Zod
cashmere would be a close second so if I
could take two that be my two I haven't
crossed those yet either I don't know
why I haven't done that yet timing is OG
lover it's it's surprising you to hear
you say
cashmere it's only because maybe it's my
selections that I was lucky enough to
find but we we um I got mine from bear
frog and I think that's the same person
that bod got his from and a few others I
think he gave them to three or four
people um and shout out to bef frog you
know that was an amazing gift
we got rid of every feno that smelled
like candy or Jack wiped it out we
didn't want that um we found fenos that
smelled like grilled
chicken um and had that like salty
grilled chicken burnt uh
Aromas and the flavor was woodsy and
earthy like an OG it it's like um
finding an heirloom peanut butter breath
or something it's just like smaller buds
that are just caked and resin and the
most unique Tarpin you could think of uh
so that's that's it double serrated
leaves real sharp saw blades just
beautiful plants I heard you say salty I
didn't hear you say chicken chicken
saying it reminds you of chicken yes and
multiple people have found this and
worked with it yeah it's the chicken cut
um we selected we selected three of them
that had different variations of grilled
chicken
smells and pass them and on the f3s and
on they they've seemed to carry that
that same trait as a as a dominant
trait unbelievable to me this is
mindblowing right now we do another
podcast called the Washington weed
review and they had like the new style
of moon rocks uh that was like a bud
rolled in
thca as opposed to like how we used to
make them and it was called chicken and
waffles and when I passed it to my wife
she hit it first and she goes it tastes
like chicken I said there's no [ __ ]
way you're going to tell me that but
tastes like chicken and it didn't to me
but if you're if you're dead set that
this thing tastes like chicken I got to
try that one out too now the flavor the
the flavor comes across more of like
uh Earth truffle you know it's really
earthy and buttery but the aroma is
chicken all
day Dad Inky grower says what strain is
on the top for your head stash this
season that's that's tough that's tough
um really looking forward to this
wedding fuel I've I've got going um
and then a banana OG back cross is just
really standing out in the greenhouse
I'll have to post it up uh later on it's
just it was a replacement plant I had a
plant on the back end of my greenhouse
and left the door open uh you know to
vent things out deer walks in about
twice a year and most of the time he
just eats my kale and I'm cool with that
this time of year he comes in and wipes
my plan out and just leaves It On The
Ground like thanks fellas so I put this
banana OG back there there um just as a
replacement it was kind of spinley at
the time I was like [ __ ] I hate putting
Replacements out you know um it beefed
up fast and it's it's it's nice so I'm
I'm really looking forward to it mus
thing that we've been chasing is like
the banana
turp I believe the one that I tried was
a was flow from a cut of the banana OG
from uh Oregon kid mhm think it was is
that the same one that you worked with I
believe so and I didn't get a lot of
banana per se okay I was gonna say
that's the same with me I didn't get a
lot of banana out of that but have you
created something with that that you
find to be very banana yeah um we
crossed it to Hannibal OG from Dr
candyman's Candyland seeds I think he's
just Dr Candyman now or Candyman seeds I
think he came back so that's cool
um at the time he was retired I think
like around 2015 he had made a release
and then just dropped off and I was
lucky enough to get a few of his packs
around like 2018 2019 and we ran the
banana milkshake OG and it was really
good and I was sitting on this pack of
Hannibal OG and c and popped it it was
it was nice uh purple buds smelled like
paint thinner and um like aerosol spray
um spray paint or something like that
old school
hairspray um it was it was really nice
we crossed it to the banana OG which is
also pretty musky um at least on my end
when I had it it seemed pretty musky um
leather kind of but earthy OG for the
most part um but when we cross the two
together you know you're thinking
muskiness a little bit of leather mixed
with some paint thinner you're thinking
more along the gas line but a lot of the
fenos came out like green bananas um you
know underwrite bananas so that was
pretty cool how many preservation jobs
have you done now at least half a dozen
probably a dozen I've probably failed
triple that that
amount you know land race preservation
is is tricky work sometimes the seeds
are olded sometimes they you know get
[ __ ] up
through sometimes you don't know the
proper at the time technique to pop
those
seeds like code stratification or
something find
something sometimes you just find [ __ ]
that's not worth sometimes you just get
wiped the [ __ ] out sometimes you find
plants that just don't flower and all of
a sudden you're like six months in and
this plant hasn't stopped vegging it's
like this isn't it something goes from
no balls to trying to bust balls in
couple days pretty early on you have to
find you have to like draw the line for
yourself and tell yourself that you know
I'm going to be selective I'm I'm not
going to like keep a plant just because
it's cool or because it holds
sentimental value or because it's from
this region or that region and you just
have to make your Cuts pretty early on
and and stick stick by that so what's
been some of your favorite runs to do
with uh the land race
preservation
um a lot of the Afghan and have
been that's it's tough and and then you
have the Maru line pretty recently that
was really fun uh the Maru red like I
talked about uh the females kind of had
that rotten body sulfur smell but then
the you know the mes passed on tropical
fruit turps so that that's been really
fun and those lwn are really fun to
hunt um the Zod cashmere going by back
to it um that's that's always fun and
probably um has made for the best
outcrosses as
well patreon member Big Bad John wants
to know what's some of your best tech
for popping old
seeds um it depends I I like to do about
a week in the
fridge uh at least a week sometimes a
month it depends depends on the seeds
what they are how they what do they look
like are the seeds really thick like
some hardcore Afghans get really thick
you know they're like Stone Pebbles if
that's the case I'm going to take them
and I'm going to scuff them really good
do a hydrogen peroxide uh solution mix
you know probably 50/50 with water
nothing
fancy um and then after that I'll pull
them out and I'm a firm believer in
microbes um so I would probably just
inoculate and plant um and then Dome
them if you need
to and again a lot of that depends oning
at
all I don't um and you know that could
just be me sucking my ways I've probably
lost out on some genetics not seed
cracking because I know people that have
had good results I've done it manually
before but um for me if if the seeds
don't want to be viable I'll just let
that go I don't really see crack too
much I figure yeah like you if it's not
going to pop open let nature take its
course if I do a week solution I'll let
them sit for two or three days that's
about the longest I'll let them sit and
then I'll pull out if they don't pop in
there then they're gone yeah for the
most part I've pulled them out before
sometimes you can hit them with some
microbes and toss them you know on a
heating pad and a few might pop but gen
generally speaking they're going to be
weaker you know I've I've yet to do that
and have a seed just like bust out of
the soil and be really vigorous and be
blown away by it and I've been doing
this for a long time it doesn't mean I
couldn't be taught new ways you know
that's that's obviously not the case but
I get it
man it took me so long to finally go all
right I'm gonna use an LED like I was
just I love the HIDs man and it is
different like I now that I've been
growing with the LEDs I'm a little bit
more comfortable with them I do
appreciate them for what they are uh I
think with following a proper VPD
knowing your plants knowing how to read
them I've got a little bit better yield
uh now with the LEDs now that they're
dialed in I definitely get better colors
without having to do too much switching
or dimming or dropping temps or anything
like that um but there's something about
those HIDs even though they're a pain in
the ass sometimes fighting heat or doing
whatever you know all the duct work you
had to do with them um they threw off
their own style of buds like you could
really get some Hefty Sour Diesel buds
with HIDs you know you really could most
most things they're just not as tight as
a lot of these LEDs are right it's just
different slightly different structure
and and appearance and all of that D I
tell people all the time one of my
favorite grows was interchanging uh HIDs
with CM between them I would do like a
315 CMH between two 600 watt HIDs and or
HPS I guess we should say HS I [ __ ]
love that Spectrum you did that too we
were doing the same thing and the
Spectrum was amazing I didn't think it
could be beat and I still I'm not
convinced it can be beat it's just being
stubborn old man you know when I when I
first got the LEDs everybody was telling
me about like par and uh ppfd and
everything and I was like man I check
with my hand they're like can't do that
with these LEDs dude I'm like if my
hands cool the plants are
cool and then you crank them up and just
fry the [ __ ] out of them I get
it guilty is charged guilty yeah exactly
I'm still learning I'm still learning
with my LEDs yeah we'll get what what
are you running right now I've got a
couple spiders at the moment and they're
kind of doing it for me and then I've
one one of my favorite lights is
actually and this is really terrible for
me to say one of my favorite lights
right now is a just a Mars bar light I I
don't know if it's a 2000 or 3000 what
what model it is I got it from the homie
it came in a box I put it together and
it's killing it it's but I'm just
waiting until you know it glitches out
on me and starts coming on at night
because I've a ball of I've had those
I've had those guys send me lights
before and I'll go into my bedroom in
the middle of the night and the light
will be flickering on and off I'm like
goddamn you Mars
damn it Mars yeah that's a that's a
personal thing with me they've hit me up
so many times about like sponsoring I'm
like no no no they harassed uh oh God
who was it ododa herb do you know hod
herb at all uh they were harassing him
forever and then he would post about him
I was like they can't be that bad man
and then they started harassing me I was
like oh Jesus and they're not they're
not bad lights I know a couple friends
of mine that are local here that really
really love the Mars Hydro the only
thing about them is they do produce a
lot of heat just because of how they're
built but they're great lights otherwise
it's the company that I'm like H yeah
not all not all of their models are
built the same for
sure after we get done with this
interview I'll send you an invite link
to the Discord server and there's dudes
in there that are like [ __ ] science
Wizards with the with the LEDs and
really help you dial them in my plants
are [ __ ] looking great with them uh
farmer fly another one of our patreon
members in our our personal friend uh
says what was your impression of the
hoar Valley land
race The Hop par
Valley um I I haven't finished any I'm
guilty man I haven't finished any of the
Hop par yet um I know that what I've
seen from farmer McFly looked amazing
and um I think he's got a back cross
going right now of it so that's really
cool I saw him working with that with a
hop par and I just kind of got rid of
mine and moved a different direction you
know uh personally don't want to step on
toes if I see a homie working a
line especially using a mail of
something I'm going to stray a different
direction and then just wait until he's
done and I'm just gonna snag some of his
crosses and run that and just get to the
point you know yeah so I I'm at the
point now where um I just kind of want
to run the homies crosses I want to I
want to run some uh some people's work
that have you know worked some of my
gear I'm constantly getting seeds from
people who are using my lines and stuff
and you know at some point it'd be cool
to just take a break uh and just kind of
grow just not even my stuff grow stuff
that they've
produced see what they're doing who
would you say were some of your
Inspirations when it came to cannabis
breeding I've been asked this before and
this is one of the trickiest questions
for me to answer because um um we really
didn't have any um and so for
us I really I really didn't have one and
so it wasn't until I started breeding um
later on you know I went a a good decade
without really looking up to anybody
maybe I guess you could say like maybe
Mel Frank or Ed Rosenthal back in the
day um a lot has changed since then I
wouldn't say I look up to him now um you
kind of get to the point where you see
how the sausage is made and you stop
eating sausage at that point um but once
I started breeding it was kind of like
bod seeds bod was really cool to me um
coming in you know encouraged me to work
with a lot of his stuff gifted me a lot
of uh a lot of things and so that was
that was cool um and then watching you
know just watching my buddies kind of
kind of work alongside you know back in
the old fa group uh book days at Delta 9
THC days that was pretty cool um there
were a lot of people kind of starting
off and then you had like Professor p
and uh dudes like that that were in the
group um everybody was pretty open there
was a lot of open communication and
transparency that you don't get now um
feel like Facebook kind of censored us
out of that everybody shifted to
Instagram now Instagram is Shifting you
know and censoring out of Instagram
so yeah I've been telling every breeder
that I know move to Discord like just
like a website you know that's basically
how you can run it and you just gather
your people there do your thing on
Facebook do your thing on Instagram
everything else is word of mouth but I
think it's way easier for everybody and
everybody that I've made one for really
uh that becomes their spot you know just
like ours is or even like I said I'll
send you a link after the show you can
check ours out but you you can you
moderate yourselves you know you decide
what your server is like what you're
going to handle in there and it's just
so much better having that [ __ ] without
the worry of being flagged or taking
down or losing your people over [ __ ]
night you know ridiculous you know I was
I was at like 12,000 plus followers and
had years worth of you know pictures
archived and and things like that and
then and then lost it all
overnight yeah and then and then lost it
all overnight you know and it was like
getting the followers losing the
followers wasn't a big deal I think most
people can tell you that losing track of
the people you followed is a bigger deal
because even though you're gonna get
something back you're you're gonna lose
touch with a few business yeah and
that's always shitty you know so
absolutely uh thank you so much for
joining me redcare it's been awesome
thank you so much for donating the
curvature the GMO Fuel and the luden's
cough drop this has been an amazing
episode if you guys have any more
questions uh don't hesitate to get them
in because we've got about 10 minutes
left here uh but yeah I want to thank
you again so much for taking this time
out with us um to tell us a little bit
about yourself and what you're doing uh
is there any cultivars that you're
looking to work that you haven't got to
work yet that's tricky man you you threw
them at me
um yeah I've curb got a few things going
now um I'm kind of digging into some
like I've I've strayed away from Citrus
for so long and because it's just to me
it's vile you know some people like
grapefruit and they like to smoke the
grapefruit for me it's like repulsive
but recently I've been I've been finding
that like if it's in in a cross but like
a few Generations back you know if it's
a second cousin twice or
mov yeah if it's a second cousin twice
or moved it can do nice things for the
pallet so I've kind of been digging into
some stuff uh you know some Citrus type
stuff uh and so that's that's going to
be fun uh got some uh let's
see kind of going
like back and forth on a few things I've
got some caramel grape Donuts from the
the homie uh the real MC blunts so
that's going to be
interesting kind of see what what that
does yeah and keep shouting out there
farmer mcfl there's like ISM
w88 there call mfly from now on
sorry it's a yeah uh it's a Back to the
Future thing with my son uh he always
thinks he's like Marty McFly or some
[ __ ] um yeah so really just looking
forward to Growing the homies work uh
305 genetics dude dude out of Florida
he's like really under the radar looking
to grow some of his stuff um just small
small time guys that's where it's
at you're if you decide you want to do
some more uh land race selection again
let me know and if I've got something
that you need I'd be more than happy to
share with you brother sounds great
appreciate all of this all this inform
yes farmer McFly everybody's
going not real name I'm not gonna I'm
not
gonna nothing about it like I'm not
gonna do that I won't do that to you
dude you already did man that's crud
this how we are we just [ __ ] I'm on a
first I'm on a first name level with him
or it'd be embarrassing you know so yeah
I'm with you brother that's awesome and
thank you so much for the for the narrow
leaves too I really cannot wait to grow
those those are some amazing seeds uh I
got that what was it the 21
Himalayan book from full power you got
that one as well did you go through any
of those I went through some I'm still
kind of going through some of them yeah
uh takes takes a long time that was a
comprehensive drop which ones did you go
through all of
them I've tried a few more than once and
unfortunately I've learned some lessons
um
I'm I'm still stuck in Moana at the
moment or Milana uh at the at the moment
and I just lost a crop of poama pink um
repeatedly every time I put the plants
out again the cuts out I lost my cuts I
lost the backup cuts um the deer will do
anything for these Pama pink this
Himalayan strain they love it I've never
seen anything like it so he look like
that hunt yeah l
uh arasin already F2 that so that's
that's lock down so that that's safe I'm
looking forward to going through those
as well uh let me know I'm going to I'm
going to message you about some of those
luden's cough drop I'd be more than
happy to support uh your business and
lift you up especially for taking this
time with all of us uh to tell us about
Red Scare um no we got one more thing
[ __ ] I
forgot can we talk about it yeah redcare
is going for
rebranding you want to talk more about
that man what's the new name and why the
Rebrand yeah uh it it's been something
I've thought about for a little over a
year
now um the new name is Garden Goblin
genetics um it just it's it's kind of an
inside joke between me and some King
gizard fans King gizzard and lizard
wizard shout out here
um yeah so we're just you know if you if
you look into the garden Goblin you'll
see some more but it it just provides
some different
uh different um marketability aspect
yeah different vibe I'm trying to stray
away from the the militant Vibe of RSC
rssc you kind of see the the badge or
the or the stamp and it's it's just
something I'm I'm moving on from uh for
the time being not to say I won't
revisit that you know somewhere down the
line in a few years but it's time to
move on from that as that side of things
and kind of uh kind of open things up
artistically you know I'm an artist and
I know a bunch of artists and I don't
want to pigeon hole them with red and
black and yellow colors it's just it's
[ __ ] lame this isn't
McDonald's if it is I would go there
every day so before before this name
change so he's going through a
rebranding guys so you guys are going to
get some of the last packs here of the
red scar seed company name he also sent
us these and these are actual wood and
this going to come with each pack of
seeds look at
this yeah shout out to cultivated laser
for making those there he's aom he also
bred some amazing gear back in the day
dude needs to get back in the game what
are they stickers they are yeah you peel
the back off and they'll actually last
quite a quite a while on a
car that's awesome he was in Colorado
one of his lasted a year on a car so
that's really cool man yeah I'm gonna
I'm gonna be fighting somebody for the
luden's cough drop and then I'm gonna be
buying like four more packs off you if
you got them and
uh but yeah uh where can people find
your seeds if they want to acquire some
um at the moment red scare seed company
uh.com or uh find me on Instagram uh
redcare seedco uh Dr Green Sky I guess
you can look that up uh Red Scare Seed
Company 2.0 and uh I think uh gobble
Garden genetics is my new page yes
follow the back up as well guys all
right Red Scare awesome interview man
thank you so
much on testing really quick yeah um
testing was you know it's it's not for
everybody um some people like tested
gear some people don't I get a lot of
requests for untested gear so um you'll
see me oftentimes release packs
temporarily for like $20 a pack um if
people want to buy them and stash them
and not test them right away they can
but they're untested and um are
typically so as
such um for me I like untested gear I I
almost grow exclusively untested gear um
probably because I'm getting so many
seeds sent to me from so many of my
friends that I just pop them with faith
that you know I know the guys growing
them and breeding them so I trust I
trust the process all right until next
time guys this has been doc CX with Dr
Green Sky of Red Scare seed company and
now Garden Goblin let's give him a big
shout out out Round of Applause thank
you brother until next time good night
for
[Music]
right
[Applause]
[Music]
nah