all right go ahead
here oh I hear a dab
going what's that I said oh I hear a dab
going I was going to ask you about that
if you did much
concentrate well more than most people
but less than
[Music]
some
[Applause]
[Music]
nah
[Applause]
[Music]
what's up everybody and welcome to
another exciting episode of the cxy crew
podcast we have a very special guest
today none other than the man himself
breeder Steve man that is uh from
Ontario has been growing since ' 89
started spice of Life Seeds is here to
talk to us today about a little bit
about his history and we're going to
talk about what he's doing now and
everything in between so thank you Steve
for taking this time today to join us
and uh talk to us about you and what
you've
done thanks for having me Doc
absolutely um I wanted to ask you you
know uh for everybody that's following
right now that has no idea who spice of
life is we've got so many generations of
Growers over here um anybody that's not
familiar with spice alive do you want to
give us a little background about how
you got started growing and how that
became spice of Life
Seeds sure when I started growing my own
um really the like
8990 there was no easy access to clones
or seeds for the average person you had
to you know Network a little bit to find
some you couldn't just go to a shop or
go on the internet and order them right
and it was imperative that if you found
something you like that you started to
save some seed of it you know so we just
got in as a hobbyist out of necessity
saving seed and and trying to cross this
and that we would just do you know a
branch in the bottom here and there so
you had like a film canister of seed
which was what we used back in the day
and when I moved to Vancouver after
University um Mark enry was there from
also Al from London and he'd I remember
his City Lights Bookstore and that cuz
he was the first one selling High Times
or true life two life crew and that was
prohibited you know so you know I was
always aware of the dude but I didn't
know him or anything but he had HBC he'
got busted selling seeds and he was the
only guy selling seeds and I thought it
was you know hey if this guy wants to
keep selling seeds I should donate him
some seeds so I went down and I took a
film canister of seeds and just said
said I know you got busted selling seeds
if you're going to keep doing it I just
wanted to donate a jar to you and he's
like well what are they you got pictures
descriptions anything I said no nothing
just see what people think you know and
then I was in there a few months later
and picking up a magazine or papers or
something like that and he and he said
hey you gave me those seeds people
really like them make as many as you can
keep bringing me seeds you know so I was
like oh
hm you could actually do that as a
business because I was purely a hobbyist
you know I just figured I'd work in
other thing and just be a a hobbyist
forever and and one of the reasons I
moved to Vancouver it was the only place
in Canada nobody was in jail for growing
even personal you know so it was the
safe place to grow and as such all the
Growers were there as very International
city as well so there was uh a real you
know Melting Pot of seeds pouring in
there there was you know seed from all
over the world you get Indian seed
Southeast Asian seed you know the West
all the West Coast stuff you know
California and Oregon and there's just
so just so much to choose from so while
I got there I just made a point out of
collecting any cutting anybody was
selling or trying any seeds friends G
gave me you know and have lots of
friends from around the world that live
there and it was so fun you know that I
was just constantly playing with them I
wasn't worried about cranking out big
pounds or anything I just love to start
a lot of seeds and look at all the
different plants and then pack a whack a
different jars you know just have lots
and just be able to share it and enjoy
it and it was a hoop and then of course
you know most people were more into
growing pounds of weed so of course when
you found something really nice you made
sure to get man I would love to see this
weed everywhere so I want these cuting
out there like that sweet Scout cutting
and you pass them around to get
everybody growing it so you'd see more
of it in the world you know so it was
great fun like I would give it to I
never even was swinging it to people I
was just sharing with people and just
saying if you really like this weed you
want to grow it you know it takes 12
weeks to flower it's not your standard
BC big butt or whatever but it just
tastes heavily so I say I'll give it to
you for free but just promise me you're
going to give it to anybody else that
wants it for free too and just get it
out there you know so it's friendly
wildfires some of these Cuts like that
and the ones that I had that were like
super interesting for one reason or
another like a sterile plant where I
thought oh my God I should hang on to
this until you know you can do something
with it officially and I wouldn't share
them and then I would lose them so the
ones that I thought were too special to
share which didn't last very long
because I I learned my lesson quickly
like if you put it out there it's never
lost you know if if stand if it's stands
on its own you know if it stands on its
tone you'll still find it 25 years later
but if it's not worth keeping it'll be
gone but if you try and keep it in too
small a circle or just by yourself it's
too easy to lose a really Beauty cutting
that way you know I wanted to ask you
those seeds that you gave to Mark Emory
those first seeds that you gave to him
do you have any recollection of what
those were yeah of course they were uh
something I brought with me I called
Medway Madness for the creek outside
London Ontario or in London Ontario
where I yeah so that was it was my
Medway Madness but I rebranded it out
there because I said nobody's going to
know what the hell Medway Madness is so
I called it Jolly Rancher because it was
kind of sweet and tangy like that you
know and just seemed like a happy name
for the Jolly Rancher so that was kind
of fun and that was the first one but I
remember when he opened the
that it was they were really really big
seeds so you didn't get as many in a
canister as if you had really small
seeds of course so you open them up and
the big he pulls it out and he says
they're freaking
coconuts I still remember he's like
they're freaking coconuts but they were
they were like small peas they were
really big
seeds yeah especially when you said a
lot of the stuff that was coming around
right then was mostly land race heirloom
type stuff uh a lot of those carry small
seed at least in my experience but I've
mostly worked with Asians and pacifics
and those I haven't done very much as
South Americans or Mexicans like you
have that's pretty damn there's a lot of
a lot of small seeds in the tropical
seed but there is some big ones too like
for hemp ones a really fat one is like
the tropical hemp Yan the Chinese one
those
are big big
beans but you know as a breeder if
you're selling them buy the Seed you're
happy with small ones because you
harvest them by the weight you know so
if you harvest 10 kilos of seed you know
you've got twice as many if they're
small than if they're
big yeah very very true I mean I've seen
some Indians that are damn near like the
end of a pin you know just tiny little
black
Opals tiny dots they're almost like
poppy
seeds so then you follow up the Medway
Madness with the sweet pink grapefruit
and a lot of people don't know this um
but you do not claim creation to the
Sweet paint grapefruit at all right I
named it I didn't make it though it's
just a clone I collected and the Clone
was I said what do they call it they
said he says The Only Thing Worth
growing he this is just the Only Thing
Worth growing that was the that was the
deal right so I said okay and I I could
tell that it was a sweet herb but it was
always cut too early for my taste so it
was kind of had a lot of orange hair and
it just it was underdeveloped small CX
you know and I was like I bet you this
would be nice if you got it finished and
had it plump up you know and and I
really was wanting to try it um and so
the girl I knew who was selling eights
of it she was like the exclusive seller
of this guy she was kind of a friend of
a friend and she'd uh she said oh yeah
he'll sell you a tray of clones minimum
orders 20 clones for five bucks each or
whatever I said that's fine so that's
what I was doing you know when I first
moved there just sit in my apartment and
send you know anybody that knew somebody
selling clones and there was always lots
of people because we go down to wreck
Beach and places like that like there
every day you could go out and find for
new people to sell you some clothes you
know it was easy Vancouver is just a a
hot bed at the time and it still is I'm
sure and uh anyways it was just so fun
to collect them and you just just throw
you know tag a couple keep as many moms
in the collection and then flower out a
couple see if they're worth keeping get
rid of the ones you don't like and just
keep doing that right and then before
you know it you say oh these are my six
favorite plants from the last year or
whatever you know and the and I you know
you can poping seeds on the side too but
it's nice to collect the Clones that are
going around town and then just see who
grows it better you know and uh then
it's like a one design race when
everybody's growing that same thing you
know the uh but when I first flowered
that out was on my balcony in my first
apartment in Kitano that was on Broadway
and U and we were just on second floor
but I had a really you know spacious
balcony there and people from taller
Towers across and people on the bus and
stuff would go by wave cuz I had this
balcony covered in weed and even on the
railing I had 21 gallon pots with 20
grapefruits you know I maybe 19 I think
I kept one in as a mom in the closet and
then then these ones that were The Only
Thing Worth growing just spread along
the rail of the balcony and just all
growing into plump little things you
know and uh maybe 1 o plants or
something but chunky little things and
uh I would ask people because I'd let it
go it was smelling super super sweet
pink grapefruit there was no no other
way it was I just said this like a ruby
red that you just covered in white sugar
it was just like that and it I would say
nothing people would come over and I had
like you know 20 different plants on the
balcony not counting those and tomatoes
and stuff and the first people would
come out and see tomato and then they
kind of realize holy [ __ ] this is all we
you know and then I would say smell
those ones on the railing tell me what
they smell like and 20 out of 20 people
went sweet pink great you know everybody
said it so it was just to me I was like
Wow SPG a fresh label on that thing SPG
sweeping grapefruit CU it didn't have a
name there so it needed it that was
that's what I thought anyways I think
the what I've heard various lore and
legends of it that it was like 17 years
on the islands after being 17 years out
of the US or or grown in Washington and
that it was some early Northern
lightline which is entirely plausible I
I mean I have no way of knowing for
absolute dead certainty but I think
through the sequencing and everything
that they've pretty much determined it
was a an early Northern lightline and it
had been so it was a pleasant smoke or
is a pleasant smoke and that it doesn't
put the hurt on people it's nice at a
party because it it lights up a party
and people are social and happy where
and chatty whereas you know you can
break out something heavier and then
everybody's
just just kind of stupified you know
sometimes it's nice to have that life
Pleasant herb that you know it's maybe
20% THC not super strong I think they
probably when I've seen it tested from
different people's tests was anywhere
from you know 17 to 22 or something like
that so I'd say the average 19 18 20 21
is probably the most common for it and
it's possible to get it a little
stronger too I think but the uh the
strongest batches I don't you know never
had them tested the um but is a nice
happy H and it's a I think I almost want
to make like red hats with the white
letters that say make cannabis sweet
again because I don't see so much of the
candied flavors there I have had some in
the last year I had the hel jelly from
Humble seed company and I just had met
the guy that uh had whereami down in
Columbia he's Colombian American and
they have a heli jelly he was telling me
about it but I he didn't have any with
him and then another friend here from
Vernon Drake he U came to visit me in
the summer and he brought me a few
different flavors and one of them was a
hey jelly two females actually one of
the fals was really nice and you know
jelly like it was nice it was sweet and
and I love that sweet fruity stuff I do
love the floral stuff as well it doesn't
have to be sweet and fruity I don't mind
a little spice even the pinies and stuff
like that there's so many permutations
of Aroma and flavor in the species that
it's just a joy to you know weave your
way through them and and you start
leaning to certain departments you know
and some people really want that heavy
Rank and some people want the real
ethereal light you know
and I really have a thing for the narrow
leaf plants with what I call
the the high tones you know that they
have you don't get those notes in weed
that doesn't take 16 weeks to flour you
know that's pretty much what I'm saying
some of these Aromas in in that the
undiluted versions of them let's say you
can get hints of them crossed down with
Afghan and that but you know
the that family of plants the Afghan
plants which form the backbone of all
indoor breeding you know by and large
and and modern breeding in general
they've been such a huge contribution to
potency and yield and you know hardiness
in certain conditions but they're of
course absolutely not jungle plants if
you take those plants to the tropics
forget it you know they're just going to
mold cuz they're designed to catch and
hold water not to shed it you know so
you need these pencils thin things and
they have they're not always Exquisite
I've had some pencil thin ones that I
couldn't stand the smell of on
Indonesian in particular but overall I
would
say my real passion is chasing the tall
skinny girls on this because they're
just so special that's definitely where
my heart lies is with the the more
equatorial sativas it's always been
something that I really really love um I
just thought of a question that I had no
intention of asking you but since you
brought it up I want to know what your
uh thought process is on this um me and
many others knowing you for now have
running tens of hundreds of thousands of
seeds at this point I think you would
know more than
anybody one of one of my Idols uh once
told me that they saw a link trait
between heavy hermaphrodism and the
stinky smelly plants and saw less of
that in the sweet fenos have you seen
anything Sim similar or do you think
it's equally possible across the board
for me my experience is that it's
equally you know
I I hav never I mean not saying he's
wrong I'm just saying I've never made a
correlation there that's never hit me
that that was the
thing it's it's an interesting Theory
you know yeah I thought so too that's
not something I've seen I've seen her
maites all across the board you
depending on I think it's more based
upon the breeder and the the amount of
effort that they put into selecting and
knowing their their Cult of Art
it's true that's a lot of it the um I
never sold femin seeds you know and I
was ruthless about killing her
aphrodites back in the day and
uh I really think I think the only one I
ever had that I let through for sheer
potency at a really low amount was the
p19 the mother of the
Blockhead and that one was it was so
unique and so Punchy but if you did
stress it too much you would see a few I
never I didn't have a problem getting
seed like you know hermaphrodite seed if
I did it since in the greenhouse but
I've heard you know from people i' give
the cuting to where they were really
cold or whatnot they would start to hey
you know I'm starting to get a Herm on
that I'm like oh I never saw it in my
hot Greenhouse where it was totally
happy I didn't to see it but when I
heard one or two people tell me that I
still didn't want to get rid of it
because it was one of the highest THC
things in the stable so I wanted it was
like this is really Punchy and it
doesn't smell or taste like anything
else it was really unusual and
uh that was a neat plant the blockhead I
really like the blockhead and I I had
the odd person mention it that they was
saying you know that's the only one of
your seeds I ever got her ra it I never
got got one in your sweet te never got
one in your Shish Berry never got one in
the tropical trops or tropas or any of
the other things but the rockhead and
got a couple I was like but but they're
like but the rest of them are
awesome You released them you know I
like good good but overall I've had a
real prejudice against them you know
like because I don't like a seed popping
in my joint I'm a smoker first and
foremost right and
it just ruins the joint and it's so
funny I know it's not even funny like
funny funny it's funny sad but I see
legal Market joints in Canada with seeds
popping in them that people are cutting
open joints with seeds like half the
weight of the joint being seeds and
stuff and from one producer twice on
different batches six months apart with
different plants and you're like how can
you do do pre-rolls with half the weight
seed and not noticed half the weight it
was like the guy weighted on it was like
a one G joint it was 49 seed and .51
Shake you know it just looked awful was
this in Canada yeah that was in Canada
and then somebody else gifted me some
and um I can't even remember who's it
was or anything because I'm not that
familiar with all the brands but the but
I was really up you know pal cuz he
pulled it out it's like here this is
really nice joint you're going to like
it and it's like a $15 joint and I think
of joints like you know 10 cents or
whatever because I grow my own it and
I'm like $15 joint oh my God and uh I
smoke the thing [ __ ] pop are you
[ __ ] kidding me you know like get it
together you know if you can't be a
professional Bud sales and sell seed in
your bud you know I thought the only
smart way you could do that is in Canada
they over tax seeds it's a dollar a seed
excise tax that's ridiculous in my head
I can't get my head around playing that
game because I want to sell seeds for
less than that like packs of sunflowers
you know so the the thing that drives me
nuts
is why should they get 50 60,000 a kilo
from your seeds that's you taxing the UN
board you don't even know if it's a mail
or whatever like give me a break now
you're going to tax the seed that's not
even alive yet might not Sprout like
it's just overreach you know it's a
paing overreach um so I don't know if I
have to ask you or not that's you know
that's a reason why I vitalized you and
your work is because you've always put
quality first and
foremost how do you feel about new seed
companies a lot of them coming out a lot
of them Ste a lot of them coming out are
saying there's no need to test these if
we knew the mother was good we knew the
Fe the the father was good and there's
no reason to test these seeds because
there's a certain amount of instability
that is in cannabis and it will always
be
there well ideally you want to test it
first but I absolutely sympathize with
people who know that they're like the
mother's killer the father's killer no
matter what the [ __ ] kids are going
to look good we don't know what they're
going to look like but they're going to
look good so if you want to play that
game that's your brand to play with you
know and and that's really all that's
happening in the you know the bleeding
edge I think of the hype is always you
have to be the newest of the new new so
you got to get the tour's newest and
cross them before anybody else and then
it's the newest new new you know so
there's just this like arms race to be
have the next inevitable crosses made on
the road to homogenization you know
everything's good by the time it's all
mixed together there it'll eventually
all be the same anyway but no it's
awesome because you think think like a
million monkeys that could come up with
Shakespeare right a million monkeys with
tyrers or whatever that's how I think
about it and that's and that's how it's
survived that's how it's evolved is is
you know all of us Growers saving seeds
for whatever turns us on about those
plants all over the world for Millennia
Millennia right so we're just a little
Link in a very long chain you know and
we all get to make some picks and make
some crosses and and put our stamp on it
for the next Generation you know and uh
some of us will do more of it than
others but it's just as long you know if
you're into it definitely do something
make one for yourself you know find your
favorites and and make something yeah I
really encourage people to breed their
own I think it's awesome you know that's
how I started pure out of Hobby and I
really you know I didn't go far with
breeding in formal education I studied
other things but I employed PhD breeders
and master agronomists and all this and
I learned so much from my staff all the
time you know because I'm not know the
most versed in molecular genomics but
I'm totally stoked to read Great Links
and to learn about it and uh I I know
because I have looked at it for quite a
while what can be done with it like bone
before we could ever get our hands here
you know 20 years ago I'd sit in my
office in Switzerland and be reading
about this going oh if we could only do
this you know think of what we could do
but at that time it was like if you
weren't you know a big government like
the us or Monsanto or somebody you were
not sequencing anything right and now
it's become so affordable and you know
available it's it's happening so it's
beautiful beautiful to see the world you
know catching up with cannabis as what
it was meant to be is just for everybody
and it's been locked down for a hundred
years and as it comes back up it gets to
enter the modern world with all the you
know stuff
is it hasn't been able to access when it
was underground you know so the
attention that it's getting in research
circles now you know in so many types of
research from medicine you know not just
in growing in that too it's it's so
astounding to see how how mainstream has
become you know I still pinched myself
sometimes that you know we're living in
the times we are it's like it's been
hellish for so many but it's seems to be
turning the corner it's still hellish
for so many let's face it for the
majority it's still horrible there's
definitely a a blessing that's been
bestowed upon a lot of the world that
you don't didn't have that
before um one of our patreon members
Jesse James from Australia uh wants to
follow up with you everybody's got their
own you know
checkbox of what they want and what they
want to breed forward to he wants to
know how do you uh test your
plant well we have a inhouse at the main
Farm we have I'm trying to think of the
brand it I believe it's a Korean one but
I forget for sure but we have the GC and
an LC there so we can test for
cannaboids and Turin on site and then
the genomas send off samples but I don't
know which Labs they're using them
because they interpret them for me and I
say I your genetics interpreters because
I can't read a sequencing report you
know but I can
segregate the traits you know and say
okay I know that group a is all purple
plants and group b is all green plants
but I'm not going to tell them what the
trade is I just send you off group a and
Group B samples and you got 50 tissue
samples of each and they'll analyze them
and then do a comparative analysis to
see which you know plasma is different
you know which section of the chromosome
is different in these groups you know
and and then you say okay then you can
tell them this one's purple this one's
green you know so you can do that with
resistance to any pathogen you know if
you had mildo resistant plant or virus
resistant plant and then you have ones
that are susceptible but they're sisters
and they're otherwise pretty much the
same it's just that some are better
against the Milo than others so that's
how those types of genes get identified
is they're you
segregate the plants and then look for
the common denominator in each group
that's different from the other one so
that's how that's how we do it and then
you have you can develop once you know I
don't know if it's proteins or enzymes
whatever they need to turn the colors
they can do oneoff dropper kits where
you can pulverize the sample and say you
can put a drop in and either stays Blue
if it's a male or turns pink if it's a
female you know you can do these single
tests to once you you can develop them
it's not like they're automatic but you
have to know something about the
biochemistry which I could never figure
out in the life of me you
know I just don't know exactly how you
go about going oh well to break down
this enzyme into pink we need this or to
make this one flip I don't know how that
stuff works I know what I want them to
do and figure out it's done you know
what what would first plant Steve think
about Steve now and all these different
pieces of equipment that you have access
to to do what you do did you ever think
hey I never a point where you had so
much passion and you were like I'm GNA
take it to this level yeah yeah you know
what I think I was still thinking of it
as a hobbyist that I wanted to do it
hardcore like when I was in university
was really when I got at it you know and
uh when I I went to University a year
early I finished high school in four
years so
the the uh that's really when I got into
growing and I I went there to do
constitutional law thinking that would
help me legalize her but after sitting
through the classes and the people and I
felt like it there was it was just such
a Square
environment and I was more of a you
daily doser kind of
guy even though I want to really
understand all this you I can't hang out
here all day you know what I mean it was
too much I didn't I couldn't get my head
around it I would say you know what is
the legitimacy of all this constitution
where does it come from like okay from a
a for from a king or queen somewhere and
where does their legitimacy come from
oh from some God botherer in a funny hat
you know give me a break this is a
[ __ ] fairy tale doesn't makes sense
the land's founded on genocide there's
no other way to put it you know what I
mean it's like where's the legitimacy of
this institution there's to me it lacks
legitimacy so I say the best I got to
accept is it's like a mafia that rules
the land and extorts the people and
controls their lives I think you know
you've just got to Bob and weave a
little and just you know maybe one leg
in one leg out for lot of people like be
you know enough to stay somewhat San
because to me it's just a once you kind
of look at the big picture it's quite
scary and you think oh man this is this
is whack you know right anyway I I've
been I'm so far gone I really dream of a
postnational future for all
earthlings because I think the nation
states that divide us are you know the
biggest problems you know it's the
stains on our planet you know so let the
Earths be so when you were um coming up
with a spice alive seed company was
there you know I would I would love to
say a company it wasn't a company it was
just spice of Life Seeds I didn't make
it a company because then then you're
it's part of the system I mean I was
really a whack out there at the time now
I have companies but at the time when I
first started that it was really just a
hobby and then it was an activism you
know before it was actually really a
business because I never like took a
bunch of money from that endeavor and
bought anything all I ever did was rent
more houses to breed more pot you know
it all just rolled back into it and uh
it was just a joy doing it you know if
wasn't like I was going buying a new
Ferrari every year with it or anything
right right that was my mistake that's
right I'm just kidding no it was never
you know I never because I always
figured too I was like oh if you do
accumulate a bunch from it then when
they come and get you they've got
something to take and they're you're
more attractive to them whereas if You'
got nothing because you just kept
spending it on concert tickets and
growing more weed and uh there's nothing
for them to take so you know I was
always like I never want them to come
and say oh we found the dude with a
bunch of cash on keep it spent you know
what concerts were you spending it on oh
God I don't know just go we would go out
to see bands in Vancouver every night
and you know just go to restaurants and
have fun in town back in the back in the
mid 90s there it was quite a time yeah
that sounds like a great life just that
alone uh did you have any Idols coming
up in that
time well you know there was
um a couple guys I really should think
and one would be Ed rosenal and Mel
Frank or two I guess because I remember
their book was the first one I'd read
but I'd ordered it at the same time I
ordered marijuana botney with Robert
conell Clark and I ordered those like
with money orders out of a back of a
high times you know I sure then got them
mailed to me at University so I've read
their books and really back to back so I
had the Growers guide and then the uh
marijuana botney which is more about
breeding and I was hooked simultaneously
you know I was like you know it was
obvious to me I had to do both not just
one you know so I really felt compelled
but I still you know grow a little sense
crop with 400 watts under the stairwell
in the studio student house you know
wouldn't bother making seeds in there or
something but for keeping like an
envelope of pollen and just seeding a
bottom branch of a big outdoor Bud on a
day when it's not windy you know just
hit that bottom I would just have seed
in the bottom branch and the rest of it
would be sense you know so I was good at
just you know selectively seeding
different branches for having a bunch of
different crosses and that would get you
a jar of each which is more than I
needed everybody always want wanted to
buy my homegrown CU I would really hit
it out of the park with nice 12 type
organic mix type of thing and always
good at picking a sunny sight and stuff
and I would never sell my homegrown
because he can't replace it so but I
would always tell people if you want to
do it here's a one page on how to you
know mix the soil and plant a hole and
pick a site and stuff I got a one page
how to and I'll give you 20 seeds so
just you go and do it and if you get it
figure it out teach other people how to
do it you know it really was just
wanting to get it out there and keep it
alive because all the forces that be in
the world we're trying to make the
species extinct which you know if that
isn't proof enough of their you know
lack of legitimacy you know what right
do they have to exist This legal fiction
to Outlaw a
species I get some heray in the chat
that's ridiculous I think everybody
agrees with you here you are on the
right podcast
sir I tell you
guys yeah man I vied with you a lot and
I had no idea we talked before the show
you said you had your own Winery for a
while you really got into wine yeah I
dropped for a while and I did wine for
15 years even did certified organic wine
at that that's really Co what are some
of your favorite wines I just started
getting into wine a couple years ago
seriously
well I'd like all of them pretty much if
they're done really really well like any
type of wine or any region it's always
nice to have the best of any region you
know because like a reasoning from the
alsas is great if it's a really nice one
and a reasoning from the Oak and Aug
grade if it's a really nice one and even
from Niagara too right so on the other
hand you get a very different cab so in
Napa than you do in Niagara
so you there's a whole lot to choose
from in wine and that wine I always
figured it was important like I started
to love wine when I moved to Switzerland
to grow weed so I just sort of TR you
know learned about that my first wine
tour was in burgundy with a friend from
Switzerland oh wow been going he'd been
going every month since he was five with
his dad to buy their household wine and
so he knew burgundy like the back of his
hand so it was really a eye opener for
me that trip and that was only like my
first year living in
swier and
then then later once we had kids and we
said you know when the Swiss Place
started to be a hassle we said let's
just change gears and try making wine
for a while while the kids are young and
do something non-controversial so I did
that and I figured oh by the time I
learned to make wine and get good at
that I'll learned something about
um the cuz I figured when cannabis was
legal it was going to fall into place
much like the wiy business and
eventually it is here like now they're
going to allow the craft Growers to open
up direct sales because if you're a
craft grower and you can only sell to
the government you're pretty screwed you
know you don't have any bargaining power
there whereas if you have directed the
public you have U you know closer to
what the market will bear for what
you're growing and you get a better
spread and that's how in BC that's how
the wineries if they're landbased
wineries they can sell direct to the
public and they only pay sales tax
there's no excise tax on it where and
they can have tastings and they people
can come and buy some and go sit up on
the hill and enjoy it you know I thought
this is exactly what cannabis is going
to be like when it's legal in Canada it
won't be like what I had in Switzerland
here they'll license it and tax it and
that's fine if it's reasonable we can
live with that but it's if it's too much
it's just embarrassing so it was a a
parallel universe of flavorful
intoxicants making wine because you're
growing something to make something that
smells great and tastes great and has an
effect and and ostensibly some medical
benefit too in moderation right glass of
red wine a day or whatever who know true
it's just an appreciate tping and being
able to pull out all those flavor
profiles and it was funny while I was in
Switzerland I was in an area where they
only grew Mero the whole valley was Mero
basically they it was all the greates
and you all the different country
restaurants had their own Mero and they
didn't bottle it you got a jug at the
table with your dinner you know so and
they drank it out of Bal lii they look
like little finger bows and people
didn't believe me they had guests come
out they see me drinking you're drinking
out of the finger bow I'm like no that's
B that's how they drink here so they'd
give you like a ceramic jug with a liter
of wine that was like 20 Franks which
was like 20 Canadian back then so you
judge these restaurants not just on
their food but by their wine because it
was literally their wine you park by the
vines and just walk in so it was very
rustic and I really thought it was super
cool how that was and most of them would
never bottle their wine but um
I realized boy they've got all the good
grow sites too and if you're remember
from way back when you had to hide your
plants the most successful commercial
pot production was always blended into
other agriculture so the common thing
would be corn but of course they'd look
in corn because everybody grows their
read in the corn right but in Vineyards
is not quite as common but it's still
done so there's you can grow weed at a
Vineyard so if you've got you know 100
acres of irrigated drip line and
trellising all out there and another
cover crop you could easily put in 10
acres of weat if you did every 10 plant
right or every 20th plant would be like
five acres of weed so you that's how the
large scale commercial production has
always been done is Blended with other
agriculture so that it can be right out
in the open and worked on openly without
you you know you can't go and hide a
field in the bush you know you can only
hide a field within a field you know and
that's the that's how it used to be so
anyway so I thought if I had a Vineyard
I could start testing out some plants
and be see how they like growing with
the vines I had a friend in Switzerland
that bought a Vineyard ripped out all
the plants and kept the trellising which
was in Switzerland they had concrete
post with the steel wires and so the
neighbors were all really pissed because
it was surrounded by apartment buildings
it was this big Vineyard in between
apartment buildings he ripped it all out
and planted it the people were really
pissed because they likeed The View over
the vineyard and they did not like the
view and the aroma from his Urban fields
that guy was Felix that was in Lardo
that was the funniest place it was the
craziest place that was so funny do I
have to bleep that out that name no
everybody know back there I I hope he's
well I hope he's watching but I'm sure
they still do that here still playing
cannabis in the middle of the vineyard
weed and I swear to God everything that
I've had out of those something about
the microbiology and the soil it makes
it taste like FY I've had some excellent
Vineyard weed actually one of my
favorite ones I grew in the vineyard was
actually grapefruit and it was one of
the strongest ones I had too this decent
altitude and and it was a hot year and
dry there was you know all those the
grapefruit that was a real hitter I
remember to that was like I remember
having that thinking this is maybe the
strongest grapefruit I've ever grown and
I've grown some good strong grapefruit
before like as strong as it could be I
thought but when I pulled some out of
the vineyard I was I had some friends
that it did put the Herd on and I hadn't
seen that before where they were like oh
that joint just destroyed me and they
were not they were like losing their
[ __ ] and I was like it's not usually
that strong but this is really
exceptionally good for grapefruit so I
never had that tested I would have like
to pest that match but yeah it's fun the
I I always remember that in Switzerland
seeing all these Vineyards around going
because especially because we'd have
trouble with rippers we'd be growing
like solid fields of it or solid green
houses of it or solid warehouses of it
and rippers were always a concern and uh
he got hit by some and definitely hit
some back but the
uh the
uh thinking boy I bet you if I just put
in these Vineyards you wouldn't see it
you know nobody even no Thief is going
in the vineyard they're not there to
steal grapes you know no Thief is going
into Vine so I thought I bet you they'd
be safer out there than behind the fence
you behind the fence people like hey
what's in there we got to get it you
know there's greenhous Le behind the
fence in the vineyard they just walk
right past us they would never go look
in the vineyard you know it's just too
much work to go look up and down the
roads right nobody had drones back then
that's the thing Ontario the Rippers are
so bad now they've got drones all over
the place and people chasing going in
with flags just like you know the cops
used to go in with the flags into the
cornfield like the tall flag so the
Choppers could tell them where to go
because they know where they are and uh
yeah the Rippers are doing that so I
think but I mean the best thing is just
that you leave it alone till it's so
ubiquitous and it's not worth stealing
just like grapes you know I actually had
had people come and steal grapes from
the the stuff that was growing over the
fence I had like C like a family that
was taking them to make their online
it's like
seriously anyway if you don't have it
behind the fence people think it's fair
game but hid and plain sight is a good
way to go like if you're still somewhere
where you've got to hide your plants
that's a great way to go I mean if you
were in France they don't even allow
Irrigation in The Vineyards so you'd
still be out there hand watering but in
in h British Columbia The Vineyard
wouldn't survive without water you know
not not in the interior in the um in
Ontario you don't use much irrigation I
don't think in The Vineyards but if you
have dir LS out there you got drip lines
and Tris and cover yeah you're good to
go you
know I was telling you before the show
that uh a good friend of mine Professor
p and his buddy solo farms over in
Massachusetts uh did a preservation of
the grapefruit work and I had a picture
that I wanted to or it's more of a video
that I wanted to show you really quick
of one that I grew out of that that was
more leaning towards the sweet pink and
uh wanted to see if it Beed any
resemblance to you to the old stuff well
you've got my
attention that's so tiny is there any
way oh let me try and blow
my go back let's see the top
again go
down
go down I want to see the stocks of it
oh this is an old video Steve oh it's an
old video I thought you were moving it
around or something sorry
sir yeah it's believable man I think so
it has you know the texture of the
leaves looks like it the shape and size
pretty
much is it starting again you're started
again I
miss
that's good you did a good job I think
it looks like pretty close it may be a
little
pointier but not too much it's pretty
close well that is good to hear man I
will pass on that
news because that was that was the main
phenotype that you were getting out of
it was plants that were looking like
that uh with just that rare one that I
was telling you about earlier that was a
little bit more sour it was uh a little
bit more potent it leave you a little
bit more head buzzed you know instead of
the up head buzz it was that extreme
like holy
[ __ ] and what did they work it
with um as far as I don't want to
misquote this because I feel like I keep
getting it wrong but I'm pretty sure uh
Professor P had the one that he called
the inbred line for the the Great fruit
and breadline and then uh solo over in
Massachusetts had the sweet pink
grapefruit and I believe that was from
your stock I'm not sure I think P
claimed that his was from your stock um
but they took those two that were kind
of unrelated you know that they're both
grapefruit different Coast lines and
they took them together and brought them
together to kind of open it back up and
preserve it it's got a little rounder
talk those ones were a little pointier
you know were a little bit pointier they
don't look exactly like it but it's very
similar like the type of resin on the
leaves you know it really looked like
that kind of Velvet Leaf kind of it's a
neat it was too it was a beautiful plant
and like you said just dead on Ruby Red
Grapefruit oh yeah delicious and it
yielded really really well too yeah
they're chunky they're chunky and
they're tasty and that's what the people
like about I'll tell you a funny story
actually
from
um back in
the let's say Lish M to late 90s there
was a lot of really nice grapefruit and
Sweet Tooth ending up in New York City
and they
would they then one time they took some
different weed that was a lot
stronger and wasn't as tasty but it was
stronger and they said the next time
they were back they said we don't want
the strong one again we have a routine
we we take take a 100 Kil 100 pounds out
of storage every morning and break it
down to 10 people they go home that
afternoon and break it down to 10 people
they go take their pounds and then they
sell ounces or sell it to the guy
selling ounces to sell eights and stuff
like that and uh they break it down he
says the guy comes home from work the
bike Courier comes over with his 85 $5
eight you know and it's so tasty they're
just like I have another one it's so
tasty they just did bong rip after bong
rip because it tastes so good and by
midnight it's all gone and the next day
the whole cycle starts over but he said
when you put the real poton stuff in
that round it took them two days to
finish it and it [ __ ] up our
cycle so we don't want the strong stuff
anymore just the tasty stuff cuz people
smoke it you know they go through it
really
well that's the cool thing is there's a
type of cannabis for damn near any time
of the day you know yeah sure and okay
that brings up a point I did really want
to ask you um a lot of breeders that I
know lay claim that breeding with femin
seed breeding with s1's um is kind of
dirtying up the gene pool how do you
feel about
that well I think over Reliance on S1
ones who put a lot more Herms out there
I think so I think
so
um a I had never been a big fan of them
and I never sold Sam seeds but the
market of course demands them at this
point like it was really just getting to
be crucial around the time I was taking
a break you know and retired from the
seed business for 15 years there
whatever now I've been making them for
five plus but I haven't
got back in the market actually had my
first hemp seed at one of my companies
is the first time I ever made a hemp
seed and it's a a feminized hemp line
and that came out in the fall as a
registered hemp seed and then the next
registered seed we have coming out that
U is a my company in Colombia that is
it's not just me of course but it's it's
a a one to one is this something that we
can look forward to in the future those
are those will be out they're literally
being harvested this week uh I just
posted a picture I think today actually
I could I'll post think I shared a
picture of it on on Twitter maybe but
that was um this one to one and if
memory serves that one was a 15 to 15
for THC and CBD and it's a pretty plant
and
hope it hope it's hope people like it
but it's not it's not spice of life it's
not you know it's its own brand so that
uh it'll be white labeled like the first
batch coming out the first commercial
batch won't be an enormous one but now
it's registered so we'll get those out
there and get people um see how the
demand is for them and uh then produce a
lot more so they can be really
inexpensive and broadly available well I
can tell you there's somebody already
looking forward to that because I really
enjoy Wonder ones in the morning it's
become like it's been know people like
it's like my morning coffee I mean it
doesn't get you blasted out of your mind
but it it's a functional lift yeah
functional lift I've I've tried him of
course I mean of course but they don't
really hit me at all like any of the
ratio plants I usually like oh that was
just a waste of r
then I go you know I I feel like I just
don't get enough off it to to float my
boat I had one that was neat was said of
the same I have friends that were
absolutely adored it that they were
there and they can't smoke the high THC
stuff and we had some plenty of outdoor
that was over 30% you know I have Rock
Solid outdoor down there that can be as
good as anything out there is absolutely
stunning and if I smoke you know I won't
even reach for the strongest one all the
time I'll often reach for one of the
tastier ones that are you know mid 20s
instead of low3s because the low 30s too
it's a different smell you know it's not
as fruity it's I find the strongest ones
[Music]
aren't to me as tasty I like them and
they have a very distinct taste but it's
a lot more AER you know it's
not it's like what they come with it's
it's like the strong plants always come
with that um well like cleaner like
really a
pungent you know piny cleaner kind of
smell that's it's more
astringent than Pleasant to me you know
and I can appreciate it for being the
astringent Beast it is because I I know
it totally gives me the headband in the
sweats like I was like oh my God I can't
feel my legs from the knees down like it
gets me really stoned that uh proper
fuel pot there but if I take like a
spike Punch or something maybe
26% but tastes really nice then I far
prefer that you know and I'm still lit
you know but I'm not like I need to turn
my phone off for half an hour
lit put down Twitter
Steve so funny so speaking of some of
your favorite type here what are some of
your favorite types that you did not
create well
easily my uh my Lifelong Love of
cannabis has been Santa Marty Gold
without a doubt
she's she's so nice and there's there's
didn't you do a release
that well I I had uh you know my biggest
one of my biggest regrets in of was
collecting was when I had it pure not
knowing what it
was but I had seeds that was gifted to
me from a friend of a friend who said
this was the best weed I'd ever smoked
and I was on holidays in Jamaica it was
golden and sticky and he said the best
weed I've ever smoked he give it to your
friend Steve he brows great weed give it
to him see what he can do with it so he
gave so my friend brought me these seeds
and his name is Lionel so I called it
lion Lion's killer and then they changed
the lion killer you know and then that
was what it was grown as it just said LK
on it for Lion's killer and they and as
it grew it was growing with all this
other stuff that took on average eight
weeks and it wasn't flowering you know
I'm like holy [ __ ] this stuff is so
skinny and so
slow but it's got a compelling smell
like if you rub the stock in that and
the leaves were just pite like really
really pretty thin and and paler and I
had um the male and females like I had
two males and two females or something
it and I said well it's totally
unusual I'm going to leave it the first
time I just kept the mail away and
didn't do anything with the mail I let
them grow just to have them a sense
these two
females and I had backup mothers of them
and fathers at the time and I grew them
and I it took 16 weeks to flower and
they were absolute pencils but they
smelled like cherry pie filling or
something it was just exotic and so I
had him I packed him into a glass
spaghetti noodle jar one of the tall
jars and I packed them in there and I
guess made it was maybe 2 ounces but
they were just tiny thin thin Buds and
they took 16 weeks and I didn't share
them with my best friend I didn't
sh they stayed in my bedroom and I would
like go up there in the morning wake up
in the morning and smoke on there before
I even left my room i'' be like oh this
is this is too good to share you know
and I was like okay this stuff's magical
I have to make some seeds with it but
instead of making a pure batch and
keeping it pure I said well nobody's
ever going to want these because they
too skinny and they take too long so
instead of making in a pure batch which
I could have easily done cuz at first I
did the male Santa Marty gold with a
Dutch Treat which was fast and Frosty
and compact so I crossed it with the
Dutch Treat and that was Tropical Treat
one and I could have easily put the
female at the same time and got a pure
batch but I was too stupid and I did the
female separately and I used the same
male which turned out to be a Northern
Light Haze that was the father of the
sweet sky
strawberry blonde and some other ones so
the but that was Tropical Treat number
two so I had the two lines of those came
out and uh I had pictures back from
people growing them in
Australia in
Hawaii just gorgeous and they loved them
they were raving above and then I I was
like they're still so slow though you
know and I grew them out to test and I
like they're still so slow so I cross
them later with shushu ber and sweet
tooth and called them Tropicana one and
two and I did those in Switzerland but
when I was growing out the tropical
treats one and two in
Switzerland um Sam the scottman came for
a visit one time and had this really
cool hermetics sealed door to slide open
into the backro and I had 36 lights in
the
aquarium and a total selection crop
going on with a huge range of stuff it
was like my first big seed selection
right there and Sam came for a visit and
he when we open the door he saw those at
the back cuz of course they're just
against the wall cuz they take two crops
anyway so you just put them at the back
out of the way and he went Santa Mar
gold and he just beelined for them you
know and he's smelling and going this is
the best Santa Mar gold I've seen in
decades where did you get this and I
said oh that's crossed down once already
he's like it's still pretty good I was
like I know it's really good still but
it's not we should have seen the parents
you know so I remember the parents like
it was yesterday it was some of my
favorite herb ever and it's not shocking
that that's the genetic they had in
Barbados that could have originated out
of Colombia right so the U even it was
grown in Barbados which I totally
believe that nice Limestone beautiful
place to grow I've seen fantastic B of
Barbados you can you can grow Dynamite
down there but the
uh um
anyway the the smell on barbad since
I've been back since I've been back in
Columbia six years trying to recreate
you know from every collection I've
collected Santa Mar gold from you know
20 different people in 20 different
places and some lines are closer than
others and usually I find like okay one
out of 20 is right and the other 19 are
[ __ ] so I I had to sift through them you
know and I'm continually doing that but
I have got some now that I'm pretty
proud of that are getting more and more
like what I remember it to be and I
actually
know um some of the families in the
North Coast that were the people that
were growing the sand am martic gold and
and they you know they haven't seen it
themselves and I send them pictures of
here look how close this is and and I
know the guys that used to grow it that
are very old men now they're still
looking at these pictures and going go
go
go they're so stoked and and their kids
have been to see it in that you know
so I've gone and sat on the tractor like
in the field where the best Sant Mar
gold supposedly came from you know I've
been I've been all explored the area of
the region of pretty you know where it
was best grown there was it was grown
really widely but there was some areas
that were considered the best zones like
ponir and burgundy you know like it's
considered a special place to have it
you know and that's where that's where
it was you know developed for x amount
of years and uh it's a true AR it's
special I really love I love to get it
you know it's been a real dream of mine
to really restore it and make it
available for more people to see and
experience because it it has these high
notes that most people haven't really
been exposed to yet you know and Haze is
as close as most people get and Haze
original yellow Haze was pure Santa
Marta gold that climatized in Santa Cruz
I think but anyway in California and
um then it became the green Haze when
somebody guy Michael supposedly added
the tie into it and it became the green
Haze is my understanding you I'm sure
somebody could correct me but that's u
in that that be along the lines of the
the haze Brothers presumably yeah I
don't know them I've never talked to
them so I can't say it's all your sa for
me that's all I'm saying you know so the
but from pretty good sources like Sam
the SK fan that I remember what he told
me about I hope but was pretty simple
with that the um and it's pretty obvious
when when you know what's tic gold
tastes like that that's pretty close to
what Haze tastes like but when you get
the yellow Haze over the green Haze you
notice a difference and um like that
popular Amnesia Haze cut that's out and
around I've had even the last three
years in a row is the only one that I've
continually put three years in a row in
my yard I only I don't keep very many
plants in my yard but a friend had given
me one it was so good I said oh give me
a cut of that every year it was so good
CU it's the closest thing to Santa Marty
gold that'll finish in the oag you know
and that's because I do cheater outdoor
they're totally outdoor but when the
rains come I pull them under the porch
which is south facing so they never get
rained on when they're in flower but
they still get a half day of sun or
something they don't get it's not the
it's not comp competitive environment my
backyard because there's shade in the
morning and shade later in the day but
it gets the best part of the day it gets
direct sun and it's cooking so they they
turn out good my backyard plants so I'm
happy for that it's a hobby thing I
travel so much so I can't bother having
an indoor you know I don't even have a
closet at home it's like plus when
you're home do you want to take your
work home all the time well of course I
want to smoke at home all the time but I
I mean uh
I've got so much her growing in so many
places but I've got so many skilled
people working with me and taking care
of it in the dayto day that I've become
pretty lazy and I feel hands off until I
have my summer plants where I have my
personal plants you know and I hashtag
pool Bud on them and I just have a
little joy for watering them myself you
know rather than having 80 people on the
farm that you know I'm never watering
something when I go to the farm I'm
walking around and making notes and
talking to people and taking pictures
but I'm not hands on with the plant so
at least in my backyard I get that
connection again because I feel like
I've become too much of an executive
grower on some level you know even
executive breeder because I have
breeders working for me that are far
more qualified as far as scholastically
speaking but their fruit oute because I
can look at the stem of a male sometimes
and tell them what it is and they like
that's not
normal so we have really a lot of fun
working together because they're from
outside cannabis some of them and it's
real eye opener for them like and it's
you know not as easy for me because I
had to teach them to grow in the first
place and teach them what to look for
whereas in other projects you know like
in the Thailand right now I have Steve
Ryner from potent ponics so he's there
on the the ground taking care of the
plants killing the [ __ ] ones taking
video showing this showing the whole
world how what's going on it's on his
YouTube channel so I get live
practically live updates from the Farms
but I get more from the Tai one than
from the ones in Columbia and in Spain
they're more research based crops right
now we have
uh we have EU funding with uh The Bash
government and then we have another
project with the Catalan government and
we do genetic research and propagation
work micropropagation work to do sematic
embryogenesis and hopefully eventually
in suspension culture because we do it
now in in pet dishes but I want to have
you know the goal was was to do it in
suspension culture but that's the
hardest type of tissue culture to
do um anyways we're on it because like
with sterile plants you can't I can't
make seeds for stero plants but I can
make cuting of my sterile plants so
those are at no risk of Ever Getting
seeded and they root in three or four
days so they're amazing plants and I can
do that with just about any plant so I'm
as I get the different selections
sterile then we'll get them registered
and then hopefully distribute those as
artificial seeds or synthetic
seeds they'll be fun it's just
scared when you people get scared when
you say that you know because they think
you're doing GMO or something and it's
not like that it's just just a
convenient way to ship micropropagation
you
know yeah absolutely so to round back
really quick would you say that Amnesia
Haze was one of your
favorites oh no that you know lately
okay I could say of backyard stuff
that's been a nice one the Amnesia Haze
this summer I had a
creamsicle um pie hole chem glue
Grandpa's breath what else God bud not
my favorite is God bud is a neat plant
because it has some really strong like
mildew resistance it has a nice chunky
Frosty appearance but it doesn't have
any flavor you know there's and I don't
get any buzz from it so I was like it
was very disappointing because it looks
so good but it's just it just looks good
so looks can be deceiving people I I'm
I'm often skeptical of super Frosty
stuff that it's going to be super tasty
because I've had so many super Frosty
stuff that was a real let down and that
the first time I saw that was White
Widow where I remember thinking oh this
looks I saw it when it first came out of
the first can of his cup and Scott
Blakey there Shanty BBA was there with a
live plant a white widow and a live
plant a white rhino and I remember you
know respectfully looking at him not
touching them and squeezing them to
smell it seeing how close I could get
without touching to try and smell them
wasn't a lot coming off and then later I
see the frosty Bud for sale in the
coffee shop say would better buy and try
some and super Frosty but I'm like
[ __ ] tastes like hay you know and the
buzz was five minutes and I'm just like
this is this is useless so and I started
looking at these frostier ones often
under the loop with the measuring scale
and they would have very small heads and
if you started making hash with them
you'd find you get more small heads in
some of these like more 45 and 73 or
whatnot
and under the scope they have very long
stocks like the gland stocks right so
you when you separate it into screens
you go damn I've got more stocks than
heads like if you just you know used a
single screen and packed your ke you
know and you're happy with that kind of
be great hash and that's what it is but
the but the there's a lot of the
Glitters that is not gold you know often
the biggest heads with the tastiest
resin they're spread out on the leaf
they got short stocks because all the
Energy's gone into the head rather than
the stalks and when when you get those
long fuzzy stalks when you get there
with a microscope and look at them the
heads are really tiny on them you know
but the buds in the naked eye it looks
just white I equivalate that I grew up
in a agricultural environment mostly
like apples cherries pears things like
this but when you give that fruit when
you go through and you thin a you know a
bunch of pairs then the rest of them
have more room to grow bigger and I've
seen that same thing that you're talking
about right there with the resin
populations if they have more room to
grow they usually
do favorites California Orange I always
like that if it was you had a really
good one there was an old one that was
absolutely smack orange like just crazy
good and uh that one was really special
what were some of the other
ones I I like the real Romulan it was a
[ __ ] for growing because it had very
bad MW tolerance it was very susceptible
to mildew and uh it was notoriously bad
for it that one but it was Punchy and it
smelled like the urinal pucks like it
had that piny smell like a urinal PU
I always I could never think of anything
else that it smelled like I'm like oh
it's real ramula that smells like a
urinal pck you know but anytime
somebody's brought me Romulan like in
the last 15 years nothing like it like
it says Romulan but it's nothing like it
you know I haven't seen a real one in a
long time I'm sure they're out there but
I just haven't uh I don't go out looking
for weed as you might imagine and uh
whatever rolls through rolls through
that you know I get a lot from friends
that share with me and I try and share
some of mine that I've grown to it's
I've been doing it long enough that I if
I stopped growing my own right now I
think I could get by on rosin and Bud in
my fridge I have a separate fridge and
freezer for personal and I've got jars
in the you know racks of jars in my wine
Celler wi and wheat cell I think I could
probably stay high for about 15
years
yeah
Lally like pounds pounds of rosin or
sift that are all Frozen because I I'll
often just turn the plants right into
Ash right away and and I like to cure
them too so then I'll wrap them up and
put them away for a while because I'm
smoking the ones I grew five years ago
you know so I love hash I'm a big hash
fan I got to say I I did want to ask you
about that you know coming up and you
know
I imagine back then you guys weren't
getting as much hash um in Canada yeah
maybe it wasn't special it wasn't
special it was we we did get Hash Hash
was amongst the first things we ever had
actually and it was uh usually it was
Lebanese blunder red there's a big
Lebanese community in our town we had
Lebanese we had Pakistani which they
called Afghani but we all knew was
Pakistani and that had the gold mascara
on it and that came wrapped in that red
plastic like guda cheese and there was a
wrap Hash Hash cutting and wrapping
Factory in Holland that all of that hash
used to come from so that's kind of a
that was you know the bulk of what
Canada smoked for a long time was that
red WRA gold seal and um from that we
started to get occasional brick weed
from Mexico or Jamaica and a lot a lot
of Jamaican green oil and you knew it
was Jamaican green oil and not local
green oil because you could really taste
the overproof rum they made it with you
know and yeah I knew the I actually knew
these guys they were friends of one of
my friends older brothers and they got
taken
down this was a crazy story I'll tell
you because it's the guy's dead now and
I think it doesn't matter but the he uh
these young guys they went to Saunders
High School London Ontario and they they
were dealing there and when they were
about to graduate and they thought we
need to scale up our game we're bring
we're selling so much dop around town so
they they went to Jamaica and they took
a bunch of cash and they took a bunch of
hookers from Miami and they threw a big
party for the rude boys and took the top
two floors of some hotel in mono Bay and
they had an arrangement then that they
would get they would have a gy Jamaican
crew that did the bathrooms and the
planes like the plane Crews would go in
and fill up bags of oil under the sinks
and then put the seal them back up and
then the Jamaican ground crew in Toronto
would unload them and they did it for a
few years and then the way they got
caught
was this guy um he was out he was like
21 22 years old has a big yacht having a
big party with all these rockers on it
you know guys and girls and it's all
crank and Black Sabbath or whatever we
listening to back then I was a teenager
and these guys were like 22 and they
and they got caught in a fishing net it
was like a lost fishing net they got
tangled up and they were way way out in
Lake Huron and this one girl was on acid
and she grabbed the radio when the guys
were diving off the back trying to cut
off the net she gets on the radio mayday
mayday we're singing and then the Coast
Guard and police and everything show up
and they're like is this your dad's
yacht and he's like no this is my yacht
you know like and you are you know so
then they looked into him and they took
the whole thing
down that's where we used to get our
Jamaican green oil
back in the day when there is no more
spice Al life when Steve's not around
anymore what do you want people to
remember when they think of you that's a
really hard question what do you want to
represent all the work you put into
cannabis to
dat I don't
know I don't know it's a really tough
one you know if uh I feel like I'm just
getting started at it still and I hope I
can put out some much better work than I
ever have yet you know so I feel like
it's far from done but I would love to
be remembered as you know competent
breeder I suppose not that um like I
more than that maybe as a decent person
but maybe
not that's a tough one too
so I don't know man I don't that's
probably one of my favorite I've
remember me as a good golfer that's for
sure
and yeah like I said that's probably one
of the best most humble answers that
I've ever heard to that that's that's
really cool man so before we get going I
want to ask you some quick fire
questions from everybody that's tuned in
everybody in patreon I see you guys
right now thank you for showing up thank
you for sharing uh a lot of Canadians in
here saying you know some of the same
things I remember that hash Jama and oil
in abundance in I'm G to I'm going to
pronounce this wrong Mrs SAA Mrs S
that's where the Tron airport is
actually
miss so yeah that was like the that was
probably the dominant form of cannabis
at one point in
Ontario by the way shout out to uh dank
Panda everybody give dank Panda some
thanks too for helping put this
together appreciate theck out you bu
steu says always interesting to me East
Coast versus West Coast Canada in
northern BC hash became
hash maybe came to town twice a year and
was $20 a grand
[ __ ] yeah onario we didn't see much
grass
until well the late 80s I think was the
first time I saw Northern Lights it have
been yeah 86 87 maybe the first time I
saw Northern Lights and there was um I
had some grown in rock wull indoors and
I'd had some grown in fields outside and
the guys that did Fields outside three
guys did 700 pounds of it by paying a
farmer with Bean fields to let him put
in small plants late in the season and
do like 20,000 little plants and then
they pay the bean farmer 10 grand to be
out there and the cops are looking all
over the corn fields and everybody's
driving by the bean Fields because
they're only knee high and nobody grows
weed beans right smart asit so that's
that's how you know people tuck them
into crops to pull it off and the bean
moves a sweet one because they'll be
looking at all the fields except those
because they think they're too short for
weed but of course now I've given out
the secret and nobody can ever get away
with it
again no but really because if you if
you can be out in the field with the
tractor and trailer people can drive by
nobody's going to think anything it
you're working in broad daylight and
they would just be taking a post hole
diggers and drilling the hole dumping in
the soil mix coming you know following
along with the clones and they'd be
tossing them in late so they just grow
up a nice poo stick and that's it so
they when they were bringing them to us
to sell we get like 20 pounds of tops we
didn't know at first you where the hell
they were growing them or anything but
first I remember me and a friend we
split they fronted us like 20 pounds to
flip so we
we're teenagers and we okay so we said
we better start putting some into bags
it's all in garbage bags so we start
pulling out the and we're like man this
look at the size of this top I'm going
to take this little crown of cix's off
it with no stem or leaf and they call it
the tip top you know cuz at first we
were like oh look at these giant tops
well we'll keep the big tops for us and
we'll just sell the small buds because
we were only selling it to get free
smoke so we would uh
we would first pull out the big buds and
then we realized damn 80% of it's all
these big buds like it's all big buds
there's very few little buds so that's
when I started saying well I'm clipping
a few tip Toops and just took like a
couple crowns so I had like a half ounce
bag that was just kx's really but the uh
that made a damaging pan of brownies for
a Hamilton Grateful Dead show that my
uncle cop ate that's a whole other story
that's something that I definitely want
to hear manzy [ __ ] we'll have to get you
on the podcast another time here in the
future whenever I know you're a busy man
but uh I want to thank you again for all
the time that you took for this really
quick before we get going Jesse James 36
says which strains of yours give the
most couch locked effect in your
experience I think of the all of the
ones that I released was probably the
Louie Legends ultimate
indicia that was a real you know sit
down and relax kind of joint you know
that mainly the hash from that it I
remember one of my friends called it the
black of black because it was like
blacker than black it was and that was
when when I had a sizable crop of that I
found it to I had other things too but I
found it far preferable for ash over
grapefruit but maybe not as much as
Shish
you know shushu ber is a dynamite hash
plant too but they make a different hash
uh yeah I would say coach loock probably
the Louis Orga Inda by sweet too BX
2p1 he Co Stone stew says star struct I
can't think of a question but can you
let him know that grapefruit was the
first thing that I ever smoked in
northern BC that smelled sweet and had a
high that didn't make me nonfunctional
made me truly fall in love with the
plant very on very on I'm glad you
enjoyed it and Jesse James from
Australia wants to know what's in the
cards for the
future well to keep
uh doing these satellite projects I've
got going I've got the opportunity to
test cannabis in more environments than
I ever thought I would so I want to just
keep at that and develop based on what I
find there's a I'm not getting bored
with it I'm totally just getting into it
and getting to do it on like a level
that I never had dreamt of you know
probably even 15 years ago I probably
never thought oh my God this I'm going
to have the ability to test stuff in 11
climactic zones in Colombia plus two in
Thailand and one in Jamaica we've got
three locations in Spain you know that
quite different environment from the
bass country to Catalia down to Al Maria
so there's getting to see all the plants
and all the different environments is
really satisfying for me and uh seeing
what I can pull together out of them is
is really a joy you know so I like to
think now that I'm planting seed
companies and you know planting cannabis
research stations not just seeds you
know because I'm training people you
know and spending years on training
people people to make the selections
when I can't you know and when when I
just can't make it or when I'll never be
able to again you know so i' love to
work with the people and I really want
to try and Inspire and train as many
people as I can and as many places as I
can to just keep pushing the envelope
with it and make selections from big
numbers and I know a lot of breeders
think that you know High number
selections are outdated now that you
have molecular genetics Labs on the
other hand if you don't have fields to
test them what good is it you know the
real world testing is you know I I'm not
knocking the labs I love having access
to the modern Labs that we do but it's
it's the um the being in a blue sky with
a green field there's no substitute you
know it's I I feel like I'm in church
when I'm in those fields selecting and
that's where I'm go off to next week I'm
down to back to the equator and I have
375 lines ready to look through from
some of them from quite High numbers and
uh I've really been looking forward to
that for
years and I'm stoked yeah that's great
once I get back from there I'll be
planning this next trip to go to Jamaica
and as soon as I'm back from Jamaica
I'll be back to
Thailand and
uh then we'll see I haven't I've haven't
been to Spain in just over year now the
people that are there doing a good job
you know I don't I'm not needed for you
know dayt day you know so it's if things
are going good and I'm getting reports
of healthy plants and everything's on
track that's what I want to see you know
I can I'm I'm not micromanaging any one
site but I'm I'm getting a bird's eye
view of all of them and just keeping my
finger on the pulse I love it half of
it's WhatsApp groups where I've got
WhatsApp groups and send me photos when
I wake up in the morning I'm in the last
time zone so so Thailand's 15 hours
ahead then the European Mainland then
some UK business then the the Colombian
time and same as Jamaica and then it's
uh up to me so by noon I've talked to
everybody around the world that's
growing weed with me you know by noon
every day I'm done you know because I've
started started at 5: in the morning and
not not every day you know but lots of
days and it's partly because we're just
having fun like they don't necessarily I
don't necessarily need a picture every
day of every plant but if my friends
going oh check this one I was looking
really good today I'm stoked to see it
you know because it's your hobby you
know it's your hobby it's not like
waking up and [ __ ] I got to get to work
it sucks you know most days it's not
like that it's like I wake up I'm like
oh sweet What's Happening Here What's
happen you I'm stoked to checking on the
fs you know so that's I feel like I'm
getting the away with something that I
can just stay home ripping dabs in my
pajamas and grow weed all over the world
and then if I get to show up and take
credit for it once in a while that's fun
too
right no I like to get there in person
and try some and taste some you know the
uh there's no substitute and of course
there's some of the places that does
require a lot of training but when I've
been able to
install um
people with experience over credentials
in those cases it's a lot easier for me
you know the places where I'm forced by
regulations to hire for credentials over
experience then I've got a little more
effort involved in making sure they're
not killing the plants like I've seen
some a lot of really basic mistakes
you'd think you know certain you know
Growers shouldn't make one example was
you know ordering some cocoa choir you
can get domestic cocoa Choir in Colombia
it's not like you're importing it from
Sri Lanka it's Colombian Coco but
they're pretty damn slack about
consistency and they might say on it
that it's 0.1 EC and you get it and it's
1.6 or 1.2 and the plants have toxic
shock because it the Coco hasn't been
washed or buffered so it's all salty and
you're screwed you know so I've seen
that happen as a mistake in a learning
curve for them and I made it very clear
you don't unload Coco from a truck until
you've done this test where you run
water through it and test the EC period
that's all you got to do it's not a big
test it's a handful of cocoa some water
and does it change the AC okay don't
take it off the truck send it back and
then I was back like four months later
and they did it again that they bottled
the cocoa without wash is not washed or
buffered and the plants get toxic shock
within 48 Hours of being transplanted
you know I show up going what
up so and then I just said you know what
no more cocoa I just ruled it out I said
you can't get any more cocoa so that's
it the uh and now I make them just chop
off hemp stocks I said we just fill the
fields with hemp and other we use croia
as a cover crop as well so I say just
chop up the cotal area chop up the H
that's the medium no more no more cocoa
and since since we stopped buying cocoa
and just used medium we grow you know
it's easy to grow fiber at the equator
there's lots of fiber plants but the um
I've been growing even on my backyard
stuff the last few years probably three
years now I've been growing with all the
chopped up stocks of years before so it
only works if you had bigger stocks when
I had some really huge ones when I
started but I've been able to recycle
these soil and I just chop up all the
stocks and put it into it it's it's been
lazy medium but if you have plants that
are really Milo susceptible you might
get some in them so I've seen it affect
some that way cuz that's totally
uncomposted like just green stocks right
but uh overall it works Dy
I I'd rather just keep using it and not
use the plants that don't like it so
what kind of nutrients are you feeding
in that sort of
medium I mix up like I used to make
Steve's Special Blend as a dry mix or as
a wet mix and that's actually going to
be released again this spring under
licens by a company in BC here but that
was I had about 17 things in the dry mix
so all different meals like alala meal
corn meal kelp meal corn gluten you know
was the cornmeal the uh green sand rock
what is it Rock
fos yeah all kinds of you know back then
you had more of a range of guos and
another they not really allowed to sell
guos so it's we used to have Chilean
seabird guano fruit bat guano and then
regular bat guano and uh I do the bone
meal at like three different grinds so
you get have extra fine fine medium for
slower release I'm also starting to
pelletize that dry mix so you can use it
as more slow releas as well or just take
it out if you're doing a plant somewhere
you want to just take some pellets out
to throw in the hole for kind of slow
release so the U what else was in that
mix feather meal I made a vegan mix with
no animal products of course and then I
had the regular one had feather me meal
and bone meal and blood meal and it
um sunflower seed Hull as
0040 that's a good one um I would still
use some Epsom salts because you know
they're you need the magnesium and epsom
salts are naturally occurring salts
they're not like a strip super phosphate
or something I feel the like making that
good dry mix and then I add my homemade
kitchen compost so from all my eggs all
my banana peels and avocados and all all
the kitchen compost I put in the
backyard which I also use uh I have a
very tiny lawn on the one side of the
pool so I cut that and dump the grass in
there to layer it up so it's totally
just home homemade backyard compost but
if I wasn't using that I would be buying
worm castings and uh even that they're
not all created equal but if you find a
nice silky black R castings there's some
good brands out there all right Steve I
know you're getting tired and we're
running out of time here anyway so I
wanted to say thank you again for your
time like you have no idea how much I
appreciate it you're a huge Idol of mine
to a million other people that are in
here right now um and we really
appreciate you for all the work that
you've done and continue to do for
cannabis well thanks very much every
your appreciation is appreciated we'll
do it again man a great night thanks for
having me and thank you everybody in
patreon right now that came in and
shared your questions with Steve you
guys are lifeblood behind this and
you've you've created this from
absolutely nothing I've got nothing but
love for all of you guys so until next
time this is been doc CX saying good
night and grow
[Music]
right
[Applause]
[Music]
n