[Music]
what is up everybody and welcome to a
brand new episode of the CX and crew
podcast sessions we've got none other
than the man himself hul of uh scallywag
Seed Company let me redo that scallywag
seed company is going to be with us
today uh collector of old school
genetics huge librarian of genetics both
greeing and greeing and growing for
decades now uh let's give a big hand to
Paul how you doing today Paul hey
everybody how's it going good uh honor
to be here and thanks for having me
so let's get a little bit of insight
from you uh I know we got a lot of
people from the US in here today that
aren't familiar with scall wag why don't
you tell us a little bit about how you
got into cannabis what was your first
experience like uh so I'm uh just turned
44 this year so My First experience with
cannabis was
uh I was probably uh What uh 13 uh 13 or
13 or 14 uh and uh I grew up in a small
town outside Winnipeg Manitoba Canada so
we're in the Prairies kind of central
Canada and uh I grew up in a small town
that was fairly religious and fairly
conservative and with every kind of
religious conservative Town there's
always a town Badd or a town kind of
punk that every parent always warns you
not to hang out with and uh somehow I
just gravitated towards this guy yeah I
think a few of us are those guys but I
think I gravitated towards him uh in our
school that we were at our high school
we took a wood shop together and just
your classic like guy who who who wasn't
really academic and uh he was making
Bongs in wood in wood class while we
were making like key key chain holders
and stuff like that but yeah we ended up
connecting oddly uh through that class
and then I kind of would hang out with
him there's not a lot to do in these
towns so you kind of gravitate to just
finding things to do and uh I ended up
linking with up up with him one night
and always um I always had this in kind
of infatuation with cannabis the leaf
the uh like the the memorabilia from the
60s the covers of magazines with a pot
leaf I would just infatuate with the PO
Leaf I was kind of into the music that
promoted
can use and so I just naturally really
wanted to get into cannabis at that
young age and I kind of gravitated
towards him and uh because he was making
bongs and stuff in class and uh one
night we were all out together me and
another friend and he drove this really
old car like the batm the old Batmobile
and I remember he just picked me up uh
one time and we were just kind of
hanging out and he was like hey you want
to smoke a joint I was like do I ever
and so we end up smoking this joint
perfect and uh at the time it was like
the first experience it wasn't really
amazing but I just remember going home
that night and eating like a lot of food
and uh but I knew it was something that
I wanted to to try again and then
eventually finally found my my high and
was like yeah this is this is pretty
cool man and what was that was the high
that you liked well just the you know
like the the first time the first few
times you actually experience like the
actual effect because I know like my
first time you know he always heard as
you as you got into cannabis that a lot
of people in their first experience
didn't really experience a high it was
more just like uh a little bit of a
fuzziness and then I'm really hungry or
I'm tired let's go to bed and so I was
the guy that got no real effect but then
got really hungry after but I remember
achieving the very first time that
really first effective cannabis with a
group of friends when we had gone and
got some more and we all like we all
rolled up our own joint we were like oh
man we got our own joint each I remember
we smoked probably had enough actually
to consume on my own and I remember just
being like this is this is awesome man
and so yeah that first experience was in
hindsight too now I know that there was
a lot of like Mexi brick that was coming
through this like this kind of group of
people like just it like where we were
there was we were still in candas this
time right yeah we were still being
flooded with like brick weed that was
that was coming from Mexico there was a
lot of like South American Connections
that would come through through Paraguay
and a lot of these guys were like were
brining some of this Mexi like the South
American brick through right and a lot
of it also came from Mexico there was
some connections to that Mexico kind of
um a brick that we were getting as well
from the states or from from Mexi itself
and so this guy actually took these
seeds and grew them on their fluoresence
at his mother's house and that's the
first time I actually saw pot that night
too that we first experienced it and it
was like classic sativa to the to the to
the ceiling and you know later on found
out that yeah he was just breaking up
mexie brick and growing whatever you
could find there and it was like
obviously really sativa dominant but
yeah I just I still remember the flavors
like spicy I remember like it had that
just that look to it I remember and it
was just like yeah it was just
intriguing and it just it was something
that you knew you wanted to be a part of
and that's kind of where it all started
and I always say my dad like my dad
really got me started he was very
anti-cannabis but he had no idea that
subliminally he was uh in like probably
I was born in 79 probably in like the
earliest years of getting VCRs he got a
BCR and the first movies this guy rented
were chich and Chong like Up in Smoke
and that sort of stuff and so you know I
always say he really influenced me into
cannabis and so you know and he was very
anti-cannabis which was funny so but he
was a big comedian guys yeah thanks D
the show first time yeah exactly would
you say those first couple experiences
uh I didn't get high my first time
either it wasn't until my second time
that I really felt anything um was that
on the Mexican brick weat no this was
like I said we would always go to the
city which was Winnipeg so we were
always like we in a small town about 30
no 20 minutes from from Winnipeg so we
would often find someone who was 16 or
have someone in our group who was
driving and we'd all p money together
and like go there was a couple places
that were very famous in Winnipeg where
you could always always find Cannabis it
didn't matter what decade it was what
year what time of day what holiday it
didn't matter you could find weed there
and it was always a couple places one
was the merchant hotel which if anyone's
from this area they'll just know it was
classic we had a lot of gang activity
back in the day and this place was a
place where a lot of the guys would
would sell their Wares and they would
just run up to your car throw crumpled
up tinfoil into your lap and you would
just give them 15 bucks and you would be
on your way but if you [ __ ] around if
you [ __ ] around you found out these
guys would carry porcelain broken up
porcelain in their pockets and they
would they would shatter Windows if you
drove off without payment so it was a
pretty rough and quick exchange and then
a really classic place was the circle
and the circle was in Osborne Village
which is a pretty famous place and that
was another place where we would always
get weed but yeah we would pull our
money together go to these locations and
buy like really good Street weed for the
time and I remember it would just you
know the first few times we actually got
the effect it was so awesome and intense
that like we all knew me particularly
like this is something that I'm going to
have to definitely really really
experience for a long long time because
I enjoyed it so much so we don't really
know what we were smoking at the time
but Winnipeg was always um a pretty
decent place to get good quality
cannabis like we had a bunch of avenues
where you could get it you could either
get it through a lot of the street gains
like there's a lot of uh a lot of Youth
gains in our city um you know and then
we also had like a lot of the biker
connections here as well we had some
that were obviously operating here as
well some of the selections you you gave
us some of the crosses in here I had to
ask about the Topanga and then they told
me like the US name of what we'd call it
I was like ah damn yeah like the Tanga
to me is it's like I said like Canada
has so many good cuts and so many like
so much good cannabis history and like
obviously you know we're we're neighbors
and so like you know a lot of us look to
you guys so and and and do when it comes
to like historical cuts and stuff and so
like a lot of the I'm very blessed to
have friends that have a lot of people
that I've been able to to work with and
and call friends that we've been able to
trade cuts for over the years and so a
lot of my favorite things that I get to
consume or hold or grow or work with is
always us stuff like I mean I know that
we have some really cool stuff here and
I I don't know if it's because I'm just
here and I've been able to experience it
a lot but like I find through some of
the guys deals with that you know what
can I not get that's what I want well
right and then and then like you know
some of the US guys they tell me too
like you know some of the Canadian cuts
that we sent up that way like they
enjoyed I wanted everybody in the chat
to know really quick members are the
only ones patreon members are the only
ones allowed to uh interact with the Q&amp;A
if you're interested in that go check
out patreon and you can ask any question
that you want to have it live those
questions get answered and played at the
very end of the show so we'll do some
quick fire questions with their guests
and you can find that patreon link at
patreon.com
fordor
calex so what was the first cavar that
you came across that really had a
name um I mean probably I mean I was so
I started selling pot uh when I was in
my late teens and I had a really good
connection that worked over the west
coast and so we were able to get a lot
of like of the stuff that had names
early on uh but my first Growing
Experience like my very first cultivar
that I really like I I'm a blueberry
fanatic like a fanatic of blueberry and
have been since the day I first smoked
it heard about it saw pictures of it um
and so came with growing cannabis oh it
was and it was just just to see
something like that was just so unique
and so um and then I would get this West
Coast blueberry from my guy and it was
like I I said i' I'd come across like
good Street stuff before but like to
actually have something that had a
blueberry smell that was called
blueberry it just kind of blew my mind
and so uh the first thing I grew was a
blueberry um uh cut and it was a
commercial cut that we grew in a like a
commercial setup where we were we were
running a house and uh it was it was
awesome uh and then my very first clones
though that I was able to like secure
from someone who did selections or was
able to get something from a breeder was
uh one of my favorite things was some of
the early um like the very early DNA
stuff they had a couple things like sour
cream and stuff like that there was a
couple clones that a guy locally had
hunted he uh had a lot of uh uh
Expendable cash and he was able to buy
seeds at time that were so expensive at
the time and he did a lot of hunting and
he had this couple cuts that were really
really special to us and then some
really old Canadian Cuts Like renie R is
a really special cut up here that that a
lot of people love and it was it was a
local cut here we have and then we had
some old Cuts called champagne like a
hash plant champagne cut that was also
really good and stuff like that but yeah
it started as a commercial stuff so we
were really trying to get commercial
flowers at the time and so it was um it
was really hunt for that sort of Avenue
of what we wanted to grow and then the
conosur park came a few years later what
was the Renee does that have any
relation to the
Irene uh no so Rene Renee is a is a
Canadian cut um uh a prominent breeder
that maybe more people would have heard
of than me is a uh great Gardener uh
Matt Baron's great Gardener he kind of
the the Clone was around for a long time
before he made it kind of his Flagship
or one of his flagships but uh the great
Gardener yeah from Canada so he's known
for Barb uh Barber Bud orange Barb uh
Renee in a seed form they did uh I think
I think they did feminize the S1 did I
think and made S1 seeds of it I can't
remember what they did with the Renee
but he made it more famous and and more
prominent but it's a really unique cut
it's got a it's not the most potent cut
but it's just got this um this
absolutely pungent uh nose and flavor
that's kind of like um cool water after
shave it's got a really unique nose to
it and a skunky like it's really awesome
and it's it's like I said not the most
potent stuff but it's just a staple here
it's got such a robust nose and flavor
that it was always really easy to move
like you could always smell it through
the bag and it had a great look to it
popcorn bud uh and it had a like a a
good high but nothing that would put you
in the couch and so but that was one
that a lot of people ended up passing up
as you know the new trends started
coming in and those are the things that
I love scooping up or hunting and
getting hold of after they've been kind
of forgotten about because you know I
always find there's either a Revival in
in a lot of ways either just from from
Nostalgia or just people seeking out
tools that are a little bit less poly
hybrid hybridized and so this cut though
is a bit of a paint in the ass like a
lot of these old cuts to grow it's uh
finicky and old and takes a lot of care
but I actually just ran a a plant uh
it's SE just in the corner uh of it and
it just finished like it likes throwing
single nanners too so it's it sometimes
can be an ugly plant but it's just the
smell and flavor it's so nostalgic for
us and I just love it so much and it's
actually it outcrosses pretty fairly
well too uh We've outcrossed it to a few
things and even though it has that
tendency to throw single nanners it
seems to sometimes outcross really well
depending on who it pairs with adds
unique flavor and noses to it that you
just don't really there's nothing in it
in cannabis that smells like it in my
opinion and in a lot of other people's
opinion that that get to experience it
but it's one of those things that not a
lot of people know of so those are the
ones that you don't got to keep around
they're so good they'll get shared and
it'll stay around yeah and there's a
reason why people like want to seek it
out again like 10 15 years after they
had they had smoked it or you know it's
the best thing when you break it out at
a party here because it is a local
stream that people know
and so when you sometimes break it out
at like a Christmas party or like a
birthday or anniversary people are like
[ __ ] man like what is that and you're
like they're like I I've smoked that
before and you're like yeah it's renie
and they're like yeah I had a guy who
had a girlfriend and her guy used to
always bring this stuff over that's it
man we love that we smoked it for years
that's kind of rny to us there's a lot
of those strains but that's R to us my
favor experience yeah my favorite strain
going growing early on would have had to
been our early blueberry cut that we
were getting and we don't know where it
came from I know it was from the West
Coast but it was just it was tremendous
it was a really really awesome
cut okay that's interesting I haven't
messed around with the blueberries too
much I have
done uh a sativa leaning blueberry and a
broadleaf blueberry the one that I got
from Canada it was definitely a thin
Leaf it had longer inner nodes and it
had very purple buds I was actually
pretty impressed by that one nice it was
it wasn't the strongest stuff but was
[ __ ] it was tasty yeah we have few
like we have a pretty like deep history
of blueberry here uh there is a lot of
blueberry that and we like like you said
we have we have two distinct kind
of types and it's obviously a thin a
thin like a narrow leaf and then a broad
leaf and both are great and I I was
keeping a couple that have narrow and
Broad and we had to narrow it down a
little bit like we were talking with the
catalog being narrowed down and I stuck
with a few of my favorites but there's a
couple Fraser Valley blueberries like
there's a a broadleaf
the original broadleaf uh Fraser Valley
blueberry it's a harder plant to get now
it's almost extinct I think uh it is
phenomenal and then there's a very kind
of narrow Leaf sativa leaning uh
beautiful uh blueberry type sativa hash
plant that I held for a long time was
able to preserve and keep but it just
had a
absolutely like for me I like a really
potent stuff like potent High it just
had no hi to me really beautiful in
every other aspect great for breeding
great for just experiencing very light
no burnout but just didn't have any
potency for me and it's funny you get
rid of things and then suddenly people
are like that's what people want and so
like I've had to I've had to sadly be
like I don't have that anymore like I
can get it but I don't have it it's kind
of a pain to find but yeah so we have
lots and then I have my favorite
blueberry which is uh my winie the blue
which is my my Flagship blueberry cut
which I love so so tremendously much and
that has a little uh tribute to Winnipeg
rhy front because Winnie the Pooh was
kind of born and bred in in Winnipeg
anoba like the the famous character and
so it was named after Wie the blue so or
Wie the poops awesome I love it and what
was the cross on the Winnie of the blue
so win of the blue comes from a lot of
my work and some of my early stock and
uh earlier things that I was able to be
so lucky to get comes from we had this
group on the skunk magazine Forum uh
this was probably about uh 10 or 12
years ago there was this really special
time uh skunk Forum skunk magazine had
this forum where there was people like
uh myself and I mean I was just a noob
but there was people like the riv there
uh snoow High um uh just some tremendous
people and there was this elder a lot of
Elders too that were not known but were
really really influential in their own
right uh this old-time Elder called Time
Tunnel and Time Tunnel um is just a
really really special guy and he had
some really amazing just amazing uh work
and stuff that he had done over his
history of loving this plant and uh he
was able to we were it was a really nice
seed Exchange Place and so we exchanged
seeds and he gave me um some original
work called uh Time Tunnel zes blueberry
and at the time I was just you know
chasing everything blueberry and I ended
up running those seeds and we found this
um amazing plant called uh that I called
wining the blue and uh actually right
now we're doing a just preserving the
line again doing some F3 work on it
right now and that's what I was sexing
like I was telling you 13 minutes before
the show started still doing sex same
work here before the show started so so
we're doing some f3s now op f3s uh just
to preserve the line minimizing some
things out of bit but going to do a um a
pretty good op op I'm hoping to do maybe
15 females what we're down to and
probably about eight or nine males we're
just kind of eliminating eliminating
some things right now that we're not I'm
not really a fan of I'm trying to get
rid of all the earlier flow and stuff in
the blueberry males and try to keep the
ones that are holding on to their their
pollen which is a first I usually like
putting both in the line but this time
around we're going to try to eliminate
some of those ones that drop PA a little
bit
so we're going to give a few packs of
your seeds away at the end of the show
as well two packs are going to go to our
members one pack is going to come to
anybody that came to watch this show
we're going to roll little roulette
wheel and you guys will get some seeds I
was looking at these ones that you
donated for us which by the way again
thank you so much Beyond generous man um
honor man but how does the Winnie the
blue differ from the Dennis the
Menace so Winnie the BL blue is the
female is a female 80s blueberry uh from
Time Tunnel so like I said that's my
Flagship blueberry strain that's the one
that I found and you can go see the
actual documentation of it which is
really cool on IC mag uh there's a IC
mag thread called uh pollen bombing
episode one because I'm also a huge Star
Wars geek and uh it's a really cool
thing just to go back and see some of
the old work that you do and it was all
preserved there so you can kind of go
back and see some of the you actually
see the run where Winnie was found um
but Winnie the blue is the female 80s uh
Time Tunnel blueberry and then like I
had mentioned I was a blueberry fanatic
early on and so once those commercial
crops started I had always been looking
at magazines buying seeds and I started
really buying anything I could buy for
DJ Short Blueberry or any type of
blueberry cross and so we ended up
buying some earlier seeds from DJ and uh
Dennis and Menace was a variety or a
phenotype I found in some old DJ
blueberry seeds so not like old not like
everyone's like pre98 pre98 like no this
is like early 2000s probably 2005 2006
so the line was still pretty decent at
the time we were still getting some like
really nice blueberry fenos uh long
before the you know the LOM and the
Sandy LOM and the musky and the like
pork wine and all that sort of like
Flavor took over the line this still a
lot of blueberry so we found this really
nice blueberry mail and I named uh this
blueberry cut that I I used for for
years in my in my earlier blueberry work
um Dennis and Menace and my
father-in-law
Dennis was a real awesome guy but he was
also a menace and so we Nam it after him
Dennis and Menace and he passed away so
rest in peace so but
yeah that's awesome yeah and that's the
difference so one's female different
line Al together and there was some
projects done with both but Winnie the
blue over the years stayed uh as the the
library got narrowed down because it's
my Flagship I just there's no blueberry
plant I've experienced to this day that
I I truly love and and cherish more it's
so special to me I I really want to dig
in and hear so much about that that
Library I've heard you have an extensive
one and I'm sure there's a ton of things
that's going to tickle not only my goat
but a lot of people that are in here as
well because we got some older Growers
um sure before we get into that
though what was the change between you
growing cannabis to breeding cannabis
was there a time Gap or it kind of
coincide with each other I think just uh
like progression like for me like I
don't know I um I always like to I when
I get into something I get really into
something uh it's like that in in every
aspect it was like that with like drugs
it was like that with everything
everything music uh so I I really just
um and then for years like you said we
just look at the magazines and we're on
the forums and we're just we're just
it's I don't know it's it's just seeing
it's seeing work and seeing other
people's um drive and and dedication to
their work work that yeah I just saw
these cataloges and then started buying
seeds and then started doing you know I
started taking some university courses
for my professional job that I end up
ended up with early on and a lot of it
was science-based and so it was just
kind of went hand inand and so started
doing a little bit of like smaller hobby
stuff just to kind of make seed and and
see what it see what I could do and and
what what we could find and then realize
that like there's nothing more exciting
now in my life than like making
selection and then putting them together
and then doing either like some some
small inline breeding or just running
pheno hunts like feno hunts to me to
this day doing it now for for quite some
time like there's nothing more exciting
in the world than than a feno hunt like
especially when it's your own work like
I always say be your favorite breeder
like or be your favorite seed maker and
if you truly if you truly have a
calendar that's just filled with your
own seed starts to me that's like you've
reached already the PIN that you know
every breeder or seed maker should reach
it's not about getting your seeds out
there to me it's not about you know
making money to me it's about loving the
work that you're doing enough that it is
always on the calendar of the seed
starts like sure you start other
people's work but the real excitement is
right in your own garden right in your
own notebooks and just seeing your work
in front of you to me it's there just
it's what keeps me going in the darkest
days when you're stuck at your 9 to5 and
you're just like you know and you're
you're going broke from all the shipping
you're covering and you're just like
you're you're struggling a little bit
but you're like dude I have a fenal hunt
going on in my room and it's just
amazing right now and that's to me
that's the doing this this one's doing
this this one's got yeah like cool thing
like week like week six week six feno
hunt on a shorter like uh uh BL like or
a hybrid like week six seven like to me
that is just there's no happier time in
the world of making seeds and running
your work and looking at your lines and
you know making plans and goals from
that that that feno hunt like that is
the most special time and I have one
going on right now it's just it's a it's
it's just electric it's just to me why
why you should be doing it and obviously
getting it out and having other people
experience it is just it's an honor and
it's just icing on the cake but it's
just like really at the end of the day
this should all be about your own
enjoyment of what you're doing or like
why do it like don't do it because you
want to make money or you wantan a
following or you're trying to impress
this guy or impress this group or crew
like it doesn't matter have fun man and
just like do what you want man and
that's that's what it should be about so
and that's what it's been about been
blessed for that but that was the
progression was just seeing better and
better things as things went on like oh
my God I was kind of hoping this would
this would be what I would see in this
little bit of work and little bit of
adjusting I did to this one line and I'm
seeing that now not maybe in what I
would like to see in the greater scheme
but I'm just seeing little things that I
was hoping to see is now present in this
further work and so it just progression
progression progression and then as you
get more in tune with people in the
community and and better relationships
form then it's just like I said I've
been so blessed not have to pay for
seeds for so long and I had a raid where
I lost my seeds and so I had to rebuild
and it was just literally because of
these relationships you form with other
people who just love the plant love the
community love sharing want progression
in friends and other breeders and other
seed makers aren't trying to hinder
anyone's progress it's just an open
sharing type community so I've been able
to rebuild and with the better genetics
that come in you see better things
better Line work and it's just a
progression all the time and so it was
really about just seeing that sort of
work and just wanting to do more and
more and more and then also getting a
better catalog better access to genetics
and then really at the end of the day
also kind of saving some money because
there was a point there where and I'll
never take a hit at anybody charging
$1,000 for their seeds if that's what
you want to do man that's your that's
what you do but like there was some
seeds that people I knew were paying
like $1,000 dollar for and you know even
up even up so so yeah it was a little
bit of everything to really progress and
to start doing the uh the breeding work
and Seed seed making
work I hear that joint be enrolled right
now I've got excellent yeah I've been
trying to get out for 15 20 minutes we
are almost the halfway mark and that's
usually where I like to smoke so if
you're down you light up that joint I
don't have a joint ready and I don't
want this equipment around but I will
definitely dab with you we're doing
flower guy it's just way easier to dab
Jo dude I'm a joint guy I smoke joints
all the time uh [ __ ] all day and
they're always like uh was sitting with
some friends and we were laughing uh
they're like how big are your [ __ ]
joints man oh nice man wow yeah that's
beautiful dude Beauty what is it it's
called Tropic
Thunder okay cool man cool I have no
idea what it
is yeah I'm doing some Siri chem which
is uh the Siri Paul which is the Afghan
Pakistani times the kemong 91 fem and
this has been like this has been just my
obsession for the last like year and a
half but this last run has been just a
feno hunt and I'm just obsessed obsessed
trade oh dude I would
love working with the the chem family
because it brings that that really heavy
potency and some of those traits like
the uh that you see in like you know the
sours and the the the rubbers and the
like the skunky notes and this the you
know just that funk and I just love the
potency and so I find this stuff is just
uh it's right on my alley man yeah
that's my type of stuff too um I've
never worked with any of it I've worked
with skunks but I've never worked with
the Kims I heard they were really picky
I did not want want to start with pain
they're real pain but like the 91 like
the 91 to me is um and just like I said
I have no place in this plant it's just
been something that's found its way
towards me and I've been blessed enough
to hold and I'll always say that all the
shadows and the accolades to these guys
that held this plant since 91 uh
everyone that had their hand in it
there's some really famous people and
some really well-known guys that have
really put their life on the line to
keep this Kem dong anyone safe and and
uh you know all all shout outs and and
athletes to those guys like I said just
a small spoke in the wheel that just
cherishes this plant and loves this 91
but I know that really at the end of the
day I just was lucky enough to
experience it so shout out to those guys
and we all know who they are I don't
have to say their names I won't name
drop those guys are just uh I mean
amazing community members and breeders
and you know they hold that place
rightly so my God that was delicious
sorry about that yeah know man like I
said I uh I like the ACD stuff but
there's still like there's still those
uh sweet trop and like there's so much
of it now that you can find some really
amazing flavors in this uh in all this
new stuff that's kind of about right now
and been around for a while I'm 100%
with you because just like I told you
I'm really into skunks I'm really into
chems I even like a good
OG yeah if I had the choice I would only
choose fruity about 25% of the time
probably yeah and I'm I'm with you one
of my favorite breeders up to this point
has been Dynasty genetics which does
like a lot of fruit you know so if I am
going to go that way I'm going to go
that way but my thing more than anything
um is pheno hunting land races so that's
why I'm not as scared anymore to work
with the chems as I was before I did
want to get some uh some thoughts
directly from you have you ever had a
failed breeding
project where you just scrapped it
there's so many that you just scrap
that's the problem with it and then what
do you do with those seeds right you
just have this like [ __ ] fridge full
of [ __ ] and like right one of the most
legendary dudes archive I mean he's got
some funny stories where he's just like
he's got fridges of stuff and I mean
archive is amazing he's got I mean I
would find it hard to believe that he's
got anything sitting around that's not
amazing but I mean like yeah I mean
there's you know it's hard I just I just
kill them like I just get rid of them or
you know sometimes people are just like
they want to grow a large population of
something and they just want to do it
and they don't want to pay for seeds and
so you just explained to them like dude
I can give you a bunch of seeds but they
didn't turn out the way I like them and
they they have this kind of negative
thing that's why I didn't want it and
you know but of course I have a lot of
stuff that has just been scrapped and
that's part of it so what would you say
to somebody that's newer newer to
breeding um that had a failed project or
whatever and that was really
disheartening uh to them coming from
your standpoint it seems like to this
day you going through feno hunts is a
huge lot in life that brings you Joy um
how do you continue on with that
attitude after filal
projects well you just have to get into
this knowing that you're getting into
something like breeding you're working
with you're working with things that you
don't really get to see into until all
this work is invested in it right it's
kind of like any art form so you really
have to have a passion for it and have
to understand getting into this that
dude it's like I said you you you can go
broke doing this like you know even
though people might you might have a
following or people have a following I
mean you have to understand there is
huge things that you give up to do this
like it's not a uh it's not a fun job
like just running a commercial Garden or
a a connoisseur Garden if you want to
use that term where you're growing you
know 100 plants and you're you're
growing 25 you're growing four different
plant or four different cultivar or
whatever it is you're growing this
amazing always exciting beautiful
flowers and you're processing these
beautiful flowers whether you're making
hash or flower whatever you're doing
usually yeah and Seed seeds is like can
be really [ __ ] boring man and like
you know you can lose money doing it and
so it's part of the game man and so it's
just like anyone that chooses whatever
pathway in this community I mean you
have to really sit back and in life and
just be like is this these are the pros
these are the cons this is what can
happen negatively this is the positive
and you just have to figure if it's
something that you're going to do but
make sure you understand getting into
this you are going to have projects that
just stink and you're going to be like
[ __ ] I just wasted eight months
pollinating you know keeping mothers
around uh taking clones of of phenotypes
that I thought might be awesome and they
all just [ __ ] stink uh you know and
you learn from it but hopefully the
doesn't happen as often as it it can
happen and hopefully you're lucky enough
to like bring some sort
of you know pre-int telligence to the
game where you did some reading and some
research and some maybe some Theory
based stuff and then you're applying it
to your practice and it's just like
anything that just the more you apply
the more Theory makes sense the more
Theory you can add and the more
application you can get uh into your
thing and get better and better and
better and like progressions always the
plan and so even if you're Notting don't
quit like I said as long as you're
having fun do it you could keep making
shitty shitty projects but as long as
you having fun I mean you know try not
to share the shitty projects that was
directly for me thank
you I got really lucky with my first few
breeding projects they came out exactly
like I wanted to and I was on an
F3 and the the progyny in that group
just sucked it was just two male
dominant in the whole [ __ ] thing and
it disheartened me so much I just didn't
even continue on with that line and I
got people ask me to this day can I get
some of those seeds I'm like no I scrap
that [ __ ] I mean to me scrapping a
project because it's something that you
don't want versus something that's
problematic is different like you can
there's definitely I have like I have so
many projects in the fridge that like
there's no problems with it but they're
just not like I want it accurate and it
turned out fruity or I wanted short
plants and they turned out tall like
stuff like that that I'm I'm still
holding on to I'm happy to give away in
large amounts to people that need seeds
but again I always explain like hey
they're they're not what I wanted that's
why I'm giving them to you for you know
your for whatever you want to do with
them so but no I definitely hear you man
so that that's a good perspective to
have on it it wasn't really problematic
I just made the wrong selection I need
to go back and rework it at that point I
had no idea or didn't even think to use
multiple males and isolate the pollen on
different branches or anything like that
yeah one
run but like I said you learn right and
then you reformulate and you replan and
then you do something again or you do it
over again right with better success and
one of the big things adjustments was uh
doing uh S1 work and so you do regular
breeding with regular males for you know
a long time and then you suddenly are
tasked with learning something new and
you know hopefully you you have some
sense and it it's easy to kind of take
on the theory which it was and then you
got to apply it and so one thing with
selfing is doesn't matter who's doing
the selfing what breeder it is they
could be the best and you just sometimes
run into issues and it's just you know
it's it's part of that kind of Realm of
of of making seeds with with selfing
projects and everyone struggles with it
I've heard the best of the best talk
about it and I just had a problem here I
was trying to do a whole room with a
certain female that was uh or a certain
uh reverse plant and uh it just did not
draw pollen and I had a time frame iom
was really trying to stick to and so
thank God you have some backup stuff
that you've collected that you know you
can use in case you need a backup and so
yeah we changed from a chem dog room we
went to a blueberry room and so
everything got hit with blueberry
instead so you know and that's just the
way it is so yeah part of it damn I'm
learning on this episode I hope
everybody over there in chat is holy
[ __ ] so let's dig in a little bit more
to this library that you've collected
over all these years actually actually
let's go back really quick because I
can't say that I there's no way I can go
over it and say I missed it so can we
talk about the raid or not oh for sure
man yeah so for sure so we Canada so
Canada legalized in
2016 I think it was uh October of 2016 I
should know but I [ __ ] sometimes you
don't remember things but I think it was
September October 2016 Canada legalized
I had been growing um I had been a nurse
for uh almost a decade and was growing
pot uh for my own medical consumption
and uh part of my University as nursing
was I really really gravitated towards
nursing law and like justice and so part
of that was learning about um harm
reduction and things like that and I
come from
2016 2016 yes legalization was 2016
too all right that I know so yeah raid
was a same 2016 but yeah so part of the
nursing
um sorry I got interrupted but yeah raid
was 2016 so I was a nurse at the time
and I just didn't want to get I I I felt
that it was just
um it wasn't right to have to go so the
way it worked is you had to get a doctor
to sign for your medical and uh the only
way you could really get a medical in
Canada at the time was you had to have
like like a really terrible ailment like
you have to have like some sort of
wasting disorder from either uh AIDS or
a cancer diagnosis where you were
getting something for for for your
symptom management right and so I suffer
from horrible anxiety depression and
have for my entire life and I just
couldn't get signage from a doctor and
the only way I could do it was I have to
go to BC to get a signage and you have
to pay $5,000 you see a doctor who
doesn't even know you and just signs you
a paper right and so I was growing
illegally but I was quite okay with it
because I knew I wasn't breaking I
wasn't hurting anybody I was applying my
own medicine and I was really doing my
own thing while I was while I was a
nurse and going through my nursing
school but for the the part of my
nursing career and so 2016 rolled around
legalization was literally around the
corner in uh in October and September uh
my wife and I were leaving the house uh
and uh boom we got arrested I mean we
got arrested so we got arrested there
and then a raid followed obviously so
they raided my house and uh they had
been following or watching our house for
about a week and it was all based on a I
have great neighbors I live in a great
Community it's like a really awesome
like middle class Place everyone's
really friendly uh and I uh I used to do
everything I could to mask smell but I
mean I'm growing really [ __ ] stinky
plants and I'm doing everything I can
like going above and beyond charcoal
filters but I'm coming up with my own
homemade things to like dryer sheets
outside and owna own a tanks and just
everything you can imagine but there's
still a bit of an odor and so someone
kept complaining about smell one
neighbor and it's more of like a a
business and so it's really not people
that live here but it's just you know
they seem inconvenience with this SM at
their business and so kept complaining
and then we started getting watched for
about a week and then uh the raid hit
and so they had been they had been
watching us for a week and they thought
they had a pretty big operation because
of the smell they were smelling it was
quite pugging they they felt and so when
they raided us they were quite
disappointed because like I said most of
my grow was always mother plants and and
a library of stuff that wasn't flowering
so my flowering area was quite small but
yeah they hyperinflated everything in
the paper that it was a real big outfit
and you know all this sort of bad stuff
but in that process I mean I lost all my
mother plants and my seed collection
which at the time was I mean I I still I
still get sad it's like losing something
that you just he never get back right so
yeah that was a raid and they like
literally they arrested US I I I ended
up having to we ended up spending you
know short of $100,000 for our legal
fight um I was ended up getting house
arrest I was lucky really lucky to get
house arrest because at the time we had
mandatory minimums for growing and I was
just a little bit under the the
mandatory minimum for 5 years but there
was still a mandatory minimum of a year
in prison and I was able to have a good
lawyer and really fight and pay and get
six months house arrest or a year house
arrest but six absolute and then yeah
ended up walking away from nursing as a
result of it because there was a fight
there for professional misconduct which
is part of being a professional but uh
yeah today I ended up uh and part of it
was also getting some cannabis uh
contracts in il legal world so it was a
good transition and that's kind of how
things played out but uh yeah it didn't
really stop me because I end up getting
my ACM part ACM PR about uh two months
after the raid I finally broke down and
was like okay this is serious so let's
get let's get some protection yeah and
and and War happened the first time man
yeah but I mean like a lot of us dealt
with it I was lucky I know friends that
did five years for for cannabis
so well you know in my mind it's
horeshit for a day really
like at the end of the day we're growing
a plant you won't you shouldn't be able
to arrest me for canis anymore than you
can for a tomato for sure man and it and
it really like like I had a 16-year-old
daughter like and you know we were smart
like we're I have a we have a pretty
pretty smart family like we knew there
was always potential and so like just
like a family makes a fire plan it's
just so odd that when you're a cannabis
family like you have to make a raid plan
but thank God we had because my daughter
was just a trooper and my wife who is
the most I mean I like I owe everything
every everyone who who does this who
makes this commitment like if if you
have a partner in your life that that
that's been with you through some of
this stuff like she's been through my
RAID you just
all everything is dedicated to them
because like I wouldn't be here if it
wasn't for her the the [ __ ] she did for
me when the raid happened uh the the
just seeing all that stuff my daughter
just how supportive they were how stoic
they were How brave they were it's just
you know if you have a partner that that
stands beside you and you do what we do
I mean like I said they're the real
Allstar so but yeah it was so hard on
our family man uh they just tear your
house apart and I remember my biggest
fear when I like was getting uh
interviewed as was like I thought they
they not only they take all my plants
but I thought they took all my soil and
so I'm a living soil guy and I i' had
been like that is my like going on my
eth year at the time of making my living
soil and so I was so worried out of all
the things that was also gone with my
soil and remember they were just looking
at me like I was [ __ ] insane that I
was worried about soil but yeah it was a
really uh scary time man it's still hard
to get over so it's crazy it just
changes you you become a little bit more
like jaded that's a that's the word for
it right there too j but this community
the community came through I'm telling
you I got my license two months later
[ __ ] had no seeds no clones left I
tried to salvage like every story you
hear I in the back alley I was able to
pull a couple [ __ ] clones off of dead
mother that they forgot they [ __ ]
they RI me down man so but within within
two months I had every clone I had
shared and and had at the time which was
a pretty extensive library at the time
not only that I have most of those seeds
that you know maybe there were some I
couldn't get back but I still had stuff
that was given to me that I knew came
from other people's special special
places that they would normally not part
with but it just shows the level of you
know if you're dialed into this
community and you're you're actually not
trying to like [ __ ] it and you got good
people and good groups with you it's
amazing it's amazing place to be a part
of so but yeah man we're all stronger
from the [ __ ] so at the end of the day
like I said life [ __ ] happens and it's
just you just got to be happy where you
are and I am let's dig into your library
really quick because I've got all your
seeds here and I'm looking through some
of these and there's some holy [ __ ]
names in here there really is well like
I said lucky very lucky to have friends
and like very lucky to be trusted with
stuff man but like I said it goes two
ways my favorite thing to do in life is
to be able to give something back to
somebody that they've lost and that's
that's the most I mean the most
honorable thing and the most honored
thing you can feel is when someone
reaches out to you and they're like dude
I lost my breeder cut of so and so and
you're like hey man just give me your
address it's out Monday so that's the
coolest thing but yeah it's just the
circle of blessing man like you you got
to really put that time and and
investment and Trust in and then it pays
back man and it's just that reciprocal
awesome thing that this community
produces it's so unlike any other
community we don't have to name we don't
if you want to you think you can do that
you wanna we can of course we can talk
your voice you just talk I'll I'll
answer whatever you got there whatever
you I was just gonna ask you uh name
like your top five favorite
but it's up to you you run through the
list run through the list I mean I could
name my top five for sure so I mean like
obviously my favorite plant of all time
is the kmog 91 it's all-time favorite
and like I said I have no hand on that
plant I'm just lucky we don't got to ask
the desert island question that's it for
you yeah I mean like grown well though
because like it can be grown it can be
butchered like it needs to be really
well grown and that comes with really
getting to know her well and like I said
I just am lucky to be a steward to her
like I have no hand in this plan I just
affected me in a way that I was lucky to
be able to experience so that's my
number one I mean I really am a huge fan
of uh like Canadian Kush plants or like
like we have a few that kick around here
so like I'm a huge fan of like and I
mean obviously like these plants
originated in the US so we can't take
any credit for it but like purple kush
the original Purple Kush
like there's a there's a few of those
original cuts that that to me are just
phenomenal yeah and there's a Canadian
guy uh direwolf who's just like a true
OG too he's amazing guy in so many ways
uh he he's got a really special uh uh
clone only of a purple kush that I think
is probably the best Purple Kush cut
I've ever consumed it's just phenomenal
and then there's like you know some
certain some other cuts too like
Garberville and there's the uh there's a
few with the SF and uh just a whole
bunch of stuff but Purple Kush and then
we have a famous cut Here Pink Kush
which is like people will tease you if
you like it like because it's so [ __ ]
well known here and everybody is just
like done with it like oh no more pink
Kush but I don't care what anyone says
it's such a special plant so that I love
the master yeah Master Kush to me like
the there's two two uh really well-known
fenal of Master there's like the short
one that's hard really hard to find
there's a tall lankier master I love the
tall lanky Master Kush uh and then I'm
an OG like I mean to me the best plants
are ogs too so there's some OG plants
that I really really cherish we have a
couple Canadian ones here there's like
Roi OG which like a purple Cali OG it's
really good and then like the obviously
like the the the American ogs are the
best but yeah I guess it's really hard
to narrow five down I don't know if I
could do it actually yeah no I can't but
those are like I'm stuck on OG now
because I wasn't expecting that so out
are your ogs what what would be top
three ogs I think uh probably the best
OG that I've ever consumed I was able
just to finally get and that would
probably be like the M1 OG or the
SBS so like the sour best [ __ ] ever also
known as like my number one OG the M1 OG
uh which I think is it's it's true its
true name that to me is um really really
special and then I'm finding to like um
we have this Canadian uh OG cut which is
Roi OG and it's only called Roi OG
because there's a a producer of
concentrates in BC called Roi
concentrates and he got his hand on this
cut so no one seems to really know what
it is but it comes from California and
it's just got this really light purple
coloring to it but it's just got this
tremendous gas flavor that I really like
and then you know there's all your
Classics like San Fernando ghost but
like I don't hold all of those um but
those are the probably my favorite ones
that I hold
I got about the Irene at all yeah I mean
the Irene is there's a couple guys in
Canada that have done a lot of work with
it and really really enjoy it uh a few
friends hold it um but like I said it's
uh it's it's it's something that's being
really enjoyed and and used by a couple
people that I know that are either doing
work with it or they're they're doing
something with it so I know it's
tremendous it's phenomenal but it's just
not something that I I hold or work with
it but I know that it's it's a it's a
legend in its own right and it's here
it's floats around for sure the I
noticed you mentioned archive earlier I
think one of my favorite ogs was the rud
boy that he made there's just something
about that that's it's a floral OG but
right that's what makes it original to
me you know it's got still got OG
properties to it but I love that flavor
we have his Hazmat OG I think it's
archives does Hazmat so and that just
came from another really special friend
of mine who uh I'm really lucky to to
know from the US and he's a really
influential guy in my library he's been
so generous uh sending me some stuff
that like you know I would never be able
to get my hands on if it wasn't for him
so I was just able to get uh some hmat
OG uh cuts from him and they've been in
quarantine and now they're out in the
bedroom they should be getting flowered
soon uh but I like I said he's a special
guy he always gets uh really special
hard to find us stuff that I'm just so
lucky to get my hands on so and we also
able to get just the um I guess it's the
the crinkle cut um Legend uh Legend Kush
Legend OG but Legend cush crinkle cut
and I think there's another grower on
Instagram I won't name drop but he grows
it quite quite well in his room and
there's a really good threads of it on
IC mag and that's another cut that uh I
just like I can't believe I got my hands
on that I'm able to to start working
with so that thing to me is just uh
unbelievable so that's the one with the
leaves that like do the wave thing yeah
it's got a weird crinkle to it just like
a distinctive feature kind of like uh
some other cuts that we that we know of
that do that and it's uh but yeah it's
uh it's it's mistaken as an OG I think
there's a a chem dominant uh crinkle cut
uh OG Kush but this is like a it's more
of a uh Legend Kush they call it like
the really guys who grow it and know it
really well versus OG so but it's really
special like I mean really really
special I love and then I'm finding my
own and that's like I said that's that's
been the really cool thing is um a lot
of the stuff um that I work with so I
find working with the dog the 91 a lot
of its its pairings or S1 work with it
like I love running large uh numbers of
Kim dog 91s ones because I find in that
population like I have found things that
have become my favorite OG types or sour
type plants that I just haven't named
but they have like a number or a some
sort of marking in my garden that like I
just love so much I'm I'm smoking more
than like the original mother like you
know cuz it's got a little bit more
bigger and it brings a little bit more
flavor and it's just like you know it's
got the high but it's got a little bit
something else to it and now like I said
the carry uh the Siri chem line which is
the Siri Paul is bringing that really
special Afghan Pakistani um from the
mother I used to the to the 91 and so
you're finding like all the traits that
I love in the 91 outcrosses and outlines
but now I'm getting this amazing like
structure and and some some other
special Notes From The Afghan py so so
yeah having this beautiful library is so
wicked
but
yeah and so stuff like that is is Canada
so breeder Steve sweet skunk so everyone
knows breeder Steve and he has this
tremendous clone only sweet skunk it's
not to be confused with Island sweet
skunk which is a seedline but breeder
Steve's Sweet skunk clone only is this
beautiful Haze Type U cultivar that's
very high pining it's got a beautiful
Pine it's got really potent uh uh
effects long lasting high long legs on
it
and uh it's just a tremendous plant and
it's like I said if you're able to get
your hands on it and grow it it's one of
these plants that like it's got that old
school everything we love Long Legs
great High great flavor great nose great
effect and uh the Jihadi Kush was I'm
lucky enough to uh to work with and have
uh Charles Scott as a a mentor of mine
and friend uh reeferman and we've been
friends for years I was a tester and and
and uh did some uh pictures for some of
his ads like years ago and so we've just
been buddies for a long time and he's
traded a lot of stuff and given me a lot
of stuff and he had this line jih Kush
that he called jiot Kush and it was um
also like an a-pack nepes line so it had
some really nice kind of land race type
based uh origin type uh p1s to it and so
that line is really cool it's got this
like hazy old school type uh uh clone
only from Canada mixed with this like
Afghan pachy nepales uh line that
reeferman did and the the siblings are
really interesting you get really kind
of everything from across the board but
all old school kind of notes and flavors
so tremendous as Joey Diaz would say
tremendous one back off guys D yeah like
I mean you I mean like I said the fridge
is like I'm moving in so many new
directions with like doing the S1 work
and the selfing stuff and the femin
stuff that I have this fridge now of so
much regular stuff that's just kind of
sitting around and so uh lately when
I've been getting some some really
awesome uh people that are are are
are grabbing larger amounts I just
[ __ ] like yeah [ __ ] thank you so
much man I just throw in like just a
ridiculous amount of freebies of stuff
that's just laying around so hit me up
man for sure whatever you want extra
I'll hit you up for sure I appreciate
that more than anything man you have no
idea and likewise if there's anything I
can get you I've got an extensive
Library sadly most of my stuff is mostly
land races but I got some good other
stuff too yeah but land race is great
and for sure man we'll talk it's [ __ ]
Joy just won't go out I'm okay with
going through chems now is because I've
gone through a few different land race
feno hunts now and it doesn't take you
more than a couple runs to realize most
of this is trash and I'm lucky if I find
something that I really really like out
of it and then at that point I'm really
really lucky if I find something that I
like that outcross as well yeah so
that's that's land races like I was in
this like I mean we all go through this
phase and some times longer than others
and we were in a long phase I had
Partners in other um Crews that we had
like my partner from uh golden uh or
from Green Bieber genetics we were on
this kick for land race like we were
running everything we get our hands on
and like land race is just what you said
it's like generally it's it's unworked
and it's just like it's it's hit or miss
you got to run through so much to find a
gem but when you do find a gem it's a
[ __ ] Gem and a lot of the times you
know if it's got some of the stuff
you're looking for in that line that you
were kind of either heard of or had
experienced early on sometimes they work
as tremendous breeding tools or
outcrossing tools and the the stuff that
you use them for you may not even
consume it that often but you do use it
and keep it around because it is such a
treasure such an amazing tool to use in
in further things that you do so I have
a lot of stuff like that where I love to
consume it but don't want to consume it
every day oh yeah but definitely keep
keep it around strictly because I love
working with it I know its value and and
using it to make things better in other
projects so just being a hobby grower
for many years I I found out pretty
quick that I really love growing work
lines of stuff that I love but some of
my favorite plants to grow were some
like you said reeferman earlier uh snow
High some of those guys that were doing
the early just straight hybrid work
before everything was poly hybridized
you know or at least fighting the the
poly hybrids that were there and just
going back to good old classic hybrids
and some of those plants were like my
favorite plants to grow and that was
something that I was like I want to
create that with different strains
around the world that a lot of people
aren't using you know something
different something new I I think
cannabis more than anything right now um
in the modern Market needs more
diversity than anything for sure yeah I
mean we're I mean we're in a period
right now like I mean everyone complains
about it and like you know I don't I
don't like to Sho on any cut or any
variety or any strain like I love I mean
cookies was so influential in my like
there was a period where I just like
obsessed with cookies like I'm sure some
people were some people [ __ ] on it like
I'm not judging there's good cookies out
there everything's got a place I I'm
just speaking from a standpoint of how
much diversity we had back then and now
it feels like more people are just
trying to get seeds out there by
breeding the same families together and
you know make it a little bit different
because you got sick of this we'll bring
some new genetics into it and there's a
new line we have a legal Market here and
like if you look at the legal market
trends it's like it's I mean it's
literally saturated with like the same
the same looking the same like effect
the effect creating types of varieties
that like we would all consider hype
modern day strains but it's you know you
just don't want to [ __ ] on anyone that's
making that type of stuff like cuz
what's happening is a lot of these um
Canadian places are buying clones now
from American clone uh type places or
places at Rabel to get like American
hype genetics into the Canadian scene
and now they're like that's all you see
here or they're buying like they're
spending a fortune on like really good
breeders work from the states but the
work is all kind of pushing towards that
direction of this like same saturated
type of thing you're seeing where it's a
lot of beautiful looking it all looks
the same and we all know what I'm
talking about like the type of structure
the bud structure the leaf structure
color it all looks the same it kind of
smokes the same it looks the same smells
the same but I find it's got like we
consume a lot of the the market just to
see like what's going on and also we're
able to see some of the Clones that come
through from the states that are more of
these hype clones like we've kept some
of them short term some we just pass on
some friends get it we smoke that so we
get to experience a lot of them but I
just like it's not something I really
want to consume very often they're nice
but not something I want and I agree I
just love the old school stuff that
you know has more longevity yeah like
that we're all wanting to go back to or
this just continually recycles we're I
don't know if this will recycle it just
continues to like saturate you know
flavor less constant Berry and constant
this and constant that I was talking to
breeder Steve not too long ago we did an
episode with him and he hit the nail on
the head with me he said I don't know
about you I've grown tens and hundreds
of thousands of plants and he said all
of these 30 centers plus that's when
they're all starting to kind of taste
the same you're getting really high
amounts of like THC in there and that's
the dominant that we're breeding towards
and a lot of them are getting that
flavor yeah what are what are your
thoughts on the modern market and what
do we have to do to to save it do you
think it's fine as it is or do you think
we could better it from bringing in some
older
genetics well I think like our Market
here in is a great example of what you
saw in Colorado when Colorado went legal
is we're having this
inflated uh uh THC and like choid uh
profiles by like labs and so it's become
this competition for for for customers
by Labs so clients are trying to take on
clients as much as they can or keep
clients and so everything here is
inflated so there's so many of us that
don't even believe that there's really
30% that are kicking around or like
obviously as many that you see I mean
you see coas here that are just they're
laughable you know and then it's just
like that's that's that's a start so we
have to get like good testing and
accurate testing in and then we can
really we can really get away from like
really like numbers are so important
don't ever get me wrong like I'm a data
guy I get it numbers are so important we
need them for a lot of reasons but we
really want to know about effect and how
that correlates to the numbers and so if
we can get accurate numbers then we can
start doing that we can see what people
want to smoke and what is consumers like
what they what motiv to purchase stuff
because that's really the end game for
everybody right now right we have this
whole Market guided toward 30 centers
everyone's trying to buy 30 percenters
and I find that I agree if you get real
testing down like you'll see that
cultivar that were testing at 20% rely
breaking 20% 7even years ago are now
well over like 28% or 30% so we get the
accurate testing down and I agree we can
bring in plants that are really 177% Tac
plants but have really interesting choid
profiles and then that at least we can
say like hey you're you're enjoying a
plant that's 177% or even 133% but it's
got this interesting camid profile and
that's why you're really enjoying it and
now the way our Market Works in Canada
buyers won't even look like you you get
people requesting on like the buyers uh
side of it and they're like we only want
we're looking for this this large amount
from so and so or this sort of thing but
it has to be has to be COA of of 28% or
above THC and so you can't even enter
stuff that's special into the market
right now that is maybe 17% like a true
177% and that sort of thing right now so
that all has to kind of fall in line for
us to really progress and do something
like that is is actually good for this
this kind of legalization thing that's
going on for everybody and so I would
like to see we're kind of seeing it
because there's more requests I'm seeing
more requests for like a lot of the
older stuff and so like it's a lot of
the people are kind of kind of coming
back or they're realizing that there's a
market of connoisseurs that they can't
bring to the dispensaries right now or
they can't bring to their brands that ex
that want the experience of like hey if
I'm gonna buy you know like let's say um
San Fernando valoi kush like I want it
to actually be the San Fernando valoi
kush and I know that when I go buy it
right now it's going to be some [ __ ]
who knows right hyp that they added yeah
yeah it's just so that sort of stuff and
so not only is accurate lineage of like
said cultivar important going to be
important but also real testing so like
when those things kind of come in line
then we can really start entering
interesting stuff that people will
consume because it won't be about 30%
THC or 9% T beans on a flower you're
like get the [ __ ] out of here man like
that barely exist if not doesn't so done
it a million times for sure but I mean
we're we're see this is resen yeah we're
seeing more people requesting and
wanting old stuff which is which is
promising but again it's as much as it's
promising those two things have to come
into line for this to really be
something that can happen because so far
still it's like I want 30 plus percent
you see 40% flower which is like if you
promote that you should just be like
silence that's just ridiculous
ridiculous promotion 40%
this has been an amazing episode Paul I
want to thank you again so much before
your time before we get going here
though I want to run through some of
these questions from the patreon members
for
sure right first up we've got dank Pandy
says do you know the genetics behind the
Lindsay
OG uh no well see ogs are funny in
Canada what happens a lot in Canada is
an OG will come from somewhere and it's
just [ __ ] renamed right so that's
like what happen the ROI OG there's a
lot of ogs that like that's
unfortunately what happens everywhere
but so like stuff like stuff like
Lindsay OG comes from uh Lindsay Ontario
Liberty Farms so all credit has to go to
Liberty farms uh you can check their
name you can just research uh Google
Liberty Farms Canada and you'll see
they're from Lindsay Ontario I better be
[ __ ] right with Ontario or I'm dead
but I'm pretty sure it's on I'll be dead
sorry worst Canadian ever oh dead but uh
Liberty farms uh and they entered
competitions they've won but no one
seems to really know the lineage of of
what uh Lindsay is but she's really nice
she's really Kush dominant so not truly
truly heavily gassy but really a
beautiful like earthy type OG Kush so uh
special in her own right still keep her
to this day one of the few that still
have her because she had a really high
peak of interest and then just [ __ ]
died off with the like cookie cake
gelato cre I hit here like she's extinct
but like I still keep her I literally
have her in my flower room right now
that's just seated up with some
blueberry pollen so uh blueberry OG hell
yeah that's awesome uh Big Bad John
wants to know what male selection do you
have that holds pollen the
longest uh all I keep right now I used
to have a a decent extensive library of
regular males now I only keep two males
and I keep one male is my favorite it's
my pinear Kush mail that comes from Tom
Hill Hayes and that line was found uh
through uh IC mag auction through
verdant green did preservation work on
some Tom Hill Hayes or Tom Hill I ha Tom
Hill punar Kush and so these were f3s
and they were like super rare at the
time and so that's the only male I keep
that regular male and I keep a really
awesome I have a really special uh
magnum opus male from efficient Auto
that I really enjoy and like working
with and those are the only two males I
have now they're regulars and uh but I
mean like my my goal I went through this
period where you do reading and research
and it's like you can't keep males at
drop pollen and veg you just can't do it
they're shitty they're going to produce
Herms they're garbage get rid of them
don't keep them man they're a nuisance
to keep but I've like over time realized
that they don't all produce shitty like
Offspring and some of them that like do
drop pollen sometimes drop pollen for
just reasons that maybe aren't going to
play out in future lines or future work
that are negative so you just really
can't tell if it's bad or not until you
really see it in numbers and in
Offspring and in combinations but in in
decent numbers so that's really my
advice on that like don't be scared to
keep them they're a pain to keep but uh
I have some males that just no matter
what you do in the past like the pine
tar Kush mail no matter what you do with
that dude he can like sit and BGE he
never drops pollen but I find over the
years of working with lots and lots and
lots of blueberry males for instance
like years of seeing blueberry males and
and holding on to them and and like kind
of keeping them for a while Dennis the
Menace was kind of unique in the way
that he would hold on to his pollen but
even at times of like certain stress
from either drought or needing some more
space in his root Zone he would
eventually throw some pollen and so
those males like I said I have kept
around and I do have some males that
hold pollen like the pine pinear Kush
male that guy holds pollen forever but I
said at the end of the day don't worry
if some drop pollen and veg keep them or
work with them but just make sure you
know what they do or at best to your
ability know what they
do
I had lots of nails back in the day
regular males like lots it was a
nuisance to to keep lots of those guys
you just they're just real estate that's
why like go ahead go ahead no just
that's why feminize breeding now it's
just like it's not lazy but it's just so
nice to do now so so nice to do I've
never done any of it I'm kind of scared
too honestly it's fun man but if I do I
will hit you up for some advice I just
thought it was hilarious that we had a
follow up patreon question here from
cadie that says uh when's blueberry OG
Gonna Be Ready oh dude I've done lots of
regular lines of the blueberry OG like
lots because like I said those like two
of my favorite things to do those
profiles I love blueberry and I love
like that's the only real sweet plant I
love is blueberry but yeah we've done
lots of regular lines of blueberry OG so
lots of like the Dennis am Menace
pollinating lindsy OG and Roi OG so
Canadian blue blueberry OG lines and
then some of the more American ones as
well we did but this time around we're
doing some Winnie the blue so we're
doing some like fem hauling on to some
of these uh these ogs so yeah man
they'll be ready probably in I mean as
as soon as you know for testing at least
probably like two three months so
definitely hit up man love just hand no
testers so whether you grow them or not
I don't give a [ __ ] either because we'll
test them anyway ourselves got a couple
more questions before we get going we're
going to give away a couple packs of
oldtime hay old oldtime one Haze which
is the old school [ __ ] UK Haze with a
Winnie the blue and ATF the Alaskan
[ __ ] with the Topanga Canyon OG's
those are going to go out to two members
uh we've got a pack going out to our
free members this a fat pack too you
loaded these with seeds man always do
man I'm too lazy to count Steve sweet
skunk crossed with Dennis the Menace the
old DJ blueberry from
05 they're fun man they're a fun they're
a fun line those ones it's like you're a
new member in here uh I want you to pick
a number between 1 and 10 whoever is
closest will get the pack got one minute
on that guys throw a number out
there uh dank Panda wants to know have
you done any work with the UBC
chemo no but like obviously we you know
we were just having a conversation about
the other day uh me and a friend of mine
uh uh and like that if I can get my
hands on a couple of the older like I'm
I'm pretty happy with the library I
don't take much in anymore cuz some
content but that is one that I would
always have an open door for but it's
hard to find every time I come across it
I've had it in Clone like I've had it
sent in cuting numerous times and one
time rooted no two times rooted but
every time I get it it's so [ __ ] like
it's so diseased and like so so so
filthy with with pests and and problems
that I just changed my mind about it and
you know I've progressed over the years
where like out of necessity of just
preserving things I take things in that
are in the [ __ ] worst shape and
sometimes a year and a half to just like
kind of get to a state where they get
reintroduced into the actual like
bedroom but yeah every time I I've ever
had my my luck of getting it it's been
so it's been such a potential issue that
I was like [ __ ] it it's not worth it
I'll find it again and it just never
comes back in that state I want to take
it in at I would take it in now but it
just hasn't come across my way in the
Years special plant though for sure do
you know are you very familiar with Ramo
at all yeah so like everyone knows Remo
he's a sweethart one of the best
ambassadors to the Cannabis planting
Community he's a really really special
human being uh yeah I I I know of him
I've talked to him a few times and he
probably knows maybe of my of my brand
but I definitely know him and like I've
spoken to him before
yes and he sponsored some of my events
which was nice that's awesome uh he was
the last one that I had heard from that
really really seemed to love that UBC
chemo and I haven't heard about it
really since that
that's cool that you have some
experience with it and you back it up
with that yeah it's it's definitely it's
held in BC and in play like it's there
it's held uh but like it's held very
tightly and uh you know it is on the
it's like some of those plants that like
if it wasn't for a couple people holding
it it definitely would be extinct
because people have moved on
unfortunately but it's truly a special
medicinal plant truly and if you're like
if you're able to get your hands on it
and you're lucky to consume it they
that's really
awesome I want to know where grapefruit
ranks on your top strengths really
special to like uh another one but like
I you know i' I've had it at times but
don't have it now uh last time I was
trying to I was trying to get it into
the library was man maybe like four
years ago uh and that was through
another uh really good Collective here
in in Canada that are a really
well-known group of guys but for some
reason it just didn't work out and I
know a couple people that hold it and
like I said it's just one of those
plants like I have a a federation in a
really old Federation Mado uh cut that's
essentially grapefruit you know because
it's essentially like a breeder Steve
line of grapefruit essentially and so
it's uh it's really nice and and that
does the grapefruit job for me and I
I've had a test that I know what a test
at I've worked with it and I really like
it and that's a special cut to me that's
similar enough to have to not have to go
chase down the the grapefruit cut the SP
you're talking about the sweet pink
grapefruit yeah yeah have you ever had
any other styles of grapefruit
great well just like I said the makato
like the makado is is a special uh so
Federation Jason uh who is next
Generation seeds now he was Federation
seeds before uh partner and they had a
line that was
essentially the the the sweet pink was
used in that line and a lot of the
offscreen that pumped out were very
great prominant and so we have a really
old school like Federation was a staple
in Canada and like from the old Emy
magazines like just a really wicked
breeding crew right and Jason's a sweet
like Jason's amazing with next Jen and
yeah he had the the the cutting and used
The Cutting and and in that subsequent
line really really awesome grapefruit
fenos kicked out and we have this
amazing cut that was hunted by a really
awesome guy out of the Yukon and he you
know he's one of those guys we were able
to return this cut to it's his favorite
cut but it's a great kind of uh really
dominant uh a great
cut that's awesome
so I asked about that because I had a
friend that did a collab with another
breeder one used the sweet pink one used
another line of grapefruit that they had
to kind of bring diversity back to the
line um instead of bring it was very
very heavy on the sweet pink at the time
um and I grew out some of the progyny
from that and the sweet pink is [ __ ]
amazing I remember growing that back in
the Greenhouse days it threw down pounds
you didn't really have to do too much of
it except for like feed it heavy um you
didn't really have to do much to it it
kind of grew itself really it was
beautiful you know and everybody knows
the sweet pink taste but we had one that
was oh God it was a [ __ ] of a plant it
was a [ __ ] of a plant it had like 2in
inner nodes on it and it would just
throw off really really small hard
budlets around it everything about it
looked like the Great gra fruit except
if you stretched out those interner noes
and something about that one I I got rid
of it the first time that I found it
thank God I went back um but I lost the
first time because I just said this is a
straggly plant nobody wants to grow this
you know and right I did the grower
thing and afterwards found out that it
was amazing and right regretted every
second of it but it was exactly like the
sweet pink but it had a bit more sour
taste to it have you ever come across
anything like that
like I always say like a lot of people
toss runts and I always find that like
the runty plants sometimes are the ones
that you want to put some Focus onto and
so I have found in my in my days like a
lot of times you run something that is
either like runty or a little bit
finicky in round one keep your eye on it
because sometimes you know make sure you
get a clone of that one for sure
specifically like sometimes you're so
busy with the cloning process and
keeping things for subsequent next round
and Keepers that you like ah it's the
[ __ ] run I won't worry too much voted
if it lives or dies but don't man make
sure that runt is cloned and make sure
that clun that uh that runt will will
will survive because sometimes those
runs are special and so yeah I've
experienced times where runs really
really shine and you're like thank God I
got a clone of it but grapefruit like I
said only thing I really really enjoy
grapefruit wise in my garden because
it's sweet and I like sweet but not a
big fan of it is federations maccato cut
that I have and it's only because of
nostalgia I love Federation it's like
one of my favorite like when I think of
seeds I think of fed ation seeds like
Canadian you know emry magazine just
running home to look at the Seed Catalog
and then putting your order in and they
were reasonably priced and everything
that that they put out in the day like
Jason's uh if you want really good seeds
Jason from Next Generation you can find
him he's a really really really special
uh Canadian breeder he puts out a lot of
stuff but yeah that that stuff is really
really special if somebody wanted to put
an order of seeds in with you how would
they find you
you just really like I said like I do so
much I have so much other stuff going on
that I just I don't can't be bothered
with websites and stuff and I had a
couple Distributors and stuff but the
best place to really catch me is like
just literally on um on like Instagram
and like I know it's it's so stupid but
it's really the best place to catch me
and unfortunately for a long time yeah
unfortunately like you have to be
there's one fake account so just like
you have to make sure you check their
page and my page who you're talking to
cuz
my page has got lots of cannabis
pictures on it and theirs is very much
not so and then just make sure you know
you're talking to I can confirm it just
by talking to you you'll see that it's
me if you check me out here you'll know
the certain way I talk it's a little bit
much sometimes that's how I am you'll
get a VI you'll get a vibe that it's me
so like definitely and like I'll confirm
I will confirm double confirm with you
in a way that you'll know it's me so
just do that but I'm unfortunately I'm
sorry that's the way to get a hold of me
you have to do that way uh maybe one day
I'll get get a website on but for now
and and I'll look after you so if you go
through the work to find me I will look
after you don't worry I promise this has
been probably one of my favorite
podcasts in a while man I got to say
thank you so much for taking your time
to donate these seeds to us before we
get going everybody that is a crew
member that's in membership that's stuck
around to the very end here I want you
guys to pick a number between four and
20 we're going to give away two packs
here the Alaskan [ __ ] the Topanga
Canyon cross and the oldtime one Haze
with the Winnie the blue I want to know
about your Oldtimer one Haze that's the
cut I'm I'm happy you asked because this
goes back to uh a really special guy
that I also have in my world his name's
uh I'll just won't shut him hope full
but is uh James T really solid guy um I
was lucky enough to have some old uh
seeds Oldtimer one Haze and I was going
to do a run and he was like hey dude
let's make it a run I think I had 12 or
10 and he was like he end up giving me
like 30 so I ran a a hunt of 40 Oldtimer
one Haze in my in my situation uh and I
have some experience running with some
of sativas so it's not the end of the
world but ran a large feno hunt narrowed
down to three we had some lab tests on
three ended up doing uh funny enough I
never based on THC but there was such a
large hunt and and so much work involved
that I had these three fenos I went with
the highest THC Plano that all that
oldtime one Haze and I think it hit just
around 133% just a little bit uh below
133% so 12 something so I took that one
had beautiful structure too was one of
the best ones out of the whole room it
was more suitable for the indoor kind of
space that I grow in uh not not like you
know where they should be growing Under
full sun but that is a pheno that came
out that large hunt so that goes to
James T took that female and then we
revers winie the blue and so you get
this really beautiful line of like
really extreme expression so Winnie's a
a real true seven to eight week flower
range can go nine weeks but she can be
pulled 7 and 1 half 8 weeks so you have
this really extreme line to hunt through
where you get this really beautiful Haze
Expressions which are are are quite
quite beautiful with a lot of the
shorter flowering when the blue traits
so you get a lot of that kind of like
blueberry Haze so it's a really fun fun
line to hunt through and yes it's it's
for sure legitimate Oldtimer one Haze so
let's say flowering time how much did it
bring it down well these hazes went deep
like we were up to uh in in indoor that
that that hunt went deep and then we did
another run for seeds like we did our
first run for just our our hunt made our
selections that we narrowed down to
three or we narrowed down to six but we
ended up keeping three for future runs
and for future work um but yeah those
went I think the longest went just short
of like 19 weeks 18 weeks like these
some of these like true true like like
wild Haze plants they were so unruly and
big uh and that was with like all the
training that I've been able to acquire
from people people over the years on how
to do it right indoor and doing no
justice because we all know this should
be grown outdoors in full sun and done
well but this is the best I can do and
so yeah they went up really high
flowering time win's are shorter
flowering time so you'll get things that
are around most will be in that like 13
14 week because Winnie will really
shorten flower time in a r Crossing
really will take over Flower time and
then you'll get some outliers obviously
that are going to be shorter but most of
the outl will be higher flowering times
that will maybe go above that timeline
but most will be in that range
that's not too uncontrollable do you
have any tips for people that want to
grow these hazes indoor how to best
control them for sure and these are all
like I said just things that have been
passed on to me this is nothing I can
take credit for but for sure lots of
shout outs to rev Charles uh reeferman
teaching all this sort of knowledge
passing on for free but yeah man my TR
my trick is first and foremost we always
have to agree that they should always be
done properly in full sun and like
outdoor proper Sun so this is just
you're doing the best you can with your
environment and so these really unruly
hazes or some of the African varieties
that go 22 21 weeks that it's just Thai
varieties that are just mind-blowingly
long flowering first thing you want to
do is you want to deal with your uh your
lighting so you want to make sure that
you're going into a lighting a lighting
kind of environment that is going to be
shorter than your 12 and 12 so sometimes
you want to start at maybe you know you
want to do 13 on 11 off for like a
period of time and then slowly reduce as
we get closer to ripeness into flower
time to ensure you get some sort of
ripeness so you don't continually get
reving ringing down to what I mean you
can go as low as 10 on like 10 on yeah
and that will help that will help
prevent this massive con like 12 and 12
you're just going to get flowering to a
point and then it's just gonna Reed re
rege so it's a real like bummer right if
you're making seeds it's not the end of
the world but it's still not not ideal
and so that's one one thing you want to
do before you even start then you want
to realize you want to look at what
these things are going to flower for if
it's some of those varieties that are
going 20 weeks be prepared dude like
you're going to take like six months out
of your life for these plants and so
plan that too so make sure that this is
what we do too so get them uh started in
seeds get them uh transplanted up you
know as you normally would and then
start getting your topping so you can
get some clones off of them but because
they're such long flowering plants you
can kind of cheat and this is what I
like doing so just get them going get
them in a good pot upsize upsize upsize
till they're a foot tall no more than a
foot tall even 10 inches tall and then
just [ __ ] put them in your flower
room and start flowering at that stage
and because they flower so long they
don't really trip uh and you don't
really see flower range trates until
like sometimes 10 weeks 11 12 13 weeks
right so you're just getting these
plants that continually are just getting
bigger and bigger and bigger so you you
can theoretically save time in planning
and just take all your clones off your
mothers and do all your your like
labeling and all that for your your
future Keepers and what you're going to
keep in round two so that's a trick to
do that and that way you can kind of
maintain and hack them down a little bit
but it's a process so flip them really
early change a light cycle get them in
really good pots so that they don't
really need a a lot of attention like
rev said at best sativas are the Wolves
of the Cannabis World they don't really
need a lot of human intervention hybrids
and indas are dogs they kind of need us
and so you know this Tiba when we grow
it I put it in really big pots and I let
them kind of just do their thing there
and because they're flowering for so
long lots of basement layering of
amendments and then top trusting
throughout the whole program but really
that's all they're going to require
right because they're going to go so
deep and that to me with those methods
keeps them short keeps them manageable
you can still clone them uh and save
yourself some time in planning and it's
just with the lighting schedule they
finish indoors and so it's not not
something that most people can't do but
but it will take some some some
experience of doing that and then some
training basic training that's what I do
and that helps a lot I I love that
answer and I learned a couple things
right there that I'm think I might
incorporate with uh some of the Ty runs
too that was very good advice thank you
so much for that Paul and uh thank you
again for taking time out of your day
this has been an amazing episode I Vibe
with you I dig where your heart's at you
got passion for the plant and that's
very evident and you take very well care
of yourself and this huge library that
you have like you seem like a very
amazing person I'm glad that we crossed
past and I look forward to hopefully
doing another one with you in the future
anytime man I just like to thank
everybody who like takes time out of
their day to like message me contact me
support me and uh a huge shout out to my
family my wife my daughter my family is
the only reason why I'm here so love you
guys I hope you all had an amazing night
we've got two winners uh the Alaskan
[ __ ] Topanga Canyon is going away
first to Big Bad John the number was
four he got closest with five
congratulations Big Bad John and the
Oldtimer Haze with the Winnie the blue
the number was 19 and the closest member
was croad with 17 congratulations CAD
you got yourself some Beyond Christmas
Haze No it should be about Christmas
right now yeah they
get him started get him started brother
all right thank you so much Paul until
next time I hope you all had a great
night this has been doc calx with the CX
crew podcast saying grow smarter not
harder
Wow Come
[Music]
on see it
baby I know you're on the road
[Music]
Sweet let's take it real
soon you know we got what you need baby
take it Mo
[Music]
along I said we got what you need
hone come
on on the
highway
[Music]
come
on come on
said I
said oh
honey
[Music]
come you got to feel
it yeah got to move
along got to feel feel feel
got