[Music]
good morning podcast listeners what is
up everybody and welcome to another
exciting episode of the calyx and crew
podcast i'm your host as always dot
calyx
very exciting episode today the duke is
back that is right ladies and gentlemen
we have
none other than the man himself duke
diamond on the show known for his work
with heirloom skunks afghanis the purple
dahlias beautiful we used to grow the
munson and the polecat 91 those both
amazing strains we're excited to get in
here we're excited to talk to them but
before we do i want to give a quick
shout out to one of the show's sponsors
stoner days apparel you guys can go over
to shop.stonerdays.com
use code calyx that's all cap c-a-l-y-x
for 20 off your order at checkout they
have all kinds of stoner inspired
apparel tied eyes and psychedelic stuff
we have dab mats from we have posters we
love everything that we get from
shop.stonerdays.com go check them out
now without further ado
let's learn about living soil let's talk
about some of his cultivars let's talk
about his work with organic and
regenerative practices
none other than the duke himself
after a minor [ __ ] up we are back with
duke diamond
of dominion seed company how are you
doing man
goddamn it
for the first time in podcast history i
forgot to hit the recording on duke's
audio so we've already gone over this
[Music]
anyway we're gonna pop back on course
here
i know you for your work with your
skunks your afghans
when we [ __ ] up that recording you
were talking about blueberry and how you
would
you got some blueberry you start growing
when you were 13.
you're working with skunks you're
working with afghanis and then all of a
sudden you're buying blueberry seeds
from a seed bank what were those
blueberries that you really liked
so
starting off with the the old original
varieties like from my cousins that i
agree with and stuff skunks afghans and
el skunk evolves into later you know
you're looking at what's hot like the
newest of the new
real exciting time we go into the widows
and then eventually revolve into the
years where the
blue bear was coming out and
like you said you were talking about you
know all the excitement back then you
know getting the money order trying to
hide not get caught just to get the damn
seeds over you know take two months or
whatever and we finally get these uh
blueberry seeds
i found good stuff i didn't find that
crazy
people used to call the blueberry yum
yum you know
but like said friends
they had a friend that i guess did you
know you got to smoke some of that and i
mean it was off the charts
but my favorite favorite one of all time
blue moonshine i had a blue moonshine
that was like [ __ ] drugs like
i mean just so so strong it's not so bad
it's still in my top ten list off of all
time
nice
just insane and unfortunately
um that was one of the ones like he did
away with because
i talked to him at a show one time being
like hey what's up with that he's like
oh yeah bringing it back i'm like why
would you have ever gotten rid of it and
he was like well it was it was a
stepping stone it was just a step in a
long process because you know dj he does
a lot he works the [ __ ] you know he's
not no hurry puts the work in
you know the dude dude really gets it in
so he said yeah i'm working on it so
that's one thing i gotta i gotta check
on you know he's like yeah i'd be a
couple years so like all right well it's
been a couple years for sure and for a
long year so i know you haven't been
going out and about socializing and
partying so what's up with that blue
moonshine dude
so it was supposed like i remember the
description it was like the blue side of
the widow family or the white or he
called it the white family you know i
know it's so much white widows
and uh my god like little kush plants
all like super super dark purple almost
black
and just this pungent
it smelled purple if that makes any
sense i mean it was like the epitome was
like the smell purple it's so pungent
man like chemical pungent funk it was
just
awesome it grew awesome and just the the
potency of it was just knockout i love
that [ __ ] did it take more after those
moonshine traits or did it take more
after the blue traits
it was uh
i can't really honestly speak on it
because i i never had his what he would
call like pure moonshine or any of that
but whatever whatever that project was i
mean
it was like if you had like the most
gnarly of the blueberry type
funks but more like i said just the
color purple man
that was the selling boy oh dude it it
was it was just ridiculous man and like
i said just so potent
just knockout [ __ ] man and like i would
that was my all-time favorite you know
delving into those lines you know i
agree that
i grew the great crush
and when i was the other one i grew it
was uh azor hayes i think okay tried
that one but yeah nothing like that blue
main show was like oh the f13 almost
forgot about that one but uh yeah
nothing like that nothing like that blue
manchan though
nice dude i feel like i don't hear you
talk about some of your favorite strains
you know i've heard you talk about a lot
of your cultivars very often but we
don't care very much about like what you
like and that's a big part of growing is
like you're taking
other people's stock and trying to find
stuff out of that too right
yeah and that's the thing is like
some guys are just like all about oh i
like this so let me get c breeder a and
c b to b and i'm just going to sling it
together and then they'll sell seeds
i've never been really
that type of dude i do my work
and then other people's work
well that's their work and i like their
work you know it's it's a done deal for
me i'm just gonna grow it and grow and
smoke it but unfortunately when you
really get into breeding and stuff man
all your space and all your times taken
up with it
as far as delving into like
newer things that people make
it was all like taking a back burner for
like retirement day or something you
know and then i'm going to jump into
those but
there was a lot of stuff that i liked
you know just like to grow and just you
know smoke it so
they were just clones that were in the
in the room and it's like all right well
i need some more of this weed so like
while i'm testing out these you know a
bunch of these beans that i just made
in the back that corner i'll have a
whatever
just to replenish you know
i feel like it's fair to say though
out of everything that you appreciate
you're more into the gassy skunky rotten
type offensive [ __ ] would that be right
yeah i like
and i have such an appreciation for all
of it but yeah i tend to go toward
he said sour
kim
type funk you know that that's typically
the way my my hand always goes
but equally to that
i do like those like really really
potent
purples and like those hash punches
really narcotic hash plants that's
definitely something i wanted to talk to
you about
yeah man that's that's another big one
for me
but then like when i'm talking like
hazes and you know [ __ ] like that you
know that's a whole another
you know frankincense funk like man i
honestly man really i'm all over the
place but i guess
you know when it comes to the evening
time the night time yeah it's like it's
going more toward that uh you know what
people say like the gassy side of things
i'm going towards those real narcotic
hash plants that have more
i mean some of them are like that too
but my favorite one was more
they said in that purple flavored uh
realm of things
so speaking on hash plans
back in the day i told you earlier two
of the ones that we grew from you that
we loved were the munson
and
the most memorable for me is the polecat
91 yeah that's a good one that pull cat
91 that had skelly hash plan in it right
yeah
and see skelly hash plant i've heard the
puck a million times
but that was a little bit beyond my time
i think the only thing that i've had it
in is
your polecat 91 can you tell us a little
bit more about skelly and what made that
hash plant so
popular and wanted
yeah so
normally out there like especially in
the
breeding world and stuff like that or
like the
people that might not be breeding but
they're like the extreme growers
actually keep track of all the all the
genetics being made and sold and
everything
anytime there's anything out there where
anybody says
nah man you can't have it
it is it makes them go [ __ ] well
that's all literally
dude
what was mine i was like
the old dealer's trick
no you can't have that jar man i'll
[ __ ] make something i'm just going to
grow up the pictures talk about how
awesome it is and when people are like
oh i want to see like nah nah
and then people go wild and then all you
got to do is let one clone out to
somebody you know he's going to give it
away all right and then when you do that
be like whatever you do don't give it to
anybody right and within the year it
should be in like you know ten thousand
different hands
somebody's gonna have two parts of it
and then at that point that's when you
drop the seeds and then you just cash
out
like
you know
you know that that would be just the
ultimate
[ __ ] you know what i mean just to
show like
[ __ ] duke dropping tips
[Laughter]
so yeah i mean there's that but
all that aside
it is super super super [ __ ] dang man
it's just [ __ ] awesome
it's one of those hatch plants that
leads them up lanes on that
just rotten gassy nasty or rag type type
side of things
extremely potent
that just slow as [ __ ]
barely even stretches when you flower it
but man it's just
amazing
and
when i was talking
to mike and everything and his you know
the dude that
originally got the seeds over in holland
and they came back with it uh hidden in
a sewn into a sweater and all that [ __ ]
it was uh
because
they got it or whatever before cincy was
doing the [ __ ] with neville so it should
have been
uh neville's uh hash blank stock oh wow
which was
i think it was like an nl2 nl2 nl1 and
something else man
my brain's been a little a little hazy
here lately i don't know like if you
yeah i mean you got the power of the
internet right you can look up the whole
c bank catalogs
and bean brains could correct me too he
even sent me like little catalogs with
her at home but i remember it was like a
heavy you know
an old base
and um anyways they come over here
they're growing it
and you know it stood the test of time
and typically anything that's that old
and stands the test of time you know
there's a there's a damn good reason for
it
so having that heavy
nl base
that was a one good reason and just the
fact that it just
it's awesome it's it's got what uh what
i like and what i want
the other side to it is like
my own personal beliefs you know like
i've heard
a billion or one stories about him from
here come from there come from here from
there yep i've always believed that that
chem is a derivative of that
so
sticking with that uh that got i always
thought that i was like well maybe it
was like an l skunk
that was you know producing that hit it
and and that's you know the derivative
so i felt like all right
if i'm going to work in this gene pool i
want to encapsulate as much as i can
of of that
into this hybrid right
which is going to be gnarly funk
and
really good potency so that was the that
was kind of the
the starting point
of um
of doing that that whole that whole
project so that way
eventually i have a dominion skunk male
which you know it was a was a hybrid it
had you know all the all the core genes
in it
and then i could use that to start
to start hitting anything that was that
was kim
and then
i did another project
that was i was trying to hit any
basically anything chem og with it which
was a 54 mail
so like i wanted to have those those
things and work them to the to the way
where
i'm i'm keeping the funk i'm keeping the
uh and keeping that the good qualities
that gene pool
good strong branching and everything to
you know go along with that rad potency
and really good gnarly nose on
everything so that was kind of
kind of that whole project to finally
hit that hit that end goal
and uh the pole cat and then the polecat
bx
were definitely
definitely up there
on the uh
on the charts with the nose and the
potency and everything so it worked out
pretty damn good
i really missed that one i gotta say
that was by far one of my favorite
outdoor plants of all time [ __ ] yeah
dude we would top i i had a patron
member ask me earlier
they heard about your tips on high
stress training low stress training they
want to know like if there's certain
cultivars that you recommend a certain
amount of training on or a certain type
of training
and they said they had a
pole cat
out crossing from you i don't think he
mentioned what cross it was but i said
if it's anything like the original pole
cat and you're doing it outdoors top at
once super crop the lowers and then just
keep everything even and it's gonna
produce like hell for you
oh yeah for sure man
and that's like another little tip for
like
anybody growing out there
and it was something that you know
i learned this early on
growing out different things especially
when you're growing from clone
say like you know our first
go around we're just like all right you
know we're just going to uh we're just
going to go for the pillow
for the for the topping
so you top it
and
you know everything's kind of little but
let's say like you don't you don't you
don't call it you go again and this time
you super cropping you know oh wow all
the flowers are like really big
some things don't
respond well
to like the multi-cola
type training right
right
so like a good example of it was the 88
g13 hash plant
if you super crop it a little bit and
get the lower branches to kind of come
up toward the top and keep them about
four to six inches below the apex of it
you know the very tip of the top
you would do great
now if you punched it again and got
everything even or if you topped it
early on your yield would go down below
half of what you would have got
and those growth options which are the
what it send into the apex you know says
like
you get the most you get the lion's
share of my energy right now
when you
have to divvy it up
across a whole bunch of different tops
it's like some of these plants like they
just get confused or something you know
they get a little worked up over it and
you don't end up getting it now some
plants you can have 12 tops and you're
going to get 12 equally large colas and
it's going to do very well for you and
then some of them it does nothing or
some cases it even did get worse
so
what i always say is like when you grow
out when you grow up from seed
kind of go not all natural but
just you know do the do the super
cropping enough to where you're getting
the lowers up near the top
and
do your first run like that find your
winner right and then once you got that
and you're gonna move forward and now
it's the next run
you know try like one clone you know
top which i have one clone super crop
you know like like you normally would
and then do another one you know with
multiple tops you know five six ten
however many types you want and see how
it responds then that way
you're kind of dialing it in
you know how you're gonna
have your space management go down and
then that way you know you can
predictably say okay well i'm gonna need
you know this much square footage for
each one of these plants they're gonna
give me give or take about this amount
and it responds what best in in this way
and you know i do that at the same time
as you would you know dialing in your
feeds
and also like your your job times too
because my first few runs i'll play
around give or take a couple days before
during and after
to really really dial in that that chop
date you know to see
if that potency really spikes because
some things man they have like a little
short window where [ __ ] really really
spikes and peaks very high
it's great and potent before and after
but there's these little windows where
should it make you snatch off sweat and
you know that's ultimately we want the
best possible right so
play around with these things and then
that way you you know something you're
going to keep you know you you really
got that thing dialed in so you're
making the best of your your space
management and you're getting the best
possible outcome at the end you know
dude that's a perfect tip for new
growers right there take that same clone
that you like grow it in as many ways
possible and see how it responds best
yeah mind your six ps right
yeah proper planning prevents poor
performance
another thing that you talk about is
something that i talk to my patrons
about very often you say it a little bit
different than me you talk about reading
a plant sign language right what does
that mean
so
no obviously they can't speak and if the
plants does start talking to you and
you're hearing a language and
uh you might want to put the mushrooms
damn it that's what's going on and i get
it man it was speaking [ __ ] clown
might make it out man
but um
so i always kind of related it to like
you know they can't verbally speak but
they can speak through sign language so
it's up to us to
know the the best way to to understand
that
and i would kind of like relate it to
if you've known somebody long enough and
you notice like they look a certain way
or act in a certain way that they might
be hungry or they're hot or whatever so
like the same like social cues like to
use with another human being
and more in particular a human being
like that you hang around a lot you
might notice a little subtle subtle
little thing so
same type deal like you know know what
know what your deficiencies look like
know what your toxicities look like
understand about light sensitivity
and know what 100
super healthy looks like
so you can you can kind of have a have a
gauge a gauge on that so that way you're
knowing like
you know the the perfect sweet spots for
like watering because you know if you're
doing your soil thing um i noticed like
a lot of people over over water like has
like a huge huge problem so not over
watering and knowing like the right
amount to give them for like what they
need for that period of time and knowing
when to give it to them you know and
then looking at the angle of how the
leaves are pointing up or flat or
less than
parallel with the floor you know when
they start to come down past that point
knowing knowing these little things and
knowing
what you know uh you know yellow leaves
starting at the bottom aren't knowing
what a little rough spot is become
familiar with all these things and
essentially you're learning their
language right and then that way you
know how to
better handle your problems if there is
a problem
and then once you start to learn these
uh these different things
know how to deal with them accordingly
if you're an organic grower know how to
do it organically
and
don't limit yourself to knowing like oh
i need a bottle of
whatever like
you know like you know there's a bunch
of ways you know you like one could even
get calcium i had a buddy that uh in a
pinch he crushed up a bunch of toms oh
damn yeah that's actually [ __ ] jesus
yeah so like you know if you're in a
pinch and a lot of that you know it
comes from growing up in an illegal
world where i can't go to a grocery
store i'm gonna get [ __ ] indicted if
i go to this [ __ ] story you know i'm
like yeah i just can't do it i can't
order things yeah you have to be able to
know your own thing so
that knowledge came from there but
you know there's there's a whole bunch
of different ways and that's the thing
is like you might have
this dolomite lime that you
you know made a slurry with and broke it
down some microbes and [ __ ] now you're
you're using that but you know you might
not be able to get out and he's like oh
man i need to
get a little calcium boost real quick
and you don't have any but you know it's
really needed maybe you're out in the
20s it's going to be a while before you
can get out
hey man you saw a roll of [ __ ] toms
you know and you're like all right cool
you know you you could potentially use
that you know so there's there's a lot
of i wouldn't recommend it of course you
know but if you had to
you had an alternative so like no
in a pinch
when in rome right
right right so
you know you gotta you gotta know know
your alternatives and and things like
that like bray rabbit molasses for
instance
[ __ ] ton of calcium in that [ __ ] ton of
calcium in that so that gives you give
you a little boost there it's got some
iron and some other goodies in there as
well so
you know just be uh well versed in uh
what to do
according to what this plant is trying
to tell you you know what i mean
so you know the more you know right
[Music]
the more you know yeah
no that's i i love how you explain that
because that's a big thing that i tell
my patrons i call it reading your plants
and it's it's basically exactly how you
described it i would say watering
practices are the number one killer of
plants for new growers absolutely it's
the hardest thing for them to learn but
after that it's just understanding
mobile and immobile nutrients
understanding what your nutrients are
and what they do for your plant right
yep you're environmental and
and the one other big one i would add to
it is understanding the difference
between
plant available
and not available yeah things that can
be taken up and then things that really
need to be broken down and what it takes
to break those down
so
knowing that
will also help with you know doing doing
things but it's also going to help you
with
uh you know another thing i've always
said with
growing
especially myself which is weird as [ __ ]
it's like the like the the horse and the
carrot
you gotta push them a little bit you
know to get them to do do exactly what
you want to really really excel
so you have to lead them along
and
you need to know why things happen
what causes these things to happen
and that way you can say okay
well if higher uv light is going to
trigger a response
for for more oil production right
we can say okay
oh we can give it more uv right now we
need to know how can we best facilitate
this so now we know how to trigger it
but we need to know how to facilitate
that right
so if you know like okay well now it's
about that time so we're going to crank
the lights up a little bit higher now
i'm going to start you know feeding it
something for a little more oil
production and understand that it's kind
of like a
not like a super stress but it's like a
stress response so uh when they're
stressed they produce little bits of
salicylic acid so let's help him out
once he's like alloy water right that's
got a [ __ ] ton of salicylic acid
so let's facilitate the stress response
what they need to produce more oil
and you know trigger it
and deliver
and then that way you know with all
these other little things
you can kind of lead them along the path
that you want
yep absolutely that's definitely a great
tip again is [ __ ] understanding plant
stages and what they're using at those
different stages right
awesome and you're also a big
no-till organic guy right
why what got you into that you've tried
hydro haven't you
oh yeah yeah i grew uh your hydra back
in the day because of uh
allegedly
allegedly i love that word
i say that one a lot allegedly
yeah so it's like you know to go to a
bunch of a bunch of different places
that are all over the state like it's
just not feasible so you have to have
things automated and everything
so that was like the the best way to do
it you know we've done you know you know
drippers you know drain drained waste
recycles doing rockwool
done cocoa
evan flow and hydrocorals you know
and my buddy used to call hydra wow
clay pellets you know right
yeah i've grown about every every way
you can think
but
grown in soil
without a doubt always got my my best
quality and i wasn't really sacrificing
much on the on the heel department
i'm just i'm not into smoking rock hard
he just doesn't burn good for me
and i'm not uh
i'm nuts because like the thing is like
it'll be like oh it's black ash what
like i mean you do hydroponics correctly
like it'd have a white ash but
you know it just wasn't wasn't wasn't my
jam flavonoids terpenes weren't weren't
there like they were in the soil
i might you know i'm gonna finish a
little bit quicker i'm with you
but man if i'm already going you know 60
something days or whatever like you know
a few handful of days ain't gonna hurt
me when it comes to
you know
the quality of the end product and
ultimately for me
that was my um
you know that's that's my that's my jam
you know so back in those days
early days
of uh alleged
pumping
you know it was fine but
it was just out of out of that necessity
and that necessity only right
so yeah like for me personally
and especially the way the world is
today it's like i don't i don't have
those worries so yeah i can i can just
do do my soul thing
so aside from the quality and [ __ ] just
the ease of it man
just the the flat out ease of growth
it's cheaper it's just easier all the
way around you know
and
especially like after the first run you
know you've you know you've already paid
for that soil you know and then you can
just rock and roll
in it in it again you know if the soil
was
really really set up for that
as far as like the no-till it's like
yeah i'm not definitely not telling but
when somebody said that to me years ago
i was like yeah yeah and they're like oh
what cover crops are you running i was
like oh no i'm
doing that i'm doing my thing inside
yeah like oh yeah yeah we know like what
cover cross here and i was like oh i
don't do that like what about your mulch
there i was like well i stripped down
the lower third of my plant like i mess
it up with scissors
and i put that
yeah man i'll throw some bokashi on it
maybe some earthworm castings and
let it go to town and
it does that does pretty awesome
but i don't i don't grow
you know another
another crop crap on it and it's just
that's just my style you know
i've tried it
it was just adding add to my into my
workload
so just mulching with my when i'm
stripping you know that was always good
enough for me
and every now and again i'm top dressing
a few things just to keep levels of
certain things up
i'm not real big on overloading the soil
like with everything
in existence you know
a lot of those things like i really want
to keep in my control
so
some guys throw it down [ __ ] thumbs
alfalfa and kelp
and they're like you know writing in the
mix and
i'm gonna come in with the yeah
it kind of smells like [ __ ] green
grass
kind of burns my throat i'm like yeah
dude that's that's that's
it right there and it's like you know
something that's not mentioning on that
bag of whatever that you know banana is
the you know the plant growth regulators
you know they're organic you know
but
the uh you know there's pgrs that are
that are in there you know so
uh trichatinol and the alfalfa is giving
that nice green
grass [ __ ] funk to it so there's that
and then that acetone there's sodium now
the kelp is really uh
really doing it up for you on the
smoothness you know so it's like don't
don't load your [ __ ] down with
everything under the sun
you have it in your room but like you
know brew it make it use it when it's
needed no and
yes you can make it available and you
can give it then yeah and just because
it's good and veg and you're gonna bloom
don't feed that [ __ ] through the whole
volume cycle like you're inhibiting a
lot of a lot of things doing it too then
that goes back to like educating
yourself like
why does this do what it does and what
is actually going on other than like oh
it worked it did good plant looked happy
you know like not like
the beginner grower notes
i remember taking those notes yep good
watered happy
[Laughter]
yeah plant green plant
plant green plant good yeah
that's awesome
so
i'm a big organic guy too i haven't
[ __ ] around with hydra i'm one of the
only organic growers i know that's never
touched hydro in his life
yeah but i went from using like a mostly
organic synganic like bald nutrient
system it was horrible it was
they had like [ __ ]
eight thirteen balls or some [ __ ] like
that
it was just yeah it was just ridiculous
i went from that i got
the ph down that was the worst that was
the worst yeah
three drops out we're way the [ __ ] out
now god damn it
[Laughter]
i look like lemon juice man perfect
now yes now i'm using lemon juice but
before i i moved into top dressing
and after that i really got into k f
practices if you're familiar with that
oh very very familiar man that it works
and there's there's books
yes
that are available to the public for
anybody listening it's not
something you know secret like you
should get those learn those and and
understand why those things are doing
good it's the same thing like with toms
or whatever like no like you can find
nutrients
literally all over the place just you
know fermenting them or you know
breaking them down
in other other ways
it's there you know and you can really
do some cool [ __ ]
yes so i have a couple questions for you
on that i
went from using knf
and every
run i would take my soil out i would
re-amend it like you were saying just
throw it in there because it's good for
veg right
and uh
now i'm getting bigger pots i'm growing
in beds i'm doing stuff like this and
i'm trying to do the no-till
hand-in-hand incorporated with the k nf
are you getting your soil tested after
each run do you gauge it
what type of organic growing are you
using in conjunction with your no-till
as far as like testing goes
for the longest time that was just
just not a practical thing that that was
going to happen for me
out here
especially like when the cbd ship went
super crazy
and that's okay and it's you know it's
all legit and everything you started
getting a lot of these ad companies that
were coming out you're like oh yeah
we'll test your soul test your soul and
at that point that's when i was like
okay yeah i can i can test this because
you know like i'm at the end of the day
like i'm a
scientific guy i might not look it or
sound it but i want to quantify [ __ ] and
know what exactly is going on so i did
get to see
you know my levels and you know what
would deplete and it wasn't
incredibly far off from what i kind of
already knew like but i had like a
tangible
actual number with it now that you know
i could i could really hone in with
versus me just
once again just looking at the plants in
the past and being like well every run
you know you know on the second you know
another run i noticed like i'm starting
to peter out here so i need to
start adding you know this that or the
other right
so yeah if if it's available to you and
you can do it
i would definitely highly advise that
because you know we want to we want to
be the best at you know what we're what
we're trying to do
as far as my soil pots
like beds are really cool
but the only
i guess downside of it to me was if
something happens yes
yeah i don't want it
so if for whatever ungodly reason say
pythium were to uh come into the mix
i don't want that spreading across the
whole bed and losing everything if i
didn't happen to notice it in a plant
you know i could at least take that pot
and remove it out of the out of the area
and you know be done with it without
break when that and
offered me a little bit of
configurability where i could you know
arrange things and move around
so but i mean beds are
they are cool you know but it's just uh
for me i needed to
have that little versatility as well
as far as my pots once once i set them
up i don't i never bust them up again
but i found out like gross stones ain't
around anymore so
i'm gonna have to go back to like
comments and [ __ ] like that i guess
again but paralyte breaks down mad quick
though so
the important part
about people that i noticed like when
they were doing these like big big huge
20-something gallon no-till pots
and we're beds for that matter is that
aeration wise they were just relying a
lot on the paralyte and it's going to
break down fairly quickly yes and then
you're going to start losing your
aeration which is going to invite you
know problems and
the plants are going to start to suffer
make sure like when you set your pot or
your bed up make sure that it is you
know it's set up good to go for it for
the long haul
sizing wise on my pots
it just i kind of just kind of honed it
in over trial and error for a long time
as
the plant that i want about the
we'll just say diameter times height
there
equal pot
once again plant plant happy plant good
[Laughter]
so
if it was like a small say like a waist
high belly button plant
five gallons seven gallons full
chest high chin hives you know
maybe a little taller you know
10 gal on the 15s depending on because
some things have the crazy insane root
systems that just want to right go go
bonkers you know and other things they
don't they don't quite have that that
vigor in the root zone that like some
cultivars do
so you know i'd play it play it by ear
with the with the cultivar as well kind
of try to cater individually instead of
like all right you're all cannabis right
all right cool you know y'all all act
the same right and it's like no no no it
doesn't work not that one not that yeah
in the corner
you know they all got their dietary
needs and
tweaks and [ __ ] and things i do like
don't like
so let me ask you another question
something we've been talking about in my
discord server with my patrons
was
keeping a no-till
in a certain size i had always heard
don't do it in anything under a 15
gallon a big reason of that is that dry
down time right and keeping that
biodiversity going exactly
what would you suggest for like the
smallest pot size that you could get a
no-till system in with
i think what it really
boils down to is the
one the person
and how attentive and how much you're
there you know in your in your garden
and then the second thing being like
when we go back to the to the plant
itself
and that root zone bigger
because like if i got something i know
that just has this crazy root zone and i
already know that
in a week
four flowers it's starting to suck water
up so damn quick i know better than to
try to grow this big bastard on a 10 or
seven so i know like hey you definitely
need to be in a 15. some things you can
get away with with a with a tent
but yeah that's that's the whole key is
like
keeping these microbes happy letting
them build their infrastructure their
highways and byways their living living
spaces and all in places where they're
reproducing you got
concentrate on them because they're like
in your industrial assembly line plant
that's job is to send food to to the
roots they're your workers and you gotta
keep your workers happy
the better they do the better that
plant's going to do long as you make
sure they're happy in their environment
and they have what they need to succeed
then they're they're they're going to
take care of the rest for you so i don't
yeah i think
with
most people
definitely like i mean if you want to
push the envelope and go back and forth
sure but yeah i think you know 15 would
be a good proper size for most people
they might not be able to you know they
might work two jobs or you know
you know life gets [ __ ] up sometimes
so i think 15 would be a good place
caveat to that
people with big 15s they start [ __ ]
watering like just transplanted you know
like you water it down you get it good
and good and down
you you put in a dixie cup
clone you know in it you watered it in
but everybody wants to water the whole
[ __ ] pot again it doesn't like
throwing the kids in the pool
yeah so it's like you know it's just
dried out or not dried out but it's
starting to dry in the immediate area of
the transplant so the rest of the pot
was good you just needed to wet out the
circumference of that area again and
maintain
a good moisture moisture level
as it's starting to go along because as
it comes more to a dry not dry but you
know it's it's
running out of these this moisture
that's what roots do it's the horse and
the carrot thing
it has to kind of go there or else the
root's going to get complacent it'll
just stay right there and not search for
water
so like it needs to come you know down
in level 4 to search for it again then
you need to reward it with some carrot
and then you know you do it again that's
what's causing that root system to go
it's looking for moisture and being fed
that's
how she goes
so
if it takes a gallon of water say to wet
down the spot real good and you
transplant in and it's good and happy
when you water again you don't need to
hit it with another gallon you know
you're probably good with you know 40
ounces of water or something like that
so that's another one that i noticed
because then they're just like oh yeah
the root zone didn't do [ __ ] and
this is never happy is this always
droopy all the time and yeah
you've been you're waterboarding them it
didn't have good government secrets bro
you waterboarded it for nothing man
yep
absolutely so i need to smoke a bowl
really quick but before we get going to
break i wanted to ask you has there been
one input
one tip one
major piece of advice that has really
changed your growth for the better
hmm it's been
so
many
so many little things that really did it
one thing
and i don't think i could even put it
down to just this this one thing man
it's uh
and so so many things but hey i guess
that means that we got uh
we got more to talk about you know
nothing bored more
yeah absolutely all those little things
that you reach for that people give you
advice over you try them they work for
you all that stuff adds up to what your
style of growing is right
yeah exactly
for me i think the biggest thing
you know it's not one thing
it's
the idea
that i don't have to throw my soil away
anymore i can regenerate this i can
not only help my plants i can help my
pocket i can help the planet all at the
same time
you know what i could ride without being
one of those things because
you know way back in the day i used to
toss mine out he said his root balls i
throw them in the garden where i was
growing you know watermelons tomatoes
and [ __ ] yep and i had like that one
section where [ __ ] was just bonkers feel
like my hand us that's some real good
soil down there everything must be
washing off going down there to the
bottom bro
yeah man i reckon so i reckon so well
yeah you throw that [ __ ] in the trash
then you know you got the you got the
chance of them seeing that [ __ ] unless
you throw it in like a [ __ ] abandoned
dumpster somewhere
but uh yeah man yeah in the country
i was talking to gas from swami organic
seed and that's one of the things that
he was talking about too he used to
throw his soil away back in the day and
one of the things that we both know is
because that's a place where you can
throw soil where nobody's gonna question
why is there soil there right
but and you know what the one time where
i just said
[ __ ] it
let's just roll again just for shits and
giggles just to see what's going on here
yep it was better
it was better than the first run yep and
that's what triggered it in my head
that's what we were saying we're
throwing that through that soil in our
gardens and all of a sudden we noticed
our [ __ ] tomatoes are happy our
[ __ ] plants are out here what's going
on here like this isn't trash made of
red
tomato good
we're gonna take a short break we will
be right back with duke diamond from
dominion seed company
[Music]
[Applause]
g'day everyone grow green daddy here if
you're like me and you can't help but
sneak in a peek and cop in a fill of
your lady flowers many times a day then
you need to stay the hell out of their
room and let the coconut mizu keep an
eye on them for you the mizu is an
affordable battery operated remote
monitoring environment sensor taking
constant temperature humidity and vpd
readings with real-time push-to-app
notifications
if your grow climate fluctuates outside
your set range you will be notified with
historical charting you can refer to
previous grow data to help perfect your
future grow style and with one account
able to monitor multiple mizu you have
complete grown monitoring on any device
signed in through the app to help dial
in your space coconut is dialing up a
discount for cal x crew podcast
listeners use code calyx calyx and check
out further savings off the already low
69 price per unit check the coconut
mizzou out at coconut.com kokonaut.com
now back to doc and duke to finish off
the session
[Applause]
all right we're back with duke diamond
from dominion seed company
i do want to talk more about your your
cultivars now some of the stuff that
you've made in the past that you're
really happy about
my help over on the podcast grow green
daddy one of the questions he likes me
to ask you guys all the time is if you
had like a let's shoot for one but you
can pick a top three cultivars that
you've made that you want to represent
your name when you're gone what would
they be
i would say
definitely the dominion g
the six mil
god damn top three it's all hard
questions okay take your time take your
time it really is
i'm gonna say screaming eagle in there
too oh [ __ ] and with that dominion v
it's like my pole cat dominion g
projects you know like those were
oh man these are good ones
you know so but yeah that would probably
be it
the the screaming eagle one was a was a
big one too
what was the difference between the
dominion g and the capital g
well the the cat g was just the the
first
the first attempt you know like like i'm
gonna make this and we're we're gonna
see what happens
a lot a lot of nasty nasty funk
resulted from it
i grew some out
for just a
just to hook up some friends with it you
know i had a little keeper you know that
that i wanted to you know keep working
with it was just [ __ ] skunk man
and people were flipping out about it
so i only had
because i did a huge hunt
jesus christ i think it was like 40
packs something like that and people
were just [ __ ] trying to [ __ ]
just i thought it was going to get raped
or something the way people were [ __ ]
creeping on me
so i was like [ __ ] it oh yeah just take
them you know it's like it's not a done
deal but i've already had my selection
i've already made a step you know in the
process so i already know like
even if they tried some some [ __ ] boy
[ __ ] which i know is gonna happen anyway
because i've been doing this a while um
there's no way in how they'd catch up
so you know i left that out but you know
the
ultimate goal was to you know refine it
further and further
further along into uh
the the dominion g
and having like a really just
same thing with the
the pole cat you know having that nasty
that kim skunk
blend on the on the nose and just knock
down
kick-ass potency and just good
well-structured plants that weren't
floppy or anything you know and stuff
that was good and hearty that you know
you could grow it indoor or outdoor
and not finicky so
in the hills and the cold
yeah they can they can take it they can
definitely
that was my favorite was growing it up
in the mountains when it was all cold
and [ __ ] it would just get thick man
those branches would be like arms yeah
by far one of my favorite another big
thing about something you
talked about was
when you're curing
you leave about like one or two inches
on your petioles right yeah man dude
that's been a huge thing for me that has
helped me out so much with my grill
yeah it really it really helps with that
with the drying process man like
it keeps things more consistent you know
so you're not drying up in one spot not
the other nice consistent drying and it
acts as like like kind of acts as like a
wick almost you know just kind of slowly
and surely just evenly
displacing that that moisture that we're
trying to get rid of you know
yeah dude turn me on to that back in the
day and
i was like yeah [ __ ] it you know he
found out by accident too yeah it was
you know some remembers this little lady
or his daughter or what but
just helping him do it and this wasn't
yeah using scissors it was a snip snip
snip so if something left it and he was
like oh no you can just break them off
and just leave it you know by the branch
like whatever
and then he had all the ones that they
you know had done like that they noticed
like wow that that made a
substantial difference there so then he
started doing it on purpose and turned
me onto it and say i'll be down
nice dude hell yeah
see before that i was doing a whole
plant hang i would leave on all the fan
leaves and everything like that and it
really i mean it was okay if you had a
couple of plants in there with really
good air flow but uh yeah you got that
thing packed after like an outdoor
harvest or something it's like jesus
christ there's so much moisture in here
and i would take them all the way down
you know cut the entire leaf off petiole
and everything and then when i heard you
say that i started leaving a little
extra on there and it actually helped
out quite a bit
yeah
yeah like i said it's those little
things that we pick up and
we start adding all those little things
together and make a real successful
regimen there you know
yep
so you shouted out
the dominion g the screaming eagle
and what was the other one oh man i can
the six mil yeah like
the six mil what was the six mil i'm not
familiar with that one
that was the uh the local with the
screaming eagle i made for my uh for my
buddy kevin that passed away there's
like two of his uh two of his favorites
his nickname he's calling the six
million dollar man
oh rest in peace to him and that's
awesome of you for making something in
his
in his likeness like that
yeah man i was gonna do it you know
doing it doing it for him anyway you
know but
is this this weird thing like uh yeah
like a spot on his back and like i've
seen it there since
[ __ ] 90s it was just like a big it
wasn't even like a mole even you know it
was just
like a giant freckle
birthmark
yeah yeah that's what you know i figured
and you know forever goes by and
you know he has old lady you know he met
later and she's you know she's like a um
a nurse or whatever and it's like yeah
you know this wouldn't hurt to get it
checked out you know
and i guess he said yeah he would go do
that
i guess they cut it to do a biopsy or
whatever and it had some crazy reaction
and
just cancer spread throughout his body
he was dead in 72 hours
oh wow yeah
that's horrible man yeah man sorry to
hear that yeah through me threw me off
because by the time he had had it done i
talked to him that day
i didn't hear from him the next day
and then the following day i'm like hey
anybody heard from him you know and my
buddy tj is like you know they're
they're best friends too
he's like yeah he's in the hospital he
tells me this is happening and i was
like is there any way i can you know
like talk to him he's like he was in so
much pain they you know had to uh had to
put him out
and i wasn't able to you know say any
you know anything so i just wrote up a
text and it was just like
you know
thought of my
you know my
final final thoughts or
you know whatever
and uh i was hoping you know maybe if he
did wake up you know maybe he would see
it or something but
he ended up uh he ended up dying that
you know that following day
well it sounds like he would be a guy
that would really appreciate what you've
done to honor
oh yeah oh yeah it was
you know being a in a hanover county
virginia dude
he he just thought it was the greatest
[ __ ] thing ever that you know i
moved out west and was just doing things
uh
doing things legit and like really doing
it up
no he wanted a real proper you know he
just thought that was just the best [ __ ]
ever you know
that's your family right that's the ones
that want to want to see you doing good
that want to see you succeed that's
awesome man yeah man yeah kevin he was
uh you're lucky you're lucky you had him
yeah man he was the best you know known
him since like
something like that you know and uh
yeah some best best friends you know
it's just
awesome dude but
you know i'll just have to
get to catch up with him on the
flip-flop you know yep and that'll
happen always does man i believe we're
in energy oh yeah man absolutely yeah
much created can't be destroyed you know
so on a brighter note
we wanted to talk to you about some of
those old skunks that you worked with
since that's kind of one of your
mainstays you had a lot that you did
like you said the dominion skunk
i remember
you had one that had a cross in it and
it was called basic skunk and i always
thought that was funny like
you know you especially in this day and
age duke i know i know you've been
you've been away for a bit but dear god
if you're hearing some of the names that
people are coming out with now
oh yeah dude orange creamsicle puppy dog
like this is the best [ __ ] oh dude it
was it was going on
before i left and we would make fun and
be like yeah [ __ ]
uh sherbert [ __ ] butthole
[ __ ]
you know what i mean and then like all
of a sudden you're like oh wow
somebody's actually calling something
right now running out of dessert man so
these
sherbet bubble yeah who's on that [ __ ]
who's on that [ __ ]
yeah i could name a couple no
you haven't one buddy
gps names but
yeah i've always just been kind of
i don't know man
by the way my name and process is weird
i like the [ __ ] names that you come
out with man it's all good
polecat was a big one to me because
when i had my cousins moved over to
montana
they lived on pole cat road
and so that name stuck out to me i was
like [ __ ] polka we gotta grow pool
cat man like
that's pretty dope but when you had that
one i remember seeing the cross on it
said basic skunk and i said
that's such a funny
way to name something when we were
talking earlier about like the old
tactics of oh you can't have that one
like
right but who wants basic skunk like
that sounds like it's [ __ ]
it's basic man
what was the basic skunk and why did you
name it that
it was a it's the nl skunk and l skunk
type hybrid and back in the day
they had the um
the basic five
uh through sativa c12 skunk hybrid which
is nl5
that's what they they i guess that's
what they decided to call it then
oh so this was a ssc original yeah that
was their old name okay uh for nl5
well that makes more sense now okay
yeah exactly so yeah using
the like an old scentsy uh shiva skunk
and basic skunk and
making this hybrid it wasn't you know
the basic five
skunk hybrids so it was just like i
would just call it you know basic skunk
and it's cool because the name like that
it was something you know we were
keeping
you know keeping in-house and everything
but still this the name of line is like
oh guys this is basics
i need to look over here guy
right nice yeah yeah that would that was
a little bit beyond my time so it's nice
hearing those stories and getting
familiarized with where those genetics
came from
is that the same thing with the cis
skunk
or was that your creation no that was
that was that was one of mine yeah
okay so you did do the cis the granny
and the local one was just one that was
running around virginia
yeah that was another one that we um
that we were just goofing around back in
the day
and um
using a sour diesel ibl when we were
goofing around with that
which that
wanted to pass out some testers to a few
people we knew some people that already
were already growing sour
and uh he wanted our feedback on it you
know because we could give a real
feedback in comparison to the client
because back then
you didn't have a whole [ __ ] ton of
people growing sour diesel you know you
didn't have even that many people ever
even smoked it so
you needed the good feedback
and um they're just goofing around had
the had the had the mail or whatever
we had this other uh
ash plant flying back then called the
cuttlefish plant okay and
yeah so we were goofing around and
that's where the local came from but we
call it it was called the local h we
were jamming out on the uh
on the radio we had a little radios
underneath of a friend's house we had uh
dug out a pit made a false door and [ __ ]
no
are you serious oh yeah
like shawshank [ __ ] redemption dude
dude what the [ __ ] yeah
are you my long lost brother
don't you're not gonna tell me you
started growing with a heat lamp did you
even had a cop or a neighbor okay maybe
well [ __ ] you mr fancy
no no um my uh yeah no my uh my first
was the no we had we had the same thing
false door [ __ ] well it was like a
little cellar and [ __ ] but yeah we had a
chicken heat lamp that was we thought
that was a good idea yeah no
outdoors outdoors first yeah
yeah
yeah it was straight up in the dirt man
we literally bug it dug it out a little
by little and we'll take ass bags up and
walk around the backyard shifting the
sifting the dirt out like shawshank
that's dope dude
so yeah
i ran electric to it and uh yeah we got
a nice nice little [ __ ] grow down
there we had a little radio hooked up
and that band local h you know that was
on to and that [ __ ] was like straight
like some dope too but
it was really really sour really really
potent you know the name kind of stuck i
was like yeah you know we'll keep that
so that that came from there
and then making uh making hybrids with
that you know it was definitely a really
really good one you know
hell yeah man you also
like you seem to like the citrus stuff
too right oh yeah man yeah i got i got
some citrusy ones like because you did
the g13 too yeah yeah the airborne g13
had that like pink lemonade citrus thing
going on yeah that was the mom and the
uh screaming
the screaming eagle project oh so that
was in that screaming eagle yes uh
that's why i've heard that name so many
times [ __ ] well [ __ ] i missed out on
that one
yeah exactly it's 88 g13 hashtag as a
mom afghani
there's the donor
big selection from there find the mail
from there and then hit the airborne g13
was that that virginia beach afghan
no no no this is a
kandahar afghan
that was used for that yeah the the
virginia beach ganny that's just the
as it's the girl this one we went uh
with the mail route down the mail
hit the 88 with it grab a bunch of the
girls saw what i wanted to see
found the mail that was best
corresponding to that
and hit the airborne with it so that way
we got a good good amount of uh d13
genetics in there plus there's some nl2
because half of that airborne is it's a
g13 nl2
from old neville seed bank stock if you
grew him out
you know his little handle was airborne
so um
you know that was his keeper so
you know between the uh afghani and the
88 hash plant the rg13 hash plant we
were kind of getting
good symmetry you know good the things
are syncing up just just right
so it ended up
[ __ ] awesome
i really really love that one
it's a great one i'm gonna continue to
work with that one too man
so
philly you know well you answered one of
the next question
yeah yeah
i need a
an affiliate
read that one
and uh
come back at everybody with it
that way i can hone in on that one
phenotype that i feel is just
just so awesome like all of them are
great but there's the one pino that like
i mean it pops up frequently but like i
want i want the majority of the pack
popping something like that and since
there was only a limited amount of them
that went out to begin with anyway
so like general public because most of
them i gave out to veterans
for them to grow or people that were
grown for vets or ptsd and stuff and bad
anxiety problems okay yup that's why i
remember so i gave most of them
and then i had a handful left that sold
uh sold off because you know a lot of
people like well i mean just need that
just people
beating your door down you know so
everybody had basically hit me up that
was going to hit me up it was like a
whole
[ __ ] year maybe even more than a year
later i was like all right let the last
handful of them out people went
pretty much ape [ __ ] over it
and um i was like yeah you know it's
something i need to continue on because
i was so impressed with it
it's such a good good thing so
so would it be fair to say that you have
plans to get back into those find that
phenotype and back cross it
so i had already done um some
affiliate stuff with it anyway
and or two steps with it
and
it really honed in it really really came
down just just doing it like that so i
don't think um back crossing will be uh
will be necessary with that one so
you're going to go forward with the line
right on
yeah just doing doing the failure i
think uh you know
just
you know we'll do the f4
and then you know check it out from
there and that's probably where i'll
i'll leave it as just set up just set an
f4 i'll keep keep driving it in and then
and then i'm getting that result of that
for them you know i'm cool with that
hell yeah so everybody's got something
to look forward to eventually in the
future
oh yeah oh yeah
when you can
when they're where there's a little
there's a lie right
when you're a free man again that's
right
so one more that i wanted to touch on
was uh i was going back through
obviously i remembered the monsoon and
the pole cap but i you know a couple of
those the capital g that pop back up in
my head when you said cuttlefish i
remembered that being talked about
but i just wasn't familiar enough and
going back through your your types i saw
one that was named swayze
yeah dude
why is it named swayze is it sexy as
[ __ ]
it's kind of [ __ ] up for real but
so that one be uh it was the ghost og
that i use
with the stone
i love ghost can you remember the movie
ghost
swayze yes okay okay gotcha gotcha
wow i didn't even make the [ __ ]
connection jesus christ i even went i
read the i've read the description i was
like ghost oh gee i love ghosts
i didn't even jesus christ i'm such a
stouter
yeah so i i got a [ __ ]
[ __ ]
yeah dude and uh it'll make it it and it
would gush you out too man [ __ ] you
would uh and you know it's waiting used
to be sliding when i was like oh i'm
done i'm out i'm swayze dude that would
definitely put you out [ __ ] uh i tell
you like you used to like rock it out
like pretty hard and used to have like
real great runs of it it was a
j plant speaker
yeah he was he was doing some gnarly
runs of it he had a really really funky
skunky one too
all right so we had some questions from
my patrons that they wanted to ask you
cue ball oh
says did you ever think you'd be who you
are today in cannabis
no
i know i do
i knew like i wanted to do some good
things for people but i had
no idea that there would be
by the time i got out in the legit world
i just saw so much
[ __ ] and [ __ ] and
you know people that were not
not the best people in the past and i'm
like wow holy [ __ ] y'all are all of the
people running this now like
and honestly like it pissed me off
before i even moved out here
and i was like all right well you know
i'm still gonna go do my thing
and i think
you know i never expected it but one
thing i can say to anybody is like
you're just doing what you do
doing the right thing every day
if it's the right thing and the good
energy a good intention
people that have that that same
basis you know in their life you know
ethics and and quality and and and just
you know the whole
the whole can of worms man like
those people are going to find
themselves drawn to you
and
what's refreshing about the whole thing
is like there's so many
really really really good people still
left out there
and that gave me uh definitely gave me
hope
yes
on the future you know what i mean so i
never know i never never thought like
when people are like oh you're legendary
oh my god you're famous
no dude i am not [ __ ] eat [ __ ] i am
just normal [ __ ] virginia dude
[ __ ] that likes doing stuff and not
like doing it
yeah [ __ ] yeah don't forget where you
came from hell yeah man yeah it weirds
me out the first person asked for
autograph i'm like what
you [ __ ] with me right
and they're like no i want it and i want
a picture with you i'm like
all right
that's cool i'll do that
past always passing the good vibes man
you want a picture get a picture with me
i don't care but it is it i i get where
you're coming from man i [ __ ] vibe
with that for sure
i had a [ __ ] i had a guy pop into my
discord the other day i don't know who
it was but he said oh yeah i'm a long
time fan of doc alex and i was like i
got i got
fans [ __ ]
yeah the [ __ ] is this and then somebody
oh and then another one of my buddies
called me boss the other day i was like
i'm not your boss and he's like well
how do you perceive yourself and i said
honestly podcasting i was like yeah
everybody wants to talk to breeders and
[ __ ] i just know something i got some
connections and [ __ ] talk to people
yeah i'm just a dude dressed like a dude
playing another dude
i said i feel like i'm the lorax
of the stoners
i'll speak for y'all
got the hair and all we're good
all right another one of our patron
members vanilla rice i love that name
vanilla rice
he said i heard you use fruit juices in
your feeding regime is it
ffjfpj or are you talking about actual
fruit juice
i don't even know what ffp
it's k f inputs fermented plant juice
and fermented fruit juice oh
okay
all right no um so i'm using actual real
organic fruit juice i'm actually
going out to like the real hippie out
stores and getting a really uh
good organic fruit
i'm going like full on jack lalanne i
got a got a
processor
i can [ __ ] turn it into a puree
and i'm mixing it all together
and then from there yeah i'll firm it
and there's a dude that asked me earlier
like i saw the diode and had a chance to
get to it but he was like so do i add uh
you say break it down do i need to add
like yeast to it
and i need and get back no unless you
want to make brandy now if you want to
make random
and make some liquor then yes
we do not want alcohol uh water and any
alcohol so no we're not gonna do that
you know break it down
so you are you're making about the best
type of ffj fpj you could you're doing
whole fruits right skins everything yeah
the whole thing letting it naturally
ferment that's knf brother
that's what you're doing
yeah man right right here in america how
about that
do you strain it out or do you use all
the pulp
i strain it
you strain it drain it out just for like
you know running it because like i would
water using a pump um i didn't want too
many solids left behind but all the
leftover i threw in my uh in my compost
bin and then i use it as top dressing on
the uh on the pots
oh [ __ ] and then you're throwing a mulch
layer over there
yep
okay i was gonna say my only
concern would be like ants and bugs and
[ __ ] like well you're doing this indoor
too right yeah yeah exactly so you're
controlling okay okay that makes sense
yeah dude that's awesome
yeah
yeah man so yeah well we're farm
castings on top of a little insect brass
mix some leaves up over top of that you
know with some bokashi under it you know
and
you're in the skin zone man
okay so another patron member okay calyx
uh good friend of mine
i'm gonna shout him out right now okay
calyx of okay galaxy genetics go hit him
up if you haven't seen him great [ __ ]
dude duke you love him good guy
he wanted to know
how long till you were growing again we
kind of talked about that already uh
future breeding plans did you have
anything else that you want to do other
than the the screaming eagle
oh man so
so much
the thing is with me is like
like i can say like yeah definitely
there's a lot
but the way that uh that i work is uh
yeah it's really long they'll know when
it's done
yeah it's willy wonka [ __ ] they don't uh
don't come out the well out into the
know until it is it's beyond done it's
literally ready for drop yeah before i
even mention it don't count your eggs
before they're hatched right
well there's that and also there's just
too many knockoffs out there and
scammers true very true you know like
they'll claim that they're doing it
you know they'll hear it oh that's a
great idea and then claimed that they
got it and they did it and there it is
available for sale
or they might even hear of a
client that's not even known of i've
seen this happen so many times and it
becomes this hot word oh yeah i'm using
this one this one this one then before
you know it all got you yeah for sure
and so we just yeah it's
it's
dude that yeah that's kind of the shitty
thing about being you know held in
regard right
yeah man yeah they're looking uh you got
a lot of people looking out for you and
then you got a lot of people looking out
for you and they're looking they're
looking to you know take advantage of
you guys
okay
i don't know if there's some inside
information i don't have or what's going
on here but he says
what was the new exciting strain of the
emerald cup
[Music]
well
no another one we can't talk about
there
well there was one that heroes of the
farm pat was doing
and then we did some stuff back in the
day
freedom fighter
they might be talking about that
there's one
that i did back in the day and i gave
them all to uh aka dean brains
and i was like yeah just have them like
what i was like well you gave me a clone
and
you know this is what happens like
things are gonna come back to you i'm
not i'm not giving them out i'm like
releasing them or anything i just want
you to have them if you want to do
whatever you can sell them your own
whatever you want it's just thank you
so uh we called it uh we called
and it thunderhole
the mail was called ass man and it hit
the thunderclock
oh his bad news
yeah so i caught thunderhole and he had
them and then
i guess uh they'll be available here
here in the very very near future
because i gave him a lot yeah so he just
had him so
i'm definitely seeing that same [ __ ]
vibe now i understand why ak said i
would like you
i was like yeah i can see that
[ __ ] saying thunder hole too
oh yeah yeah
yeah piss [ __ ] damn [ __ ] you know yeah
so the thunderhole
what
has he got to talk to you about it much
like what is it that he loves about it
so much
and just insane amounts of resin and
really really strong knockdown potency
but
he was getting these uh a real strong
orange uh citrusy
finos that he was just blowing away with
like nice
christmas tree bud
i was like yeah knock down puts is
definitely i was like between that man
and the thunder [ __ ] it's like it
doesn't really have much of a choice
you know
right yeah big beefy plants man and um
yeah just
get out and [ __ ] plop down they take
knock you down [ __ ]
good deal man
so are you more in
i mean you work with skunks you work
with g13 you also do so much afghani
work and [ __ ] do you have like a
preference in the type of high that you
enjoy i like them all
oh this depends on the time you're like
yeah they all have their own place
exactly is there one that you're like
wanting more than the other
ah like so
and this is kind of segue with the you
know we were talking about medical stuff
too
is like if you smoke that same thing
every day day in day out yes you build
up that tolerance and it's just not as
great as it was you know you said like
chasing the dragon looking forward again
but you just got you got to put it down
and get away from it so i always like
you know the so for our time and place
so like my day times
three to five different things i like
for the daytime
intermediate in the evening i want to
chill but i still got to do [ __ ]
you know at three to five i like that
and three to five for just knocking me
the [ __ ] out at night yeah so that way i
can rotate through these and the same
thing with like dealing with medical
patients is like finding multiple
things that are getting to that same
goal for them and leaving them whatever
element it might be right
and that way they can rotate it so this
one day this one the next day and then
go through that cycle so they don't
really build that tolerance up to it so
they're getting good relief you know day
in and day out
so
yeah i had a lot of different little
ones for the day and then in the evening
and then you know definitely for the for
the night too
good deal good deal man i'm very much
the same i feel myself going for the
more heady [ __ ]
most the time and i'm one of those guys
that's like i'm gonna keep going and i'm
going all day until i pass the [ __ ] out
there's no relaxing and going to bed i'm
just like [ __ ]
when my body gives out i'm done and
that's when i'm gonna smoke my bedtime
[ __ ] yeah
so that's pretty rare for me in finding
a cultivar that i appreciate for that
time of the day
when i'm just i'm ready to go to bed i'm
done i want to be relaxed i want to lay
in my bed float for a second and fall
asleep yeah
what have you produced that you would be
like man this is this is what you need
to go out for betty bye
i would say
for the night
that local skunk was pretty [ __ ]
knocked down and uh
some of those phenos like it was just
over you know overboard
i would also have to say
these purple dahlia finos were real good
for me for going to sleep
[ __ ] yes
i was looking at that one
yeah
great i really like that one
stash plant was another another real
this heavy
put you out type type stone
grainy skunk that was another one that
was definitely more on the narcotic
narcotic side
screaming eagle
i'm like if you're really chief and
chief and hard you know it's definitely
gonna definitely gonna put you in that
zone too
there was uh the beefcake d which was
like a figure four uh male to the kim
dog d
that one was pretty
pretty heavy on the on the sedation as
well
i don't know why
but kim and og bring me up
like a [ __ ]
i was gonna say that too
i don't get that but a lot of people it
knocks out it brings me the [ __ ] up i
love kim in the morning
i had a yes i've had friends in the past
like you ever have any friends like they
put them on ridlon or adderall or
anything like that
no
no no all right so it's like a 80 [ __ ]
that would make a lot of sense though
bounces off the walls all the [ __ ]
time right
so they give them the [ __ ] and then just
mellows them out
you know allows them to concentrate and
you know do
right be more calm right
now if you give that same drug to
someone else who doesn't need that
they're going to [ __ ] bounce all over
the walls and and it's the exact
opposite right
right
so there's some people
that can take like narcotics even
percocets and oxycontin and shellica and
man they're they're [ __ ] singing
around the [ __ ] place doing doing
work and talking a million miles an hour
and then you know the next man
you know he's gonna be passed out for
about eight hours
so it's like
depending on the person you know it
really had you know you could say like
the majority of people
experience this but yeah sometimes it's
the exact exact opposite man
and i found that interesting with those
two because i'm typically one of those
people that
if it is more along that indica and i
say that very openly because that's such
a
you know coagulated topic of what's
indica what's sativa yeah but more of
those style of plants usually do put me
out and more of the hazes and the
sativas if you will do bring me up but
for some reason chem and og just they
don't fit that profile
you know what you could start using
yeah
all right man well [ __ ] we learned a
[ __ ] ton on this episode i'm so happy
you threw out all those [ __ ] tips
taking your time to talk with us about
your cultivars your plans for the future
and sharing so many [ __ ] laughs with
me man that was this was by far one of
my favorite interviews i've done and i'm
really glad i got to meet you thank you
oh man thank you
[Music]
what is up everybody your boy doc alex
here before we get going from this
episode i wanted to ask you were you
aware that we have our very own private
discord server
that's right very own private discord
server you can check it out entirely
free at discord gg forward slash calix
crew podcast
you will be limited to the general chat
in the reception area you can kind of
talk to me you can see what's going on
with your grower you can just share some
of your experiences and growing it's a
great community probably one of the best
platforms that i've ever dealt with if
i'm not coming across too cocky we've
got a great team of people in there if
you want to unlock a little bit more if
you want a little bit more of the calyx
crew podcast experience you can check us
out on patreon at patreon.com forward
slash doc underscore calyx we have two
different tiers in there we have a five
dollar tier that unlocks all of the
discord we have a total of
got like 161 channels in there
everything from growing showing off your
glass showing off your joint heart
teas brewing teas integrated pest
management pretty much anything you can
think of
we've got a team of specialists that are
just [ __ ] killing it and they're
really helping me out teaching guys how
to do stuff that even i didn't know i'm
learning [ __ ] in there every day so i
want to give a quick shout out some of
those guys that are helping me out
shiggity flips our very own sip
specialist if you guys aren't familiar
with sip it's a sub irrigated planter
it's an awesome way to do organic
growing in an organic and growing
environment he's also on instagram you
can check him out there tk geico our
scrog specialist you can find him on
instagram as monster scroggin always
killing the skog if you want to learn
how to scrog that is the boy to go to go
check him out tinkle turp is our host if
you come into the discord he will see
you right away grow green daddy our
league content creator that helps us out
with all of this you hear them on the
mid rolls my funny australian bastard
friend i love him to death and then my
other australian friend harshi83 who's
in there moderating our discord awesome
dude we also have a 10 tier if you guys
want even more behind the seasons
content we just had an awesome one with
duke on the story of tommy two dicks
we also do q and a's with our podcast
guests we do game day giveaways the
infamous do or dab that everybody's
heard of you get a chance to come in
there play games win free prizes
build a community an awesome [ __ ]
community it's worth checking out at
least completely for free jump in there
see if you like it and we'll go from
there love you all appreciate y'all
thank you for supporting the show and i
will catch you on the next one this is
doc alex saying good night and grow
ready
[Music]