[Music]
good evening everybody and welcome to
another episode of calyx and crew
podcast before we get started i want to
give a quick shout out to coconut
sensors coconut sensors has one of the
best sensors on the market right now at
a retail value of only what 69
you can pick up a sensor that checks
your humidity your temperature your vpd
and i heard from anton coming here soon
is also going to include not only the
chart
for the live vpd but co2 as well which
is very very nice
today's episode i'm highly stoked for
i've been anticipating this for a very
long time
very long overdue he just did a podcast
with the james loud show
romy lynn jake of romulan genetics
how you doing
good how's everybody doing good man very
good it's an awesome day we finally got
some heat over here today i got a little
bit warmed up i rolled up some sour
diesel for this and i just wanted to
talk to you you know
we've been talking about doing something
like this for a very long time and today
is the right day
today is the day
so before we get started
not all of my listeners are going to
know who romulan genetics is the story
behind romulan or anything like that why
don't you introduce yourself really
quick tell everybody who you are what
you do what your company is about and
what your goal is
i'll try to remember all this
[Music]
my name is jake i'm the owner of romulan
genetics you can find us on
rumblinggenetics.com
i've got an instagram under the same
name i've been around in breeding for
going on two or three years now i forget
in 2015 my father passed away and as
part of him passing away
the romulan clone that was kept in our
family which wasn't known as ramayana by
our family but it was handed over to me
and it was kind of the torch was passed
and i was told to keep it alive and do
well with it and
i started uh by giving clones and cuts
away for a long time and then eventually
kind of people just kept pressuring me
you know hey you got to make seeds you
gotta you gotta do some stuff and so i
started doing it just as a hobby and i
got such great positive reaction it
turned into far more than that it's kind
of become a life calling passion more
than a hobby now i'm really stoned right
now so i'm gonna try to
remember i remember you said my goals
and then there was something in between
something in between that maybe i missed
there but as far as future goals i don't
uh
i've got a small little road map plan
that i've been sticking to for the past
few years of
things that i you know right when i kind
of set my mind that i'm gonna do this
and do romulan genetics
i came up with a bunch of stuff that i
knew i wanted to breed it with that i
knew i wanted to try and see what it
would come out like and then i had some
other things that were personal projects
that i wanted to do
and so i've been sticking to that road
map and i've got i don't know about
another two or three years left of that
and i figure once i get done doing that
it has a lot to do with making a as many
rig seed lines as i can along with a few
feminized versions in between to kind of
keep people happy that like to grow
those
but my plan is with the reg steep stuff
is is to get us a decent stable for me
to work from so that over the next 10
years and a couple years from now i can
start stabilizing those lines the ones
that i like the most
do some things where i you know final
hunt and find some really nice unique
ones and make feminized versions of
those for people
but try to eventually get to where i've
got about maybe a dozen ibl versions or
close to that
and that's my long long term goal
but that's stuff that will
you know we're talking at least 10 years
beyond that for me to just get a few
things available at that point that's
awesome though man you got plans already
to take what your father bestowed upon
you and put your own signature on it i
love that
i love it i want to take a step back
really quick
because you just said something that i
hadn't heard from you before
and that's that your family didn't know
it as romulan right
what did you know
so it was just basically because back in
the day there weren't really when i was
growing up and this was in the 70s and
the 80s
you didn't really have as many names for
mud it was really about the location
where it was from you know it was maui
wowie and a few exceptions but right for
the most part you were talking about you
know alcohol gold or colombian red and
it was called red because the hairs were
red or gold because the hairs were gold
and where it came from and this was
called pine bud
and there was a mountain nearby where i
grew up called pine mountain so some
people would call it pine mountain bud
people that were close to my father
would call it g-dubs bugs those were the
initials but it was mainly because it
smelled like pine and nothing else some
people just referred to it as the pine
bud
that's awesome man because that's
exactly how i came to know it before the
name romulan came by was port alberni
pine but that's what we always right
and when i when i when i first got into
this i didn't know about
that that was stuff that i had to learn
early on getting into this and talking
to people and they said you know there's
a much deeper history than what you can
kind of just look into on the internet
and then i started talking to my my uh
pop's friend that was that hadn't passed
yet and getting more information from
him and
and that was where i learned a lot more
about about all of this because
initially it was just that wow i know
this plant's great it's fantastic i gave
it to some friends
and then the word coming back was i mean
it's it's a lot more than that and
people don't really have this anymore so
you have to try to get it to as many
people as you can did that so it went
from just a burden
it did you know it went from this really
kind of small thing like you know no big
deal like i'm sure i can keep it alive
you know and i've got i've got my dad's
friend that i at the time he was still
alive and i you know i can talk to him
and he can tell me what to do if i've
got questions and it was real you know
carefree you know and i remember my
first harvest and i think it and i just
was floored at how good it was
and you know okay this is i'm gonna keep
doing this this is great this is kind of
what i've wanted to do my whole life is
have my own grow that no one [ __ ] with
and
so i can definitely do this and then as
soon as i started giving some of the
flower to friends
then people started asking me for the
cut and i started giving that to them
and then you know month down the road
they were coming back to me saying you
can't just keep this to yourself
you have to you have to get this out so
yeah the burden really kind of got heavy
at that point because i knew that wasn't
something i was
prepared or wanted to do or capable of
at all
and i started just giving it away to
people and i
was on forums and eventually people said
oh you know go on instagram and i got on
instagram and i was trying to find you
know people that wanted it that had the
biggest grows that i could find on there
you know big outdoor grows and stuff and
people that were in california as local
to me as i could find
and i eventually got to give it to their
nursery and i gifted it to them and i
remember and i kind of had this fantasy
that you know it's only going to take
them a couple months and they're going
to be clones are going to be everywhere
and it was years later before they even
did their initial release
during that time i had people asking you
know can i get seeds from you can i
study i have some old ones but i don't
really want to give them away this is
all i have for my dad and so it doesn't
really go well with me
how old are you and uh when he passed
that cut to you
this was in 2015.
so yeah i'm damn near 50 now okay
so it was it wasn't that long ago when
he actually passed it to me but i grew
up around it and i was i can literally
remember in my diapers
it was it was around before i was born
so right
well you said it was a long-term project
between a lot of guys
yeah
so
did you have any growing experience
prior to your dad giving you this cut
i had
not
all on my own i had grown up around
growing and cultivating and i'd helped a
lot of friends
do things various different growth
outdoor closets all that kind of stuff
many many times but i had never it was
never my grow it was never from
beginning to end
no one else was doing it it was always
just kind of i'm coming over to a
friend's house and we're doing this
together
at best or it was i'm giving him advice
you know
so it wasn't really
ever my
grow and it it
there were several well i was involved
enough where it was you know this is our
pot and everything you know me and my
friend were saying how we grew this but
it was never my own and it never felt
like
i knew what i was doing so whoa that's
it
was such a burden then
yeah exactly you know i had a decent
amount of knowledge and i had a lot of
access to everything i needed to know
but at the time i
i knew enough to get started that was
about it
right
so
now
you're kind of down the line for a while
you did an awesome job at preserving
those genetics i guess they
and now you're hybridizing all these
things to find new things to hunt
through to kind of take that romulan
staple and put your own signature moves
on it and i love that i gotta say that
fritter bomb that you made recently
if you would have caught me any other
time
i would have just called [ __ ] like
with a lot of cookie stuff i usually
call [ __ ] but we do our hype strain
reviews
and on our hype strain reviews we did
smoke that apple fritter and that was
one of maybe three of the hype strains
that i've ever smoked that i was like
that one's actually really decent
yeah
and uh love that's lumpy's who who made
that and he's pretty local to me here
too so that that one was special to me
that katsu chose that because it was
it's a guy that's you know i don't know
him personally but he's not far from me
and i think he created that in 2010 or
2012 it's been around here for a long
time and it's just now starting to
become this big hype thing so it's been
really cool to watch that process
so that one was really special to me and
i was fingers crossed that that was
going to turn out good and it
blew my mind how good it actually turned
out
if you've smoked apple fritter you know
it's it's pretty potent stuff oh yeah
and the two of them together is it's uh
it's real good and the taste is amazing
i think a lot of people that are kind of
chirp chasers and flavors are going to
love it just because of that but because
it's so potent and so strong
how did it get you right your profile
it's not exactly the same as it smells
you know a lot of things though
but it it's got a real good sweetness to
it
and it's kind of
the best way i can describe the smoke
because for me i have a harder time
pointing down flavors than i do smell
it's kind of like smoking a sweet candy
that's got some
kind of cushy piney
ganja type you know
flavor in the background to it but it
really it's like it's almost like
smoking candy it's
i'm trying not to dip back into it and
smoke some other stuff because when i
get stuff that's that tasty i
i'll smoke an ounce every few days and i
can't see it like that that's too much
preserve it a little bit yeah i'll just
be sitting on my couch like a zombie 24
7.
so let me ask you
when you were looking at putting your
own signature on this
and finding
things that you were going to breed with
the romulan
what were the boxes that you had like
what were you looking for
so that one's real easy i want romulan
that
tastes different i want to be able to
have some options to smoke
different tastes
i love raw meal and i smoke it all the
time i smoke it every day i've been
smoking it for years straight and i
never tire of it but it's nice to smoke
stuff that tastes a little different
every now and then right most the stuff
that i go out and get or i get from
friends or i grow myself that is a
totally different profile
i don't really like smoking it i like
the taste of it but i you know 10
minutes after i smoke it i'll go and
smoke the omule because
that's the high that i want to feel i
don't want to feel whatever it was that
i just smoked right
so that's the first
category of that is make a bunch of
things try to at least
that affect me just like romulan does
but have a different taste to it
different smell
and then i want to have
after that i want to have things that
are more far more sativa leaning or far
more into cleaning i want to have stuff
that's you know
better for her if i just want to zonk
the hell out or watch a movie or yeah be
really couch-locked yeah oh you know
more stuff where i you know i want to be
almost like i'm on amphetamines or
something you know cleaning my house
mowing my own and doing everything right
yeah i want to have that broad spectrum
because i like everything that that
there is within the cannabis world for
smoking
so
first this flavors and trying to stick
with stuff that hits me just like
romulan and then it's that kind of stuff
that's
it's close to the romulan effect that i
can get but leads far more in one
direction than the other
no this is why you and i have always got
along is because you're very [ __ ]
real with what you say
you're not trying to promote yourself
out of nowhere you're just telling it
how it is and the fact that you're
working
with romulan in this way
because it's something that you love to
smoke
and you want to take that to different
lengths that are still going to work
good for you specifically that means
that you're breeding for what you
like and you're actually putting that
intent in it and that's going to come
forward in your work
i hope so
i can't remember all of them
you know i go through so many seeds all
the [ __ ] time i got so many friends
that do this
i forgot everything that you had to
crossed the romulan with
what all did you pick other than the
apple fritter
so
for the cats who collab
that's uh he he made those selections
that was all his choices
i think he may have
tried to choose things that
he knew i would be interested in like
two because he did make a lot of
selections right up my alley and in fact
several of two or three of the things
that he crossed with he didn't know what
i was doing at the time and we made the
exact same cross we both made a road
kill skunk and romeo and cross we both
made a great vape in romeo and cross
and that was one i think one other thing
we both did the exact same thing
and on one or two of them i think the
grapevine we were using the same cuts so
we were literally making the same cross
the roadkill skunk i hunted mine from
seed
that i got from copycat which was i know
some people have issues with that and i
don't really give a [ __ ] i had some
people i highly respect said
it doesn't it doesn't matter what what
you hear about him if you're going to
grow something of his and you like the
old school [ __ ] get his vocals and it
was a guy that's been growing for 30 or
40 years that told me that and then
someone else repeated it it didn't have
quite as much cred in my in my world but
it was yeah i heard it from several
people and i went okay yeah i'm gonna
get it and they were right it was legit
and it was fantastic and i found one
that was
the one that i chose was not quite uh
the skunkiest
that wasn't the best selection in that
area but it had a really nice structure
had a really massive yield to it
compared to the other ones
and it didn't have as much of a
branching issue or anything it didn't
need any support so that was my
collection because it was a real nice
reader
i wasn't going after it just for the
skunk profile
that's awesome i really appreciate
strong branching
list they want a good structure
but like if all the progeny you know
they're either weak and limpy or strong
they don't really mind too much
and it makes it a lot less work when
you've got something that yields really
nice that's not flopping all over its
[ __ ] self needs to be managed on a
daily basis
yeah
i can't help because of my personality
with being kind of ocd with my growth
when i'm doing them and so i'm in there
almost every when i'm breeding i'm in
there every day checking every single
plant
looking trying to literally with my
eyeballs and hands look at every node
every portion of it going over the whole
plant to make sure nothing's going wrong
nothing's you know
and
if you trellis things and have all kinds
of supporting that gets to be a huge
pain in the ass to even get in and
prune and trim and things like that so i
can't stand
the fact when my romulan cut is it's a
pain in the ass and that in that sense
you have to support it you have to
trellis it in almost every type of
throat
and it's a lot of work in that sense and
so i try to when i'm reading with it i
already know that that's an issue so i
try to choose things that are gonna not
continue that as much as possible
awesome
exactly that's exactly what you want to
do is you know with every
outcrossing that you do you want to take
what you already had and make it better
the point isn't to go backwards so the
fact that you're breeding for those
weaknesses within it that really shows
your passion i appreciate that thank you
so it's the learning process and
i kind of thought getting into all this
breeding stuff i was like you know
there'll be some
some failures i'm sure i've heard that
you know but i figure probably most of
the stuff because if i choose right most
stuff i make will be will be great you
know
it's been like maybe a third 30 25 of
what i've made has been
okay now this actually is stuff that i
can i can sell for people
we're going to take a short break and we
will be right back with romney and jake
of romulan genetics stay tuned
[Applause]
hey guys while we're on short break i
wanted to give a quick shout out to one
of my favorite sponsors one of the best
affiliates that we have on the show
coconut sensors you guys can find them
over on ig over at coconut inc where you
can find their website at
www.coconaut.com that's k-o-k-o-n-a-u-t
dot com
i believe their sensors retail at sixty
nine dollars each and it's such a cool
little device guys i cannot praise them
enough i use them in all of my rooms
especially at that price you can't
really beat it they are battery operated
the batteries have never ran out on me
and i've been using them for over a year
now i believe i heard that the batteries
can last in them for up to two and a
half years but that comes with the price
point what coconut does it's a pretty
amazing little device you can get an app
that works with it on google play
you can get it on the apple store
but what it does is it connects your
climate data
to your hands so you can tell what's
going on in your environment if you need
to go away for a while if you need to
take a vacation whatever you know what's
going on inside your grow room and it'll
help you keep track of keeping
everything
where it needs to be within vpd values
is pretty amazing it tracks it you can
bump it you can find it you can refresh
it at any point and see where your
humidity levels are at where your
temperature is at and where your vpd's
at it's a pretty damn handy little tool
you can add multiple sensors on the same
app so you can check your bedroom you
can check your clones your seedlings
your mother's your flower room whatever
you need to do
awesome awesome guys awesome retail
value i cannot
say enough good things about them i
heard they are also going to be
incorporating co2 as well soon so i'm
very much looking forward to that i
believe that is going to be a bit higher
price but not much not much at all but
with the co2 i believe he said it was
going to be running a higher power so it
is actually going to have to use a wall
plug on that one either way we love them
we support them won the best sensors who
won the best price points if you guys
aren't looking to go out there and spend
300 on a sensor but you do want to keep
control of your of your climate in
different grow rooms i would highly
suggest coconut sensors go give them a
follow over there that's
coconut.com one more time
www.coconut.com or you can find them on
ig at coconut inc
huge shout out and let's get it back to
our episode with romulan genetics
[Applause]
all right we're back with romulan
genetics before we left we were talking
about some of the
people that you were collabing with like
katsu you did the release with katsu
who else were you thinking about clavin
with
i've talked quite a few people and i've
for a while since i started this i've
had a
short specific with the people that i
wanted to work with katsu was on that
list before him and i even taught me
so i was really excited to work with him
and
that's turned out to be pretty amazing
because you know i see what most
breeders do with a collab and they make
maybe one or two strains and that's
their collaboration and then they move
on with their lives to other things
and that's what katsu and i were going
to do and it ended up turning into
really big projects and ongoing and
years worth of releases and
we're talking about doing more things
and so it's it's almost becoming more of
a a long-term partnership and a
collaboration
and he knows a lot so i'm learning a lot
from it too and getting to see
crosses with stuff that i've wanted to
see for years
and he just went and did it and got it
done and i get to see it so it's really
[ __ ] cool
but i did that with him and i'm talking
with
13 hills
in ufo genetics i think those might be
the next ones i don't know exactly if
both of them are going to happen or
what's going to happen with them because
we didn't get too deep into specifics
with it and it's been a little while
since i talked to ufo genetics but i
recently got my cut into
paul's hand he's the guy who runs
nuclear speed bank and he's uh
really good friends with a guy from 13
hills and the guy from ufo genetics so
he's going to try to then get my cut
into their hands because they're
and uh so those should be the next two
people that i'll be
doing one with hopefully if things go
well
i've talked extensively to gage green
group but it's been about a year since
i've talked to them and we never really
got into specifics
i haven't heard we didn't talk a while
yeah i was thinking the same thing
they've just kind of just kind of been
quiet for a bit hopefully that means
they're hard at work yeah and i'm sure
it does
but i've talked to them several times i
talked to uh ethos a little bit and both
of those i was pretty excited about so
you know i hope to maybe one day get
talking to them again about things
i think that's it as far as like what
will actually happen
there have been several other contacts
from from other people that things
probably won't happen because i just
you can only do so many things at once
you know yeah you can't fight too many
wars on different fronts you know
well so some people can it's you know
but i don't i'm not the kind of person
that will ever i'll never be dropping
two or three new strains every couple
weeks i'll i'll never do that you know
on a consistent basis for years some
people
drop things like that and that's
that's not how i work so
yeah i like smaller batches just so i
can really pay attention to those few
you know and try to take on too many
projects and your mind starts going all
over the place and becomes a little bit
fuzzy yeah i usually try to
i try to stick to it to one or two and
that's how i've done most things in the
past i just recently bumped it up and
did like a five different crosses at
once rig feed stuff
it was a little bit too much for me i
didn't like it so
i probably won't do that that many again
so it's too hectic having having to pay
as close attention as i do to all the
different plants and when they're all
different that's harder to do you kind
of have to like go wrote a row type
thing and a lot of times my plants will
get mixed up so i'll be like look trying
to look at the tag stick with the same
cultivar for until i get through them
and then move to another one but then
that gets too hard to do
she's paying me
yeah no i hear that man for sure so out
of all these collabs that you did with
katsu what would you say were the top
three that you personally you were like
i really appreciate this one
so we did the first one was a year ago
and it was a feminized speed line and he
did basically about the same thing that
we did with this
current release coming up with the
regular
he did like a dozen different cultivars
he reversed my romulan and let that dust
all these these things he'd been growing
for a while and working with
and
several of those
he we hardly got any seeds from it we
didn't get very much at all and there
were oh there was only enough from two
of them to release any so we released
old school dank which is kind of like
white romulan
it's the white ramen
and then we were released
yeah
and then we released uh space field
which is east coast tower diesel and
romulan and both of those were
top notch just fantastic but we didn't
have that many packs we didn't have that
many feet it was pretty limited release
i still have several packs of myself
that i kept my ball that stuff was
really really good but there were 10
other cultivars that no one really got
to see or smoke and i think only a few
testers got some stuff from katsu and
most of them were fantastic there was a
black line bubba kush in romulan that
was
about the most potent stuff i've ever
smoked i mean it would like feel like i
got hit in the head with a frying pan
and then i would just basically pass out
10 minutes
yeah you know i guess if you if you get
home from a hard day's work or something
that's exactly what you're looking for
oh yeah oh yeah
sometimes
but it was it was just remarkable on how
potent it was
and its taste was really good too
but there were several of those things
on the regular seed thing that
i just test ran and i'm smoking all the
stuff of it now and there's a few
there's two that haven't quite finished
up their long-winded 12-plus squeakers
so i'm waiting for those before i can
talk about those but
the fritter bomb
is probably
for what's going on in the industry
right now is probably the best one of
those that would be what i would pick
with number one if i'm trying to appease
everyone with my selection it's not my
own personal number one
but it's
the easiest to grow
just about the highest yielder in that
room and i ran
12 different cultivars
it was really really high yields uh
really pretty plant really frost covered
really potent really tasty you know just
kind of crossed all the different boxes
off that people look for these days it
looked really exotic and [ __ ] like that
that one was probably the number one
the
right now number two for me is
vapor trails which is the roadkill skunk
and romulan
because
it's got that old school flavor to it
and it's extremely potent on the indica
side and i don't smoke a lot of
harder indica [ __ ] it's i just try to
when i have stuff like that i only smoke
it at night
so it just doesn't feel like i'm smoking
that much of it because all day long i'm
smoking romulan from about an hour after
i wake up
until i go to bed and it's sometimes
i'll smoke a bowl every 10 minutes
that's nice i smoke a lot
yeah you know i smoke a lot a hell of a
lot and
sometimes i feel like i have to because
i have so much weed on me
that i have to keep smoking that much
because otherwise you know what how am i
going to do it it's eventually going to
go bad
well yeah i was going to say something
there but i can't
put a marker there
it's a pin in that one so
yeah
vapor trails number two and
probably the stocks which is u-dub and
romulan that'd be my number three wow
nice and that's because
yeah and that's because my choices are
kind of going to be a little different
like the head dip is awesome
that's how i've been in romulan
all of them are really good that's the
thing
they're all so good that it's kind of
hard to really choose and so most of
them it's like
well this is a lot like that parent or
this parent and so it doesn't impress me
as much as the ones that are
very unique in their own right
the ones that came out much more like a
true f1
are the ones that i've got my eye on
it's like wow those are special those
are really cool because when you look at
both parents they're coming out as
pretty evenly as something in between a
mesh of the two and quite unique and the
stonks is
really really special saying that f1 the
blend between both parents is very
dominant in that
yes exactly
yeah whereas
most of the other stuff it was
that things were in one direction or the
other there really wasn't as many
phenos that showed up that were in
between you know it was a really nice
mixture of the two parents that's most
civil war
that you can tell that leans more
towards romulan or you can tell that
lean leans more towards atmosphere
just as an example that's not a good
example
so yeah and the stonks one was really
interesting because there was a really
off smaller plant that
finished really fast and i got to smoke
it early on and it tasted exactly like
great blunt wraps
nice like really strongly so when you
smoked a bowl of it in a glass piece
it did this really strange thing with
your head where you're like
am i smoking blood wraps like i don't
understand what's going on here
and people in the room too like i the
first bowl i smoked i blew out and uh
someone walked in the room and they're
like are you so good i'm bloody here you
know
it's just sweet
everybody has a different perception of
what something tastes or smells like you
know
some of those and it is it is
interesting
it is interesting to see because i i do
get some people that have grown my
romulan cut and specifically my cut
they've got it from dark heart nursery
and every now and then i get someone
that
they're like oh it tastes you know
creamy vanilla it's something totally
different than what everyone else tastes
and i'm like i'm like really and can i
see a picture of the girl and they show
me a picture and it looks fantastic they
did a great job and i'm like they must
just have kind of like a different
you know yeah profile with the way that
their body takes it in
oh i remember what that when i did my
first and it was it was horrible i
didn't have a handout right off the bat
you know nobody gave me any cuts
everything i had i had to work from seed
but the very first cross i did
i just was not happy with it by the time
we got to f3 it just wasn't stable
but we i think i saw you talking about
that but we had all the testers growing
them out and it was very heavy on the
skunk side of its family
and all the testers by the time we came
to harvest they were saying oh it's
really really earthy skunky
or it was there was some like sweet
skunky phenotypes but everything was
like overall very skunky
it had a little bit of hawaiian in it so
you get that too but we had one duster
that said it tastes like mint i was like
is it dragged it's totally awesome it's
just totally off the wall it throws you
off too you're like oh [ __ ] really
i mean you know you went pretty far off
the spectrum
yeah one guy had me hunting for like a
female that i wasn't gonna find in mine
for a while that was weird
oh no then
we got talking about we got talking
about something else and he goes he goes
yeah this tasted like this to me and i'm
like what
wait a minute you know that's everyone's
smoking it
it was it wasn't lg it wasn't og but it
was something like that where everyone
universally says this is what it tastes
like you know and he was like nah no
it's totally different for me but i'm
like that with so many with so many
strings so many things and i was like oh
sh yeah okay
well i'm gonna start a new one out here
that sucks man
so how long were you hunting for that
one
it had been like uh
i was probably three gross so like nine
months
i made a cross one of the first early
things i did i never released it was the
hog with romulan and it was insane i
remember it was really really good but
it had a very high intersex weight it
was like 30 somewhere around there
and so i couldn't release it so i was
trying to hunt through it and find
better things but i had had people that
did test grows and they were like no
herms [ __ ] crazy yields like the
biggest i've ever seen
and super potent super potent
some of the best stuff i've ever had and
one guy
because i i wanted to call it alien
bacon once i realized i was going to
cross them i just kind of had that name
stuck in my brain
and one guy said no [ __ ] i have a fino
that tastes like bacon and i was like i
gotta find that
so that's what happened i was looking
for this bacon you know and it was there
was no bacon pinots to be found there
wasn't anything close to it i just i
kept looking now thinking yeah i'd be
looking for that too
that's awesome bacon
right who doesn't like i love bacon
everybody loves bacon i don't know i
mean not everybody i guess but yeah
they should they don't know what they're
talking about
got to be the pc one i gotta put another
marker now
there's probably countries where they
don't even know bacon and that's just
that's i know
god damn it more markers we should have
a bacon across the world
program will start and it'll give out
baking to underprivileged bacon cups oh
no
yeah i gotta cut that one out
i'm enjoying this man thanks for joining
me and doing it you said it was gonna be
a session smoke and be relaxed yeah
that's exactly what i'm being so
so is there anything else that you
wanted to talk about on the show man i
don't want to like force your hand or
anything
i mean i don't know i don't know quantum
physics i don't i don't know what do you
want to talk about
well you know now i kind of want to talk
about quantum physics you got some [ __ ]
or what
i mean yeah i i can go pretty deep in a
lot of different areas
yeah okay i've done i've done a lot of
reading and stuff throughout my life and
and my beliefs are very [ __ ]
let me start with what i believe in okay
so i believe
that
i'm a christian and i believe that most
of what's written in the bible all that
what in the bible is true most of it is
interpreted truly that's the best way to
explain it but you don't want me to have
a podcast today
but no no no no listen
this is this is important and you can
air any of this i don't care i studied
orthodox christianity and what what i
was taught
by the people who was teaching me in
orthodox christianity which is an older
form of christianity right is that
there is room within christianity and
believing in god and all of that for
bigfoots ghosts aliens wormholes portals
time travel [ __ ] anything
anything because
god created everything and as humans we
shouldn't question what was created amen
we should examine it and
do our best to interpret it and all
these things but we should not ignore it
we should not deny it and we should not
question it because if he created it
it's not our job to question what he's
made and that was one of the first
meetings i had and this was kind of
something i was being forced into i was
going into a marriage and they said you
have to be a christian
so i was going into it a little
hesitantly and i asked him these
questions and i said what about these
things because i've read the bible i do
believe a lot of it but there are some
issues i have and i explained my issues
and he said well
most people look at that the wrong way
because they don't realize with god
there is no time
so a lot of what you're reading that's
being explained is time isn't kind how
we see him that's how he sees you oh
yeah so maybe a day can you build a
million years
maybe it's a billion years can you get a
date
right so he's like a lot of people don't
realize that in reading it and they they
misinterpret things and they take it the
wrong way they take it too literally
so i have spent my whole life studying
all these different things and i firmly
believe i've seen ufos i've had
very dramatic bigfoot encounters
anybody not where people would have been
there's no other explanation that i can
plausibly come up with because it wasn't
people i was dealing with that were in
the forest
next to my property my dog was going
nuts my dog that doesn't bark at people
ever
never loses his mind and he was going
ape [ __ ] oh no
and there was something moving in the
bushes about five feet from my fence and
it's a fence this wrought iron you can
feed through it
and i couldn't see what the hell was
there
and
then something else moved 15 feet away
to the right then something else moved
way over here and i knew it there was
now i'm dealing with multiple things
because that one thing didn't move it's
still there making noise and so i
started talking and thinking it was
people
and i got no response nothing
and
i'm armed and so i pick up a rock
and i throw it high arc up in the air to
try to have it land behind
whatever is out there to hopefully get
them to at least make a movement so i
can better know whatever's out there
where it is
and as soon as the rock landed a rock
hit right next to me there's a huge pine
tree that's like
you know you can't even put your arms
around it dig around
a big rock hit the tree right next to my
head about 16 inches 18 inches from my
head and bounced off the tree right
behind me almost hit me
so it happened any bigfoot
that's the only thing that's the only
thing i come up with because um you know
i turned on the light after that at that
point i really kind of got scared
shitless yeah and i started shining
flashlights and spotlights and there was
nothing there and it's not it it's hard
for me to explain but it's not a place
where people
would be
it could possibly be but it's not a
place where people would be and they
certainly wouldn't be there at two
o'clock in the morning a group of them
without flashlights without anything and
able to move from the area without
making as much noise as
ever there's all kinds of sticks and
branches and whatever was there moved
away silently
it just
wasn't there anymore i heard very
minimal movement that i knew it was
moving and then it just wasn't there
i don't know how to explain it was
either a ghost that threw a rock at me
and many of them that were just [ __ ]
with me and my dog could see him and it
made the whole property smell weird
or it was bigfoot
no i just love how like dead on serious
you are right there or it was big
yep i had other people here that was
that was witness to it with me and
yeah don't let me know
i mean everybody has [ __ ] encounters
of some kind or like i'm just the worst
[ __ ] skeptic and it's probably
because you and i both have that ocd
problem
yeah but yeah i'm the worst skeptic ever
and i try to explain everything and yes
i get that because i've been down that
road the opposite way and like i've had
i've seen pans fly across rooms before
just all kinds it's a long story i'm
going to have to tell you about that
sometime
i actually went to college at what had
been recreated from a old mental
hospital and they turned into a college
and there was just some crazy [ __ ] that
happened there
but even miss c like she loves ghosts
and she's like and you don't believe in
ghosts and i'm like a ghost would
literally have to walk up to me and say
what
up you know i'd be like all right you're
real
yeah but yeah i get there like that it's
just like there's no explaining that you
know like seeing a knife
go off a three foot counter through my
buddy's uh rubber boot
oh jesus yeah you don't have enough
velocity to do that no
yeah and once you've seen something like
predators it's you're like you know okay
how do i explain that yeah
so anyway we talk about cannabis
sometimes right
yeah yeah let's just get back on subject
too let me this is what happens when the
weed you're smoking is too good
that's good way off track at least it
means we're smoking good stuff because
you and i are both in this i love it
this is by far one of my favorite
podcasts i've ever done i feel like
we're sitting on opposite couches in the
same room yeah
that's how it should be that's how it
should be that's how i've always done it
uh even back on when we did like all the
ig live shows that's all it was we were
just sitting there smoking talking about
weed with everybody and it should always
be like that that's what i love that's
my passion it works that way yeah that's
how it flows you know
it reminds me of you know my younger
days just going over to friends houses
friends coming over to your house just
to smoke you know
you'd sit there for hours just plain low
in the background just chatting laughing
that's what i'm shooting about
so i did want to ask you one question
that we always ask
all of our all of our guests
and this one i'm super interested in
because there's a few options now from
what you've said that you have to pick
through but we always say if there's one
i don't like to say strain anymore i
hate saying strain i've been saying type
cultivar type variety yeah
cultivar uh
well i think cultivar more as like
not a type i i find a type is more like
your fritter bron footer bomb crossed
with romney one and then like your cut
would be the cultivar right
yeah like that that's that's that's
so hot on
okay
you know i didn't question myself all
the [ __ ] time so i don't know
i agree we're gonna get technical about
it that's that's spot on yeah
so i like to ask people you know
out of everything that you have
everything that you work with
if there was one type
to represent your company and what your
goals are
what would you say it was
one to represent romulan
genetics oh jesus
the tough questions
i mean
i could obviously just be easily saying
well ramen you know this is my favorite
and i smoke me one time right but you're
putting your own signature
i'm torn between i'm torn between two
okay
one is communion that i made and i made
a rig seed and a feminized version of it
i don't think i ever released the reg c
version because that's i want to work
that further before i do any releases of
that but that one was
really really good and i i put a lot of
work into it i started by crossing two
other things first and working those and
then crossed that with romulan
time to do that yeah it was a great
stomper og and durbin poison if i'm i'm
remembering right if people are reading
my website or something right now going
no it wasn't then i'm sorry i have a bad
memory
that's what it was i've liked both of
those and i was excited just to cross
those two together
for some structural things i wanted to
see if i could bring over that the
trichome production of
and the
the bud siphon stuff from
the gravestomper into the turban poison
because that's just a gorgeous plant to
me and i love growing what about this
flavor
i love the flavor too
it's great i mean anything that's
anything that's older is just right up
my alley you know
basically if you get to if you go
through the history of cannabis once you
get to headband that's kind of where i
started checking out on
these things tastes great to me
everything after that just wasn't as
good as the older [ __ ] mm-hmm
so i said there was so between
between between the communion which was
that okay and that came out with a
really good grape candy or a wine kind
of flavor
and it was just delicious really really
potent but a nice like
you could chill on it and you know relax
the indica high but it wasn't like going
to put you to sleep
so i i spent a lot of times listening to
albums and stuff smoking that and i tore
through
i think i had like a
half pound of it and i smoked it in a
couple weeks or something it was just a
stupid short amount of time that i
smoked all this weed to myself
that one was really great but the first
thing that i made it ended up it started
as a poly hybrid project it ended up
being a double poly hybrid i made
called it ring of fire i got a feminized
release and i did a f1 release and
that one probably best represent
stands for who i am and what i do that's
awesome
that was
yeah i'm gonna work that further and
release uh like an f4 f5 if i get antsy
if i don't get anthony and i can be
patient it'll be an ibl by the time i
release it again
good
but that who knows how long that could
take me because there can be setbacks
and all that [ __ ]
so that one i think best represents me
because of the fact that that's the
first real thing that i made
that's what i set out to make
and i ended up with a double poly hybrid
which if you know about breathing those
that's it's far more complicated far
more complicated the more things you do
when you're doing that and
it was it was all over the place i had
so many clones i didn't know what the
hell to do with them
at one point i was i mean i was
jam-packed
and
that was how i wanted to start learning
to do this
was to try to
get the most difficult stuff
out of the way
first
so that everything else wouldn't be
a challenge in a sense it would it would
be enjoyable
and it
i'm really proud of that creation it was
something i spent a lot of time on and i
didn't i was like a secret i didn't tell
anyone for a long long time what i was
doing
and then when i finally released it i
kind of did it all without much notice
when i first dropped it
and did like a real limited release at
first and
gave it out to a bunch of people as
testers
that one i think best represents
what i do and what i want to do because
if you've grown it and smoked it the
feedback i've got from from everyone is
they absolutely love it there's a lot of
people that have keepers they found and
that's what they continue to grow
it was a really really good thing
it was a really really really good smoke
and um
i know i'm like sitting here going back
i know some of that i can see
but i think that's probably the one that
the best represents me
communion i would say also is there
because
a lot of the stuff that i will be doing
not so much as a personal project for me
is going to be like that the stuff that
i try to appease people with is going to
be more like community
the stuff that what i want is going to
be more like ring of fire it's going to
be stuff that may be unruly to trim it
may be a pain in the ass to grow but i'm
not going to care about that because my
ultimate
i can grow something it's fine i care
about how it smells that's
nothing else matters i don't care what
color the leaves turn that's stupid they
trim off anyway
you know so i only care about what it
smokes like and ring of fire was it was
finicky it was she was painting the ass
to grow she was a super painting they
have to trim their leaves and frost
everywhere
but the smoke made it all worth it
so
but i do try to do a lot of stuff
because i have people that are close to
me friends and stuff that say you know
hey you crossed these will you do that
so there are some things that i i'm
choosing and working things through i
made a mac one and it runs across with
romulan i crossed the mac one of the
runs together first and worked those and
made a selection
and then i crossed my romulan and i'm
calling it burning cap and that's a
strain that i'm probably going to be
releasing
somewhere within six months from now
and i did that project solely because i
had pressure from like three close
friends to work with those two cultivars
and work it with romulan and
two different people were specifically
one was asking for mac one was asking
for runs so i said [ __ ] it i'll make
them both happy and i'll start by
crossing those together and then i'll
cross that with romulan and uh i think
it turned out pretty good
yeah i think it turned out pretty good
but i never would have done that
at all if it wasn't for people asking me
if it wasn't for some of my followers
saying you know hey i would love to see
a month and run
people wouldn't even know about it if i
wasn't yeah so that's all that matters
there's a lot of stuff there's a lot of
stuff i've scratched that you know like
for example i didn't like it when i
crossed just romulan with mac one i
thought that might turn out okay because
i thought it would look good and it did
okay so you did try it out across it
yeah
that plant sucked and the smoke sucked
in my opinion it just
i would be saying the same thing if
those people who
could be offended were in the same room
yeah you'd be staying in in front of
[ __ ] respect
it's a lot easier when it's that way
because you know when someone gets
offended you can explain yourself and be
like you know i'll apologize and all
that if you can't fix it yeah but i
don't want i don't want to make your day
harder
yeah no i know i've been i've been
dealing with that long enough now where
it doesn't really trouble me as much
anymore
especially when it comes to time and i
still don't want to [ __ ] deal with it
the offending people drama thing has
gone very well for me lately when it's
happened i had a dojo seed stone ninja
he put a post up i didn't know about it
people were like oh my god coming at me
talking all this [ __ ] i'm like what the
hell is going on
and they're like you can't call this
strange uh cold stone because he had
made a strain name of old stuff yeah
we didn't know about it i think it was
him and i
yeah and he just put a post up and he
wasn't trying to start [ __ ] he even said
that in his post but it his followers
blew up on
and i got all his backlash and so then
i'm like hey hey brother i sent him a dm
and we just started chatting and
everything was totally cool right off
the bat and he was a great guy and i'm
like we'll just change the name it's not
a big deal we haven't you know it's
months from release doesn't even have a
date yet and he's like cool cool no
worries i mean you can keep the name if
you want i don't really even care
so he was super chill and everything
worked out fine we just changed the name
and there was like no drama but for a
couple days on instagram
it was you would have thought you know
someone's grandmother
so
let's end this how are we going to end
this
all right man well [ __ ] i want to thank
you for coming and joining me on this
yeah thanks for having me i know you
haven't done very many of these you
don't really like speaking publicly or
anything like that but i hope this
really helped you break out of your show
because you and i have been talking for
a while now
especially about doing something like
this
and it definitely helped i'm happy as
hell that you finally came out and that
you were able to you know talk about
this because your story is special you
know and uh i think it's something that
needs to be out there especially just
you as a person i respect you as a
[ __ ] person
and thank you i don't say that about
very many people
i appreciate that stupid i really do so
and thank you for having me on it's um i
know you and i kind of talked about
maybe doing something else
i as long as it's not immediately i'm
i'm definitely down to do this again
soon i just need to like i said i need
to catch up on my sleep what an amazing
episode i hope you all enjoyed it jake
is always a great person to talk to him
and i always click and it's just it's a
never-ending source of entertainment
talking to him and we look forward to
having him on the show again soon
before we get going i want to give a
quick shout out to our patreon that's
right we have a patreon it's only ten
dollars a month gives you all access
pass to our discord and it gives you
right up as far as learning how to grow
with k f
i'm merely
your guide in cannabis i'm not going to
teach you how to grow cannabis that's
something that people need to realize
you are the one that's going to teach
you how to grow cannabis i am simply
there as a helping hand to help guide
you and whatever style of growing you
decide is best for yourself
we do have write-ups consistently on how
to use
k f how to slowly incorporate it into
your grow if you're interested in
transitioning into those methods
all kinds of great stuff i also want to
give a shout out to all my guys that are
over there following me already on the
brand new discord
charlie brown covert dylan farmer fly
funtime grower grow green daddy hershey
husky gardens j train
country green thumb farmer john and
twisted gardens these guys are all
joining me on the brand new discord
they're learning all kinds of stuff if
you're wondering if it's worth it go
give them a follow on ig ask them what
they think of it it is a great great
community and we've been having tons of
fun over there
we have all kinds of threads anywhere
from a general chat soil building
genetics making different teas we have a
suggestion box so you can tell us what
you want to see
of course we've got the show off thread
joints dab art all kinds of good stuff
we even have home gardening threads
a place to promote yourself to talk
about growing to talk about harvesting
plant training ipm making your own
concentrates we even have our own
connections thread to help connect
people that are in our discord server
with people that are close to them and i
think it's an amazing tool and i would
love to see more of you in there
you also have access to all kinds of
seats we invite our breeders or our
interviewees on
to our discord server for a video chat
after the show typically and these guys
have been winning awesome seeds they've
been winning seats from swami from canna
queen all kinds of good stuff and i hope
to see you in there so if you do did
enjoy the show
send us a like
send us a share shout out the show share
it with a friend that you think might
enjoy it as well and until next time i
love you all i appreciate y'all this has
been doc calyx with romulan genetics
wishing you a very good night stay
growing people
[Applause]
[Music]
you