[Music]
c
good evening everyone and welcome to a
brand new episode episode of the CX and
crew podcast sessions I'm sitting here
today with Jacob Rolf known better as
Jacob Collins from Trailer Park Boys
he's also an illustrator a cook a print
maker and allaround great guy how you
doing today Jake how's it going doc all
well here
Scotia how's the weather up in Nova
Scotia today it's a lovely day nice nice
Ocean Breeze not too
muggy nice I see you're you're already
smoking up
probably the quickest guess to light up
ever what he the last few hours trying
not to get to uh too high before uh you
know coming online and then you just
start it right off the bat with the
joint I'll light up with you right now
I'm smoking on the seventh star from
Dynasty genetics it's uh blue Magoo
times
Huckleberry oh sounds
good I'm smoking some uh
we've got like there's there's legal
weed here as well as the Black Market
still but I I ran out of my uh the
uh I was smoking I bought some
government weed here but it's some Ultra
sour good and nice Ultra sour nice cheap
outs hell
yeah if you uh if you had a preference
to smoke is there does Jacob have a a
favorite strain favorite type man there
was weed around it was it was before
legalization and it was in some of the
uh sort of like these black market shops
that were allowed to exist it's like
complicated but it was called pinky in
the
brain so I don't know my genetics very
well but I think like the pink pinks are
a realm of weed and I don't know what
this was and I haven't like I've tried
to search it online and saw reference to
it but no like not much info about
it but like whatever it was it it's it
seemed to be it was like fireworks that
stuff
everybody over in chat right now I'll
I'll pay somebody a pack of seeds you
look up pinky in the brain find that
strain for me let's get it over to
Jacob yeah I was buying it like a this
shop in Toronto this like like chain of
you know little illegal but tolerated uh
he had dope
shops [ __ ] what were they called we'll
call them gr Market oh Cana something
something like that I I can't remember I
was hoping to give it give it another
clue there but failed well over a shout
out so how long have you been smoking
cannabis
Bud gosh I mean since
uh since grade
11 grade 11 okay so yeah I would have
been about I guess 17 then yeah a
junior yeah we the same like High School
uh like naming uh conventions that you
do with like Junior seniors and such
right so I don't know what I would be
called there but yeah it was the third
year of high school okay but we had five
years scho so that might complicate
things do you recall that first
experience can we talk about
it gosh the first time I ever smoked it
was hash at a party and uh my
buddy a cook in the restaurant I was
also working in the
kitchen like I was young you know
underage having a couple beers at this
you know work party and he like sitting
there on the couch just pulled out this
chunk of hash I like oo check this out
and I had no idea what it was like what
do you got there so we smoked some of
that um I don't really remember how that
went I was already drunk so I might have
just like ended up getting you know more
more effed up having a couple puffs off
the hash joint but the same dude hooked
me up with some weed after that and that
was the first proper time smoking weed
was uh or cannabis was you know that
occasion and yeah again not knowing what
I was doing I tried me and my buddy went
to see this uh band called all at
Carlton University in
Ottawa and yeah we didn't even know how
to roll joints but we each rolled sort
of like three joints really badly for
ourselves out of this you know little
bag of weed we got and I remember was
the uh the what I remember most was
sitting like you know three meters apart
from my buddy and we just smoked our
three joints solo like in a row you know
not sharing or anything for some reason
I don't know why we're sitting so far
apart we smoked them all and then like
went to see the
concert and strangely I didn't get too
high that experience but what year are
we talking here this would have been
like 92 something like that 1992 okay
right oh crap my neighbors mowing their
lawn hope it's not too [ __ ] for the
audio it's all good man so we can fairly
say there wasn't any seeds in that bud I
don't think it was very good weed um
because again oddly that was like the
one time we got weed back then and it
was only hash for like a year or two
which weed was not making it to the
Ottawa like you know scene but the hash
was pretty good got to you know learn
about hash smoking hash joints doing
Bottle
toes and then we you know eventually did
come back onto the scene and uh the rest
is history I guess
absolutely did that did uh cannabis help
play into your acting career at all as
far as developing characters
or gosh I mean my only acting job has
really been like where I've act like
other than background work has been on
Trailer Park Boys and I mean the Jacob
the character I play Jacob Collins is
you know also sort of a Stoner you know
kind of slacker type dude well although
he does work seven jobs maybe he's not a
slacker but sort of slacker Vibes he's
constantly working yeah yeah yeah he's
constantly working so it feels wrong
calling him a
slacker um but yeah I mean there there's
certainly some over AP with uh with you
know the real Jacob in that regard so I
guess you know maybe it would uh I'm
able to easily tap into that uh you know
kind of Stoner Vibe yeah so you're
saying it's not too far off from the
real Jacob not too far at all no if uh
if the character Jacob Collins could
make meet Jacob rol separately in a day
what do you guys think you do together
for the rest of the
day yeah [ __ ] I mean some joints goes
without
saying but uh yeah I mean I think we we
we both like uh Little
Adventures maybe go on a go on a hike
low grade
trouble low grade trouble what's low
grade
trouble yeah I'm I'm I'm just joking
really I don't get not on the Ricky par
not on Ricky par maybe some mild
trespassing you know so when I first
started talking to you here
must have been like two years ago now I
saw you post up a picture of two plants
that you had growing in your window
there and I asked you about it and uh
you said yeah you were growing a couple
plants there was that your first
experience growing or have you grown
previously
um first time like I remember having a
weed in my window like back in the '90s
some some just bag seed I got and it was
a male plant I had no idea till it
started like dumping pollen everywhere
like oh this is weird I don't want to
smoke that um but yeah it was just and
it was in like a you know it was getting
basically no light uh but then in in in
University um I was in my late 20s when
I like when this was going on me and my
roommates set up a grow room in the
Attic So we had to go up through this
cubby hole in one of
the in in one dude's like closet and
then we built a room up in the attic so
it would be you know out of sight
uh and yeah like like bought a bunch of
equipment and had a hydroponic set up
there one of the dudes there had a bit
of experience so he was definitely sort
of like you know running things but uh
like the rest of us helped like lug
water and like whatever you know watch
out for the landlord and stuff his name
wasn't Ricky was
it oh
man I mean it that's pretty insane that
that's how it went you know you're doing
water in this guy making
you knows all the goods it's from the
operation we had some good clones that
we got uh and uh we had yeah we know it
worked out well we we got a bunch of
good weed at least from like from my
perspective it was H you know probably
end up with four to six o each and and
there were four of us so you know it's
pretty good for a for a first grow um do
you remember what any of those clones
were oh gosh no idea yeah no idea at all
I don't really have a head for like
remembering such yeah such details
unfortunately so is this something that
you just do on and off in your free time
or is this like a I'm gonna grow for
myself every year yeah well I mean since
living in in that house at at school I
guess I never really had um my own
place I mean I I had places with like
partners and stuff girlfriends but we
never had enough room to have a grow
room or and you know never thought about
like you know I guess actually growing
weed
but but often I didn't have space to do
it and so not until I moved back to Nova
Scotia into this house I'm in now where
I've got like a bunch of extra rooms
that I was finally like woohoo I'm gonna
like you know grow some weed H yeah and
it was so yeah and and and so I did you
know got me uh got me some lights and a
little grow tent and uh kind of fumbled
my way through it and so I've been I've
just been doing it like you know one or
two cycles in the summer is when I'm
here in Canada um I often travel in the
winter so I can't like just you know
have a constantly rotating crop or
anything but I'm it turn it turns out
I'm not really good at it at all so it's
uh like I enjoy it to a point like when
the plants get too like stressed looking
it can be sort of a stressful thing to
have to deal with like oh man that's my
job man is I teach people how to grow
and grow correctly and I don't believe
there's a person on this planet that has
a brown thumb I think there's unless you
know that subject which that's my
subject that's all I do is
cannabis um unless you know that subject
and you get into the details of how to
take care of them best and make that
kind of like second memory you know um
as far as what environment they like
what kind of medium they like what
nutrition they like little tiny things
it gets easier um the more you learn
about it but I'd be happy to help you
with that if you ever run run into
problems or anything hit me up I will
help you out we'll get you on track well
thank you I'll I'll take you up on that
I'm not growing this summer I took a
this summer off because I've got like a
big backlog of like because I the wheed
I grow isn't that great I turn it into
weed oil which which is like like
topnotch as far as I'm concerned like
that that stff does the trick great
absolutely so I do like being able to
like you know have all this wheed oil
around but I've got so much now that
I've made from previous years and this
summer I'm sort of going and coming
traveling more that'd be tough to S of
monitor my indoor uh you know setup so
anyway I'm not growing this summer but
yeah next year I'll get back on the
train and uh get some uh get some tips
I'm kind of a
lazy I I can be lazy sometimes like when
it comes to like paying attention in a
sustained way to something so I don't
know it could be a character flaw of
mine that's like you know I don't think
so at all
it just sounds like you got ADHD and I
think 90% of the people in here
do like it is I sort of feel like the
five years I've been doing it I've been
trying to like bring in an extra element
and correct for it like I started off
you know with sort of you know just the
b super Basics and I you know bring in
more like okay I'm gonna get a pH kit
and like next year like okay I'm gonna
try to like be better with temperature
but I feel like I was getting worse
every year somehow despite like trying
to pay attention to more things I think
an unspoken part of growing that not a
lot of people mention is there's
something spiritual about growing
cannabis um just the fact that our
systems made to work with it that we
have that endoc canabo system is just
there's a relationship there that's been
around for a very long time and I feel
like the energy that you bring into your
grow room has an effect on your plants
to some degree even if it's just a a
little bit um because you can see people
in their daily lives that are really
stressed out and they go in the gr room
stressed out every day and oh man it's
not getting any better I'm doing worse
and their plants are looking like crap
and then there's people that will not go
in their grow room unless they're
feeling in the right kind of mood and
are doing good in doing well in life and
happy and you can see their Grow rooms
proliferating so I've definitely been in
both situations myself I've been
stressed out over worked got so much
going on can't focus and my girl room
starts looking like crap and then
there's been other times where it's like
okay there's something wrong in the grow
room I need to fix it now be on it get
it done with and yeah I do I have an
avoidant sort go if things do start to
go like you know like oh I don't know
like what's wrong with this plant's got
some things on the leaf and then I will
start to avoid you know my like problems
yeah exactly oh yeah
exactly exactly how I act with that it's
looking like crap I just don't want to
deal with it right
now so let me ask you really quick uh
what was your how many seasons did you
do 11 no you came in after
Trevor right I was my my my role
expanded yeah uh in season seven after
Corey and Trevor left um but I was in it
the show from season one I had a small
recurring role where I sort of get fired
from job every season yeah okay I was in
every season except season six I think
if memory serves um and then I was sort
of there I guess laying in weight when
they're looking for like you know
someone to fill the jail cover role um
so after all that time what was uh what
was one of your favorite moments
filming like in all of Trailer Park Boys
yeah gosh I mean there's been you know
it's pretty there's been lots of fun
times like for me it's it's always
pretty surreal being on set even at this
point like it was in the early years
just being a regular Joe you know
working in kitchens and then being you
know pulled out and going to like work
on Trailer Park Boys or you know be on
TV every so often totally not used to
it and so it was you know I was always
kind of freaky and then like when my RO
expanded and I was on the show a lot
more I got to see how stuff worked and
it always remained yeah super kind of
surreal and freaky like you know just
just cruising around in the back of the
ship mobile is you know could be a
pretty good time like the smell of
gasoline wafting you know the the the
wind in your hair old garbage from like
Seasons past still like hidden around in
nooks and
crannies that's awesome but I mean
there's like yeah there there's been so
like all the crazy shenanigans that we
get up to you know in the episodes like
like [ __ ] around with the horse stuff
was pretty fun
um [ __ ] around in the woods in season
s and because season seven was such a
big like change for me like like from
just being on set once or twice a year
to you know all a sudden being on there
for a whole season like most days and
being involved so much in this plot was
uh yeah like like pretty mind-blowing
you know and and fun but like all the
stuff in the woods when like we crashed
the car into the woods and we're like
lost in the woods l the train tracks and
you know for the sey express that was
you know pretty
uh just but I mean there's so many times
and it's almost like the rule as opposed
to the exception but it's like you know
this is crazy this is my job like like
what's going on
here I was reading your Reddit AMA
earlier and I saw where you were talking
about the shitmobile and it actually
running having to be dropped off by a
flatbed truck jump started every time
time funny that's a memory by the uh by
the end I think they still have that
same old one which is like this actual
second ship mobile but it was still yeah
like wouldn't start couldn't like hold a
charge repl
gas not not Road licensed at all but
there's this dude in London Ontario
who's got a replica of it I don't know
if you've ever come across that on a a
replica he built a replica uh it's uh
shout out to Mike raspberry
[ __ ] it like if you look up
shitmobile I can't remember his his uh
his username but uh raspberry ship
mobile go find them yeah he's got this
beautiful replica of the shitmobile and
uh the boys have been filming stuff this
summer again and they actually H got him
to come out and uh use his car as the as
the like the set car for the boys so
it's a proper running roadworthy version
of the shitmobile the door comes off and
on as you know oh my God
looking this up right now awes
um what was your least favorite
moment I mean I find like moments when I
feel like I didn't
like like nailed the scene properly like
I didn't sort of you act good could be
like pretty nerve-wracking
like you know get I get like sort of you
know super self-conscious about it if I
feel I yeah couldn't like I guess to
deliver the lines in a way that seemed
realistic or you know whatever the case
may
be
um there one scen stick out is a
genuinely hard one for you to do one
scene that comes to mind was yeah when I
was supposed to be acting drunk in a it
was in the Don't Legalize It movie and
uh I was supposed to go on a on a
mission on the road with the boys in in
the movie but then like my dad Phil
Collins grounded me basically and told
me I couldn't go so I had to to go and
tell the boys that I couldn't go and I
was you know nervous about it and super
drunk and yeah acting drunk like trying
to slur your words and like you know I
guess be or you know whatever like you
know be uh woozy on your feet and that
kind of thing was yeah super hard to
execute and I don't think I did it at
all oh I bet yeah well if Jacob col or
yeah Jacob Collins comes so natural to
you and then being in a sober state of
mind trying to portray yourself in a
drunken state of mind that would be
pretty
difficult yeah I'm no uh I'm know John
John dunsworth that's for
sure he was yeah he was amazing and I
think I I heard that he was not much of
a drinker at all in real life is that
true yeah that's uh that's that's my
understanding and yeah he could turn on
and turn off the like yeah you know
super super drunken state it seemed you
on on demand it's incredible um if I had
to ask you like your top three
influences when it came to acting uh who
would you shat out my top three
influences
yeah gosh you know I don't
have like like my approach to acting
like I I'm not like I don't really see
myself as acting I'm just sort of like
you know doing this the stuff in front
of the camera but like I don't
have like sort of Role Models or that
kind of thing uh um or like actors who I
sort of aspire to be
like how about art
influencers yeah for art that's uh like
I um Robert crumb would be one I I I
really liked his stuff like when I was
growing up my dad had some arrum like uh
stuff
around
uh and like the Psychedelic kind of um
music posters of the you know 60s and
70s I liked a lot oh wow so uh like like
Peter Max he's an artist who did like uh
I think posters like in the more in the
60s maybe like Led Zeppelin some sort of
okay you know bands like that but like
an early sort
of really trippy screen prints uh nice
stuff what's another don't remember his
name I would have to look it up and send
it to you later but there was a guy that
did a bunch of art for I don't know if
you've heard of them or not but band Yes
back in the day yeah yeah yeah I I know
the style yeah that's totally Peter Max
style I don't know if Peter Max did like
NES stuff but it almost like could have
been like a similar very similar yeah
the alien landscape kind of but like and
yeah like nice and colorful real trippy
stuff I always love that we've been
talking about that art in our server uh
here for a while now just the other day
we were talking about heavy metal uh the
old movie that they had put on on the
artwork that was in there that was
really cool yeah uh was there any times
when you guys were filming scene where
it led to actual real
trouble
um gosh real
trouble once once the cops had to get
called because uh one of the background
performers had some
handcuffs that they didn't have a key
for they were they were real police
handcuffs it turns out which real I
guess non- cops aren't allowed to have
civilians it it turns out but I guess
they were in like the props you know
whatever like
kit and this background guy wasn't
supposed to be handcuffing anybody but
just like like the way the scene played
out he you know he was with with Julian
JP and I put the handcuffs on
him and then they they couldn't get him
off you know when when the scene was
done time to get ready for the next take
and so you know after a bunch of like
holy [ __ ] what do we do they had to call
the cops to come in and use their you
know cop keys to get the uh the
handcuffs off and of course the cops
were curious as to you know why you know
why
the is logging you up with some actual
handcuffs I think in the end the cops
are just like don't do that again but
let them keep keep the Cuffs if I recall
don't don't quote me on that cool that's
cool they were cool about but they were
just like you know come on
guys I mean kick out of maybe coming to
set and you know yeah we're too we you
know got the right cops were you ever
actually high on
set gosh that would be against actra
rules so I don't know if we have a a
fifth amendment here in Canada but uh I
better oh yeah we can it's completely up
to you the people that saw it live is
that you answered it perfectly and we
can edit that
out
no no need to edit it but yeah no uh no
comment okay like you you'll be du to be
on set late in the day have a smoke you
know hours go by are you still a bit
High who
knows I'll tell you what I'm not the one
that's here to
judge
so um how did they portray cannabis on
scene on um I mean it
was there was plenty of times where they
had grows going or you guys had bags of
weed yeah like yeah I was just thinking
about like how to how to describe it it
was like sort of glorified but also you
know the dangers with the law were also
certainly you know made evident uh on
the show um but yeah I mean it was seen
as something that was you know that uh I
guess huh yeah how was it portrayed like
what what's your opinion on that was it
like uh what were they using
to that you guys were walking around
with to oh that oh yeah yeah just like
fake green stuff basically like like
other other herbs some sort of herbal
mix they would have bags of for like
like when when we're smoking joints it
would just be some sort of like herbal
mix but it was
disgusting like there's you know Blends
out there that are you know can be
pleasant to smoke like with you know
this and that and it I don't know
anything about herbal mixes but I don't
know if there is going for a budget like
using like a legal herb mix yeah a bunch
of legal herbs and then when they had
like like Buds and like fake weeds or
plants they'd be these when like often
when you saw Out close it'd be real sort
of like gangly looking not very
realistic but at a distance or you know
for set decoration it would it would it
would pass as weed plants right I guess
some were better than others depending
on like what resources they had and uh
yeah I guess what was going on in the
scene um but yeah it was like weird
random like just like weird fake plant
stuff or even like Styrofoam kind of
foam stuff that' be spray painted to
look like
weed they portrayed it pretty well when
the I there was a time when uh Ricky
Julian and Bubbles were in a field of
marijuana that must have been real weed
yeah yeah think they did I've also
wondered I don't know if they knew
people who had a grow operation or if it
was maybe a hemp some sort of hemp like
feel if they had those here yeah like
the scenes with reita mcneel uh it look
like a real weed field to me so we
haven't got to touch much on your art
yet uh people some of these people don't
know that you're a very accomplished
Artist as well um when did you start
doing
art gosh I mean like back when I was a
kid I used to like to you know [ __ ]
around with the crayons and stuff
probably like you know most most kids
but I always doodled like through
school I liked art class in high school
um although I didn't take it all the way
through uh for what it's worth but yeah
like I would doodle it at in you know my
notebooks in like high school and and
University and
uh yeah like turned it into started like
screen printing a little bit here and
there I I took a few courses After High
School like print making this and that
but like just sort of out of Interest
not planning to like sort of be an
artist or make a living for in art
um but then when I when I moved to New
Finland in 2007 I uh like bought my
first house so I had space to have a
studio there and set up a screen
printing studio and uh started making
posters for our friends band and that's
how I sort of like learned how to screen
green print and like learn some of the
skills cut my chops so to
speak that's cool and now you're taking
it pretty seriously you've got your own
online shop where can people find your
art at yeah I've got a uh website um the
uh URL is
b.ca
b.ca uh and yeah yeah you know I'm
like I'm a better I I'm better at
production than sort of the business
side of things but uh yeah I got my own
website which I which I set up at the
beginning of the pandemic and Etsy shop
before
that and
uh yeah yeah I sell uh I do screen
prints like which if you check it out
you you'll see the style of my drawing
but kind of like you know colorful
Trippy cartoon kind of stuff yeah he
does a lot of uh trailer park Bo
inspired art he does a lot of his own
original prints you do
t-shirts um you can buy canvas prints um
what else did you have over
there yeah that's uh that's the most of
it yeah like so yeah it's mainly screen
prints that I make myself but there's
also some some yeah reproductions and
some T-shirts and uh I guess some
stickers for
example I'm I'm already planning on next
year to sort of like work on like
diversifying my selection a bit
um I'm working with some guys down in
the States on getting some pipes made oh
cool which that would be awesome with
some original art on them um and like
the pipe itself being an original design
as well that uh that they're overseeing
so uh that would be that would be really
cool I'd get a bam pipe for sure I see
all you guys going off in chat there we
will be answering your questions uh
towards the end of the episode we still
have about a half hour to go um yeah
I've got chat off like I say earlier
I've got I I can't focus on too many
things but it's all good man I just
looked over there right
now just having a quick uh quick peek
what's up
everybody uh so you've been off scene
with trailer park boys for a while um is
there any upcoming projects for you
acting or any more Trailer Park
Boys the yeah co co really slowed things
down for Trailer Park Boys as it did for
a lot of lot of [ __ ] but uh yeah they
they made a third jail season just back
in April of this year a few months ago
and I was in for a few days on that and
so yes so was good to see the gang and
you know so yeah like with the jail
stuff it's mostly the boys in jail and
it's sort of different main secondary
cast but there were a few scenes with me
and Corey or me and Trinity Gina my TV
wife uh so yeah we're still there like
alive in the
background um and there's plans for
another season in the park next next I
think next year is the current like time
when it's like they're saying it's going
to happen like all through Co I kept
saying like oh yeah we're hoping to do
it this year hoping to do it this year
so there is a plan I I I don't doubt but
um I'm not exactly holding my
breath okay but there is a there is a
new jail season that I assume is in the
editing room these days and will be you
know coming out sometime this fall or
next
spring so look forward to that guys and
Trailer Park Bo were still stuck in the
same
spot Bran Bran you were always one of my
favorite characters especially uh when
you started impersonating Julian that
[ __ ] just cracked me up the first time
that they pulled up on you and you were
with uh who was it the meat
guys yeah the meat
dicks yeah I started losing on that
one the
obsession what would have been some some
of your favorite extra scenes that
you've
done I know you've done multiple shows
that people might not even freaking know
uh you did some with like I said vgo
morson earlier um you did a bunch of
extra zombie work what was some of your
favorite extra work to do yeah the the
zombie stuff would definitely be the
funnest uh and you know what what like
the the standout background work
especially when I was getting like you
know full make up and like Prosthetics
and stuff so you know looking like super
you know super super
zombie and I was in a number of zombie
movies I was I was living close to
Toronto like in the early 2000s when
they were filming a bunch of zombie
movies it was like the zombie
Renaissance so I happen to be in the
right place at the right time for a well
and basically if you wanted like it was
such grueling work working nights that
uh a lot of people like dropped out so
but yeah so like the the the work was
there if you're willing to do it
basically um and yeah so so it was it
was it was fun but also yeah like like
but by by the end of it I was sick of it
and sort of Happy the movies would be
ending yeah no more zombie stuff for
Jake huh yeah being up all night never
really was my bag I find it like sort of
really throws me for a
loop oh my the uh the lawnmower is real
close oh you're good it's not coming
through very bad at all
excellent okay
so is this dank magician who's de not a
bot come on guys come
on pretty sure it's thank magician says
what is your favorite line from the show
is
Jacob gosh my favorite
line I mean they' always keep my lines
kind of like kind of limited like
knowing my knowing the the the
limitations of my acting abil ility like
I I never got Giants giant you know
chunks of uh you
know lines to uh to memorize and
read but yes it's funny like I'm I'm
totally drawing a blank on that uh on
that
question when what was there a
particular scene that came to you and
you could just automatically do it you
had no trouble with it and you came out
of it going I [ __ ] nailed
that I mean a lot of the scenes are
pretty casual sort of like hanging out
and you know I don't like [ __ ] around
I
guess
um you know I I would really do well to
watch watch the series again to almost
reacquaint myself with all all the stuff
that happened I'm uh I haven't seen the
whole series in probably over 10
years um so it's been a
while so you don't go back and rewatch
much of your own work
no no I mean often I find it like like a
I don't like watching my scenes
necessarily like often it's fine but if
if the ones where I feel I was like that
were you know poorly executed like like
I can cringe like like the rest of them
but yeah no no no I haven't seen it uh
in ages I did watch season uh like
season five a couple of winters ago and
uh like you laugh my ass off it was it
was great um what brought you back to
season five it was just one that I
wasn't I think it was one of the earlier
ones I was least least familiar with uh
and so I just happened to like you know
hit play on on Netflix on that one so
yeah nothing in particular brought me to
it that's got to be surreal watching
yourself on
TV it is yeah
it's it's
strange I don't if I really like yeah
register it necessarily like what do you
think young Jacob rol would have said if
I would have told him hey you're going
to be a pretty famous
actor
um yeah he might have been uh he'd
probably be like right
[Laughter]
on Al
I that's so real though Park Bo famous
is a special kind of yeah sort of micro
uh
micro
Fame although it's it's been great like
I've been n like it's it i' I've
benefited from it obviously like
wonderfully um like like most of the art
I was I was doing screen printing for a
while alongside Trailer Park Boys and
just started doing trailer park boys
theme prints like maybe three four years
ago it was maybe a year before covid but
they're by far my like yeah bestselling
stuff and so it's like um
yeah I'm like riding up I'm riding the
Trailer Park Boys waves even though I'm
you know happy to be adding like my own
you know something I like your own thing
that you got going on there the Trailer
Park Boys Art's cool it's funny as hell
uh I think more than anything what I
appreciate about art is the artist and
having that trademark signature thing
that they do you know and a lot of your
prints uh are heavy on the red you do a
lot of heavy Reds on stuff and that
makes it pop and it's kind of like an
alternative comic type art I think it's
really cool how you do that man it's
your own thing uh we are going to be
putting in an order at
bamca so a few of our members here are
going to be winning some of that art
look forward to that um all right on
good luck everybody I give you guys a
few minutes to an ask a question this
how you use it taco
he says after the last season of
Skinwalker Ranch what do you think's
going on out
there is that an alien reference yeah
yes do you believe in aliens I think
that's what he's
asking um I definitely like think that
there'd be other life in the universe
whether or not they're like contacting
our planet you know I guess
uh I'm I'm I'm I'm neutral about
it like
open to the IDE in the news like like
the testimony before Congress and the
states and stuff I I've heard it's going
on I saw a few memes where they they
they put Jacob like uh into the Congress
you know
testifying for example and uh so I'm I'm
I'm I'm I'm s vaguely aware of of that
going on but yeah I'm not aware of like
you know what they've been saying but
uh I yeah I definitely think that
there'd be other it would be like pretty
presumptuous to think there'd be no
other life anywhere in the universe that
that seems ridiculous how I feel about
it
too steu says where in the [ __ ] did the
idea for Steve French come
from yeah for some reason I think it was
from the mind of uh Mike Smith AKA
bubbles although who
like I mean I think the like clattenburg
and the boys would write sort of write
together in the early days
excuse me have a sip of tea
here so it yeah it could have been from
the mind of Mike platberg
yeah yeah yeah who I'm I'm I'm amazed at
uh like all the good ideas that the guys
come up with you know even like ideas
like a giving a cougar a name like Steve
French
genius yeah that that was
ridiculous um besides your own character
what was your favorite character on the
show not people not actors but actual
character I think like Ry the uh Ray
Ricky's dad both because I mean both
because it's so well you know executed
well acted but yeah he's just such a I
mean sort of like Ricky they're
characters that like you come across in
your life you know as you're going
around in the world but aren't
represented much on like you know like
stand sort of you know TV and movies
um if that makes any sense yeah free
spirit but yeah yeah just
like yeah relatable sort of like a real
dude in like sort of believable dude in
his own way exactly yeah very relatable
to most people oh God you're going to
make me do this or him do this Anonymous
says can you do the BAM for or us the
BAM all right I'll do a
bam yo doc
bam hell yeah we got a bam I do feel
like a trained monkey
sometimes but I also like bringing
people uh pleasure yeah
absolutely uh Stu says pinky in the
brain is pink cush crossed with brain
OG that sounds very believable all right
have to look that one up I know some
people that were growing in the area
about that time they might know more
about
it so throughout working on trailer park
boys doing extras um even doing your
art what do you think some of the best
things that you've learned from
progressing your life through that
situation uh what has it taught you
oh
man I've been reflecting like in recent
you know days weeks how uh I feel like
I'm you
know sort of learning the same lessons
over and over again in in life so I
don't know if I'm learning anything
really sometimes sometimes you gotta
learn some things
hard I'm really trying to this stage of
my life I mean I'm I'm 48 but and I've
been doing this for a while but it's
like hard I mean it's easier said than
done but sort of simplifying things so
like moving from the city to the country
it was a big you know step in that
direction so it's just like you know
less less
distraction I guess like like sort of
simplifying in a physical and and in a
mental sense
um and uh so yeah it's like I'm I'm I'm
I'm feeling pretty high all of a sudden
here as I try to describe this
oh no Jacob Gins of all [ __ ] people
is high on our podcast about weed like
yeah dare I'm trying to like arrange my
life so like to like you know not be in
the rat race but I mean that's like I
mean I guess who wouldn't like that in a
way but
uh I find it's easy to fall into the you
know sort of habit of working
constantly um I mean often like you're
doing that just to get by you know I'm
I've I've been that in that situation
you know a lot including in recent years
but then like yeah trying to figure out
a balance between yeah like work and
life where you're not like working too
much I mean I I do take like I I travel
in the winter and take a lot of time
like I wouldn't be working full-time
when I'm traveling in the winter so when
it's averaged across the
year maybe I'm like doing pretty well
but I still feel like I'm working too
much by my standards it's it's a
constant balance that's part of life is
trying to find that balance try to find
that yeah and as an artist I find it
hard or as an artist as I don't know as
a stoner as a human
like and sort of being in charge of
myself I find pretty challenging to like
you know um manage my time in a way
that's effective often you know like so
that's that's a constant [ __ ]
struggle for me man oh
man I I don't think it really stops
until you got somebody wiping your butt
for you you know
I think that's just one of those things
you're always chasing whether it's yeah
whether that's because you're old or
because you're just Rich enough to have
some hopefully the
lad
no uh John you're taking my question
here
man says favorite cut of cannabis on
island pick one so that's a question I
usually ask on my my meet the breeder
episodes where we interview cannabis
breeders but uh we'll see if you got one
what does that mean exactly can you bit
I will re read it yes
John um if you went on to a desert
island I told you Jake you can only take
one type of cannabis with
you and nothing else for the rest of
your life what type of cannabis would
you bring oh I guess well I mean find me
some of that pinky in the brain that
pinky in the brain what was it about
that that was so outstanding was it the
flavor the
it was I guess like it was the High
um I guess it was like the right balance
of like body and head in a certain way
that was both
like strong but not too strong where it
sort of like would would knock me out
but I was still like I guess maybe had
like some euphoric elements to it that
uh that I liked and and it didn't seem
to like Peter out over time at least for
the time that I had the weed I don't
think I had like a giant p of it or
anything
but um it wasn't a quick High it stuck
around for a
while it was and it was like a really
full kind of high is what I like how I
want to describe it for some reason had
depth to
it
um in the way that you is that oh man so
out of all your time uh doing Trailer
Park Boys and everything do you have any
regrets
um no I mean like certainly not like to
do with the
show I mean like like sometimes I wonder
if I could have like parlayed I mean I
can still like look for other acting
jobs it's not something that that I
actively do at all but uh like I may
have you know missed opportunities to
like yeah parlay my trailer park boys
like you know sort of minor Fame into
other like
jobs I
guess like acting or or otherwise I'm
I'm definitely not really like a like
much of a hustler type um but still you
know like sometimes
uh you know my lack of sort of get up
and go um it's it's one of the things
you know reflect on from time to time
but yeah calling it a regret might be a
little bit uh I I try not to think of it
that way I guess yeah
oh yes thank you Taco um so we were
talking about rolling joints and taking
dabs earlier you said you weren't much
of a concentrates guy unless it came to
like a vaporizer pen um what is your
favorite method of
consumption I uh I like to smoke joints
um and
uh maybe it's because it's a product of
growing up in Ottawa so I I like a
little sprinkle up tobacco with my flour
which I know a lot of people will like
uh you know B at but uh yeah that's
my that's my favorite all doesn't need
to be much like just you know 5% 10% not
like the British style where it's like
80% or you know the vast majority of it
is is tobacco those I find hard to smoke
but yeah yeah I find con just stronger
than NE necessary by and large although
I certainly enjoy like hash yeah do you
buy like pre-rolled cones or do you roll
them yourself I just roll joints with
like regular size papers normally like
some little you know OCB is that your
preferred paper or is it just any paper
it'll do that's just just what I they
were uh I I bought these on on Amazon
they were like you know decent price on
them but I just like any any thin paper
will do basically and I don't like to
spend like three bucks on my papers
so I'll try to get a deal hell yeah all
right man well before we get going here
oh Taco says what's your favorite type
of
edible oo you know I think I I haven't
done Edibles in the in uh in the last
week or so I think I might have some
tonight but maybe just a nice glob of
Rick Simpson Oil you know like a maybe a
double rice grain like right out of the
syringe onto my thumbnail and
then nice yeah I mean that's that's a
good utilitarian simple way to do it
although I certainly enjoy like I had a
delicious uh [ __ ] what was it I think it
was a peanut
butter cup or something that like this
fancy Bakery had made that was
apparently an edable although it was so
delicious I didn't taste any uh cannabis
like there there was no there was no
discernable cannabis flavor in it not
that that that couldn't also be
delicious if depends it depends it it
can be overpowering or in something it
doesn't necessarily blend with a flavor
in a way that's like yummy but uh these
tastes like straight up like baked you
know baked good so that was I was
impressed I was wondering like can this
really be this is this really in
edible there's definitely different
quality variants of most Edibles even
with the what you were calling the weed
oil the Rick Simpson Oil or
RSO
um I've had some of that that just makes
me choke it's just nasty just really
really bad and then I've had other ones
where it's like oh my God I appreciate
every flavor of this cannabis you know
it just it tastes like cannabis cannabis
yeah not like where some others are dark
and alcoho and I generally try to like
just swallow it and not get it like into
my mouth but yeah like when you do get
it in your mouth I again there's a lot
of flavor in there like if it's all you
know if the tacky oil is like spreading
around your mouth yeah and it can be
either
like yeah kind of pleasant and
interesting or yeah like overwhelming
and like yeah not good basically awesome
there's there's a lot of factors I guess
that go uh that can be at play there
I've seen like R that's like or so
that's really chunky and like suspicious
looking like maybe not filtered properly
or I guess I do get chunks sometimes in
the bottom of cook too long gets really
thick maybe yeah but uh but like
normally it's pretty consistent oil I
guess maybe on on the second run you get
more like maybe some waxes coming out of
the uh plant when you're if if it's been
seting in the alcohol longer it's been a
long time since I've made Rick Simpson
Oil myself but maybe somebody can speak
on it in chat before we get going here
Taco says can you make a print of you
like the lady from
Titanic I don't think I'm comfortable
posting posing like that taco like off
the prow of the ship like
yeah okay I could do that one I'll be
comfortable with that I was I was
thinking the French girl scene I'm
like oh like naked lying in the uh like
lying in a on a couch kind of thing like
yeah I guess that's what he's going for
there I've got some pictures of Julian
that are kind of along those lines so
you know maybe those there you go there
you go head over to bam. ca that's Three
A's in there guys it right here
to get you guys some prints from Jacob
Collins of Trailer Park Boys Jacob thank
you so much for giving us your time uh
talking to us about your life your
cannabis experience throughout it um and
how it plays into you I've seen you go
around at a lot of dispensaries that are
local to you um and Shout them out would
it be fair to say that you are a
cannabis Advocate and that you advocate
for the plant
um I do yeah I'm like sort of passive
about it but yeah for sure I'm a I'm an
advocate of for cannabis hell how how do
you view it is it something that works
for you medically I would think so
taking
RSO yeah or is it more of a
recreational I
mean I guess like a little from you know
joint a a little from joint
B I do I mean
I've come to think of my you know
smoking weed as you know some version of
self-medicating like you know sort of in
retrospect from what I started smoking
it to the
present AB but I also like smoking it
for fun yeah with you I'm with you
that's how it always was for me as a kid
going into it it was definitely a
recreational thing you know I want to
get high with my friends um and as I got
older I started getting back pain neck
pain things like this I really started
focus on
this is helping with that which strains
which types can I find that balance me
out in those areas the most which one
takes away my neck pain the most which
one helps me with my back pain the most
um and then also a side effect of that
is you get high so it's it's for both
for sure yeah and I mean I also find
that like uh like with eating it like if
you get like a small dose of oil or you
know whatever your your your method um a
preference is like doing a low grade
dose during the day is a nice you know
way
to
like like it's it's not the the same
heady high or noticeable sort of buzz
but uh yeah it's sort of a mild uplift
which you know
um is uh which is real
[Laughter]
good we're both that this is awesome
so I'm so glad I got smoke with Jacob
half the second joint and look what it's
done to me oh my God yeah that was my
second too anyway thank you so much like
80% of my sentences so that's you
know says where can I get that shirt I'm
sure that is up at his online store too
well this is a shirt from a um a dude in
based in Halifax called uh oh uh
something Yeti quarrelsome Yeti and and
uh name Jordan um it's it's all
handprinted stuff and yeah he's awesome
so check out his stuff but I've also got
a bunch of shirts uh on my on my website
as well we will tag that shout out up in
the in the edit for you give a shout out
to yeah yeah he's another Nova Scotia
screen
printer so you've been going around
quite a bit um Tour all over the world
is Nova Scotia your favorite place to
be what's Paradise to
Jacob I mean I I like Nova Scotia fine
um and it's you know it's it's great in
a lot of ways beautiful ocean rocks but
I mean there's so many beautiful places
in the world uh that yeah I definitely
don't
uh I mean on one hand I sort of don't
pick favorites but there's like there's
there's so many cool spectacular you
know trippy places that would be you
know there is awesomer than this like up
the Himalayan Mountains for example is
that it is that the dream spot I don't
know I mean not necessarily for me I I
like to go up there and just like chill
for a couple of months or something like
just in some little Hut kind of in the
middle of nowhere that' be cool um but
yeah I don't know if you know like
forever if that's my if that's my
forever place
but somewhere you know you know
somewhere in the Hills I think where
it's you know like not too hot not too
cold sort of Goldilocks uh climate
right like at this stage I'm looking for
somewhere to sort of move to where I
could like do what I'm doing now but
like in another country where it's sort
of Cheaper to
live um that's sort of my like longer
term
dream is it fair to say you kind of like
the off-grid
lifestyle I mean being away I'm not too
like super sourceful in terms of like
super off grid but I like being away
from like you know uh sort of the hustle
and bustle of cities it's nice to have
access sort of to it like for when you
want some of that action or you know
need the resources but yeah yeah I like
sort of more like cin in the woods kind
of Lifestyle but you know where you can
walk to a village or something yeah if
you need to go somewhere it's not a not
a journey not a trek but it's also
disconnected and private I definitely
Vibe with that
man thank you so much Jacob for joining
us I know was it was great to Great to
talk to you doc absolutely I learned so
much about you doing this uh you know
before really only knowing you for
Trailer Park Boys not knowing that you
were a cook
beforehand um that you had done all
these extras and scenes apart from the
zombies um I didn't know that you were
in that movie with vgo [ __ ] that's
pretty cool I'm going to have to go back
and watch that and try to find you
that's an awesome movie uh yeah I mean
I'm just in yeah like if you haven't
seen it yeah I'm I'm just in a little
scene but that movie overall is an
awesome movie A History of Violence but
how many people can say hey I was in a
movie with vgo morson it doesn't care if
like you were a background guy like holy
[ __ ] still that's gool yeah I wasn't
expecting uh wasn't expecting it uh that
that he would be there so yeah that was
that was pretty cool
really yeah yeah I mean like like doing
background you just get a call and be
like hey are you free for you know this
day yeah whatever night or next week and
it's yes or no and you get there and
yeah like you're you're lowest of the
low as a background performer on Set uh
so yeah they they tell you nothing so I
seen him he was such a he was like a
super small dude like five and a half
feet tall maybe yeah you're pretty tall
aren't you you're taller than me I am
pretty tall so it's yeah that's like he
he was working at a disadvantage there
but like so many Hollywood dudes yeah he
was just a just a short little
[Laughter]
fella behind his back but you no
offense I loved hearing about uh
cannabis in your life and how it's
related to you and played into your life
and your acting um thank you so much for
giving me your time I'm sure everybody
appreciated this look forward to those
prints from Jacob uh we're going to put
it in order with him and get you guys
some prints from
[Music]
bam.com
I say it
baby I know you're on the
[Music]
road sweet
Hy let's take it real
[Music]
soon you know we got what you need baby
so take it move
along I said we got what you need honey
coming
blow come
on on the
[Music]
high come
on