questions
[Music]
what's up everybody and welcome to
another exciting episode of the calyx
and crew podcast I'm your host as
always.calc we've got a very special
episode today I have an idol of mine
somebody that I really look up to
especially in the work that I do we've
got none other than the man himself
every days of the podcast let's all
welcome heavy days
how you doing
thank you so much for having me my
friend what a what a cool opportunity it
is to be here on the show and um really
stoked to be here to talk to you today
that was such a nice intro man I have to
um I have to give you massive thanks for
that
absolutely I appreciate you taking your
time to come out and uh spend this with
me and get to know you a little bit more
um obviously you've been doing this a
lot longer than I have so like I said
you're somebody that I've kind of looked
up to in that aspect
um
let's start from the beginning so I I
can get to know you a little bit more
when did you first get into cannabis
what was your first experience
great question
um I think so so my very first
experience my mother at the age of 30
has finally told me that she did have a
joint when she was pregnant with me for
morning sickness so I guess I get to now
be OG and say in utero but I always
remembered the dragonfly guys said that
and I thought oh that's pretty cool
um anyway so the first time I ever
smoked weed I think I had that pretty
classic experience where you don't
really get high because you're not
really sure what you're doing and you
know you probably didn't really draw it
down into your lungs uh but then uh the
next time I did I got a little more high
but to me sort of in that early period
the one that really stands out as super
unique was me and some buddies were um
like in this little Forest area near my
house I was lucky enough to grow up in
an area called Tweed heads like shout
out to eat bread
um and basically really nice coastal
town in Australia and there was this
little forest and we had like found some
shopping trolleys that were in the
forest and so like we just tipped them
over on their sides we had like this
cool little makeshift couch
and we got super high and basically I
think it was maybe one of the first or
within the first few times I'd ever had
like indoor
um weed because in Australia uh outdoor
is quite common and if you're like a
young person you know Beggars can't be
choosers you're probably getting a lot
of bushweed so I had this sort of potent
indoor stuff and I got so high I
remembered looking at my buddy sitting
on the shopping trolley cart with you
know the trees as the backdrop behind
him and very distinctly saying to him
like oh man like you've got a green
screen behind you like that the trees in
the back that's not real men that's a
green screen I can see the outline
around you it's fake and I guess in
retrospect it was sort of the first real
psychedelic experience because I'd
gotten high but like I was I was truly
like having some visuals and I guess a
reflection of having such a low
tolerance but that one always lasted
with me I loved it and then one other
one which I'll mention which I haven't
really mentioned before was as I was
mentioning we're getting a lot of
bushweed right like in in the Australian
bushweed is largely speaking heirloom
Thai varieties so they're like these big
Thai varietals that handle the Heat and
the humidity really well you get huge
yields off them Unfortunately they
didn't quite have that tie effect that
you would hope for like this really nice
you know connoisseur sativa sort of
thing so it wasn't quite the high but it
had most of the other characteristics so
one time I get this batch of weed and
it's distinctly minty in smell I'd never
had anything like it very minty and it
looked like essentially what sort of
Tire sticks look like nowadays and I
hadn't really experienced that so I
tried this stuff and it was truly
memorable but I never had the words to
describe why I liked it so much and
looking back it was because it was like
it was uplifting and creative and really
fun and me and all my friends had it at
a party it was a great time so I think
when I first got into weed I sort of
didn't think I had these very
interesting stories and then the more I
thought about it I'm like no no like I
guess I have had some cool stuff happen
so that would be how I sort of first got
into it
awesome man
and I you've come such a far away since
that moment you know you're you're doing
more than I even knew about
um honestly I didn't pay that much
attention to podcasts when I started
doing this maybe a couple years ago I'm
still pretty fresh at it
um but it's funny when I get people ask
me you know what podcast do you listen
to Doc and it's like I I really don't
listen to podcasts it's kind of a weird
thing but I do this and I don't really
listen to very many but one of the ones
that I am always consistent of is the
podcast and that's because I've always
appreciated you as an interview or
you're very articulate you get very deep
into things that mean a lot to people
like you and people like me that
actually grow this plant Steward this
plant and love and have a passion for it
so we can speak from that perception you
know of like the home grower
um so it's really cool seeing you get in
with some of the biggest names in
cannabis you know especially people that
I would just dream of [ __ ] talking to
and you have this amazing catalog build
up from you doing this over the years
how did we go from your first experience
with cannabis into
I'm going to create a podcast and this
is where we're gonna go with it
how did okay I guess the good question
would be how did a man from Australia
where this is such a hard [ __ ] thing
to you know be public with go from that
to becoming the podcast
uh again man I gotta start off like
thank you I gotta gotta keep my head
from getting too big you're giving me
too many compliments but I really do
appreciate that you take the time to
listen to the show and I totally
understand what you're talking about
like when you're running a show
sometimes you get like audio fatigue and
it's almost hard to find the the mental
space to listen to other stuff so I
totally get you there's still a few
shows I listen to I um I try to stay in
touch with all the guys who I'm homies
with so like yourself do gross show
um breed of Syndicate Adam Dunn those
are sort of the the staple ones I check
out for sure but I think your question
is um is good it's I've thought about
that myself uh I I think that there's a
lot of factors at play and it plays into
what you said
part of My Success has been the momentum
I got from certain episodes and I really
want to acknowledge that that I was very
lucky to get certain guests and that
gave me a certain amount of momentum
that I think I wouldn't have had
otherwise so definitely want to
acknowledge that and I think the obvious
one would be
um I think the first two episodes really
set me up to be able to approach other
guests
but to get more to the heart of your
question uh how did I go from yeah being
like sort of this guy in Australia to
doing the podcast I think situationally
there wasn't too many podcasts at the
time so I I had made the transition from
like a smoker to a grower and I was
watching the weed nerd I was watching
um Emerald cup talks there was this one
that used to be up about uh the Rev
talking about just giving Organics a try
and that sort of what got me into
Organics and then I would watch sub cool
and I'd use his super soil recipe so I'd
sort of watch these different
um programs and I was just learning I
wasn't growing particularly great weed
at the time very much still learning
and after a while
I sort of felt like I had watched
all of the content on like YouTube that
I could sort of get my hands on that was
interesting and I felt like there was a
really good amount of information for
entry-level Growers but at a certain
point I was looking for more advanced
sort of content and I I the names on the
tip of my tongue I really want to give
them a shout out it was a guy from
Portland he um
oh I'm gonna at some point in the
episode I'll remember and I'll chime in
and say it but there was one guy I used
to watch uh Maddie Cropper that was his
name Maddie Cropper
um I liked his content I felt like it
was like a little more targeted a little
more advanced but basically I just sort
of looked at it and I was like hey it
seems like there's a bit of a vacuum
here there's a lot of great content for
entry-level people but there's not too
much intermediate stuff and there's
nothing Advanced really and I don't know
if I'd put my show in the category of
advanced I'd say it's probably more
intermediate in the grand scheme of
things but I just thought you know what
like no one's doing it so that's really
advantageous right because they can't
compare you to anything so like that's
helpful
um it sort of it makes makes your thing
better if it's hard to judge it so
um I I thought to myself
right yeah so I thought let's do it and
I started messaging people and like no
one really got back to me and I think
that was because I I can't remember how
I was approaching people but what year
was it
good question 2015 I think wow 2015. so
I should give a little more context in
the two years prior to that I had
started an Instagram and I was trying to
be active in the Australian community
and I was just giving away seeds and I
was just hoping some people would grow
them so I was making seeds before I
started the show and part of my
motivation to start the show was that I
just legitimately had a bunch of
questions I wanted to ask the big
breeders and I knew that I think I tried
typing some out one day and I after I
got to like a Page worth of questions I
was like No One's Gonna like you know if
I got an email like this I'd be like no
way too hard basket
um so I sort of thought a podcast was an
interesting way to circumvent that
excuse me and essentially be able to
like ask a whole bunch of questions to
someone but because it's recorded
everyone gets to benefit from it and the
breed is more likely to be like yeah
I'll give that a go oh so there was a
few considerations at play but I thought
like it could work and at the time I was
like and even up until a bit more
recently I um I was like toying with
like stand-up comedy and so like I sort
of had an idea of how to talk to people
and
um how to make it work so I just thought
let's just let's just try to blend it
all together oh and then the final thing
was
um I I've always enjoyed producing music
in my spare time I like playing music I
like writing music so I had like the
audio know-how to be able to like put so
I I was really lucky in that I sort of
felt like there was these three or four
different pieces of the puzzle and I
just like coincidentally had them all so
I was like okay I can on a technical
level I could make the show and all that
so yeah I'm emailing people
responses from people and um then I
eventually just started talking to Duke
diamond and he uh was sort of obviously
incredibly generous and nice with his
time
um but he sort of I asked enough
questions that he was like okay like I
don't think this is gonna be terrible
and he jumped on and and we did that
first episode and it sort of all went
from there and I have to be honest I
never anticipated it was going to be as
successful as it was I remember I sent
the first episode to my friends
and like cannabis friends and um and
they're all like oh yeah that's really
cool man like um where'd you find it or
whatever and I was like oh that's me and
at the time they'd never heard my voice
so they didn't and they're like that's
not you and I was like yeah yeah like
seriously I'm gonna I'm gonna try to do
this show you know and um so it was a
huge surprise to all of us that it went
so well but um definitely a labor of
love and one that sort of really took
off
um with a lot of its own momentum
that's really really cool dude I had no
idea that you did any of the audio
editing or anything like that
um you said you were musical as well
what do you play
uh yeah look I I try to be in my spare
time I am I I play guitar and I play uh
bass and on a good day I like to think I
can play drums and on a very good day I
I can maybe play a bit of piano so
um nothing I'm sure I'm sure everyone
out there who plays an instrument could
probably play it better than me on their
instrument but I can play a few which is
helpful and then
um I I don't really say it too much but
like any of the music or anything you've
ever heard in the show is just like
stuff I've made in my spare time
um so so yeah I like to do a few
different things it just helps me um
relax I find I love music for that
are you telling me right now that all
the music that you hear on the podcast
you've created
yeah bro yeah the bird noise is
everything
yeah yeah yeah I mean you just record
that right like I just recorded that in
the field
still that's really amazing man uh I
don't think my audio skills are up there
but I think it's really cool that you
and I play the exact same instruments so
yeah I'm not a master at any of them but
uh I would say guitar is my main you
know my main circumvent
um oh yeah but yeah are you the same
instruments we both dabbled in audio
before we got into this it's pretty damn
cool man
um I've got a couple questions I wanted
to get through really quick right here
from our patreon members
dank magician says what is your favorite
guest you've had a chance to interview
uh dank magician thank you for the
question it's one that I am always like
um battling myself internally because
I've got a bunch of favorites and people
always say to me like what's your
favorite I think undeniably a lot of
people really enjoyed the Chimera
interview because it was probably one of
the few interviews I did that does fall
into that more advanced category
and so that was quite memorable because
I was able to have quite a high level
discussion with someone about genetics
so that was really cool
um on a personal level I really like
episode 40 but I always be flowering he
had some very very modern takes on a lot
of issues
and I listened to it now and I could
totally believe it was recorded
yesterday like everything he says is
still so incredibly relevant and
accurate and he talks about strains that
are like still in the common Zeitgeist
of like hype stuff today and this
interview was done like three plus years
ago I really like that and his whole
thing that I took away from that was
like rather than getting mad at these
other dudes like you know secure your
own bag like you know don't get angry at
someone else doing it like for the most
part
um you know do your own thing so I
really love that
the the skunk VI episode I think is is a
brilliant one because uh he is a
fantastic Storyteller and largely
speaking the episode is just him
recounting his life story as opposed to
other episodes where like we'd talk a
little bit about your life and then like
a whole bunch about breeding and stuff
he was just largely speaking just
telling you his life story which I
thought was incredible so those ones
would be up there for sure but I'm also
going to throw out a controversial one I
absolutely love the Masonic one it was
such a uh a different perspective and I
try to do the show as like I try my best
to just
um not be too fussy with like there's a
lot of people who'll be like oh don't
get such and such on I don't like them
and I try not to listen to that sort of
stuff too much and just get anyone on
who I'm genuinely interested in and I'm
really glad I got Masonic on because his
views are so like contrary to the common
um answers you hear for questions about
breeding about
um collaborations things like that so I
think it was it was very different
probably very polarizing but I did enjoy
that one I have to admit do you know
we've all got what we like and what we
don't like but as our job as podcasters
is not deciphering that it's
interviewing these people taking in
their perspective and how they view the
world and then letting the viewers
decide for themselves you know
um so yeah I completely respect that uh
patreon members Stone stew says does he
remember there being named strains back
in the day or like where I grew up it
was just weed or orange Bud purple bud
etc etc
uh look I um I didn't get named weed for
the most part there was one or two
instances where I've got better quality
weed and I was told that it was white
rhino
more recently when I'm like you know in
the Cannabis scene and had some really
good White Rhino I can't exactly vouch
that the stuff I had back then was White
Rhino but I guess that would be
something which among my friends circle
growing up it was always touted like you
know bro White Rhino White Widow man
those are the strongest strains on Earth
if you can get them
um surprisingly I never got anything
that was called mullumbimby madness even
though I grew up not that far from about
two hours or so from sort of that area
so
um yeah surprisingly it never got given
that but yeah definitely I remember
White Widow White Rhino were said to be
the best thing ever and then I remember
when I turned 18 I went to Amsterdam I
tried white wine and right Widow and I
remember thinking I've had other stuff
here that were stronger I think so much
Sour Diesel Soma's diesel uh I thought
was better so there you go hopefully
that answers it for you my friend
hell yeah I have to ask for myself did
you ever have any encounters being in
that region to with the PNG
I don't in my heart of hearts I don't
think so I wish I wish I could have it's
like it's the Moby Dick man I'm chasing
it everyone says it's the best but yeah
I'm just not sure I got a buddy of mine
um who says he might have some seed
stock
but I think you'd have to grow It
Outdoors you know it's it's meant to be
so gnarly
yeah especially something that's become
acclimated to that region for so long
so
doing what you do
was there ever
any major worry about being in the
public eye
yeah I mean obviously still now but but
was there ever a point where you were
like [ __ ] maybe I should quit this or
maybe I should slow down did you ever
have any doubt in what you were doing
yeah a few times I think my barometer
has always been um my girlfriend I've
I've largely speaking I when I first got
into cannabis I was with this really
great girl who allowed me to do a lot of
growing even though she wasn't a smoker
and I I will always be grateful to her
for that and then I've also been with my
wife
um so over the whole time the public has
known me I've only ever been with those
two women and they would always be the
one who would tell me when I'm getting a
bit too grandiose with how many plants
I've gotten maybe maybe railing it in a
bit
um so I do need to give a shout out to
them for being the voice of reason
however there have certainly been times
where I've been concerned I've always
said to people look I've actually never
had any issues and
um I think the reason for that is pretty
simple I absolutely do not associate
with anyone who sells or uses hard drugs
now I don't want to go into the ethics
of like you know anything about that
really you know like I think drugs
should probably be legalized and stuff
but everyone I knew who ever got in
trouble it was always through that right
it was and so I just thought as a point
of precaution purely speaking I would
limit my Social Circle in that regard
and as a result I've actually never had
any issues and I think that sort of
speaks volumes for itself in a sense so
there have been times when I have been a
little bit worried about being a bit too
public like maybe you know the podcast
is out there you know the Australian
police could look it up and decide maybe
they want to try to find out who does
that but I don't think they are because
they largely speaking um have come out
on the public record they've done like
amas on Reddit surprisingly
um but they've done amas and people have
asked them you know like do you troll
through the Cannabis subreddits did you
draw through cannabis forums blah blah
and they were just like we don't have
the resources you know like we're too
busy trying to stop murders and rapes
and
um if something gets put in our lap if
if if your neighbor calls us up and says
they saw it like sure we'll do something
but we're not we're not putting any
resources into it and so for me I think
that bit of knowledge in combination
with that little bit of precaution I
take is largely speaking being able to
steer me pretty keep me on the pretty
straight and narrow so to speak because
I'm sort of like
not really bothering anyone and like I
oh and the other thing I should mention
is like I don't sell weed that's like a
big thing I think for me which helps
um like I don't sell any weed period
like I sell seeds but I don't sell weed
so I think that helps as well because um
yeah it's a different clientele
yeah it's a good mindset to have
and that's that's been something that's
helped me out as well you know
um obviously it's much more accepted
over here but where you know back in the
underground days I didn't there was no
regard just a plant count if you were
going to get busted with 10 you were
going to get busted with a hundred you
were going away either way no problem
um so where there was kind of disregard
for that then it kind of came into this
podcasting and everybody's like oh when
are you gonna be you know hunting you
know five different land races and [ __ ]
again like I I just don't have the heart
with what I'm doing now to to be like
that anymore
um not associating with people that do
hard drugs we definitely share that one
in common and uh I am a firm advocate of
um decriminalizing deep penalizing the
plant
um where it's not something that anybody
profits off of sure there's offshoots
like podcasts and things like that but
the actual product itself I would rather
see it like tomatoes in your garden than
anything else and I'd rather see
Neighbors sharing it amongst each other
you know you want to try some of the
sour diesel you want to try some of this
Rude Boy whatever
um and that's how it should be it should
be a gift it should be something that's
shared and that's kind of my perspective
on it
yeah man fully fully I am it's an
interesting one I still am not sure 100
where I land on that one but what I can
definitely say for sure is it seems like
the 215 model was Superior to what
Australia has now or
um what California has now like you know
where like home Growers are supplying
dispensaries and then other people can
get it from there like to me that model
sounded really quite sound
um and it's unfortunately not the case
in Australia you know there's only a few
big producers and they don't do a
particularly good job at it but
hopefully that changes in the future you
know
have not heard good stories yet I know a
couple of Australian Growers over there
I know a couple medical patients that uh
have gotten that stuff and they say
they'd rather get stuff off the street
most of the time because it was better
quality than the stuff that they were
getting uh access to
oh yeah yeah yeah the in my opinion it
is pretty well regarded as like you know
it's it's the general consensus the best
quality stuff you can get in the
Australian medical system is imported
from Canada and so what that Indica like
it's it's not the best you know like the
best is staying there we're getting I
joke around with people I say man we're
getting like the floor scrapings you
know
um and yet that's the best you can get
so it's such an indictment on the
quality of the domestic produced stuff
admittedly the companies are new you
know these Canadian companies have been
around a long time so they've sort of
got the production down a little better
but so much room for growth and and
there are some companies doing some cool
stuff in that space I've
um heard of a few things but yeah such a
long way to go
or a patreon member Greenwich says have
you ever interviewed anyone that pissed
you off
and you hung up if so who was it
no no no no that's fine I guess I guess
like let me answer that question and say
yeah definitely there are times when
people say things
um that I'm definitely like that's not
my view and
um I generally wouldn't I would hope
that you don't notice those moments
because my goal is that you you don't
pick up on that
um however as a point of
um sort of journalistic Integrity
something I realized very early on in
the show was that
um
plenty opportunities to like sort of try
to voice your own opinions and stuff so
for example I might have asked someone
to come on the show
and like maybe they said yes and then
like never turned up or maybe they never
replied and like there have been times
when I've like like anyone you know in a
moment of weakness you know you want to
leave a snarky comment or something like
that but you've got to rise above that
and recognize that if you say one thing
or if like right now I would say yeah
this guest said this blah blah blah then
any potential guest in the future will
will you'll sort of lose Integrity with
them because the guest needs to
ultimately trust that um you know
anything they're not comfortable with
will be removed that you know you're not
going to try to make them look too bad
so 100 man there there have been people
who have said some [ __ ] that I do not
agree with
um then unfortunately I can't tell you
their names
exactly much respect on that one man
so let's talk about breeding really
quick yeah cool that's not something I
knew about until fairly recently
how long have you been doing that
yeah good question probably the first
intentional seed cross I made was
probably
2013 2014 wow and then I don't and then
I don't think I made one for another
year or so I tested some of those seeds
and I just kept growing
um what I did was I did this cross very
early on into my growing career so I can
say yeah I made this cross all the way
back then but I then recognized that
there was no point breeding when I was
still growing relatively [ __ ] Bud
um and so I just needed to learn to grow
better weed first so basically the cross
I made was Don FM's story Amnesia
crossed to a Blue Ox mail by rare
dankness and I just jokingly called the
name blue story because it's like it
never got out I never really did much
with it so it was just easy even though
I'm sure there are strains called Blue
story
um anyway it was a really nice plant it
ended up making these um really sativa
bodied plants they had the strawberry
Amnesia structure
um but then they had like this sort of
Indica potency from the Blue Ox the Blue
Ox was like a blueberry cross to Bubba
Kush sort of thing so real Indica Med
sativa hybrid really cool plants I found
this one keeper Fino I still Daydream of
it was like um strawberry flavor with
like true vanilla I've never had it
outside of this one plant but like true
vanilla as I said I daydream about this
thing and um anyway yeah that was the
first cross I did and then it was um a
few years later at that time I was uh
studying my undergraduate degree which
was it was a Bachelor of Science and I
had two majors I did one in chemistry
and one in molecular biology and
genetics so I had an idea of what I was
doing but I wasn't growing great bud so
then I just focused on growing good bud
took me about a year
um got better progressively and then I
started breeding again and I'm really
stoked to say that some of those
earliest crosses are the things I'm
working on now and this would play into
something I would recommend to people
I I'm trying to get back to that point
because the the period of time I'm
talking about I didn't have as many
preconceived ideas about genetics back
then as I did now and I picked stuff
that I just it was interesting the
descriptions were cool it was like
something I'd never heard of and I truly
think that like some of the crosses I
made with that sort of stuff are the
most interesting to me because
um a lot of it was unintentional you
know I might have bought a certain pack
of seeds going yeah let's breed with
this and then something else happens to
produce a male that's really interesting
and you're like you know what this might
actually be better so I I encourage it
and I myself am trying to do it where
I'm trying to get back to like almost
like not looking at the breeder and just
reading the strain descriptions and just
looking at the parents and and trying to
just pick stuff that's different because
I'm telling people these days in regards
to breeding is like you know you you
can't compare to JB disease cushman's
reversal so so um you know don't hedge
your bets and try to do a cush mint
hybrid there's already people doing it
like maybe instead try to do something
that's totally different because people
will genuinely be interested if you're
like yay I use this blue Amnesia that is
strawberry Amnesia across to this Blue
Ox thing and you've probably never heard
of either of those but it's it's a nice
plan I assure you
um I think that's a way forward for
people who feel like we're in the corner
of genetics and are not entirely sure
where to start you know I would say
start by just picking stuff that's cool
that's cool that you brought that up I
haven't heard the Blue Ox name for a
while
but that was one that
I was really interested in it I never
gotta grow very much a rare dankness's
stuff
um I should say Scott uh but that Blue
Ox that was one that really excited me
the only one I ever grew was the ghost
train Haze and that one died off for me
after a while it was all right to begin
with and then it just kind of peaked out
there was another one about that time I
want to say it's called night terror
yeah yeah yep okay that one that one was
one that I'd probably still grow that to
this day I've been kind of looking at
no so out of everything that you've made
what are some of the standout ones to
you what are you most proud of like if I
was gonna say heavy days you got three
strains
that you can take and say I want this to
represent my genetics
oh great question
um
Okay so
the first one which most people would be
aware of with my work would be the
raspberry Mama
um basically this is a phantom Kush F2
so I got a pack of phantom Kush from
Ken's GDP it's pink Champagne cross to
Ken's Kush
I popped the seeds I found a mother that
was very shamp Pink Champagne leaning
and a father that had the same structure
appeared to be very Pink Champagne
leading I bred those together
so I made f2s and then from that popped
seed found a mum that was just entirely
what I was looking to find right it's
just basically Pink Champagne so then I
got that in like 2016 and I sort of
established myself with it it's like
this really nice Indica cushy thing with
like a baked raspberry tart sort of vibe
a bit of champagne to it really nice
perfumey cannabis it's not gonna put you
to sleep but it's like to me I describe
it as the perfect afternoon weed it's
like it's gonna take the weight off your
shoulders but still leaving you able to
get up and do stuff but you're just like
oh I don't feel like it's the end of the
day I feel sort of nice and it was a
really good for anti-anxiety at the time
I was having like sort of sporadic
general anxiety and so it would just hit
it on the heads I loved it so I made
some hybrids with that in like 2017
maybe 2018
um 2017 I think and then um uh it was
only a very small limited production
they never got out too far but a few
people who got those seeds like they
still hang on to the cuts and a few of
them have made their way back to me
which is really nice
and I did hybrids I did s1s
and then I had to move and in the
process of moving I lost the mum and it
was crazy because I thought I had it
backed up with friends but then it turns
out like they had lost it as well and I
was shattered and I lost it and then um
fast forward a few years a good buddy of
mine feral genetics he popped some of
those seeds he popped the S1 so it turns
out I gave him some and I sort of forgot
he's like yeah man I grew them out
um like not only do I have them I've
already grown them out I didn't tell you
I've popped them three months ago and
they're ready they're ready to harvest
and um one of them is insane you've got
to come look at it and I was like oh
yeah because he had never seen the mum
um so I went there and I smelled I was
like holy [ __ ] dude that's exactly it
like not not nine out of ten it like 10
out of 10 it
um and more importantly it was it was
dark the bud was purple and I for the
life of me I could never have gotten
raspberry mum and go purple she was just
like this green cushy plant so as far as
I was concerned this is better because
it's everything the mum had but it goes
purple really easy so that was pretty
cool and um so I got that and I've been
doing work with that but it's still that
S1 he found
um it's still just one of my favorite
plants so so definitely the raspberry
Mama which
um a lot of people don't know what Pink
Champagne is think of like a cherry pie
sort of thing like a unique
um Berry tart perfume sort of vibe so
it's similar to Cherry Pie in my opinion
so that would be the Phantom uh the
raspberry Mama the next one would be the
jelly breath that I found from in-house
genetics I've then worked that into a
bx2 line
so that would be the other one because
it's a really solid line
in-house has done his own jelly breath
work but it uses a different cutting and
I've spoken to both him and the guy who
found the cutting two-tone Willies it's
called the North Cascade cut of jelly
breath anyway mine's totally different
they're one
yeah yeah so it's like more of like a
dosey doe leaning Fina or like a 50 50
whereas my jelly breath is is almost 100
Mendo breath dominant so it's it's a
very different plant despite having the
same name and so my jelly breath work is
quite different to in-house's jelly
breath work
um
but that would be the other one so the
bx2 which is really cool
um and admittedly that is um you know
obviously in-house's work but I I feel
like I've worked it into a pretty
consistent bx2 line this particular Fino
and then the final one would be the dog
jelly which I made more recently using
that jelly breath mother I referenced
and then Crossing it to some seed stock
I was incredibly lucky to get
um our buddy Duke Diamond so he gave me
a chemd across to the Local H and I
think he said to me he only gave it to
like three or four people and I was one
I found a really nice male I hit it to
the Jelly breath and made this strainer
called Dog jelly and it's beautiful man
it's like cookies and like super loud
chem dog and gassy it's it's a really
special one to me and I've done my best
to really get those clones out I found a
few thinos that were really nice and
I've been giving them out to people all
around Australia and um I'm starting to
see it pop up more and more and I think
it would be really cool to get it out
more so I'm going to sort of do my best
to do that so that would be my three
jelly breath bx2 the raspberry mama and
the dog jelly and do you have those
available in both regs and femmes
because I know that you were doing
Femmes
yeah great question man so
um I I have done the Femmes and when I
was talking about historically having
done the raspberry mum Femmes that made
the s1s which then gave birth to the
plant I use now
um I made all the crosses back then with
the intention of trying to do reg
versions of them thereafter so at the
moment as you referenced I've I've
femmed to keep a mother onto my other
keeper mothers and you got the Femme
crosses but I'm also in the process of
working regular lines of those out
um I do regular crosses in general you
know I've done some different work with
some different males but I specifically
wanted to do like a male a regular
release of the Femme line I released
because I was lucky enough
um when my buddy found that S1 of the
the female he also found like a male in
that pack and we were sort of quite
suspicious at first and we were like
maybe it's like pollen contamination
Maybe some weird but we sort of stress
test this male and it dead set would not
show you what sex it was until you
actually put it into flour and let it go
for a few weeks so my thought process is
like there's a there's a chance it's a
small chance but there's a chance that
is in fact a male from Femme stock which
is known to happen Sam the skunk man
spoke about it and um very low chance
you know you're only meant to see that
oh cool right oh man maybe you can tell
me about it because I'm just trying to
figure out if it's real or not really
but yeah
I mean
you never know what's unless you're
packaging them yourself if you were in
that grow yourself you don't know what
happened maybe a bean rolled off the
counter from a different one you don't
know what their process is like but I
have definitely had a six-pack of Femmes
um I believe that was
I think those were Alaskan Thunder [ __ ]
and
one or two of them popped up mail I
think it was just one I think it was
just the one
cool
did you ever do anything with it or it
was just sort of like a cool Oh no I got
rid of it right away yeah I know I was
like well that's not what I was looking
for I mean most that that market in
itself the feminized seeds those people
are looking for a very specific thing
you know these are people with low plant
counts or that just want to guarantee
females in their grow so when that pops
up it was just automatic no no not at
all
yeah no I can appreciate that for sure
but yeah looking looking to maybe cross
that mail to the same mothers and then
see do those resulting seeds bear any
resemblance to the feminized ones I made
obviously it's a different plant but
it's from the same strain so you'd think
like it should be like just some basic
similarities just enough enough to be
able to be like yeah that doesn't seem
like it's contaminated pollen and it's
totally something different
can I ask you a very controversial
question
hit it let's do it
how do you feel about breeding regular
seeds with feminized seeds
I look I think the devil's in the detail
right but as as a rule of thumb I would
say that it appears fairly certain from
empirical evidence that you can breed
like you can get a mother from Femme
stock and then fem that onto other stuff
doesn't seem to inherently increase the
rates of hermaphrodism you can
selectively see it but it you don't see
it across the board because people like
canarado that's his whole business model
is like make a series of Femme hybrids
phenohundham the best one is the one we
reverse for the next round of Femme
hybrids we make and the same is said for
compound genetics and it just doesn't
seem that the empirical evidence is
there that enough people are putting
their hands up and saying hey this is
like I'm getting at least one home a
pack or something you know and I sort of
joke around with people and say that I
think you should honestly go into every
phenohunt with the expectation that one
plant will have term because a it's not
that high of a bar you know you should
give people a little bit of slack you
know plants harm every now and again and
it just happens but on top of that any
more than that and you can start to have
some um you know questions that are not
unreasonable to be asking you know if
you're getting two herbs in a pack maybe
there is something unstable about those
genetics but
um and then if you're getting 10 herbs
in a pack it's probably on you bro check
the light leaks but um uh yeah it's
definitely an interesting topic I do
suspect that if you femmed on to famed
onto Femme for like forever
then like yeah you might see some
deviation in the way the genes Express
themselves in terms of sexual stability
but I don't think we're there long term
and it seems as though like enough sort
of Femme stuff happens that you know if
it is if it is increasing the rates of
hermaphrodism it's happening very slowly
and we haven't in my opinion we haven't
yet truly detected it and
um I think it's just more anecdotal you
know like I I honest to God feel like I
I get less homes now than I ever have
maybe that's a reflection of my
environment being more dialed but um
yeah at the moment I would happily pop
seeds that are like femin to Femme and I
would happily make those sorts of seeds
and sell them
um so long as I was confident they were
stable and that everyone sort of knew
what they were in my most recent seed
release that I did the sort of version
twos of the raspberry Mumma fans I
wanted to make it very clear that the
plant I was reversing was an S1 you know
so I I think I did make that very clear
in a number of ways
um in terms of like if you read the
descriptions on the posts and the actual
infographics and all that but yeah I
just think like as long as you're
upfront about it like this that that is
really up to the consumer to decide and
I myself as a consumer
um don't I I would run Canada I would
run compound I don't think it's going to
be home City so to speak
very very good answer and I appreciate
your honesty on that one okay one of our
patreon members dank magician wants to
know uh what solution do you use for
your reversals
nice one good question I have used uh
Matt Wright's reversal spray in the past
and had success with it I would
recommend that spray I more recently
have used a local option which was
um just in the past when I've used matte
spray it's been very successful for me
but it comes from America you know it
takes a few weeks to arrive and
sometimes I'm not as organized as I
should be and I don't have a few weeks
unfortunately
um so I've been using some more local
options which I've had some good success
with my buddy has a company called
um
uh old sod's reversal spray and that's
an australian-based company that you can
use who do a really nice STS solution
it's made fresh when you order it
um and you can also have the option of
mixing it yourself if you'd like I've
had good success with that
um and I've also used another product by
a buddy of mine uh called feral genetics
I've mentioned him a few times he also
sells an STS solution
um I think that's a slightly different
formulation and I've had success with
both of those products so if you're an
Australian person definitely check out
those two guys they've got great
products I would be really interested in
using hybratex solution which is the
cobalt chloride solution as opposed to a
sodium thiosulfate so yeah so I I'm Keen
to give the cobalt chloride solution a
go I've heard nothing but great things
about hypertext product which is that
but I've also had great success with STS
I've never used colloidal silver and I
don't think I ever will because
um I I just hear like it's it's a bit
finicky the application you've got to
use it Con instantly and um yeah just
seems like less efficient to me
how often are you using that one
uh sorry which one are we talking about
specifically the one that uh did you say
you were using the Cobalt recently
no I would like to use that but I
haven't but apparently it's literally a
once application I've spoken to
I can't remember who it was it might
have been right
so they all say one time but
um I I tend to use an STS spray a couple
of times just to really ensure you're
saturating all those nodes because it's
really like that axial branching node
point that you really want to try to
saturate so I I I go against the rules
and I apply STS a few times and I don't
see any negatives to it and I like to
think it slightly increases my chances
getting a successful reversal
um however I've been told I'm quite good
authority that that Cobalt one you
really only need to apply it one time as
hybrotech advertisers because apparently
like it stresses the plan out a bit if
you um if you applied a number of times
I've seen some very frazzled looking
plants and the other thing to quickly
mention because you know people may not
know this until they've done a few
reversals the first reversal I ever did
went reasonably successful in the grand
scheme of things and then the next two I
did went horrible and so I went into
them thinking this is easy I've done
before it worked like I just sprayed it
and it just worked
um and so it's worth noting that like
when you reverse a plant to make
feminized seeds it's sort of it's not
like a binary outcome it's not like oh
this plant successfully reversed or this
plant didn't it's usually like oh
there's some bananas but mostly female
buds or it's like
all the way through to there's no
bananas and on the other end of the
spectrum it's expressing as if it's an
entirely male plant and so it truly is
important to reverse a couple planets
um I would say three is a good number
and you'll be fairly certain to get one
that will reverse really nicely and
you'll just get like that male
morphology and it's just damp and pollen
that's what you want
um because I've had like two that have
just sort of like not really got there
they're not really releasing much pollen
at all and it's like a failed reversal
and so keep that in mind and if you are
making feminine seeds anyone out there
always have a male backup Mass medical
taught me this and it's true because
um I I did this femrun and the Femme
failed and I had a I had a different
strain I was also spraying and I was
like if if the the main one doesn't work
I use the backup one and the backup one
didn't work either so like at the end of
the day yeah the the end of the day you
need a mail that you know will produce
pollen on cue if it's in the right light
cycle so um yeah that would be a bit of
advice too otherwise you'll end up
getting a Scentsy crop when maybe you're
hoping to have some seeds
very very good answer
so we have a few more minutes here so
I'm going to ask you a few more
questions I wanted to get into
the other controversial one really quick
which is how do you feel about testing
yeah great question
um
like just to make sure we're talking the
right thing like THC contents and stuff
no testing uh your genetics or stability
no there's no hard and fast rule but I
think that it's important to be very
upfront with what you're doing so for
example the most recent raspberry Mama
release I did I had not finished
flowering out those plants yet because
they were remakes I had already made
those crosses a few years ago so in that
situation I didn't really felt like it
was going to achieve much more than what
I already had in terms of the
information because it was like I'm just
doing the V2s
um so that situation is one where I felt
comfortable for it to go out and then
when I did that
seed run I had some new mothers in the
room and those ones didn't really go out
because I'm still testing those now
because I'm just some of them others are
new I'm not as familiar with them I
remember I was talking to JJ from Top
Dog genetics a while ago and he said
something that lasted with me which is
like you probably should test everything
right but for someone like him if he's
got like a certain Tres dog male he's
been breeding with for like five years
he sort of knows how that male is
generally going to interact with things
and so I'd be happy to accept if someone
said to me hey look I've got this mail
I've had for a number of years I've done
a few different lines with it like a few
different releases like you know maybe
20 strains in total with it and I I know
what it works with I could probably tell
you it's not going to pair well with
these sorts of strains they tend to her
um I could accept that and be like yeah
that that's I'm happy to accept that
that's reasonable empirical evidence but
I think that if you're making some
totally new stuff
um
it's important to test it not from
necessarily the consumer point of view
because as Masonic does he's so upfront
I don't test anything like you know like
it's not tested but I'm charging you
this price take it or leave it
um however the reason why I think you
should test it is because it takes five
years to build your reputation and five
minutes to destroy it and um I think
that's what is really at risk is your
reputation because
um
you know at the end of the day I don't
like if someone stuff Herms on me it it
is what it is you know I'm never gonna
get that time back so it's sort of a
live and learn thing so I think that
it's it's it's tough one because and
this is the other thing you know if
someone grows your seeds and they Herm
and you're like oh hey I'd like to make
it better and send you some seeds they
probably don't want to grow more of your
seeds out
um and so it does leave you in a tough
position as a breeder because you might
be like oh I'd love to make that right
for you but it's um I'm not exactly sure
what so yeah it's um it's it's an
interesting one to navigate that
Minefield but I think above all as long
as you're honest no one can really
criticize you and if you want to make
sure you don't end up with egg on your
face maybe you should test but you don't
necessarily need to
everybody has their own goals absolutely
um before we get going here buddy I
wanted to ask you
aside from things that you've created
what are your top three favorite types
of cannabis that you've smoked today
uh what a great question man all right
um
I I used to have as I mentioned earlier
I used to have very bad anxiety like
generalized anxiety so it sort of just
come on sporadically nothing
specifically triggering it and for that
reason I struggled with sativas I just
couldn't handle them
um
however as I got over that that was
probably about eight years ago as I got
over that I began to enjoy sativas now
to the point where it's like they're
they're definitely my favorite and um
they're probably I can probably honestly
say there will come a time when I will
only smoke sativas probably
um and so as a result some of my
absolute favorite varieties are like
unique sativas
um I think
death
definitely if I had to give you three
genius from Brothers Grim is one of the
most memorable clones I've been able to
smoke it was unlike 90 of sativas out
there it was it was um uplifting and
cerebral but it was very clear-headed it
was very focused sensitive is like Cindy
99 you smoke them and it's great but
every 10 seconds you're like what was I
doing again because you got that
fogginess but um genius was the opposite
the name fit man makes you feel like a
genius so clear-headed and focused and
that was one for sure I've got to give a
huge shout out to um like Jack Harris
Super Silver Haze it's probably gonna
get me uh clowned on a bit but being
someone who didn't live in America I've
never been burnt out on jakara I've had
some incredible samples of Jack Herer
and I think to me super silver haze that
keep a cut that you see floating around
is in that same vein of like very racy
very uplifting
Piney terpenly indominant sativas I
really really enjoy that this is
probably a very like unexpected answer
but like I love that [ __ ] but the final
one would be
um I had most years when I've come over
to the states I've been lucky enough to
spend the night before I go home I would
usually spend it at Bodie's house and I
would just get to smoke all this crazy
land race [ __ ] and then um jump on the
plane all buzzed and fly home and he
gave me
I believe it was Vietnamese number seven
it's he posts about it on his Instagram
you can see it if you check it out
um you'll find it Vietnamese number
seven it's like you know he popped who
knows how many Vietnamese seeds and that
was the number seven some of the most
unique weed I've ever had in my life
like so legitimately giggly like nothing
is giggly compared to this stuff like
uh my dream would be to like do a comedy
show and to force everyone to smoke this
on the way in it would be insane but um
yes so uplifting so fun yeah one of a
kind that's a great answer man that's
cool uh we're both musicians who both
appreciate sativas you do the comedy the
[ __ ] I've been searching for giggly
weed that's something
that I feel that's been lost throughout
time you know something that's really
been bred out I can't say I've had any
modern cultivars I don't I don't truly
believe
that it's something
that you can find in a lot of modern
cannabis anymore because everything that
affected me that way I don't think it
was a tolerance to build up to THC that
did it I think it was a certain
endocannabinoid profile that
made that you know that effect
um and I get it with some ties and
that's why I appreciate ties so much but
that is something that I've heard about
the Vietnamese and that's a reason that
I've been kind of looking that out do
you know if that was the Vietnamese gold
or the Vietnamese black or
but
sorry excuse me
um I I
honestly don't know it was green so I
don't think it was the Vietnamese black
um I think he said that it was like a
low land Vietnamese he said he thinks of
them as like either Highland or lowland
I think from memory he said it was low
land
um so maybe the highlands turn purple or
something in there the Vietnamese blacks
or
um I'm not 100 sure but I have had a
bunch of um
ties a bunch of different stuff I had a
very memorable tie from Bodhi actually
it looked exactly Picture Perfect like
that Infamous photo of um Dr grinspoon
with like just the single alternating
calyxes
um yeah it was it was really cool stuff
equally special uplifting fun
um yeah really cool stuff and I think
when I spoke to Bodhi as well he said
that largely speaking the the strains
um just move around in those areas and
so like Vietnamese Thai it's like it's
it could be very interchangeable really
similar regions
yeah it's very cool man and that's
something I definitely want to look into
I cannot wait to do another episode with
you if you are ever down for that
because we gotta cover so much I learned
so much about you on this episode uh you
are very detailed and very skilled in
your answers just like you are when
you're interviewing so I really
appreciate having you on as a guest and
you not giving a [ __ ] and sharing your
true opinions on these things it's been
very cool
uh you're too kind my friend I really
appreciate the opportunity to come on I
would be honored to come back again and
chat some more and um really really
lovely to be able to have a fun
conversation with a contemporary and
with all the listeners you know really
appreciative again
absolutely man
appreciate you again uh all of our
patreon members thanks for showing up
asking questions for heavy days and
until next time you all have a good
night
[Music]
I said baby
I know you're on a road
[Music]
come on
and moving on