foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
why don't you cry
[Music]
good evening everybody and welcome to
another episode of the calyx and crew
podcast I'm your host as always.calyx
and today I am joined by two very lovely
women uh can a Queenie here
how are you doing I'm
doing very well thank you for asking and
we have Canik here inspired hey guys
I came here to talk to you guys today a
little bit about what you guys do can a
Queenie you are an absolute Powerhouse
I've been helping Mentor you and I can't
wait to see you [ __ ] explode with
life because you've got so much going on
for you Canna Care you are already an
independent Boss by the time I met you
so I'm very excited I want to know a
little bit more about what you guys do I
know canacure makes Edibles actually I
should run and grab one of those during
the show that's what I should be doing
because I promised her I would I still
have that land
but I want to know what Queenie what is
the can of Boss Beauties tell me more
about that okay so cannonballs Beauties
are women who are no longer in the green
closet so they're not hiding that they
medicate they are not hiding that they
use the plant their mothers they're not
mothers their their sisters their best
friends they're just women that want to
come together unite smoke medicate heal
treat themselves and be able to do it in
a safe positive space without judgment
and make money and turn that love of the
plant into some type of small business
because a lot of the Cannibal's Beauties
are disabled they suffer with chronic
illness so they need to make their own
um stream of income
so I couldn't be a can about you you can
you can be a Cannibal's Beauty you know
because it's not limited to women die
no no no no no no we accept everybody as
a matter of fact a part of the platform
in reality is a big um a big Spotlight
on mental health for men so we have a
lot of men who come on to the lives and
they talk about their own trauma their
own relationships and I think in
listening to all of us they're learning
so much about themselves so I think a
Cannibal's Beauty can be a male or
female because I think men are beautiful
I don't think beauty is limited to just
a woman so I'm down I accept everybody
I'm inclusive not exclusive
like yeah everybody seems to kind of
have their Niche though so I was
wondering if that was part of it I know
you guys definitely Empower a lot of
women especially women that have small
businesses to you know blow up and kind
of expose them you all help each other
out kind of like we do over in the
Discord you all group together and
you're out to help each other you're not
there for competition you're there for
one purpose and that's helping each
other out constantly I want to talk to
you about your Edibles here for a second
Let's uh let's bring you up really quick
on the big screen
wait what
all right so how long have you been
making edibles
it's like
I think edibles
only a year
yeah what was the first edible you made
um just cookies regular chocolate chip
cookies
so how did we go for cookies to cake
pops nerds ropes
I like
this in the kitchen I just constantly
I'm making new things so it was always
empties everything with DHC every well
once I started influencing after that it
was like constantive confused everything
yeah where can we fit this in that's
awesome yeah huge congrats here in a
little bit and show everybody
not only are they awesome but they're
extremely potent way too potent for me
I've been growing since 0-4 and I've
made the classic brownies and cookies
and all that [ __ ] but never in my life
have I I think the most intense thing
I've ever seen is like a silo Simon
infused truffle like a chocolate truffle
and those are amazing but
the the [ __ ] that you do with cannabis
is pretty damn cool
and 200 milligrams or a cake pop that'll
knock out a horse it won't
I have a horrible metabolism and so I
need two and so I am a frequent Shopper
of candy
because
I did try the cookies the cookies were
very very good
um but I have yet to have a cake pop and
I think I'm going to take at least I'll
take half of it I'll take half of it I'm
not as cool as you Mel I can't take that
many Edibles I don't know what it is
I'll dab anybody under the table or
smoke them out all [ __ ] day but I
ain't about to get into an Edibles race
I'm so excited to see this
I am too
so when did the Cannabis Beauties thing
start
um I started can a Queenie combos back
in I think it was uh March of this of
2022 and then the girl started just
coming on and we couldn't figure out a
name because at the beginning I was like
oh can a mom boss but cannabis Boston or
whatever but I can't be like that
because not all the girls are moms so
I'm like okay what are we gonna do and
baby oh Olga I was on a live one day at
an event and she's like you know what
Mel cannibals Beauties and I think that
was like June of this year and we put
cannonballs Beauties together with the
Cali trip and it just kind of stuck and
that's what we are that's why I keep
saying it's men and women because
when you I I get the thought like
Cannabis beauty you think women but
again we got to start including men in
in the business I Empower women but at
the same time if I shut off my mind
to not dealing with men in some sort of
in some sort of capacity then you and I
wouldn't be having this exchange right
now
and so I had to find a balance where I
could still
I could still include men but make the
women feel like they had their voice and
I'm still trying to figure that out but
I think I'm I think we're on the right
track because most of the men that come
to our lives are super respectful
they've been in the Cannabis industry
they kind of know what we're about and I
think we've already showed people that
if
you know if any of the men come to our
lives and they're disrespectful or you
know they can't
um treat us the right way we kind of
unite as a group and we stick up for one
another and we'll go to bat for one
another to make sure we're respect you
guys had your Cali meet up pretty
recently and everybody sounds like they
had a very amazing time at that I mean
I'm sure it's a Vegas situation we can't
explain everything I don't need every
detail here
but what was some of the highlights of
the trip
mushrooms
trip yeah
yeah that's what I like to hear I'm
definitely a silo Simon uh Advocate just
as much as cannabis I tell everybody I
use cannibal cannabis for the physical I
use Silo 7 for the mental
as well definite highlight of your trip
me and a wall had a very deep
conversation and uh I remember
physically having a conversation with
the wall and like expressing my emotions
and you know what it was the first time
as a woman that I was like I am actually
speaking to a wall but change is
happening like because I'm usually it's
okay this
will all [ __ ] understands right now
can a cure got me through that
he got me through that shroom strip
she really thank God you got somebody
like candy absolutely I'd get I'll do it
again with her any day I'll get I'll
I'll trip on from her was that your
first time doing shrooms
pieces
um you're gonna feel like you have
energy and then it said 10 and up the
walls are gonna melt well I ate 12.
because I wasn't raised to be a quitter
and I went balls to the wall and the
walls melted the walls truly did melt
Spider-Man was moving
Spider-Man was dancing I swear to God
you lost me it shrooms in a box okay so
it's chocolate it was chocolate shrooms
okay oh so this was like a homegirl that
gotcha
I was like what where the hell are you
getting mushrooms in a box because I
need to go down to California
we're gonna go Costco on that [ __ ]
what are you smoking on over there
Queenie
uh from my personal pharmacist in the
west coast oh gee rights
OG runs right on what about you can't
okay
I am smoking the white runs
everybody's rancing up their life huh
damn I'm the only one different over
here
I will say I enjoy
you know West Coast guys
you're on the west coast right doc
you're concerned right yeah I'm up in
Washington right was that the farthest
you've ever traveled
quit I can shut up for a sec we can hit
something I'm down
maybe not smoke today
hit it DOC
I will say while you're warming up your
Banger there
that
uh can cure
played an essential role in some of the
changes that I made and a lot of it had
to do with the fact that her and I we
um connect on a level of having 80 you
know being women with ADHD and I think
that this trip was the first time that I
was in a position
where I was constantly being
overstimulated
I wasn't sleeping you know the strain
after strain after strain after strings
I was kind of like up and down and I
remember at one point Canada cure had a
we had like a deep talk
and
and a lot of it had to do with the fact
that I finally found someone at 44 who
could understand my ADHD and not make me
feel bad about myself
so out of the whole trip I probably took
the conversation that her and I had
together in her car that was probably
one of my favorite moments out of the
whole trip
you know what I mean because it was like
I finally felt understood and accepted
for exactly who
I am at such an older age too
cheers
[Music]
no
like you said in the Discord doc we died
with each other here
we we don't mute when we dab I'm Discord
right we just die together
[Laughter]
the Discord is like
so I've been doing this [ __ ]
on IG and like 14 or 15 somewhere in
there
excuse me and back then uh it was me and
my ex and we'd just sit on a couch we'd
have my phone right in front of us and
we'd just smoke weed and talk to whoever
popped in there wasn't a point
we were just getting high with random
people
yeah and uh it eventually turned into
like
people that I knew coming into lives
with us and we just talk about [ __ ] that
we learned about cannabis and uh people
started watching it and realizing you
know who I was what groups I ran with
and [ __ ] like that and it just kind of
naturally evolved and it got to a point
where
I never felt I never had enough
confidence in myself
to think that I can be a business owner
I uh I grew up in you know Orchards and
[ __ ] I was a farmer my entire [ __ ]
life so
um for anybody that's
in that lifestyle it's kind of like this
is the rest of your life
Farms get handed down generation to
generation that's what you're gonna do
you know and that you're not ever gonna
be much more than a farmer
so something happened along the way
where I got
seeds and I fell in love with the plant
and uh I disconnected with it for a few
years and then got a bag seed and a bud
of like ghost train Haze and said you
know what I'm going to try to pop this
one open
and I sure is not enough cracked it and
it was kind of like the old days just
water it let it grow but I didn't really
understand too much about the plant so
at that point I really wanted to
understand how some of these people on
IG were like getting these you know
great yields and [ __ ] like that so it
took my interest to learn as much as I
could and I just
I can't even put into words the amount
of passion that I have in myself for
cannabis it's beyond anything else
and everything LED down another Wormhole
from going to learn how to get better
yields and training my plants and to
soil what's going into the soil the
science behind the soil what I can do to
make it better
um the environment everything I could
learn about cannabis I did and I'm still
learning every single day but uh
I guess at the end of the day I looked
at it and I said hey this is still
agriculture
it is and it was time to up my game I
can do something with my life and that
was a huge change to me and having that
much confidence when I see that and
other people that have that [ __ ]
passion and that fire like you uh Mel
when I saw you you had so much fire and
passion and you I just knew you needed
that little boost of confidence and a
little guidance to get you to where you
want to go just like I did and I had a
really good friend help me out as well
so it's nice having
make friends with people that are going
to make you a better you
if you're surrounding yourself with [ __ ]
you're going to have [ __ ] if you
surround yourself with [ __ ] leaders
and positivity that's what you're going
to have in your life surround yourself
with the kind of people that you relate
to that you want to become like you know
take inspiration from those people and
don't let people uh you know put you out
at all it's easy where humans we're
emotional creatures but uh there's
always going to be somebody that doesn't
like you you know
[ __ ] him there's 10 people that do like
you for everyone that hates you you know
that's why they hate you so much this is
my Mantra be friends with someone that's
not afraid to say your name in a room
full of opportunity
you know what I'm saying like that's the
type of people I want to roll with when
I go somewhere maybe okay so I do make
candles on the side and you know I don't
even talk about it because it's not
where my heart is right so I forget that
I even do it but if I go somewhere and
they're like
well I don't like candles but I like
Edibles well I got somebody who knows
Edibles why like somebody who does resin
well then we'll throw them to santuli
santuli does resin or I need someone
that does shirts well you know so we
we move like that Sarah and I went to um
Thicket the thicket now headquarters out
in Chino and before we left we were
looked at each other and Sarah was like
I'm not leaving without something for
the girls and I was like I ain't neither
what are we gonna ask for like are we
gonna ask for nine tickets like are we
gonna and Sarah was like yeah let's ask
for [ __ ] night think it's like two
shirts and I stood there and I was like
[Music]
we walked out of there with
ambassadorships for each and every girl
with their own code and like
okay
we gave them an opportunity to now
become ambassadors so they could go to
other companies and [ __ ] they know
I've done this before I've already had
my own code you know and they feel
empowered and that is what a can of Boss
Beauty is my sister's success is my
success
we are not in competition
but the Cannabis Community has to stop
being in competition there's room for
everyone
we have a common ground so why are we
trying to be in competition with one
another when we can help one another
there's always someone for something for
and so I'm still trying to find myself
in Canada Queenie but that's where it
keeps leading me down that road and it's
helping other women get to where they
gotta go and maybe coming up with an
idea for another woman that she didn't
think of or
but candy cure for me is more than just
edibles
like candy cure also does RSO and she
does like you know RSO greens and she
does
CBD and she just
she heals my family too like I trust her
products with my son and my husband and
so
when I think of candy cure I Edibles
comes to mind but more her RSO and her
Dragon juice and her infused lemonade
and the way people can medicate without
smoking using her products
you know I'm glad you brought that up
that's something that I wanted yeah yeah
like I thought that was a more recent
Venture uh you getting into the RSO
how did that end up coming out
um I started making RSO uh around the
time my dad died well I made it before I
died
um
kind of for somebody
a patient who would actually buy all of
it so I never got to
confuse any of it
um and then when my the patient ended up
dying he was a cancer patient so it was
you know
then I started making it for myself or
for my dad and then it was kind of too
late on that end
also as well
and now I kind of get to keep it as cool
[Music]
migration and
it's for you guys
um I didn't really treat myself before
with any of my my medications besides
with herb um
there was a big change when I did start
doing that now
the inflammation has definitely changed
I know this difference a lot
that I'm using it uh I don't have a lot
of that when I when I use the RSO I
don't have information and I don't have
pain it's very obvious it's very it's
clear
um smoking and medicating with RSO is
completely different
um I feel like smoking has been almost
no benefit but for mental benefit
um that's pretty much it
definitely not as powerful or pain
relief
um because when you smoke it you're
you're hitting a lot of CB1 receptors
when you eat it
um or digest it like you do with RSO and
edibles
they're hitting CB2 receptors and those
are a lot better at uh at treating that
pain
100 percent
different feeling different
um
absorption I don't know it's different
so on a daily basis uh what would you
say milligram wise was like your
treatment
where are you like I'm okay I have very
little pain
um I don't know I probably take like
four grains
a day
I don't think that's a lot
and your res your most recent edible you
did uh
the lemonade the sweet tea and there's
one other what were those
300 milligram drinks I heard very good
things about that from everybody
yes I definitely want to get in the
sweet tea
do you think the pink lemonade
the pink lemonade hands down the pink
lemonade is my favorite
what about you candy
it's the pink lemonade
pink was that the consensus that you got
and reviewed all those it was like
everybody's saying pink lemonade or was
there something that was a little more
popular
names I think you need a third judge and
I think I need to be that person
okay I'll send you
because I saw that I saw that I was like
I'm all about that
so what's the newest Adventure
for uh your podcast there Mel let's
shout that one out really quick oh thank
you actually I'm gonna start I've
committed to start dropping my episodes
every Wednesdays at 4 20 p.m Eastern
Standard Time
and I think I'm gonna start focusing on
endometriosis
uh fibromyalgia
and I think I'm going to start doing
like a dab review
because I'm really liking the dabs
so I think that that's the next venture
I think I'm not going to do one-on-ones
on the podcast I think I'm Gonna Keep
one-on-ones on my lives and then I think
on the podcast that's just gonna be me
speaking no camera
and I'm gonna you know do outlines and
I'm gonna stick to all
kind of scripting so that's gonna change
that's gonna be different from my first
four or five episodes
um moving forward I'm gonna call It
season two
I'm gonna call It season two and that's
just gonna be more me doing my own
cannabis education my own mental health
awareness my own chronic illness
awareness Journey
um
and do like strain of the day like
strain reviews
so I think that's what I'm gonna start
you're both awesome women and you're
doing awesome things and I want more
people to find out about you I want you
guys to be more successful and more
happy uh with your lives you know thank
you guys yeah absolutely I'm gonna go
grab that edible from Canna Care really
quick uh um in the states like I've been
to Dominican Republic I'll make Puerto
Rico you know but I've never been I've
you know because I I studied and I lived
in Puerto Rico my husband's from
Dominican Republic so but this was the
first time I went from like East Coast
to West Coast like across the country
per se I loved the Cali climate I loved
the tacos
I had tacos every single day
I love the tacos
Del Taco
um shout out to Del Taco
um I
enjoyed waking up every day and session
with my Canon sisters I enjoyed being in
an environment for the first time as a
woman where I was encouraged to eat
where I was encouraged to snack where I
could walk around with just a t-shirt
and underwear and everyone would scream
Mel get your pants on but no one judged
me like you know I was able to heal from
trauma I was able to
be away from my husband for the first
time since I was 17 years old wow and be
on an independent trip without my
partner in crime like
I had to grow I had to depend on myself
for every single moment
and for someone who's been in a
relationship
more
more than she was alive without one that
was an incredible journey for me
to go on and to feel those feelings
without being able
to turn to my husband and have him
encourage me so I learned a lot of
self-validation
and a lot of self-correction on this
trip
so
yeah and let me tell you Ventura beach
was beautiful uh Pismo beach was
beautiful
uh we went to Ventura Beach at night we
had a bonfire me candy care we were
waiting for Rasta and you know I healed
that night on the beach I have a lot of
trauma with the beach
and you know I held my sister's hands
and we went into the water at night and
you know I got all of that on you know
there were moments that maybe the girls
didn't even realize were just Monumental
for me and they were the small things
that no one would think mattered but
they mattered incredibly to me like my
drive with canacure seeing where she
grew up seeing the school she went to
you know meeting her grandmother meeting
her brother you know
it was a privilege and it didn't it
didn't Escape me what a privilege it was
to be accepted into her home into Olga's
home into Stoney the Latina's home you
know
um I'm blessed to know these women you
know I didn't grow up
with this type of community so to find
it at an age where I was already
starting to feel lost was
um life-saving like cannabis and can a
Queenie save me and cannabis saved me
you know cannabis saved my life and
what I've I've encountered in Instagram
good bad or indifferent has saved my
life you have changed me for the better
so
that's my reflection
that's all in what what year did you
start smoking like what was your first
experience
well you know I'm from the South Bronx
so I grew up around weed you know I
always believed that weed and Hip-Hop is
the Bronx in New York like you know you
can't talk about the South Bronx and not
mention weed and Hip-Hop so I was
probably like
I want to say 15 the first time like I
used to have a blunt with like a bacon
egg and cheese for breakfast you know
but it wasn't anything but to be out
smoking with people and cutting class
you know
um in 2015
I was was when my endometriosis started
to flare and I became I had three months
left to my masters and one month left
for my own Department after working for
23 years to get it and bladder
endometriosis took all that and none of
the pain medication I was on help
amitriptyline Gabapentin Lupron I did
chemo for it everything nothing worked
and finally my friend's husband who was
one of my patients at the hospital he
brought me a blunt he drove from
Greenwich Connecticut to the to New York
City which is like almost an hour and he
brought me a blunt and he was like yo
sis hit this and I was like no I can't
do that you know you know if if I go
back to work they'll drug test me and he
was like no hit this hit this
and I remember just taking a poll
and then by the third pull my bladder
just relaxed and pain that I have been
fighting for three years
like it relaxed and I never turned back
but now I do more than just smoke I dab
I take RSO I take CBD you know I
I I treat it
I do it more than just recreational now
I feel like it's 360. I treat myself in
different ways I did not know that much
I didn't know that you went through
chemo for it that's yeah lupon is one of
the Lupron is one of the first
medications they give women with
endometriosis because what it does is it
causes medical menopause and the thought
behind endometriosis is a dominance in
estrogen and I know you're a dad to
three girls so it's it's quite an
opportunity to be able to educate you
while they're still small because one in
three women have endometriosis so if you
have three daughters the chances that
one of them may have endometriosis is
more than 76 and so uh girls as young as
nines begin with signs of endometriosis
and
um we don't get we don't get much
research we don't there's no treatment
plan so what they they do is they say
well let me give you the loop run
because if like if you you don't have a
period in a year and then your pain goes
away well we'll do a hysterectomy
because that's the only way we can take
a woman's estrogen right well this is
the problem I'm on the Lupron there's
tons of [ __ ] side effects from the
Lupine and I'm talking hair loss bone
loss bone density loss um hot flashes uh
chronic pain fibromyalgia depression
suicide anxiety these are all the side
effects and I'm still in pain
and I'm not menstruating and I'm still
developing new endometriomas
nobody can help and so
endometriosis is what brought me to
cannabis and I'm making it one of the
main parts of my platform because I keep
meeting people like you doc who have a
daughter you know I have three daughters
or you know a a husband who's like you
know my wife is always in pain and I
don't know why and
it's become almost a part of the vision
and the mission to make clear that
cannabis is the only proper treatment
other than surgery to help with
endometriosis healing it is the only
medication that can help manage stage
four endometriosis pain period well no
one can convince me and when you mix the
flour with the RSO there's even studies
that show that RSO can help generate new
tissue which is what women need new
regenerative endometrium lining tissue
so there's there's research that RSO can
help with that and so if I can bring
that and I can just help one woman
then my job is done
that's how I'm gonna bring 25 years of
clinical experience and my journey with
cannabis and endo
to the table
that's [ __ ] incredible
and see this is that passion I was
talking about as you got into that and
you told the story and you got deeper
and deeper I can feel it bring you back
in this is something close to you that's
[ __ ] amazing thank you that chemo
would not work for you but three hits of
cannabis and you almost get instantly
saying something about the plant facts
it's a fact
so you recently both of you recently
joined uh my Discord Canon Queenie
you're a member over there I can't care
you came in recently what do you guys
think about it so far yeah
I look forward
whenever
we all know who that person is he's like
my personal cheerleader it's not dark
sorry it's painting
I think it just takes a lot of death
he just makes me feel like I did a five
gram dab and it's like a tiny and he's
like yeah Queenie [ __ ] yeah yeah oh yeah
and meet the tiniest little dad but no I
love it I love the vibe and I love the
environment that you created at your
Discord dog that's just period that's a
fact I love it I love it love it love it
it's it's a hard thing to do
and I will tell you uh one of the
greatest tips that I could give you is
don't be afraid to fail
nothing that you ever do for the first
time like this are you gonna start off
awesome or there's nothing to learn
there's no reason to grow at all you're
gonna [ __ ] up and I've had some big [ __ ]
ups during this thing but all those
fuck-ups are doing if you sit there and
you focus on them you're gonna drive
yourself insane
um but at the end of the day like you
got to realize you're going to [ __ ] up
and you just gotta deal with it move on
you would not have made a decision if
you did not think it was right at the
time so just make your decision and move
on uh but stick true to your values
because you know not every person that
you bring into your group or you're
gonna be like yep you're right for this
that's the point of finding those people
that you do Vibe with is uh you just
gotta you know stick to your morals set
your boundaries and the rest will do the
work itself
facts
cheers
so we over at Canada Queenie we're
always saying that our journey is like
an elevator and not everybody makes it
to the top so on every floor people get
on and off when you're in the elevator
right so thus far we've had people get
on and off on and off
and right now me can a cure and uh you
know a selective few that we're still
kind of binding together and making it
work I feel like we're the ones that are
just gonna make it to the top together
so I'm ready to make it to the top
mechanic here
[Music]
going up
good going up [ __ ] yeah
[Music]
I'm so sorry I did not want to sit for
10 minutes off the stream rummaging
through my fridge trying to find that uh
lemon one so I promise you I'll eat
those that one within the next couple
days but instead what I brought you guys
is uh this amazing arch enemy of mine
the baby muffins oh the muffins
see the muffins are good though
she's laughing her ass off because I
hate like one of them and I felt I I
said don't worry about it I think she
told me
150 milligrams and since there was three
in there I assumed that they were you
know 50 milligrams a piece yeah
that's right right they're 50 milligrams
a piece yeah yeah that's why she's
laughing at me
[Laughter]
so I tell her I said don't worry about
it I said I do uh over here I don't I
make some cookies and I make some
brownies but I'm not I'm an awesome cook
and I make some really really cool
cannabis infused dinners but I don't
[ __ ] around with Edibles too much as far
as like treats and snacks and stuff like
that I'll do like a few salad or infused
pasta infused barbecue sauce we may
confuse salsa
um
but it's just like keeping cannabis
cupboard and it's making regular recipes
with infused ingredients you know so
it's it's not too much different to me
but I'm not that creative where I'm
gonna go out of my way to make a nerd's
truck and [ __ ] that's incredible and
cake pops
cake pops kind of okay there's two
treats on it this is the high section of
the podcast there's two treats that piss
me off sugar cookies
what kind of hate sugar cookies and I
hate cake pops
not not the flavor candy care I cannot
wait to have it but I'll tell you why
because when I think of Cake Pops I
instantly think of uh
and
they have those [ __ ] cake pops on a
stick and they want what like five six
bucks for them
it's like one bite of cake just buy me a
piece of cake
I
never thought about it
you actually bought one
no I will not pay that much for one bite
of [ __ ] cake
if it's infused sure because that one's
gonna [ __ ] me up you know for a while
worth it yeah I mean that's where I got
the lime coconut bar idea
um that I make for what the one edible
that I have I actually got it from
Starbucks
um because I went there
before work
and I never eat I mean any desserts
obviously but I did see that on the menu
one day and I ordered it because
obviously that's an awesome idea and
then I got the ingredients and I made it
that day on my way home
work it was so awesome
it's so awesome and it's the best the
best thing on my menu now on that one so
Starbucks
wait a minute which muffins are those
which muffins do you have
uh these are the banana nut
those are so good oh my God
they're so good I you have to try the
bacon maple oh I saw that one it's like
bacon maple and then there's like what
like is that a cream cheese or like a
vanilla frosting inside oh my God
yeah
these are maple cream
ten minutes later
that quickly sets it off man the coffee
sets it off it's
been giving me the munchies
I got them my cheese I think he's just
high as [ __ ] thinking about food now
screw you both I just did a 12-hour
shift came in to do a podcast with y'all
I still not have not ate not have eight
you have not ate yet I not have eight
not have a nothing
let's teach poor grammar while we're on
here because we're high as [ __ ] so I'm
going to I'm going to bite into one of
these muffins really quick
um what other flavors did you make
Hannah here [ __ ] lime and coconut
that bad sounds I would be all over that
[ __ ]
definitely the lime coconut bar
my favorite
and a bacon maple
um you say it I taste it every time you
say it
you know they're not green at all
but you can smell the weed
I mean they want to be green oh look at
this
like when people start with like a
really like
do you do you ever do butter
even fuse much better
for me
yeah
I make butter that's how I I make
everything I have to make butter all
this all the time what are you talking
about so right so when you make butter
so when you make butter
yeah no it's not a trick you gotta think
there's people watching the stream that
have never made nettable in their life
you're talking to me but you can
completely relax
thank you
my mind
you don't [ __ ] know me muffins are
made with [ __ ] butter yeah I know
and I'm like Butter's literally on her
menu
calm down candy here we're about to get
into the section where we have to speak
Spanish
all right
wow
I'm gonna sit here don't taste any weed
at all no it tastes like damn good
banana nut bread
did you sprinkle sugar on the top
no do you like my nuts
I love your nuts in my mouth they're
amazing that's what she said
if you want oh no that that one's
getting left in that one's getting left
no shame I'm completely confident in my
sexuality yeah the work in a factory is
my day job around men for 12 hours
literally half my life
if you think I'm scared of a nut in my
mouth joke I'm not at all
loving my nuts in your mouth knowing
that they were in my hair and they're in
your mouth
very moment
okay
oh yeah I mean you could go as far as to
say there were other people involved
between them being in your hands and
going into my mouth
not just one bullet
a lot of people
I didn't even have to pay for it
now I'm trying to think about how many
people have touched
candy cures
dude your your nuts have been all around
the world at this point just dropping
and mouse making people happy
nuts
[Music]
and that's saying a lot
most of them have an off taste everyone
loves a moist nutty muffin
everyone loves a moist and nutty muffin
I mean yeah I like my nuts
who doesn't like a moist muffin
I do
I hate that word
most people do doc most people do
oh it just sounds so vulgar
sounds vulgar but not your nuts in my
mouth you're not saying my mouth is it
vulgar but moist that's comedy relief
there's nothing comedy about moistomy
I'm not laughing if you say moist and
now I'm saying it driving myself and
saying over here and then when you put
the muffin part in there it just got
worse
I don't know I guess when it comes to
okay I will change my wording I too
enjoy a non-dry muffin I love a non-dry
muffin
who doesn't
[Laughter]
this train is going off the tracks right
now I apologize
yeah this is exactly why my podcast I
enjoy my own podcast the most because
I'd give no [ __ ] let's throw it all in
there
interviews best one yet is this one I
swear to God It's the funniest and most
real
it's easy it's easy it's easy um there's
a another good tip for you uh
your number one
best quality that you could have as a
podcaster going into you said you
weren't going to do the one-on-one
interviews anymore it's extremely
important for that
um but even if you do group interviews
or you know smoke sessions and stuff
like that
make sure your your co-hosts are
comfortable okay well the more you're
over in Discord the more you'll see it
because that's like dark and filtered
over there
I get that Vibe over there that's why I
feel free to beat me over there too
good that's the point behind it so yeah
there are no [ __ ] in Discord I don't
think I I don't get that back no there
are no that's not that vibe
Vibe shut up Mel go ahead doctor no I
was about to eat the last bit of this I
really I really feel like the best thing
that you could give me is feedback about
what I've created I feel like to be in
Discord you can't be a [ __ ]
you can't be a [ __ ] because we do a lot
of everything is texting everything is a
lot of it is texting and I in Discord it
taught me how to not read a text with
emotion because I and a lot of no man I
don't even know sometimes if it's a man
or a woman because I don't know what
their handle or their Avatar is so
Discord has really taught me to not read
something with emotion to just read the
words for what they are you know because
it could be
um I don't know it could be any of them
and they're just writing while they're
driving or I don't know but I learned
how to not be such a [ __ ] in Discord
it is what it is there's no there's like
there's no crying in baseball there's no
bitch-assness in Discord
that's just me that's my thought you
look like I'm gonna take a screenshot of
that during that part of the podcast
because you when you said you can't be a
[ __ ] you literally got that like hard
look like you're like
a [ __ ] a Discord
I I agree and that's what I love about
your Discord that it's just that type of
vibe there's no everyone's taking shots
everyone's light-hearted everyone is and
I feel like I'm home there I feel like
I'm just amongst a bunch of cousins
everybody's taking shots you know that's
me yeah and there's there's a lot more
to experience about it like you were
saying not reading info or not reading
emotions into what people are writing in
there
um I try to stick to I I do so much
anymore it's hard for me to stick to one
single thing talking to one person for
too long messaging everything throughout
my day I'd rather send you a you know
voice chat or something because I'm
[ __ ] I can't type to that many people
a day it ain't gonna happen
um but I try to make the focus on it
where there is cannabis information we
can share different things talk about
things and text fine but I've really
really have been trying to focus on the
video and that's why we have like the
voice smoke room sessions and stuff
where you can turn on your camera you
can turn on your audio you can get to
know that person you can connect with
different Growers all around the world
uh Canna Care you can go the bottom of
the server
um find the US connections click on that
it'll show you every state in the US you
can find California click on that one
everybody in that thread is Growers from
California
thanks Ken
it's a it's an awesome feature and then
obviously our live shows uh you are
going to be on do or dab coming up I'm
so proud of you milk
thank you thank you for that one thank
you now I must secure the dab for said
competition
which I will because it's the end of
November do you know who my opponent is
do I I do not run the doer dabs anymore
I I host the doer dabs but I do not uh
that's Panda that gets all the writers
together shout out to hostile panda
I'm hoping he puts me up against the
amateur like myself because I'm uh I'm
afraid I'm not gonna be at a pro level
yet so yeah
I need I need an amateur Dabber like
myself I'm hoping
uh if not there's gonna be a lot of
dabbing and a lot let's do it do you
want to go against another female or do
you want to go against the male
I'll go up against anybody I ain't a
punk
Instagram
[Applause]
so be a bit actually yeah
actually ask candy cure that's what we
say and Cat when we were in Cali and we
would choke on the dab we were like
don't be a [ __ ] don't be a [ __ ] you
better [ __ ] swallow that [ __ ] you
better not throw up smoke
yo we were trying to see like who could
take the big crazy
it's like a sorority frat house this is
funny it was that's awesome
you've ever been
absolutely I mean I normally I've never
dabbed so much in my life so now when I
find myself without dabs I can feel the
difference with just flower and I'm not
happy I want to be a you see me with my
flat iron Dot I'm trying to make
homemade dabs I don't even know what the
hell I'm doing
nobody wants to be an overnight success
I actually talked to another podcaster
one time that had a reel that went super
viral and everything and she said that's
the worst thing that's ever happened to
me I said well why because then you have
one video that's getting you know a
million views
and you're getting no interaction at all
why because these people like that video
they didn't like you you know and
there's gonna be a couple that stop by
but as far as the algorithms concerned
you fell off the face of the Earth it's
like being a one-hit wonder back in the
90s
be that slow is the best place to get to
where you want to go
look I think I believe low and slow is
the best way to do
damn near anything
food grow a server grow a following you
know
try to get live rosin out of flour with
a flat iron
okay so that brings up Point number two
about the flat iron and me because my
perception was a little bit different
you said you were in the elevator
uh
I've always pictured one road it's the
beginning of your life this is the end
of your life everybody's on that same
[ __ ] road
some people walk faster than others some
people walk a little bit slower we're on
different paths but we're all on the
same [ __ ] Journey so it doesn't
matter if uh you're 80 years old and I'm
20 years old I might know something that
you don't and you probably know a lot
more than I do you know it doesn't
matter age is just a number but we all
go down these different Paths of Life at
a different rate so don't there's no
reason to compete with anybody
yeah I agree and I think some of the
best changes I've made
thus far have been from the women in my
group that are not mothers and are
probably 20 years younger than me
um
I think I've had tough conversations
with my kids because in my cannibals
Beauties I got young mothers like uh
Bella and then I have someone young like
Stoney who's not a mom and I get both
perspectives and because we love each
other like unconditionally like that
I'm open to all of their advice they're
open to all my advice and together we
grow
that's just how I think about it you
know so I don't care if you're 20 or
you're 60 I'm going to learn something
from a conversation because we are not
at that same age sweet we're not
experiencing things at the same time
we're like we are elected plants you
were explaining like taking one and
taking another and putting them into
separate environments and even if
they're the same string they're going to
grow different so and I got a whole
bunch of streams cannibals beauty is a
hybrid and so I'm taking the best out of
each plant that's in front of me and I'm
creating something amazing I'm creating
a happy Miracle or what do you call
those happy accidents or no they're not
accidents they're happy Miracles they're
happy manifests oh you can keep the
happy accidents
I'm a huge Bob Ross fan and would you
not make mistakes we only make happy
little accidents so I think
yeah I grew up in an environment where
if you weren't a mom you could never
give advice to a mom you know you would
hear something like oh if you don't got
a kid you don't you'll never understand
and that's that's a false statement you
know some of the best advice you can get
as a mom comes from someone who isn't a
mom because they they're not jaded they
haven't lost sleep they haven't
sacrificed for their they haven't gone
through that they're not jaded it's the
most innocent
like sometimes Stony will say oh why
don't you ask Marcos like this and I'm
like I didn't even think about that
because she's not dealing with those
stresses she's easy to just sit back and
give almost the most innocent point of
view so
who am I to tell someone they don't have
a right to give me advice what if that
advice is the most best life-changing I
could get you got to stay open
the same way you opened up your mind to
different strains when you go to a
dispensary and you're willing to just to
you're willing to experiment
I feel like you got to do that with
people you just got to be willing to
experiment with different people and see
where it takes you
what's pushed you what's Driven your
confidence and helped you out more than
anything else
um
I don't need anybody to approve
or validate who I am that's up to me and
once I stopped waiting for people to
like me and I started to like myself
I I realized that I had been in my own
way the whole time
so
I'm not looking now for anyone to
tell me what they want to see from me
I'm gonna give them what they got I'm
gonna give you what I got and if you say
you say if you don't you don't
I'm good
I've learned to be good I'm good I'm
good
what about you candy care
it's okay
like I just don't listen to anybody else
[ __ ] and I just listen to my own
my own
so my own God and my you know because
all the other noise
is what it is
noise
and I know what I I like I guess I need
and I and I just block everything
else out and it works
not the best advice
yeah you focus on those stressors you're
going to become stressed it's not
helping you out if there's nothing you
can do to change something it there's no
reason to waste your time stressing out
about it because you can do nothing
about it
going to not like you people are not
gonna like some of the decisions that
you make
but as long as you're cool with what you
did you need to stick to that [ __ ] don't
give a [ __ ] what anybody else thinks
because it's not about them it's about
you
exactly
you're not there to bring have them
criticize what you're doing
to change it or warp it into something
that you did not intend
always block the noise
that would be the best piece of advice I
would give someone
um
don't share every idea with everyone
some ideas just need to keep yourself
and hold favorite because not everybody
is supposed to understand your journey
and so sometimes the opinion of opinion
of others could really block the
blessings that are right in front of you
so sometimes the the ideas that you have
as as
enthusiastic as you are you have to be
able to bring that in for a minute and
take time to focus on it before you
share it with the world not everybody
deserves a seat at your table they
really have to earn it you know don't
give that away so freely
that's my biggest advice don't give away
your talent so freely and even your
respect that's a damn good piece of
advice thank you for uh saying that I
actually could use that see you're
helping me out just as much as I help
you out and that's something I love
about both of you both of you sorry I'm
going to say both to you guys
it's okay I call my daughter's dude it's
okay I'm okay with it I'm okay with it
personally I'm all right with it okay so
that's something I love about both y'all
is uh you're very very strong
independent women but you are also very
inclusive like you were saying uh when I
first met both of you you guys were
doing lives that you do regularly with
all of your Cannon boss Beauties and
it's always a different you know
arrangement of y'all but you all have
you all bring something to the table
that's a little bit different but you're
all there for the same reason and that's
what attracted me to you guys's lives so
much right from the get-go is there's a
lot of passion there's a lot of [ __ ]
mainly Sisterhood I'm gonna say yes
there's some men in there but there's a
lot of Sisterhood beyond all of y'all
and even the men that you hang out with
you're very very close with
um but you guys especially with how
close you are when you start going off
on stuff like we just did with the
[ __ ] nut muffins that's when I just
go crazies because it's like you guys
did such a good job at talking about
cannabis being serious going in depth
about different things that have helped
you
but then you just go off the rails and
that's exactly how I like my podcast as
well so you guys all did an awesome job
your story is extremely moving Mel
you not already know how I feel about
you and your story
um you are one of the strongest women
that I've ever met so I
I just got Mass respect for both of you
um before we get going here
through all your years of cannabis
what's been your favorite thing you've
ever smoked
I'll let Sarah go first
um I just want to say I remember smoking
something like Skywalker OG way back
it was like well
yeah
um the OG Mist obviously but
it was definitely
definitely a head head high but like
also a body high
I know
santulli's blueberry
hands
hands down
santuli's blueberry I smoked it at her
house back it was a day before my
birthday I'll never forget it was Friday
May 13th and I sat there in her on her
sofa and I took that first pull from a
white owl
and instantaneously my head got fuzzy
my body pain relaxed and it was like
everything was okay with the world
and she sent me home with a little gift
of it
and I cried when that strain
um was gone but lo and behold she gave
me a clone and I'm growing it in my own
backyard now
that blueberry
has my heart and it's from me yes I love
a good blueberry and that's exciting
santulli just came into the Discord not
long ago too and I've seen a couple
other girls she's doing very very well
she's very dope
hers are amazing
so is there anybody you guys want to
shout out before we get going here
my little sister Stoney
she found some love and
um and and I just want to give her a
shout out
I love her
I took her to find love and I'm really
happy
um I want to shout out I don't shout out
all my Canada boss Beauties I want to
shout out my husband and my three boys
and my dogs for putting up with my crazy
self and shout out to you Doc and
canacure you're dope like we're all such
a dope Vibe and I love y'all
I truly do I love y'all
absolutely thank you both uh for taking
the time out of your days to come do
this with me this was an awesome episode
I had a lot of fun with both of you all
uh this edible should be kicking in very
very soon so I might even do an IG live
later we'll see but this will be edited
very soon and it'll be available to all
of you on YouTube probably within the
next couple weeks so look forward if you
missed any part of this live you can go
back in a couple weeks and you'll see it
fully edited with all the fun effects
and Transitions and crazy [ __ ] that we
do uh before we get going I want to give
a quick shout out to the Cannabis
Beauties obviously you can go find
canacure inspired over on IG at canacure
to underscore inspired you can find
kanekwini at canada.queeney two e's two
e's
uh both of them are very very awesome I
want to give a shout out to all my
patreon members as well uh you are the
life behind this and I could not do it
without you you all are [ __ ] awesome
and you've gone above and beyond to help
me build this into what it is now
so I got much much love for all of my
members uh can a Queenie being one of
them over there obviously pink tank KW I
I couldn't even go on forever there's so
many of you uh Roger for being with me
for so [ __ ] long all of you you know
how much I love you and I will be
catching you in the voice chat very soon
if you guys want to join the Discord and
you have not been in there yet you can
go check it over at discord.gg forward
slash Cowlitz group podcast you can also
find me on IG at Doc underscore calyx
and you can find the podcast over at
calyx underscore crew underscore podcast
let's end this right now it was an
awesome uh podcast I enjoyed hanging out
with both these very very inspiring
women uh this is Doc Alex saying we're
smarter not harder
[Music]
come on