[Music]
hello podcast listeners welcome to the
calyx and crew podcast
podcast by the cannabis community for
the cannabis community i'm very excited
because today we have a very exciting
podcast for you
joining us on this episode we have chef
sebastian carosi chef carosi has been
published multiple times in high times
weed world magazine maximum yield just
to name a few he works with a multitude
of cannabis events and specializes in
sustainable organic foods and
out-of-the-box local ingredients
before we get started with chef carosi i
want to give a quick shout out to our
patrons for their help in supporting the
show so that we can continue making this
epic content so shout out to barry turt
funtime grower tk geico jessejames3006
jaytran071
metal matt ak farmer john 13 charlie
brown
harshi83
covert dylan and twisted gardens
i've been grateful to build
relationships with these guys in our
private discord service
as well as teach them regenerative and
sustainable gardening practices whether
they're on their first or their 100th
grow
thank you all from the bottom of my
heart i really appreciate it
if you're interested in supporting the
show i urge you to check out our podcast
page on instagram at calyx underscore
crew underscore podcast there's a link
to our patreon in the bio for ten
dollars a month you can get access to
our discord server bonus content games
giveaways as well as behind the scenes
interviews with our podcast guest or you
can check us out at patreon.com
doc underscore
share the show with fellow cannabis
enthusiasts like comment subscribe i
greatly appreciate your feedback and
your support
now before we take up too much time
let's welcome our guest chef sebastian
cross what's going on doc how are you
thanks for having me good appreciate it
i'm very excited to have you on this is
a bit of a different podcast it's very
cannabis related but we're kind of
delving into what you do today and i'm
actually extremely excited for this when
did your interest in working with
cannabis begin i'm 50 years old and i
grew up in a household where both of my
parents were cannabis users
they were also both in the medical
industry my dad became a doctor my mom
left the medical industry and
became actually a nuclear physicist so
she moved into a different realm of
stressful jobs but they both continued
to use cannabis throughout my life and
then when i grew up
i
saw that
there were two people in my life that
were successful no problems
had basically whatever they wanted to
work for to get and
used cannabis
and
my dad
being in the medical industry would
always
you know he'd always had plants going on
but he always had something to make out
of it you know whether it be something
silly back in the day like brownies or
rice krispies treats you know i hate to
use candy and sugar vehicles like that
as a topic but
you know those things were vehicles for
cannabinoids back in the day when that
was your level of cooking with cannabis
so
i just kind of took that and added it to
my
profession as a culinarian and as a chef
and
just
tried to apply it without being too
scientific at the time
everybody's getting really scientific
now and everybody knows everything and
yet
everybody knows everything everybody's
the master grower you know everybody's
all this
and it's really it's kind of a
convoluted
i don't even care i can't call it an
industry because it's not an industry
because it's not nationwide
it's sparse it's in certain areas and
it's controlled in different ways and
nobody's controlling a [ __ ] carrot in
all these different ways so why are you
gonna try to control cannabis in a
different way and i know that the
benefits are highly different from a
carrot versus cannabis but i mean still
if they're going to regulate it they
really need to start coming together and
because there's people out here there
like me
who are
not looking for the highly processed
edibles in the store we're not looking
for the next strain that is named after
a candy bar or a wrapper
we're not looking for that
what i like to call real cannabis
consumers
and not just end users
so a lot of people are in this industry
without drawing a paycheck from
a company you can't be in an industry if
you're just an end user oh i smoke a lot
of weed yeah i'm in the industry i come
across that all the time and it just
it's it's like jaded me for a lot of
things and it's kind of moved me away
from a lot of things
i get these
messages all the time from j s casting
to go and be on the next you know
chopped cannabis show and all this and i
don't answer any of them because i don't
feel the i need the validity of what i'm
doing to shine through i need to maybe
talk about things a little bit more
openly
and ask people
i.e the larger conglomerates and
companies i mean people in general but
there are owners and ceos of these
companies
that are buying 65 000 pounds of sugar a
month
and only buying and only buying 20
pounds of cannabis extract to put into
their gummies and then selling them to
the mass market which is basically my
grandmother and it's just so sad
i want people and i'm sorry i'm on the
dennis miller style rant here but
no you're i really want people to
understand that
the plant is edible from the roots to
the tip
the leaves are highly nutritional the
biggest benefits that we found from
cannabinoids and cannabis yet are not
from any of the ways that any of us are
consuming it it's juicing it
and drinking the juice immediately all
the studies in israel that were done in
the 60s and now that are done in from
2005 up
are the phytonutrients and the
availability of what you can get from
just and then auger juicing and that's
another thing everybody's like oh i'm
going to go out and get a juicer and i'm
going to juice it and i'm going to be
like yeah yeah yeah
no you have to have an auger juicer like
you were juicing wheatgrass
because the centrifugal force of
the force-driven motor-driven juicers
are just killing half of the nutrients
it's just like we're doing when we're
smoking weed but i'm not really yeah i'm
not gonna stop smoking weed i'm gonna
get as many cannabinoids in my body as i
can
and i don't eat heavy doses of cannabis
a lot of people think i eat a lot of
cannabis because i cook with it i don't
if you notice a lot of my food is based
around raw cannabis and the leaf
and other
forms of cannabinoids and the recipes
and using the can't you know tonight i
made a panna cotta with cannabis pollen
a friend of mine that's a breeder gave
me a gift of cannabis pollen and it's
highly sought after i mean some of it
goes for 600 bucks for a quarter gram
you know if you're a breeder it could go
for more than that but it's loaded with
protein
and i always see all these chefs
and all these culinarians in my field
always looking for the next thing you
know they're all looking for like moose
nuts from the congo of south brazil you
know something that's like
people are just going to be like oh i
need those moose nuts that's that's it i
need those i heard of those and i need
them and the chefs are all driven that
way but yet they have an ingredient
that's readily available to them they
could be using micro greens they could
be using juicing greens salad greens
it's really weird because
i got involved in the first farm in the
country that is usda and fda licensed to
sell micro greens juicing greens and
salad greens cannabis hemp whatever you
want to call it sour tsunami is what we
were growing and i grew 50 acres and you
know i only had two chefs in the world
buy it
only two wow and i got it out there i
mean i got i gotta reach you know i
write for seven magazines i mean i'm out
there i can get it to people even if i
have to send it to you free i'm gonna
let you try it
do you think that's lack of experience
in working with those materials yeah i
think it's scarce slack and just lack of
knowledge but yet though they're all
looking for like and if i tell them i
got truffles they're like oh can i get
some can i get some
yeah everybody wants the truffles
i saw your post the other day about the
truffles and i want trouble
you live close bro and here in the next
two months you come on over this way and
i'll pick more truffles and you can sell
dude i would love that i would love to
go out and forge with you and just learn
some of your knowledge
i've got an extensive knowledge of
cannabis but i've just never
really been exposed to the world of
mycology as much and that's something
i'd definitely like to learn i'm not a
professional i'm not a mycologist i'm
not a botanist
i'm nothing like that
i've gone on everything that my family
has kind of handed down to me
and just whatever region you go to has
got its
the things like that
so let's loop back on that really quick
since you brought it up from my
understanding are both your parents
italian immigrants yes
both of my parents were first
generations born here
and your father was the one that got you
into mushroom forage yeah my grandfather
vito his father
yeah he was a truffler he is a forager
we had like 300 acres farm in rhode
island when we first came here and
we didn't have no money man you know if
you wanted to eat you either had to grow
it or forage it
and right americans don't and i'm not
talking [ __ ] about americans i'm an
american i'm just saying americans don't
have
any
well there's no seasons in a grocery
store you go into a grocery store in
january and there's plum tomatoes you go
into a
grocery store in the middle of july
there's plum tomatoes you go in february
there's plum tomatoes
cold storage
and that's the thing is is that
i'm so scared right now
monsanto has registered and copy written
over 8 500 stranger cultivars of
cannabis
really nobody's paying attention to [ __ ]
man they did it apparently they did it
they did it with vegetables they're
doing it with all the hemp right now
because they work cannabis for like the
past six years now they're doing hemp
because the hemp farming is getting so
damn big
but people just have to shake off a
little bit of the dropped on their head
syndrome and kind of like
just wake up i think wake up sourcing
things fresh
naturally and locally
is very important no to them that these
people need to focus on yeah but here to
them if the that doesn't adequate that
doesn't fit into a drive-through method
that they don't do it or there's no app
for them that's you know what i mean
i'm with you yes absolutely
i'm very glad we did this interview i
think you and i vibe together just
perfectly okay so i wanted to touch back
you said your grandparents were italian
immigrants they came over here they
taught you how to forage and work with
these mushrooms
and another thing that you said was that
you used the entire plant from the roots
to the leaves yeah
okay if you're gonna make rso or you're
gonna make something and you're a grower
you've got the roots those roots if they
are not and i'm not a grower i've never
grown weed in my life my wife is i have
cannot i murder plants for a living
that's my job so
if you're growing in a basin and it's
say hydroponic and you have roots that
touch the basin
between that root and that basin that
micro space there's a lot of bacteria
that a lot of people don't know about so
personally if any roots touch the basin
i wouldn't use them but any other roots
i would put them in your rso i would put
them in your anything i would make from
root to tip you juice them and do
whatever the hell you can not to waste
them
what's your favorite way to prepare
roots i
like to make things like if i'm making
well so i like to juice
you like did you yeah i like to juice
them because they're extremely bitter so
there's lots of parts of the plants that
i like to juice because
different areas on the plants and i've
done i've sat there and juiced like
70 runs just testing the taste on a few
different strains i had available and a
few different methods of juicing but
they're so damn bitter that you really
have to mix them with some plant matter
juice to get them down
okay i mean that's very cool pollen very
cool pollen's loaded with all sorts of
i mean you think about what pollen is
and it's the it's baby flowers floating
around from one flower to the flower so
it's already got so many nutrients and
it's loaded with protein
minerals
all sorts of vitamins and then those
things aren't necessary and we'll just
let them go you know
yeah that one doesn't scare me at all
you know i've been consuming bee pollen
for a long time so why not go with a
plant that i'm already working with
that's really weird because i'm
developing a recipe um for maximum yield
magazine right now and it's chocolate
chaga truffles with bee pollen just a
little sprinkle of b palmer i'm a junkie
for b-pawn love people i am too yes
absolutely
one of the things that i appreciate
about your work that i've really been
following and been interested is is the
fact that you work with
ingredients that are kind of out of the
norm you know
one of the ones that i saw you post
about the other day was a gun powder and
can of pickled green strawberries oh
yeah what
so a lot of people don't really know
about gunpowder the but the highest
quality
green tea in the world is actually
grated as gunpowder green tea
really yeah
um so i like taking healing things that
people don't really know about and
people that are a little bit unknown to
people and like i said it was so easy
being a chef when you have all these
normal things available to you
but
if you wanted to work in my kitchen as a
culinarian first of all you had to name
five apples and i don't mean grocery
store varietals you also had to name
what the things on the end of a fork
were and then you would start talking
about maybe you'd wash dishes and then
maybe you could peel carrots or
something like that but
you gotta if you're gonna be a
culinarian you gotta know your way up
and around everything that you're doing
so
you go to a chef and you're like cool
nice dish it looks like it was put
together by 3000 people and 20 sets of
tweezers where'd your salt and pepper
come from
and they look at you and they and i
i
uh
yeah so that story kind of sucks because
they can't even tell you where the
freaking salt and pepper came from yet
they put it together like this
noma museum of art and charts you 65 for
three little bites you're gonna stop it
somewhere on the way home and get
something to fill you up you know
i was never
i couldn't sleep at night as a chef i
worked for two sitting presidents i
worked for president zarkozia france
i didn't cook food for them
like i went behind the boathouse at
walker point in maine and smoked weed
every day while the bush family was in
there eating lobsters
and nice i didn't feed them
uh [ __ ] but i also i didn't have any
political i have no political
affiliation i don't talk politics i
don't do i had one conversation with
laura bush and it was about lobsters and
the politics behind lobsters but other
than that we've never i've never spoken
you know it was about food
so
for me
it sucks that all of this has become
instagramable because
it's all
kind of based on
elitism and like
you see people like
and i'm just gonna call it what it is
but you see
people that are registered sex offenders
and rapists like
being held in iconic status because they
smoke weed
yeah what the hell is going on
that's that chad cold you know what i
mean
it is what it is i mean
you're always gonna have that yin and
yang right yeah i can't so i can't deal
with it so i turn a lot of people down
like like i just broke a contract off
with identity cbd and
i started working with them because we
developed some products for the
norwegian olympic team we developed a
bone broth out of norway
but a lot of people don't know that the
owner of identity cbd also owns
futurolla usa and futurola he's a big
player he owns a couple other companies
too but he
he runs he's business partners with
ranch now and i was like well i can't no
i can't do anything for you now
yeah i feel like
yeah you know what i mean i mean he's a
bigger player he's a bigger star you're
gonna get more publicity from putting
pictures out of a registered sex
offender than you are of me
i got to kind of back up you know
yeah and you don't need to affiliate
your name with that no they thought i
was weird you know
i kind of have my own
i stay in my own little situation as
much as i can because
all the early cannabis chefs out there
are now all they're doing is peddling
products on their instagram they're not
pedaling it's either regurgitated
information that they got from somewhere
else
it's none of their own
i appreciate your organic more of you
know staying within your own realm
of this
especially the work that you've done
just locally you know for our state
you back in the day you were doing hemp
fest right you were cooking over at hemp
fest for the staff that's really weird
that you knew that
dude
you went to hemp fest for years
17 years
i ran the kitchen at seattle hemp fest
for the volunteers
cooked
meals ten thousand meals over the five
day period i've also done a few other
things for hempfest but again
i got jaded by what i saw
that was real
and i had to be
really honest a lot of my friends became
legal
and hemp fest was long time ago right so
my friends you get a legal cannabis
business and then
hempfest comes to you and says hey can
you sponsor the event it's 15 000
you know or can you buy food for the
event it's this and this and this it's a
1.8 million a year party no matter what
year you throw it it costs 1.8 million
dollars because of the land you got to
rent all the [ __ ] you got to do
and
every year
every year there was a pallet of food
that i couldn't give to the homeless i
couldn't give to the needy i couldn't
get to the hungry and they made me throw
away but yet five but yet five months
earlier they were begging me to beg my
friends for the food to feed people with
and so it got to the point where
i wasn't gonna be quiet anymore and
vivian's great nivan's great don't get
me wrong
but
it's just
it'd be so easy to get rid of too there
oh man when you have hungry so many
people would appreciate that bro you got
hungry people right on the other side of
the fence and you're having to tell them
no i'm not that [ __ ] person man i
walk no i walk right by see you later
i'm not responsible for none of this
[ __ ] hey y'all here's a bunch of
sandwiches boom beast you know what i
mean yeah
dude much respect yeah it was bad it was
really bad and i found you know i work
for in the i-502 and olcc i worked for
about 40 companies as a freelancer so
i'm in the back door of a lot of places
and
i sign disclosure agreements with
anybody but it's not my business to talk
about their businesses but
i
am really happy staying
to myself
and just letting
cannabis and psilocybin progress the way
that it's going to be with the
lecherous money-hungry vultures
getting their parts first
yeah it's like i was approached last
year in november by national geographic
and scentsy magazine
they wanted to send a team out to
forage for wild psilocybin for the first
time and i was like you know that's cool
but i've been going to this spot for 28
years now it's shown to me by a pretty
important person
yeah and i realize that things are on
the cusp and
they're coming
two-fold and everybody's like wow and
it's cool and it's hip and it's like
this but like i said i've been picking
here for 28 years so i don't want you to
be too disrespectful of the spot and and
they did it right
unfortunately when they left they called
me back and were like hey you guys might
want to go get a coveted so my wife and
i went and got kobe test and sure enough
we both had govind
but that was a hell of a
hell of a surprise from the national
geographic team
but um
it's
weird how this
so 15 to 20 years ago they looked at me
as a chef because i didn't wear a chef's
jacket and i pushed vegetables on my
menu and garden grown foods
and they were like you hippie granola
the [ __ ]
and now
you know what i mean and now
that's the stuff i like so i'm laughing
at myself and now they're like oh my
goodness the organic heirloom grown in
no-till soil
carrots cosmic grown carrots from blah
blah blah and it's funny how
i'm gonna and this is this is a funny
thing for me sitting in a cabin deep in
the woods is saying like ted kaczynski
is that social media has
put everything in everybody's fingertips
so everybody knows everything now
it makes all these
professionals a lot of
masters of nothing yeah master gardeners
they're in it three years they got two
crops down and they're a master gardener
on their profile yeah i know i know the
chefs were like that too uh
i just hope that
we have less
candy on the shelves in dispensaries and
pot shops or you know whatever you want
to call them these days
i hope that the culinarians start
learning how to
utilize cannabinoids without using sugar
as a vehicle to get them to people
and i hope that the government gets the
standardization practice going because
if they have a standardization for what
organic is then they can surely have a
standardization for what cannabinoids
are and what form they are and here's
the five forms that are acceptable you
can [ __ ] use what you can use here's
what you can sell here's what you can do
anything outside of that's the market
it's just like people that are going to
get in the carrot market and start
selling as carrot dust because it's you
know carrot dust
you know what i mean and there's some
people that'll be fooled with the as
seen on tv carrot dust
but just get a normal carrot and eat it
simple
amen so before we
head to break
i want to ask you what are some of your
favorite types of cannabis to work with
so fresh
cannabis pollen and young leaves i mean
a leaf that's like a shoot of like an
inch
um oh is there is there a certain
variety of cannabis that you like to use
so it really depends on what we're doing
i tend to stay away from ultra ultra
gassy terp style
things when it's going to be eaten raw
you don't get a huge chirp profile but
some of it does show through
and i like like popcorn buds to pick a
hole
they pickle up whole tickling yeah they
pickle up good like if they're the size
of the tip of your pinky and you do like
a warm bath pickle like pour the like
get like two or three cups of them and
then pour the warm pickle liquid over
them let them sit at counter room room
temperature for like three hours and
then put them in a jar and then put them
in the fridge oh my goodness they're so
young tender you get this little slick
of
cannabinoids and other compounds that
floats on the top it's it's pretty nice
to be able to plant it like that an
incredible idea
how does the infusion work on that does
the do the cannabinoids bind to anything
in the pickle here's the thing so you
just ask the perfect question so with me
i tend to layer my cannabinoids i want
people
to open their their cupboard they're
pantry and i i need you to have a i need
them to stop thinking of oh i need to
grow weed and i need to have this and oh
it's just so complicated to know jesus
what am i going to do and it's like no
find a way to do it find a supply
whether it's your dispensary your grower
your whatever farmer farmers are best
just like our food source we're talking
about cannabis and then start making
things for your pantry if you use
balsamic vinegar infuse it it's acid it
infuses either do it the old-fashioned
way in a jar with decarb cannabis or do
it in a magical butter machine or
something like that
olive oil grape seed oil soy sauce
sesame oil tamari pumpkin seed oil
sesame seed oil rice wine vinegar apple
cider vinegar the list goes on and on so
you go to make that and then use your
vinegar for the pickled cannabis bugs
even though it's cannabis and you're
pouring a liquid over it that's hot
you're really not going to hold decarb
times you're not going to do too much of
that
so use half
cannabis infused vinegar in the recipe
that's a great idea so we're going to
take a quick smoke break when we come
back i want to talk to you a little bit
more about different infusions that
people can be working with everybody
works with butter everybody works you
know with the commonalities with things
that we learned online that we you know
went back for generations oil
typical oil
people are start starting to break into
different things like you just said
avocado oil grapeseed oil things like
that but i still don't see like
just this general knowledge a big
palette of materials that most people
work with at home so i kind of want to
touch base
with you on different infusions that
maybe people could be playing with that
that they can benefit from i also want
to talk to you about your work with
these mushrooms and like what benefits
you're seeing from them what kind of
dishes you like making with them and
just dive deeper into what
chef sebastian crossy is all about in
his practice totally totally
all right we'll come right back when we
get done with our smoke sesh
[Applause]
man i cannot wait to get back to this
interview with chef sebastian crossy if
you guys haven't checked him out on
instagram already go check him out at
chef
underscore sebastian underscore kurosi
while we're on this quick break go run
grab your pipe grab your bomb
grab your papers roll you up one smoke
with us that's what we're doing
while we're on this break i want to give
a quick shout out
to the next light led
next light led is a pioneer and bright
white led technology their spectrum is
absolutely amazing that won the best
warranties that have ever seen the five
year all component warranty down to the
very last diode they have a model to fit
any style of growth
doesn't matter what you're doing
i have the magus i have the pros i have
the 420s and they're all amazing go
check them out at nexlight.com
now let's get back to our interview with
chef carosi
[Applause]
all right listeners we're back with chef
sebastian crossy before we went to break
we were talking about
using you know every part of the
cannabis plant including the pollen the
roots some of the different infusions
that you like to do i want to talk now
like we were saying
a lot of people know how to work with
oils and infuse oils and fuse butters
what are some other
mediums that we could be using to infuse
i know you do things like sugar and
stuff how do you i try to stay away from
the sugar i try to let people have other
vehicles because if you are going to
make the sugar you actually have to make
a high alcohol tincture and then dump
that into the sugar evaporate the
alcohol out the cannabinoids are left in
the sugar so on and so forth but i try
to have people make
like
vanilla infused with cannabinoids so if
they're making pancakes or a cake they
can just
put a little thing in so you always
think of these little micro doses that
you can get to build up to a macro dose
if you need to
but have them in everything in your
cupboard and pantry well you were saying
oil before because a lot of people
associate fats and cannabinoids bonding
really well
and right that's good and you get the
most optimum
extractions when you do things like that
but you can't neglect the fact that
acids
time
and other things also create infusions
so
you can infuse vinegar you because it's
acid you know most vinegars are at five
percent at ph seven percent ph for a
normal vinegar
and then i would also recommend people
and this is going to be weird because
you see it everywhere but
people are all into the mct oil the
coconut oil yeah that's the worst thing
you could have in the world for you
because it's been
treated to get the way that it is to be
coconut oil is not shelf stable and
clear and at room temperature it's
cloudy it's got solids in it you know
the other kind like the non-mct coconut
oil
okay i have not used the mct oil but i
have seen a lot of people don't okay you
yeah i was afraid about the coconut oil
because i've used that a lot but it's
always cold
i
the cloudy stuff the chunkies yeah
that's what you use but so the mct oil
is like liquid at room temperature and
clear and all that and it's easy
infusion and [ __ ] but realistically
it's medium chain triglyceride so what
they did is they took the full chains
away so you don't have full branch chain
amino acids floating around in there and
there's only a few three or four but
they've stripped it of that and then
they've taken more parts away by taking
that natural
whitish
opaque pulp that's in there that's the
real oil they've taken that away too to
make it clear liquid like you know and
realistically it's just stripped is
stripped so
if you have to use it use it but i would
say
use olive oil overly processed yeah use
olive oil
if we if you live anywhere here where we
live i know and we're talking we live in
the pacific northwest we have california
below us but we also have olive growers
in oregon that are right there they're
50 miles away from portland you can get
a bottle of olive oil from them travel
times little and i'm not bagging on
anything from italy that's where my
family comes from but
i try to buy where i can when i can
locally because to me
it works in two different ways i
the farmer down the street is actually
my neighbor and if he can't afford to
put shoes on his daughter's feet
or a baseball glove on his son's hands
because the local folks don't buy his
farm product well that's not a community
to me so socioeconomically
says to me
let me buy from him when i can
all the time when i can
and because i see his daughter regularly
i don't see the olive grower in italy
and france's daughter i don't even know
her damn name
so if somebody's going broccoli it's the
same with wheat if somebody's growing
something that you use as a commodity in
your life
that's close
try it out you know if you if your
family eats apples find an orchard
go pick apples
don't just try to buy the five dollar
bag at the grocery store it might cost
you thirty dollars
at the orchard to pick the apples but
guess what look at your kid in the face
when you're doing it and be like oh damn
that's priceless you know
and those things are taken out of a lot
of things when we get back to where
we're talking about earlier the
commercialization of cannabis and all
that it's like
like the homegrowers got forgotten the
old school breeders forgot forgotten
because it's so commercialized now and i
hope
to start the conversation off when we
first got back from break it was to fill
the cannabis pantry up and what ways we
can do that i don't want to see a bunch
of commercial [ __ ] in the pantry from a
bunch of conglomerate style big
companies
you know when these people can do it
themselves
and it might not be easy to always bake
your own cake sometimes it's a little
easier to go and get one from the store
but
try
and it might be that time where you're
going to go down the street to the hemp
farm or the cannabis farmer and be like
yo i need a half pound i'm making
olive oil for salads um making uh
making a grape seed oil for salves and
i'm making this for this and this and
hey do you got any calendula flowers and
what else do you grow
so
here's a funny thing
we're talking about that
you and i are gonna hit it off great you
guys we're gonna hit it up great i'm a
very
sustainable and regenerative
local nice farmer
and i'm very into growing with k f and
that's kind of one of the things that i
preach
so i'm always working with things i'm
always going out into my lawn picking
dandelions and using that for like fpj
which is nutrients for the plant
or even our local orchards my dad's uh
you know he's an agricultural farmer
so we get we get all of our apples and
everything like that from him and that
we live in and there's a place called
los hernandez it's a they make tamales
there
and it's a james beard award-winning to
molly you get asparagus tamales two
weeks out of the year well that gives
[ __ ] away too right then the location
[Laughter]
and then i'll tell you what me and carla
will drive the four hours two hours from
our house just to get those tamales when
it's asparagus season in the center of
washington
oh yeah i'm gonna have to check those
ones out that sounds like oh yeah but
yes i have eight over there
quite a few times they have excellent
[ __ ] tortillas
some of the best yeah
he just got a james beard award like two
years ago man he's got an award that i
would dream of getting
so
i thought it was really funny when i was
checking out your page the other day i'm
that guy that's going out in his lawn
picking dandelion leaves using those for
fbj and stuff like that but when you
were talking about
salt and pepper like that being the
basis like
you want to be a chef you want to cook
you want to do this but you don't even
don't even know where you're salting
your peppercorn from some of the things
that we use the most in cooking
and i saw pictures are you growing
peppercorns well we have uh we have
peppercorns but they're the reverse
peppercorns so it's a szechuan
peppercorn so you don't use the corn you
use the husk
and it's the one that makes the lips
tingle it's got a chemical in it i
forgot the name of it because you put me
on the spot damn it
i have a habit of doing that i'm sorry
but it's uh it's so it's the reverse
peppercorn and you only use the husk of
it and um so here in
we live in the southwest corner of our
state and it's kind of uh you can only
grow certain things
and
that peppercorn tree does really well
over here it's actually
a bush the size of the house so it
produces more than we can we can harvest
we actually moved some of it to a friend
of mine's winery
so that he could get him going because
he wants to do uh he wants to distill it
down because of its lip tingling
qualities
but it works the exact same way as like
a peppercorn does just with a little
absolutely
you know it's like like i said it's the
basis like
the cooks that used to cook for me they
used to
i used to come onto the line like you
know half hour before dinner check
everybody's setup check everybody's
stuff check all their consistency all
their products and they used to have to
go through a mashed potato test and they
hated it because it was something simple
it was mashed potatoes but i was like
listen if you can't make mashed potatoes
right how are you going to make my 45
steak right
and then you're going to make 30 45 of
steaks a night right i don't believe in
that because you can't make the mashed
potatoes right so why don't you make the
mashed potatoes right every night for
four years then touch the steaks
and i wasn't really harping like that
but i really wanted people to get the
point of
if you're not consistent with the things
that are on the bottom that you think
are the bottom
you're never going to be able to hold on
to the top when you get there
you know and that's like what i say
about salt and pepper
they're the basis of our food you really
don't need nothing else some water some
vegetables some salt and peppers you
know the you talked about dandelions
earlier and
i was approached by i love dandelion
yeah i was approached by a friend of
mine during the covid lockdown
and he said hey sebastian i need you to
come on a
show for me and cook
and i was like okay cool and i'll just
let you know this was a vice president
of high times john capetta
and
he said you're going to see 15 million
people in your 45 minute segment and i
was like
um um
um what'd you say john and he's like
yeah you're gonna see 15 million people
and i was like all right this is gonna
be great this is really my opportunity
so
they you know i'm sitting here with my
wife's got the computer pressure's on
and everybody everybody's got everything
all set up we got all the filming
equipment here and all that and
they cut to me and i
bring my phone for the the cut screen
and i'm in the front yard and they're
like oh we're here with chef sebastian
christie and it looks like he's in his
front yard where'd the kitchen studio go
sebastian and i was like well you told
me i could make anything i wanted
so i'm gonna make country fried
dandelion flowers with milf style ranch
and they're like
dandelions countryside dandelions with
milf and john goes
like mother i'd like to [ __ ] ranch and i
was like yeah like the one down the
street that you always know what the
[ __ ] man
so i proceeded to make country fried
dandelions for 15 million people on 420
last 420 for
during the cove lockdown on high times
virtual virtual thing it was pretty
funny
i don't know if you and i'm not trying
to brag like if you've seen the last two
recipes that i did for high times but
they don't ask me
to put what
everybody expects
high times to want as a recipe in their
magazine
they are expecting the rice krispies
treats the chocolate the this the that
and the pasta right the past recipes
that i've done for them are salads
avocado toast
you know things like that
things that really let people know that
there's another level that we can cook
with cannabinoids cannabis fresh
cannabis processed cannabis and they
know there has to be everything even the
products that i dislike you know i can
sit here and bash
this and that but
my grandmother's gonna get to an age
where she can't make her own infused
olive oil you know she can't go to the
garden she can't do this and she can't
do that and when that time comes
for my grandmother your grandmother me
you anybody else that's thinking about
their health in their life
i want there to be reputable products on
the shelf
not
products like
and i'm not trying to
bag on
you know coca-cola or soda but i don't
want the cokes and pepsis on the
cannabis shelf and i know there's gonna
be but there needs to be room
for the
medium-sized guy and the small guy
all at the same fairness across the
board so that the people can make a
choice because there is levels of buyers
that are out there you know and there's
there's there's people out there that
think
is not guilty but i mean sorry
i'm probably going to have to edit that
out just so i don't get sued
[Music]
oh man
that's all right but
i'm a firm believer that there's a
reason why we're at where we're at and
uh
i won't like i said i won't stand behind
products when there's question behind a
person behind it or anything like that
without having to name anybody and it's
just it
it makes me feel better you know as a
as a chef
i don't know if you know my story but
when i was 17 i grew up in the puget
sound
in seabeck washington and
i had a lot of growers in the area
and
my english teacher was a grower and i
found out that canvas had a value and i
really didn't know i didn't smoke
cannabis at all you know and he'd be
like here give me a little half ounce
and it stinky and [ __ ] and i was like oh
my god no my friends were like where'd
you get that and i said i can't tell you
and then finally he got to the point
where he was like hey can you deal with
these five pounds can you do with his
five pounds and i was like
yeah probably you need to be like okay
give me the money
and then it'd be like can you deal with
these 10 pounds 10 pounds and i was like
yeah cool i got a boat i started driving
across the hood canal where i lived and
going to bed i know going to brennan
and
actually
was making like two or three runs to
through de bob bay
to victoria like
twice three times a week and i didn't
know the coast guard was watching me so
i got caught
and i got caught with 32 pounds of
cannabis in a little fishing boat
and i got a seven year sentence so i
from my 17th 18th and 19th birthday i
was at walla walla in the washington
state penal system at the washington
state penitentiary wow and i moved from
walla walla to clawland bay which is
another closed custody facility up in
klaman bay and
right up on overlooking victoria island
where i got caught believe it or not
they did that on purpose and then of
course
mcneil island and monroe i was at a few
other the penitentiary so as a 17 year
old i did
five and a half years
in the washington state penitentiary and
then
i got out and went to culinary school in
portland and as i was finishing culinary
school i noticed that the paperwork to
do my internship was at
the presidential estate in walker point
maine where i had family and i was like
this is cool i'm never going to get this
but i'm gonna apply for this [ __ ] and i
was the first one they called and i was
like what
i gotta fill out top secret paperwork
and i called my mom and i said mom you
know i know i've i know i [ __ ] up when
i was a kid and i got in trouble
but they're asking me on the paperwork
if i've been convicted of a felony and i
feel like lying and she's like just
don't lie this time just really just
don't lie
you know and i was like
i need a job mom i'm broke you know
she's like just don't lie don't lie just
put it on there and see what happens
you've had plenty of times where they've
told you no go because you put it on
there and
so i put it on there and they're like
okay can you come for an interview with
secret service on tuesday and i was like
what
i said i was in prison for five years
and they're like can you come for an
interview on tuesday and i was like yeah
and they said the company that you work
for cape porpo's kitchens will they
vouch for you and i said
i'm in president zarkozy at francis
house three days a week on a private
contract i think i'll be okay with the
bush family and i have nothing political
you know and then then they
pull my jacket from prison make sure you
know everything was good everything was
good and then so i ended up doing three
days a week at the bush residence in
walker point and then right across the
sound from him or peninsula or isthmus
or whatever it's called is president
zarkozy of france the former president
of france
property and i would do three days a
week there so it was kind of cool
because i went from prison
to two presidents one of a foreign
country in one of our country
and i would sit in the back of their
houses and smoke weed every day that i
worked there and it felt really good
but i never thought that we were going
to move mainstream in my lifetime like
we are right now
that's pretty incredible wow man and now
you're doing stuff locally to us too you
while we were on break
you were talking about the papawi yep is
that how you so believe it or not the
word papawi is a native term
and it's
the only people
that have
a word for it is the native folks and it
is uh it means the force of which
mushrooms
are pushing themselves out of the ground
overnight that's what the word papawi
means
it's really weird because they're the
only people that have a word for it we
don't even have a word for it i tried to
dig up you know my my ancestors are
northern italian from abruzzo and i
tried to dig up there's a lot of what we
would consider witches and people really
associated with the land from where i
come from in italy
they don't even have a word for it so
the natives and specifically the natives
here in the pacific northwest
had a word for
the force
of which a mushroom pushes itself out of
the ground overnight with
so the papali definitely for me means
something and this event is held
going to be held in november 12th
13th and 14th on the long beach
peninsula of washington and for those
that know psilocybin mushrooms that's
actually the psilocybin mushroom capital
of the world in november
you can forage for
psilocybin as a resident which is a
wooden
most psilocybin dense mushroom on the
planet believe it or not um i think it
was uh
discovered i know people discovered it
prior but i think i know paul stamets
from fungi perfect i here in olympia
washington are local hero mycologists
shout yeah i've actually
hung out with the sun azur several times
so he was the one that coined the
psilocybin as a resin and named it the
azi so our 27-mile stretch of beach in
the long beach peninsula of washington
is actually
as the capital of the world especially
in around november
you will see people from all over the
world converging on it i've lived there
i operated several hotels and
restaurants there
one being james beard's old favorite
restaurant and hotel and i
every year go and pick between six eight
ten pounds of
as a residence and dry them and use them
in
various different things just like
cannabis
i like
i microdose daily that going to prison
at 17 you know it's kind of good these
stories ran together but going to prison
at 17
crushed me it gave me ptsd like you
wouldn't believe it changed all sorts of
things about a child's life and
perspective so
i live with virginia tsd today and
society really helps me get through that
and i micro dose daily
and i really
like
the conversation that's going to have to
arise soon i know we're talking about
the howie but this the conversation
that's going to have to arise soon is
like the conversation that's that arose
a couple of years ago you know sun grown
or light you know light depth you know
all this between the cannabis world and
indoor outdoor and that's lab cultured
psilocybin
or wild psilocybin
and
i treat myself with both
but part of the psilocybin therapy that
i help push 109 and i-34 with in oregon
for the decriminalization of psilocybin
is
part of the therapy is getting out there
and finding the mushroom
you know if you spend three hours out
there in the dune grass just nature yes
that's part of the therapy that a lot of
people that have ptsd and depression are
missing and it's like you look at the
list that they give you you want to
crawl out of your depression the first
thing you do go for a walk and it's like
hey [ __ ] meditation yeah so go for a
walk and hunt for some mushrooms
and then the other thing is is that when
you're out there in the dune grass and
you're able to find
a freshie
a mushroom that's fresh in psilocybin i
don't mean one that's been dried in
dehydrator dried in the sun from a
laboratory but a fresh psilocybin dense
mushroom and put it in your damn mouth
and eat it
don't make tea don't make anything you
know a lot of people are like oh i'm
going to go to brazil and i'm going to
do this ayahuasca and i'm going to drink
iboga and i'm going to do all this
and it's hey
there's nothing wrong with that and i
have nothing wrong with that but
i believe that from where my ancestors
came from in italy we didn't have any of
those things we had psilocybin mushrooms
so i believe therapy should go back to
where your ancestors originated from if
you've got some latin in you then
explore those things but if you don't
don't explore those things because
they're not
made for you chemically
so the psilocybin for me that's a very
interesting i think people are going to
have to start paying attention to these
things you know what i'm saying but just
like like what i was trying to get at is
like i well most americans are a big
melting pot though and
you know they're just a mixture of
everything so delve down deep oh both of
my grandparents are from south america
okay i need to be doing ayahuasca or but
my grandparents are islanders or they're
this or they're that you know nobody
needs to be licking a [ __ ] frog
because that [ __ ] is there was nobody
that was licking frogs except for people
in arizona when they told us what we
were getting
so i have a question for you really
quick
sorry to cut you off there but it it
goes hand in hand with this so one of
the things that i've always talked about
my theory on this
as far as what foods are good for you
what type of cannabis is good for you i
feel that most people have that sensory
memory
where they're attracted to a certain
like terpene a certain flavonoid where
their body says hey you need some more
of this or that's why you're craving
something like this
and i'm glad that people can now tailor
their medicine before when we were
living on the black market it was like
a strain name was just something we used
to sell what we were getting from the
dude we were getting it from oh yeah
this is o.g kush this is vanilla [ __ ]
thunder [ __ ] and you know and it's like
it was just like a sellable of a
sellable point for bag appeal but now it
actually matters
now
with the medical industry prior to the
wreck industry for eight ten years in
oregon people can actually say you know
you were saying something about blue
dream and it's like you know
like that dj short blueberry that came
out of
eugene oregon has led its way into all
the blue strains and that's because
those med growers you know and i'm not a
grower but i do follow genetics
especially old genetics especially land
race genetics because
i have to tailor my yes we are going to
be best friends
i have to tailor my medicine too because
it's like i just don't smoke weed you
know
carla we got live we've smoked live
resin now for the past
probably four years solid just live
resin i haven't smoked flour
for 18 to 20 years
after prior to that for the past 20
years it's been bho you know for 15
years it was some raspy ass bhl from up
here in the pacific northwest but it was
all we had and it was way better for me
to smoke bho 20 years ago off a swing
plate than it was to try to smoke flour
because i had to smoke two ounces of
[ __ ] day to get where my head needed
to be you know what i mean
and i knew that back in the day
but the silos have
micro dosing kind of took away from that
or
like how much cannabis you need to
consume so carla and i smoke about a
gram and a half between the two of us of
live resin a day
she tends to go for the more gassy type
of
gassy wet style live resins i like like
right now i'm smoking lemon sour diesel
because everybody in vancouver grew that
for like
eight years in downtown vancouver here
so i was used to it it's that particular
the lemon sour diesel really nice for me
i enjoy it she's smoking agent orange i
believe
yeah so i like california orange i like
all those other strains carla grew for a
long time you know so she's well
well-versed better in the
genetics and the things around here i
just know what the black market had for
over the past 25 30 years here in the
pacific northwest and then of course
throughout the country but yet the
combination of
good
live resin
and
psilocybin therapy
and trying to eat right trying to do all
the other things right well
that those are the best things you can
do and nobody no matter if you're
getting a paycheck from warner brothers
studios and have multi-millions in the
bank in the biggest house
those people feel bad too
those people have ailments there's no
separation between there's no
they're not better than us because their
house is bigger their [ __ ] bills are
bigger
everybody is the same everybody is
abusive yeah so
and we all have our different paths in
life and some people just go there a
little bit quicker yep totally or and
some people have different expectations
so
my expectations out of cannabis is
and even psilocybin but moreover
cannabis because
we're not legal in all states right now
we're still got ways to go and
that the
we need standardization everywhere so
that people so so
everybody's grandmother in a different
state isn't having to worry about a
different rule and not worrying about
the other thing is is that
in my states two states oregon and
washington
and in california i lived in california
growing up too and they pushed it even
quicker medical in california is that
we legalized and recreationalized in
these states under the auspice of
medicinal values for cannabis
but yet
all they are selling us is sugar
you go into the dispensaries in the pot
shops man and it's bad and we have to
have conversations like this
so that at least two people go oh wow
wow there is a lot of candy wow they
just added popcorn oh wow and chocolates
and oh wow and this and that and it's
like wow how about just weed
before we get going i wanted to touch on
a couple more points with you this
pacific northwest
yeah it's i it's sorry we got lost on
that for a second you know oh you're
good one of the biggest things for us
holding this event is that your
we like to call them campers people that
uh attend our events campers can can
actually walk outside of their room in
their hotel in november right on the
beach in the dune grass and forage for
wild psilocybin we're going to have the
release of
the fantastic fun guy community cookbook
i contributed five recipes to the cook
community cookbook it's the cookbook
that follows the movie that of louis
schwartzberg eugenia bone and
paul stamets did
so it's kind of a huge deal for me and
i'll be creating uh for the
we'll have four a's so people will be
able to go and forge for kingbo elites
aziz saffron milk caps
violet quartz some other mushrooms the
porcinis or the king elites are highly
prized by a lot of the culinarians
but
for those that want to find a source of
psilocybin therapy right there
as close as possible it's a huge
educational event to be able to
recognize wild psilocybin or any
mushroom in the wild
is good it's like you know the growers
that walk up to a plant and they're like
wow this is sativa dominant han i'm like
what huh huh you know it's like
the mushroom world is still like that to
me i only know like 17 20 mushrooms
from this area and i stick with them
because they've kept me alive this long
but the events really to throw a party
for the release of the cookbook because
that's a huge deal
and
bring
foragers and like-minded people together
you know we just hosted the autoflower
cup in august and that was you know a
lot of people
with camp burger a lot of people don't
know what rude rouse is but yet
you can talk to
12 of the 30
tier 1 growers in washington and they're
like oh yeah we're testing some autos
out man we got four acres going and it's
like oh you mean you're testing your
abilities to make more money out is what
you're doing because you're you're able
to run three crops now and blah blah
blah so
we hosted the autoflower cup the second
annual autoflower cup in august at an
oyster farm
and we like to do these immersion
educational style events where we bring
people not from say like this event we
did we brought not only autoflower
growers but we bought mushroom
enthusiasts we bought chefs it was on an
oyster farm
we had
native prayer in the morning each
morning
lots of speakers
this is kind of going to be mirrored
after that but more driven towards the
azeressence and the long beach peninsula
and wild edibles there
nice
what kind of uh
mushrooms do you like to use that you
can find out in these areas me my
favorite
my favorite is started last a week and
it is the pacific golden chanterelle the
white chanterelle and the cascade
chanterelle
and we actually have a rainbow
chanterelle here but i don't go after
those i only get like two or three but
like carla and i picked uh probably
about 25 30 pounds just the other day
and this weekend we're gonna go to
the lowest lewis river falls in gifford
pinchot and look for some mushrooms down
there but it's chanterelle season it's
my favorite as a chef everybody goes
for a lot of the more exotic more
expensive harder to find mushrooms but a
chanterelle is
one of the most exquisite in taste one
of the most versatile to use it doesn't
have any bugs naturally it's got it's
immune to any bug so you don't have to
worry about any of that [ __ ] you know
it's got these beautiful apricot tones
to it it's easily pickled easily cooked
and easily eaten for anybody that's like
ew i don't like mushrooms
so what would you equivalate the flavor
the chanterelle of a chanterelle is like
it's its own it's like
i couldn't pinpoint
if you ask me what a porcini or a
kimboli tasted like i would like it like
the woods like the
good part a good point yeah
like the earth that's growing in like
you can pull out
like if your palettes really train you
can pull out some like apricot
undertones some nutty nutty nutty
undertones to it um but nothing in
particular it's really
where and how that chanterelle was grown
um this past weekend we picked uh white
chanterelles and i'll tell you what they
even they're like
they're going they're going crazy this
year because of the weather the weather
each year we get a new like flush of
what's going to come in a heavy thing
like like two years ago we drove over
where you over by where you live because
you had a lot of wildfires and the
morels the burn morels were prevalent
over there
i was gonna say that's pretty cool that
you're into the chanterelles because
everybody around here is about the morel
yeah no see it's actually my
it's not my least favorite but it's my
my least favorite is a big
big king bolete or porcini because it's
going to be buggy and i got to dry it
you like some of those you just want to
slice and eat but i like chanterelles
that are no bigger than my thumb um not
big and floppy eared
and i love morels don't get me wrong i
don't like burn morels a lot i like true
morels more i like blondes better
i love lobster mushrooms although i
don't we don't eat a lot of them but i
love lobster mushrooms
cauliflower mushrooms
well lion's mane we usually don't find
lion's mane here we find bear's tooth
you get oyster mushrooms and cordyceps
oh no no no cordies but we get lots of
oysters like you can just
so here's the thing carla gets mad
because like i'm like played out on
mushrooms like i've like seven years of
picking oyster mushrooms so i'm like i'm
not going to pick damn oyster mushrooms
i'm waiting for santa chelsea so i'm
gonna be lazy you know what i mean she's
like no no no we need it every season
but yeah i i thoroughly love going out
anytime you want to head out this way
you're more than welcome
yeah i'm stoked i
love that i think you and i we vibe
together pretty damn well and it sounds
like we we have a lot of the same
similarities we definitely need to do
another podcast together but before we
get going from this one i wanted to talk
to you
maybe you could shout out like a quick
recipe for our listeners that they can
try at home
i know one that i was interested in
was
that you put i i'm not a big drinker i'm
really not i appreciate a nice scotch
every once in a while on a special
occasion
and i like micheladas oh yeah and
you posted about a marijuana michelle oh
yeah
tell me about this so you can do it in
two ways
actually one of my favorites like i said
build the cannabis pantry you know if
you like absent make some absinthe
infused and if you don't want to make it
in the machine do it the old way and
just de-carb some bud put your favorite
rum whiskey
liquor into a mason jar with the decarb
bud and let it sit there it's alcohol
it's got acid in it it's got alcohol in
it it's gonna it's got extraction uh
opportunities available you know
everybody i know and i'm going to veer
off for a little bit
what about with the beer though because
that's only what three and a half to i
think the max that we have in washington
is like so with the with that you would
really you want to add it to your other
ingredients you want to add to your salt
you want to add it to your you know
whatever you can get it in
in that situation
we in particular
have it in our hot sauce
so that's the way that i we made that
okay what i'm saying
so you're you're making your hot sauce
with the vinegar exactly and actually
the hot sauce that i made was not only
made with cannabis vinegar it's two-tone
so it was the peppers were fermented
then decarb weed the peppers and liquid
was added to the magical butter machine
which is i put it on no heat at that
point in time and just did the puree
then i put it on low heat which is about
60 and did an hour
then let that cook then i just strained
it out no particles of bud or no color
left because i used wajio peppers
they're all dark so you can't even see
if there was flakes of butter in it but
then now it's double tone
it's got
the d carp
are you trying to bring that flavor
through too a lot of
people don't like it a lot of people are
they're really scared of it and a lot of
people will get like a little toothpick
of rso on their tongue and freak out and
be like oh my god and it's still on my
tooth and oh my god
i love it
rso can be bad you can have bad rso
but there's some really clearly but some
people like their like you know it's
like some people are like oh i want to
smoke cannabis but i don't want to smoke
it and all right oh i want to eat
cannabis but i don't want to eat it and
it's like just make up your damn mind
and get over your fear hurdle and just
say
nobody's died yet
and you're not the room's going to spin
you're going to want to go to sleep
that's the worst thing you know
so
yeah so with the beer
i would def
make some hot sauce
and then made your red beer out of that
and you can uh if you want to make the
sugars and
the salts out of alcohol-based tinctures
by any means you can and just add layers
what do you find yourself typically
substituting sugar with
i know you shouted out vanilla agave
nectar
but i'll tell you what so okay i'm a
type 1 diabetic i just became a type 1
diabetic i was a type 2 diabetic like a
year ago and just became a type 1
diabetic and
are you going to talk about the sun
syrups right now yeah i know i got a jar
out there right now ah damn sunscreens
and agave nectars and all that that
those are really the ways that you
can and if some people are like me and
they can't get away from like a little
bit of sugar and actually i need to have
it around to direct my sugar believe it
or not
because if you're up you're up if you're
down you're down you need sugar one way
you know one for one and one for the
other
but
i would
if people can get move away from the
hidden sugars they don't necessarily
need to take the sugar jar off of their
counter
but if they can get rid of the if they
can just be more conscious about the
things like like a hamburger just isn't
a hamburger the bun has got like 30
grams of sugar in it
but if you go to a non-sugar bun like
say an egg bun like a hawaiian roll or a
potato bun or something they've even got
less sugar in them because they're made
with another ingredient like a potato
oh yeah and potato bread is like the
best totally
i just recommend people think think
about what they want to do think about
how they want to do it and think about
what level of convenience they want to
work with when it comes to cannabinoids
and having that pantry available and
buying products
yeah absolutely
and on that note i think we will end the
podcast i want to thank you man
we definitely have to do another episode
anytime you like
that i think i could talk to you
you know for hours about this
you work with so many amazing things if
you guys have not
familiar
familiarized yourself with chef
sebastian go check him out on what's uh
what's your instagram is chef underscore
sebastian underscore kurosi and we have
camp rudor alice as another uh page but
usually if you go onto my page the chef
underscores sebastian underscore kurosi
you can
find out all about the events and all
about the things we like to do we do
random pop-ups here and there we do
all sorts of stuff and we travel a lot
for education so we're all around the
country pretty much throughout the year
very nice
awesome man thank you for coming on
thank you for sharing a couple recipes
with us your beliefs in uh sustainable
sustainable cooking lowering sugar
intakes being organic regenerative and
locally sourced we really really
appreciate it i'll tell you what doc
it's really easy when somebody can jive
with you in the conversation it's not
just a one-sided conversation i gotta
tell you i appreciate that
absolutely anytime man thank you
hey everyone grow green daddy here thank
you all for listening to this episode of
the calyx and crew podcast what an
awesome episode that was we thank chef
sebastian carrosi for taking the time
with doc to share some of his knowledge
advice and stories with us today check
him out on instagram at chef underscore
sebastian underscore
kairozi hey before you go have you heard
about the calyx crew discord yet
if you're picking up what doc's putting
down or maybe your plants are a bit how
you going and you need some advice come
check out the calyx crew discord
we have channels set up for all types of
cannabis related content along with our
members sharing stories advice humor and
most of all encouragement for one
another to grow
it's free to come check out
meet the crew catch a vibe and chat with
doc
if you do enjoy your time with us and
you want to join up as a member you'll
receive access to all content channels
do or dab competitions game day
giveaways and more we've given away some
amazing prizes recently such as seed
from romulan genetics and swami organic
seed you'll also receive access to the
patreon for more exclusive content
including doc specialty korean natural
farming
membership is only 10 bucks a month head
over to doc's instagram at doc
underscore calyx where you'll find links
to the discord patreon and information
on how to join us in the calyx crew
we'll look forward to seeing you all
soon
[Music]
you