Instagram
[Music]
what's up what's up everybody good
evening and welcome to another exciting
episode of the calyx crew podcast we are
joined by our good friend today the
Clone coach what's up buddy how you
doing how's it going man how's it going
very good very good uh you're going to
be smoking with us today we're going to
be talking about keeping Healthy Mothers
keeping healthy clones I know you were
interested in some of what I was doing
as well I think plenty of people that
are joining us over here in chat
um have you know had problems with their
clones and are looking for tips and
advice on how to keep healthy clones and
get successful wraith throughout their
cloning and I think the big thing about
that is you need to start a good if
you're going to have a good house you
need need to build it on a good
foundation right which would include
keeping a healthy mother you're very
experienced in this if you guys aren't
familiar with the Clone coach you can go
catch him over at clonecoach.com he
actually does Consulting over there
um I know that you're doing 50 clones
per tray what what's your average tray
amount where are you ranging between
these different consultations you do
so it's
it's for clonecoach.com there's a
coaching program so I try to do this as
remote as possible so I could help as
many Gardens as possible right so
there's different coaching programs for
clones and mother plants and then if you
really want to get in depth and you're
doing commercial scale stuff there's an
on-site option as well but there's two
guides come with a PDF a video uh
training video and a one-on-one coaching
call with me like this so that really
covers should cover 100 of everything
you need to solve all the Clone problems
you're having and get you the best
clones ever same thing with the amount
of plan so it's a little package PDF
document
um a training video and a one-on-one
coaching call
awesome awesome man
um so like we were saying you know all
those cuts to get a successful rate most
of my Growers are home Growers so it's a
little bit smaller scale but you know if
you're keeping hundreds of literally
hundreds of cuts just between a couple
trays
um in a commercial setting it should be
more than easily possible to get four or
five good cuts off a mother in a home
growth situation uh but a big part of
that is having a healthy mother and I
think more often than not home Growers
skip that fact they don't have their
mother in perfect health before they
take those cuts and that's kind of like
a a setup for not for having bad success
right 100 I mean it
I started as a home grower right I
started with the small with the small
bedroom and before that was a closet
with some plants in it you know for
mother plants specifically you could
have a small closet have one mother
plant and one tray of clones that you
could root right next to it keeping
things very simple and get get success
right and that one mother plant if it's
in a little two by four little closet
area you should be able to get oh
probably a couple dozen clones off of
that on a really consistent basis and I
say clones where they're just all tops
and um grow uniform in the growth right
so uniform in the tray uniform and veg
uniform and flower so on and so forth
but a little two by four closet man you
could you know probably do 50 clones a
month off that space keeping it very
small but as long as you keep it simple
keep things uh as steady as you can
wherever you could maintain your
parameters as far as humidity and and
temperature this is I'd rather have
consistency and play with that than have
irregularities and unpredictability in
your room environment so keep it simple
keep it steady and you know you'll get
plenty of vegetative growth clone them
root them and you know share them with
friends [ __ ] yeah man I want to back it
up a little bit I want these guys to get
a little bit more familiar with you how
did you get into cannabis and how did
you go from that first experience with
cannabis to becoming a clone coach
oh it's been a journey
um I mean we're talking I'll be third I
just turned 34 so that is 16 years
without counting my minor years as a
journey right because you know as a
minor I I was consuming cannabis and
became an advocate for it I was I was
that guy in the family right you know
that that was me you know late teens
going into you know 18 I got my medical
card here in California and I've been a
patient ever since right I'm an advocate
I'm a patient through and through and um
earlier on you know I didn't have the
ability to like there was no commercial
facilities that I was able to like work
at
but you know I had the desire to to
cultivate you know did the collective
thing cultivated that way and stuff here
and there but really grew that into when
2016 hit like 2015 hit I left my
corporate job because I just couldn't
ignore the desire to to cultivate and
and you know give my all to this plant
really and uh you know I made that a
switch you know I turned a spare bedroom
into a little nursery and I was well
back up one quick step I was trying to
you know Garden you know make a garden
you know Causeway a little room
but when it came time to get plants to
fill the room get clothes to fill the
Romans where I got stuck I couldn't find
a Dependable consistent source of good
clone so I could plant a crop that was
my first struggle so when I did my first
room I was able to finally Source
genetics and clones and instead of
flipping them to flower I said look I'm
just gonna fill that need because I had
that need and I you know took my first
tray of clones and turned a spare
bedroom and threw up a few lights and
and just was Off to the Races applying
um the medical dispensaries and medical
collectives out here in the area and
then 2018 hit
recreational came to California and I
started working at a recreational
facility huge licensed commercial grows
started popping up here in my backyard
so it's like I dove head into there
and I've done brokering with sales for
clones for different nurseries and stuff
but it's always been nurseries that's
clones nurseries mother plants that's
where I've maintained the focus
throughout the whole cultivation career
that I've had you know up until now and
uh just to quickly sum it up till now
you know I've always had a good desire
to help people and you know I was
turning around nurseries that I was you
know managing I'll take them from point
A to point B and point B was a lot
better than point a and you know turning
these nurseries around and I wanted to
help more nurseries than the one I was
just working at so
I started helping friends that were
remote you know I would send in some
info I'd hop on the phone I'd send them
emails I would you know do everything
kind of just just scattered around until
I finally kind of packaged it up and
said you know let's let's see if this
really helps people with this package
that created and it's it's been working
people all over the world are getting
results with this package with the
coaching call you know and now we're
really changing the standard of what we
accept as like viable clones like no
more little sick purple yellow little
baby clones that you need to spend
another two weeks to tenderly bring them
back to health
exactly so that's
that's a quick the quick journey of the
last you know 16 years you know playing
with this plant
that's awesome man yeah I'm glad you
brought up that point like I was saying
you know you have to have that healthy
Foundation right yep that's a big
problem that a lot of people have with
their clones is that wilting that
purpling the yellowing
um and more often than not I find that
that's due to either just watering the
[ __ ] out of them thinking that they need
water [ __ ] constantly to the point
where they don't get air
or uh just too high a humidity levels in
general without that air exchange
usually the coupling of those two is
where I see that
um what's been your experience with the
the yellowing the rotting tips
yeah I mean if that's happening in your
clones it's if you're getting rotting
fuzziness damping off mold things like
that you have excess humidity and it's a
very common problem it's like it's like
over Watering your your vegetative
plants or your flowering plants you
could have too much humidity in your
clone domes and your clones for too long
and that leads to problems so a huge tip
that I could give to people is just let
the plants breathe let them breathe
don't trap that humidity that stagnant
stale humid air
on these clones for days and days and
days on end if you just eliminated that
out of your process and you let these
clones breathe a bit more
you'll have you'll eliminate you know
good chunk of those problems we just
mentioned so
a very common thing is just like too
much humidity for too long that and if
you combine that with a little bit
cooler temperatures like in the low 70s
recipe for for disaster recipe for
issues recipe for extending your rooting
time recipe for all the above really
yeah I think you and I kind of came
around the same ERA with the HPS and CMH
kind of being like the new thing wow
these are pretty cool you know because
now there's LEDs LEDs are dominating the
[ __ ] Market well when it came to the
LED switch
um they're so efficient we're often
running lower power which results in
lower temperatures
um so that's something that should have
been brought up so I'm glad you
mentioned that
um our patreon member crawdaddy wants to
know what is the optimal Temp and
humidity I run mine like low 80s high
70s and I don't think I ever surpassed
like 70 on my RH what is those are your
parameters yeah if those are your
parameters that's that's spot on it's
real good advice if you could maintain a
steady environment shoot for 80 degrees
if you have to deal with a little bit of
a swing you know try to see what side of
the Swing is better for you right a
little bit warmer rather than a little
bit cooler right with humidity if you're
capped at 70 like that's a Max that your
room hits that's that's great you know
shoot for 65 60 you know you don't want
to be 40s and 50s because then it's
you're too dry and you're really going
to readjust your whole Dome protocol to
compensate for that lack of humidity
there
um but even if you're a little bit more
humid and you stay at 70. as long as
your room could breathe if you treat
your room like a dome like one big dome
and let that air exchange happen without
days and days and days of trapping that
humid stagnant air humidifiers pumping
and if you just let it breathe you'll be
able to you know deal with a little bit
more consistent higher humidity as well
good point what is some of your favorite
methods for cloning
um I I've had Growers that are I've
personally have used the hydro cloner
I've uh cloned directly into soil before
that's actually one of my favorite ways
just because for the home Growers it's
cheap easy and if you got your you know
you got everything in line it'll happen
for you with pretty good success rates
if I've done that I've done uh those the
root right and Rapid Rooter Keys I've
used uh the rock wool I wasn't crazy
about the rock wool but I wanted to know
a little bit about what your preferred
method is what are you seeing the best
success with obviously it's a little bit
different grower situation per situation
but the man himself let's hear let's
hear your little thing there obviously
you can't give us a secret sauce but
yeah I mean my favorite versus what's
the best are two different answers I
would I would probably say right off the
bat right I mean but you know my
favorite
I like
you know any like 50 you know clones per
tray that's that's a good solid number
for me
but in the tray mediums you know root
riots were good
um I mean you could always root in a
root Riot the only thing I don't like
it's like it's a little bit inconsistent
in the holes but yeah you'll get that
thing to root no problem right
um but the the insert trays as long as
there's a little bit of a gap between
the insert tray and the solid tray and
the bottom I really prefer that because
then you could really get these huge
noodles of roots hanging out in that
inch of space where it's just enough
humidity and moisture where those roots
can grow kind of waking it up untouched
yep and that's how you get those really
big like chunky you know squared out
roots of you know inchworth down the
cube so there's some Gap in there that's
my favorite because visually when you
lift that tray it's just noodles
everywhere you know good point with the
roots hanging down the secondary tray
um
how I like to do it if I'm gonna go that
route is the little Ridges at the bottom
of them I keep that like full to the top
with my nutrient water but I don't
really let it go above those higher
ridges
um just so the moisture is there but
it's not
they're not sitting in a pool of water
you know yeah and that probably gets
changed every day if not every other day
yeah every other day for human you know
life happens you know
um but yeah leaving a little bit of
nutrient solution at the bottom of the
tray I love doing that too
um I only have to you know usually do it
um in like the last third of the rooting
process right like at the very end of
the rooting process the last you know
three or four days of the rooting
process is where I'll potentially start
leaving nutrient solution for me
um yeah just start acclimating yeah yeah
and then if they're ready it's like
they're already switching the veg then
hell yeah I want to give them more nudes
more light do you know make them use
that that root system that I'm building
up so uh yeah man I love that trick and
that's really how you get those long
spaghetti noodles that are you know that
lift up and super long because they're
hanging out in a little bit of nutrient
solution so is there anything that we
can do to our mothers to kind of prep
them
for more successful clones
just make sure
she's healthy
that's it definitely that's number one
make sure that you know the plant is
vibrant enough that it's transparent
enough to where it's drinking the
nutrients on a consistent basis right
it's it's up taking that water it's not
become bogged down that root zone is
really healthy and active you have that
good balance of light to where it could
veg out enough and as long as she's
green and happy and praying and eager
for that next watering right like it's a
vibrant plant that's that's what you
should do it doesn't matter what
nutrient brand you use doesn't matter
what just a healthy plant do that follow
some simple recipes some simple
additives keep it real simple you know
and just make sure that plant is
thriving and that's how you really
prepare for a good cloning session it's
just having the healthiest plant you can
and if you want like specifics I usually
allow two weeks of growth before a clone
so two weeks of uninterrupted growth and
then a clone if you're going to keep
vegging after that then you would need
to prune and time it to where like two
weeks before you're gonna clone is where
you just leave it untouched
let's go a little more detailed into the
actual clones themselves because I
believe I was looking at your stories a
little while back and it made me laugh
at the same time it made me really happy
for you when you did your experiment
with your shorties
in there
I was always taught take a healthy sized
clone the more nodes you have the more
auxins you're you have the more rooting
hormone you have
um so it's really cool to see you
getting these entire Flats of these
little tiny shorties and [ __ ] like that
and at the same time
I was watching that and retaining
something else that I had seen on your
page before that and it was that you
didn't use clonex you you weren't a fan
of clonex what root what rooting hormone
what rooting practice are you using
I I think you may have gotten that
mistake and I did do uh I do like
clonics gel uh okay I don't like the
clonic solution or you know oh okay I
don't need the clinic Solutions you know
for my soaking
yeah the mist or the solution but the
gel is what I you know do purple gel
yeah so that it is here oh and that's
what you were using in the ketchup
bottle awesome yeah by the way that's
the coolest [ __ ] hack I've ever seen
you know man those shorties and that
ketchup bottle Tech once again I was
managing a nursery right I was you know
from sales production the build out the
design the you know the the the plants
everything and uh you know the Shorties
came about from you know the healthy
plan is going to give off Roots no
matter what so the level of auxins and
stuff that you mentioned in my head as
long as that plant's healthy through and
through wherever I cut it it'll it'll
root it'll want to root it'll need to
root you know
um so those shorties came about from
like needing extra Revenue like hey how
can we you know juice things up in a
nursery he's like well we're throwing
away all of this material all these
nodes that we trim off these stems just
green waste right we're paying for that
to get picked up and you know from from
trash to cash with those shorties man it
was just and because the consistency is
there for these side nodes as well like
you'll find a little rhythm or pattern
on your canopy where like you'll have
this size shorties you'll have this size
okay maybe you don't plug these all of
them this size plug them up you know and
it was the same process and you know
those little shorties are
shoot man if they're healthy yeah
absolutely and I think that's a big part
of it I think me without knowing or
recognizing it I think that was a big
part of my lack of success with the
short clones was because I was usually
taking one's lower down on the plant
that just weren't as healthy as that
canopy they weren't getting as much
light they were really stubby you know
so kind of going in they were a little
bit subpart of my even canopy I was
known for doing like multiple tops
flattening things out so everything just
was kind of lackluster underneath and I
think that was kind of incriminating
before the get-go but that that leads
into a good question as well is uh the
location of your clones I believe that
you said you like to do tops yeah well
yes tops for the consistency and the
trays and the consistency that passes on
to the vegetative state and the
flowering room right and you know when
I've always managed my nurseries there's
always you know uh nurseries for sale
you know stock for sale so I was
providing other cultivators their stock
so I had to provide a consistent product
that was number one so that's you get
that with that uninterrupted growth at
an even you know starting with an even
flat canopy
uninterrupted growth for 14 days you'll
get all even clones from the same size
same amount of light that they got the
whole time so on and so forth
um that's where I like you know taking
Mom stock off that next like B or C
Level stuff that the canopy you're
leaving behind
um there's nodes there there's clones
there there's you know branches you
could cut and root but those are B and C
grade you know you're starting to play
with that so
you know you'll get at Max B or C grade
coming out you know
um so that's why to keep it at the top
you know the bottoms are just like if
you got to keep the genetic alive or
whatever but it's not um good practice I
guess I'm with you I'm with you on that
one yeah I didn't even ask you what are
you smoking over there
oh
um
I think this is a little melon OG
yeah what's your typical favorite kind
of flower like what kind of you into the
fruity stuff the sours the hazes
oh you know if I could still get good
Haze like some super super Haze or
something I used to get back in the day
man I would you know I'd bless that
person yeah
I like yeah dude I like
I like stuff that keeps me working you
know I'm a smoker and a worker you know
that's I kind of get in the zone and
just you know get get in my you know
just like put like like a Ryder puffing
cigarettes and drinking coffee or
something you know I'm [ __ ] puffing
joints
um so anything that keeps me like
creative you know um kind of sharp and
then the complete opposite as well you
know something that's just like behind
the eyes
you know just brings you down and you're
just like all right time to relax you
know
is those two spectrums you know I'm a
good flower on top of anything as long
as it's burning good smoking good
tasting good then that's what I'm more
concerned about then I could kind of
pick and choose from there really you
know
so with what I do I'm more knf specific
we've got Growers all around the world
that are doing synthetic that are doing
organic they're doing commercial and
home grow
um so on the home growth scale I do more
of like a no-till on K F Type style
practice so we're usually using organic
natural products and I really like using
aloe and kelp to help promote my clones
do you do anything like that
well I'm like a True Believer in both of
those things right and so the journey is
you know finding the best quality and
the best source and the best producer of
those active ingredients that so yeah
um I want to do more experiments with
Organic cloning you know
um with
with like a full organic line you know
I've I've rooted in like loose cocoa
right that's pre-charged with nutrients
so some people that have reached out to
me like hey you know they're organic
Growers and like how do you suggest I do
it right I can't just mix up you know
some liquid nutrients and put that into
you know my cubes and stuff so I've just
suggested them to try like yeah we'll
get the same kind of soil that's still
active that the plant came from it's
getting the same food that is a real
theory behind it gets the same food so
as it Roots it'll root right into the
same food so all we gotta do is initiate
rooting the aloe and the temperature and
stuff and humidity and then once it hits
that
if it was already feeding that and it
wasn't too much and it was happy then
that moist media and that excess
humidity and The Roots striking should
keep the momentum at the same pace is
that what do you what do you think about
like using the same soil that you know
it's already that's what I do typically
yeah yeah uh I use those roots I the
first time I ever attempted clothing I
did rock wool and I was I never I've
never done a synthetic I've done
synganic nutrients but I've never done
any synthetic growing is that just like
bottled organic stuff
yeah it was I think it was like an
eight-part system from Roots Organics it
was too many [ __ ] balls to be be
doing that was the old Norm it's not in
the norm anymore you know you know
Secrets out I mean fifty percent of the
secrets now you know
no more and then uh after that I'd move
to the root riots or rapid rooters kind
of those interchange I believe but I had
the same problem that you mentioned I
was really I got irritated about the
inconsistency of the holes on one you'd
have one that was a perfect size maybe
even five in a row and then you'd have
one that was barely in there and then
you try to open it up and you just rip
the cube and it's just it's not pliable
enough to where you could pierce it with
the stem right right so much resistance
and like you couldn't just Pierce a new
hole like you could even with rock wool
you could make a new one you know eighty
percent of the time with Rockwell seven
percent of the time because there are
those little hard spots you know that
you hit every now and again
so there was this point where we were
I want to say this was early 2010s we
were getting really in heavy with
hunting Thai land races and one of the
Thai land races or there's a certain
region about that Burma Myanmar border
where they have a certain type of plant
that they call a creeper and the
humidity is so high there that the lower
branches will actually touch the ground
they'll start rooting to the ground
and then they'll just keep going on you
can cut them right there disconnect them
and they're their own clone you know
just naturally like that but if you
don't that was like them you'll just
become a stronger base of the plant
exactly and I'm just like so if they can
do this in nature if they've got enough
rooting hormone because they are healthy
outdoor plants that get whatever they
need in this humid humic environment
um why can't I do the same thing so I
basically took the exact same practices
which it sounds like you and I kind of
cloned similar you know within similar
conditions and everything
um I was utilizing the same practice but
I started using my soil instead and it
started off using like Solo cups and
then I put a little hole in there you
know same same idea
um
pre-moistening all my medium before
doing it
um and then I would just take like a
Ziploc bag or something and put it over
the top and tape it on you know as a
humidity Dome after a couple days I
would cut one corner of the bag a couple
days later I cut the other corner of the
bag and just you know increase that
airflow and I was getting 100 success
and I wasn't having problems and I was
like what the hell I had a couple that
died
um and they had like that dampening off
around the end there you know Roots
rotting whatever
um so I was like well we got to open up
a little bit more airflow on the root
zone so it started off with just mixing
some more rice holes in with it
um and aerating it more it doesn't need
as much nutrition at that point but it
does need nutrition
um so I added some more rifles and I got
a little bit better better uh process
with that one and then what I ended up
my favorite thing to do is take like a
little small soil blocker same thing add
a little bit more rice hole so there's
more aeration but then I'll take a soil
blocker which is like a little have you
seen one soil blocker no yeah it's
called the soil Block it's a little tool
where you can reach into your your soil
there it's like this size of a square
tube you can get like a one by one or a
two by two square they'll do four at a
time and then you just clench it
together and it'll pack that soil
together in a square almost like a rock
wool Cube like that type of size and
then you just put a little hole in it
boom go I have seen that I have seen
that a commercial Nursery Productions
have that it's a tool have a loose bed
of soil just boom scoop it pack it boom
there's a you know 12 by 12 or whatever
comes out of whatever yeah and then soak
it the same way you know and keep The
Ridges at the bottom with a little bit
of moisture in them I do great with
those well look man when it comes to
cloning all we're doing is initiating
rooting right the plant's going to want
to root it has hormones in it that tell
it to root you you supplement those same
hormones to encourage rooting you
initiate the rooting process and once
you start rooting
you're switching right back into the
vegetative process so it's just right
back to where it was before just growing
in a veg you know that's that's it you
know a week of rooting a week of veg
plan is ready clone is ready if you just
you know take it a step back and like
how you did it you know fairly
rudimentary with the Ziploc you know but
you you were accomplishing that and you
got success right the plant's going to
want to do those not going to take those
steps naturally you know so yeah man
it's it's
I I'm glad we're on the same page there
with like just using the same medium of
the plants that the mother the mother
plants in in organic situation right
yep and uh I haven't used I did use the
clonex
in the rock wool I use them in the and
in the rapid rooters as well but when I
started moving to my soil
um I wanted I just kind of I'm a little
bit of a hippie and I wanted to get it
as organic as possible so I started uh
taking something that gas told me and
that was taking fillets off my aloe
plant and uh dipping them dipping my
clone straight into that aloe
um
yeah right same thing or doing a full
years with kelp and root drenches with
kelp and things like this I I was under
the impression that you ran
um heavy synthetic nutrients in most of
your growth
as a base nutrient I do I do run the
base mpk with just you know a simple
two-part you know synthetic nutrient but
the bigger piece of a healthy plant are
all the bio stimulants and nine times
out of ten they're organic biostimulants
like that is what makes a really healthy
plant you know for me like it's it's
always been like you know cocoa and
um you know bottled based nutrients and
then organic biostimulants and that
right environment Right light that gets
me a healthy happy plant you know
um so I mean but I'm right there with
you man it's like it's
if you could have the organic covering
your bases then bio Simmons don't change
right if you got your mpk covered the
biostimulants don't change the plant
wants all those natural healthy things
how do you feel about the use of micro
binoculations with with Hydro synthetic
growth
it's one thing that I say I won't grow
without
really wow so how do you feel about the
people that uh say that the salt-based
synthetic nutrients are killing off
these microbes
that's not what salt nutrients do
right microbes and beneficial fungi and
beneficial bacteria that are active in
your root Zone could only get killed by
a fungicide or uh you know something
like that that kills fungus and bacteria
that's what kills it whether that's a
chemical fungicide
um is usually the case right where that
will kill off your microbes but
salt-based nutrients are just providing
exactly what's in them right the
nitrogen phosphorus potassium copper
sulfur you know all the micronutrients
um as a base and that's the mpk value
but you know it's not a fungicide you
know in its chemical nature so it won't
kill off any beneficial fungi
cool very cool
um yeah that's something I've always
appreciated being able to talk about
because I'm nor I'm not one of those
no-till guys it's like oh man Organics
all the way you're the devil if you I've
got Growers all around the world that do
every kind of growing and I ask
personally out of curiosity because I
have not got to grow in that way uh I
haven't grown in your way with the with
the other way so like I'm curious too
man because this plant's an amazing
thing right like so the inputs that it
receives that we provided like dads what
drives a curiosity we're like because
that drives different results and you
know for me like a healthy plan is
undeniable like I don't have to tell you
I can just show you and you just see it
and the plant will tell you that it's
[ __ ] oh yeah you know so healthy is
is healthy healthy is undeniable
absolutely I think I had my biggest
wake-up call
um back in the days when we had to hide
our growing [ __ ] like that and it was at
a local nursery and I was still in the
soil building at that time I was doing
super soils and pre-mixing everything
and uh I was I was looking at some
amendments and the guy from the store
comes up to me goes what can I help you
with and he goes I don't remember what
it was at this time but he started
pointing out a synthetic nutrient I was
like oh no I don't I don't use anything
like that I'm really Strictly Organic
and everything he goes
well everything on this Earth comes from
something
[Laughter]
like that you guys will sell all these
salt-based nutrients are made out of
organic inputs yeah just raw real raw
organic
they might be lab created but they're
created from something that was of this
Earth
just opened my eyes where I was like wow
yeah you got a point there man you're
right you are right
those are just elements right you know
there's elements of nutrients like
that's what we're going after right
where we need the same thing we need to
say minerals like
that's that's that's funny man I I'm
gonna borrow that I'm gonna use that if
I can remember it yeah
something else that I saw that you had
suggested earlier
um really intrigued me because I've
never not done it do you you don't
scrape your clones you don't split the
stems
I don't I I don't but
I have and I've definitely done it but
for me it's always been you know helping
others and managing Crews and teams to
to execute certain steps and get certain
consistency out of the out of the
production of the nursery stock you know
so I wouldn't implement it because
everybody's scrape is a little bit
different the tissue is different on the
Clone so how many layers how deep those
layers are
um you know those those slices become
very inconsistent
and um
you don't need them to make Roots you
know clean simple cut in the right
environment you'll strike roots from the
whole inch the bottom inch of the stem
right like you you also don't you don't
need it to gain the success is it bad
will it hurt you no no it won't if you
could do it and you could you know keep
everything as consistent as you can with
your slices and cuts and scrapes then
um yeah there's really no harm in it
it's just for like scaling up and
managing people then I like to avoid it
you know at that level
what do you use to uh cut your clones
and what do you use to sterilize those
tools
I used to use razor blades single-sided
razor blades
um then chica Masa scissors were always
classic clean cut you know made a clean
cut
um that's the cut the stock off of the
mother plants and then I'd always use
either razor blade or scalpel to do the
final slice where I'm measuring the
Clone on them on a measuring mat cutting
mat cutting board so make them all the
same size make the 45 degree cut all the
same size of the stem
uh that's usually with the scalpel
um and then Yemen you know 10 bleach is
always gonna work it's always going to
work as far as disinfection
um and it's and it's usually always
handy and the cheapest option so
clean not RO water I wouldn't say mix RO
water with the Bleach you know just get
some filter tap water or Ro that's
topped off with some tap water
um and make your 10 bleach solution to
dip your tools and your blades in you
know that'll get you as much protection
you know as you could could desire our
uh patreon member twist says
any tips on taking clones after flower I
recently took five clones from a
flowering plant and I'm wondering if I
should be doing anything special
so I have not so much experience with
this first hand a lot of experience with
the second hand and I've seen a lot of
people just you know get success with it
right you know that plant at a certain
stage kind of depends on when in flower
because I've seen stuff like before
Harvest get cloned and you'll they're
obviously more sensitive to humidity so
you know that that nug and that moisture
is already made up of you know 70 80
moisture
um so just anything special watch that
moisture you know on that foliage on
those buds
um and just treat it the same treat the
roots the same you know we're shooting
strike roots and encourage rooting and
then take it right back to you know this
vegetative growth
I wouldn't say it's ideal to go to a
re-vege it's definitely
I do it quite often with my female hunts
just because it's a little bit faster
and easier for me to find that genetic
that I like and go back to it
um which brings me into something else I
wanted to ask you
which might be a little bit different
for wreck in commercial I'm not 100 sure
but how do you feel about seed mothers
versus clone mothers
I would prefer them if you have the
ability to choose the right
um plant to make mother stock from
that's from seed right A Mother's mother
stock whether it's from Cedar clone it
should be a proven genetic should be
something that's proven trustworthy you
know what to expect that's why you want
to duplicate it over and over again you
know but if you have the ability to get
seed stock and choose your mother from
that
you always get oh man there's nothing
like a seed right a real healthy seed is
going to be super vigorous you give it
all the inputs just you'll probably get
some drastic size looking fan leaves
just a plant that's just crazy thriving
right so 100 if you could do seeds and
find that right one you want to make a
mother out of
yeah it's the way to go is there any
difference between the time that you
would keep a seed mother around in the
time you take keep a clone mother around
no but I guess the seed mother would
have more of a longer life just because
of the early stage of the seedling and
then slow cooking and stuff so that
extra time that gets added
um
you know would probably be the only
difference
okay so you're not seeing any any
weakening in the genetics uh going on
from a seed mother to a clone duplicate
mother of that seed mother no
um
unproven healthy genetics you know one
or two generations or even a handful of
generations down if you keep that plant
in a healthy State you know free from
pests and disease and just gives it all
the give it all the inputs that it needs
you have a healthy plant you know I see
very few cases of that genetic drift you
know
um you know in that sense and the plants
are getting older and like oh it's old
mom stock genetic drift you know it's
like well
a plant that you know is going to live
for a very long time shouldn't get the
same recipe as a plant that's going to
live for a short amount of time you have
to you have to look at the whole picture
right so it's usually
the plant you could keep a healthy plant
going
for six months nine months like you can
you just have to do a lot of things to
make sure it's really healthy and free
from yeah disease for that period of
time you know that's awesome man yeah we
used to do that for
uh our outdoor season we started running
these big old greenhouses outside and I
was like man this is not indoor growing
anymore you know we've got to kind of
change our headspace up we need more veg
if we're gonna wind up with these
gigantic ass plants you know yeah yeah
so we would [ __ ] there was a couple
cultivars that were really really slow
growing and to get a nice proper Bush
and the other thing is going from an
indoor environment when you're growing
over the winter
um you know and getting a nice healthy
one before that spring and bringing it
out there you already got something big
that acclimates a lot faster than you
know like a little tiny clone wood that
was already used to an indoor
environment so we'd Bush these things
out for like six months indoor you know
we just get these huge ones that were
about to touch the light and then just
move them outdoor and wind up with like
14 foot plants it was so much fun but it
is a pain in the ass oh my God yeah it
is a pain in the ass and then you got
all that defoliation that trimming and
just trying to keep that shape oh but
see there was one in specific that's
coming to mind we had a femme of uh and
I don't grow very many Femmes but we did
have one that we liked and it was called
blueberry cheesecake
and it was such a finicky genetic
if you grew it outdoor in all natural
sun it's completely fine would give you
amazing yields it would grow like a tie
it'd be really really tall you grew that
same thing indoor under synthetic or
unnatural lighting and it would throw a
nanner or two every single time
yeah yeah it was like we were keeping it
over winter just to grow it outdoor
yeah
I mean genetic is is different in that
sense and like where it grows and how it
grows and the inputs that it receives
and what it likes and what it can thrive
in is really unique to each genetic you
know like they're bred in certain ways
bread from certain lineage you know like
there's there's real to that you know
these environments guys I know a lot of
you have to grow you know your veg with
your clones or
um mix it up like that but if you can
spare the time uh to make your own clone
room they definitely have their own uh
conditions that they grow in
um and to be able to control that
environment a little bit more what
light schedule do you prefer to use for
your clones because I know a lot of
these guys are using are doing the same
thing like I said growing veg and their
clones in the same room
um so they're probably running 18 6
maybe 24. what what light schedule do
you like to use
for for clones I like 24 hours man for
clones like 24 hours I like I like
consistency that I could kind of predict
you know that that stable environment in
my in my you know little micro
environment with the Clones you know
um
and if I have 18 6 going on nearby
I'm not worried about
um that little bit of light Interruption
you know because you're you're still in
a vegetative state you know the plants
are still asleep right a little bit of
you know lighting is not gonna you know
Make It Stop vegging or make it veg more
like what's gonna happen is there's a
veg more like yeah
so uh I'm not scared of a little bit of
you know over lighting you know like a
little overlap you know indirect yeah
direct no it's a different story you
know that's just lighting you know but
uh yeah with the Clones 24 hours you
know keep this thing is nice and stable
and you said you were using kelp as well
how do you like to use kelp do you use
it as a root drench or do you use it a
foliar or both both babies both oh yeah
how do you schedule your your kelp feed
to the time that you take clones
oh it's a good question so
they get kelp on day one of Clone as
well so I kind of just reverse you know
go back from there you know and and have
my weekly root drench you know planned
out of you know about a week before that
um you know kind of based on what I'm
gonna clone because it's gonna get
another treatment then right so
um
yeah that's I kind of just take it back
you know about a week before and okay
give us some Cup in The Roots cup in the
in the foliar I do like a little sooner
like the the day before or you know
within you know a day or two before
um cloning I like to do a little uh full
foliar spray with the kelp oh yeah
getting those natural plant Regulators
in there
um to get those roots shooting now
before you get them taken that's awesome
man have you cut is there any uh any
types that you've come across that
you're just like you walk into a room
they're like all right clone coach we're
doing this today and you're like [ __ ]
well you haven't worked in a license
industry and I haven't that's why I'm
asking
well look man it's there
the the license regulated industry the
companies that are popping up this
cultivation sites in my experience at
least you know I can only speak on you
know what I've experienced you know if
I'm 2018 of working at different spots
there
there's startups that are like kind of
micro corporate right they're like
corporate startups but funding from you
know all over the place because they're
just startups right and startup
operators and stuff and then the state
and all the extra regulation and just
all this stuff like it's
yeah man if you're asking if ever have I
ever walked into a room and said [ __ ]
after hearing some news yeah man it's
happened once or twice
that you've come across that are like
harder to clone than anything else
there's some harder ones
um there's just some uglier ones you
know just things that just don't veg
nice but
you know and don't give off a lot of
clones in a mother plan or anything like
that but they uh you know had popular
flower you know so
but yeah there's some stuff that this
doesn't veg very well
um what's been some of your favorite
genetics to work with
I guess I start off with the first
genetic that I worked with you know uh
which was Wonder Woman from Nirvana
seeds that I ordered in high school
hadn't stored in a drawer and had a
brother a friend of mine
um need them provided the seeds and then
when I was when I quit my job to start
cloning those are the first clones that
I ever took was from those that genetic
that they had going we had a little
bathroom of it went into the bathroom
got a couple mother plants took my first
like 30 40 clones of this Wonder Woman
strain
and started my Nursery there man like
that was full circle with those you know
seeds that I bought online you know as a
kid you know in my teens
what lights were you using back then
metal highlights metal highlights were
like the middle highlights yeah that
that I kind of just stuck with early on
in the early days
and now you prefer the CMH silly
I do I do yeah I mean the plants do so
you know I listen to them
do you have some do I hear some
resentment to the LEDs
I hate having to adjust everything to
accommodate for these LEDs
that's just me
um and still I'm still
you know not get
I don't know yeah they're still they're
still not a resentment man you know
there's I've definitely vegged some
solid mom stock and veg stock underneath
LEDs but it you're playing a different
game and you you really are adjusting
everything else and they're usually
higher inputs not lower inputs you know
for those lower light LED lower wattage
but then you know uh yeah
the efficacy they require a little bit
more
right yeah because I mean for me to get
the same result in my plant you have to
give it a bunch more right if I under
CMH I could have very healthy very solid
green solid green and from from top to
bottom solid green plants
um healthy like you know the low twos in
the EC right low low to mid twos in the
EC healthy bio stimulants and light and
stuff like that
um but with LED like I would get purple
that's where I'd get purple stems purple
striping so I have to adjust base adjust
uptake adjust you know yeah that start
adjusting
um and for veg specifically
I don't you know
the the wattage is not that big of a
difference like I don't need a lot of
wattage and veg anyways so for flour
maybe it's a different story you know
um but you know that's not my reality
I'm with you yeah but for veg man you
don't need much I mean you less than a
thousand Watts over four by you know
over 32 square foot you know full by you
know tray you know you got a thousand
Watts on that you get get a thousand
clones a month man you know no problem
good point good boy yes I switched over
to all those LEDs but uh honestly I
still prefer and I wanted to ask you
about this as well to see if it lines up
if you're in a situation where you're
doing clones on racks and you need that
low profile lighting
would you still go LED strips or would
you go with the T5 how high output or
something else
for that for that vertical racking you
know you can't go see a mage because I
tried that and you're like 16 inches you
know with an LED light you could
probably be at four inches
um
T5 I never really liked I never really
liked using t5s and never needed to
because I was using the other lights and
stuff so
I just don't like them because I've just
never never used them enough to really
like them you know
um but yeah man I'd go LED I mean I'm
I'm playing with them too I got you know
some LEDs in the closet right now like
it's oh so you're still doing home grow
as well
you know it it comes and goes
um you know whenever whenever I'm able
to but yeah you know I'm a patient first
so but I am kind of re
regrouping that room to make it more
value based for like you know trials and
research and stuff for you know the
channel for clone coach and stuff so
um you know gonna give it a little bit
more effort so it's on pause for now
you know but
um yeah man I've you know a spare
bedroom changed my life you know so
I would I would definitely look into uh
what I'm gonna do is after this I'm
going to send you an invite
um to my private online community it's
Growers from literally all around the
world Australia the UK Ireland you know
whatever you can think of we've got a
lot of Canadians over there as well
shout out to the Canadian shout out to
the Americans I'm not leaving you out
I'm just one of you so I don't think
about you
but we've got Growers all around the
world that are doing all kinds of
growing and what I would like to see is
you come in there and just chat up with
everybody because there's so many ideas
going around so many different types of
successes you can turn learn so much
knowledge and I would like to see you
know maybe in the future if it's
something that you like and something
that you get used to
um seeing a clone coach Discord where
you can grab people that want to learn
all this information about growing but
maybe don't have enough for a one-on-one
consultation and then you can start
monetizing that and I can help you with
that as well because I know there's a
million people just alone in this chat
right now that needed this information
today you know there's always going to
be new Growers coming in and out there's
going to be that next Generation over
and over again and the number one
problem that's going to keep going up is
I love this [ __ ] plant how do I keep
it around
yeah and clone coaches there to help
them so I appreciate you for taking this
time with us today man you did [ __ ]
awesome so much information passed out
there
guys go check them out if you haven't
you can find even more information that
we came across on this over on IG at uh
clone coach or clonecoach.com for more
guides and Consulting thank you again so
much man uh do you have any more
questions or any shout outs you'd like
to give before we get going here
to you shout out to you man thank you
thank you for hosting thank you for
being a great uh great host man I was
this was a lot of fun man I could have
could have kept on rapping man we gotta
we gotta have another one you know
whenever you have the time and um we
could get into it again man but uh yeah
just you know thank you for everybody
that tuned in and thank you for having
me and uh yeah if they're you know head
over to Clum coach I try to on IG I try
to You Know cover as much as I can there
and really doubling down and providing
out content that's really digestible and
really you know hits a lot of those
problems that we experience you know
making clones so thank you thank you to
everybody absolutely man
I appreciate you all for coming in here
from the patreon members that have
supported and made this [ __ ] possible
asking questions bringing it in here I
got much love for you we're gonna invite
the Clone coach over to our private
Discord community and uh hopefully he'll
be able to come in and check out one of
our games we've got do or dab coming up
here pretty soon if you want to
participate go get at hostile Panda he
is our event coordinator and he's
putting these games together you guys
can win free seeds just by [ __ ]
getting high what a great [ __ ] game
to play you know so uh do not hang out
it is a dank magician what's his IG
handle it is clone coach you can just
find a clone coach you search that on IG
you will find him the guy's got a wealth
of information check out his uh his
highlights he really go breaks down a
lot of the questions that are uh pretty
commonly asked for him so in held next
time guys we've got a lot of changes
coming here in January we're gonna
introduce a couple new tiers we're gonna
introduce one that's higher and we're
going to introduce one that's lower with
the new tier that's a little bit higher
you'll get a one-on-one Consulting with
me where you can talk to me anytime uh
during the month we'll set up a couple
different sessions where I can talk to
you one-on-one and help diagnose your
grow to get it optimal we are also gonna
do a lower tier which is going to be
more of like a support the show you know
for the people that don't have a lot of
money but want to get a little bit extra
maybe watch the shows after we're done
recording them but before we release
them or get involved with the crew a
little bit more we're going to have a
little buy me a coffee here for the
people that do want to support the show
but don't have the time to get into the
Discord and all that so look forward to
that Discord is going through a bit of a
facelift right now and that should be
done by the end of the year here so yes
thank you again clone coach for coming
in teaching us so much about cloning
your practices your history it was an
awesome episode and until next time
everybody
this dark set calyx Alex I'm [ __ ] I'm
pretty hot this is not calyx fan have a
great night
[Music]
the second real soon
come on
[Music]