foreign
[Music]
i am
drunk
[Music]
[ __ ]
[Applause]
[Music]
what is up everybody we're here with
josh and garrett from the smoking with
podcast how are you guys doing what up
we are fantastic oh yeah thank you for
uh inviting us on man yeah yeah honor to
be here
[ __ ] you anytime how's the weather over
there you guys are on the west coast but
we had a heater today and it was it was
rough
i think we had a heater for for our area
yeah it's like a spicy 72 degrees over
here
everyone's sweating breaking out the
shorts
of rain clouds
people out barbecuing man we're smelling
it getting all hungry over here so yeah
oh it's been a beautiful day man
beautiful day first night first
beautiful day in a long long long time
yesterday was like
but today this is the one we had an
interesting winter that was for sure
that last outdoor season was really
rough
really rough so i'm hoping for a better
one this year that the heat will keep up
and i can finish some flowers a little
bit later
yeah that'll be dope right like actually
get a full season
exactly
washington's really hard to get that
full season in oh bro yeah such a [ __ ]
so
you guys host another podcast called the
smoking with podcast yeah why don't you
tell us a little bit about that well i
hit this dab hell yeah dude uh well
me and garrett have been friends for a
long time and smoking buddies for a
while and i mean [ __ ] we
got really into like
the nerdy side of weed like just started
deep diving and watching videos and
you know garrett was growing there in
the beginning and you know i kind of
grew started growing shortly after him
and
we just always had these deep ass long
growing conversations and then
finally we were like you know what we
should be we should be recording this
this is this is stuff that i feel like
other people would want to listen to and
you know eventually we got down to
buying the stuff we needed and and
recorded you know
well i mean we didn't even buy the stuff
for episode number one episode number
one we actually had a buddy at my work
his name was greg
and uh that's the title of the first
episode of smoking with greg
and he's just a sound guy for our work
for my work they did a lot of in-house
commercials and stuff and so they needed
a production team and i just asked them
i was like hey dude like we're trying to
do a podcast but i don't know [ __ ] about
dick about
recording or like audio or anything and
you know i'd really love your help and
he you know so graciously let us come
over to his little apartment and
use his mics and his setup and yeah got
the ball rolling
oh yeah man
so
how many episodes did you guys get in
before you're like
we're gonna do this like we're gonna
invest in some equipment and start doing
this ourselves
one
yeah i think uh after that first episode
um
pretty much
beyond that like right after that we
went and went on amazon bought these
mics that are in the shot today and um
bought one audio box and we didn't
really know how to use it very well it
was like a usb one um upgraded uh or got
another one because josh was out of town
quite a bit and we had to do that from
afar
just because of his job but then we got
the one that we're using today which is
great it's
uh
it's like the pod track yeah the pod
track p4 and it's got like four sound
bite options for it it's got four
channels and it's i don't know it's
really good
so that was our like latest purchase and
we have a camera as well it just
doesn't work very good uh so that was
kind of a shitty purchase but you know
it's all
it it's all in the in the learning
process but yeah from like episode two i
would say we we invested into at least
these mics to get good audio quality
because that was one of the things that
like was priority for us um is you know
we listen to podcasts and some of them
you know just don't have the best
quality uh just audio wise and so it's
kind of hard to listen to sometimes and
that was one of the things that we were
just like dead set no we have to have
at least some sort of you know at least
mid-range quality mic yeah and landed on
these at night they sound pretty pretty
good i think all right yeah
hell yeah
so
the smoking with podcasts you started
this just your smoke buddies you're
hanging out smoking all the time getting
into these deep conversations
where did it go from there is that what
it still is is it just smoking uh i mean
it
as we
i guess mature as growers in like
cannabis we're both in the industry so
it's it's evolved into more of a
like a grow talk kind of situation where
you know we try to cover some topics or
some news that's related to the industry
or
you know some tidbits information we got
or you know latest grow or
product review but
we always try to keep that aspect of uh
keeping it like loose and free and you
know if we want to talk about something
totally sidebar we do and you know it
happens often especially with guests
because
the whole
criteria for us doing this was we wanted
people to come on the show and feel like
they were smoking with us right like we
wanted the listeners at home to feel
like oh [ __ ] yeah like i feel like i'm
at a smoke sesh right now with these
guys and it wanted to keep it really
like low key and and comfortable
uh our first guests weren't
super you know experienced podcasters
right so it kind of helped ease them in
by you know it's just a regular
conversation and we're going to pass
around a joint and you know we
kind of
that's the one thing we want to keep
going forward is that that vibe
oh yeah that's important i think a lot
of people that are at home especially
stoners that are into like our kind of
niche of podcasting that's what they're
looking for is not that i mean we all
know we love information learning more
about this plant it's [ __ ] amazing if
you can find some other way to
incorporate something into your grow
that's going to work with it then you
get down that wormhole it doesn't matter
and you just keep going down that
wormhole and learning more and more but
as stoners there's also
so much attention time that you have for
it you know before you start going off
into the other stuff so if it gets too
serious they kind of throw me off i've
listened to quite a few that are very
very scientific cannabis podcasts and i
can listen to them and i love them but i
can only listen to so much before i'm
like okay i need to take this
information and
you know
break that [ __ ] down then i'll take some
more you know
so it helps to break that ice especially
when you're getting guests on um to
throw curveballs like that which i will
be doing with you guys
i want to ask each of you though really
quick
individually
what was your favorite episode
that's you
it's hard to quantify that
and i think um when we were on we were
just recently on another podcast with
derek um
and he asked us a very similar question
and it's very hard to nail it down
because they're especially our guest
episodes there's just so much
information packed in there as well as
like people's story and stuff like that
and it's
it's hard to just like say one episode
but i think my favorite type of episode
is when we would just get stupid high i
guess i'll break it into a type is when
we just get dumb high we'll start off
talking about weed um but yeah like you
said it just kind of just goes in in a
completely different direction and those
are fun because you
at a certain point of the conversation
the mics aren't in front of you anymore
in your head you're just you're just
talking and then you don't
you don't
have any expectation for the show and
those are just so freelance um when
having guests on it there's more of a
structure to it right you want to dig
into them and those are great in their
own right because like i said there's
nuggets of information and stuff like
that that you can get from these people
um about you know
the way they grow or whatever but yeah
the freelance free form
smoking just uh episodes were really
really fun but i i can't say a favorite
i got one that's been coming to my mind
lately i i won't
i guess i'll give the political uh put
it out front i love every single one of
our guests and i'm glad that they gave
us the time that they did and you know
most people especially the breeder
episodes like i learned so much just
from talking
to somebody for an hour right so they're
they're super cool but man my favorite
was like we we had
this girl on name alya but we had done a
back-to-back so right before we had her
on we were doing another recording with
my homie yonder
and uh
he was just there like he was like yeah
i was like you want to stick around dude
like you can just keep smoking with us
and he was like yeah sure so like we
just surprised guests on this other
podcast and i mean it was really fun we
smoked and you know i he actually
brought some stuff to that one too so i
was like oh okay this ended up being
okay but it was just a super long
session i'm like yeah [ __ ] it dude you
can be here i was already high at that
point so it sounded like you're going
yeah
there's certainly an evolution to our
podcast though there's those days where
we would go for like two or three hours
and put that whole episode together and
would just go off on just the most
random random things we could find
whatever was in the news or whatever
that was just kind of a funny story we
would talk about it and then have our
own
opinion on it but
yeah no definitely we've kind of gone
into this more cannabis niche and we're
still open to having whoever on and
talking about anything i mean we've had
you know people yoga instructors do um
you know aaliyah you were just talking
about uh she she's like a very mindful
type person um
yeah like more spirituality mindfulness
like positivity kind of thing yeah uh
we've had
people who were
you know into cooking and i mean i've
had people in oklahoma that
we did like a pokemon card episode and
that was pretty fun with my homie riley
and he's random too but like 90 of the
episode was like pokemon guards
i like the ones that are unexpected like
that you know if if it's too structured
it's not fun anymore
yeah right you have to have those
[ __ ] hooks
yeah
so i didn't even ask you guys i see
josh is over there with a joint i think
i saw garrett with a joint earlier
same joint
oh [ __ ] you guys are in the same room
yeah
yes sir
you could have swore josh was out
somewhere i tell yeah i tell p i tell
them that all the time i was like it
looks like
we're in two different places but we're
always in the same spot
what are you guys smoking on today
uh that's the singapore sling uh that's
a tiki madman
collab situation from a while ago that
we had at our facility um
when i first started working there
the first iteration of this that i tried
was like not
not good
uh you know like i'm sorry it sounds
like you're going really easy
yeah it was it was pretty trash dude and
like i was it was harsh and i was like
oh man this is like this can't be what
we're putting out all the time right
like you know like in my head and i
wasn't gonna say that at a brand new job
but i was like damn dude this is this is
rough and then uh
you know we tried it a couple more times
and it just never
got the legs it never got to where it
was gonna go but then they were like hey
we wanna we really want this to work
right so they tried it one more time
actually this last time dude it's
it's good you know it's got potential
and i'm like okay well if you know if we
tweaked this a little bit more i'd [ __ ]
with this hardcore it's it smells good
it's got good structure now uh and i
mean the high is pretty great i'm pretty
focused it's more like on the hybrid
sativa side of life for me and we don't
have a lot of those at our facility most
of [ __ ] is like knockout like straight
indica
put you down into the floor
and the ones we do are like the citrus
terps which are seem like in in at least
washington that's like the bottom of
people's choice
uh for terpene profiles so it's it's
hard um
but those ones we have also they're
they're a sherb cross it's emergency
from sea junkie they released it a
little while ago but it's sherb to uh
blow pops orange orange blow pops uh so
it's got citrus but it also has like
some sherb to it so it it kind of is a
good
segue i guess into it rather than it
just being like full force chop cookies
yeah
like the name drop with the chop cookies
for sure we we have a very
love-hate relationship with the chopped
cookies
this is all dangly [ __ ] it is
and it's like the bud tastes so good
when tropicana cookies is grown right
it's really really tasty bud
the high it's not bad it's not the best
but it's not bad at all yeah but yeah
just growing her she's just kind of a
[ __ ]
oh you could tell people like with warm
cookies tropicana cookies at the end of
the grow
it's kind of like you got a finger in
the bubble at the end of sex like you're
like oh that was nice but
yeah and then you go to harvest it and
you're really like i got [ __ ] up
because they're like this small after
they dry they're just tiny little
cookies ugly yeah exactly but they are
some pretty flowers too
yeah and they taste good right they have
their place it's just yeah it takes some
patience extracts
that's extract for sure yeah yeah that
would be a good one
so
when did both of you get into growing
like what was your first experience with
cannabis
i'll let you go that's chronologically
yeah um
you know it's hard to put a date on it
uh i don't know exactly when i just know
it was roughly when i was around 20
uh i believe it was 21 because we had
dispensaries here and i was able i was
buying wheat out of dispensaries so 21
we'll say that
um
we i've been hold up back
i've been smoking since i was 16. that's
when i first first got introduced to it
i was in high school um
and
was really off and on with it
and then had some friends who whose
parents grew and stuff like that and was
constantly around weed right and i had
access to it so i just
and then i
i got
to the point where i was like smoking
daily like i am now and so uh it got to
a point to where uh me and my buddy were
just like we really want to grow this
it was a different buddy before i met
josh and um
started growing with him but
we decided that we wanted to grow the
weed and hope in hopes to make some
money not make money off it but like i
guess recoup our money from
the it's like spending it on
dispensaries so rather than spending it
at the dyspo that weed is kicking in so
i'm kind of rambling here that tends to
happen i'm sorry
um
we got some we got some seeds he ordered
some up out of like amsterdam or
something like that there were some
northern lights um that he was a real
big fan of and so we decided to grow
that
and it was like sketchy style right like
send them a money order and then hope
the seeds come later yeah but it was his
money so i was totally okay with it
happening i was like all right if you
want to do that man like whatever um but
yeah we grew those in a kind of [ __ ]
way uh we grew them in soil to start
under some like um cfl bulbs like two of
them
um
and then he had been reading a lot about
like dwc and stuff like that and
he was like i think i want to do that
and so he was like i think i want to
transplant the ones that we have in soil
they were about like yay big
um and uh
i don't know why we thought that that
would be a good idea but we were brand
new to it so like all right i was like
all right you think this is gonna work
and he's like yeah you just gotta wash
off the roots and set them in this
hydroton stuff and i was like all right
man like whatever um
like out of the i think we had like five
or six plants like three two or three of
them made it um and we had swapped he
had bought like one of those blurple
lights off amazon for like 100 bucks um
the ones with the fans that uh are awful
um
i've seen some really good bud off of a
couple of those brands uh i know what
you're talking about but like uh
god damn now i can't even think of the
name of them either but like viper
spectra
yeah viper spectra was one of them there
was like bloom i don't know bloom plus
was kind of like a yellow there's a few
of them though the viper spectra are the
ones that come to mind the most
like the onboard fans that would you
know blow all the heat away from the
light and whatnot but yeah i've seen
some really pretty buds on there it's
just a matter of your environment this
wasn't this wasn't like a bootleg
version of not this one
no and you know we didn't know [ __ ]
about environment or anything like that
they were growing under this little
under the stairs closet in there um
and i mean we did decent there was it
was it wasn't successful i wouldn't say
i don't i don't ever remember really
i can't even think of harvesting that
bud like i can't even remember that
that's how like i don't
that's why i can't say it was successful
we did some really really dumb stuff and
i continue to do dumb stuff but i'm a
little more calculated with it now like
i understand components right yeah yeah
no you're never going to be perfect you
know 24 7 ain't going to happen sorry
but that was my introduction to you know
growing weed and
eventually you know did some butt
tending stuff uh and then finally made
my way into a grow here in washington so
oh yeah man that's awesome
yeah so did garrett influence you josh
no
like a little bit i was thinking about
it at the time we were working together
uh
just like started construction together
like we were doing some like remodel
type stuff with this investor guy and i
i had been to his house i'd smoked over
there i'd seen
you know the tent or the little grow
space you know with the blurple light
you'd open it up like oh god and then
let your eyes adjust for like three
seconds and then you could actually see
the plant uh
you know like [ __ ] around with that
and i was like okay well they're doing
the thing and then you know i'd seen
when they started doing the dwc there
was the like three in there and the five
gallon buckets like i remember that
and shortly after that time
my brother
hit me up and he was like hey
i started growing this weed plant
uh
but i don't know what's wrong with it
could you figure it out and he asked me
because he knew i knew people who grow
weed and he you know he's like i don't
know anybody right so i'm like okay well
let me
see what's up like send me a picture of
your plant
and he sends me this picture and it's
it's a [ __ ] like you know 18 inch
plant
and it's in a
like you know those soup bowls
uh
but are also mugs like it's got the
little mug handle on it yeah like bigger
mug so he had it in that
uh so i would say maybe like a solo cup
and a half worth of
dirt for this 18 inch
uh plant any drainage holes
uh no uh-uh nope it was like just
sitting in soup pretty much uh
and he had
he had it growing in the windowsill
but like facing the south side of the
house so there was never like any direct
sunlight ever it was just always like
getting
ambient sunlight from the window
and i was like okay so right off the bat
i don't know a lot about a lot right now
but i know that you need lights to grow
weak i know that you can't just put it
in your windowsill and do the thing it's
at least got to be like outside like
catching a lot of sun right like you
can't that's number one and i was like
number two like
that's not a pot dude that's a cup like
you need to get it out of the cup and
into like an actual pot for plants like
you know i'm like that's that's what i'm
thinking and he was like okay well like
do you want to take it because i can't
grow it any bigger than it is now and i
was like
sure man but it's probably going to die
right like i was like it's already in a
bad spot it looks hella sick it's like
turning yellow it's got different spots
on the leaves yeah like spider mites too
it was just like like this plant was
doomed to fail right and i was like [ __ ]
it dude send it to me so he gives it to
me
i go buy some [ __ ] we like bought these
lights off of uh
like offer up
we went and met some sketchy dude who
used to grow some like black market grow
in tacoma that was like yeah
not tacoma yeah yeah yeah
we're like more on the federal way side
of things so it's like kind of like out
in the cuts uh so we're over there and
uh
he just
you know shows up in this
suv
sells us these lights and i [ __ ] you not
dude gets into like a [ __ ] other car
like a charger that's already parked on
the same lot and drives off bro like it
was so weird it was so sketchy i was
like dude he just
like i feel like these lights are stolen
or something that but you know we took
him anyways we're like [ __ ] it dude it's
offer up he's not going to say anything
we're not got the money yeah
we gave them the money we took the
things it's a different area code we're
all good yeah we just we drove back
south and then i was like okay so i took
one of these it was like one of those
magnum xxl like uh
man did i have a metal haloid in it
first i don't remember i had something
it was it was not efficient it was hella
hot that was hps oh okay orange yeah a
little hps uh it was doing the thing
1000 watt
and i like hung it and i put it over
this little plant and this like i think
i transplanted it into like a plastic
one gallon
uh
and
it came back to life dude like it just
said it lived
yeah so i was like okay well now i
actually have to grow this [ __ ] plant
right like it didn't die
uh so now i'm like researching and i'm
looking at all this i'm asking garrett a
million seven questions right like oh
what about this and you know like he's
letting me borrow newts and
[ __ ] like that and coming and checking
on the plant and like we floured this
thing out we ended up like
he had some pollen from one of his
plants and we ended up seeding like
half of it
and we got hella seeds off of it now we
still have them to this day like that's
like a supposedly the
bag seed that my brother grew was from
acapulco gold but like i can't
confirm or deny that so i i'm not gonna
call it that i'm like i'm not gonna say
this is a land race
without knowing for sure it was it was
crossed to um
tangerine dream seeds that i got when i
went up to canada
they just somehow like was in my pocket
when i got home it was weird i like went
up there we got some weed
smoked that weed and then i got home and
there were seeds in my pocket that's a
tangerine dream i don't know how they
got there but that
there was a male out of that and um
that went to this acapulco gold and we
have some seeds here uh somebody just
ran them recently and yeah i sent them
to a homie over there in new york and
they're currently flowering so we'll see
how those go yeah i mean let's do the
thing yeah the old-ass seeds bro like i
don't know like five years ago now like
five six years ago and
yeah like
i mean that i got a bunch of bud off of
it too like we smoked it i was like wow
this was
hella successful like i felt good i felt
like i had a green thumb i was like yeah
this is
i can do no wrong with plants and then i
did my second round
that was the exact same
real run
man i'm a natural at this and then you
lay off on the second one you're like
[ __ ]
absolutely
this horrible sketchy tacoma story about
picking up lights and then three seeds
in your pocket yeah that's awesome
yeah [ __ ] yeah you know you guys are
from washington too
i i apologize to my tacoma people you
know i love you know washington i'm from
there like that
exactly and i feel like most
people you'd be like i don't [ __ ] with
tacoma and most tacoma people would be
like hey
well
i'm fair enough
the answer is always well this part of
tacoma's okay like it's never like oh
well tacoma's fine it's always like well
this
this one section if you drive over to
that part of tacoma it's cool like
there's like mansions and
like totally we don't talk about like
the south side we don't talk about the
east side there's not you don't talk
about hilltop really
like it's just like oh well like the
north end of tacoma like downtown that's
cool like that's it i've been to
anywhere sketchy places in washington
but tacoma is one that i don't like
going to and then uh chinatown and like
portland i guess that's still oregon but
yeah that chinatown portland holy [ __ ]
portland i've been chased by a
literal clan of bums
in chinatown
i just like
their property
and we were riding those little electric
scooters are you there that you're right
yeah yeah yeah you guys want to have fun
go down to portland rent those things
just get high as [ __ ] you can smoke a
joint just like going down the water
pier down there at night oh it's so much
fun just do not go to chinatown do not
go to china
at the time her and i were going down
to portland she goes i want to see
chinatown i go and i've been around
portland quite a bit i said you don't
want to go to chinatown
and she goes yes i do i want to see it
and i was like all right fine and she is
so adhd she's just oblivious to
everything
around this one corner and all of a
sudden there was a bunch of they look
like heroin addicts just like
it was horrible they were definitely
grouped up and doing [ __ ] and uh
she just blasts by him just completely
oblivious and then i'm behind her like
protecting her ass
and i turn around this guy's like hey
what are you doing on our turf blah blah
and him and like 15 bumps just come
rushing at us and she's just like
oblivious and i'm behind her and
he's like what's the problem it was like
he didn't see the army of [ __ ] bums
chasing us
murdered come on now yeah that sounds
like a scary movie beginning for sure
wow good thing you were there to save
the day dawg i feel like
and the scooters were fast right like
you had to
i mean for scooters they're pretty damn
quick they get it i mean they're
obviously a bunch of like
i guess they're on heroin so that is a
downer so maybe that like made them a
little yeah but like you know that i
mean they were running this [ __ ] to
bite me
you don't know what that you might turn
into a zombie for real exactly
homeless people just bums our
our this generation zombies yeah well i
mean
out there for long enough yeah it's like
ooh
isn't that like an episode of south park
or something if not it should be yeah
but yeah i think it is yeah yeah i think
it was yeah
okay so i got my first hook question for
you guys okay if you were to start a
secret society
what would you call it
what a secret society no i heard the man
i just
i told you it was a hook man
i got nothing bro
i don't i've never even thought about
that i don't right that's a point
gonna have this dead air while we sit
here and think about this weed i would
call it octopus they're just straight up
just octopus yeah
what would it be about
i don't like octopus are so hella smart
right so i'm thinking like is that where
you're thinking or like hydra well i
also thought like
logo later and i was like i could just
rip the hydra logo and turn it into an
octopus off of like captain america i
was like easy
i'm like all right perfect
octopus
they're smart they're
[ __ ]
cool they can change colors and [ __ ] i
don't know that sounds like [ __ ]
going for like the human reptile secret
society yeah yeah
you still get still got nothing over
there
i don't i just i don't either
never comes dump them i just there's
nothing man nothing coming to my mind
like i would want it
i don't know if it was to be like a
secret society where why are we secret i
don't want things to be secret well
maybe like you know like maybe a secret
for a good reason
right but like what do i gotta hide
right like the only thing i can think of
is like a secret society of weed but
like i mean it's a planet or something
i want people to know so they could help
me save the planet you know like
i don't know i don't know that
there's no power that's too much power
for one man
i mean
it could be a big ass society right you
could have a huge society
oh yeah yeah i mean it could be three
people i don't care yeah it could be
three people
million people
i don't know dude
i love the letter z so it would probably
start with z
like i got two dogs they're both they
both start with z
um i don't know it'd be like like
zentopia i don't know something like
that
wow you hit me with zentopia and i was
really expecting you to go like some
like really hardcore german name that
starts with a z you know i'm not
i was like yeah okay
that sounds like a like a scary secret
yeah i was gonna say we're gonna be a
secret society i swear i'm not putting
it in german
it's like a bad recipe
people be like what the [ __ ] is that
you're both originally from washington
though
yeah i was born in seattle oh right on
what about you gary
uh yup yup right here in olympia
oh in olympia right on i go through
olympia quite often man actually i'm
gonna be headed over there probably
through there towards the end of july oh
dude and then maybe again in november
so
let us know if you're in the area yeah
we'll we'll smoke down or do something
yeah for a little while we could
actually take you to the facility and
give you a little tour oh [ __ ] yeah
that'd be badass yeah [ __ ] yeah oh
that's an interesting tattoo you have on
your eye man what's that
uh this is hebrew for protector of
israel my son's name's israel and i
wanted to get a tattoo for him but i
like he came super early so the time i
had to think and plan this out was like
cut down to like two days
uh and so i was like oh okay i'm just
gonna get this
and i had a homie who was uh
he'd studied hebrew so he like was like
i think these are the words you're going
to look for and so i did i looked it up
on google and sure [ __ ] there the words
that he said that they were going to be
and then this lady who was jewish that i
met later she like read it and she was
like oh that's so cute blah blah blah
like
no problem so i was like okay it doesn't
say like soy sauce or something on my
arm like
i wanted it to say
uh yeah worked out good got it in
oklahoma like right before i came to see
my son
i saw this image one time it cracked me
up
but it shows all these americans walking
around with like chinese letters and
stuff tattooed on their arm and then
said imagine if china was like this and
they just had like water written on
their arm in english
and i never thought about chinese single
tattoos the same after that
they're so much better than like but i
mean people do that right people tattoo
[ __ ] stupid words up their forearms
or across their chest or like that's a
thing it looks cool i like the japanese
characters i like chinese characters you
know it's cool writing but uh when you
think of it in that perspective just
like yeah yeah it's weird like imagine
going to the country and that's their
thing you'd be like why do you have that
just going and also country and yeah
seeing english letters tattooed on
somebody's half of the half the tattoos
would be something weird because they
think it's this but it's not it's like
translates all weird word yeah and so
you're like
that dude on your body like that
please don't barn door written
yeah
this means strength and you're like
you see it all the time with like i
don't know like you'll there'll be memes
essentially of it but it's like
clothing a lot of the clothing over
there they'll like knock off clothing is
like misinterpreted or miss
so i assume the same principles would
happen if you were to get a tattoo
of an english word
yeah oh yeah 100
exactly
and plus english is such a [ __ ] hard
language to like learn and understand
and so is chinese like so
each other trying to understand each
other like the worst combo right like
you
any other way you have something better
right yeah i need a chinese person
right like i know people who are
bilingual chinese english like they're
genius they're leather level
i i know
quite a few languages but i'm not fluent
in like any of them except for english i
can get by with most of them if i sit
there and i listen and i take my time to
speak it back and think about what i'm
saying but i'm not just like off the
cusp oh yeah i got this you know
even that's impressive dude like just
being able to understand and communicate
with people like even if it took you a
long time because i think about meeting
you know people from different countries
here in america and like any english
that they speak i'm like yeah dude like
i'll [ __ ] like tell me like i want to
hear what you're saying you know even if
it's broken and they got a thick accent
like whatever i'm going to try to
understand and so i feel like it's the
same right like they just appreciate
that you're trying to communicate with
them in a way that they can understand
so like they're like yeah
dope
so if you could learn any other language
what would you learn
i'm already kind of halfway there with
spanish just you know heritage wise but
maybe japanese
i watch a lot of anime
like a dumb amount in fact i don't watch
any tv period except for anime like
there's not another show where i'm like
yeah i watched that like maybe once a
year i'll like watch a different type of
show but like
it's 90 of the time it's anime
right huh now that makes a lot of sense
my first instinct is just to say russian
and i think the only reason why is
because like i don't know it sounds cool
um similar to german like i already know
a little bit of german and have gone
over and visited for a couple weeks
there through an exchange program which
was really cool um but awesome i don't
know russian and plus i play a lot of
video games and some of those video
games have a big russian fan base like
cs go or like escape from tarkov then so
like i don't know to be able to
communicate or just like talk [ __ ] to
them
[ __ ] to americans in that game uh that'd
be kind of yeah i don't know funny i
learned the whole language just to talk
[ __ ] online
also probably kind of like low-key
useful in the political climate right
now right oh yeah
that's awesome
russian and german are two very angry
sounding languages yeah
and like i'm not gonna lie german is
like
it's like an ugly language to me when i
like when i think about german it
doesn't it's not soft and like sweet and
like sound good it's like if somebody
was gonna yell at me or like be mean it
would sound good in german but if
somebody wanted to like swoopy talk
sweet enough things into my ear and a
whisper and they were speaking german
i'd be like oh like
what are you doing
it's just a lot of consonants
i don't know any russian at all but i
knew a little bit of ukrainian and at
the time i did not know that there was
much of a difference but i had a couple
friends that were russian and i had a
couple other friends that were ukrainian
the ukrainians were the ones that were
teaching me ukrainian but then i would
talk to my russian friends and they
would understand what i was saying but
they look at me like
you're saying that like all messed up
and i was like it's ukrainian they're
like yeah it's like slang it's like
it's like hispanic compared to like true
spanish yeah like they understand each
other but it's like yeah but people from
spain are like yeah on a different
on a different level like i don't even
like hearing them talk some of the like
ways that they
put accents on their word or like the
way they like say the th sound of like
with a lisp it's like
like they're constantly spitting on
yours and then yeah
it doesn't
it doesn't sound very good to me it's
more akin to like
that type of spanish though is like how
i get like french and italian and them
being all the same thing because it's
kind of all got that same error of
whatever that latin base yeah
oh yeah so i didn't even ask you guys i
asked you what you were smoking on
what's your favorite type of cannabis
like what do you primarily go after
the
i would say like the the necrotic type
of effect or not
[Laughter]
oh we just hit the second joint and it's
a different type of weed it's a really
stoney stuff but
um the stuff that could just like i
don't know
like yeah put me out but like or like
narcotics or so more so relax me and
not
[ __ ] with my brain functionality not
like really slow me down up top um but
also just like slows my body down
because um and and josh is more so worse
about this than me but we don't stop
fidgeting that's just kind of
ingrained like if you're if you're
standing still like i it just doesn't
work for me it doesn't feel good so um
to have something to slow my body down
but like keep my mind alert is always my
go-to
that makes that makes three fidgeters in
the room i'm with you i'm like over here
with my wedding ring
yeah
what about you josh what are you into
well
i'm like kind of on the other side of
the cusp i like me a hybrid that's got
like some sativa effects like those are
always my like go back like oh i miss
that weed like today
on the way home from work i'm like oh
it's really nice outside i'd love to
smoke some lemon skunk right now and i
was like [ __ ] dude there's i'm not going
to be able to find that
anywhere so now i have to
grow some and i'm like well how do i get
seeds and
you know
i'm like i know skunk is like one of
those ones like in order to get real
skunk you got to get them from like
greenhouse or something in amsterdam
and so i was like i wonder if [ __ ]
like lemon skunk is like that right or
somebody's got him and and like i'm not
finding any reputable sights or breeders
that got lemon skunk and everything that
i am finding is all like sketchy and
no reviews and like yeah just making me
feel weird about it and like the one
country or like one out of
i don't know maybe ten legal countries
like we we're the only ones that they
don't ship to like
directly
uh all the way
lemon skunk seeds man okay well good
anyway
i like guys need seeds i mean i can hook
you up with that i don't need the seeds
you know like there's a bunch of other
[ __ ] i probably should grow you know
that i'm just like looking at like i got
my little collection but like you don't
need a good amsterdam that's right here
buddy i'm about it thank you sir uh i'll
get you taken care of but yeah like
those like lemony like citrusy or
grapefruity kind of like
notes with like some funk like some like
like some feet or some some something
you know like or some skunkiness like i
i don't know i kind of like that
contrast and
the effects for me are always kind of
like they don't mellow me out they keep
me focused and i i like being able to
like be happy and be relaxed but also be
able to do things uh i am 90 certain i
have like some undiagnosed add adhd
and so like having something that like
helps me
stay on target for longer than six
seconds is dope right so i'm like oh i
love that weed like that that weed's
good for me because i can literally head
down on this task focus in and just go
and crush it
oh yeah man would you say that limonene
chirping was like one of your
more favorable
profiles
but it's more like the funk from the
like
because anything that smells like gmo or
like just like makes you puke in your
mouth a little bit is really where i'm
like ooh
i want to smoke that but like that with
that like someone's squeezing on top of
that
you know like i like those combos
because i don't like just straight up
orange like tangy is cool but like
you know it's not my
thing okay nice sometimes time it's got
enough pining in there to be different
you know it's almost like an orangey
haze
and uh
but like when you get that funk but you
can you can get a little bit of the
citrus i don't know that's a good combo
for me yeah i think weed is situational
like like you were that you were just
asking i was like what our favorite type
is but yeah i think like you were saying
on a nice day like today i wouldn't like
to just be on the couch zoned out you
know
um so yeah i think wheat is definitely
situational there's plenty of times
where i i fall josh and i have the
similar palette when it comes to weed so
yeah we're generally smoking and can
agree on the same things that's why
we're good smoking buddies that's how
this started because it was like that i
like that too okay let's get it we're
gonna go smoke that
oh yeah dude that's a good smoke partner
to have
yeah so we both worked at danks they
would be like ooh have you tried that
yet no and i'm like you should and then
you go get it you're like oh damn i'm
trusting that another agent yeah oh yeah
so
garrett uh what about chirping profiles
anything but the haze
terpene profile i don't like
like me like i don't mind the flavor
right like i can get down on it but it
just it puts my anxiety through the roof
did you say that haze doesn't like me
correct
once
honestly i'll smoke that stuff and i'm
like damn that tastes really good i mean
it's just like a refreshing pine tree or
like you know some rosemary um
not
and then my body starts my heart starts
beating and i and then my brain starts
focusing solely on that and it's like oh
that's beating pretty loud and then then
you go through this
uh like stair step paradigm
yeah into this weird paranoia and you're
like oh [ __ ] am i even breathing right
like this
like it feels like something's in my
lung maybe i should go to the hospital
no you don't need to go to the hospital
you're okay yeah that's just tough it
really [ __ ] with gary and like almost
like sometimes he's allergic to it like
he'll like sneeze and get itchy eyes and
like oh [ __ ] yeah it's like no it's not
well yeah
and i'm over here like nah this shit's
pretty cool man
yeah that's our only difference it's
like i'll smoke a straight up sativa
sativa and he's got to be careful about
which ones he does
there's there's i really really like
hazes
but i do prefer a little bit of uh the
indica i say that very [ __ ] loosely
uh indica but like more affy bread and
do it where it's gonna bring it a step
down but it's still leaning towards the
sativa side you know
right i can get down on the cross the
haze crosses like i've gotten some lemon
hazes that have done me all right uh
super silver is my worst enemy
um
and then like just classic hazes is just
not not for me like the old pifs and
stuff like that i just can't do it but
there are there have been crosses that
that i'm like oh i can i can enjoy this
this haze um but yeah not this not the
straight ups not the pining heavy
uh go-getters
i've been getting into growing a little
bit more of the hash cultivars just
because i want to play with making my
own ash rosin okay so just
made bubble hash for years pressed
flower rosin but i've never gone through
pressing my bubble hash because i covet
bubble hash so much that if i have it i
just smoke it as bubble ash like i
[ __ ] love that like if i had to be on
a desert island and they said there's
only one method you can use from now on
and i'd be like give me some [ __ ] ash
what easy what makes that like what why
i i need to understand that i've never
been able to like truly ask somebody why
like bubble hash or just it's usually
some old dude coming in to buy it when i
was about tender and he would always hit
the hash and he's like dude this stuff
is legit and i've tried it myself right
but like
i don't like in your mind why is that so
like upper level
i've always been a flower guy for the
most part i enjoy rolling joints even
when dabs came around i didn't get into
them for a long time just because it was
like oh that got me high really quick
but it takes the
experience away from it when you're in a
circle with your friends and [ __ ] and
you can sit there for you know a half
hour pass around a couple joints or
something have these big long
conversations next to hey you want this
dab done yeah and it was a little messy
when it started out right like
doing dabs way back in the day looked
really weird like some of the [ __ ]
looked like pickles and i was like a
[ __ ] night
yeah
yeah i look like [ __ ] drugs it still
kind of does like my dad will come
around and see me take a dab and he's
just like
your clothes is just weird
that looks like [ __ ]
so to answer your question
i always appreciate joint speed because
it had the full flavor of the plant and
that's what i love is the flavor of the
plant i love that experience with it too
hash when you're smoking bubble hash it
burns for quite a while it's a thick
smoke but the thing is you've isolated
those glands there's still a little bit
of contaminants whether it's stalks or
like you know small leaf matter whatever
depending on what grade of hash you have
but i feel like you get all the
cannabinoids every bit of that plant and
that flavor is just packed there and
then when you press into hash rosin
unless your environments exactly you
know like perfect like you have a cold
room ready for it a cold environment
cold storage cold water everything
you know your spatulas everything are
cold
you're going to lose terpenes through
the process
through processing it
hash cures really well so the oxidation
on the outside will change the color of
that and it'll make like a hard shell
and kind of preserve everything that's
in there
so that i feel
i'm really interested in making the hash
rosin just because pretty and i'm
interested in making consistencies like
diamonds and sugar and because we blew
bho back in the day but that shit's so
[ __ ] bad for you you never get all of
that out even i'm not talking [ __ ] but
even a lot of uh the wreck industry i i
taste some of these bhos shows and
you're like there's it's definitely
still in there like you can't have a
twang you're like
yeah there's some really good guys doing
it out there but then there's some that
you're just like okay you open it up and
that shit's like [ __ ] dark amber
orange and you're like
[ __ ] see the butane in this
aaron uh no yeah
was always the best for me
okay you made me a believer sir like i
subscribed like you that was a good
explanation i'm like yeah yeah well as
you're talking about it i'm sitting over
here like me and josh have ranted and
raved about uh rosin like we would
always say we would always talk about
rosin in that way and like
that's just one step further than the
stuff you're smoking right so then you
said you wanted to play around with the
hash rosin and i was just questioning
you on a question i already had the
answer to so
you know
sorry about that but i get it was just
it's just a different it's just a
different process i guess like you don't
dab the bubble hash right so
i don't know i guess maybe it's like the
predecessor you know right it's just you
know i get it like for me it's the
cocoon version you know it's like it's
good
but when you like squish that into some
five star or six star or whatever like
that is
it's the plan right it's like the
essence of the plan yeah they need to
start paying me to do ratings yeah dude
that plan for sure okay so i've got my
second hook question for you guys
i'd rather sleep
wearing handcuffs or a bike helmet
uh
can i like can i ask a question to the
question yeah the handcuffs in front of
me or behind me they're behind you for
sure right behind you yeah like come on
with them in the front well they didn't
say arrested just handcuffed i don't
know what's it maybe are you like kinky
and you got like one
and you're just sleeping on a bed you're
like oh yeah this is fine this is cool i
mean if you're freaking out the bike
helmet could be just as sexualized
enough
no you're behind the back you're
arrested dog okay yeah that helmet like
hands down i've been i've slept with my
hands
handcuffed
my back for a little bit took a little
nappy nap in the back of the
vehicle on the way to where i was going
uh
you are a very patient person it wasn't
bad
bad i leaned over i wasn't like on my
hands and you know it was just a regular
nap at that point
i think the bike helmet would like mess
with my neck that's the only way i
hesitate like i'm so specific on how my
pillow has to go behind my head when i
go to sleep at night for me to like fall
asleep but i can only imagine having
this [ __ ] thing on the top of my head
where i'm like yeah no yeah like you
drop or do stuff that's got to support
the pillow the pillow didn't now it goes
to the neck and now yeah right but like
trying to get that right just sounds
frustrating you move you're gonna wake
up with a headache oh for sure sure
gonna wake up with a headache you know
if you wake up with it you don't wake up
with a headache when you sleep in the
handcuffs maybe your fingers hurt a
little bit i still teasing bike element
okay so when you guys had me on your
podcast the other day which is great
saying i i loved some of your episodes
that that phenotype episode is the first
one that pops out to me as it was the
most recent one i listened to um
but
it cracked me up how far out you guys
could go out there and i appreciate you
guys coming on my show and doing this
with me because we've done the exact
same thing we get to talk cannabis we
get to have fun but we also get to throw
some [ __ ] out there so i want to talk
about that episode specifically
good towards the end
you guys start getting into aliens and
[ __ ] like that
tell ya what
what do you each believe oh is there
life out there oh well it's for sure
thousand
one thousand percent
and i i will talk about any i will tell
people i'm like
right now with the technology we have
you can't even kind of say no right like
you can live in your hole and hide under
your rock if you want to
there's just so much evidence out there
and
[ __ ] dude like i i don't know about you
but it's not that hard to go see a
[ __ ] experience like
you know like i think everyone's gotta
like i've seen that or you know
yeah that's
what about you gary yeah dude there's
just absolutely
yeah of course there's [ __ ] out there
it's like they tell us like i don't i
don't know specific numbers but there's
hundreds of thousands of i don't know
how many galaxies right like galaxies
and we're in the milky way right which
is comprised of many different
uh you know solar solar systems
there's no way it's just empty for just
no reason right and even like bacteria
on another planet would count as an
alien right because it's just life on
another planet exactly like
even at that level like you gotta
believe that at some point right there
it could be something right and then
they tell us there's earth-like planets
out there it's like well then
yeah i saw this statistic that was like
just in our like galaxy hubble telescope
alone has already yeah noticed quite a
few planets that have potentially have
water which is the basis of life and
that's the way that i see about it is if
we already perceive this and we know
that there's a few planets out there
that could potentially have life within
the vision of the entire universe that
we can see which is way beyond our reach
which is like this much right i forgot
what they named it but there's a brand
new telescope that's even more powerful
than the hubble was i've been seeing
it's pretty cool
but they're getting way better pictures
within just imagine if we find even more
of these you exactly like you said if
there's not like a [ __ ] amoeba or a
protozoa on that is that not an alien
right like so at some level like we win
like there's aliens and i'm a safe bet
that is a safe you could put your money
there and be all right yeah we're not
talking the aliens in the movies no like
no literally though
like if you guys if you're trying to ask
me like how i really feel yes like
yes everything everything everything
that you've been
riddle me this why have so many alien
things come out like in that as of late
and like that now it's like second
nature now shit's coming from a
different planet superheroes whatever
like it's it's just okay it's accepted
dude like i feel like that's like slow
roll
like desensitization so that when they
tell you there's aliens it doesn't melt
your brain out of your face right like
you don't just go into a panic and start
lighting your pants people think we've
already been visited
oh yeah
yes yeah i agree like
ain't no way dude bro i just watched
this like an hour long documentary on
mummies in the grand canyon
and i i'm convinced well there's like a
sphinx or something they uncover no
there's so much it's like i'm not going
to go into it because it's so long but
like i need to look this up
yeah was it a credible source
there's multiple different videos on
this and the credible source is this
place exists and there was these things
found there what the source is that's
the debatable but the one guy i watched
was very convincing and already kind of
like was explaining things along the
lines that like
i'm making sense of aliens in my head
right so i'm like oh okay this could be
some more some of that [ __ ] right
and uh you know
i'll i'll give you the link after this
but yeah you get into it and
there's gotta be right like also like
why does the pyramid
look like the one in
the aztecs app like why does the egypt
one and the aztec one look the same
they've never seen their other
they're not homies
right they're not kicking it they're not
taking boats over they didn't consult
and be like hey this is really good
shape you should do that winston like
they were blessed
with [ __ ] that we can't even understand
how they made it to this day exactly
we're like i
need i don't know maybe mammoths
just peruvian temples alone seeing some
of the structures of how they put those
blocks together where it's almost like a
puzzle piece it's not simple
you know
yeah holy hell
but those ones are like on like peaks of
like these cliffs because i like how
crazy the rain comes down there's like
so much erosion that there's only so
many spots you can build and everything
else around it's a [ __ ] valley like
in a river right like there's just
rivers everywhere so
like yeah to move all these rocks
with like you got canoes
and
you i don't even think they had horses
like i don't even think that aztecs had
like
first like beasts of burden like i don't
i don't know on that one yeah like i
can't think of like i'm very obsessed
with egyptian culture but i don't know
very much about peruvian yeah right so
i'm like did they even have animals that
could pull that [ __ ] like
maybe an ox or like an alpaca but like
how many alpacas would it take to move
one of them [ __ ]
stones dude
[Laughter]
some beasted alpaca
ripped like look like small horses with
long necks
yeah dude there's no way even that we're
the most advanced right like that's
not even close if everything's infinite
dude like there's you just got to
believe that everything is everywhere
like technology wise we're on a very
slow roll until very recently too like
something to think about
what's the best wi-fi password name that
you've ever seen
steamer hat password or or like
the wi-fi name oh
i don't know like
this is kind of an old meme but like i
like the like police fan
uh ones
those were pretty funny uh when when
people i think that kind of started this
whole
revolution of
like the antithesis of i like that one
i saw like get your own [ __ ] wi-fi
like i forget the name of the guy but it
was like
directly pointed i assumed like a
roommate
but
it could have been a [ __ ] neighbor it
could have been like hey dude get your
own [ __ ] like get off my [ __ ] there's
apartments and i was like what who would
there be just putting them on blast
every time i try to sign into something
i see this right like just everyone
knows it was it was very easy such a
disservice if you don't change your
wi-fi name just something incredible
i like to [ __ ] with my neighbor so i
named my wi-fi after him
with his name drawn out in an
exclamation point at the end
so every time he gets on it says his
name
he's like oh [ __ ]
i know
they already know
[Laughter]
oh yeah so you guys are doing this
podcast and you're going
um
you're talking you're you've evolved
more
into talking more about cannabis
specifics a little bit and you guys work
in the wreck industry i've noticed
especially
um you guys are monetizing now you have
your own discord
correct
yeah yeah yeah all right we will put
that link down here in the description
if you guys enjoyed josh and garrett on
the show you can go check out their
discord i'm in there too you guys are
awesome you're sharing a ton of
information
not just on the podcast alone but you
have grow
threads
and you're helping people with growth
problems and whatnot right doing our
best yeah yeah do you guys ever do like
live shows or anything
it's things we're thinking about right
like to the future we want to make sure
i mean so we did like a live 420
giveaway thing for like an hour or like
45 minutes or something maybe
that but like
bahaki came on and he's our homie right
he's been on a couple episodes and
he's our very first ever patron very
first ever patron like we like this guy
a lot and he he came and kicked it with
us but like nobody else jumped in or
asked questions and i was like man i was
really expecting this to pop off so i
think i would do a live show when we
were like maybe double digit k and
followers or like you know like
that was just instagram live too i think
that there's merit for going on to like
something like twitch and doing a show
like that and
potential to have a bigger audience um
that was just kind of like a thrown
together thing it was
it wasn't really
super well thought out i would say no
not at all
so but there's definitely
eventually going to have some live shows
whether that be just for patrons or not
um we're still kind of toying with the
idea of that uh because we like to give
back to the homies in there who like to
support us so
yeah
for your following and the people that
follow you are really ultimately going
to be the people that truly support you
want to see you doing better and push
you to be better
yeah i'm telling you guys it is so much
better going slow and building up your
community with those people that you
really vibe with because in the end
you're going to be a lot happier than
having you know 10 i've seen a million
videos
uh from creator friends of mine
that said the worst thing that ever
happened to me was a video going viral
well why is that because if your video
goes viral everybody knows you for that
one video and they're all following you
but it's not people that are interested
in you they just like that video
right one thing not all of your content
yeah you get this huge influx and
followers and then they're not liking
your content they're not sharing they
don't give a [ __ ] so you're ultimately
doing yourself a disservice because a
bunch of people are leaning to seeing
your stuff and yeah whatever i like to
call them uh nameless numbers you never
get to know their name but they're just
a number exactly so it's really
important to get those people that you
know you're vibing with and that you
have that and you guys are [ __ ]
awesome i can already tell i'm gonna get
along great with you and we're
definitely gonna have to do more of
these episodes oh for sure dude i've
wanted like you're in washington so i
would like to have like a live like
together episode like we go over there
you can come over here whatever but yeah
like there's no reason we have another
microphone right we have another
microphone we can bring all three of
them like it don't matter yeah
right on man so you guys are you
monetizing on uh patreon at all
yeah yeah a little bit we have like what
our five dollar slots
uh that used to be three like we're not
yeah we did we did we had a few packs
from our homie pinoy poi we did an
episode with him um he sent over a big
old care package uh one each for me and
josh and then some extras just to do
whatever we wanted to do with giveaway
anything like that so we decided that we
would put it on for our patreon
you know as like an incentive to you get
some like legendary seats for three
dollars so it was just a no-brainer it's
like
um incentive
and
then uh 420 rolled around and we had
some we hadn't met our we had 10 packs
to give away we got to about seven so we
had three left to give away so we did
that on 420 it was just kind of like a
blessing the people kind of thing
and um
so then we just moved our tier to
uh
tier to tier two which we still have uh
free seeds on there too
some sweet tea seeds
from we got a pack of sub cool we got a
couple miles out of it we did ourselves
a breeding project with those
and they have
a decent amount of variability in there
but there's still like a pretty
pretty
small gap of different phenotypes that
you can get out of there and there's
been a couple people who have ran them
here and there as well um
if you wanted to i haven't grown any
myself
so
um i just kind of gave them out to some
people and they grew them so but that's
on our on our tier now and then we also
produce some extra content on our
patreon
um
just for like the uh we go over very
specific topics yeah um it's more geared
toward like a new grower right like
trying to put them on a game a very
educational it's like a 20 30 minute
like hard focus on like ipm or
ph or you know soil types or
you know
and these are patreon exclusive
podcast episodes awesome very cool
well i appreciate you guys coming on and
taking your time to join me for this
smoke session it was absolutely awesome
thanks for having me congratulations on
being my very first video guest dude it
feels good
you should keep doing these for sure
this was cool i feel like people are
gonna like it and you're hella dope man
yeah i've had fun on both the podcasts
we've been on with each other now and
you should definitely keep doing the
thing i will listen good energy man
absolutely if you guys aren't already go
follow them go check out their discord
go check them out you guys are on
youtube you're on spotify stitcher
everywhere pretty much pretty much
everywhere smoking with podcast one of
the two podcasts that i actually listen
to
all right i'll catch you guys later
[Music]
i am