[Music]
C
what's up everybody and welcome to a
brand new episode of the CX and crew
podcast I'm your host as always doc CX
and I've got two very special people
with me today I've got Janelle and Corey
Le plant of Tastefully baked how are you
guys doing today good good how are you
good all the way from Portland Maine
these guys make art in edible form it's
amazing they sent us a bunch of stuff to
try that we will be trying out during
the episode but before we get into all
that you want to know a little bit more
about you guys why don't you tell us how
you first each individually CU I'm sure
it was a different a different story but
each individually how you guys first got
introduced to cannabis yeah so um
basically I started in high school to
replace my Aderall um like a lot of my
friends did just to trade it for weed
and um yeah it's basically
self-medicate mainly because everybody
didn't want me to and it and it helped
made me hungry so um yeah from there um
I went off and learned how to weld and
hated it um so then I decided to go surf
in Hawaii and figure out what I was
going to do met a guy who actually was
up your way um you know grown in a
warehouse and ended up getting out of it
and moved to Hawaii and sold all his
stuff so he kind of you know planted the
seed in my head um ended up going back
East um you know trying to figure out
how to grow uh ran into you know a
couple people up North Carolina
Mountains that you know really taught me
some things and then um that's kind of
when yeah we kind connected your life I
had never consumed cannabis it was
completely foreign concept really to me
at that point in time I think it was
what like 19 yeah so then I went down
for a trip to visit him because we had
started dating at the time and I was
still living in New Hampshire
and yeah kind of just
was I'm trying to even like think of how
I want want to describe it but it was
just kind of went down there and he had
had something that he had to tell me
before I kind of went into the house had
no idea because I had no idea about any
of this yeah so you know you figure you
like fly down spend a whole you know day
and then all of a sudden you get there
and he's just like so before you go into
my house there's something I think um
you should know and I'm like okay what
he's like well I have some you know some
plants upstairs in the you know in the
spare bedroom I'm like okay
that's cool I don't care and then I say
that was probably my first time ever
consuming weed was uh during that trip
down there y yep hit up basically every
grocery store that had the free little
samples for you to go ahead and grab
food so what was your first experience
with did you guys just smoke a join
or um I think we were smoking bongs
actually I think it was yeah it was what
Northern Light blueberry cross if I
remember correctly got me the cut of
that one damn shout out to
CAD yeah when you were replacing your
Aderall with it you didn't like how the
Aderall was treating you and you were
getting more relief with the Cannabis
yeah I basically just took my took my
appetite and stuff away and I was super
skinny I weighed like 115 pounds when I
graduated high school didn't make didn't
you know I just couldn't stand it hated
the way it made me feel hated coming
down off it so yeah I started uh just
smoking weed and everybody's like oh
he's doing great a little I know I just
wasn't taking my medicine and
um yeah I mean it obviously worked for
you right yeah how did that growing for
yourself growing at your house uh you
guys meeting and how' that turn into
Tastefully baked where did the idea for
Tastefully Baked come from the idea for
Tastefully baked came from when we ended
up yeah we moved to Maine after we got
in a little bit of trouble in New
Hampshire um and then yeah we kind of
needed something you know to call our
Creations we knew we wanted to get back
into cannabis after the ordeal that we
went through in New Hampshire was more
so just trying to figure out like
logistically how you're going to you
know make that move make that jump um
happen let's cover that really quick
what happened over in New Hampshire for
everybody that doesn't
know in what
2000 2013
2013 we
were in inded on a bunch of charges for
cultivating and what they distribute to
distribute to distribute uh cannabis so
we were raided by the drug task force
went through the whole entire ordeal
that is New Hampshire is very stri
prosecuted it it was it was a big deal
it was all over the papers um all in the
news we were you know going to court
every week we had you know High bail and
stuff like that so we were basically
looking at spending the rest of our
adult lives and and State prison and
then go into federal prison for some
guns that we had at the house um on
weapons charges after that so it was
either fight the whole thing um or take
a plea and just you know take 10 years
and go go take a long uh trip away so we
decided to fight it got you know got a
really good attorney and we ended up uh
proving that they lied to the judge to
get the search warrant which made them
have to throw out all the evidence so
took about a year to fight quite a bit
of stress
um you know lot of money lots of stress
lots of money lots money
really on the judicial system yeah we
had to cancel our wedding it was it was
it was hard on our families I that was
probably the hardest thing was putting
my mom and dad through it yeah that was
the worst her her family that that was
the hardest part
um a
lot want to do that again so we figured
out you know we're going to go do it the
right way as as best as you can don't
don't upset the mother-in-law
exactly we got we got the DEA don't
worry about that but not the
Mother-in-law exactly that's awesome so
you guys went from your indictment there
and fighting that into going up to
Portland Maine creating Tastefully baked
I know you guys have a lot more products
than what you sent me but I just want to
show them off to people really
quick I believe uh I believe Janelle's
drinking one too
right now but you have these amazing ju
Juiced infusions and they're 50 migrs a
piece right yeah how do you guys go
about infusing a drink like that I've
been wanting to talk to in Edibles
expert for a very long time about this
I've had infused seltzers before but
coming from a homeg grow perspective
where we make a lot of cookies and
brownies and gummies and like you know
simple to make stuff at home uh the
concept of infused Seltzer is something
I can't even fathom how do you guys go
about that process so for like
background um our company we do
cultivation we do extraction and we also
obviously make our own cannabis infused
products um we like to have hands kind
of on into everything that goes into our
product so we can make sure that
everything is up to to our caliber um so
it really all starts obviously in the
garden
and then it heads over to my husband and
he does the extraction
um so yeah basically for the celer we do
um we take like a full spectrum extract
and then we strip everything out of it
except for the THC so we basically do
like a full chromatography column scrub
on it and take it so it's completely
flavorless um and then we homogenize it
at a really really really high RPM yeah
there's a certain um I guess I would say
certain recipe that I've figured out
over the past probably what did probably
nine months of yeah nine months R&amp;D
research to try and create something
that would be water soluble so there was
that whole back end and then kind of
once I figured out the recipe for it we
just kind of um ran with it the main
reason why we personally have decided to
take out basically everything that could
taste like vegetative growth or any sort
of Flav Flor that resembles that of the
cannabis plant it's just I personally
don't like to consume Edibles that taste
like cannabis if I wanted that then I
would have like a juice or something
else but this is for more so for the
palette that doesn't want it to taste
like cannabis gotcha yeah it depends I
think there's some things that it pairs
well with and then there's a lot of
things that it just tastes like weedy on
top of whatever you got you know so
there's a time and place I think for
everything um from my personal
perspective of just doing Edibles and
food infusions over the years so you're
saying after you extract all the
thca uh that in itself is water
soluble the thca is not you have to
break it down basically into Nano
particles um okay and then yeah then you
mix it with a carrier you basically have
to homogenize it into an intermediary
liquid that gets mixed into you know the
bright tank basically a brewery style
tank like a big
tank um then it gets carbonated um goes
through the can every we can and then it
has to go back to the lab um for for lab
testing like I mentioned earlier you
guys have the passion orange guava and
you sent me a lemonade too is that the
only two flavors or is there more than
that they have a sour blue Ras as well
and a tropical punch and then we have
something else we're kind of working on
behind the scenes that we'll hopefully
be ready in the next
3 to six months damn you guys hear that
all new flavors coming out you said blue
raspberry and now yeah I think I got to
put in we got to make a main trip here
pretty soon it's a beautiful place to
come to in the fall you if you guys want
to you guys can go over to their IG it's
Tastefully baked at Tastefully baked on
IG at Tastefully baked
2. at Tastefully baked 2.0 you can see
videos of them actually creating some of
these things but they have and I'm going
to [ __ ] up this saying again calam Moni
cheesecake confection
[Music]
bar whole world alls for the Tak
bringing home theed BAC got the good
good
[Music]
good yes spe right now like yeah that
one and these are 100 milligrams a
piece has a QR code on it if I hit that
QR code what's going to pop
up that'll take you to the website and
then if you scroll down towards the
bottom of the website we have a
certificate of analysis for that
particular product I would love to know
where you guys' dose is 100 milligrams
is like I don't know if I don't do
enough edibl but that's a top for me and
I smoke all day every day but 100
milligrams really gets me there where
are you guys at I'm about 50 we'll
generally split one of those y it's
pretty it's relatively Rich so we'll
we'll generally split it but yeah our
Market here as far as Edibles and
infusions is high dose very high
dose that's what I was going to get into
with that
[Laughter]
bar one of these what goes into making
this how much much time does it actually
take to make a camasi cheesecake but
those are definitely a labor of love and
more so a passion uh project at the end
of the day I do them
because I really just enjoy trying to
create a flavorful experience with
cannabis um so that consists of three
different layers the first layer that
you have is the calaman pat toi so a
calaman is a mixture of between like an
orange and a lime and they're
predominantly grown in like really
tropical climate so I think the
Philippines is a very common place where
you can find them so you have to make
that layer lay it all out let it sit
overnight then the following day you
need to frame out your next layer to put
on top so for this one is a white
chocolate cheesecake
ganache which is absolutely delicious so
then you throw that on
top and then you need to wait again for
the following day basically and then I
finished it off with a graham cracker
cheesecake ganache so most of the
ingredients that we source to I try and
find either anything local as far as
local agriculture we have a lot of local
dairy farms um local or organic is
really where where our focus is at the
end of the day all the chocolate that we
use um is sourc from companies that
don't use child slave labor for their
caca heart harvesting so once you go
down that rabbit hole it really wants to
you know make you stay straight on your
morals once you start learning all the
nitty-gritty about the chocolate
industry so that's really also kind of
our thought process behind everything
that we try and create we try and be
conscious of the various um places that
we Source our ingredients then the you
have to wait till the following day back
to making this so then the following day
is when we end up actually cutting it
and then we let it again sit out until
till the following day it gets an
enrobed drizzled and then we need to
wait for the test results to come in for
us to package it up and have it to over
to the patients so is everything on that
bar infused or is it a simple part of it
that is I have figured out more so which
um parts of the recipe are easier for me
to infuse to keep the dose
accurate easiest way to keep the dosage
accurate throughout everything so on
that bar in particular is the
pad to that's infused which some people
I found out who are like you know gluten
intolerant they're like okay I'll just
have as long as I know the pieces that
I'm eating that are infused I'll just
leave at the gram cracker so that's kind
of funny too now this thing is 100
gr Chocolate Bar says milk chocolate
1,500 migr per
bar that's ridiculous guys like the
other thing other part of our
demographic too is also you know the the
health conscious part that wants a high
dose but doesn't want to consume a bunch
of sugar and a bunch of chocolate or you
have the people with a very high
tolerance those are kind of like you
know the two patients that where we have
in mind when we create something like
that fair enough fair enough I I've just
you know when I get into a chocolate bar
I'm not going to stop at the first
couple bites
so I feel like that for me would be an
Allin or allout thing but, 1500
milligrams I don't know if I could do
that oh
yeah oh we should definitely ask him
about that Panda says I'm at over
9,000 wow so and I've heard about this
before people that don't process Edibles
the same way that other people do is
that something that you guys have
experienced not personally but with
various you know stories from patients
most
definitely it's funny I've heard from a
lot you know a lot of people who are
super heavy concentrate consumers smoke
flour all day long they have five
milligrams of exactly like no way yeah
but and that's the thing I do I will dab
and you know flower all day type of guy
I do I appreciate flower more but I take
dabs more throughout the day just
because I'm so busy all the time and
it's very convenient to be in and out
and done you know or take an edible and
let that ride out for sure but still
with that tolerance level 100 milligram
drink will just I think the last time I
did 100 milligram drink I was on a hay
ride about Halloween time and I was just
spacing out on every animal that we went
by it was horrible I mean it wasn't
horrible it was amazing but you know it
was
unexpected with your infusions on the
chocolate bars are these I've seen some
on your page that you break open they're
like car Ral
fil is that what this is or is it just
strictly a regular chocolate bar that is
just a solid piece of chocolate okay so
you guys have a few different options
when it comes to your chocolate bars
then we do a lot of uh limited kind of
releases it allows us to be creative
with things that are in season it allows
us to do you know stuff out of the
necessary production Norm so we get to
use you know our brains a little bit
more than just trying to be cogs in a
you know a machine yeah really keep it
engaging and interesting for us and so
that way there we're always expanding
and you know who knows what kind of
flavors you may bring together that you
know I got to say I I think we all
really appreciate that you guys are
sourcing local you're locally minded
you're uh very well in tune with what
you're putting into there and how you're
doing your dosages that's pretty amazing
and it shows that you care about your
clients tell base for
sure I not eating the whole [ __ ]
thing dank no way it's not going to
happen I will not be able to do the rest
of the episode I'll tell you what I am
going to take a bite of this bar though
I got to see what Tastefully baked is
all about cheers
[Applause]
guys I was expecting it to be thicker
harder shut up
guys look at
this
Wow might hit your pallette
first it's hard to say what hit
first wow oh my God that is amazing you
guys that probably one of the best
edibles I've ever had no [ __ ] thank you
thank you I appreciate that
wow the chocolate kind of coats your
tongue right off the bat just because
it's there but that the Citrus just kind
of cuts through all of it totally
different than anything and it all mixes
and combines very well and then right at
the end even though you got the texture
of it the flavor of the gram cracker
really like follows everything up holy
[ __ ] I love cheesecake that's amazing
that's dangerous that's dangerous it is
all of this is dangerous I need to wash
it down now I'm not going to do it with
that drink because I think need rest
that
bar so let me ask you guys really
quick from the all the pleasure that you
guys get from doing this what's your
favorite part of
it I think the emails from the patients
honestly for me
personally that yeah that's a that's a
huge say I mean there's nothing like
opening up you know your inbox or your
DMs and having messages from patients
that are super excited either you know
wanting to know where to get your stuff
or giving you a compliment about
something that you've made it really
like that makes it all worth it that
makes everything you know that we went
through in the past and just the you
know the stress and the hassle of of
running a small business it that's over
regulated business yeah it's very over
regulated business um that makes it all
worth it at the end of the day no peer
pressure guys come on like I've got [ __ ]
to do later I'm a busy man I want to be
it is hard to eat just part of that I
will say showing great
restraint out of all
the pieces of art that you guys do
through your culinary work which seems
to be the most
popular I feel like there's the are
Staples but then the patients really get
excited for whatever New Creation we're
going to make next like they're always
anticipating that so they kind of have
our Staples to keep them
occupied while we're over here trying to
figure out what we're going to concoct
for like the next tasting experience so
you guys are constantly creating new
things yes that's awesome that's really
cool can can we get any insight about
something that might be coming up
here I mean we like we have our like
conf ction bar line like you have we've
kind of themed that so we'll do like
different drops different flavor
combinations throughout the season
depending upon what it is um Christmas a
Christmas staple for us is like a bon
bon five piece variety um assortment of
whatever we come up with Valentine's Day
again for us is like another huge bon
bon um event because everyone likes to
gift each other chocolate of course for
Valentine's Day so we tend to more so
stick with like the certain you know
themed items but really change up the
flavors depending upon either what you
know inspired us or whatever maybe in
season or some sort of holiday flavor it
really
varies would it be fair to say that you
guys favorite consumption method is
Edibles I like flour personally I smoke
flour most of the day
um I find edes are a great like
nighttime thing they're they're great if
you want a wonderful seamless night
sleep to not be interrupted by anything
or anyone but as far as for like daytime
consumption for me flowers where it's
at definitely a flower guy too I think
most people in chat will agree oh I see
cad popping up just want to hug them
they've done so well yeah definitely and
your packaging is off the chart guys
like it really pops so and we've talked
about this many times before there's
companies that make kind of of an
inferior product and I'm not going to
say who cookies uh I'm not going to say
who but they throw it in a package that
pops and it's basically like putting
makeup on a pig there's nothing behind
it what you guys have done there's
definitely an incredible product inside
of that case and it's wrapped in a
beautiful rapper so this something that
you guys can expect you can go over to
Tastefully baked.com and see all their
products what else do you guys have on
there that's uh staple if you will
besides chocolate bars drinks and uh
these probably I would say probably our
Vape cards would be our next next in
line we do like offer Vape card like a
cured res like a cured resin um it's
like a low ohm more like a nicotine
style Vape that like blows a bigger
Cloud it's higher voltage type of deal
oh right those are super popular let me
ask Corey first uh Corey if I had to ask
you top three strains of all time what
would you
say um we had this discussion the other
day a little bit that's kind of funny
probably number one would be
headband
um probably number two would be one that
we just got from the guys over at DNA
recently which is a GMO kosher Kos cross
um really almost smells like a skunky
kind of like Thanksgiving dinner it's
really weird um definitely have to be
into like some weird weird TPS to like
it
um but it's one of those things that
people just get really obsessed with
once they actually smell it really kind
of a skunky background but definitely
some Thanksgiving Vibes
um and then maybe like the original
gorilla go I like really gassy stuff um
really offensive kind of TPS for me
personally going to say I'm seeing a
pattern here
yeah yeah I Vibe with that I love a
little bit of everything but I am more
into the accurate stuff for sure yeah so
Janelle how about you what would be your
top three o I'd go
cheese that's just I don't know to me
that's a it's a classic I I just the
perfect kind of go-to smoke of the
day then I would probably go with what
do we have LA LA Confidential yeah la la
woman we had LA
Woman way back and that just took you on
an
interesting borderline scary borderline
borderline kind of psychedelic
experience so that really yeah that was
a really really good one yeah yep
somebody in chat would you look up the
lineage on that one really quick LA
Confidential oh they right now with I
can't
remember I can't remember for the life
of me and and then I
say our headband that we had so how was
it
psychedelic it just kind of put you in
this made you really think different
sort of way I can't even like your brain
was
just in a
pulsating
distorted and it made your top three
though
yeah yeah I love it I love that Martian
mean green is the other one Martian mean
green and LA Confidential it's from DNA
genetics again okay right on so are you
guys over there in main are you able
to uh both process and produce mhm so
you guys can grow your own medicine for
your own Edibles yep yep we do we're
vertically integrated besides sales but
yes that is awesome so what's in The
Grove room right
now right now we have we just popped a
bunch of cheese Gorilla Glue crosses
from expert
seeds um we have what Super Lemon Haze
from Greenhouse the old school one GMO
kosher we have a banana OG crossed with
Tangi double stuff
sorbet cantaloup Haze I think I said can
I think I think that's that rounds them
out for right oh and a cherry pie yeah
cherry pie cherry pie is there one covar
that makes it IND your Edibles more than
others
um we have a smaller Garden so we kind
of cycle through streams we'll run them
for a little while and then we'll kind
of we're always kind of feno hunting
something different and then always
cycling stuff out okay so whatever that
run produce that's what's going on as
long as we find something better we'll
retire what isn't quite as good and
we'll keep a keep a few going and we'll
just kind of have a competition for for
Real Estate so what do you think is the
future of Tastefully bake do you guys
have like a 10-year goal what would you
like to see Tastefully B become how can
we progress more from where it is right
now um I mean a lot of a lot of that
stuff's can you can have a vision it's
just always a little bit hard to make
it to know I guess how the legal path is
going to pave its way over the next 10
years that makes that's probably the
most challenging thing about planning a
growth for a cannabis business and
trying to kind of figure out how you
want to go about it if you're to you
know expand Beyond state lines are you
going to want to do it in you know the
MSO type method or you going to want to
do it more in like a multi-state brand
type way and I think that's super
individual um for everyone depending
upon whatever workload or whatever
they're kind of deciding to invest but I
think um really just focusing
on creating things to
be I mean in the future I I see us more
so pivoting towards honestly a
greenhouse model um than the way that we
currently have things set up but again
that takes you know time for brand to
grow and there's a lot of Old Farms we
want to grab an Old Farm and like you
know have a have a greenhouse and then
do some outdoor stuff um and kind of
have some food production along with it
so we can do a small CSA for our
patients and stuff like that like to
incorporate a lot more just just regular
agriculture as well um we're really
passionate about high quality uh food
and what we put into our systems I think
a lot of people who consume cannabis are
also very conscious of other things and
what they consume so to really kind of
tie more of the philosophy together um
is what I see us
doing that's amazing guys I I really
respect that like crazy um next time I
go up there I'm definitely going to have
to come check you guys out I I am a West
coaster to a te I have not spent that
much time on the East Coast I was over
in Boston I didn't realize that was like
an less than two hours away from you
guys so next time I'm over that way I'll
definitely have to meet up with you guys
check out what you're doing I would
definitely love to uh you come on very
high honors from cadie we talked about
before you guys met over in North
Carolina uh you know I think everybody
wants to hear about it because everybody
knows croad and now we're getting to
meet you guys how' you guys get to know
each
other um so we were working at app ski
mountain in the ski shop together and a
mutual friend that I was talking to um
about growing weed was like Hey if you
got any questions this is the guy to
talk to um yeah we struck it up did some
partying and um he gave me a bunch of
tips got got some stuff going and we've
just been in touch ever since I mean
we've gone down there a couple times to
visit throughout the years too it's just
oh yeah hell yeah CAD coming through
with the with the Cannabis help all
right we got a bunch of quick fire
questions here from our uh our patreon
members let's dig into them really quick
fanda says do you make a Christmas
Advent calendar we don't that is a great
idea though a great idea it is a yeah
it's a fantastic idea we actually had a
few patients request one really so
that's been of that yet but I mean I
would get one for sure that would be a
rough month
man well you the edible you just you
know eat it before you go to bed well
after dinner all right Taco says what is
one of your favorite Edibles that you
use but don't
sell I don't think there is anyone that
we really I
mean there's nothing that I ever make
that's specifically for our line I would
say is kind of our lifestyle in a sense
we kind of what we'd like we make and we
won't sell anything that we wouldn't
personally want to buy or have so we've
kind of let me ask in this perspective
is there another company that makes
Edibles that you're like I would buy
theirs
honestly she won't need anybody else's
Edibles at this point
um
just uh steel says how do you feel about
edi's packaging that seems to resemble a
lot of the candy on the market for
example the nerd ropes and things like
that I mean teach their own do whatever
is on brand for for you for me that for
us that's not that's not our image
that's
not the the type of product that we're
trying to put out or
portray um I could never like put out a
Nerds Rope just it's just not our style
so but as I said to each their
own okay out of regular just like
everyday food is there something that we
can expect to never have from Tastefully
baked because you guys don't appreciate
it is there like a type of food that
each one of you just absolutely I will
not eat
that um for me it's walnuts I [ __ ] I
hate walnuts you don't like walnuts we
do stay away from nuts in our facility
that's the other big thing we do have a
few patients that I know that are you
know really sensitive to nuts and it's
something that I'm conscious of that a
lot of people don't eat certain things
because there's Edibles that are
produced in a facility that does with
nuts so I will say that if if I were to
draw a line somewhere on stuff it would
be
nuts are you just in Maine or are you in
other states of
Taco we are just in Maine just in Maine
right now yes do you guys have a
storefront where you can get edibles too
or is everything online so everything is
available we have so how it's set up
here is we have um we're the distributor
and we have various other storefront in
which we distribute our products too
okay so you guys grow you process and
then you have retail stores well we
probably have about 15 partner stores
around the state that sell our
products so other
than Edibles and vape carts is there
anything else you guys are
producing um well we have our flower
yeah
um our rendition of a gummy which is you
know
kind of a I wouldn't say healthy version
but a a more conscious version of a of
candy can you all consider making some
AA fresa flavors for example a horchata
drink I agree with that one I agree with
that one Steele I'm all about the
horchata I will look into it uh Big Bad
John says best home
recipe what would be something that you
guys would recommend for medical
patients we use uh we Infuse local honey
and then a lot of people like to make
tea with it um which is makes a really
good evening thing or there's a couple
recipes that I have up on our website
that mainly utilize honey and I think
honey is a great Universal ingredient
that people can apply to any dish really
and voila you have a cannabis infused
meal but there's a really good one up
there too for brussels sprouts with our
honey and a balsamic glazed drizzle with
some toasted pine nuts it's really good
it's really good
I know a lot of people don't like
brussels sprouts I'm a brussel freak I
love them but pan Fred nice
crispiness you can't go wrong I'm all
about that one so you guys can can go
over to Tastefully bake.com and check
out these infusions for yourself how are
you infusing the
honey the honey yeah everything that we
do is through a mechanical
homogenization oh okay so what it does
is it breaks everything down into really
small particles um so to make sure that
it's evenly homogeneous throughout the
entire product so you know it's
basically like a big metal cutting head
with another cutting head on the inside
that spins at like 40,000 RPMs and just
basically smashes everything apart at a
molecular level yeah to really
solubilize it yeah correct wow yeah uh
Big Bad John says you guys need to do a
cookbook that is a great idea that's
been another thing that's been on
on the back burner for a bit um but yeah
I think there's a you know it's fun to
be able to kind of take your dosage or
whatever into your own hands and kind of
make your own things at home that you
can serve for guests we definitely have
a some patients that do that as well so
they'll come back and then they'll tell
us what they made with you know one of
our
ingredients I I will give you guys a
good review after this I'm already it's
starting to hit me me right now if you
can't tell very light body floating
feeling not too intense definitely worth
it absolutely but I think I'm not going
to eat the other half of that yet
because I do got to drive
later so I will ask that question for
you Taco but I'm going to reiterate it a
little bit more uh he always wants to
know and honestly I need to start making
this a staple because it's a fun
conversation topic to have with people
all over the world uh we do another show
we do a few different shows uh my
production company itself does the
Washington weed review we do the cxy
podcast here uh with sessions and meet
the Breeders and we do another one
that's just kind of fun to get stoned on
if you guys are into conspiracy theories
and just like shooting the [ __ ] about
that that's something we do as well
everybody wants to know from all my
guests what are you guys' thoughts is
there aliens out there or
not I think there's aliens out there
until the government says they are and
then I think there's other aliens out
there that the government's trying to
hide from
us I want to get that have you guys ever
had a paranormal
experience never but where so in New
Hampshire up near what the lon Mountain
Exit there's a certain gas station and
in the bathroom in the gas station all
over the walls there are a bunch of
newspaper clippings of stories of like
UFO activity in that area over the past
I don't know how many hundreds of years
type of
thing okay guys you guys have like five
more minutes uh if you have any more
questions get them in there really quick
um so if I stuck you guys out on a
desert
island I said you can only take one you
can take a lifetime supply but you can
only take one of your Edibles with you
for the rest of your
life you gonna
take I'd probably take the selers
personally
you take the saler I think so
Island yeah
well if you yeah it's an island Vibe
plus you get to have something to
drink I mean that's the most important
part the first she
show yeah that's fair enough that's fair
enough but they are 50 milligrams a
piece they are I'm sure after a while
after a year on the island you're just
going to be numb to
it be all right I'm hydrated and I'm
used to
it I'd hate to be the guy that had to
pick you up from that after a couple
years all
right we have seen some [ __ ] together it
sounds like I definitely know your story
Cad and I've heard theirs now that's
pretty cool that you guys have a working
relationship like that for as long as
you have and gone through the [ __ ] that
you have for sure um I I know that's no
fun I know I got it a lot easier than
most people I can't imagine what you
guys had to go through but I got to say
not only do I greatly respect both of
you uh for having gone through all that
still put all your love and passion for
the plant into what you're doing now uh
but having standards and morals of We
Care what's going into our food we care
about putting the best products into
what we're
creating and making it something that's
going to not only be enjoyable imp
palatable uh but amazing and new and
coming up with New Creations all the
time to meet the needs of these patients
and putting people before you know
anything else I really really respect
that and I want to thank you guys uh for
taking your time out of your day to come
join us and talk to us about Tastefully
baked yeah thanks for having us we
appreciate the kind words we got a
couple more questions really quick
before we bounce out of here Steele says
I want to ask her if she uses less ofan
to emulsify her drink drinks do you guys
use Le leian in
anything we use not
B sunflower lean it's a carrier a lot
lot of home that's how the to comes as
far as being
manufactured but no we don't add lein to
anything oh and that one comes from
Miranda thank you
Miranda all right guys thank you so much
for taking time out your day again uh to
join me and do this it's been an amazing
episode you both are amazing people um I
definitely look forward to reviewing
these on our other show the Washington
weed review where we're going to get
royally [ __ ] up on A500 Mig bar some
drinks uh you guys can go over to
Tastefully baked 2.0 on Instagram and go
check them out you can see their
processes see how they go about making
some of these Edibles even that
cheesecake bar that I just had they just
put up a video of that absolutely
amazing it's like watching a cooking
show if you guys want to check out some
of their products they are available up
in Portland Maine and you can check them
out at Tastefully
baked.com thank you guys again till next
time this has been doc calex with the c
and crew podcast saying good night
[Music]
rightow come
on I see it baby
I know you're on the
[Music]
road Sweet
py let's take it real
[Music]
soon you know we got what you need baby
take it move
along I said we got what you need hone
come
and come
on
roing on the
[Music]
highway
come