my first guest is Garrett Bain from Jean
Khanna hey Garrett yeah nice to see you
again
I had a we already had a panel in
barthelona and Garrett is a cannabis a
hemp farmer from Kentucky from Kentucky
USA and you are chief sales officer of
chincana and you have 15 years of
experience in marketing technology sales
and management um you have been in
business segments across multiple
customer channels with proven record of
exceeding multi-million dollar goals
with while expanding new businesses
lines and profile opportunities is that
right I don't know who sent that but yes
and when it comes to regulation and
we're talking when it comes to cannabis
regulation and we talk in frameworks
regular regular regulatory frameworks
we're talking about a lot of frameworks
keywords em are a GMP GP PJ APC novel
food regulation and so on and so on
you're producing hemp in Kentucky the
USA does not yet have a similar
regulation framework like Canada or the
European community has is that right and
in which way does that affect your
especially your international business
connections sure so currently the
foundation of the US market started with
some legislation around hemp farming as
a as a crop right and that's what we see
today under the US under the farm bill
that recently passed legalizing hemp as
a as a crop in the United States
federally now you still have
state-by-state considerations and state
by state legislation that needs to
potentially align certain states with
the federal legislation some states have
done a really good job of that Kentucky
being one of them that's why we're there
so they have done a great job of putting
into putting a framework together with
the state that complements the federal
legislation which is enabled a very
successful hemp program and I believe
the model that will be rolled out across
the entire United States at some point
as as the Layton states the states that
have not come on so quickly realize the
economic opportunity for the farmers and
for the rest of the tangent businesses
are not developing as quickly in their
states they're gonna look to other
states that have been successful and
copy that model so I think from a
legislative perspective the US has done
a good job of paving the way for the
crop as an agricultural commodity what
we're waiting on is the FDA to weigh in
on what is hemp derived CBD and
cannabinoids is it a food is it as
nutritional supplement or is it a drug
right or pharmaceutical and there is a
meeting at the end of May the FDA is
hosting a public comment and Gymkhana
will be participating as well as the USF
Browne table to provide public comment
on you know where this fits into the
economy how it helps farmers and and
folks that are using it in the community
so the FDA we're hoping goes back
considers these facts and comes back
with guidance that clearly defines and
we're looking for structure we're not we
don't believe it's about safety in the
end right food safety supplement safety
and drug safety so we don't believe that
we're not just asking for carp lunch
we're saying come back with a reasonable
framework that we can implement on
labels right nutrition fact panels
ingredient fact panels and and something
we can actually put into into our
business plans as we build and get into
mass market retail how important el is
the compliance of your framework with
other frameworks international framework
a lot of national frameworks sure so
we've spent a considerable amount of
effort and resources in creating a
compliant and accredited manufacturing
and processing framework from cGMP BRC
was known as British Retail Consortium
one point it's a very high level of
audit scheme for food great standards
internationally so we've we've gone
after all of these accreditation Xand
audits in order to create a platform to
launch quality safe products this
industry has been plagued by a trust
issue with consumers right there hasn't
been a lot of trust between consumers
and where that product came from you
know where was it grown how is it
manufactured it's kind of been a gray
market right and I think it's time that
folks in this injury's industry rise up
and create standards and adhere to
global standards of manufacturing that
will create trust with consumers and
take this industry from being a gray
market industry into being a global
market industry thank you very much
Garrett so let me introduce to you dr.
Francis as Callum he found these the CEO
of cloud nine is OTC pharmaceuticals and
also the founder of cloud mind LC LLC
rotc Pharmaceuticals established in
Switzerland in July 2017 and has
subsidiaries in Jamaica and France
besides he's a member of the
International Association for cannibal
cannibal need medicines which makes him
an expert on both fields on the one side
on the economic field on the on the
other side on the medical field so my
first question to you recently
irregularly the the framework is about
medicine and about product
what would you say needs to be needs to
be implemented faster on international
level the regulation for medical
international regulations for medical
for cannabis medicines are regulations
for cannabis products on international
level
good morning everybody just to qualify
what Mika just said we were a company
that do two things were very active in
the in the field of edibles and our
first products we launched in January of
this year in Germany which is a Swiss
chocolate containing the cannabis
extract and we're active in the area of
pharmaceuticals as well but
Pharmaceuticals is more our medium
longer-term business plan we already
have two products that are ready one is
for the treatment of glaucoma and the
other one is for bronchial disorders
asthma particularly I thought you were
actually gonna ask me about novel foods
good question because we have to do some
more types because and I know you're the
expert the medical front in a way is
somewhat more advanced than the food
area at the moment particularly since
you you probably all know that the the
w-h-o came out last year the the expert
committee on drugs a dependence came up
with recommendations about rescheduling
cannabis from scheduled for completely
delisting it and also delisting cannabis
extracts from schedule one which
actually also gives hope to a lot of the
CBD players in the world because if it's
off that then that supposedly can open
up some opportunities for the CBD market
things are moving on the under medical
front because in January of this year in
the EU a group of em EPS that put a
motion for resolution to the European
Commission that was adopted under 17th
of February for the medical use the
harmonization of the medical use of
cannabis medicines in the EU and also to
encourage and promote research in the EU
for medicine purposes so that's that's
moving ahead quite nicely and don't
forget in the background you also have
GW Pharmaceuticals who applied for
approval for epidural X in the EU market
- so that's spending and we expect
something
to come in the next couple of months
regarding that so it's the medical side
is moving quite quite nicely ahead in
the EU market the food side is in a bit
of a chaos at the moment a chaos because
since January of this year you know
everyone's been talking about novel
foods this morning up until 2018 it was
already very complicated and in
fragmented in terms of the
interpretation in different countries in
the EU it got worse in January because
the European Commission decided to try
and clarify things I think it was in an
effort to clarify and they made some
amendments to what's called a novel
foods catalog so if you go on the
internet you type in novel foods
catalogue EU pop up a page and you can
search in there and you can put in
cannabis and today there will be three
references that will come up three
entries one is about the plant cannabis
sativa L which is not a novel food then
there's cannabinoids and then there's
kind of BD all candy BD all has has a
red mark against it and cannabinoids has
a red mark against it - they are at the
moment up for novel food status let's
say put it that way
so it's another thing you need to
understand that the catalogue itself
different from the regulation because
there is an actual ratio let me ask let
me let me ask you regulation a small
question in betweens Lise just for the
better understanding so cannabis sativa
L is also listed sure it's in the it's
in it's in the catalogue and it's not a
novel food planet so if if the THC level
is in compliance you could put a
cannabis sativa L sure in the food here
without oh sure and don't forget
cannabis sativa has been consumed in the
European market for centuries the year
the European industrial hemp Association
met with the working group it's called a
p.m. it's called let me see now it's got
a funny name plants animals food and
feed that's the name of it in it's a
working group that
Commission defer to for determining
whether a substance is considered novel
food or not so the European industrial
hemp Association met with that committee
in on the 12th of March showed shared
with them basically the usage the
consumption even industrial quantities
of hemp products hemp extracts in the EU
going back to 1220 in Bologna if it's
it's it's nothing new and you know
Mikael mozi man
I completely agree what he was saying
it's nothing though yeah so what you
actually say is that if you use the term
cannabis sativa L instead of curs
cannabidiol you can stock up ship so the
regulation so you need to understand
your regulations you need to understand
what type of ingredients you're using
what is allowed and what's not allowed
you need to understand the regulation or
novel foods read it carefully because it
is clear actually it is clear it's a big
document but it is clear you need to
understand processing conditions you
need to understand labeling because
currently today's CBD on a product is
not compliant and the reason it's not
compliant and the reason why a lot of
countries in the EU such as Austria
Italy Germany most recently have been
marching in with police and removing
products from the shelves and finding
people and arresting people is because
CBD simply is not yet considered a novel
food the individual substance the
molecule is CBD if it's called cannabis
sativa L that's fine
that's not a problem that's okay so what
you say is you just don't have to put
CBD or on a label on the label that's
right and you avoid a lot of problems so
your cannabis sativa of course it
contains CBD okay yeah just to make a
note on that in US it's a similar
similar scenario with
of a lot of sellers on Amazon actually
are selling CBD products but they're
calling hemp extract it's very it's kind
of a sleight of hand but by not calling
out CBD specifically and calling it a
hemp extract they're able to remain as
resellers on Amazon there's another
confusion in the EU space and and it
goes back to the the change that was
made in January in the in the novel
Foods catalog as I said in 2018 there
were only kind of video in cannabis
sativa L there was no cannabinoids so
they what they did is in an effort I
think to clarify but it actually made it
more confusing they just threw
everything into one basket including
extracts and this is where the confusion
also lies does it say cannabinoids in
general or does it define this in every
know it says cannabinoids in the entry
and inside that entry they list all
different cannabinoids and they also
make reference to extracts also being
considered a novel food and there's also
a grey zone because they don't
specifically mention whether it's the
leaf whether it's the flower so it made
it worse what they did is really made
the situation worse one another mep a
guy called marco Zullo from from that
crazy country italy he he wrote to the
european commission he made an official
written request to the Commission to
clarify this situation in Europe
regarding foods and regarding cosmetics
he did that in March now they're given
six weeks in order to reply the six
weeks was up Friday last so I would love
to be able to tell you some latest hot
news this morning but there is none
there hasn't been any movements in the
last month from the European Commission
there's been no you know hot news that
we can share today it's election time
it's election time true you know that's
true okay M thank you very much our
third guest of the panel is Tom Suber
from Super Lawyer in California he
founded a Super Lawyer together with his
brother Jeff super in 2003
I'm super faciliate collaboration among
his colleagues and the system with
growing and client relationship mr.
super also manages intellectual property
and disputes and deals around the world
and consults consults clients in
relation to global intellectual property
portfolios and as I think I can say you
are specialized also on canopies regular
regulatory framework in California and
my first question is how does the
disparity of cannabis regulations
between federal state provincial and
municipal governments complicate
cannabis cannabis commercial Commerce
and the USA yes thank you mika so i was
originally asked to speak on an
intellectual property panel so I think
that that bio was suited for that but I
also on the managing partner of super
Lawler and we've been in the cannabis
industry in the US for over 12 years so
we represent many of the biggest players
in the u.s. cannabis space and in that
context I deal with a lot of regulatory
work FDA work and other work in
association with cannabis companies as
well as fortune companies to answer your
question as far as the disparity between
federal and state and municipal
regulations cannabis related regulations
in the States it creates a a great big
mess and so I guess in that sense it's
not unlike the EU so just for folks who
don't know in the United States there
are indeed three different levels of
regulation oversimplify things you have
of course the federal regulation the US
regulations and the FDA is going to at
some point regulate just about
everything and the underneath the
federal regulations you have states of
course much like Canada split into
provinces the EU split in the countries
the United States is split into 50
states plus territories are in each
state has its own disposition toward
cannabis CBD products THC products and
other cannabinoid products and then even
within each state municipalities differ
in the way that they regulate the
cannabis that the plant and products
that touch the plant and so in this
context there's a great deal of variance
so even though the federal government
has decided
so in the United States the prohibition
of cannabis is affected by what's called
the Controlled Substances Act and
cannabis until recently
CBD as well has been on Schedule one of
that act of the Controlled Substances
Act along with heroin and cocaine
so recently just this year the Congress
D scheduled CBD that's derived from hemp
so long as the CBD product contains less
than 0.3 percent THC it's categorized
this hemp and that's legal so to speak
but even still there are variances in in
terms of the states and how they
regulate hemp so as an example in
California you can't just start growing
hemp you can't create a farm to start
growing hemp and that's counterintuitive
in some sense you've got to part partner
currently with an agricultural research
institution and it's as complicated and
complex as it sounds because there is no
pathway to obtain a license to grow hemp
in California so that varies state by
state in the US furthermore THC is still
on schedule one of the Controlled
Substances Act so it's still treated
like heroin at least theoretically
however the federal government turns the
other way and so each of the individual
states is left to regulate THC
containing products and there's a great
deal of variance among the states over
30 states have legalized THC to some
extent whether to a medicinal level or
to a recreational level and then
underneath that the municipalities also
differ in the way that they regulate the
THC plant so what you have in the end is
really a an inability to have a national
strategy in relation to a THC product
and and what that means in effect is
that you've got to begin operations they
novel in each state so as to how this
affects things well as an example it's
awfully difficult to create a brand in
the sense that you do in other other
industries so if I have a well let's say
I'm having a can of coca-cola here in
Zurich and I have a can of coca-cola in
Tokyo or back home in California I have
substantially the same experience right
I
exactly the same user experience almost
the same brand experience except for the
language differences in cannabis if I go
to the same retailer shop here in Zurich
or in California did the experience
within a brand can change month to month
so then when you consider the fact that
in the United States the regulations
vary by state and furthermore you can't
ship THC across state lines in the US
how much more difficult does it become
to create a consistent user experience
and so when you think about it that's
everything that's associated with a
brand
so as the cannabis industry grows up
this disparity between federal and state
and municipal regulations is going to
increasingly become a greater focus for
cannabis companies that are going to be
more ambitious and trying to create a
consistency of user experience
underneath the brand across state and
sovereign borders thank you very much so
what we have heard so far in any country
or in every country the national
regulations are and are not a homo
gained all over Omegan in most countries
even within the countries they differ
and on a scale from one to ten somewhat
what you say how much does that
influence international cannabis
business development or the the
international development of the kana
business between one and ten points what
would you say so I would split that into
two answers one is the THC answer and
I'd say it's a 10 in regard to hemp
derived CBD I'd say it's still probably
a 2 and and so in regard to THC
obviously if you try and ship something
across the United States border you're
going to get arrested so so there's that
in regard to hemp derived CBD there are
still issues it's legal but apparently
some federal institutions some United
States governmental institutions didn't
get the memo that hemp is now legal so
products containing CBD will still get
stopped at the border and so you've got
a hire an attorney to go educate
relative governmental operatives and say
you know what this is legal I need to
let it through all right so that's
that's still going on in the United
States
and CBB that that would be for CBD
correct so so CBD it should make it
through and you can theoretically ship
CBD product across the border and in
fact our law firm is involved in
conversations and in relation to a
number of territories throughout the
world but you wouldn't de sure a client
that that if you try and ship CBD from
here to there across the United States
border that it won't get stopped because
folks are still considering that a drug
and then you've got to explain though
the the the farm bill was passed this is
legal now and you need to let it through
and that's that's that's a conversation
and an argument and a fight that happens
and it's a function of legacy issues -
next question is also Gareth and we're
talking about frameworks international
frameworks actually I did some research
we have in the frameworks we have m.i.a
we have GD a GMP we have GP p in Canada
we have G AMC in so why is Carib is not
included or cannot be included in their
already existing international
frameworks which are in compliance
except actually and I think it's
starting to and you're starting to see
that movement for instance BRC that that
accreditation we just did that for the
first time so it's not that it couldn't
be done it's just that it hasn't been
done and I think GMP is one of those
things you're hearing a lot of the
buzzword of GMP all over the world in
the u.s. we've done a Jane Canada yeah
we've got a you have a TPP right G not
GMP and so I think you're starting to
see you know supply chains bridge those
gaps internationally for instance now we
have to get a you EU GMP audit company
to fly to the United States to do the EU
spec GMP audit in order to be in
compliance in Europe and not just in the
US which is a different audit scheme so
I think that the industry is very young
but as it matures you're gonna see the
International frameworks come together
and start working the way that they
should it just hasn't been done yet and
I don't think there's anything
the industries from doing that for legal
products it's just it just takes time
for that to take place
if I could also add to that that's what
Garrett had said a lot of it in the
United States I think everywhere comes
from a lack of understanding of the
plant and all of this happens so
suddenly and so the current regulatory
frameworks that existed absent cannabis
don't fit cannabis so as an example the
FDA has a policy that's existed until
today whereby if something is a drug
it's not a food or a supplement right
and so then you have a pity elects which
went through as a CBD drug and so that's
approved as a drug so that would
according to the FDA I mean that
anything else that contains CBD needs to
be regulated as a drug and so the FDA
has expressed an intent to make an
exception in that regard because there's
so much CBD product out there and I
think everyone agrees that that would be
a bit silly so there's going to be some
sort of threshold which categorizes CBD
beyond that threshold of content as a
drug for perhaps that'll be a function
also of the usage of the CBD if it's
applied to a particular physiological
condition and then other forms of CBD
used for other purposes will still be
categorized as food and end as a
supplement and those are governed by
different tracks under the FDA so that's
it just goes to show that that the FDA
was not prepared to receive this type of
this type of subject matter the cannabis
subject matter and as a function of that
it's going to have to change some of the
habits that it currently has meaning
some of the policies that have existed
today thank you very much
my next question question goes out to
Francis we've heard that the who is
building up a regulatory framework for
Europe
we also heard in the long term the US
will set up a regulatory framework which
is which will be similar to the Canadian
or so what do you think how how
important is it that the European and
the authorities from oversea cooperate
so the business can prosper develop um
it's a good question and it's also
linked to what Tom was just saying
because the way
the FDA is approaching it and we're
you're anticipating the maybe the cutoff
between what's a medicine and what's a
food or food supplement I think the
European Commission are going to
legislate in the same way that's going
to come later on this year and that will
help to give clarity how it should be
how it should be approached and I think
be at a very high level between the u.s.
between the EU there are talks between
the two through two trading bloc's and I
think there will be a type of an
alignment that will come I'm
anticipating this it's my my crystal
ball okay so it's not written in stone
but this is I think what's going to
happen because there's too much at stake
there's too much at stake in terms of
tax dollars in terms of jobs in terms of
a whole new industry that's that's there
and that just needs to be freed a little
bit or given clear clarity and
regulations so it can go ahead yeah my
next question is - he - Keith and it's a
very specific question in Europe we have
a regulatory framework for seats what's
going on in the u.s. concerned about
hemp seeds a regulatory framework is
there anything planned now or is the
NIDA and I DEA still importing seeds
from the in the US there is no framework
like the year there's no registered list
we need to remain compliant under the
federal guidelines of 0.3% THC or less
but outside of that you're free to do
genetics work and we do and I think that
you know the structure of the EU seed
list is is cumbersome especially for
folks that want to innovate and create
more farming and agriculture so I
believe that the the u.s. framework is
more advantageous for farmers and for
the market in general because it doesn't
have strict regulations and
registrations related to the individual
seeds and genetics
thank you very much and let's go to the
novel food the novel food regulation and
my next question goes out to Francis
about there because he's the expert on
novel food regulation and in the panel
before I estimated after the novel food
regulation is implemented it will take
another two up to three years till all
the national laws I implemented would
you agree or do we think there's a
difference not really over won't take so
long there has to be a harmonization
process that's true but it could be
accelerated it could be accelerated
because of the the changing economic
landscape and for sure the EU doesn't
want to be fall behind what's going on
in Canada and going on in the u.s. they
want to be competitive for sure and you
have an important lobby group the eih a
again which is receiving positive
feedback from the European Commission
and I'm hoping that it's at EU level I
think the clarification will come within
this year maybe towards the end of the
year but then when it gets translated
into the national laws is where it takes
time and that'll take another year but
as a person who has contact to
authorities you you've got the feeling
that he wants to be competitive yeah
they waddling sure
so it's not too much money involved it's
not like a black sheep know anymore no
they want to be competin yes okay um
thank you very much my next question
goes out to Tom and when we talk about
framework we also have to talk about
patents um how do different countries
protect from genetics and other aspects
of cannabis technolon of technological
value do you have any experience in that
in California already sure well there
are in the United States first of all
there's a funky sort of patent called
the plant patent which is a bit peculiar
to the United States so there are ways
to protect plant varieties in the EU and
in other parts of the world but as there
are in the States but in the United
States you actually have a particular
type of patent that is designed to
protect a strain a set of cannabis
genetics that are produced asexually and
so this has been it's it's this
historical oddity the the plant patent
exists the United States to protect a
better strain of rose for instance our
law firms uber Lawler's actually just
obtained what we believed to be the
second ever issued us plant patent for
cannabis strain which is pretty cool
fact admit so in in the United States
and the there are really a variety of
ways now to protect the technology
associated with the plant and as we move
forward in in terms of the cannabis
industry continuing to mature from an
illegal industry toward a legal industry
or corporate industry intellectual
property is going to intersect
increasingly with regulatory frameworks
like for instance the FDA so as an
example of that the to take it back to
the FDA for a moment and then the
comeback patents the FDA of course when
you think of the FDA and you think of
the approval process you think typically
of the drug approval process right like
a PDL X and that's a ten year process a
ten year plus process is a billion
dollar plus process typically and that's
that's that's a got it's a threshold
that really typically is only met by a
pharmaceutical company given the
enormous resources that a pharmaceutical
has a company has to throw at that type
of application process but there are
also two other tracks to oversimplify
things at the FDA that are gonna come
relevant to cannabis products you have
the NDI track which is for new dietary
ingredients and what that is basically
supplements right so supplements that
are not quite drugs so if you have a a
CBD product that you're using for
seizures like a PD LX that's a drug if
you have a CBD product that you're using
for better sleep that would be
considered a supplement and so typically
you would put that through the NDI track
the new dietary ingredient track at the
end of that track you could even get the
ability to make certain claims like
helps you sleep better or promotes
better energy and those are called
structured function claims there's a
third track
just called the crash track they
generally recognized the safe track so
that applies to foods like novel foods
you're in the in the European Union and
so that track also it takes about a year
like the NDI track and it's much less
it's in the low six figures maybe a
hundred one hundred and fifty thousand
dollars to get it through so those are
reasonable pathways and when you think
about CBD products THC products
CBN products these are typically aside
from topical creams and that sort of
thing they're all foods or supplements
or drugs so the FDA will govern
everything and so when we think about
when we think about patents the reason
that the way that they intersect with
the with the FDA processes is for
instance if you if you're successful in
obtaining an NDI approval for
supplements say a tincture that you're
going to use to help folks sleep better
at the end of that process in the United
States
others could ride the coattails of what
you've done so let's say that Francis
puts through an application with the FDA
he achieves an NDI approval he's got a
tincture now he can say it helps you
sleep better and he starts to put that
on the shelf I could come out and say
you know what I'm gonna do it Francis
did and I'm gonna go ahead and put my
product on the shelf and ride the
coattails of that well you can use
theoretically you can use patents and
other things to make it more difficult
for me to do that so let's say that
Francis's application were to rely on
particulars like for instance a
particular strain that he's patented
well then in that sense it's difficult
for me to do exactly what Francis has
done without infringing that patent and
so I think what you're going to see as
we go forward is a greater communication
a greater intersection between
intellectual property and FDA frameworks
I think also what we're going to see is
a bit of a reckoning so what folks may
not know out here in Zurich in the
European Union around Zurich in the
United States and California last July
90% of the product came off the shelf
I'm gonna say that again because it's a
phenomenal fact ninety percent of the
product in legal retail shops were taken
off the shelves last July why because
they didn't comply with regulations that
came down last July the amazing
phenomenon the the that's associated
with that fact is we all knew it was
going to
than anybody who thought about it last
January or February of March or April or
May understood that most of the product
was going to come off the shelves in
July when the regulations landed there
are some of us in the United States who
believe that sort of reckoning is going
to happen at the federal level in
relation to FDA regulations and and the
reason why is because it seems to me and
to others that the FDA has to regulate
any product that makes a claim that it
helps you sleep better or that it helps
you improve energy or that it improves
your gut or what have you because if it
doesn't then the FDA becomes a mockery
so many of these products that are
making these claims now there is going
to be some sort of reckoning at some
point and so it makes sense for
companies that look to enter the United
States to start thinking today about
becoming compliant tomorrow so that you
have that advantage that your one of the
that you're among that 10% or that 5%
that 20% or whatever that percentage is
that's compliant when the FDA decides
that they're going to regulate but rest
assured the FDA will regulate because
all of this stuff is food it's
supplements Grug thank you very much Tom
Garrett I felt you wanted to say you
wanted to add something Oh am I wrong
no he's exactly right and you know we
would advising our our brand partners to
lay off the claims stay away from claims
and in stay away from letters from the
FDA that you know they have sent them
out notifying folks that they're making
claims that are unsubstantiated so take
a conservative route and wait for the
FDA guidelines food supplement or drunk
can you compare this situation to their
European situation Frances whatever
saying anyway yes yeah we have to wait a
little bit more to get the clarification
this within this year I hope to see that
at European level then as I said before
it's going to take time to translate
that into the national laws so it will
take time we'll take some time I like to
prefer to be optimistic and positive
about this because there is a there is a
lot at stake yeah absolutely
thank you very much and I look on my
something under Swiss level of course
where we are short on time here sorry
sorry because next month on the 13th and
14th of June all the cantonal chemists
are actually meeting with the federal
office in Bern to discuss CBD to discuss
cannabis extract CBD what to do in
Switzerland so you would also say Swiss
authorities want to be competitive
meanwhile they they they have to put
clarification as well they have to do it
to it so they're watching what's going
on in the EU because if you know on the
food the food area particularly there's
a there is a strong alignment between
Swiss legislation and EU legislation
also concerning novel foods and the
reason for this is because the biggest
export partner for Switzerland is the EU
so again it boils down to trade and
money taxes and I think one gentleman
earlier this morning said Switzerland of
the few countries that makes money out
of this whole business it's true so
thank you very very much I don't know do
we have any we have time we have time
yes we have time for a question or two
does anybody have a question I have a
question on the intellectual property I
mean how does it work like cannabis has
been decentralized for such a long time
it's always been kind of a open source
software for breeders and everything I
mean there's a couple guys who try to
hide some strains or seeds but usually
it just gets out and everybody's all in
the mix I mean you can't really patent
OG Kush or train wreck or bubba or
anything like that so i mean how does it
how do you decide that you own the
rights to a cannabis string sure I'm
happy to take that one first of all
that's such a big exciting question and
man I'm very interested couple days
answering it so I'll make a couple of
points here as succinctly as I can first
of all what you pointed out really is a
prior art problem right the cannabis
industry is so novel and strange and
wonderful for so many reasons one of
those reasons is that there was a
thriving illegal economy around cannabis
for decades right and so there's all
this information out there however it
was illegal so there's no prior art and
and when I use the term prior or what
I'm for
- is really all the stuff that's out
there that the Patent Office the US
Patent Office that analogous patent
officers throughout the world will look
at to determine if something comprises
an invention right and so when the
Patent Office sees something today
somebody puts through an application to
let's say obtain a patent for anything
with any product that has greater than
95% CBD content which is a patent that
for instance United cannabis Corp is
obtained the Patent Office doesn't know
what to do with that because they're not
aware that those products have existed
because everything was illegal there's
just no prior art out there and I don't
mean to pick on that patent that's not
my point and it takes that that's been
through a process of challenge and it
survived and and United cannabis Corp
deserves credit for obtaining that
patent but what I do mean to point out
is that what you're looking to really is
a prior to our question and in the
cannabis industry you don't have access
to the prior art that exists because
nobody was talking about the illegal
stuff that they were doing experimenting
with cannabis um so that's going to
change now one other thing that I would
point out is that the cannabis industry
is a technology industry period it's
just that the cannabis industry doesn't
realize it yet most of it but the patent
litigation is going to affect all of our
lives anybody who's here with the
cannabis product will be affected by
patent litigation in some way or another
the reason is because there's so much
technology in that plant and there's so
much technology that lies between the
plant and the human physiology that we
don't yet comprehend and so many of the
patents said well there are a few
patents today that are celebrated but in
in my view and in the view of some of my
colleagues these patents are not
necessarily capturing the substance of
the technology that's inside the plant
in the sense that they're speaking to
isolated cannabinoids one of the things
that's so fascinating about the plant is
how complex the interaction is between
the different cannabinoids terpenes and
ballast and other bio chemicals in the
plant and the way that these
interactions between these bio chemicals
affect the degree to which different
cannabinoid receptors within the human
body take up a cannabinoid so as an
example isolated CBD which is taken up
by the cb2 receptor not to geek out too
much I'll try and keep this as simple as
possible is not is not really taken up
that well
so the reason why if you take a CBD
product you give it to your mom or or
your your grandmother and they say I
don't feel anything that's not
surprising because an isolated CBD
compound does not get taken up well by
the cb2 receptor however you add a bit
of THC and all of a sudden the
receptivity of the cb2 receptor to the
CBD increases the entourage effect the
entourage effect and and and that's
really an understated way of putting it
but that's true and the thing to keep in
mind is that there are over a hundred
cannabinoids in the plant
there are many receptors in the human
body that take up cannabinoids but we've
only studied - we can only currently
test for between 13 and 828 cannabinoids
depending on who you ask and how you're
counting so what that tells you is
there's so much that we don't yet
understand that technology is going to
get patented and and that's going to
we're going to start to see increasingly
interesting patents speaking toward the
interactions between cannabinoids
terpenes ballasts and other bio
chemicals in the plant the way that they
interact with particular human
physiological conditions and as these
patents land they'll be enforced and all
of us will be affected thank you for
keeping it very simple and we can just
add just a note on that we've actually
just started the process on a we
announced a 0.0% THC cannabis strain in
conjunction with the University of
Kentucky and that's under under the
patent process at the moment so that
speaks to the - the genetics and the
plant side of that and not as much to
the receptor and to the entourage effect
thank you yeah if one more question
instead I have one more oh yeah thank
you just on the three components or
whatever that are registered under the
novel foods Bach was it or catalog that
was three and Todd yeah cannabis sativa
L is defined as what the plant yeah
that's a little bit ambiguous your eyes
there are 63 variety 6969 for the common
registry yeah
but the plant itself is cannabis sativa
L correct and that is not 69 varieties
so just two things there's common
registry which Garrett was referring to
earlier in the EU
so for crops and for consumer products
you you have to use a plant that's
listed on that registry for it to be
compliant with EU regulations and that's
why you have things like EU certified
hemp because it's a hemp variety that's
on that list but novel foods is another
regulations a complete different
regulation it has nothing to do with
there's no there's no bridge between the
two so when they talk about cannabis
sativa L they talk about it as its use
in food products and it talks about
whether you can use the seed or whether
you can use the leaf or the stalk or the
root are the flower and and this is and
the problem with the entry in the
catalog is that it doesn't explicitly
say some things to make it clear what
you can use or what you cannot use so by
absence it's it's it's quite ambiguous
to understand what is meant by that this
is the this is the problem that's
linking with that entry into come in the
in the catalog okay if fantastic great
thank you all so very very much we are
unfortunately out of time but that was
very informative thank you very much
[Applause]