hey Joel in the middle yeah this is all
they were we've migrated we get david
winger henry bowl at the end and we've
got Joel Sherlock in the middle
gentleman just introduced us
sorry everyone get out there know
everyone's still awake up after lunch
I'm David later on the global
initiatives officer for the Bank
Corporation one of the keynote sponsors
of the event help everybody has a chance
to come to our party tonight about space
monkey I do not and nothing the industry
Canada's mystery since 2016 I started
investing in Canada and then invested in
the United States early on in some of
the now leading multi-state operating
operators own recently I started
shipping some of my investment focus
from multi-state cannabis operators to
brands and one of the companies that I
invested in is bang and I've gotten to
know the team more and more I haven't
thought that often great yeah yeah
Monica Joel sure like so we've been
invested starting the private equity
side in a Canadian space since 2011
you know starters were generalists and
weren't a lot of the big names very
early on so it's been a good market to
us
I had a focus in the US for the last
couple of years and now really focus on
the European opportunities here and
really narrow down our scope into your
investment ecosystem my name is Henry
Buhl I'm working from framework we
control a small family office we
actually have not invested into CBeebies
and Canales companies yet but the main
reason why is to look at opportunities
potential for such companies in the next
one or two years but I could also make a
very short-term investment if there are
some interesting use right now here very
good so you guys see a really diverse
group on the panel the investors
basically rooted in Europe Canada in the
US but all of them investing globally
but um that's where the market is right
now and all of them touching both
private and other countries so really
interesting viewpoints jumping right in
as we say in Switzerland some of the
other panelists discussed you believe
that exit lens is the Swiss but really
jumping in what are the primary
differences in raising funds right now
this is North America start fuel even
away the order or first ones were
immediately backed by our capital and
then Canadians but most of our
experience in the public markets in the
early days was actually selling things
that we killed two publicly traded
companies if these difference I see when
you look at like the aim or the next of
some of the markets over here the
barrier to entry and I'm just allergic
wired over here is quite a bit higher
than need a finisher or this CC indicate
you might see it for most of the
cannabis companies now so you know
they'll be a lot more questions a lot
more diligence you know in requirements
just from reporting business plans kind
of basically all the things we should
have in candidates and I think that yeah
yeah essentially more mature from the
gym yeah yeah I think the maturity
aspect is very important I think looking
at where the US was a couple of years
ago I've been
sir it was a pretty fragmented landscape
and you're quite sure how the business
was warm and a lot of the companies
raised money we're not very professional
what's become much more professional I
think in Europe looking here looking
around there here's a sunset a lot of
the operators here are bringing a very
high level of professionalism right from
the get-go I think that also looking at
this market from the US operators
perspective and investor perspective we
seen on out twice what has happened in
the cannabis industry in Canada and the
United States going from some talking
and building that talk building up to a
groundswell of support to an industry
built and I think that looking at the
air market if there's no question about
the same things that happen here so
investors are going to be looking at
this market with a certain degree as
patients and they're also bringing
capital that has raked in need in other
markets from campus activities so
there's a degree of confidence companies
and operator NFS or they have looking at
the market here I think it's both very
well for the operators here looking to
raise I'm going it looks vertical keeper
partners and also helper and that's the
result of opportunities here
thanks could just add that I see the
potential of CBD you I know as the 2000
estimate of utility where we had the
public so right now Europe is still very
premature and if you look at the US
companies or some interesting CBDs
companies they start from the seat all
the way down to the to the selling of
the product and I would rather invest in
the US kind of deal where they grow
seeds and state I don't want to name any
compared to Syria another
some European countries definitely Syria
so let me take a quick poll here CDE is
seems to be a hot topic here
that's all operators or investors in the
sector who here operates a business or
invest in a business that is kisi only
hands Wow
and CBE only THC and CBD okay very cool
so let's segue into a question right now
about investing in CBD and so Henry
start us off David you've obviously made
a not just an investment but you're also
putting in additional resources your
mind shift means you've essentially cpp
I wait here investment bank and others I
do CVD to me of one aspect of the
cannabis plant I think that the cannabis
plant is where the that's the word worth
of the potential ins before this
industry age the whole time in all the
calves annoyed and I think that THC is a
big big part of that but we have to of
course deal with the radio tower
realities and I think that CBD is
available now and there is a quicker
ready for a pathway to to CBD being
watered available and I think that's
where the market the markets following
that but from a personal perspective I
think that there the demand for THC a
underestimated as well LAN I'm talking
about necessarily high THC of people
giving zone but there is something to
being home and the afternoon if you're a
housewife and cleaning up the water here
or a house with a husband and have a
little bit of THC can make it
interesting right we're not talking
about them sell them so I think this
whole plan offers a lot so the type of
personal take on this to ancillary
businesses that work synergistically
together and the FarmVille you know
rocked our world gave us a much bigger
for instance with but calm instead of
delivering in California and then going
and setting up partners and framework in
Massachusetts and then doing that in
Florida and the states allow those right
amended sort of regulations now we can
go ahead and ship CBD next air basically
globally it up our addressable market
immeasurably so when is over 99% of
people go to our site but calm
I generally can't deliver them and this
unless state live in these parts of
California and so all the sudden it's
changed the game there are a lot of
companies or whom this has happened so
again is a professional investor so what
do you see CBD as it is a professional
investor rate of it what we focused on
the agent downside risk right it's like
if everything goes well we're going to
power
faster but what happens when it doesn't
go well and so you know from a
cultivation stamp on the THC
I was never pro cultivation is you have
jurisdictional risk you're limited to
one state and you know if you buy a
license in Washington and look as
pricing margins and you can't do
anything else with that license so you
know CBD has a whole lot of really
interesting opportunities simply because
you can cultivate it here make a brand
here and then ship it in a whole lot of
different areas so you know our focus is
now big things that they'll have that
kind of rich or risk
you know from equipment companies that
manufacture machines to you know we have
an ethanol company we want to companies
are difficult or tell us which
manufacturers extraction machines will
make those in Canada or ship them all
over the world so you know that's really
very important part of our thesis is
just not having that jurisdictional risk
which is exciting you were one of your
big plays as a it's a hardware
manufacturer right to there its
extraction equipment what percentage of
that equipment do you think is being
used inspect CD a huge amount of it I
mean the interesting part for us is we
used to buy extraction equipment and you
know we have this machine over here a
different one over there yeah I just
fundamentally believe that if you're
investing in brands you need the same
extraction methodology you know there
needs to be consistency of that brand
you know when you can who's a Starbucks
or McDonald's it's the same expresso
machine the same cash register those
consistency of that experience you know
if you get a license to brew Budweiser
they don't tell you to just go and buy
whatever equipment you want that's
exactly what they need so that it's the
same another market and so you know when
we started Vitalis it was just something
we had a standardized platform for
everything and then we started making
really big equipment and I mean we
should oughta make enough for the CBD
more coats but now we're starting to see
you know co2 extraction machines there
the whole facility that can do
a little tons a day so you know basket
incredible pace it's just a skill some
of these facilities of what I think that
speaks to the fact engine CD is just
driving one song you wrote it just
flat-out is we also run a hardware
business where the make bullets pattered
tech does have the scale to which right
now our dress will market is rung for
that they wouldn't have built those we
should those EOT machines without TV so
the other interesting thing is what see
me he has done is it's rock both saying
that were averse to TC forever ease and
regulatory because are the psychoactive
work with their model but an investor
like Henry and invested broadly
different verticals now finds himself in
his room because it seemed so very easy
I just want to happen I am from back
home medical doctor and I never been
like the toxic part of the THC and now
we have the non-toxic product available
which can be used in both ways and we
already have approached by one of our
own energy doing that people who wanted
to go or not a volunteer after we've had
this problem to put CBD in the drink and
that's how we got away
what wait a minute that's interesting so
it's just
[Music]
so so we passed it so to me it's a
little hard to it's gotten so big but
it's it's only one component of this
space and generally when we talk about
CED just like when we talk about
cannabis it still breaks out to its and
hardware's and software is it flowers of
cultivation is it packaging right so
right now the question to investors on
the panel is never going down what are
the types of verticals what products
what within the space is right now sort
of most demands as best or better
oh my perspective nothing is any Brezza
there's so much white space and so on
opportunity and thus of an illegal part
after two goes for operators or anybody
watching the business there's so much
opportunity all over the place setting
in order to succeed you need to have a
measure of focus and whether it's a
certain area that you're focused in or a
certain market or what any cattle lane
because they're just looking for the
next opportunity you just won't do is
just too much so I mean the way I look
at it is of being I've tried to become
an expert in companies that make and
sell cannabis products I don't really
look at any of the other ancillary
verticals not that there's not a lot of
opportunities here of course they are
but I focused in that area and what was
in that particular area at least in the
u.s. I've seen a trend I wrote a white
paper in September of 2018 I spoke about
it in Berlin called the green regulatory
arbitrage case for investing in u.s.
multi-state vertically integrated
cannabis companies and that set out the
history of where I think lovely
prohibition were I think legalization is
headed and my thesis were investing and
after time multi-stage advence operators
I think those are still great investment
opportunities in the United States but I
think that brands in the night
we're the real real winners are going to
be levantate upwards
some of them are Denzel French but the
reason why illegally my personal
investment focus has turned of brands
and why I'm doing bang to help them with
global initiatives is because this is a
CPG industry nobody really really cares
you know where I was grown our who grows
some kind of sores but most people don't
and they are buying a proc CPG finished
product and they want it I think they
many times from a credible brand bang is
one of the first cannabis companies in
the United States found in 2010 the
company has navigated all the challenges
of existing in the US cannabis ministry
for ten years to go public in the next
next couple of weeks and I think if
you're looking at and that's one of our
Chinese liquor brands that I haven't
have half traction that's good it has a
time and I have the potential to become
in the case of US national brands or as
our missions are to be a global brand so
so interesting so cpgs brands
manufactures essentially I think
anything Joel's got a different strategy
and also it should be noted that brands
are right now I think it's it's a little
pretty given Canada
so non-existent they've got something
like that one would say yeah but yeah so
what's your sort of you know I mean
first and foremost for us as always you
know people you know the management team
is the first thing we look at but
ultimately I mean it you know whether
you're looking to make an investment or
or if you're looking to receive
investment I mean look the other side of
just the cash right like what else can
you bring to the table what else does
that company need do they have the right
people to actually execute the strategy
you know the early days of Canada it was
like oh we have a license and then the
values would go out
I think you know that's come to a
grinding halt now you have to be able to
execute business plan and make that
important stuff of profit you know one
of the Canadian companies forgot to do
that if I you know for us it's always
about you know what if we're negotiating
a deal and the infrastructure that we
already have can really help the company
or investing and our money's not the
same cover right but we can make the
investments we can get the operating
capital but we can also provide them
with you know being our global network
of supply people on the equipment side
if it's another equipment company or you
know if it was a brand if we can
introduce them to our license processors
who all have the same machine right we
can invest in a brand introduce them to
our clients and globally get them into
legal markets with partners who all have
the same extraction machine here the
SOPs and that gives the brand an unfair
advantage so it's good for the brand
it's good for our investment and it's
also good for the people who honor our
machines so it's full transparency it
really is a win-win-win
so it makes us a very good partner for
you know our what we call our our
ecosystem so that's what we're focused
on them to super focus focus I think the
overarching we feed off investors there
is so much out there that you can't
really dive in and understand a space or
a bit of a new level you're not trench
I would agree one for the two gentleman
said before so I'm just in the learning
process I'm very excited of this new
or call the CBD investment but I agree
to what everybody has said before so
that hey that I can have he can be
closing smart CVD yeah well not with all
the the cash bugs
I was definitely the best of all so so
that will click on on CED by touching on
the regulatory component just because
David sitting here has some very
interesting color working essentially
with with Senate committees look
beautifuller so here you see is that
will absolutely impact you know the
investment landscape right now it's a
big open question what you see him and
please also describe the capacity before
so the white paper that I mentioned
before which was published on new
cannabis ventures was read across the
world and also in the US Congress and
got me invited to join the US Senate
candidate working group and the US House
and this working group so I'm in DC
twice a month of in your two working
groups which are with with our members
of their congressional staffers working
on drafting and crafting federal
cannabis legislation and trying to get
more support for it in the US Congress
and we worked through a whole bunch of
issues done on a cannabis ion the HTM
CBD aside I'm probably speaking from the
legalization of cannabis I very much
agree with the congressman world record
view this morning and the frankly the
whole industry worldwide it was a debt
of gratitude to him of the world record
our amendment is a single most important
piece of cannabis legislation in the
world so uh I think that I agree with
him that it worked with moving forward
quickly in Congress there's a lot a lot
of activity behind the scenes
our the state packing act is very likely
you're going to have something they'll
have in this summer no that's going to
advance the industry very very
significantly when banks like JP Morgan
bank of America seed bank are banking
the industry it's going to become
normalized by quickly on the CBD side
a recent economy there was a reduction
that Mitch McConnell was the second most
powerful person in the United States
after the president the Senate Majority
Leader he was largely responsible for
getting the farm to the past
at the end of 2018 at the farm bill hemp
from the CSA no longer a drugs now
agricultural Mitch McConnell used center
call use a lot of his political capital
and a lot of his key supporters in
Kentucky I work wishing he got the farm
bill week in place and he got it done a
monumental accomplishment in the skin of
Congress but now the FDA has effectively
put a great sight and said no you can't
put seaweed in food and the claim is of
course any to please that can't have it
to it you can't market ourselves as a
dietary supplement
so they they've started interested
there's this massive demand and the FDA
has stepped in and the Congress I think
is frustrated with that they're not
happy with that and the f getting
headaches have things like asthma
indicated that big they want Congress to
legislate some more about em about how
CBD can be active food and I think
Congress has perspective is that no you
FBAR agency charged with doing this and
the messaging that it should take for
years it is unacceptable and the FDA
regulates drugs and alcohol which tell
people every day yet are sold every
single day
it is worse not helpful right at works
doing it the oxide and the downside of
it are get the outside versus the upside
that the FDA should be able to with him
I say six months figure out how this he
brought to market in a sensible way with
dosage
patience potentially but we're not
dealing with something that's dangerous
here so a Congress is actively looking
at forcing FDA to move forward quickly
including through appropriations
measures and other measures so I think
that don't be too pessimistic about the
progress of CBD food in food in the
United States I think there's gonna be
harvest they're doing - yeah you know
those barriers you know I have created a
ton of opportunity there's certainly
things that you have to watch out for
and you know as state by state or you
know the different rules of Switzerland
anymore - wherever you know around
potencies of CBD to th see you know
different allowable limits etc I mean
there's great opportunity if you know
how to navigate that you know as soon as
safe banking comes in and our bills
totally cleared up that's also gonna
bring in a whole lot more competition
both on the capital side but you know
also on the production side so you know
once once there's lending and people can
build much bigger farms and get mortgage
rates and you know you're not having to
go out and work as hard as everyone
those rivers work the Builder business
is the dam you know there's a lot more
scale a whole lot more production which
is gonna drive prices down so there's a
great opportunity right now but you know
you still have to make sure that there's
a there's a plan for the price
compression that baby is coming it's a
no doubt I'll say it has an operator you
know clearly hemming them just more
readily access to the big banks as far
as funding is one thing but for us you
know having a business with 120
employees they're made out of cash
weekly is asinine
it's beyond asinine and we have a person
accounts money that's that person's job
and so the efficiencies that are
come from at my perimeter or there is
parking and sort of moving the words
yeah they're just it's it's it's rough
operating right now so I think it will
smooth things not just with a capital a
man like normalize operations and that's
the crazy thing in California where were
the you know if largest economy in the
world were we're the largest and this
market in the world and it bank accounts
closed you know so and right now our
industry is hiring more than any other
industry in the other state no doubt so
interesting things and I think in all of
them absolutely opportunity lies right
so I don't know where we're at but
generally this is a panel that elicits
tons of questions so I want to go ahead
and take it out your banking system my
name is Graham you are from marginal
density which is like a crypto currency
system and Ruby don't wanna pursue an
alternative and having a diverse life
as a senior companies so I think if we
look at a lot obviously because of
having necessity and it's sort of an
option I think a lot of folks have taken
the view that you know two negatives
don't make a positive
we're already sort of in a you know
difficult industry so now sort of poking
the bear a little bit more and saying
hey we're gonna use this sort of off the
charts method of you know taking in our
funds that's why you haven't seen it
it's because it's the bigger players
don't think that
is a great look for the regulator's
right now that will trying to convince
to let us bank but you guys have any
insight onto that I know what I've been
asked that question I mean I've seen all
I'm gonna tell them from pop a green
coin a whole bunch of them if so many
kinds but you know if someone could
bring me a paper that basically like the
KYC side of this like anti-money
laundering approval that this would be
okay the process cannabis payments that
way I mean all day long it solves a few
throng no one's been able to prove that
so you know I'm with you there like two
wrongs don't make a right
it's a huge problem that's an
interesting solution but I don't think
it's great right area for me personally
any solutions in a book right now but I
think that's where a long-term close to
sort of hold it is I think they're
coming in the sunset I think the
blockchain camera in the cannabis
industry is interesting I know
IBM instead of doing a partnership with
a company called wasabi to build
watching to cover the entire painting
cannabis industry nap and I see Chris
Tillman of cannabis duck I usually stop
reading it not because there's anything
wrong Grizelda just to the point that he
made I think it's too much it will leak
too far to take both of these leaks in
one in one chop there's gonna be more
questions probably have a question let's
talk about this opinion you know me like
does it work like I mean yes a point
where people Calvinists yeah what's the
stop the government from shutting down
oh you're seriously dying I think that
the difference between crypto and
cannabis is
Devendra campus is very easy to
understand and the demand is proven or
are those two things right there are two
things that we don't have a fertile
[Music]
earlier money and also the fact that you
need right now armored vehicles so
actually it's so soon the new on sucks
but what's worse is it's a like you're
risking lives you know so people will be
killed so in Oakland which is a huge
animus of in California there are you
know the crime is it's is a big issue we
had our facility broken into most of our
neighbors most big brands in California
deal with this and and it's no fun so
it's not just about the new since it's
about like we are friends and employees
like danger that is that you walk into
this but you're in there so security and
guns and cameras and all because it's
yeah yeah well I mean what do people do
little like you didn't lobby the federal
government I suppose it is going to
resolve that yeah we don't think of this
time next year we're gonna be having the
same conversation and that's why I use
companies in the cannabis space that are
I think the closest to this issue that
are have been processing payments or
cabbage companies are really ramping
down their operations them in
anticipation of having regular banks
gonna go once we had there was a point
earlier
one of the questions and talk about
biggest differences in the US and Europe
and I think that the maturity and the
fact that you come out without this sort
of marking obviously their pockets and
you know are slow nine years that's
their the cultures there but the
businesses is is growing up basically
like ground up legal mature and there
were a lot of deals that we looked at in
the US which would have been fantastic
investments but you know for you to jump
on a plane and go and pick up a hockey
bag every month is just not an option
right so we had to pass on them but you
know with with I mean the track record
that was talking about you know the
European landscape is gonna be very very
interesting I mean the borderless nature
of these you is very interesting there's
so much opportunity here so yeah I was
just going to say that I think that most
another component part from the
government to sign Lending Act is also
the aspect of money laundering and how
dealing with cash yeah is facilitate
some reason well we have you know the
funky thing is that someone used funky
early that's German word it is like a
you know like yeah there's a there's
they're different components
[Music]
so usually the connotations with cash
are like hey it's cash and even sock it
away when you're not that's not true
though in our case everything is run
through tractor trades and through our
books so all the benefits of cash money
are not there in this industry it's
literally just a nuance of hearing
bags with you places and to pay
the you know to pay our taxes those bags
ash you know our excise taxes you know
hundreds of thousands of dollars so we
need to make one more point about the
deployment from from before
yeah the FDA looks at companies I might
look at this more closely and I think
for sure
the same thing will happen in Europe the
company that will won't be targets for
the FDA and will succeed in the industry
are ones that follow meticulous QA of
standards and have detailed labels and
not only odds cross some T's of follow
all the rules rules to to a TEM you USAF
GRS notifications and various ways drug
and you you have probably Eagles not
script curriculum processor to
regulation around food safety so I would
encourage anyone in the state's looking
at the food category book just in
general to become CBD they think
technology and all of the rest of being
meticulous about all the things that you
think we should be meticulous about
because it'll be to your advantage as
industry becomes more and more regulated
we just say what one thing to that point
home I think that what we're seeing
we've seen it in Canada with the company
like products but what we've seen in the
US with other companies companies that
are able to navigate this regulatory
landscape and comply with it are the
ones that succeed and otherwise you just
anticipate for Nia and over and over
again so it is important to be very you
know to into that a company like ours
has done this for decades already very
well huge
in all this but we see here's a
question what did you need to do to be
able to stomach invest in your company
that right now is you know has all these
sort of regulatory issues you're the guy
that liked CPG so these are all land
touch what was that process like well
III think that if you look at any
investment right any investment is a
balance of risk versus reward
all right website here's risk the other
side here's reward I'm the the reward
side of this of this industry and
cannabis cooking cannabis products is no
moral here in this room because we know
that the demand for this product is
massive
it's underreported it's going to be
tremendous when it's right regular
normal wing pot so you look at that the
reward is known on the rich side I think
bill illegality is what the risk is and
it's not in my view our real risk and
it's just a question of time there's no
question the us worldly wealth
decriminalized reschedule legalized and
as I said earlier there's no watch thing
about and in my view there's no question
about it in Germany and Switzerland
inflicted like that too as once we do it
the single convention will have to be
revised and we're the ones who call it
business so when we dig ourselves out of
the mess that prohibition has been the
rest of the world I think will follow
suit over time so I think that the the
perceived risk of investing in cannabis
products is much it is large but it's
not an actual risk and that was the
title of my white paper the greening
where the other Tory Arbitron hazardous
it it's an arbitrage is a mismatch in
value because of this artificial fair
that's been created hemisphere is where
there's lots of money that you need we
didn't run out of time but this is a few
really artificial people go to jail
people Chris well there hasn't been
already and
since 2016 on it although I don't
anything
Annabeth's top producing companies the
reason for that is because even though
individual I mean maybe not a federal
rate but there's still space already
they're either gonna federal grade or a
seizure on a cannabis company since the
end of 2016 anyone knows of an instance
we probably have the federal that
they're definitely interested ring so
look I think the point being here is I
think you went in and you assessed and
the risk relative the reward and clearly
you make me consider I'm an investor I'm
you know if they invested a lot of my
own money into my businesses and we saw
the same thing so please don't see me as
a complainer about bags of cash I'm just
talking about that as it's a nuanced and
obviously their recognition seems to be
gained but it's an amazing market in
California we actually make profit
there's a lot of weak so ya know