very cool from Japan to whites give you
have received her PhD in chemically from
Muhammad University in Wellman drop me
in Raqqa my mother commits in the
hospital
your company is in marketing laboratory
devices are also kind of emotional
possibilities from you company focuses
on your equipment
what would the company need to produce
GMP can abstract extracts in Germany are
in excellent I have a short version of
the list
yeah yeah but here's a longer version
yes so basically when you go to GOP
correction yeah it's a publicly
available of this all things that you
need to do yes what's concerns over
these consoles equipment in a new
location
atchoo into this very get your stuff
from also the lessons that you use
expection and also about documentation
yes who it's a very long this the basic
usually is one of you have to come very
high to regulations yes and what I what
you need to think about this advice be
three steps you know one thing has to
get your stuff home do you know you're
if you're Robert Boyles yeah you know
when it was Roman can you have it we
have no my god
Buddhist yes this is one thing and then
you also have to easily document and
come
[Music]
yeah yeah yeah please ask your trusted
if more question on that in Germany for
example describe a type of practice
occurs in Switzerland and in Germany
there is a complete loss we have
certified medical cannabis for masters
of pharmacy in Switzerland there
[Music]
which is because I have to partner up
for somebody at the start so facts about
somebody this will comes up in certified
it's necessary or you find a company
that has a cheap realize yes making your
stuff then you have only to take care
about your is you intrude yeah and then
find another for example
it doesn't a kitchen for me and my last
question on this topic and how which
which will be the we talking about
extraction products yes so for which
purpose who append a product and do
licensee I'm Switzerland as long as
there's no medical law for cannabis
that's a record of recreational yeah so
it's no less and as we can all right
so basically the only limit that you
have to test is the HD on time to put at
each day but there's no about how much
DVDs you should have in your package in
oil and extract so basically you can
pass some olive oil without any kind of
CD as long as your street-chic on you
know on percent yeah and so what I have
now is people were doing to change the
content that's additionally in guchi to
avoid a taxation yes if you don't test
one cookie you have to pay an extra
tricks okay thank you very much
and I think I'm going to you don't know
you know he's these like 80s 1998 you
know has been questioned at the bottom
and CBD have extraction and today as US
company he raises them to the rank of
apps extract a consulting for different
companies tremendous expert working with
the best breeders
at the other pucon 60 degrees and VP
laps with us I've done Frank Kevin
Joseph repeal up specializes in the
research of distribution on CBD hemp and
very wise and you know you are not a
real your own videos national robotics
trash and the basis of any instructions
which all of us have with less than 1%
THC if you produce CDJ extracts the THC
concentration maybe some is a true
that's true yeah
even the first easier step 2
to make that Campion just easy just say
before we are you or with the solvent
and then you keep it little one my
company we will make different technical
give me the duck down first with the
starting material we make kind of
process to get some extra people one
person we can also do it during the
extraction with a co2 system co2 system
just take out and also post extraction
we have different technique by
destination by selectively a
visualization and so it's one thing what
you would consider as a middle of
extraction this specific whose extract
me are you doing yeah because I only
heard so far that it still looted but I
have never heard that the CBD is like
separated from the THC after the
extraction yeah so we make a process
then we can eliminate the CBD after
extraction in the in the tree but that's
a very complex pressure if different
kind of thing and then you know we come
with the most important in the next
option for overseas the surgeries first
security then and then good stuff here
and I come back to a company like long
let me introduce Vincent before because
we're really short on time and we listen
this so the first time is we on the
podium and is a co-founder of CEO of the
curator of unity of Sh
telephone in Dayton destroyed it is
reading cannabis from a crooked over -
oh they're partners worldwide in active
operations in LA we are Europe and South
America and in shark you are a real
expert in extracting so your company
focuses on non phobic solutions and your
people will think of opera fama making
hash in the plastic bowl
I want something common with new
technology and approach you know you do
not call them the extraction yeah we
focus on 9000 extraction after Ashoka's
originally sovereign status but we
started it's a rosin extraction
equipment and idea behind problem
extracts hasn't changed much since the
Moroccan old beating is still pretty
much similar reforms of solvent
extraction I was categorize further
categorize solvent extraction will be
dry stick rosin and I swear - so dry sip
or mechanical separation rosin which is
using heat and pressure or ice water -
which is using cold water those are all
different ways to use non solvents
although some people can say water is a
solvent but I rather than solving its
like homes in moves away from the player
to play materially a vessel yeah and so
what we hear from you is the techniques
of iconoclast
in California because it's a legal
market and you can work openly so I
would say in general to take the pocket
in California is very paragraph and
comes with high construction on the
other hand we have German and Swiss
companies when it does when it comes to
extraction from hop and other plants
which are not cannabis where Europe
Europe is well Peter what would you say
what could those two industry to learn
from each other because they are
basically doing the same thing they make
a full full spectrum extraction of
plants these are two different totally
different industry what was a lot for me
cause I hope you take relax sure I think
right now the u.s. is open their eyes
and their analytics they're really good
about you back to how like just
whistling the Germans are leaders and
extracts
other things I think as the Swiss
Germans Europe starts to play and this
is where they're gonna continue to be
experts and interactions you're just
having had a time to play and let's go
back to Jana Jana my next question to
you is he right now allows business
multi are you expert materializes in
which way heavier companies of marcus
lepidus authorization
Hahnemann trying to find the best ways
also some additional comments we're
trying to find the best way maybe a
plant and you tell me this is my boy - I
can just and the second thing is facing
me anyway if you go through this was Jim
watch you be the same let me ask
additionally because the so what I
actually wanted to ask is is there any
specific years is there any specific
heat for cannabis analyzers of cannabis
extraction you don't get you don't have
fun with other plants do you get respect
from from scientists that say okay I
need this or this special developed
equipment for - well I think what you
have to think about is I mean I mean if
you go for some experience doing
exceptional hops specialization you know
it's usually grown somewhere in Europe
legally by trauma yeah if you go to a
cannabis market yeah if you grow
cannabis
so that you can be sure if you should
not have any kind of toxic metals inside
your yeah but you should know where your
house on the downside somewhere between
yeah I mean you cannot be sure that
there's some toxic metals inside and
I've seen one case of a patient and the
hospital was poisoned by marijuana and
he had a deep poisoning
it was not a boxing with the marijuana
he died awfully pardon me yeah somewhere
you didn't know and it was because if
you don't you get in trouble
okay controlling input is fine nice
Mikey work for or you know we talking
about caliber needs DHCC believe all the
time perhaps what Walter B's who you all
can you also extract our kids understand
that has a target school is there any
amount on my leg romantic hero on the
moment we just not focus on thirteen
because it's actually difficult to walk
with some CBD strains we go one person
you get good fragrance but not the real
presence of will th see straight road
number so in America there is a lot of
perfect having already because they get
stopped in like they have to do it we
make up in by this division from the
extras in our company and we make with
its exclusion from zucchini plant and we
mix different different kind of fun to
me but there's a team at other market
also gotta step in a structure or
whatever you say inches in alley we'd
start actually we're not
and let's go to witnesses they often
pull up on all the mistakes concentrates
I say let me get some charts
so Church sir teens has become one of
the hottest keywords there is in
candidates in California right now to
flavor the aroma and the feelings that
the chart profile contributes is huge so
up here right now we're talking a lot
about CBD isolate distillate those are
concentrates for short but that's not
concentrated when I find a concentrated
a market selling concentrates a
concentrate in the market of California
when someone wants to concentrate on
market is a jar of rosin or shatter or
cromwell or vho of some fashion and it
has a turn profile considered with it
like the flavor and aroma and the fact
that you get from the whole sensation is
what that concentrated is known for CBD
isolate and dislike it has its place and
i see more of a place as it moves
towards medical or as supplements or
food it's great as ingredients a
connoisseur market of kindness
concentrates it's not about isolating
it's about the full spectrum is about
entourage effect is about all the
cannabinoids not just cqd into each seed
is that on your other ones that we don't
talk about it all right now and it's
about how those kind of toys interact
with each other along with the turqu
paint robots that's the true magic of
this plant is how all of that combines
each other and that's why none of us
fully understand it yet because it's all
those different parts playing together
at once that give us these feelings of
why we love this plant do what we do so
sure people from other industries think
that we're going to come in and we're
going to
same thing we do with sage we're gonna
strap one thing but the thing is we're
extracting one thing we're forgetting
about the 99 other things that flames of
the fact that that we need to consider
right now so so let me ask again because
this is I think is a right more topic
that is the different between isolating
and extraction which a lot of people
especially who are not so much into the
topic
do not read it do not recognize is that
right that what you mean sure well
isolation is a type of extraction
attraction means you're you're
condensing the categories and into a
more concentrated forms goal means
concentrates are taking the cannabis
plant you're getting a lot rid of
everything else was so so they have
going to the trophies of the concentrate
we're isolating danger distilling things
were further concentrating work now
we're isolating into your CBD or TMC
your CV and anything else you want your
terpenes your your individual chart
means your trip in place however you
want to break this plant down you can
then do it because yeah we know how to
separate things we can always further
separate things but I think we get too
far ahead of separating and completely
and before we understand before were
separated and please let me come to the
next question because I think the color
party market is dance or the US market
is very hard trance and if the
preconditions are equal how does the
debug for extracts of that Ohio cannabis
in general develop if all products
illegal yet Switzerland real good
situation not autonomous product a
leader but if given the case all of you
good I would ask this right shoulder on
sure I think I touch on that a little
bit of BDS analytics and concentrate
market is surpassing the cloud of market
flowers demo works traditional but as we
open people's eyes to more products and
other ways to consume
I mean I change people's thoughts
all data concentrates where a lot of
people are very hesitant on smoking I'm
straight and that's why we got into
solvent so I can think another part of
you and squish it and squeeze is
basically like juice
now I have a concentrate there's nothing
no magic in Java or anything you can do
any chemical process to it or anything I
have a concert in front of you I let you
smoke that concentrate and he were
traditionally smoking flower before that
I'll show you the proper way of slow to
concentrate you're gonna continue small
pension tricks thank you
my next question goes out to you and
Rihanna as well I would say and in
Switzerland we heard we had a little bit
legal problem tooth extraction which is
not a you can I guess you really want to
because you have to stick to certain
limits but in general if though the
legal frame would be given do you think
Switzerland is ready to produce full
spectrum cannabis extracts on a
political level our guilt ompany is
ready for that yes it's just the next
step ok sharpen time today and I think I
like to us is evolution another
hypothesis questions but this is the box
that we have today and we only have
another 12 minutes for questions from
the audience a lot of these artificial
turf feed companies where they're like
oh we need to sell you the German
suppose push look they're dye extracted
from OG cooks or some things like that
my dream of terpenes is an isolated
isolated jockey the problem is like when
you're buying oh gee push it's somewhat
formulating what they say oh gee pushes
churn so i expansion like a bomb merci
merci and to think a combination of the
terpenes to create with is now og cush
there's nothing fake about those strings
at the end of the day so if you're if
you're looking for cannabis lemons and
Canada's effects and you want to get the
true kindness effects and blemish or you
can you can destroy proteins if you're
only looking for flavoring the
difference between limonene from a lemon
or lime from do they have the same
effect so you looking for campus style
effects right so mom will save you no
mercy neve tzedek hands is a THC or or
lemonade essence other qualities like
the terpenes give you difference more
than just GH seem to give you a
different effect to but do these
artificial burpees work the same way
yeah they're not artificial they're
derived yes from other location on
cannabis turn on cough drops are
glancing that there's a medically drive
therefore they're they're isomer may be
different or there
and answering configurations of air
molecules and it essentially in you can
create - maybe recreate a combination of
synthetically reconstituted terpenes but
they wouldn't necessarily do the same
ones that you would extract from the
original raw material source but my
question is actually pretty common they
don't try to make it quick like you
mentioned that a patient at the hospital
died from lead poisoning and that also
the only really real requirements in
Switzerland right now are to test for
CVD or THC content meaning the real 1%
and CVD sometimes I guess the test for
that thing by mixing do any of your
customers or clients actually try to
test for heavy metals because they do
test okay
I also have a lot of customers in the
police force
yeah if you know your source yeah if you
know you stuff go back there again you
need to test for heavy metals yeah what
I would really be always recommend you
to test this if you have organic hemp
where you don't use any pesticides test
four hundred seeds because this is their
entrance most toxic substance that you
can have and I mean I mean everybody
thinks if I was healthy and organic is
happy it's not actually if you don't
store your stuff my body let me keep it
dry in a dark place you have mold and
this move is very very toxic yeah in
small quantities so that's what we have
it always has
second thing is you don't know where
your stuff comes from heavy metals
because it kills you yeah I've never
seen any kind of an issue because of the
cutsy overdoses
there's so much do we have any more
questions good timing man let's hear
[Applause]