yoyoyo
be taken away to the ones that you make
some noise for DJ Eliot Jamaica
go make some noise did you happen to be
a feisty visionary oh that's a good girl
just like that that's like three times
before I get a response let's see if we
that's the second time how loud we can
get no make some noise think of the
Pullman Berlin bus get up pretty icy be
seen and it's several steps in heels I
need an image have full respect of
appealing in Deutschland hey Liza yeah
where as they see this in the strikes
Mike who's that mean by we love we love
you Berlin and we're really really happy
to be here full respect for everybody
we've got a great event for you
I'm just trying to give up people to be
quiet okay you guys we are the German
cannabis industry right here they said
it couldn't be done I was in the German
prison twelve years ago no trust me
piracy famous is nice group
two companies for trolling is for the
exponent is becomes select about each
half is happy to sleep beside miss
singularity and he shot my lady's leg
give excellent foon debts while he's
been in the famous sports world yeah
Dawson's Babu olives in here yes so make
some noise if you're happy I went to
prison because you wouldn't be here and
it's really important that
nobody goes to prison for cannabis and
everybody needs to know that and
everybody needs to know that we have to
come together as an industry okay and
there's one group that's really doing
that in Germany and they're the ICBC s
greatest strategic partner okay they're
an amazing group and what they've done
is they created a lobby to push
legalization we have medical we will
have legalization in termini to make
some noise for the deutsche humph upon
everyone dana power if you do not belong
to this organization you want to do
business in Germany you must belong to
this organization they have helped me
immensely their fearless leader is
somebody who I admire not just more than
anybody in Germany but more than anybody
in the cannabis industry almost he's an
amazing person doing a lot of things for
the industry and he is the driving force
for legalization for Germany you guys
give it up for Gilbert everybody duck
come on
nicest company the wealthiest company
and the most beautiful company of all
and that's good but what we do is making
it a little bit
United stands as he said we are the
cannabis industry we need proper
regulations we see here the German
government doesn't get it done to give
out licenses to could use cannabis in a
fair way at the moment is completely
trashed and in that situation you can
have the best company of all but you own
it anywhere we'll bet government what we
do is take a tiny proportion of big
money you let us do that by fight for
cocoa regulations for everybody for
patients for consumers and for the
business and then we make the best one
begin and with the waste then it's all
good and think about that talk to us we
have here
you can talk to us in English also and
for the ones who our when is thunders
the last little message we didn't get
Alex to be here as Fonda rocks will be
reception to be asking us to represent
this here because he likes our we spent
100 percent of our money for work for
you so for to us have fun have a nice
conference and thank you
[Applause]