this is the international
cannabis business conference Barcelona
uh
uh don't forget the party tonight at the
hotel Arts at nine o'clock also we have
discount tickets for Berlin which will
be in late June in Berlin but you can
buy the tickets here today and Nick will
be out in a minute and there's more
exhibitors upstairs and an after Nick
we're gonna go to lunch and then we have
a bunch more panels toward the end of
the day we're searching for a microphone
if you have a microphone in your pocket
give it back
we'll find it we're good we got them all
okay uh one was in the couch huh that's
what happened all right never mind we
found the microphone problem solved
thank you all for helping out we
appreciate it and now
coming to the stage he's the managing
director of Multiverse capital and the
CEO of 3C Consulting and he's gonna
break it all down for you I always look
forward to his talks when he's here
let's hear it for Nick Easley
[Applause]
I get to double fist it today with a
microphone and a clicker
yes it's a special pandas you'll see
um well yeah good afternoon
um they're gonna pull up something here
what a world that we actually get to be
here three years ago this was canceled
for a big deal I'm like now we're back
together in a room so uh very excited to
share a couple things about the global
cannabis industry
um
let's see
is this here we go almost Randy back
there he's actually the man who's
amazing
um
well I'll just get started good to go
Randy
nice
there's too many emojis in there
especially uh
yeah you'll see here momentarily
all right well I'll get started with a
little bit so we're in Spain which is
kind of interesting because you think
about 500 years ago places leaving
Europe to go and look for new resources
around the world and what we're starting
in other countries is now going to be
coming back to here so it's almost the
reverse of things about 500 years ago
so back in the day let's go look for
gold let's go find all these amazing
opportunities right because Europe
people have been here for a long time
opportunities are kind of sparse
civilization's been going on for a while
and there's not very not very common
that a new commodity or a new business
will just pop up and change a nation or
the world and that's pretty much what
we're doing here now a little disclaimer
I just have to always start I'm not a
lawyer I'm not a CPA I'm not a financial
analyst use professionals if you're
going to get into this space I've been
in the Cannabis industry for over 16
years and without good lawyers without
good accountants you are completely
screwed because this this is all brand
new and they're not going to be right
all the time but if you don't use them
and you go in this alone you will lose a
hundred percent of the time
um I will say some things that may or
may not offend you most likely depending
especially if you're from Canada
apologies in advance
um but it's just from what we've seen
from working for so long so like I said
I've been in the industry for almost 60
18 years I'm originally from Wisconsin
small little place
was in the military as foreign
so yeah was it linguist speak a few
languages got hurt in the service found
cannabis in 2006 in Colorado
so you know Colorado is kind of
important because we were the first
state to ever legalize medical for
commercial uses not like non-profits in
California in 1996.
and we're also the first state that
legalized adult use or recreational
cannabis in 2012.
so kind of a big deal that started in
2014 so I've seen this evolve from
Colorado to multiple States to Canada in
2014 Germany to now over 40 countries
that we've worked in so this just got
started right when I got into this based
on really needing cannabis as medicine
is this worth getting into this industry
be it hemp be it medical cannabis adult
use cannabis
having seen thousands of companies and
what they're doing what's working what's
not like I said largest emerging
industry in the history of the world
because it it was all illegal for so
long but it's just a plan when you think
about What's the total addressable
Market size when you think long term
this is just on adult use and medical
cannabis this isn't including all the
awesome parts of hemp like paper
textiles protein sources
Plastics all of those really sexy things
that we love him for that no one cares
about mostly they care about CBD Delta a
thc0 all these other random things they
can do with how quickly to make money
instead of the long-term sustainable
uses of hemp which will be
incredible once we are able to overtake
cotton and paper and all those things
but remember if that's a total
addressable Market of 150 billion
look at those other commodities
in the United States alone they say that
the illicit Market the illegal market
for cannabis is 150 billion already
and in the United States it's almost
half a trillion
500 billion dollars a year in alcohol
this last year almost tobacco almost 300
billion
so cannabis you know it's starting but
it's barely begun even though we've seen
it for so long I also used to be a river
guide in the Grand Canyon I just got off
the river so you're gonna see lots of
pretty pictures from the Grand Canyon
when we look at what's happening though
all around the world just remember in
the United States our country totally
illegal like it's the same as
heroin marijuana cannabis heroin same
but States unlike countries in Europe
can do what they want states have rights
and they've legalized medical and adult
use so just don't be confused when you
look at the United States map it's not
legal there as a country but in the
states it is which we'll get to
but this this has been going on for a
long time and some of us especially here
in Europe you think this is happening so
slowly because you look at what's
happening in America there's social use
consumption lounges in Las Vegas adults
21 years old they can go into a store
and buy cannabis edibles
anything
and then other states there's people
rotting in jail so the industry's really
been evolving from an adult use
standpoint with Canada taking the lead
with Uruguay Germany hopefully trying to
do something which we'll get into and
remember there's a big difference
between legalization and
decriminalization legalization allows
the commercialization like actually able
to make revenue from this and like use
Banks and taxes
the International Medical Market is what
we love it's so incredible let's get
patients medicine we're using
Compassionate Care laws and going
through those from like the United
Nations drug treaties to actually
legalize but International medical
cannabis the thing you must remember
that's a doctors writing a prescription
for something and that's an API like
active pharmaceutical ingredient in the
United States doctors make
recommendations not a prescription not
covered by insurance
recommendations everyone allowed the
industry to proliferate so everything
you hear about medical cannabis in the
United States is very very different
than International Medical and how many
doctors are willing to actually write a
prescription for something not that many
because remember the last like what 70
80 years doctors were just told that
like marijuana is the devil it's
horrible it's a narcotic it has no
medical value
we all know that's not true so that that
Paradigm is definitely changing
when you think about the United States
though you know far away not legal at
all like I said but this is where all of
the revenue all of the product
development is pretty much happening you
compare the whole world and everything
that happened this last year the United
States about 34 almost 35 billion in
revenue of medical and adult use
combined that's not the illicit Market
that's the state legal Markets Canada a
little over 3 billion
International Medical less than a
billion so almost 40 billion total and
37 of it almost or 30 35 of it almost in
the United States
and that's not even legal as a country
for the states that have done this sorry
Texas also as a medical program I had to
put the little green arrow but
you know California started this in 1996
with medical but when you look at the
adult use States now and what's
happening and almost half of the America
lives in a state where you can buy
cannabis
but it's not even legal in the country
like this is the market where you're
going to see what works what doesn't and
yes taste profiles are different every
country is completely different but the
opportunities and what we can do in in
the United States we're following
regulations of each state and states
have no idea how to do whatever
they're doing they each come up with
their own rules their own license
applications their own product
development standards for testing it's
not like the the FDA like the Food and
Drug Administration is actually telling
States what to do and what they can't do
because it's federally illegal which is
kind of crazy similar to also what's
happening in the European Union but it's
happening and it's happening faster than
you could think but many of these
markets just because they have a program
doesn't mean it's a good program some
it's like a one percent THC Market or
like low THC markets where you can't
even have flowers smokables edibles but
as soon as the program starts it always
evolves and it always gets better it's
just a matter of how long it's going to
take to get better how long it's going
to suck along the way
but eventually it's all going to get
better
so we started off 2023 we're out looking
for gold it's going to be a great
year right well when you look at
what's actually happening
I'm always talking about Portugal being
amazing which it is an international
medical cannabis long term will be so so
good but when you think about all these
public companies cutting staff cutting
companies reducing assets
they all ran over and thought they're
going to take over the world but then
sadly it didn't happen to legalize as
quickly as people thought and they're
holding all these toxic assets well
meanwhile small private companies are
like we want to be a public company like
them but they're the bed at the
same time so do you want to actually be
somebody who looks big and all fancy
that actually is billions of dollars in
debt
and asking for more money like was that
four billion dollars that can it be got
was that not enough you got to
do a 95 million
convertible note you just need more and
more you're like given like it's If
You Give a Mouse a Cookie
it's gonna ask for a glass of milk and
that's what that is
um I make fun of Canada a lot These are
times just looking at like the five-year
Public Market but Canada was the first
country to legalize adult use like
federally other than Uruguay but Uruguay
is not like a love Uruguay
so they started this since it wasn't
federally illegal they could have public
companies cool so then they started
raising all this Capital but then like
it's Canada you got less than 40
million people and they almost all live
90 live within 10 miles of the U.S
border
is it going to be that big is it is that
a great country to like grow bananas or
pineapples and Export them to the whole
world no
but they were first and they thought
that was going to be the case now
they've sadly mistaken you then look a
little bit later you're like okay Peaks
and valleys it's going to get better
eventually legalization is going to
happen all over the world and it'll be
great
and then here's today this is the entire
history of public companies in Canada
that have Assets in the United States
all over the world
if you look at that line not super fancy
there sad face
so where's this going the bottom is
cannabis just suck no
we just thought it was going to legalize
a lot faster we thought doctors would
get educated people would get on board
apparently giant commodity change
doesn't happen as fast as we'd like we
think about alcohol that's been around
for what 10 20 30 100 000 a long
time tobacco they were looking for gold
they found tobacco over there about 500
years ago they're like let's bring that
back
hmm huge commodity if only weed was
addictive how this would have been
legal already fill up British America
like they all would have like it would
have been good
but it's not so this doesn't mean that
everything sucks it just means how they
were guessing legalization and capital
raises it wasn't correct and a lot of
money has disappeared because of that
so when we think about Canada I had to
bring up I haven't seen this movie yet
but last week there was an announcement
from one of these companies that's
actually like from the 1980s like a
pharmaceutical company there was this
news like hey they got approved to have
cocaine it was like this much cocaine
for clinical trials and research and to
import leaves to do like not legalized
cocaine but everyone's like hey
weed first now this their stock just
skyrocketed they've been around for like
40 45 years they make like three million
in Revenue so nothing company they made
more on that one day in stock than
almost anyone in this room's whole
family would make in three generations
but it all disappeared because these
Bubbles and these news and people
jumping on like little things
it doesn't happen so it's like a
bear on cocaine just destroying crazy
it's not going to work out well for
anybody not even the bear
so just as you're navigating this world
especially here in Europe think about
like Don't Be Like Cocaine bear don't
hear like oh safe banking is going to
pass or like this is going to happen
Germany's gonna legalize like let's buy
millions of dollars of real estate it'll
be like just like Canada or California
or Colorado or New York or New Jersey
no this is Europe
you're it's going to be different and
don't just jump on some of these news
items
yeah again Canada
I had to say though that's it you know
that's a tundra Swan so I had to put up
the Canadian goose I used that years ago
I just love that so just don't
do what Canada did no offense Canada but
like there's a different way you can do
this in Europe so hey Europe new
opportunity it's like we discovered a
whole new continent except for in
Reverse right all the stuff we've been
doing over there but granted the
Netherlands and the coffee houses and
the genetics like the history of this
Market in Europe blessings y'all have
been dealing with the same things that
we have but just you haven't had the
same opportunities you got the
Netherlands weed experiment these Social
Clubs in Spain
Germany's new program
but when you think about
like Big Brother and big sister I like
to call these two like this is not like
States
you know countries but your members is
something that's kind of significant and
not just going to let you do whatever
the hell you want to do so when you
think about like the population the
medical Market what's happening like
German import side like amazing that the
bee farm started that the Netherlands
allowing bedrich hand back 2005 like
medical cannabis is evolving in Europe
amazingly but not fast enough and at
higher standards than anything in
America problems though
same different day these are all
the public companies here in Europe that
are like Hey we're gonna take
over the world where European public
companies they're coming to the show
about eight years after Canada
nobody's looking that great and the ones
that are actually bona fide are doing
other things not just weed
sorry it's like that's a nice picture of
to Pete's Canyon there in the Grand
Canyon like a lot so like don't fall off
the cliff don't do the same same
things are happening over here that were
happening in Canada
this is kind of a big deal I talk about
this all the time but remember December
2nd 2020
we rescheduled cannabis internationally
at the commission for narcotic drugs
pretty awesome during coronavirus
Ukraine voted for it down at the bottom
big deal
this is not even three weeks ago
the European commission literally is
suing Hungary in international court for
not voting with them
for the scheduling hungry's like oh
we're not ready for that but they all
said as part of this European commission
European Union like we're gonna do
together we're all homies they just
didn't vote to like reschedule cannabis
and they're taking them to court
what the do you think that the
European Union and the European
commission are going to do when it comes
to Germany
legalizing adult use awesome which I'm
all for it's just remember they said
like they will legalize it and draft all
their laws and I know we've talked a lot
about Germany today before me but I'm
also a realist it's not going to happen
as fast as you think it's not going to
be how most people think and Big Brother
Big Sister also dealing with a
war in Ukraine right now on your border
like
there's other things that are a little
bit more important than like how
Germany's going to legalize weed but if
they just do it for adult use it won't
be like how we do it in America and it
won't be like it's been done anywhere
else and Germany you are up they are big
huge GDP 90 million people but it won't
be the same
so when we're thinking about like look
at all the Canadian companies that came
and tried to take over Europe a whole
bunch of again
hmm like they just like put up their
feet like they're at nank we've been
thinking the world's just going to be
great we're taking over the world not
looking that great
selling those assets
switching over to Spain we're here
social use kind of consumption lounges
but not really you know we're all
medical patients with our little farms
and so forth but tolerated programs are
different than legalized programs and
what happened this last week with the
Spanish Parliament which you guys all
heard about earlier today
very much indicative of what's going to
happen other countries are going to keep
pushing bills forward just like in
America and they're going to hit a lot
of roadblocks or those Steamrollers but
at least remember like this is a
medicinal plan
we're all related
patients need safe access to Medicine
first
but medicine is really hard to like
educate doctors about and everyone's
already using this plan product so like
what modalities are going to work here
in Europe and how are you going to
capitalize and grab those opportunities
that's really what I like to help
navigate
switch into the world here Latin America
is one of my favorites I mean you look
at some of the Farms that we've helped
to develop and the things happening in
like Columbia or could be happening in
Peru with Uruguay with their adult use
side and their medical side with like
free trade zones and large cultivation
and imports it well mostly exports not
much is being imported unless it's just
for
fake news so that they can have higher
priced stocks but like massive
production going to be happening here
long term for medical and adult use
it's just where the sun grows it's the
same with like Thailand or anyone near
the equator but like major things
happening here but it's just going to
sit hold do the right thing not make a
ton of money but long term like where
does coffee come from
where do bananas come from it's not
warehouses in Canada it's not
greenhouses in Denmark it's not even
warehouses in Germany
maybe in the beginning
but it's it's all changing you think
about Africa Africa has been a little
slow South Africa was really the first
big mover and then like lesotho's
Zimbabwe and then you had like Swaziland
doing things but Africa has been a lot
more complicated than most people
thought but also like with South Africa
with sap run some of their changes like
pushing towards adult use or
decriminalization a lot of developments
have happened there but not tons of
exports yet but it's definitely one of
those markets that like long-term you
know when you're thinking about like
Malawi legalizing medical and some of
these other countries the opportunities
could be vast coming from Africa
Asia have been slow as hell Thailand was
kind of an accident where it's like they
really confused decriminalization with
legalization they did Medical in the
beginning with the university and it was
like this is awesome wow they used to
put you in jail and kill you now medical
research with the college cool and then
they're like hey decrim everyone's like
that's legalized
and then it kind of like the cat's out
of the bag right now and no one really
knows what to do including the Thai
government
but then it's one of the only countries
it's a pig's country one of those pic-s
countries where it's the same
pharmaceutical development standards as
the European Union and the FDA in
America
that's why like Thailand is like
potentially Beyond incredible long term
Oceana kind of been shitty gonna be
shitty for a while good good for the
patients anyone who thinks they're going
to take over the world from Australia
probably not the case remember in that
game of Risk it's only two troop
reinforcements every time it's not that
big it's way down there you got some
weird taxes New Zealand though like they
will pass adult use this next time
remember that last time it was shy by
like 4 000 votes like that's gangster
they can do that because they're not
part of the European commission or
European Union they're their own kind of
little thing
those are the countries like Canada that
can do some massive things so
all of this takes money we all are just
who we are but like one of the biggest
problems raising Capital right now in
this space well one we're pretty much
illegal
like we've been considered a narcotic
forever
it's an amazing plant that all of our
ancestors have used for tens of
thousands hundreds of thousands and
millions of years and like co-evolved
with it like we made our houses from it
we sail across the seas with this plant
we write our constitutions on it
and then we also like ruined a lot of
people's lives and put them in prison
for growing a plant selling a plant
I mean alcohol is legal tobacco is legal
those are great for society right only
positive things happen from those
I mean it's fun sometimes but like
swedes so like how do we raise Capital
now Family offices private institutions
it's not just saying you're going to be
some gangster internationally making a
public company and then not delivering
on those expectations once you go public
and you have shareholder value coming
down and staring down your face
you got to be ready for that scrutiny
that's why private companies I've said
this for the last decade the private
companies that can get in hold positions
scale and raise that private Capital
with the right debt loads
they're going to take over those are
going to be like the cargills those are
going to be like the Nestle's but like
not evil or you know not like not evil
but like in a good way like a good
Nestle imagine that
like that's what private companies in
cannabis could be
but so many startups remember we're a
startup industry it's brand new full of
startup companies
and 99 of those companies fail
because business is hard you got people
doing things changing regulations people
die there's Wars resource stuff
pandemics like it's hard to run
businesses if any of you do I work with
them every day internal and external so
if you're a startup in the startup
industry how can you be a good startup
even if you're around for five years ten
years you're still a startup
you're not like something that's been
around like Deloitte or something
long-term or like
Mercantile marine or like 500 year old
companies Dutch you know
so if you need Capital raising start now
plan out your business remember just
because this is cannabis industry
doesn't mean you can just everyone
thinks we're going to make all this
money this is not 10 years ago this is
not five years ago and this is not last
year
but like the capital that you need if
you need that in your business start
planning that make your models start
actually thinking is your business plan
viable can you actually do what you want
to do do the laws allow it just because
Germany might legalize in how they're
going to and you're going to do all of
this like delivery services with an app
or something cool but like
what are the key constraints for that
what are the risks how do you actually
do these businesses and anything that
you think you're going to do in Europe I
guarantee you I'll say 90
9 98 of the time we've already
experienced in the United States of
solving that problem of like pre-roll
joint packaging or like app delivery
cash management systems consumer loyalty
programs greenhouses it's not some new
light it's not some new fixture that's
going to like be the Innovative thing
that changes the world your new coconut
core or nutrient or fertilizer is
probably not that great remember this is
an agricultural commodity this is a food
manufacturing product or pharmaceutical
product and a retail consumer package
good at the end of the day and a
sacred beautiful plant that's like saved
a lot of Our Lives
and we didn't start this movement we're
not going to finish it we're just like
caretaking it for a little while here in
this time so like if you're going to do
this and raise into play Capital you've
got to do it right this is a huge
responsibility for future Generations so
the world's changing and it's
changing fast just like this is called
the Butte fault it's deep in the Grand
Canyon I love this place so trippy but
like everything's changing and evolving
and like there's forces and pressures
and heat but like how do you actually
sustain some of these forces erase
Capital you plan those companies correct
it's beautiful but then you got to be
ready to change and adapt with it
because if you don't you're gonna get
destroyed and be those Boulders at the
bottom and Europe is not going to be
that different than America happened
at least in terms of time but like we're
all people and like I said earlier
there's taste profiles there's different
preferences but this is a plant and at
the end of the day growing tons of it
oil extraction from Fields with combines
will be very very similar
to like other like corn soy wheat other
sorts of Commodities and the big
are going to take it so we only
have so much time because the big
want it it's too risky for them
to take it yet you know yeah
constellation through 4 billion into
canopy you know that happens you know
I don't want to say that four billion
dollars is a drop in the bucket but no
one's in it yet so if you're in this and
when those changes happen just like in
America when Federal legalization
happens those companies that have
massive market share and position and
all these different little States
because if I grow cannabis in Canon
California I can't sell that in a
company in Colorado like what grows in a
state has to be sold in the same state
and consumed in the state can't take it
out of the state for businesses or
people
but that's why like each State's its own
little country right now but then our
European commission or our European
Union aka the federal government America
doesn't can't really do anything like
cats out of the bag here the cat is not
out of the bag you got Netherlands
Amsterdam about to maybe take away
coffee houses and oh damn here they
just approved four more times yes
this is a great song saying like hey you
got five minutes you better be ready
yes we like that
so
you only got so much time same panda
that pan has been down the river like 14
times so uh you gotta start going faster
you got to start collaborating the
people that are with you here the things
you can learn from other lessons
that's how we grow as a species and like
I said this plant we didn't invent it it
was given to us we're at a very unique
moment in time that future Generations
will look back at and they will
judge us if we did this wrong like this
does not need to be like other things
but it is like other things so take from
those sorts of lessons and just know if
you're going to look forward into this
in the future like it just got started
you're not late to the party we just
started the dance it seems like it's
been going for what Colorado almost 10
years of recreational adult use cannabis
I mean 1996 like this has been going for
a while but it's just actually really
getting started so
I'm definitely open to some questions if
we got a couple minutes uh if anybody's
got anybody appreciate you letting me uh
share a little bit and swear a little
bit and tell you actually what's going
on in the world instead of most of the
news that you see so thank you
anybody got anything want to refute
something
educated them completely truth indeed
that's a good way to start well enjoy
lunch great to talk to you all if you've
got any questions we'll be around
outside later this afternoon but thanks
for coming this is revolutionary
[Applause]
Nick Easley everybody let's hear it for
Nick Easley
let's go to lunch we have an hour be
back at 13 45. enjoy your lunch here at
the international cannabis business
conference Barcelona 2023. don't forget
to give tickets for Berlin you can get a
discount if you get them here and the
after party tonight and please visit our
exhibits upstairs as well thank you