and coming up to discuss and analyze
Germany's recent cannabis policy
changes the founder of kfn law office
and uh kind of a big deal he's like kind
of our lawyer over here all the way from
Germany let's hear for Kai frck
[Applause]
Neeman yes
yes so great um maybe I pick a
m yes so great so uh yeah thank you ICBC
team for setting this up here and for
inviting me here for having me
here um yeah I started to visit my first
Cannabis Conference back in
2017 and uh by that time the first CBD
products came up and nobody really know
knew how to handle that from a legal
point of view so I took a deep dive into
that and u i uh started a Blog and
published some articles and because of
that I was invited to the MJ day League
conference in Toronto and became member
of the international cannabis Bar
Association and since 2017 we got a a
whole set of new regulations which I
want to introduce you today but first of
all let me say the new regulations are
in place since April this year and a big
relief went through the country uh the
big relief starting with the prosecut
UTS the judges the police and at least
the consumers so this was a really
really good decision it's not so far as
we have all wished but it's a big step
and a big relief in in Germany so U that
was a very good development and we will
take a look at the details
now yeah the CBD market so you see here
different products CBD gummies Edibles
chewing gums uh
um
Beverages and uh at the last product we
had we saw was the CBD oil but as a
cosmetic mouth care product come to that
later so the hype of CBD the CBD Market
is definitely over the enforcement of
the novel food regulations since 2019
was pretty successful and CBD oils are
no longer are not longer on the market
as food even the shelves of the big
retailers withdraw all these products
and now it is mainly marketed as a
cosmetic oral care product but this is
also very very small numbers right now
and uh we saw still partly persecution
on the ground of the narcotic act that
stopped now and we'll get a new law for
these products um as well which I will
explain
later and the um important thing is
these applications for approval as noal
food are on the way especially the
application of the European Industrial
Hemp as Association the Iha they did 80%
of the way and the final results are
expected in
2025 um the toxicological studies are on
the way there is a big um study starting
in Portugal with 400 participants
participants uh and we expect that the u
u uh authorization by the EU commission
will be granted at the end of 2025 for
full spectrum products a little bit ear
earlier for
isolates so with that you can Market CBD
products again as a supplement and as a
food
product yeah there was this one study
from Belgium a cosmetic study and they
found out that CBD has a
antibacterial effect in the cavity uh so
it's the new mouth care product 2.0 uh
as as they say it it and that was the
reason why companies started to um uh
distribute these products as a cosmetic
Oral Care spray with hemp leaf
extract and
uh then we had two decisions uh who um
uh confirmed that this um distribution
way is possible that was in Hamburg even
in the court of appeal confirmed
that uh and one in dorf that was my
decision I was working on that um and um
yeah as it is it's not food since
absorption through the oral mucosa does
not represent absorption through the
gastro International tract no
application of the NF novel food
regulation uh and uh it all also depends
on the expectation of the consumer so if
you write on the product it's only for
the overal care um then the consumer
will respect that and that was the
confirmation of the
court
but we have other Court decisions in
Berlin in munic and in B buen saying
exactly the same the opposite thing uh
so it's very hard to uh comprehend that
to to get through this uh with logic so
you have the situation that you can
distribute these products in dorf and in
Hamburg but not in the rest of Germany
so the uh authorization as a novel food
is indispensable for the CBD Market um
otherwise you we won't be able to uh to
revive this Market this Market
again okay you see this here the other
problem is which came up the last two
years is uh the uh pharmacological
effect of CBD products um and there was
one um uh decision from the colog
administrative Court saying that CBD o
CBD oil should in principle be medicinal
products even if underdosed there was in
this case it was 18 milligram CBD
recommendation intake per
day uh and uh then the news came from
the FSA from the UK uh they came came
from 70 milligram per day daily intake
and now recommend 10 milligram CBD
intake per day otherwise it would be a
medicinal product but the European court
of justice explicitly says uh that uh
you need uh exceeded that you need to
exceed a significant threshold and you
have to prove that in every case so this
decision is against European Court
decisions you against European law uh
but we will have to take a look on this
this will be U probably uh will be U
yeah in the courtroom again with this
question but of course the results of
the no food application from the AA will
be taken into account as well they just
finding out that this is
safe okay then we have the other CBD
Market we have U flowers and hemp leaf
tea there's a great demand very popular
in Germany CBD flowers they are all over
the place from from the south of Germany
to the north of Germany sold in Kiosk
and petrol stations and supermarkets
Etc uh but the LA law enforcement de CBD
flowers as an arotic due to a possible
risk of
intoxication um police raids and Court
sentences against Traders happen on a
daily basis still still right now uh and
the problem is uh that in Annex one of
the narcotic act and now in the in the
kakang in the consume cannabis law there
was this Clause that a misuse of
intoxication has to be ruled out how can
you intoxicate yourself with hemp anyone
has an
idea okay the the the high court of
Germany the federal uh the federal high
court of justice said if you bake 15
gram of CBD flowers into a cookie and
DEC carboxilate it bake it and then eat
it there may be the chance that you can
intoxicate yourself with 50 milligram of
THC yeah U you have to pay €50 for that
um and you have to eat this
why these this brownie then but that was
the uh the the the the yeah that was the
the consequence of this um expert saying
2,000 in one of these cases um that this
might be possible and because of that
all the police rates and all the
sentencing uh took place so but now we
get a new law uh the uh draft is already
there the associations can take part in
in a hearing and is scheduled to come
into Force at the 1st of January
2025 uh and this law will delete these
misuse of intoxication Clause big big
big progress for the whole sector we had
Farmers confiscating or we had
prosecution officers confiscating whole
hemp Fields whole hemp Fields because of
this clause and uh it's really really
about time that this will that this will
stop and uh CBD flowers and hemp Leaf te
will be freely marketable after the 1 of
January
um and um but of course it's 0.3 not
like 1.3 like here in like in the Czech
Republic we heard or what you guys are
introducing here and if you have
a if you have such a low threshold for
THC the practice was that uh the
genetics from Switzerland they have 0.5
0.6 0.7 too much for the German market
so what did they did they do they washed
it down in washing streets with solvents
uh and added and by that you wash away
as well the CBD and the Turpin and you
have product which is like nothing you
rape the plant so to say and then you
add um artificial turpins and CBD again
on the product so that you have a smell
and that you have CBD on it um and then
you sell it in the German Market I think
this is unbearable practice has to stop
somehow so please think about better
genetics because the consumer wants
these butlike uh uh products and you
can't get that with 0.2 or 0.3 with a
European variety you need another
variety like 0.5 0.6 uh but um this
product shouldn't be on the market uh in
in any in in the in the first place so
let's see how this will
develop okay yeah we have to to uh to
love we we suit the for two clients we
suit the federal government of Germany
on the grounds of the free movement of
goods principle because these CBD
flowers are legal in Austria Belgium and
Luxembourg so we said if they are legal
there they have to be legal in Germany
on the grounds of the free movement of
goods principle these lawsuits are
pending in at the administrative Court
of brke right now uh and if the law
comes at in effect at the 1 of Jan
these um law fluts lawsuits are
Obsolete and but I talked to the judge
and he's thinking about having a hearing
uh this Autumn so maybe this decision
comes first or the change of the law
comes first we have to
see okay conclusions CBD oils extracts
isolates are not marketable as food now
CBD infus Edibles beverages gummies Etc
CB D oils as cosmetic Oral Care Products
partly marketable certain regions of
Germany if correctly
labeled uh we have the novel food
authorization by the ukom commission
indispensable now marketability of CBD
flowers we will see CBD cosmetic and CBD
liquids are marketable if no Health
claims are made I forgot
[Music]
to yeah here you have
um you have to write on the label with
these Oral Care Products it's not
suitable for
consumption you have to spit it out
after certain seconds and do not swallow
that's what you have to label on the
product there so pretty silly and not
good for
marketing okay then we have hhc as well
on the German Market very popular two
years uh eventually it was stopped in
June this year due to an amandement of
the new psychoactive Substances Act so
hhc H4 CBD thcp they are all banned Now
by federal
law um and uh the new uh cannaboids are
already there 10 hhc or 10 hydroxy uh
and I think you can't win the race
against the development of new
semisynthetic cannabinoids you better
take the check rout as we learned this
morning regulate them all or regulate
all non internationally regulated
substances or products in a in a special
law and uh don't push it into the
illegal Market again uh issue licenses
take care of prevention take care that
the uh the Traders are obliged to give
information material prevention in
information Etc I think this is the
better way but we because you can't you
can't win this race
same with katom not very popular unless
unlike in the Czech Republic when you go
to Cana Fest in
Prague uh you will see Kum everywhere
they are selling it in the booth on the
on the grounds there uh so that was the
reason why Czech Republic is taking care
of this I
guess and um it's good that they have
this this approach with this new cycl
motor Substances Act we suggest that
from the organizations to the Ministry
of Agriculture to do the same and the
Ministry of Health in Germany let's see
how this will develop if uh the Czech
Republic makes progress on
that okay then adult use U yeah we
started in November
2021 uh the new Coalition came into
place and the Coalition negotiations
took place and uh they said we are
introducing the controll distribution of
cannabis to adults for consumption
purposes in licensed source so a
complete commercial route was intended
to for all these for all these um
esteemed uh goals like Health protection
child and use protection product quality
and illegal market and crime
displacement what came out was what we
see now uh there were several legal
problems along with this legalization
especially the single convention the
mother of all evil um which restrict the
traits of cannabis to Scientific and
medical purposes article
four there were several solutions to
solve these
International
obligations like Canada like a
respectful non-compliance which which
Canada does unscheduling of cannabis
very unlikely U amandement um uh via a
simple procedure how also highly unlegal
but could trigger useful political
debate and uh the most popular was the
termination of the single convention uh
and the re accession with the
reservation of cannabis that was what U
Bolivia did for Koka and that was the
model what we thought the German
government would do uh for for cannabis
and then these inter modification
procedures then you can uh negotiate uh
trade deals with Canada for example that
um you can modify the rules of the
single convention interp
partis and start trading cannabis
recreational
Cannabis but this was too complicated
too much time too much effort involved
too much diplomatic and uh political
issues so the German government decided
not to do that um and the European
problems is article 71 of the Shen
contract this is only relevant for
transborder situations so not really a
problem but this article two of the
framework
decision G also talked about this
morning um and uh saying the same like
the single convention uh only uh for uh
scientific and medical purposes but uh
jinri pointed this as well it's article
two number two
uh exclusively for their own personal
consumption as defined by national law
and this rule or this black letter law
uh came was interpreted like this that
you can have two columns uh column one
and column two column one is deep
criminalization of 25 program possession
in public and 50 g at home homegrown of
three living plants Harvest limited to
50 gr successively harvesting was one
phrase in the reasoning of the law uh if
you now about cannabis you know if if
you have to harvest you have to harvest
the whole plant and you can't
successively harvest the plant so very
silly and uh cannabis cultivation clubs
for Collective home growing because they
are privileged under a un agreement and
EU law so that was the results now
Edibles allowed now exraction allowed
except of CBD but hashish and life Rosen
um this is because our health Minister K
laak was in Canada and always heard the
stories of little kids and child having
to go to hospital because they were
eating Edibles with THC because their
parents didn't secure that properly and
so he said now edibles but wasn't
thinking about that you can have life
Rosen with high concentrates uh
concentration of THC as well so you you
see it's not so easy to set up logic and
sound cannabis law column two model
projects we'll see in a
minute yeah um exactly oh hang
on yeah you see here details column one
cannabis handling almost everything is
still forbidden it's forbidden
possession possession growing producing
trade import export um to obtain
cannabis or to dispense or distribute
cannabis so if you have your own Harvest
of 50 gram and you give 50 gr to your
neighbor or to your friend criminal
offense not possible if you use your
cannabis for a fat extraction at home to
uh to produce
cookies not allowed fat is an extraction
is a solvent uh not allowed criminal
offense so uh but then we have these
exemptions so so it's a very very uh
restrictive approach and you have to
find your way through that
law yeah we have the consumtion bands
bands in public areas 100 meter from
kindergartens
playgrounds um prohibition of
consumption near children and minors
also for medical pish patients this is a
real disadvantage in comparison to the
former legal
situation and numerous new conflicting
panel and fine regulations it's a sexy
we have 45
paragraphs sometimes they are
contradicting themselves um so uh really
crazy uh this law needs a a rehaul very
very soon to make it sound again um yeah
cannabis possession consumption still
stigmatized by this
law okay then we have seeds and clowns
uh seats were deemed as an n otic ever
since in Germany not like in Czech
Republic or in Spain uh and the new law
took over the um definition the
International International definition
for cannabis means the flowering or
fruiting tops only if you have fling or
fluting tops it's cannabis in the sense
of the law so quite easy if the Cannabis
is not flowering it's not cannabis you
can trade it you can legally trade it uh
you can give it away to a a colleag or
friend or whatever uh and um what
happened then is that
um the seed importation for hom growing
cation clubs from within the EU is
possible as seeds are not listed in the
single
convention uh and also domestic
commercial trade is possible that's
clear by now but what's not possible to
produce seeds because if as long as the
seed is at the plant uh it's cultivation
of can and you don't have a license to
do so unless you are a cultivation club
which is which are not in operation
right now uh so uh like a miracle uh the
seed is uh separated from the the plant
and you have a legal product because
it's not cultivation anymore uh very
strange
so and you can't import it from third
countries uh because you have to um uh
because the EU EU law forbids that you
can't import hemp from third countries
then you have to have a special
permission and you have to talk to the
EU commission Etc so they somehow have
to appear in the European Union then
they are legal um and that's um yeah we
have to deal with that um but the um the
clowns is a problem we had couple of
seizures of clowns from commercial
Traders uh because there was a very
misinterpret uh reasoning to the law
which says if you cut the catling put it
plant it in uh then it is a Seedling and
In This Moment it's cannabis again okay
uh that was in the reasoning uh um it
was taken over into a commentary in a in
a law commentary uh and this was the
reason for police to go after clone
Traders again
uh it's wrong it's so obviously wrong
because the definition is clear if there
is no flowering top it's not cannabis we
will have to see how that will work out
but in fact in principle we have two new
legal products on the market which is
seeds and
clones yeah some more details of column
one we have the cultivation associations
yeah go through that um it's uh it's a
bureaucratic overkill for for cannabis
clubs uh we have
280 uh applications right now uh in in
in whole of Germany uh a couple of
handful were were granted uh
authorization already uh but under
reservation because uh the prevention
officers haven't been appointed yet
because there were no C courses for
these prevention officers which they
have to uh fulfill which they have to do
because they weren't yet so
um I don't think this cannabis
Association model will be a success uh
let's see if a couple of clubs next year
will be able to be uh
to uh be able to yeah to put some
products on the market maybe a handful I
guess but not really on a large scale
throughout throughout Germany and yeah
this was driven by over complying with
International and EU obligations
and a healthy policy alism by the
federal health Ministry rather than a
human rights and Justice
approach
okay yeah the model project there were a
bit of confusion the last couple of
weeks because the city of weisbart
together with other cities announced
that they will apply for model projects
um without a new law defining that uh
the government in the first first place
said um we um want a new law we want
these uh these aspects being being
covered uh and um you need to have a an
Institutional a legal framework for for
model projects like the Switzerland does
and with the framework in place you
can't have model projects in in my
opinion um but um let's see how they how
they will how they will do it this
situation will be clear will develop
will show will turn out in the next
couple of months three to four month I
guess uh but as we saw in the
Netherlands and in Switzerland the the
the the phase from the first idea of a
model project to really implementation
to the real implementation of the model
project took five years so we are far
away from from implementing model
projects even if we get a new law uh and
a proper uh framework which implements
that um yeah but it's cannabis it's
never be uh boring and always something
to
do okay medical
cannabis I think I have 26 minutes we
have Peter homberg this afternoon
talking about Metal cannabis uh I think
I will skip that and uh
uh I'm open for questions yeah takeaways
CBD Market stays complicated no real
changes new legal products seeds and
clones and medical has a lots of
potential we see we
saw uh skyrocketing prescription numbers
uh skyrocketing import volumes uh at the
end of the year I would be surprised uh
that what kind of numbers what what
number of tons we will have been
imported and how many patients we will
have in in Germany so let's see thank
you very much let's he we have time for
one maybe one question if you don't have
any question questions that's okay one
anyone ber all right let's move on Kai
Fredick nean
[Applause]
everyone that was great and I think you
have the best suit that I've everyone
here