you can hardly see police you know
embarrassing people for a joint so I
remember when you went to jail and there
was a movement here in Slovenia to free
B we cannabis scientists we know that
cannabis has no influence on the driving
when you are regular user I don't know
what your audience think about former
Yugoslavia but former Yugoslavia was not
the Eastern block I have an important
question to ask you Bojo how old were
you when your first smoke we
[Music]
we are in Slovenia lublana and today we
get to interview someone who is uh very
special in terms of the Cannabis
industry and the Cannabis uh movement
and one of my best friends uh in
Slovenia and I just want to welcome the
one and only boa rishit uh to the
program how you doing Bojo hello I'm
honored to be with you man we're honored
to have you dude um we were actually
just having dinner last night at our
favorite place uh the restaurant uh Bojo
and I we like to go out and uh eat uh
meat on the grill because uh that's what
we do here in the
Balkans uh boo why don't you just tell
us a little bit about uh Slovenia just
describe in in your own
words uh how you feel about Slovenia how
would you would describe Slovenia to uh
someone else
else H Slovenia generally is a miniature
country but uh we have everything you
know we have a beautiful sea we have
mountains in Slovenia you can ski and
swim in two hours
difference uh we have still quite
healthy
environment but the only thing we don't
have yet in Slovenia is can good
cannabis policy good cannabis policy but
uh when I'm walking around the streets
here in
lublana uh I see weed everywhere I I
actually get to smoke my joint uh with
impunity it seems the cops this I've
lived in a lot of different countries
and though the Cannabis policy here uh
needs to modernize for sure um they say
uh implementation is 90% of the law and
so when you're on the ground here and
you're and you're and you're smoking
weed and the you know some places you
feel the cops you feel this like this uh
we would call a police state right but
in Slovenia in ter uh uh in comparison
to all the other places I've lived on
the planet it does not feel so much like
a a police state can you speak to that
at all yes of course uh generally
speaking you know police uh regarding
cannabis is way
more tolerant uh than our bureaucrats
because uh we achieved through l 15
years many ver verdict on the Supreme
Court and police is following it so uh
nowadays you cannot find almost any
police who will uh put charges on some
uh patient who is growing for himself
you can hardly see police uh you know
embarrassing people for a joint in
lublana you can openly smoke almost
everywhere uh so
in practice is way better than in theory
say I yeah no and I think everywhere uh
on the planet you see a disconnect with
where the people are at with where
versus where the politics are at but a
lot of times you'll find the police are
in line with the politics and so
there'll still be cracking skulls for
for for yeah not in Slovenia there are
some data that almost one3 of Slovenian
are using cannabis on regularly almost
oneir almost one3 and I think also many
police is uh in this onethird of the
population for me it seems very accepted
it seems that everybody when you bring
up like when I tell people what I do
here in Slovenia everybody's everybody's
interested and everybody's curious and
I've had nobody say or I felt I've never
felt I can hardly think of one one
example where someone like
uh recoiled had some visceral recoil
because I told them something that they
were just appalled by no it's actually
on the contrary exactly people are so
open in Slovenia so why do you think the
public is so because I've lived in other
European countries also and it's not
like it is in Slovenia I've lived in
Holland also and it's not as open that
in for General Society here it just
seems like people really just don't give
a [ __ ] they just know that it's cannabis
is a benign plant they just in general I
think people don't give a [ __ ] here and
what I mean by that is they they they
think you do your thing I do my thing we
leave each other alone is that kind of
what's going on here yes more or less
more or less and this is the result of
the our movement or let's say activism
in last 15 years you know uh because we
didn't we were mostly focused on the
patients and the sick people mhm not on
the smoking M yeah yeah and uh with this
especially if you have a lot of
scientific data
behind uh you you turn over the public
opinion against some things mhm you know
uh we already started and the one reason
is also because we organized like 10
scientific conferences until now mhm uh
back in the days when I was in jail it
was everywhere in on the national
television all newspapers you know
magazines and this is when people start
to think really you know when so I
remember when you went to jail and there
was a there was a movement here in
Slovenia to free bjo yes um and that's
that's still your email domain to the
state can you tell us what happened
because as far as I know you went
on a hunger strike in prison yes I went
on a h hunger strike interesting times
uh yeah the I was I had open one old
case from
2008 uh but I wasn't prosecuted for 4
years and then in
2012 uh they imprisoned me uh because of
uh few
plants you know on my garden
uh but I openly grow cannabis since I
don't know 20 or more years I never hid
it because you cannot hide a 4 met plant
on your in your garden you know um so I
knew it was very unjust because it was
for actually very small amount yeah you
know and uh the judge
was let's say not very happy with
cannabis because I live in very rural
area on the Hungarian border and the
situation there is way different than in
lublana you know uh I used to have a
friend he unfortunately died he I met
him in prison where he got in morco soot
a one year prison for one gram of wheat
one gr was that a possessions charge or
did they somehow get for cultivating or
Distributing too no just possession just
possession year for that how long ago
was that uh 12 years only 12 years ago
and you don't just to to to interject do
you think that would happen now no not
even in your area and that was also
unjust in in in uh for that time it was
an abnormal case very abnormal case and
I didn't know actually that it happened
until uh I went to the jail and he was
in the same cell with me and he
presented me the papers you yeah because
Canabis you know in
Slovenia let's say 20 15 years ago was
uh easy money for police for prosecutors
for attorneys and for J yeah so that's
what I mean about the police state
usually the police will or a lot of
jurisdictions they'll go for that
low-lying fruit so how did that
change they realized that it's
counterproductive you know uh I I am
helping people since 2012 when I was in
jail I can tell you that we freed uh at
least 15 or 20 people on the Supreme
Court who were already uh already um no
convicted so you know so your activism
work started setting new precedents yes
uhhuh all the way to the all the way to
the Supreme Court mhm yeah I was lucky
to have a good uh friend uh
very high in this circles lawyer and so
on and he advised me how to do it but uh
I was always calling out the human
rights you know the human rights aspect
of why we should cannabis prohibition of
course we have listen cannabis is the
most research plant on the planet more
than 150,000 studies it means like seven
studies a day
are published on cannabis and we are
still imprisoning people because they
want to help themselves you know this is
this is really crazy because none of
those who were convicted was uh
trafficker it was always just for
themsel growing growing cannabis at home
you know so you're talking about a lot
of convictions in Slovenia we're just
for cultivating at home cultivating most
mostly in possession uhhuh it was never
trafficking even mentioned but you know
courts and uh prosecutors they
somehow put on the on this Eagle Eagle
uh equal scale yeah it should not be
trafficking is trafficking and
possession is something else for sure
yeah I mean I think it all should be we
are we both think it all should be legal
but when you're looking at it from a
legal lens clearly one's more benign
than the other I would say legal you
know legal uh I agree but uh cannabis is
legal in Slovenia like right now
legality it means that we have certain
laws about cannabis but it should be
regulated
more more logically and more uh
towards patient orientated you know so
if you could what would you do if if you
could snap your fingers and make new
policy now in Slovenia what would you do
and is there any are there any other
countri countes in Europe or the or
America or the or states in America or
the world that you see as um
exam examples to use for Slovenia
uh if I pick from different countries
different regulations we can put
something good together you know what I
mean because always something what
should not be Let's uh for example Czech
Republic yeah they legalized how many 15
years ago yeah where we are now and uh
last year when I was on Cana Fest the
police is still bothering people for
smoking a joint on the cannabis event
you know it's really don't but still
they can AFF Fest their police still
because I knew I heard they were
sometimes at cultiva a couple years very
also in cultiva many people are losing
their driver's license you know because
they are checking this is another issue
with cannabis uh you know it's crazy
America when they used to just uh cops
used to just sit outside the Grateful
Dead wait till the Grateful Dead
concerts were over and just bust people
but you know very similar yeah very
similar but we we cannabis users and
cannabis scientist let's put it that way
we know that cannabis has no influence
on the driving when you are regular
user well that's funny and sorry if you
don't mix it with alcohol of course yeah
of course well that's funny you say that
because there I think there's two
studies done on that there was a study I
think in Jamaica done about that uh
driving in cannabis and you know I think
that's the dirty little unknown secret
you know that all us cannabis users
clearly know that you're not impaired
because it's a matter of impairment you
know cuz I know when I've had three or
four drinks in a couple hours maybe if I
know I probably shouldn't drive you know
but when it comes to cannabis you it you
just you know your impairment level each
individual knows their impairment level
so there was another study done by I
think it was sanj Gupta when he came out
with that second uh CNN that his first
one was the charlott's web which blew
everything up you know which really
helped the the movement in America and
Beyond and then the second he said
that's was their conclusion is they did
a they did a an experiment and they had
a two I guess you'd call them test
groups not a control group but their
there was the the drivers who were uh
who were had smoked not see this is the
point just because you smoke pot doesn't
mean you're stoned so there was the
drivers that smoked pot that had smoke
that were regular pot smokers and then
there was the drivers who smoked pot
that were uh uh not regular uh pot
smokers and clearly uh the drivers with
that could uh that were regular users
were were not impaired they they drove
perfectly fine and the the ones who
weren't used to cannabis and were just
high as [ __ ] you know it's like you
wouldn't recommend to anyone who who was
a novice uh you know it's like hey if
you're going to smoke don't don't drive
so I think these are like really
interesting almost esoteric uh facts in
the Cannabis world that make cannabis
something like you know it in alcohol
you can even in alcohol there's there's
hey you could have8 08 in your system
and some people be able to drive better
than others yes and some people are not
able with uh 0.2 in the system ex
exactly therefore the doctor's job is to
determine your impairment exactly
exactly no not just because I have
metabolites in the blood you know I I
smoke for
47 years now cannabis I have to knock on
wood I never had car accident and I
smoke all the time you know me yeah uh
so uh I can clearly say it doesn't
affect driving you drive slower you
drive way more careful right especially
than on alcohol but there is another
senses are heightened too of course
there is also another thing last year I
was on
the Parliamentary committee for health
health committee and there was also a
guy from
police Ministry of uh Internal Affairs
and he was you know giving us some data
on the traffic accident and so on so
alcohol is responsible for more than 30%
of all uh ex car accidents in
Slovenia and you can have up to
0.5 you know is that what it is in
Slovenia yes
0.5 uh you don't pay a fine and later if
you're drunk as hell you can get your
driver's license back on pero mhm you
know uh and you pay some fine the in
cannabis or all drugs in Slovenia are
responsible for 0.3% of the all
accidents uhhuh uhhuh and you pay 100
1,800 Euro fine and uh they take your
driver's license away for what yeah and
they take it if you're driving I heard
in Germany they take your driver's
license if you just get caught with
cannabis in your system even if you're
driving or not yes
it's crazy you know it should not be uh
and there is another issue which I want
I hope that I will uh soon bring
somebody's case to the Supreme Court uh
because nowadays also in uh Public
Service Services uh public jobs let's
say you know Court police and so you
should not use cannabis at all do they
drug test yes and this is completely
against the Constitution because if you
are my uh
employer it's not your business what I
do outside of my working time yeah yeah
yeah until I uh I fulfill my
contract uh with you as the employer do
they add prescription drugs to that
also uh not really not really just
ilicit drugs just elicit drug drugs but
you know elicit drugs are more than 400
uh in on the list but they just check a
few cocaine
heroin and uh cannabis and
methamphetamines maybe and such no but
again here is the here's the the Crux of
the issue I think is impairment if
you're driving are you impaired or not
if you're at work are you doing a good
job or not are you in and I think a lot
of this stuff I know a lot of this stuff
in America has to do with liability
issues and so they've got to they've got
to put the blame on someone at some time
yes uh the system and so they'll they'll
basically you know because of liability
they'll have to be like well hit a canis
well no you even though that's mistake
was made but but it we can't associate
it with you being impaired it's some
maybe other spous thing that happened
that well you've got to go you drug
tested no so but this could be a good
employee but then the system is
compelled to fire them or let them go
because of liability stuff is that
similar in Slovenia at all because I
generally in Europe they don't have
quite as much liability Europe is very
very very strange on this issue of
cannabis and drugs you know because
Europe have a big uh bureaucrat system
and it's divided from Europe to the
national
and Europe is not good example for
anything uh on the field of drugs but uh
there are some
uh bright lights I'll just talk about
drugs makes me want small yeah uh you
know there are bright lights like uh
Malta now uh Germany especially because
Germany is very strong country in
European Union
Luxembourg and others but the differ you
know we live in the same countries it's
similar like in the states in California
or in you can smoke anywhere everywhere
but in Arkansas they will lock you up
for 20 years right right right right
right you know it's it's crazy and uh I
think that punishment and the uh
the policies towards any drugs should be
based on
scientific data not just because use
drugs you know do you think it's going
to change and and doesn't I hope so and
do you think obviously the EU has to or
the UN and the EU have to change their
their mandates towards towards drug
policy or or Germany just has to do what
Canada does and just say [ __ ] it we're
going to do what we what we want you
can't really how punitive can you be
against us or towards us uh if if it's
Germany the economic engine so I'm not
sure if Germany will good example for
Germany now you mentioned Germany is
that they asked European Union if they
agree you know with the changes on
cannabis policy in Germany and they
didn't but they did it anyway right you
know what I mean right so it can be done
right it can be done and more uh more
States or more countries will join this
club easier will be for others so so for
Slovenia are they ever going to they're
so small you know we only have so much
arable land here are they uh where do
you think uh where's Slovenia is uh
niche in terms of the Cannabis Market in
Europe the niche is knowledge
science and boutique products we don't
have big areas like Ukraine or you know
other big countries to have thousands of
hectares of hemp Slovenia is 22,000
square kilometers
you know it's that's a size of New New
Jersey yeah something like that uh but
uh maybe
until last September when you organized
the ICBC in uh in Blade you didn't even
realize how much knowledge is already in
Slovenia you know how many people are uh
uh working on the Cannabis research from
hops Institute to everywhere actually
yeah and uh this event was very good
because we showed the Cannabis and all
the movement from different angles so
you have a company uh you're not just an
activist you're a businessman also uh
tell us a little bit about your company
uh research nature
yes uh it's all started back in
2014 when I realize that there will be
no changes if you don't do it properly
so I start
organizing uh scientific conferences MH
I uh I invited people the best uh
researchers uh researchers from all over
the
world uh and
we started that way then I realized that
it's not enough if I want to do
something or we all together want to do
something with this field we have
to take scientific approach so I or uh I
founded research nature Institute with
my unfortunately late um partner from
Slovakia uh the guy had a prostate
cancer and he was cured of it now he
died from some other things uh which
were uh we will not talk about this
today uh and he bought us
uh uh gcms so you know gas
chromatography because one of the goals
was I wanted to prove to our uh
government that there is no influence on
driving uh under
the when you smoke cannabis so uh there
was a project with Ministry of internal
affairs and police where we wanted
because we have some polygons in ransco
for safe driving you know where we
wanted to
prove what is the influence of cannabis
on the average but they stepped back and
you know because they know uhuh there is
no
influence but then again already back in
2015 we started to profiling the
Cannabis products uh which are on the
black market people buying from dealers
you know or
suppliers and uh then step by step we
developed then uh you know lot of
product projects going
on then with my uh colleague
Roman uh we someh how succeed I still
don't know how that was with that was
with University of L yes yes so there
was an idea Roman you know Roman stukel
he was on the faculty of Health Sciences
doing some other things
and he said uh listen we could do
something would you buy Dad UV detector
for cannabinoids you know and maybe we
start profiling cannaboids and I said of
course you know and that's when you
started working with the University of
Lan yes so first we bought I bought our
our Institute bought thead
detector and when the we got the gcms we
signed the agreement of cooperation and
I in installed the GCM at the machine on
the in the laboratory of faculty in
lublana
uhhuh so that was the start until now we
um participated on 12
phds with our machine with our help
uhhuh uh we are profiling for uh for
patients for Growers for
industry uh you know
so as any other thing it's Dev in
through through years if people want to
reach out to you uh is there a website
you can go to research.com
research.com yes but you know uh
Slovenia is so small that hardly anybody
is this just for slovenians or can other
people outside of Slovenian participate
it's uh outside we also do some uh
profiling for big companies
uhhuh uh but still we are growing muh
you know and you have to start small and
well for sure and Slovenia is small it's
a great place to Beta products I I think
and uh if you can make it in Slovenia I
think you can make it uh anywhere and uh
what's what's great about what you said
is Slovenia does have it's like a A
Little Switzerland a little Holland a
little Israel that's how I feel when I'm
here a little bit of everything yeah and
the people have this connection they're
very high Highly Educated people I think
it's the Dutch and the slovenians that
speak the most languages per country uh
uh uh per individual uh on average and
and when I'm here I'm really Blown Away
by the the talent uh in Slovenia and all
the research capabilities you know we've
had meetings with uh all the all the
people we've had meetings with all these
institutions and uh it's uh it's a high
level of uh work that they that they do
and uh I think it's only a matter of
time that I agree with you I think that
slovenia's Niche is research and
development and I'm excited toh see
where where that goes but uh but I have
an important question to ask you Bojo um
so how old were you when you first when
you first smoke weed 13 13 where was
that in mka so in Mora behind the school
behind the school yes did you get
high you know cuz sometimes you smoke
the first couple yeah not I didn't get
high the first time I either not really
I was 12 yeah but you know back in the
days that was
1975 uh-huh nobody bothered us because
of cannabis it's all started later when
let's say after
the 2000 so that was actually one of my
questions so it started after 2000
interesting what was the Canabis scene
like in Yugoslavia because that in the
70s was obviously Yugoslavia it was
elicit drug it was ilicit nobody but
nobody gave a [ __ ] so kind of like kind
of like now or in like now now like no
it was you know hard to buy hard to get
but it was everywhere I studied in in
lublana everywhere everybody was smoking
cannabis you know yeah but more hiding
it was more private it's not it's not
open like today but no body went to jail
actually and who was using cannabis then
did did it have a certain demographic
like the the the the the the the artists
quote unquote or was it the the workers
or was it students you know fessors yeah
it was still a hippie movement back in'
70s uhhuh yeah you know yeah because uh
I don't know what your audience think
about former Yugoslavia but former
Yugoslavia was not the Eastern block we
could go anywhere with Yugoslavian so I
think that's a really good distinction
that the audience should know because I
uh it's a it's a very it's a big
misconception that Yugoslavia was part
of the Eastern block which meant that it
was part of the Soviet Union which meant
that it was more of a stalinistic
communism not at all it wasn't it was a
Tito communism which is bordering on
like heavy socialism I think the biggest
distinction cuz I remember growing up
you know in the 70s and ' 80s and and
and thinking the Soviet Union was the
most evil place in the world solely
because you couldn't leave the country
without special permission and we had
people that would defect and that was
always like a big thing um but I but but
but in Yugoslavia you didn't have that
restriction correct no you could you
could go travel anywhere yeah with
Yugoslavian pport passport could travel
to Moscow or to Afghanistan or to yeah I
remember there was United States
wherever that the Yugoslavian passport
actually could go to more countries than
an American passport for a while or yes
uh actually Yugoslavia was a promised
land for Easter block mhm because uh
hungarians bulgarians everything
surrounding it they they could not go to
the vest but they could go to Slovenia
to Yugoslavia really really interesting
because Czechs slovaks hungarians they
uh visited
Yugoslavia U the coast Dalmatian Coast
as a tourist really oh I didn't know
that that's fascinating but so they
could go as a tourist but then couldn't
they if they wanted to escape then from
CAA
was you know I live just in Hungarian
bord and my
uh uh Aunt lived in um Hungary uhhuh and
always when uh their um family came over
one of family has to stay home so I get
it you know what I mean yeah so you can
go but somebody is behind oh my God yeah
and I think that's the reason most
people didn't defect because of those
yeah that's that's a really good point
but interesting I didn't know that they
had the privilege to come into
Yugoslavia so they could go to they
could go to De brck or split or
something oh W that's that's interesting
so the Cannabis scene but then you said
in
okay so then Yugoslavia breaks up
Slovenia becomes a country what in ' 91
something like that yes and then and
then it then you then it got bad for 10
years is or things started decline first
10 years it was a chaos uhhuh more or
less but then in 2000 we accepted uh uh
the law about the illicit drugs uhhuh
and then the
bureaucrats saw their opportunity and
police and they started to really push
you know oh so it started to get bad in
2000 yes in 2000 was and then after this
uh that because Slovenia was coming into
the EU and wanted to be a good boy or
whatever no just because the new law you
know just because of the new law uh
because always when the new law is
introduced they want to show that they
are fulfilling everything but uh it
doesn't uh last for long you know uh um
because uh they mixed up criminal law
with the minor uh offenses because since
2000 nobody in Slovenia or yugos
Slovenia sorry should not be jailed for
possession of any illicit drug because
possession is not a criminal offense
trafficing Cas yeah yeah yeah so that's
when you say drugs are or cannabis is
legal you kind of you said before that's
the qualifier right there uhhuh yes uh
but the problem is that every bureaucrat
or every police or every prosecutor you
know try to push a bit more so yeah well
so but they they can't and when you say
try the prosecutor would then have to go
for well they're trafficking or
something right because they can't get
them for possession and for trafficking
they have very very stupid reasons like
too high electricity
consumption or if you are unemployed and
you have plants at home you will sell
them and such a [ __ ] you know so
without any evidence and this is what we
start to fight and today you know a
friend of mine the doctor medical doctor
grew for his wife cannabis because he
has cancer and police came they want to
prosecute him but it stops on the
first level on the court you this is not
a criminal offense yeah right right so
the police will still sometimes try to
yes push where they can and then at the
generally the first level especially
some rookies in police uhhuh you know
they want to prove themsel mhm but
uh before Slovenia had around 2,500
criminal cases on cannabis a year on two
two million people that's a lot mhm you
know yeah
but that's a lot that's a lot it's two
and a half or it's 1
1.25% yeah uh not as much as in the
States but a lot it's a lot well I don't
know per capita that's almost as much as
the states maybe per capita but not
today anymore not today anymore if they
don't catch you with really big big big
amount with some proof of trafficking
you will just get fine or not even this
I feel extremely safe so was that the
time you became an
activist yeah the the activist what is
activism you know yeah uh when you
proactively started to the first the big
jump into activism was when I was impr
prisoned you know then I was stupid and
stubborn enough that I said [ __ ] you I
go on the H hunger strike and how long
did you go on your hunger strike for oh
82 days 82 days yes
I lost like 28 kilo I was like in a you
lost 28 kilos that'd be about almost
65b almost 1/3 of 1/3 of my weight yes I
lost that's that's crazy it was
interesting time yeah I bet but I
remember it and you got a lot of but
then they dropped the charges right you
know I just got on pero for one year so
uh it was the fight between me and the
judge uh-huh because you know he
expected to be there and say I'm sorry
I'm sorry and so not but I fight back
uhhuh you know I fight back I was
fighting with the prosecutor I was
fighting with the judge uh then I uh
achieved that I got another judge
because I proved this was was corrupt
and stupid uhhuh you know so did you got
the judge switched yeah yeah I was
yelling on him as hell oh my God you
know the cour that takes balls man yeah
I know but I was in investigation prison
you know they could lock me up to 10
years what I have to
lose they can lock you up they can keep
you there for 10 years because they they
uh they charge me as organization and
it's 5 to 15 oh my God not three to
that's insanely scary and so that means
you had to have even bigger balls you
weren't just facing a
year oh my God and when you are in
investig prison you know you don't have
contact for to OU the world you have
telephone call right to your lawyer and
your family and they are all uh
listening uh you don't have internet you
don't have telephone you it's really
hard to communicate you have to write
letters and your lawyer comes your
lawyer you communicate through your
lawyer who comes to you yes I had the
best lawyer uh ever imagined because he
done everything what I want to do from
him so he was there just as a that's
great that's great and he told me Mr
rishit this we will not want you will go
to jail I said don't worry Mr har we
will win and I had uh 12 criminal
charges and I was actually just one was
and successful for and that was your
probation then you got from that oh my
God what a story well I know you changed
Slovenia in a big way uh and uh you know
I think that's really important for
people to know in the cannabis
industry we think we just got here and
now here we are but there was a lot of
people who took risk went to prison
actually cared about it you know it's
not just the economics of cannabis
shouldn't be legal because the economics
it might be legal because of the
economics of it exactly but the human
rights aspect of it is the it's a civil
liberty to uh to use cannabis and I
think you you proved that in uh in uh
Slovenia and made really big inroads in
the culture
here we all did yes it was a long way
with torny way you know uh but yeah you
can see the difference you started to
come to Slovenia 20 years ago mhm 20 21
years how was 20 years ago everybody
hiding more or less actually 20 years so
that was so that was that's actually a
funny story because that's one of the
reasons I fell in love with Slovenia
because I Mo I I came here in 2002 to
pan right and I had a little tiny piece
of hash with me and then after like 3
days it was gone so I started I started
asking on the streets in puran and the
first thing when I did get to puran
spray painted on the rocks on the
prominade around the Punta yeah uh was
Pam P PanAm PanAm and I was like pamer
Dam Oh shoot that's that's cool and so
then and this is a true story
so I found someone on the street he I
said can I get some weed he's like he
said yeah come to the Puna bar at
7:00 at 1900 and I said okay so I went
to the Puna bar and I uh was expecting
to see him just in the cut in the corner
or whatever in back and he was at the
the Shrunk the uh the the bar she was he
was at he was at the bar behind the bar
and I was like uh Hey and he was like
Hey and I was like you know I just
wanted uh an uh like a few five grams or
whatever and back then it was toll ours
and he was like well it's 5,000 tolls or
something like that right which would be
about 20 EUR or something like that and
he reached under the counter and without
a bag or anything just put some I think
it was some Albanian wheed so it was CED
whatever but I was happy to have
something and uh I just looked at him I
looked at him I gave him the 5,000 totet
and he just looked at me and there was
the weed all over the and I just took my
shirt and I put it into my shirt rolled
up my shirt and kind of duck walk back
to my hotel with my weed and my shirt
and I just knew that I had found home at
that point you know what I mean so for
me and you stayed yeah and I was coming
I had I had lived in Amsterdam for that
yeah and I stayed um and but I was
living in Amsterdam and I actually
thought wow this there's something even
more free maybe that's cuz that was
obala that's how we say Co here
in but uh maybe there was some other you
know little bit different Spirit but I
also remember going to lublana at that
time and going to the schmoutz and
smoking weed at the schmoutz and nobody
gave a [ __ ] and I was like exactly I was
like wow this is uh this is uh this is
insane it felt it felt so open even back
then right
now people seem to smoke everywhere in
lublana and it's no big deal when you
pass through Liana every 5 m you smell
wheat or something you know yeah boo so
even 20 years ago it was pretty open and
that just shows how crazy it is because
you were on the coast and in Liana if
you would come to our region then it's
something else I know I know I I moved
to styka for a while and it was it was
definitely different but at the same
time there was the I used to go to a
place called picara to do music and it
was like
it was like it felt like what was
Christiana in h Denmark where they kind
of have that open that squat that open
free yeah or matela or well matela I
didn't know
matela actually I did know I knew they
both existed so matela is is the bigger
version of uh the free state of lublana
where they take the old army barracks
and turn it into a a squatter's uh uh
area and then the squatters make it what
it is and the cops kind of leave them
alone or it's to at it's tolerated here
and then when
rookies are in Liana because they send
them usually from the rural area to
lublana they may have some problems you
know but it's very
very rare that you have any problems
because I will tell you do you think
that police didn't knew what is going on
in PNA or in metova they could raid the
place every day yeah right but they
didn't right because not nothing
happened there there was never any
problems you know what I mean because
where is the wheat there is no problem
right that's that's amazing and that's
why that's why I that's one of the
reasons I I've always loved Slovenia uh
they're just really cool on the weed
scene and you go outside of Slovenia you
don't feel that safe or that yeah and
then you come back into Slovenia and you
feel super safe so here we are in
Slovenia with this very open liberal
these very open and liberal attitudes
towards
cannabis politically or policy wise eyes
uh where do you see Slovenia in 5 years
do you have hope that things are going
to change in Slovenia yes my hope is for
years now I guess you always got to you
got to always have hope yeah but uh now
you are in Slovenia and you know a bit
about our political system about our
parties and so on yeah we have usually
we have very unstable governments rarely
one government stays all four years you
know yeah and before the election they
all promising we will do it we will make
it better we will legalize or regulate
or whatever but they all forget after
the elections mhm and this is now for 20
years like this I guess the better
question is where do you want Slovenia
to be in 5 years normal country uhhuh
you know regarding human rights because
uh uh you use of cannabis is also human
right because every use of cannabis is
therapeutic and what has to happen then
to make that happen cuz I agree with
what you say compl we have to put a bit
more
effort we are doing it already mhm you
know y I think we will raise Now voice a
bit in the parliament soon MH not
yelling but raise a voice uhhuh but you
what I mean make the message heard uh
and if there is any
any Common
Sense among politician it should be done
yesterday or at least this year right
before the elections right because after
the elections then you have to work on
new connections new let's
say lobbying I don't like the words but
it is kind of lobbying because you have
to organize politicians
bureaucrats uh journalists everything to
come it's organizing for sure so I think
with your help and our work we will do
it this year okay well from your lips to
God's ears Bojo uh thank you for being
on this podcast uh where the world meets
cannabis the first ICBC podcast uh it's
been a real honor to have you badish uh
research nature
if you want to go check it out uh check
him out there Google him he's our Legend
in Slovenia we love him we love you uh
Bojo again thanks so much
brother thank you boom see you soon in
see you soon
[Music]