how's everyone feeling y'all feeling
good this morning whoo so I'm talking
about Mike we're really happy to have
everyone here today in Portland we are
the ICBC we do our conference all over
the world we are the first b2b to go
international and we started in Portland
four years ago it was I remember me and
Anthony talking and I said we said what
are we gonna do and we said we're gonna
start the international cannabis
business conference says we're ever
gonna start was at Portland and so for a
few years we weren't international we
were just in Portland in San Francisco
and then eventually we became
international we went to Vancouver if
that counts
kind of like international a half right
Canada you're still in Cascadia right
and so we went and we then we then we
went to bars for Lynn and we rocked it
we turned it out and of course our event
in California is the longest-running in
California and now we've partnered with
spannabis to be in Barcelona also next
year so we're really thank you we're
really excited about what we're doing
what we have done in Oregon and what we
are doing worldwide so I like to think
that wherever we go in the world
we bring a little piece of Oregon with
us and it's really important because
when you go to Europe and they're
growing all that shitty weed and they
just want to make money money money and
you're like hey maybe you could you know
go organic or you know maybe there's a
product you know you
we can bring a little that Oregon
consciousness to the world and I'm not
saying we're like all Mother Teresa's
here in Oregon but when you do leave
Oregon and you talk to people and you
talk like in Europe and you talk about
some hippie like activism should they
look at you like you're an alien like
what are you talking about but it's
really important that we push that
narrative and what I tell people in
Berlin Haley Anthony Haley
Anthony please thank you appreciate it
what I tell people in you know Berlin
the first thing I say to them is your
beer as it's this nascent new market
over there it's really crazy what's
going on in Europe
I say hey you're bureaucrats and
politicians are going to [ __ ] [ __ ] up so
what's important
is that you have a robust home garden
and all criminal penalties are ended
towards cannabis and I think it's really
important because the industry will get
messed up in Oregon smaller people have
been pushed out you know for better or
mostly for worse and this is not what we
ascribe to at the ICBC we think cannabis
is an opportunity for the world not only
for business not only from human rights
or civil rights but we think it can help
end the industrial some of the
industrial complexes in the world and
just like my mentor Jack hare said hemp
can save the world and we believe it you
know I thank you thank you we used to
say it on Haight Ashbury you know back
in the day with my dreadlocks I used to
have my signs and hemp can save the
world and I barely believed it myself
you know but it's true hemp can save the
world and when we don't have a lot of
hopeful [ __ ] going on in this world
these days hemp is a hemp is a great
bright light so want to thank our
sponsors I thank Jefferson packinghouse
for that great party last night we want
to thank both they have a big party
tonight with DJ Muggs we want to thank
organic alcohol company the main sponsor
know this could be possible without
those guys so let's make some real quick
clap for our sponsors and the old
parties tonight at spirit of 77
don't forget your pass it's at spirits
277 right across by the Convention
Center
we've got DJ Muggs from Cypress Hill
there tonight
DJ Nature and it is gonna be a
hootenanny so it starts at 9 o'clock we
are feeding you all day to day in the
expo room on the side there we have got
buku food we're feeding you breakfast
we're feeding you lunch we got an ice
cream social in the afternoon so you can
stay here you don't need to go spend
your money and eat anyplace else if you
don't want we've got you covered right
here taco bar in the afternoon it's
gonna be off the chain so I just we
really appreciate you guys we want to
feed you and make sure everyone's got
all their energy this is our last Oregon
show so I did want to just give a
heartfelt thanks to everyone never say
never but we do not plan to do another
Oregon show for some years now and this
is our 12th show in Oregon in four years
you know like I said we're not gonna be
an Oregon anymore but everything we do
and how we
fourth we represent we represent Oregon
so what we're trying to do is create
conduits so when we can finally export
cannabis
I'll have created all these awesome
conduits around the world so we can sell
all our Oregon weed to the world it's
only a matter of time - it's only a
matter of time and that's really gonna
change the game up and we're actually
gonna be talking about that we got a
great program but that will be delving
into a lot of that how organ can export
in some of the pasta possibilities um
that's it this is our woven a purer
woven a pit on our woven a piss makes
you communicate with all types of people
throughout the conference and you get
all our updates on little announcements
contests where the party is and all that
stuff and when lunch comes out and the
ice cream social and all that good stuff
so get on woven we're gonna have this
sellout up for about 10 more seconds so
if you if anybody needs to get on wove
oh I just go down to registration and
they'll sign you right on up okay are
you guys ready to get this thing started
oh you guys ready to get started you
guys we have such a great program for
you today we have a lot of amazing
people I'd like to kick it off really
quick with a person who's gonna
introduce our opening video he is a hero
of Oregon like I just told him a second
ago I hate most politicians and I love
you what is going on here you know what
I mean because most politicians are it's
hard to be a politician because the game
is rigged right but guess what on a
local level we do have a few folks that
are conscious mock consciously minded
and revolutionary thinking and who
actually have some power and can get
things done and our one big ally in this
state is Senator Floyd presents key so
without further ado please make some
noise for our beloved Senator Floyd
who's asking
you know make some more noise for Floyd
y'all so I want to thank all of you that
are here today I also want to thank Alex
for bringing forward this conference
he's been a trendsetter for the state
and as well as he said on an
international level without this type of
discourse we would not be able to move
forward as we need to thin this industry
it's been my opportunity to at this
point really to just take a few moments
to introduce Jeff Merkley before we hear
from all in his video what I first met
Jeff back in 1999 that is the year that
he came into office as a state
representative representing part of
Portland on the east side at that point
I got to I guess get to know who he was
in 2003 four years later we had our
offices next to each other this allowed
us to spend a lot of time talking
together not only on the issues that
were facing the state but after hours
just sitting around anew selecting on
where we were what we wanted what were
our values how could we move or go nians
forward how could we take care of many
of the issues that we're facing us
including the economic depression and
uncertainty in many rural areas he comes
from a background of a rural area Merle
Creek for those who do not know is in
Southern Oregon he his father was in the
trades as a laborer and they moved up to
here in the Portland area and where he
finished his high school it was one of
those situations that when we were
sitting around and talking I always
found myself just being drawn in by his
thoughts his visions of what he would
solved for the state and how he thought
we needed to move forward this is one of
those situations that I remember when he
decided to run for the US Senate Senate
I was actually traveling back from
Byrnes so I was on highway US 20 and I
got this phone call from Jeff and Jeff
says hey Floyd what do you think about
me running for US Senate and I just kind
of did a little bit on my drive there
going wow that's a pretty big step
you're thinking about he had just been
elected and served as the Speaker of the
House he had been the Democratic leader
prior to that and so I know that he was
getting his message out in people who
are listening so I told him I said if
you really feel that you have the
ability to move forward at this time in
your career to run for that seat I will
support you and he didn't won't go
forward and as we all know he won the
Democratic primary that allowed him to
go up against the incumbent Gordon Smith
and it was a very close race but Jeff
seceded and he's been in the USN since
2009 what's really important is seeing
how he's taking his visions for this
state and has taken them and moved them
into a much larger larger broader area
for the country and it's one of those
situations that I've been very impressed
to see how he's not been afraid to take
very controversial issues and put them
out on the table for us to talk about
and for others to listen this is one of
those situations that he was the only
senator to actually endorsed Bernie
Sanders for the primary in the 2016 and
you can only imagine being a senator to
take that type of step at that point in
his career what he was demarcating that
Heath was going for who he thought was
going to be the best individual to
represent the Democrats and the national
election after that he earlier in that
year he he attempted I should say
earlier this year he's attempted to
enter into one of the immigration
detention centers this is down in South
Texas for those who have not met me
that's my birthday and when I heard that
Jeff went down to the Harlingen area
what he was attempting to do was to see
how children of parents who had been
arrested trying to come in to the u.s.
seeking asylum were being handled and
how they were being taken care of well
ironically they were place they had
placed them into a detention in a former
Walmart and he was denied access as a
u.s. senator to go in to check on the
welfare of these children of course this
made big news throughout not only the
nation but also internationally
and it just showed once again where Jeff
was willing to take that step to bring
and expose the the needs of individuals
that are more disparate than he is and
how he could in fact bring and shed the
light to make certain that they are
being taken care of besides that we have
seen even this week where Jeff has
actually was seeking an injunction to
stop the confirmation of Brent Cavanaugh
because as he says how can he as a u.s.
senator be able to vote on the floor for
a nominee without having all of the
allegations that have been raised
against him being invested investigated
through the FBI and then being able to
have all of that out in the open be
transparent and then make the decision
as to whether or not that justice should
be elevated to the Supreme Court so at
this point I think it's worth noting
before we hear from Jeff that in May of
this year he came forward to co-sponsor
senator Corey Brooks brokers marijuana
justice Act this would remove marijuana
from the federal list of controlled
substances ie making it legal throughout
the country and I think it's really
important for us to see again where Jeff
has been willing to take that step to
move forward to get us as a nation to
deal with issues that we should have
dealt with back in 1971 1972 so with
that let me just end with that he has
not only just been a co-sponsor of the
legislation I just mentioned but he's
also been active and trying to get the
reform in the banking as we all know we
need to open up the banking both through
financial institutions that include
banks as well as credit unions so we
can't in fact have the accountability as
a legislator I'm very concerned that
we're not helping and facilitate so we
can in fact make certain that there's
accountability and the reality there's a
safety risk here but as many of you that
are in the business to have that type of
cash sitting around and not being able
to actually do what most businesses do
that
is a financial institution is wrong so
he's taken little eat there and I think
it's very important that we also
acknowledge that he is also saying that
VA doctors should in fact have the
ability to actually give counseling to
vets in states that actually have
medical programs as to the benefit of
medical marijuana for those individuals
so I hope that gives you a little bit of
flavor of who Jeff Merkley is and I at
this point want us to have an
opportunity to see where he's heading
and what he wants to do for this
industry and so we'll have a few words
from Jeff by video thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
greetings I'm Senator Jeff Merkley and
welcome to the International cannabis
business conference in state after state
the American people have stood up to say
that it's time to change cannabis laws
in America
that's why four years ago I was proud as
an Oregonian to support major ninety-one
and become the first United States
senator to vote for legalizing cannabis
in my home state now I'm working with my
colleagues in Washington to help make
these changes at the national level
because here's what we know about the
impact of legalizing cannabis from the
states that have done it more jobs more
tax revenues fewer arrests and a second
chance for individuals convicted of
minor drug offenses who have had their
records expunged just look at the effect
right here in Oregon the fiscal impact
committee originally predicted that
legalizing cannabis would generate
between seventeen and forty million
dollars a year for the state but the
state is on track to double the higher
end of that projection and bring in more
than eighty million dollars a year
forty percent of that revenue goes right
back into our schools
that's roughly thirty four million
dollars for our students and teachers 20
percent goes in in mental health
alcoholism and drug services another 12
to 13 million for the state police and
over 4 million for the Oregon Health
Authority and Oregon isn't alone the
same kinds of benefits can be seen in
Colorado and in Washington State and in
Nevada all of which have seen actual
revenue beat the initial estimates the
time has come for us to change the way
our country looks at and deals with
cannabis and I'm working in Washington
to make that happen I've introduced the
safe banking act to ensure that
legitimate businesses following state
cannabis laws have the same access to
resources and services that every other
business has not too long ago I went and
saw for myself our business owners cut
off from services and opportunities have
to pay taxes
stuffing backpacks and duffle bags full
of cash and driving hours to Salem to
deposit it there is no reason that if a
state has voted to legalize business
owners should have to operate in this
way it's burnham sin'
and it's dangerous billions of dollars
in cash is great for organized crime
it's great for money laundering it's
great for cheating on wages and taxes so
we would all benefit by banking the
cannabis economy we also need to make
sure that hemp products with low THC are
not regulated under the Controlled
Substances Act and I'm proud that this
change has been included in the Senate
farm bill this year while we still need
to get the farm bill over the finish
line getting rid of this illogical
restriction will help create jobs and
strengthen the agricultural sector
across the United States in addition I'm
working with senator Booker on the
marijuana Justice Act to decriminalize
cannabis stop racially disproportionate
enforcement of cannabis crimes and give
those convicted of past use of
possession crimes a clean slate and I'm
a co-sponsor of senator Schumer's
marijuana freedom Opportunity Act which
would also be criminalized cannabis
throughout the nation times are changing
the American people are demanding change
to how we treat cannabis across our
nation they know the benefits that
legalizing cannabis brings socially
economically and in our justice system
and I'm determined to help bring about
those changes and I'm thrilled to be
working in partnership with all of you
to do it
let's give a big thanks to Jared our
signer here today thank you brother
one more big thing for Senator Merkley
and let's make some noise and hope that
he runs for president because I know I'd
vote for him
so at the ICBC we like to bring a little
star power sometimes and we've had many
exciting guests today we have a very
exciting guest who's going to say a few
words and introduce the head of the olcc
you know it's so cool because usually
our big stars we've got to import from
LA or someplace around the world but
this big star lives right in Oregon in
Southern Oregon and grows cannabis and
loves cannabis and has a lot of feelings
towards cannabis and hasn't necessarily
been so outwardly vocal waiting for the
right time and today he's just gonna say
a couple words about how he feels about
our state cannabis reform and opioid
addiction so without further ado please
give a warm warm Oregon welcome to the
one and only mr. Jim Belushi go make
some noise Jim Belushi in the house
thank you very nice introduction I am
here because of the free taco bar this
afternoon I understood that I was going
to be this morning and when you
announced that I moved it to the
afternoon and I'm a little disappointed
so let me get over that for a minute I
love tacos I do live in Los Angeles
by the way Alex and I have a beautiful
little farm on the Rogue River in Eagle
Point in Southern Oregon right in the
middle of the banana Belle I have a
small beautiful grow there and I have
become so intimate with this plant by
growing it cultivating and curing it
cutting it selling it it's just brought
me closer and closer to myself and it's
brought me closer and closer to the
miracles and the spirit of this plant I
I believe cannabis I wrote it down
I believe the wellness of cannabis
includes helping to heal Alzheimer's
back pain headaches anxiety seizures the
wellness of cannabis also includes the
enhancement of creativity the spark in
the spirit the enhancement of the sounds
of music the taste of foods the touch of
your lover's skin but also includes
euphoria joyfulness higher consciousness
all this is the wellness of canvas and I
am getting closer and closer to all that
I have been educated here in Oregon
Oregon is a great state and that is the
great state of cannabis by the way
I think Oregon is gonna lead leave this
country in the great quality and a great
science that they produce here I visited
with finalists and all the different
Sciences here it's just mark about what
they're doing here I'm just overwhelmed
by it the more I get into it the more I
realize I don't know it's just a
wonderful plant to be engaged with it's
just changing my life personally I had
an experience last year I've visited
over wow maybe 2025 dispensaries and
they're waiting in line to come in and
take a photograph and try out the
cannabis setup and be produced and I met
a veteran who was shaking a little bit
and staring at me and and he walked up
to me and he said you know I was a medic
in Iraq and I saw things that happened
to the human body that nobody should
ever see in their life he said my PTSD
is this so bad that I I have three kids
that I have trouble relating to a wife
and I can't sleep and he said your black
diamond OG is the only strain I have
found where I can talk to my children
and I can sleep and he like had tears in
his eyes and he hugged me and I wanna
thank I didn't make this stuff man this
has been here for a long time I I just
you know I think it just planted Isis he
goes you are the Stuart I don't know how
that's pretty cool and we all are
stewards from this medicine to heal our
community the number one fear in life is
death the number two fear in life is the
collapse of family that is a number two
fear where their family falls apart from
divorce disease PTSD
addiction a death in the family creates
trauma 80% of the families that
experience this kind of disease or
trouble don't succeed the families
collapse and I believe that this
medicine is going to help our community
and help our families get back and not
collapse there was a woman whose son had
40 seizures a day she said he would drop
like he'd cut a string on a Marinette
she didn't know what to do she was in
that bedroom with that boy every night
never sleeping with her husband because
they care for this child and he was in
hospice taking all kinds of drugs and
she used some CBD oil changed his kid's
life changed the family's life that
family almost blew up so I just love
what this dude I'm proud to be a Stewart
and I'm proud of all you for being a
sewer and keeping this that's going I
mean I believe that I believe if we knew
what we know now about cannabis in the
70s if we knew what it was capable of if
we knew it was medicine instead of a
drug there'd be a lot more people alive
today and it is not a gateway drug it is
a gateway to healing it's a gateway to
medicine as a gateway to spirituality
I am grateful to be here I'm proud to be
in Oregon and I have gotten to know a
lot of people and our next speaker I've
gotten to know this year pretty well
he's more than a friend he's an
acquaintance okay was it joking you got
that good I'm so glad I I have been in
relationship with them because we've
been discussing it's very difficult to
get done there's a lot of little things
going on but we've been discussing an
opiate trade program to begin here in
Portland where we can get free marijuana
to the veterans people on the street
people who have opiate addictions
prescriptions and I know that every
farmer and every manufacturer in Oregon
will be glad to donate anything to this
program so we've been talking about it
Steve is a very smart man I have found
that the olcc is my partner is my friend
and I'm grateful that they gave me a
license I am their partner they are my
partner and I'm proud to know this man
I'm proud to know all the people who
were from actually Steve isn't really
that good or that smart it's really
everyone that works so for him I mean
these guys are really stars there's a
few I'm standing back a wave you're here
they get nothing they're always in the
office hello give them a hand
they make Steve look great
but he is doing everything he can to
make cannabis work in Oregon everything
every day finding solutions every day
running into more problems than finding
solutions and fighting and not giving up
he is our director he is our steward and
I'm proud to introduce the director of
the olcc Steve Myers thank you
and that tacos are going to be early in
the afternoon