so what would you start with a very very
quick real quick introductions to keep
this moving like hi under this comfy and
then we'll move into some other question
into conversation haunted some money was
then Adams and work with files file
sites where cannabis genomics company
may support United States
my name is irrational bunny on this DTO
africana we're at Ronald based biopharm
company located at the johnson johnson
innovation incubator jail absent he also
cultivate in colombia so we do R&amp;D and
cultivation my name is Sheldon Curtin I
would at the spot technologies founders
presidents we produce and processed
canvas in Edmonton Alberta Canada as a
licensed producer and we're currently
opening operations in Denmark in the UK
so so I'm missing a thing no question
here when when you see people in private
industry what exactly does that mean
does it mean research testing labs
doesn't mean testing doesn't mean
growing
does it mean formal entrance what
exactly does that mean I think it's
probably means something different all
of us and probably specific to what we
each do technology so when you see
Nestle what's separating the girls boys
if you want to do that time everything
guys I'd say more than the varieties
available in the market today
so the clear you like multi cars in five
years let me conclude that day totally
useless in the means when you say that
what do specific candidates Elvis never
undergone intensive breeding efforts and
so because of these ways that the loss
of change many biotechnology companies
including finalists which was collected
the motion of data on campus in the
world
canals you intensive breeding program so
we could read it in agronomy traits to
this point they're not just brief or
itcs
three four specific flowering times
specific cannabinoid levels you know of
course it's the baseline from me and all
my doing on that as well like they it's
the breeding for me acceptable rating
but also the formulations attached to
mrs. Weston three four so you know if
you want a different amount of
cannabinoids innocence it's um
CBG for instance you can breathe for the
CPG and you know what you said is true
sort of genetic stock market today will
probably also be a few years from now
just because of the amount of reading
that's work right now in reading for
specific neighborhood profiles what
happens then is in the population side
of things which is what we specialize in
it's important to realize that the
genetics really dictates which to pull
out as your ultimate fuel from that from
that particular string or cultivar so
essentially the way I looked at last
night right now in this industry at
least is that it's really about what she
which in grower basically three four
then when she can pull out of that flex
and then formulate from the specific
compounds that you read work-related so
if you have a Landry strain which is
interested aren't landrace traits better
for what you can pull out of it than
turning to and that's that's what what
are what does that meet you in the
direction I would say that necessarily
and so they have unique send these
pathways that may be modern varieties
done so there's a lot to learn from that
but I would say that the interest of man
recent more mobility post anything else
waiting
production-wise with labor strains in
our community so they could take a break
on the flower they may produce very low
cannabinoid content
I'd say the games more about my ability
maybe the baseline for breeding programs
ladies weren't actually under tie
company or it was it was basically Asian
country musica Australia or New Zealand
or
from that part of the world who actually
had started to engage in trying to find
new land race across Asia and Latin
America
why would I completely do that because
they want to breathe air in medical side
of things want something to do that
again most unique subjects pathways that
don't exist in modern varieties so
violence my company we essentially
started as a property theater he's
seeing of Natural History in New York we
see once about a thousand land race
rides from over 80 different countries
but most of those were from the
University or barriers so they existed
pre-prohibition so they were formally
eighteen hundreds to the 19th century so
so what you guys are doing is basically
creating documentation and testing for
the cannabis formulations of tomorrow
whether that's your plant or whether
that's the liquid in your jar or the
stuff in your medical device or the
stuff in your so here basically you guys
are the formulations the foundations of
that industry right yes so I to answer
your previous question of what I think
of the biotech industries what people
there's a big misconception in this
initiative guy when a jurisdiction is
legal and go that's natural it equals a
safe and effective product that's not
the case so for me keep it simple so for
an example could be that you can have an
oil teacher sitting on a shelf right now
for medical patients and you don't know
if there is stability testing on that
product so meaning that that product is
actually stable for the past ten months
if the cannabinoid content is still
there if it's not decorated but even if
it could be toxic
there's not real testing really done in
the industry not something that
kind of bridge - yeah and that's why the
medical community has not as in Seoul
distant or open-minded - you know
prescribing medical cannabis for
patients and you know bringing that
education is plagued requires data and
rigorous testing we need to do
formulation where you need to do you see
where QA work you need to do analytical
test preclinical testing eventually
individual testing this is the type of
stuff that at a basic level we need to
bridge that gap between the medical for
medical community from a physician
perspective as well as the patient
perspective
let's save cannabis innovation is of
mass law higher kid needs than breeding
the baseline of that period in that
formulation go up tonight that's right a
math test and that's what you're getting
at is the testing really that proves the
accuracy of those tamarins that you're
save reading for and we're reading for
and then testing in the labs which is so
important because really what you're
really what we're trying to do in the
end you trusting and highly ethical
focus is making sure that what we
produce in the middle market has a
formulation of work flour even on
certain markets or campuses to be the
formulation it's important to make sure
that the patient is getting you know
come today they're looking for and
really dynamics down to the camera
quality flower or robot formulation and
of course the stability of that
formulation this is very fascinating and
but I'm the next question is how would
you guys say this ties into things like
GMP now for those of you who don't know
what GMP is right it says it's a
standard here in Europe that applies to
it's good manufacturing practice and
it's like a seed to sale quality test
how does what you guys do tie into that
discussion it creates a standard global
standard that you know when you're
following certain types of protocols and
practices and as a cultivator in
Colombia
there is a stigma around the Colombian
market but when you say you're like for
us where we're G ACP going to be G AP so
good agricultural practices so we're
going to be Agri we're going to be
producing these products with these
international standards and then
manufacturing them with GMP standards as
well
it creates some sort of level of comfort
and a level of sophistication because
you could say I'm a cultivator in
Colombia and you will some people might
think you're growing in the jungle and
you know I was like an illegal market
but that's not the case right there's a
lot of it adds that that prestigious
level and and creates a high quality of
the the active pharmaceutical ingredient
that we treat the cannabinoids us okay
so I'm gonna I'm also trying to get some
reaction from the audience can I have a
hands up who in the audience is actively
engaged in this kind of environment or
this kind of activity in Europe is there
anybody in the room if you if we can get
a microphone to you are you hearing
things from the folks here from
non-european sources and I know you your
global as well but what I'm curious
about is how this discussion has
differed so far from the conversation in
Europe on these because do you have any
insight on that well do thank you it's
hard to give an estimate over here since
there's very very few companies who do
do so or specialize in its kind of R&amp;D
activities don't take this for granted
maybe I just don't know about all the
companies that are active in this field
however what we're focusing on is fairly
similar to what you guys do so I think
it's in a way on par on par so so do you
think I'm gonna bounce this back so cuz
my spirit is sitting here this seems to
be the groundwork all the next certainly
the medical discussion right so if a
doctor knows that they're prescribing
this brand that is proven to be stable
and you've gone through the tests and
it's treated like a pharmaceutical
that's that's a great discussion but
then there's the flip side and those of
us in the room who are older than
probably 35 remember this Hardwell fear
that sort of came out of the old timey
or industry of like oh my God my strain
is gonna be bought up by Monsanto to
name one company and they're gonna rule
the world and then cannabis is going to
go into another strain controlled world
and how scary
I guess uh so when when you're talking
about types of specific indications that
people are suffering from and you know
they're already using different types of
pharmaceutical products right so in in
in our field we we take it very
seriously as well so there has to be a
level of sophistication you don't want
to give someone an oil to ensure that
you say oh this oil to ensure works for
epilepsy and they have a bad reaction so
this is why you treat it at this serious
level it's a social responsibility for
everyone who's in this space as as much
as it it people you know think it's a
very it's a new economy that's being
built and it's a very interesting
fast-growing industry but you still need
to have that responsibility that if you
are gonna put products out there that
they should be properly tested I agree
entirely I think the global reputation
is on all of our shoulders right now
well that's my question
I mean it is it being really regulated I
mean certainly in Europe if you're if
you're a medical product if you're a
pharmaceutical product there are testing
and other things that go along with it
that are mainstreamed into this
discussion is this regulation discussion
saying that on the biotech front
certainly in the American hemisphere
what you guys are doing is ahead of the
regulation I mean that for for me being
in this industry for about three and a
half years the European market feels
like Canada three and a half years ago
so it we are trying to look the good
thing about being in Canada as well and
being based in in in Canada's from being
the first g7 company to our country to
to legalize marijuana for not just
medicinal but recreational the one good
thing is that we could do R&amp;D at a
federal level and we can do clinical
trials at a federal level so these are
Health Canada approved testing that you
know has a level of sophistication
globally in the US unfortunately
cannabis is not considered it's
considered a controlled drug so it's
illegal from a federal level which
limits the Americans to do any Rd and
clinical development so they can't
necessarily generate real actual data at
market that data or use that data in
their in in their production or on Rd so
in Germany what I've noticed is now is
like because it's such a young ingenue
yang industry here or in Europe I should
say that it's so growing and it's in the
early stages there's a lot of room for
growth and to add that level of
sophistication just makes it that much
better for medical practitioners in
Europe to bridge that gap and be more
comfortable prescribing medical cannabis
so I'm gonna push this one again and
come back to you Meowth where is there
is another example of the industry being
ahead of the regulatory environment or
when you call cannabis say a medical
product does it slot into the testing
environment even in the United States
even before federal reform because
there's something called the FDA this is
their narcotic it will probably a
schedule 2 I mean all those things are
coming I'm gonna go back quickly to the
intellectual property and GMP factors
because I think that GMP first off you
know good manufacturing practices for
the European Union which is essentially
at least right now in the cannabis
industry the highest level you know it's
similar to what you might do in a
pharmaceutical industry that's I believe
important because if you focus on that
and you're you're manufacturing to that
level you're gonna always get a
consistent product for the patient which
means you're gonna of course be able to
provide things like the stability data
and other things that I personally
believe is important if you're selling a
medical product you can do that with
flour even but it just it just takes
time basically proving that stability
but is important if you have the right
flour then you can still potentially
make that the right medicine now
intellectual property a whole complex
ball I should say basically because it's
very it's kind of difficult to register
certain things like cultivars in fact in
the US it's what's what's a cultivar a
cultivar is a strain it's just the
proper way to say it so the scientific
term would be cultivar the black market
called it a strain but actually if you
talk to any of my breeders they say
cultivar and they'd actually but just
anybody over like 35 sister okay it's a
stranger in a strange strain or first
more it's like bacteria
so exactly strains actually a plant
virus so so cultivar is a little bit
more you know if I can get everyone here
certain cultivar that's what I'm gonna
do variety work to it's a variety yeah
that works but so intellectual property
is something that's very hard to
register when it comes to plants the
Monsanto model a bit of an odd model but
they did pretty good at it but if you
look at some other companies that that
are doing similar things what they do is
effectively they register plant breeders
rights which takes a plant breeders
permit which takes someone who has at
least 15 or so years of experience in
plant breeding which is rare so if you
can combine these two things and
essentially find someone who can do that
then register those strains and then
manufacture that a GMP level that's
essentially the future of cultivation at
least in in my in my books when it comes
to formulation there's a whole nother
aspect of intellectual property and of
course the efficacy of all those
different formulations it's a nice
you're a wealth of information okay so
I'm gonna jump in with one of those
stupid questions okay so so why would I
go ahead and register my strain I don't
know excuse me it's my cultivar if I'm
going to go ahead and just like have a
like a processed something which is
obviously has to be tested and whatever
but if I'm just going to be making
liquids or something from that and
mixing and matching or whatever
certainly if I'm out of the medical
space I mean we're just I mean I
understand to a certain extent why this
is important but again to my question
where are the people telling you guys
what to do whether regulations or are
you guys doing this as you're going
along which is not necessarily a bad
thing but where is that and get a good
lawyer but I mean you know really it's
it's it's just it's very hard to
actually register some of these things
it's actually more like a process patent
it's not so much of protecting the
formulation itself and then of course
there's the trademarks in the brand
associated to that particular product
that's probably the key takeaway from
that that's that's your IP really not so
much that you've just combined CBD and
and some particular you know flavonoid
or something so it's it's really about
the process of how you derive that then
how did you put it together and then if
you can protect that in some way that's
that's a way to secure some IP and even
in the u.s. it's a way to secure IP in a
place where it's not
completely federally legal and Europe
you can do it as well it's just only in
certain places right now because THC you
can't work within certain countries okay
so I didn't do a quick hands up I'm
gonna keep you active all right hands up
in the audience who is kind of like
bugged I mean not like you know a
professional and you know whatever but
just as visceral level who is bugged you
need to time out I said it no I'm crazy
bugged by this whole conversation man
awesome so there's one so hands up who
is bugged by this conversation ends up
or is p4 this sleep sleeping who is like
profoundly worried right now about the
fact that private companies no offense
cuz these guys are really smart private
companies are creating IP this is
intellectual property is protected by in
cannabis hands-on well they're a couple
why I'll tell you why it's the old
hippie of me first of all cannabis has
been decentralized for a very long time
right it's 257 these sort of things
sometimes seem to me to be the opposite
of how cannabis culture has evolved and
I understand that the world changes and
I understand that business is business
but how do you patent a plant what's
gonna stop people from saying like I
said you have to grow these seeds you
have to buy these seeds from us all the
time I'm surprisingly I'm actually very
anti capitalist but to make the hippie
here modern very happy we actually think
we've collected about now three thousand
or sequence of the DNA of about three
thousand plants from eighty four
countries to date and that most of that
data has been uploaded to the open
canvas project and the NCBI
so we are currently fighting utility
patents and creating data space to fight
future utility patents what's a utility
patent it's just a broad scoping patent
on a particular plan
Shelburne I'm actually probably like
I've got I've got the I've got the
strain and you can't use it but
varieties like the og cush trainwreck
things that we're on the market today
can never be patented and they never
will be nor should they be no no no make
it quick go ahead go ahead
so there's a there's a landmark US
Patent Office ruling I think the 2013
ruling its myriad versus someone else
that basically says that anything that's
natural anything any plant or anything
any DNA that any genetics that existed
naturally cannot be patented but if you
have if you have modified the genetics
in the lab you can patent that so
anything that existed up until now
naturally cannot be patented the process
to extract to do whatever you want to do
can be patented
but the genetics itself cannot be and
everybody in the world pretty much uses
that that's ruling which was a big
Supreme Court case in 2013 so so my
question then is so what you guys are
doing well important and cool and like
the land race discussion is awesome
right is what you're doing really for
the pharmaceutical market I mean I can
certainly see an application or is this
really for the recreational folks who
are like you know what this is my beer
this is my gin this is my cigarette this
is my data I mean where do you really
see this being applied the commercial
recreational space or medical and be
honest specifically for philo so it's
both medical and recreational that's why
we're in multiple markets today from
Canada Colombia Spain all the United
States
I'd say it's both in that sense
pharmaceutical will definitely be larger
market in the future and that's where
breeding for novel cannabinoids will
come into play but I'd say a recreation
is still a big part of it as well too
I mean I have to agree I mean I look at
what happened in Canada with with
legalization there's I think the
recreational is in the future probably
going to be a big part of the market
Atlas is focused on medical so because
we focus on the formulations and and the
efficacy of those formulations that's
that's really where we
where we focus our efforts but I do see
a huge opportunity in the recreational
markets and I think a company like yours
is gonna do very well with that well I'm
gonna throw another one in here okay so
those of you who are in Europe know
about this whole novel foods discussion
right so if you guys are like
registering all these strains for those
of you don't know what novel foods is
the European Union has regulations that
say that any plant-based material and
you can if you know better definition
please criticize me later but basically
the European Union says that any
plant-based material that makes its way
into human food that is was not in
common use before believe 1997 has to go
through a special regulation process and
of course CBD in particular in food
right now is falling into that
discussion across Europe so how is what
you guys are doing and maybe if you
don't know that's fine how is what you
guys are doing going to help or aid or
hold back or hinder that novel food
discussion here in the EU let me speak
to that because I think that for us
being able to infuse are isolated
compounds proven compounds that we know
are consistent and dosed properly is a
huge part of what would make people
comfortable having an infused product of
any sort be it a beverage or a you know
an edible product and I think that for
Europe having this big debate right now
with regards to CBD and how it should be
produced and and how it should be
distributed I think it's important that
being a something that many people
consider medical and I personally
consider medical it's important that it
goes through the right processing the
checks and balances to make sure that
what you purchase is actually what you
get and I guess that's that's an issue
I've seen in a lot of places including
in some parts of the US where where
there's less regulatory environment and
you get a product and in fact we tested
30 products CBD products or claimed to
be a CBD and out of 30 there was
actually just a fraction that even
contains CBD and only three that
actually had the amount that they said
they did so to me that regulatory
environment that's going to oversee
what's going to be an infused product is
is important and how it was produced and
is it clean is a real that's also
important okay so so any questions from
the audience
any thoughts okay there's one over here
I have a question
when do strengths you develop but they
can cross in nature with the original
hemp strains so we can see it in the
corn industry or corn farming but the
natural strains no more exists in the
world because the artificial strains
crushed in the fields with the natural
strains and so the natural strains they
have been here maybe 30 years ago you
can never find in the planet anymore and
I'm afraid that this danger will expand
worldwide with a hemp - and the old wise
plant our hemp will disappear from
plamen planet great I totally agree with
you and I think preserving seed
diversity particularly in cannabis is
same thing is very important during the
20th century we saw a massive decline in
the diversity of seeds available which
is what you're speaking about
I think only maybe 10% of the original
varieties that existed a hundred years
ago are still available today there's
only one kind of banana damn-near I know
we have to avoid monoculture and I think
part of what
Philo's has done at least with working
with the American Museum of Natural
History on a project called the cannabis
evolution project is about identifying
and then preserving the seed diversity
and so that's actually where small
growers around the world will come in
and they will be the powerhouses that
preserve this diversity of cannabis we
see today which absolutely needs to
exist in and as we move ever forward we
have to remember where we came from
always and I couldn't agree more
honestly about preserving those strains
and making sure that first off the
breeders the the jedis of the industry
that have been around forever that
they've they've really been the ones who
have defined the industry today and it's
important that they're recognized and
that's where these these strains and
strain names and other things cannabis
and hemp really it's important to
recognize who originally brought these
to the market who's been producing these
and and then we don't forget that
because we don't want to wind up in a
city
where everything goes away like bananas
for instance you know which you're right
they are gonna go away at some point
well that was my question about the
regulatory environment I mean think it
is lagging and those are issues
obviously so the next question yes early
this year a team from Berkeley have used
synthetic biology to produce purified to
each C and CBD using yeast has has
vector so I'm wondering how you has
traditional breeder are considering
these successful new advanced which will
be one of many others in the next year I
mean I think we also Raphael mushrooms
talked yesterday at least I hope we did
I think it's impossible to get those
East genetically engineered East
varieties to produce the same level of
compounds that cannabis can today talk
to the research kings in Dortmund
Germany well they were talking about I
mean just producing THC cannabis is the
whole entourage effects actually just as
THC is the CBD the CPG the CDA and the
mercy the blah-blah-blah-blah cost to
produce those isolates from yeast is
extraordinary it's absurd to do that
might as well just grow a girl weed
first yeah yeah okay I think no sorry
the boss says no I'm sorry but of course
as always you can all huddle in the
hallway and have heated debate and
discussion and coffee we thank you very
much let's hear Thank You Sheldon in a
rush and Marguerite's
you