Bridging the Gap between uh public and
private sectors here to lead us to
moderate this panel the founder the CEO
the executive producer of all the ICBC
uh event series is please welcome Alex
Rogers all right how's everyone feeling
everyone feeling good huh get some good
Lune got some energy Mala here we go
all right I'd like to thank uh can we
put our hands together one more time for
Mr homberg for being the Oracle of
knowledge that he
is thank you Peter we appreciate you man
um so our next panel is on private
Public
Partnerships uh cannabis is an
interesting topic uh in terms of uh
public and private partnersh ships um
there's there's a few Nuance uh
different uh things that go on with uh
uh traditionally cannabis companies
private uh uh private companies with
Public Partnerships however the analogy
is intact and we have a panel of
esteemed experts uh today that are going
to talk about p uh public and private
Partnerships in general in Slovenia and
then we can find cor laries within that
of how that can be analogous to uh the
Cannabis industry as well so I'd like to
introduce my uh my colleagues uh firstly
uh at the end here is Boston F Dr F uh
he's the founder and the director of The
Institute for public private partnership
Slovenia boson CH is that how you spell
it CH okay cool thank you a co-founder
of labina a lot of people know uh uh the
labina company very uh very important
company here in Slovenia he's also the
co-founder of Biotech Hills
and uh I'm not sure if this man needs an
introduction who's sitting next to me
but Dr dco velovic and he's the
president of the uh Board of Slovenian
business and research Association in
Brussels uh please give us some Applause
for our esteemed
[Applause]
guest and thank you guys for being here
I know this view sucks but uh you just
have to endure we'll just have to endure
it together here in Lake bled um uh uh I
think uh uh
dko I'd like to uh start with you and uh
ask um uh when we talk public private
Partnerships what what do you think are
some what's the most what are the most
important types of relationships that
can happen with regards to
[Music]
that okay well hello from my side as
well uh nice public here a lot of
interesting discussion going on
especially from a legal perspective
regarding I mean my let's say interest
here um yeah talking about PPP I mean
it's uh it's very I would say broad
subject really and um uh I mean I don't
think it's idea that we go into details
what kind of possibilities are here
possible but I mean for me uh what I
know now about this industry you know
that you are representing uh here I
think it would be so important to
improve and en llarge
research because uh I understand a lot
of things haven't been properly
researched yet regarding cannabis I
think this is the most important issue
really so whatever you know cooperation
even you know I would I would go broader
than just PPP you know because PPP could
be quite uh specific you have different
forums different legal I would say
contracts Etc maybe colleagues can go
more deeper into that but for me it will
be really important to to improve
cooperation between research institutes
which let's say in countries like
Slovenia are mostly public so that would
be public part of this Corporation and
of course you guys that you do business
uh regarding cannabis would you know
benefit from this research and of course
you would cooperate so it would be kind
of cooperation so win-win situation I
would say and through that you know
maybe I can go later on into that a
little bit uh through that I even claim
maybe at this point theoretically you
could get some EU funding for that you
know because uh there aren't any I would
say tenders calls in in Brussels
regarding cannabis as such however there
are calls regarding medicine Health Etc
so whatever Innovation you bring into
that you can get funding so you wouldn't
be able to go for a certain area because
there isn't area cannabis there within
those calls but there are as I said
Innovative Health projects and I mean
deepening research in this area could be
potentially also legit for for certain
EU funding and is is that also the case
not just for biom medicine but for hemp
Also let's say for Eco Solutions like
making a more environmentally friendly
building material for example I meant
first of all like medical part but of
course mentioning this I mean if
somebody I don't know we had this uh
batteries issue right it was introduced
in lublana in in in the in the
parliament even you know so using let's
say cannabis in batteries then maybe
when you talk about green economy there
are possib is their agriculture you know
I mean I think all this should be more
introduced in Brussels as well in order
to to get certain more I would say
precise reaction from European
Commission because right now uh by the
way preparing that our event on the 15th
of May next year in Brussels with the
idea to you know put that on map in
Brussels more uh how should I say more
precisely uh uh so I think this this is
really important you know so really to
put broad picture what all cannabis can
be used for and of course uh medical
part is probably the most important but
not necessarily it's it's it's important
to put all this on the table that's uh
very interesting I I agree and and just
the last thing I apologize maybe just
that uh uh so preparing this event for
the next year 15th of May in Brussels I
also learned that let's say whatever you
ask commission about cannabis right now
they are very very cautious about it so
nobody wants to say anything really
direct so maybe with the new commission
coming up there's a chance and I think
it's good timing next year may yeah to
get more from them yeah that's great
we've uh josco and I are planning a
disruptive event in Brussels on May 15th
on private Public Partnerships and we're
basically it's a it's a Lobby effort of
sorts for the policies that sort of
stuff yeah exactly very interesting grco
so we'll need lawyers these good lawyers
that you have here we'll need them in
Brussels next year for sure Peter so
there you're so
there whether you know it or not Peter
you're
there um Boston uh uh I should say GOP
because we have two Bost um on the panel
um uh that Segways into what are the
various ways uh in which the public and
private sectors collaborate in the field
of research and development can you
expound on that a little bit yeah thank
you thank you for invitation uh I think
that pppc is only one way uh we
shouldn't forget the traditional way
that is subsidies most of the EU funds
came to the subsidies
agriculture uh research Health and so on
so subsidies is the first pillar and
maybe combination subsid of subsidies
private funds could make ppps work uh
next pillar or next layer I think it's
very important also that you focus a
little bit on public procurement because
public procurement is uh public
authorities are huge buyers and if you
can uh sell them Goods services this is
huge market and that will make the
confidence on the market for other
buyers higher and easier to to purchase
the same Goods uh and then I think came
the PPP which is the most complex uh uh
part of uh
collaboration uh because of two reasons
first reason is that you always have to
some sort establish public interest
what's public interest in PPP health
issues I don't know
agriculture some research education
whatever and this is always a political
question public interest is always a
political question because I know in
Slovenia that makes I know uh government
degree or city council decision or
something like that so it's political
question the other part is the transfer
of risks if we have PPP contract we have
to deal about identification of risk
allocation of risk and who will take
this risk through the different pro
project stages so these are two main
questions but the biggest obstacle uh
when you are preparing the PPP project
is always not only on this specific
topic that you're talking about in this
conference but also in public
infrastructure or public services is the
public opinion public opinion is against
ppps because that means privatization
that means profit for privates and so
like that but this is not the real idea
of ppps the idea of ppps is to combine
resources knowledge funds and everything
to get something added value to get
added value and do you do you think that
Slovenia is changing a little bit their
attitude and understanding the
importance of the private sector and
Entrepreneurship okay I think that on
the government level we didn't change a
bit we are
still mostly in the I don't know
public uh institutes and public founding
subsidies are the main uh way of
financing but on the municipality on
local level we can see some mayors that
are more
Innovative they are more open to to new
projects and what we as a Consultants
did we changed the name of the project
we are not speaking about PPP anymore we
are speaking about I don't know energy
Contracting or some other smart some
other name that basically is legally PPP
but it sounds much better so are there
more are there some opt options in
Slovenia then that are more open to this
type of Cooper a and more Nimble and
adaptive yes I think I know lublana is
one of the examples Crown here nearby is
also NOA there are some some
municipalities they are quite open and
they see that ppps could be one
alternative to the traditional way to uh
to develop quicker and easier than and
even some very small ones even small
ones you know small cities or so you
know practicing that a little bit and
but if I may say a short joke you know
how Slovenian you know understand PPP
you know so uh public sector will give
infrastructure money and private sector
will just take
money that's what the that's what the
narrative is right that's not many think
you know but of course we have to turn
it around and you said you know I think
it's it's great potential there where
I'm from in America we actually look at
it kind of as the opposite it's just the
the government that's on the take and
the privateers are trying they don't
succeed unless everybody succeeds around
the private part private part would not
go into PPP if if he she doesn't see you
know potential profit or quite sure
profit for sure so let's so let's take
it back really quick to your first prong
you said was subsidies right now um
would would would would you be also of
the opinion that a PPP is a more
sustainable model once you get it going
than subsidies per se basically I no I
can I can give you the example of Energy
Efficiency there was a lot of projects
in Slovenia of refurbishing the old
public buildings and we combine EU funds
but it's subsidy and private funds and
do it really quickly and efficiently I
don't know a lot of projects all around
Slovenia on the on the municipality
level but interesting on the government
level I don't remember one project that
can be successfully uh
presented I was I was I was hoping you
wouldn't say that may I jump in with one
sentence so that's why European Union is
projecting for the next uh budget which
is starting on on the in the uh 2028 but
it's planned already now more let's say
private part so these subsidies will go
down if now let's say certain projects
are financed 70% from EU funding in
future there will be maybe 60 % in order
that private part would give more into
the project through that you can somehow
get more let's say guarantee that
project will be successful and the
private part will put everything in not
just money but also all other resources
that makes too much sense yeah it does
uh BOS John uh uh so you're the
Privateer here with the business um what
does it look like on the business side
of things I know you've started a very
big project called biotech Hills um and
which has to do with a lot of what we're
talking about could you expound on that
a bit Yeah so uh thanks and uh obviously
great to see lots of faces and some
familiar faces as well in the room um so
maybe just just a little bit of intro of
of what we do um please I come from uh
labena labena is a family company um
well established not just in Slovenia
but internationally here in the region
we operate internationally or globally
we do um our main focus is research and
development uh services for
pharmaceutical uh and bi Biotech
Industry um uh we have also Laboratories
here in Slovenia where where we are
based we have the biggest part of
operations here um and maybe I'll
um what we started in the in the in
labena years ago and that was in
2007 uh before I joined um I so I myself
spent a lot of time in abroad and
actually um working in big
pharmaceutical uh companies GSK Nova
Nordisk OTA Pharma which is a Japanese
company um and worked actually already a
lot abroad on private public initiatives
or Partnerships um um we in labina
started doing that in 2007 as part of um
research uh collaboration especially we
we we uh became Research Institute as
well institution and hence we also
operate not just for profit but we
operate to generate science and science
that can be potentially translated to
commercial opportunities and now to tie
into um so we have quite a bit of
experience um working with with the
public sector and working with the
public sector not just on projects but
significant initiatives I think is key
and why is it key that there are two
things so first of all
and I'm I'm going to say this a little
bit against obviously someone who's
coming from a private sector working
with the public sector keeps the the
private um interests a little bit in
check in terms of that if you
collaborate um with the public sector
you you have to kind of look look from a
broader perspective of Interest as well
it forces you to do that um but it gives
you the leverage of actually um
obviously higher impact and influence
which you cannot achieve as a smaller
you know or a limit or limited Private
Business uh so it is very important and
um I would say that um this is um if you
want to build an ecosystem which I think
in the world of cannabis would be
extremely important uh and when I talk
about ecosystems I I mean all players
combined within an within a territory
that can be country it can be a region
it can be even Europe working together
to achieve something it is it is
inevitable that you have to work in a
private public
partnership and this is kind of what we
learned from experience in laena this is
why we um we got together with some of
the other partners um and I'll tie into
into uh cannabis industry here as well
um to to form uh just a few months ago
the idea about forming an Institute or a
platform to to make sure that we can get
together uh policy makers um so get
behind the same T policy makers Academia
institutes uh and obviously private
entities to be able to effectuate change
in in in this space and this was the
initiative of Slovenia biotic Hills so
Slovenia biotic kills it's a it's zot
it's I would translate institutes
basically um and we we it was actually
um uh we signed a memorandum of
understanding with the with the
government of Slovenia with the minister
of Slovenia actually right in this room
exactly two weeks ago where you sit um
just right there in that corner
um uh whereby we agreed on on certain
metrics to make sure that we together
Elevate the the the prosperity and added
value of Economy based on development of
one of the most important sectors in
Slovenia with the probably the longest
tradition um and added value currently
which is the biotech sector um and
cannabis inevitably Falls within the
biotech because there is you know when
you are when you manufacture a product
where by whereby cannabis as as a plant
is a base um you go through a
biotechnological process inevitably or
where you developing products from from
Cannabis so it very much sits in this
domain and um why we think the public
private partnership is important um it's
not only to secure finding actually the
first question we got was do you want
more money from the government is that
why you did it and the answer was um
well eventually yes but not directly we
don't want to be subsidized what we want
to do is develop conditions policies tax
policies policies to attract skilled
labor force into Slovenia policies to um
introduce levies for uh in Innovative
startups which can be startups in
cannabis or B Tech um so that they will
set their footprint in Slovenia we want
to put Slovenia on the map on the on the
on the global map when somebody thinks
biotechnology Slovenia is on the list of
countries where you would want to you
would want to put your manufacturing
plant um or R&amp;D capabilities that that
is the ambition and cannabis uh pertains
to that and and and so I kind of see
ppps in a much broader sense Beyond just
the project but actually initi Ives that
will drive increased added value for
Citizens living in a certain um
geography that that can be Slovenia or
it can be a wider geography um and I
will just say I mean because we you
asked me about the initiative so the
initiative itself it's called Slovenia
by kills but really the vision is that
we um we give um we kind of create an
environment in connections and
collaborations and networks through
central eastern Europe
uh so that central eastern Europe
becomes a more recognizable Hub through
Slovenia as well uh for for biotech
Innovation including cannabis industry
um so that's kind of sorry and that
sounds amazing I mean I love to hear
that it's a very entrepreneurial
attitude it's a very what I would
consider real progressivism talking
about how will we incentivize people to
come to Slovenia how will we partner
with the with the government with the
policy makers with all the players to to
have things like uh incentives like I
love the idea of incentivizing but not
subsidizing because that means it's
actually sustainable right and this is a
I think this is crucial and this is hard
when you come from the European social
State mentality um it's hard to break
that and and because it's like I
remember years ago and I'll just say
something quick before I go to the next
question but years ago I was listening
to National Public Radio and uh they
were talking about non profits and how
the model of nonprofits have had had
changed previously if your nonprofit
raised
$300,000 80% of that money goes
immediately has to go to to or at least
80% maybe 90 has to go to do do but
you can't reinvest money that you get
donated for a nonprofit but now uh and
this one particular show was talking
about how this guy would come to
nonprofit and say well let's take let's
take $20,000 and throw throw an event
and a fundraiser and see if we can't
with some of that money that was donated
create more money and more like a
business would do not a nonprofit who is
just depending on subsidies or or
donations for example so I always think
of that that listening to that maybe 20
years ago as a big change in because I
related to that CU I think if you're a
practical logical person you want to you
want to grow in a and a in a human who
wants to evolve and develop you want to
grow you want to be proud of what you do
right and and so I think that's the
that's one of the most in interesting
things um that we could mention now is
that almost that shift in mentality of
hey we got to be more responsible but
there's more and the maybe there's some
risk too but the reward is there and the
and the sustainability is there as you
build Brick by Brick not just get a
brick then take the brick away then a
new brick then take the brick away um uh
Boston uh uh uh uh Mr fck are you aware
of any notable examples of public
private partnership in the areas of
innovation research and development in
Slovenia specifically that you could
talk about basically we have one very
interesting micro PPP here nearby from
cran uh city of the cran uh they have
the privately founded uh Institute that
research human fish this is a cave
animal living only in the cross region
it's also a a brand of a beer now but uh
they are focused in on
the environmental influence of this
species very rare species uh and they
have for 60 years they have problems
with funding and there was always
struggling for public funds and there
was a big challenge how to make some
self-driven model self- sustainable
model uh to make their work visible
public and to make it uh also a business
model that will will cover costs and U
they make the cooperation with
Municipality of cran uh because this is
a cave animal we use Old Second World
War tunnel which is under the the city
uh this was the input from the city uh
and the guys from The Institute they
present the exhibition uh life animals
and everything and we prepare the the
new uh tourist attraction that creates
money invite people buying tickets with
these tickets we will finance the cost
of the new attraction but also the The
Profit will go for research so you can
do it on the micro level you can do it
also in the higher scale it's even
easier because business cases are better
that's uh amazing and and
dko do you want do you have something to
add to that actually yeah I mean PPP is
is let's say more complex to achieve but
it gives of course more uh security for
both sides actually you know so that's
that's I also understood you wanted to
to show that before with your cases
right it's not just money to get the
money but really to get all other you
know I would say components that are
important for that yeah and have one big
Advantage this is long-term ter uh
partnership it's not only for one year
or two years but it could be for 15 20
years and if you are planning to do some
Innovation some research then you have
to run for a long long PA yeah I think
there's another example I mean there are
examples um in Slovenia there's many
examples internationally but there's if
we talk about Slovenia first there's an
example of
um uh automobil grost I think it's
called like uh Mobility yeah it's for
for mobility and for cluster exactly
cluster automobile cluster of automobile
manufacturers grost is cluster exactly
grost is like a grape or cluster
uh so that's that's an example uh which
has been around for quite a while and
and obviously Slovenia is one of the you
know major expor exporters automobile
parts to Major automobile manufacturers
that what's that work covich acrapovic
is one of the manufacturers here for
example that represents 20% of Slovenian
GDP
automobile stuff automobile stuff really
20% that's over 10
billion holy all the industry yeah
well um and then there are there are
very sophisticated uh examples that I
wanted to expand on I mean much more
inwi I would call them not just
Partnerships but really
ecosystems um such as the you know the
the the whole Boston area on on biotech
and the MIT connected directly to
companies um as well as obviously the
the federal government involved in that
I mean that that is you know that that
in itself is an example exle that a lot
of countries in Europe followed and
implemented to become certain hubs or
centers for development or research in
in certain areas but this is not you
know these are not funding projects
these are project I would call them
projects of ecosystems or ecosystems of
public private Partnerships well the
ecosystem that creates the
sustainability right or the
sustainability that is the E I mean it's
it's it's a it's connected correct yeah
so so you I mean I think the point is
the EOS system comprises of different uh
contributors that can be public or
private but actually uh aligned around
the common interest to to to usually
invest their time and resources in a
certain location that's that's so
ecosystem is usually bound to a certain
location um and and and I see that you
know private public this is how I see
private Public Partnerships or their
role importance I think it's much
greater than just a produ project level
but actually influencing and impacting
longlasting change in this environment
that's why we need connections between
the business and the industry because
the the uh the business sorry and the
the public sector the business is the
the the obviously the reality sector
that kind of contributes to the economy
however the public sector makes sure
that it it kind of protects interest of
the of the wider public and you need to
you need the collaboration between the
two right yeah I mean it makes it it not
as transient and ephemeral you know it
it makes it long lasting it's not just a
a quick fix it's not like you say do oh
we want to go for the money no yeah
we'll take the money but we have a
bigger Vision you know we actually want
to work hard and make it happen and if
we get any help thank you very much but
it's the entrepreneurs you want to give
it to it's the it's the it's the folks
that are going to actually work put in
the work and and make it happen so all
those partnership and all that
ecosystem you you you you feed off each
other and it becomes uh you don't feel
like an island uh so much exactly yeah
that's uh yeah I just add something I
mean uh I mean to me ecosystem means it
includes all factors for success of
certain business certain area but let me
take let me tell another joke you know I
was in maribor in one big event just
well just before the summer and there
were discussion you know about different
garment instruments you know how to uh
you know trigger more entrepreneurship
more Innovations Etc you know there was
one guy there who's running and he's
owing one of the very important
Slovenian companies you know and he said
okay I don't care what kind of
instrument will you come up with you
know I'll just take the
money well I mean I mean you if the
money's there who's not going to take it
so you can't blame the person to go get
the money you have to blame the system
yeah he's he's a big entrepreneur really
innovator you know so he was I think
maybe a little bit annoyed with the
discussion going on like he said okay
you just come up with an instrument I'll
take the money and I'll do the rest yeah
yeah too much talking not enough action
yeah uh that's funny um so what is goko
is there is there uh money for uh uh for
this type of thing in in the EU and is
there money in for Slovenia because I
know when you do when one would do a a
tender for example there's money from
Slovenia there's money from the EU
there's money from Slovenia that the EU
gave back and I like to say give back to
Slovenia
uh and then they get appropriated yeah
true very well put I mean I always
explain to people who are you know
somehow starting with this this sort of
funding you know there are two types of
EU funding one comes directly from
Brussels Brussel and the other one uh
comes indirectly or directly from the
Home Country so you have uh four funds
four different funds that um let's say
each Home Country National country is is
in charge of it it's cohesion which is
the most uh known I would say funding
then are Regional funds uh social funds
and also funds for agriculture and
Fisheries and Forestry so these four
funding of course cohesion um represents
the the largest part of it and I think
probably most of you heard that although
if you make a PO on the street asking
people what is cohesion I'm not sure
they would be able to answer but okay
it's quite huge money there and of
course there are some direct it's direct
funding from coming directly from from
Brussels as well there's additional
funding uh which came up after covid
which was connected to Next Generation
uh EU so that was additional funding uh
which um each country got so and there
were certain projects including there as
well in cooperation with European
commission which has to kind of approve
them U on General level so they're
mostly mostly digitalization green
economy and certain and similar stuff so
you know it's it's I call it I'm 10
years in in in Brussels now working
there and U sometimes still certain call
surprises me you know because I never
heard of that fund you know but I'm 10
years there so you know it's really a
jungle you know to be quite honest you
know so um myself and my team we do the
best to to naate to navigate through all
of this to know really how things work
out and we helped a lot of companies
mostly slovenians because we are
Slovenian Business Association but also
many International ones as well so we
basically worked for I would say um all
EU countries already and some non-eu
countries like we had some really
interesting cases from Western Balan Etc
so so you know it's it's jungle but you
can handle it if you have good people
good team and um of course if you you
know try to swim through this jungle you
know you better wear your
flippers um gentlemen thank you so much
please give it up for our steam
panel thank you guys so much did uh did
anybody we still have time for one or
two questions un we do have time for one
or two questions does anyone have one or
two
questions does anyone have no
questions does anyone have some
questions have one over here one over
there all
right about funding people usually come
to me after the my speech you know yeah
they don't want to ask questions
publicly
so well I I I'll take the
chance afterwards also if I may but uh
uh nevertheless we were speaking about
the funds tamana gich ecqa uh European
project leader uh certified that our uh
country and Europe and um you were
speaking about the funds and about the
cohesion funds which are not applicable
for the phys physical or uh private
company you know they have to they have
a different agenda so uh I meanwhile
when you were talking I was just typing
in in the procurement and public H uh
the European commission portal and
regarding hemp there is no one so uh
since the the mechanism of European
commission is that if there is need uh
sooner or later uh a a fund or a call
has to be defined and it is uh it it is
uh coordinated and designed from
different parts from different uh uh
European uh members uh I suggest that if
you are if you intend to to do your
public uh uh what what did you call it
uh diversity no uh diversion uh um uh uh
event on May the 15th next year I
suggest that you invite people from as
many countries as possible because the
need to to design to to have such a call
has to come uh alive and then the
European commission can uh can
respond uh otherwise it won't I've also
been to the Horizon uh uh medical uh uh
course and public procurement and if you
don't have two millions in uh uh of of
Leverage uh and you know that means
active money on your account uh they are
not interested and uh
since the the hemp issue uh relates to
the supporting activities of either
industry research or medical research um
it is almost impossible to come through
so this is why we have the problem in in
in lublana we have or in Slovenia we
have great institutes we have people who
re who do the research but since they
are not able to come to uh to to the
relevant data either in Slovenia or in
Europe and see they don't have uh a
person uh to speak to or the uh referee
in European commission it's uh almost
Miss mission impossible so what's your
question is it how do how how do you
intend to uh make aware uh that the uh
you know how to how do uh how would you
like how do you intend to to address
European commission with your event with
active May yeah yes please okay thank
you for your discussion and your opinion
but actually I mean if you listened
carefully I said that there is no call
for for this industry right now uh but I
said that on the other way on the other
hand there are calls which are just for
Innovation so so so theoretically you
could go there because it's not call for
any particular subject is just call for
Innovation Innovative product which
could be whatever Innovative product so
theoretically it could be Innovative
product including cannabis regarding
industri green economy Health uh
whatever theoretically in a small
country and I'm talking about European
Innovation Council which goes for this
uh stuff sort of that there are six
different instruments there I I mean I
can go in detail if you want but I I
don't think anyone want to we're running
out of time but you know that's that's
one point and that's why we are making
this uh that's the idea of this U
conference in Brussels it will be more I
would say uh regulation and policy
oriented to make aware commission uh
about this industry about this potential
and as I said at very first beginning I
think we should improve research in
cannabis in order with this scientific
research the scientific results and
research persuade those who still don't
believe there's potential here and
through this the calls are far away from
I mean specific calls for this area
they're far there you know but we have
to start with the persuasion and with
the research scientifically proved
results of some issues yes and that's it
technical Readiness level for each core
of innovation is at least three or four
this is impossible to to to to develop
in Slovenia especially if you are a
small country well first I'll say
nothing's impossible and I don't really
like I don't love to hear all that talk
you can have a problem and you can say
it's improbable but don't ever say it's
impossible but you can have you know
again you can have international
Partners Etc you don't mention just
Slovenia we International Community here
and most of the calls actually ask that
you have some International or
crossborder Partners so don't say just
Slovenia or we cannot do it or something
like that I quite agree all right we're
good let's hear it again for all the
panelists very Lively discussion toward
the end and I'm sure they'd love to talk
to you uh more about it out outside