all right our final panel of the day
last but not least we may have even
saved the best for
last uh all these people have built
beautiful cannabis companies that have
stood the test of
time and the panel is building a
cannabis company with lasting value and
that's important right yeah let's hear
it for long-term thinking to lead us in
this my man you know him you love him
the equity partner at hybrid Pharma uh
he's a cannabis education and medical
Partnerships Master at loose Brands and
he's here for you today give it up for
Alex
R hello Ling on thank you so much and
God you should know me better by now
I've done so many of these panels that
you would think you'd know my Intro by
better oh don't get me singing with you
anyways thank you so much much for
coming this is a very important panel
I've done a few different panels but
truly I believe this is one of the most
important panels that I've been a part
of because it's about scaling your
business and scaling your business is so
important and as I was explaining to
someone why they want to come to this
this uh 450 show instead of going to
smoke at 420 thank you by the way for
coming back uh is that if you have a
business and you don't think about
scaling it's literally just a job if
you're lucky you'll make $100,000 $150
$200,000 you know you know that and
that's not bad at all but it's barely a
business a real business is scalable and
looks to the international market to
make a lot a lot of money I mean and
that's what I think about business and
that's what a lot of ICBC people want to
know about so I'm here with these
awesome panelists I'll let them
introduce themselves then I'll introduce
myself and then we'll jump into this
topic and I'll definitely leave some
time for questions because I'm sure
there will be some so Alexandre KCK us
up hi so my name is Alex on go I'm the
VP of research and development at origin
nature origin nature got licensed in
2020 when we expanded to the bowler
capacity we're now at 8.5 ton we sell in
Germany in Australia and in Canada uh
we've been named Canada top grower 2023
and 2024 uh we've been lucky enough to
be profitable since our first quarter
with the license so we've been
profitable for the last uh four years
also I'm George Terry I'm the Executive
Vice President of radsource Technologies
uh we focus on the Cannabis sector as
well as many other sectors we won uh
best lab um equipment uh from Canada two
two Awards in 2022 and I think we're up
for another award this year as well
we've scaled as well oh we got Award
winners
nice um good evening everyone my name is
John John le and I'm from the OS medican
group um OMG for short and the OS
medican group is a biotech company um
laser focused in drug development and
clinical evidence so we have a number of
Key Products which are going through um
clinical trials now in
Australia very cool Brian uh my name is
Brian staff I'm the co-founder of align
Ops group uh and uh what we do is help
companies set themselves up for Success
long term by helping them scale and and
set their operations up from the
beginning uh and then also in the states
there's a lot of distressed assets uh
and I work to help turn those around uh
myself and a team of 16 uh and in the
past uh scaling wise I've worked with a
lot of the largest companies throughout
North America uh that have scaled both
successfully and
unsuccessfully uh and got to see what
worked and what hasn't uh and was able
to grow my first consulting firm and
sell it to one of the big msos uh so
we're we're scaling and growing again
now all right very cool Round of
Applause for these awesome panelists so
we're very lucky to have such experience
on the stage with us and I'm Alex revich
uh I helped the first ICBC back in 2017
uh it's so amazing to see how big it's
grown uh and been coming back every year
uh I'm in Canada my day job when I'm not
doing ICBC is I have luch Brands we in
Edibles contract manufacturer with about
80 products in the market and I have a
pharmacy called hybrid Farm which has
medical cannabis and pharmaceutical so
that's me and uh really excited to do
this topic with you all and I never
really like to start with anything
negative at the beginning of of a panel
but people were really asking me a lot
about you know why this is so important
this panel and we talked about all these
crazy negative stories of what people
have done in the past so we're laughing
backstage about some of these examples
of these people who have done bad
scaling whether scale too fast scale too
slow so maybe let's start with a few
examples of why this is such an
important topic to give an example of
who's what kind of disaster can happen
if you don't plan for
scaling um so I think Canada is riddled
with example uh you have to know that
95% of companies in Canada are not
profitable uh you know selling at a loss
is definitely not something anybody
should be striving for and of course all
your favorite names are there orora
canopy ta Ray EXO all the big ones uh we
firmly believe that none of those
scaling up were good I mean a lot of
those company at first has at uh had a
mandate of scaling as fast as possible
and we'll see later what we do with it
while you saw happen most of those
companies don't even grow in Canada
anymore they now contract
grow yeah I've I've seen in in the
states and you're talk you're looking at
a person that's been in hundreds of
grows um you go in hey I've got this
great plan I'm going to I'm going to do
24 acres underglass and I'm going to
flood the market with with flour and
they say okay how sustainable is that
because right now you're getting x
amount per pound wholesale and then when
you go in and you pull this flower on
the market Market it's going to drop the
price so you know it's it's just a never
ending then the price goes down it goes
down it goes down to the point where now
you you priced yourself out of the
market by flooding the market so you
know you got to have a you got to really
understand your market and the strategy
and you got to understand what parts to
accelerate what parts to decelerate so
that's what I've seen as a big issue
with people good point uh well joh and I
think um I think good on them for giving
a goal to scale
um clearly it's because they use someone
else's money because otherwise you
wouldn't do it um the first question
that you need to ask yourself is can you
sell what you're actually producing now
back in the days when it was just
starting it was very obvious and
transparent from a regulatory
perspective that it wasn't a case of
build and they will come um because no
one's going to come if you can't sell
stuff that you actually grow so I was VI
perplexed early on looking at um the
cost of the scale um to do the business
um and what they could actually
essentially generate as revenue and the
revenue from my um analysis was was was
negligent because what they hadn't
surprisingly taken into consideration is
the fact that the regulatory framework
doesn't allow Australia to grow cannabis
and sell it just just to anybody in
different parts of the world obviously
we all know here we're very educated in
this space but for some reason I don't
think anyone um really took that into
account and therefore got a bit
overzealous um build it they will come
and we will sell it um interestingly now
those companies are complaining about
Imports um because they're saying we
can't make any money well of course they
can't make any money because you can't
make money if you're going to grow
something that cost you $10 if you can
buy it for $2 it's a commodity so I say
good on you for giving a goal they've
done an awful lot of heavy lifting but
for any company that wants to drive
Innovation I would suggest that what you
would do is you'd identify what the
disease state is that you want to focus
on and then you would Tinker around what
um ingredients and recipients whether
CBD or THC might address that market you
then take that product from your lab and
you go through the various clinical
trials to get it to the point of on
shelf so scale is all about having the
right
evidence-based paperwork to be able to
sell a product worldwide
otherwise how do you it's a complex
Market there's different regulations in
different markets if you think about
what GW did with the EP dialects they
focus on registering a medicine and
that's why they can actually be
recognized worldwide as a registered
medic and it's important what you said
also uh about the investment you know I
like to joke if you wouldn't use your
children's college fund money on it
don't do it just cuz investors are
giving you money now I can tell you that
that ship does not last for a long time
and then when it stops coming you're
you're out of luck uh Brian what do you
think I mean I'll I'll tie into that
which is the the investment may be here
now and there may be you know ample
funds to be able to find in this market
today but I could speak from experience
in other markets where as the industry
evolves if you're not returning for your
investors because you have not scaled
properly or have not built the business
properly that investment will dry up
quickly uh and which makes it
exponentially more difficult to achieve
your goals yeah and we're going to jump
a little more into investment later on
because that's such an important part of
this uh and we'll we'll talk about in a
moment but you know since we start off
with something negative and all these
disaster stories of what happens if you
don't plant a scale let's talk about
some examples of people who have scaled
I know you have some of your own
examples and don't be shy to talk about
them but you know let's talk about who's
done it right cuz some people have done
it right not many but some um so I'm a
little bit biased but I'm going to name
us origin nature of course um our vision
was really crawl walk run um so CIS you
need to understand is the most
wellestablished black market uh industry
in the world uh you know there wasn't
really ever an over Supply in Canada
there was big companies that grew a
bunch of [ __ ] weed that they couldn't
sell at the price they produced it at
and so they placed it as over production
because that's what they had to say we
first started by meeting the first
demand that was there in front of us so
we went to C the sqdc which is the
government uh the government control
Quebec and the distribution so we asked
them what do you want we want a sativa
$5 perfect we're going to build that
once we met that demand and we were able
to grow a life plant consistently
whether it was from the flower aspect
the Canin aspect and we were able to
build some brand recognition that's when
we decided to go ahead we also by that
by that time it was a project that
started with $6.6 million and we did a
dividend payout of $1.5 million after 18
months so we did secure an investors
before actually moving ahead and
expanding when we did that expansion we
didn't also place all our eggs in the
same basket we right away decided to go
to Germany to go to Australia uh um
contract growing also we didn't just
assume that everything we were going to
produce was going to go to the W Market
like before so we made sure to diversify
always have a plan A A Plan B a plan C
cuz Things fall out really quickly in
the canvas industry so we really took
our time to crawl walk run another good
expansion is the one that can did in in
uh Quebec so if you don't know te God
like to invest a lot of money in super
impressive uh green houses uh one I
think they did 60 million canara got it
back for 12 million they didn't turn
back on the entire facility when they
got it they're renting a lot of it to
other people they turned on little
section per little section as they were
rolling out their product throughout
Canada because you don't grow weed that
you haven't sold yet and so that's a
very good roll out from canera with a
gigantic facility that a lot of other
companies that were mentioned before
would try to just put in full-blown
activity like let's say a side in
Edmonton that was called
Sky yeah well there's many Canadian
examples of uh that but we won't get
into that George some with some good
examples yeah I've seen I've seen plenty
of them I mean there's an outfit out in
Las Vegas called Shango um they what I
really appreciate about what they did
was they had a plan they said this is
where we're going to be in one year two
years three years four years five years
they stuck to their plan they they they
had a building that was too big for what
they needed but they didn't fill up with
with other stuff they said okay this is
going to be future growth this is going
to be future growth so really the only
thing that they were stuck on was real
estate right so they didn't buy a bunch
of extra equipment they didn't buy a
bunch of extra Grow rooms um they they
sold vertically within their own
dispensary and then I also see it with
some of the big msos in the US as
opposed to some of the stuff that we saw
up in Canada as well um you know the air
Liberty Cresco um uh cure Le
um these are some they have they have a
lot of people that that are looking at
the Cannabis which is used to be
um what was the Cannabis called
before they're big I forgot the name but
but they're huge yeah you know who they
are who's who's called what the Cannabis
they're called the cannab the Cannabis
now acreage yeah yeah acreage hold yeah
so but they they you know they they have
good plans and and I always find that
the people right plans with the good
plans that follow the plan you know hey
by the way you know look at this bubble
hash or look you know we want to do this
other product over here follow the plan
because if you're thinking that you're
going to do it there's already 12 other
people out there thinking they're going
to do it how much you think that people
are going to buy how many people are
going to buy it guys you know and know
your audience the other thing I see is
you know people that that know who their
buyers are because somebody said it
earlier but you have you know somebody
goes out there says yeah I I grow a ton
of month I'm like great well where do
you sell that well we we use half of it
ourselves and then we we're we're going
to export it to freaking uh
Antarctica you know and it's like okay
do you have a distribution Network set
up because because not only have I heard
that from you I've heard that from the
last 20 people I've talked to
everybody's going to sell you know flour
in Germany everybody's going to flow
sunflower and mol every got you know
everybody's in so you really got to
understand your Market of what you're
going to sell because you might think
you're going to sell a ton a month and
you're not you know are I have to give I
have to use a quote to something you
just said Mike Tyson I have to quote
Mike Tyson to say everyone has a plan
until you get punched in the face I
don't know if anyone knows that line but
that's actually works in the Cannabis
industry completely like so you have a
plan but then you get punched in the
face by the regulations or or something
else or the the bank or whatever and
then sometimes you got to Pivot but uh
Fair Point uh what else do you guys
think
I agree 100 good examples yeah very good
yeah and I agree in terms of um and and
my introduction earlier I mentioned that
we're laser focused that's the reason
and like that I've actually experienced
a lot of different companies going oh
it's co let's do this oh it's that let's
do that so they keep jumping all over
the place so I think for me it's a bit
different in terms of what I see is
Success because I'm not looking at it
from a how do we self lower or how do we
man ufacture stuff or how do we grow
stuff because we're about drug
development so the companies that we
look at in terms of the ones that are
exceptional are doing at scale are
companies like GW Pharma that have spent
the time to um invest in the clinical
data um getting the results that is
required to get registration and then
investing in that registration and of
course that worked out very well for
them as we all know because as soon as
that one product was registered they
sold for $7.8 billion to Jazz
pharmaceutical so from our point of view
we' have been laser focus from the
beginning it's very much on that pathway
it's about what products what indication
and what can we
realistically um register in terms of
the Cannabis in general I think that I
would say to everyone here um it's very
important of course cash flow we all
need a bit of cash flow
so for us for example At OMG we have two
divisions I'm not selling anything I'm
just trying to give you a bit of an idea
is to tell in terms of the strategy um
one of them is a division that we can
sell products over the counter I won't
get into the details and that early
stage that allowed us early stage
Revenue quite significant and enough
that we can invest that money straight
into the clinical trial which means that
as a company we're not out looking for
investors we're not scratching around
try to get a dollar here or a dollar
there we're very focused we had the
budget when we started and we're going
down that pathway so any company that
puts in the time and the hard jards and
the money because it's not for the
fainthearted um is about Gathering the
evidence so that they can have a product
that
worldwide can be
sold yeah no that's a very that's a very
good point uh Brian sure to give you two
examples uh both of these from the
states of Camp companies that were
successful in scaling uh one brand
called wild w yld d the other called
Wana W na both uh gummies Edibles Brands
um the to me their success has been
dictated by two things they've stayed
very asset light where they proved their
model in one market and then took that
model and licensed it to many other
markets uh and didn't go through all of
the capital expenditures of building
their own facility in every individual
Market uh they took their IP made sure
that it was easily repeatable uh and
placed it wherever they could and
managed the quality control through
those agreements uh if you can stay
asset light it's going to make scaling
much easier because you won't need as
much investment
obviously that's a excellent point and
you know one thing I've heard from all
four of you I think that's really
important is the import to being focused
but also having a business that funds
your business like it's nice to have big
plans and Innovative and be a dreamer I
mean yeah we need that and in cannabis
we're always pushing the boundaries but
you also need a business like at lch we
also do contract manufacturing we make
products for some of the biggest
companies in Canada we don't make a lot
of money on it it's a volume thing but
it keeps the lights on so that we can
actually have some of our own Brands and
and try to do Innovation and I think I
heard that from all four of you uh you
know much like in California which
people think is an awesome Market you go
to La and you're like wow this is the
best Market I've ever seen but then you
actually talk to the business owners who
own the businesses and they're they're
dying they're not making money and I
said how is that possible the ones that
survive are finding other ways to make
money which I won't say uh up here on
the stage but you got to find ways to
make money to fund your dreams and hopes
but uh you know as we're looking at uh
funding you know this is such an
important part and me and Brian were
talking about this before and a few of
us backstage it's nice to have these
dreams but if no one's funding These
Dreams they're they're just going to be
dreams and if you think they're going to
be funded later like hey let's just get
started and we'll find the funding later
I've seen many shutter down facilities
we were talking an example you were
saying the caner example how they bought
over a facility of a bankrupt company
that's that's a good strategy because
that other company didn't plan for
funding maybe Brian if you want to start
off you have a lot of experience with
this how important is funding and what
what can you what kind of advice can you
give these people when it comes to that
sure yeah I mean something I like to say
is that funding is the fuel that that
really lights the fire without it you
have no fire your business goes goes out
uh number one thing uh that I've seen in
the last two three years the big
difference from say 5 to 10 years ago uh
is that everyone is focused tremendously
on iida are we making money can we make
money uh and so in order to illustrate
that I emphasize the importance of
having a a business model a financial
model that's you know on paper that
actually withstands
practical
experience years ago say 2012 to
2018 most models were based
on I mean hopes hopes and dreams that
didn't come to fruition uh often the
business model was showing a relatively
steady line of wholesale pricing for all
of the product uh which as we all
understand supply and demand as that
market saturates that price creaters uh
which makes know everything more
difficult and makes the model Now fail
uh so what the best way is to be able to
show that model can work with practical
knowledge
showing some commonalities between
markets every Market's going to be
independent whether we're talking
Germany or then other European countries
Canada or any other you know state in
the US everything's going could be a
little bit different but they all follow
a very similar path where prices are
very high early on and you can take that
extra margin reinvest in your business
like we're saying if your business can't
continue to fuel your business you will
again run out of run out of fuel uh but
really um if we can oh just just lost
that train of thought I get because you
said bless you in your mind I also do
that if I see I always say bless you but
no those are those are some really good
points uh George uh I I know you I'm
sure have some thoughts on funding and
investing uh like making sure you're
well funded and John we were talking
backstage uh how how important is being
well funded and and having the right
investors in
this well I don't know cuz I haven't got
any okay so so maybe's your secret and
the reason is be deliberate deliberate
because I believe just like you said if
you don't spend your grandchildren's
whatever it is and heritance so you're
not going to put your own money in in
your bucket
so Scottish people tend to shove their
own money in make it work build it tweak
it build value and then we can talk
about Investors investor opportunity but
until there's value I wouldn't invest in
a company that I didn't see an end
result so in actual fact
my um my desire was to invest in a
company that's all I wanted to do
because of the all of the stuff and I
won't bore you with the details but by
exciting Market but
interestingly when I went and met people
all over the world it was wonderfully
exciting their decks and their
positioning and they were going to make
gazillions of money but when you start
to ask them questions about well who you
selling it to yeah it's like like well
anybody can buy it we'll sell it to
anybody you know any everybody's going
to want it but of course we know this is
medicine and I'm talking about from a
medicinal perspective so it's not as
easy just to sell stuff so we were very
deliberate not to go out and um and to
raise funds until we actually gathered
the evidence created and developed our
own products not white labored products
and we actually started selling them so
obviously we were six years in that
development stage and for the last years
we've launched worldwide with our
products so in terms of the the going
out and talking about investment it's
not something that we're actively
looking at now now the group CEOs in the
room somewhere he's probably got a
different perspective um in terms of the
future um the co is usually the one that
has to worry about that he'll be worried
about that he's telling me that we he'll
probably have a different view on that
but for us for me I will only only
invest in something if I can see
something that is going to give I like a
bit of Blue Sky don't get me wrong but I
need to see something what is it that
you're going to have if it's a CBD
product then it has to be different from
any other CBD product well if you can't
make it different then what viable
product have you got that you're going
to generate revenue from because if
everybody's got a CBD product and it's
CBD or THC what makes a difference then
we get in to the price to the bottom so
for us it's it's it's it's more
important to build the value so that
investors will come we don't want to
have to go out and start spooking we
want to say look at what we've done is
this something that you feel will value
and would that resonate to your um your
investment strategy then we can have a
discussion right and yeah but not with
me cuz I can't talk about money with
anybody but we can talk to the group
anybody of any interest in that front
yeah and uh yeah I'm sure I'm sure he
would have a different perspective of it
and we were talking with Brian also
around the importance of complacency and
not being complacent and how complacency
can kill you like you're in a great
position you're a leader everyone's
giving you money you be careful cuz
someone's coming after that very quickly
and you can change you know I I remember
I was here a few years ago and someone
asked a question what's the num number
one piece of advice you would give
someone to get for the Cannabis industry
I was like w it's a lot of pressure I
have like literally one minute to answer
a question question and I said be
careful you get your money from when you
get investment don't just be excited
that someone wants to invest in your
company like someone might want to
invest in your company and that's going
to destroy you because the wrong
investor is going to whip you and make
you rush and all of a sudden you're
tripping on yourself and you're not
executing your plan the way you thought
you were and boom you've actually lost
your whole business because you took the
wrong investor on so uh Brian what do
you think about that I'm sure you have
some thoughts yeah I was just going to
add that cannabis is so unique and again
you know Market by market it's so unique
that you need an investor that has an
open mind so that they're not forcing
your hand there's so many situations
that come up where a regulation changes
or perhaps we're doing it this way in
one market but the regulations Force us
to do it that way in another in a lot of
scenarios an uninformed investor the
wrong investor doesn't fully understand
the true length of time that it's going
to take to execute on that change or
that idea and creates a false pressure
that then forces decisions that hinder
the business long term yeah or even
worse if you ever seen an investor who
gives you advice he invests and all of a
sudden they start telling you how to run
your business I've seen that before and
it's like excuse me if you knew how to
run the business you'd be running the
business and not just as an investor I
don't know if you've seen that before
but it's pretty crazy well I I wanted
exactly to touch on that like we're
talking about getting funding but you
exactly what you said you should ver
watch out who you get that money for you
should probably not have invested on the
board also that have divesting interests
on what's actually happening right you
need when you build a canas company it's
not easy money it's a lot of hard work
scaling up takes a lot of time to be
done properly so it's very important to
find the right people to put on the bus
before you're actually driving that bus
and one thing that we've learned is you
know uh to get the 40 investor to start
origin nature there was over 400 meeting
right so every no gets you closer to
that yes for every nine person you see
find the right one but do not haste in
getting money do not haste in you know
most people that don't understand canvas
are going to try to push you to do
absolutely everything pre-rolls canas
2.0 just expand expand spread your res
psychedelics why not psychedelics too
whatever mushrooms let's do it and that
will kill your business so get the right
people on board before you drive the bus
and get it to the right place everybody
needs to be align so don't just rush
into getting
money and just from a perspective of
seeing a bunch of different C SC arios
you
know you got to really understand your
investor and their motivation that's the
key thing is their motivation are they
out there yeah are they are they there
to make money yes but are they either to
make money in the short term or the long
term and how much are they how much are
they going to try to influence you to
change your plan and how
much how much influence do they have
over your plan so you just got to be
careful with investors because if you
don't play it right they're going to be
up they're going to end up being claim
filers and further riding the bus it's
like he's going to hijack the bus right
you just invited him on a seat on the
bus next thing you know he's kicking you
out in your he's driving your bus to use
that analogy but uh we're going to open
up the questions in one moment so
hopefully some people have some
questions I see some people looking over
there one last couple quick bullet
thoughts on International markets that
either you're scaling to currently or
that you're hopeful for uh to scale to
one day I met someone earlier that's
waiting for Mexico to open up and he's
like Mexico's going to be so huge I'm
like yeah keep waiting but yeah maybe
one day but maybe something a little
closer uh that's that's actually
happening faster or that's you're doing
right now any any thoughts on countries
I'll kick it off with uh Thailand uh
seeing Thailand really explode um
something I've been learning about in
the last couple of days is just
exponentially that the growth that we're
seeing there uh that excites me because
it seems to be a uh an interesting
Market to to see well we should talk
about that because they've exploded and
then imploded but that's a story for a
different panel but we can talk about
that after that's an interesting thing
sorry to jump over but so I've met
probably a dozen people I said oh yeah
we're going to grow in in our country
and we're going to send it to Thailand
yeah yeah yeah but yet you know and and
more than there's more than a dozen I
was just being fous right but yet the
Thailand um you know you don't know if
Thailand comes back and says hey look
we're going to buy flower from within
our own country first now what is that
person who's just said oh I'm going to
grow this whole truck full and I'm going
to send it to T they don't even have a
lab my friend ATA is setting up a
laboratory there there is no laboratory
why would you send weed to Thailand
Thailand can grow weed for nickola
gram right the true nickel bag they
don't they don't want your weed I need
that sound bite to play like 12 times a
day next time someone says that to you
just be like hold on go talk to that guy
uh I'll tell him I'll be honest about it
yeah it's like that's a good should I
say that aloud so I won't say that fine
um you want to open up the question
sorry no no no no it's okay you know
what I see some people with questions
very but you did you know these people
paid a lot of money to come to the show
they did they paid a lot of money to ask
good question so who I see some hands
over there there's one over here he only
takes questions beside him by the way so
you actually have to like go
close thank you gentlemen uh considering
customer excuse me considering customer
confidence quality and service which
would you say is the most important and
why when building a successful brand or
company what were they again the three
things again customer service quality
customer confidence quality and service
which would be the most important and
why when you're attempting to build a
successful brand or company I would go
with C uh customer confidence so
establishing a brand in canas is
extremely hard uh all that American way
of pumping a lot of money in marketing
does not work in canas you're only one
lot away from losing all your clients uh
in the sense that it's a recession
people want something that every time
they pay for it it's going to be the
same effect it's going to be what they
paid for it's not going to be one batch
at 20% the other batch at 28 and I'm
really talking dry flower right I'm not
on the Pharma side so it is custumer
confidence for us to build a brand
recognition we had to be the number one
selling sativa for the last four years
before it actually started to happen
there is absolutely no brand loyalty as
there shouldn't be at the beginning of
an industry cuz we saw how that went
through there's no celebrity brand in
Canada that actually did good the Snoop
Dog weed was terrible like so that you
need to understand you cannot sell weed
with a lie consumers will not be tricked
so gaining their confidence at every
time they go to that store and they buy
that pouch or that bottle it's the weed
that they want and it's going to be the
same time same thing time and time again
within a very reasonable canaban range
is the hardest you can do by growing a
life and don't go telling the booth out
there who has the Snoop brand uh that
someone on the panel said that uh just
don't don't mention that but yeah
celebrity thing agree with his answer
with everything else comes from consumer
confidence quality customer everything
else if confidence is there all the rest
Falls in Brian what you think just going
to say quality above all else I mean the
consumer confidence that's it I mean if
if you can't produce a quality product
time and again it's over consistency and
standardization I think that's the kind
of key with those words uh question over
here question over here over there hi uh
thanks for being here uh question two
questions question number one we have
Partners in growing in Columbia I uh
what type of advice and what do you
think would be the future of growing
Colombia and actually exporting medical
to Europe question number two now that
we finally open up in Germany on Social
Clubs starting July 1st in order to
apply for the growing license um any
advice in our personal interest as well
that we now want to start kind of a
social club in Berlin um any advice on
that your Congress can give if I just
quickly start off by saying we I we need
to stop calling them Social Clubs I did
a panel yesterday at 11 there's nothing
social about these Social Clubs we were
joking they're called antisocial Social
Clubs because they actually do not allow
you to consume they're really more like
grow clubs um and yeah the advice you
should have been to my panel yesterday
but Colombia quick thought they're
actually finally doing something
impressive I thought I saw the number I
think they did about $1 million it took
many many years to get there but I think
they're finally doing something
impressive if they can get eug GMP
certified product and there's a few that
do it and they realize that stuff is
going to demand a lower price point I
think there's an opportunity there those
are my thoughts and I've got clients in
Colombia and we got units in Colombia um
the the the thing about Colombia is is
the is the uh the the stigma you know
the uh the the history the culture the
you know Colombia can really break out
by by exploiting hey you know we this is
the jungle grown this is the this is
this is from the mother earth you know
it's this is this is what been around
for years and years yeah the rainforest
everything I mean so it's I think it's a
lot of branding and and bringing
something different to the table and I
think that's something that that you
know Thailand you know Australia all
these places Germany you know it's funny
because people want to export everywhere
and everything you know but you know
it's they're they're making the same
strains you know like if you like
Colombian coffee where do you get a load
of Colombian cannabis yeah right right
col the smart man at ball all the C all
the c letters I noticed they're with the
letter c but you really have a good
opportunity in Columbia especially you
know the clients I have down there is to
is to really like homeo county in
California you know you know they
they've got the brand there because hey
you know where the guy you OG's of of of
weed in the US Colombia is the OG of
weed in the world you know so and I
would answer to to the Social Club um
we're going to really going to have to
build a very strong business model to be
able to design that operation and design
that facility to execute on that mainly
because of your not for-profit
requirement at least for now uh we'll
want to make sure that the money that
you have we put it to the best use
possible to be able to produce
consistently for your members so that
you don't risk them jumping to another
club because the way I see it is you're
going to want to retain those members
forever so that you can keep that
revenue from them and there's going to
be a way to design and build facility to
be able to keep it as as operationally
efficient and keep your costs low so
that you can provide really cost
effective product to your members to
keep them yeah and Alex you had a super
quick point before yeah so um for the
canas clubs uh for me I think it's a
legalization that's kind of broken it's
going to change for sure uh the reality
of the fact is you know I I explained
Greenhouse weed and outdoor weed is not
consistent it's not necessarily going to
meet regulations not necessarily be able
to build a brand on it the real value of
the fact is Germany does not have the
power grid to supply indoor uh
cultivation of canvas it's just not
possible with the power you guys have we
barely have enough and we're the number
one supplier right um so what's going to
happen is once you can't meet demand of
proper canvas you're going to promote
the black market if you don't uh help it
so I will build build a very small
facility 300 kg can be ran by 200 meter
of canopy flowering space right and gear
up to bring in Imports of course the
Imports are going to come in cuz you're
going need to supply all that demand so
it's
unrealistic like honestly guys there's
at least 200 tons of consumption
probably in Germany alone Quebec is 300
tons per year with the black market by
the way Poland has the lowest cost of
electricity in the Europe Europe so I
don't know if there's any Polish people
here but I think you have an advantage
sorry go ahead question any um so say
someone would have a um a relatively
successful business that they built from
uh from nothing but they think that um
they probably need some advice to get it
beyond that point and they're thinking
maybe of an Advisory Board like what
would be some of the maybe Unwritten
rules of engaging someone to say hey
would you be maybe interested in that
well first of all I think advisory
boards are one of the most important
things I'm a huge fan of advisory boards
I sit on a few and always recommend that
I mean to give you tips I think there's
a long conversation I don't know if
anyone wants to throw a few tips but
you're welcome to to come see us after
I'm happy to kind of give you some
thoughts on that cuz I have like a
40-minute keynote on advisory boards all
right yeah just carefully because I know
I know you're a consultant but he's a
wellestablished consultant so ask around
I used to be a consultant not in this
space but years ago ask around ask for
um if you're going to go the consultant
route having Consultants um give you
input and help you helping you to steer
decisions are is very good but ask
around uh make sure that they have I met
somebody yesterday was a car salesman
like a year ago now they're you know you
actually just reminded me last year
someone asked me about um uh about the
importance of advisers and and what I
told them is make sure your consultant
your adviser actually has done it so
many people are consultants and advisers
who have never actually done those
things they're Consulting and Advising
on so like make sure they've actually
successfully done it people like oh I've
done this this this was that successful
oh no uh this is the reason it wasn't
successful like okay I don't care do you
have any successes no wrong person
sorry next last one U thank you guys so
much Nea vesa here uh quick question
pivot off of what Alex uh you said it
earlier Alex or Alex the French one or
the Canadian one French oh ition about
French all right but this applied name
is i' love to hear any answer from
anyone here you me you mentioned
something very quickly which is try to
convince your investor or enable like
not have them on your board every that's
one of the biggest things I always see
anytime you're taking money they almost
always want at least a board seat how do
you how have you ever seen it
successfully convinced an investor most
investors actually want to have a seat
on the board when you said how don't let
them have a seat on the board I was
going to say that's a very hard thing to
say real investors are like they don't
trust anyone and they want to see on the
board but isn't there a percentage you
know like hey look if they're going to
throw 40% in you know but if they're
going to put in hey here's here's two
grand I want to see it on your board
absolutely take a hike guy and that's
what we mean by choose your money
carefully if someone's going to be
giving you that much money to be sitting
on the board you want that person to
have the proper qualification and share
the passion and the value when I say we
build a cabase business and we do 1.5
mil dividend in 18 months if that's
division forever it's going to be hard
for us to scale up at some point we can
be paying gigantic dividend and scaling
up at the same time so that's where the
vision needs to be understood you know
also you know do you want to build a
business that's going to be a legacy
that's going to live on after you're
done with it or sell have you ever heard
of an instance where an investor was
like I don't need the board seat um
unfortunately I'm not the most
well-versed uh you know my professional
career is mostly cannabis before that I
didn't really go to school so I'm not
the best one to answer that question but
but I will point out I think it's okay
for them to have a seat at the table but
as long as it's a seat and nothing more
than that I think it's all majority
board's made up of five people seven
people as long as there's less of
investors versus actual business people
on there I think you're okay but yeah
having a seat at the table I think is
okay so they know what's going on and
they feel comfortable and hey sometimes
you actually need need more money from
those investors they're the easiest
people to get more money from so if they
know what's going on and they feel
comfortable they're the most likely to
reup and add more money which is kind of
but what's that percentage what's that
percentage where you go back to somebody
who wants to invest and you say well if
you give 20% or whatever what's the
percentage to get them good point I
think 20% if you have anything less than
20% you can't even ask them for a board
seat I I think if you have at least 20%
invested you can actually request but if
you're like 5% I don't know unless
you're awesome and they really like you
sometimes people that's actually a quick
Point uh invest having an a strategic
investor sometimes it's not even about
the money honestly this might sound
crazy to say at a business conference
the money is not the hard part I swear
to you if you have a really good
business and you have really talented
people lots of people will give you
money it's about taking the smart money
and having strategic investors that will
do more for you than just give you money
banks will give you money well not if
you're in cannabis but anyways uh they
do they do no they could and
internationally we'll see what happens
but uh you know this is the end of the
show
and uh yeah really awesome shout out too
and Alex Rogers and Jesse and Noel and
all the awesome people that put and
shout out to Alex and Alex and George
and John and Brian
fantastic
that
concludes the 2024 International
cannabis business conference Berlin
panel conference series we will see you
in Slovenia in September we will see you
back here in Berlin in 2025
uh April it's on the back of the program
there uh April 29th and 30th next year
back here in Berlin also look for us in
Brussels look for us in Slovenia look
for us in Barcelona wherever there's a
need for cannabis business the ICBC will
be there shout out to Alex Rogers shout
out to Noel Jesse Randy the whole AV
team uh Lisa uh Emma Leon Mike I got to
name all the guys I can't remember
everybody that's enough for now uh my
name is belum and we will see you next
time cheers
[Applause]