thanks for joining us Lori thanks for
having me hi everybody
gosh what a year it's been I feel like
we were just here last year but it's
it's also been really long has been a
long year and a long January 2020
well we got to go fast and there's a lot
to cover it's a big state so let's just
dig right in what are some of the top
2020 borough of cannabis control
regulatory changes to expect I'm seen
emergency rules about QR codes I'm
wondering if there's anything going to
be new and lab testing or coming for
retailers or distributors and certainly
I'm hearing a lot about metric although
that might be on the DFA side right so
as most of you know we just released our
emergency regs for the QR code require
retailers to post their QR code to help
consumers make informed decisions to
make sure they know they're going to
license retail shop so that just got
released we of course had some
legislation that was passed last year so
we are looking at SB 34 the compassion
care we had to make some changes in
metric in order to accommodate that and
all three licensing authorities are
working on regulations so that's going
to give a folks in the supply chain the
ability to donate cannabis to to folks
that yeah that really need it and so
that's coming up really soon so that's
pretty exciting and then we've been
working on a variety of changes so it
really encompasses a lot but a lot of
cleanup changes looking at the three
licensing authorities over the last
couple of years you know some people
have pointed out there's some
inconsistencies so what for example man
you know CD pH is written doesn't really
work when it gets down to distribution
so a lot of that cleanup we're looking
at so I think you're gonna see a lot of
things coming down more you know there's
a lot of confusion on ownership I think
how the Bureau looks at ownership is
slightly different than the other two
and so all that needs to be cleaned up
because if you're gonna apply for a
license it should be fairly consistent
between the three licensing authorities
what legislation is Bureau of the Bureau
of cannabis control watching in 22
you know the governor just released his
budget package and talked about a little
bit of agency consolidation potentially
potentially moving streamlining taxes
what are you watching what salient in
this new year well I think there's a
couple of things obviously the
streamlining of taxes I think that's
important to everybody even when we look
at you know where the point a collection
is going to be that may change things
for the bureau but I think you're
looking at things like trade samples may
pop up again so I think we'll be
watching things like that maybe what's
even happening on the hemp front you
know does that fall under you know a
regulatory structure and then of course
we will be watching how things develop
with consolidation that's probably a big
one right yeah just to jump off on
consolidation is there a timeline around
that at all is this a fast-moving thing
or a slow-moving thing and I mean that's
all relative to the speed of government
in general all right I think you are
gonna see some changes fairly quickly
when it comes to really just starting to
have a plan of what consolidation is
going to look like and what that
leadership's gonna look like so we're
all you know reporting to the same chain
of command I think what's going to take
probably anywhere from 12 to 18 months
is really we all have we all are located
in different facilities and really
geographically getting everybody in one
place or deciding where people are gonna
be I think that does take some time
I think anything I mean depending I you
know at at the state level I don't know
what's what you consider quick to what
we consider quick but I in my eye you
know if we get this done in the next 18
months I think that's that's a pretty
huge accomplishment and that's fairly
quick and I think the important thing is
is that the industry it's smooth with
the industry I mean there's gonna be a
lot of work to do within but as long it
we need to still be making sure we're
getting those license applications out
that we're answering your question so
hopefully as quick as we're moving the
industry isn't affected by it too much
what are some of your success metrics or
goals for 2020 at the
cannabis control wow that seems a change
every year so well I'm gonna tell you I
mean it's pretty exciting I mean for us
it's always the priority is making sure
people that are qualified to have a
license and want a license we get them
licensed I mean the more people we can
get licensed working with the local
jurisdictions to educate them making
sure we're helping them to approve some
of these licenses and then you know
enforcement I think for the next couple
of years is going to be a big priority
and making sure we're still have our you
know foot on the pedal of going after
unlicensed activity across the state
obviously consolidation is gonna be a
big priority for us and you know I think
it's a great opportunity I think the
fact that we're all gonna be one agency
is it just makes sense and I think in a
lot of ways it makes its combining all
of our priorities I think it's gonna be
in a lot of ways for the folks out in
the audience that works with California
it's gonna be really nice when you can
go to one place for your license search
to see who has a license one place to
apply for a license I think I mean us
streamlining that process and making it
more business friendly for the consumer
to apply for a license and get
information I think that is gonna be the
goal for this year to make sure we do
that right because I think it's
important we do that right is the BCC
fully staffed up how staffing looking
this year I know we got annual licensing
going on and these are two separate
questions but what hiccups can people
avoid common hiccups can they avoid any
annual licensure yeah so we're we're
we're getting we've staffed up a lot you
know within the bureau we're close to a
hundred employees we are we are almost
fully staffed on our licensing and
really probably the biggest hiccup we
find with people is just a lot of just
just things like that when we reach out
to folks a lot of times it takes time to
get things back but I think a lot of
people have trouble with the application
maybe what they need to do
maybe not understanding what they need
for like providing us and I think the
biggest thing I can say is like please
reach out to us have that everybody here
if you have a application with the
bureau you're assigned a licensing
analyst to work one-on-one with you with
your application if you're having
trouble with that application we want to
know we want to walk you through it and
so I think instead of like anything else
when sometimes you don't understand what
you need to do you tend to put that off
oh yeah we all do that I do that and I
think it's like just let you know
whatever we need to do to work through
that application the good news is is
that for the annual application most of
you are getting Provisionals and a lot
of times we can get those Provisionals
out and then we can slowly work with you
to get those annual requirements so I
think it's not gonna keep you from doing
business so I would always encourage you
whatever we need for that provisional
get that to us first so we can get you
in a provisional and then we can work on
all the rest is there a BCC help phone
line have you considered doing one of
those yes that's a good point so we do
have a phone line that can reach
directly to our licensing people and you
know you're gonna ask me for it right
now and I'll get you well we'll get you
it but it's more to your point anyone
800 BC yeah we're we yeah that's what we
do need that yes we we do have that
number but I think I like your idea we
need like that vanity number so it's
easy to get a hold of us and with more
people it allows us to be more
accessible and I think we're trying to
you know not everybody wants to be
communicated by phone someone email but
somewhat text so I think you're gonna
see us exploring more of hey how maybe
asking you on the application how do you
prefer let's communicate to you so we're
making some changes to the application
where we're gonna ask those questions so
then we know what your preferred method
of communication is I know it's crazy it
is but I think it's good we're also
looking at doing a lot more in the
application process putting little help
says we find that there's a lot of
things we can head off by just putting
those things and so we're really looking
at how that application is online and
trying to make some really needed
changes to it to make it easier for you
so you don't have to call us up that you
got the answer right there
how is your email response times I
gotten a couple social media questions
about like I'm having trouble getting an
email response back yeah you know I you
know I could I think I'm gonna say we
are we're really responsive especially
on the the questions that we answer on a
regular basis we those are we got those
right we even have a database that we
house those on our website which is your
questions answer it's a searchable
database I always say on some of the
questions likes unique business models
that we get those do sometimes take
longer right because we don't know the
answer and we are and sometimes we have
to contact public health and food mad
because it's sometimes it involves all
three and so we do just so you know we
meet every week to talk about email
questions we're not sure how to deal
with and have a controlled trimmer
agency doesn't have any pot but anyway
that's my job you guys have creative
questions - there's like ice cream
trucks well there's all sorts of things
you guys have great ideas and we got to
keep up with all those great ideas one
question people have is what is the
future of lounges
there's certainly a number of
consumption lounges there tend to be
locally licensed and the BCC is yeah
really lounges is is more of a local
jurisdiction issue and we that is really
if the locals allow a lounge most of the
time there's not gonna be an issue with
the BCC unless it's violating some sort
of regs but so far we haven't had any
issues with the the social consumption
lounges that have been issued
there could be some out there that we
don't know about that we could have an
issue with but but yeah that's more at
the local level and so yeah you know one
thing you guys do have is eighty-five
events like events licensees this year
can you speak to that licensing space it
seems like there's a lot of them as it
means we're gonna have a lot of events
this year what's your read on the event
this awesome events license that no
other state has and California cannabis
tourism in general well I just was at a
reason I understand Michigan sort of
they took what we did you know I I feel
like I hope that we get a lot more event
temporary events coming up we had some
really big ones last year you know we
have had Emerald cup we've also had
grasslands which was under council it
was huge and it really went off with
with no issues at all and so I think we
you know if you go back to years when
the statute only allowed you to have
temporary events on on fairgrounds or
district agricultural places and then
that got changed to allow for it could
be anywhere where the jurisdiction
expressly approved I think we thought
there'd be a lot more event licenses and
I don't know that we've seen that and I
think the locals are really trying to
figure out where the best place to have
these things so I really am optimistic
that we're gonna have a lot more of
these this year what do you tell people
who ask I mean so much of this stuff is
local what's the best way to affect
local change that you've seen do you
have any stories that stick in your mind
where locals really changed their
environment I think of people running
referendums or taking city council seats
I mentioned you know that last year yeah
I mean I think all of that at the local
level has to come from the constituents
of that jurisdiction and really engaging
with the local politicians though that
that that's a full that could almost be
a full-time job
you know that you have to be on top of
that and so I think also though it's a
lot has to do with their also struggling
with resources they have a lot of other
issues they're dealing with in their
jurisdiction whether you know
homelessness and housing and all those
things so I think the more you can keep
them informed about what's going on with
cannabis and the statutes and and just
keeping them educated is also you know a
really valuable thing and if you know of
like a local jurisdiction that seems to
want to do cannabis regulation but maybe
they don't know where the start we're
happy to Steve we know will step in and
send people there and and really talk
with them about it because you know we
want to make sure they get really good
information so if you think there's a
jurisdiction out there that's struggling
that you think would be valuable for us
to talk to we're happy to do that as
well I saw for the first time that the
League of California cities this
Association of California cities that
does a lot of lobbying they not only
have model band ordinances on their
website but for the first time they have
actual model dispensary ordinances and
it struck me that the lack of
institutional support over these years
has left these bewildered citizens who
you know are in charge of their locality
kind of gun-shy about moving forward on
a lot of this stuff do you see any more
institutional support emerging to
support locals who again remained the
wildered and outgunned in terms of the
legal innovation required to do a local
ordinance well I think you're seeing you
know one of the things we did do last
year is released the local social equity
grants we award ten million dollars to
ten jurisdiction we there's now go-biz
just announced another round of yeah
there's close to thirty million and
they're they're also going to be giving
out grants to local jurisdictions and
intend to do a social equity program so
I think that's really going to really
you're gonna I think you're gonna see
more local jurisdiction looking at
cannabis regulation look at in social
equity programs so I think you're gonna
see some of that changing also you know
because we get
so many questions from the local
jurisdiction I think people if you're
not from California
you forget we have over 500 different
cities and counties that we have to
interact with it's it's it's huge and
country yeah and we're finding locals
are asking more questions we're
expanding we have a local liaison unit
and their sole responsibility is just to
work with that local jurisdiction answer
their questions we having a dedicated
phone line so they're not waiting for
answers because we want them to get
answers so they can answer you as well
so I think you're gonna see hopefully
I'm trying to be optimistic that that's
gonna change this year how many stores
do you think California new ones well
well the state might license this year
well it's actually state and local I see
the licensee numbers come out every week
I see new stores opening in places that
have never had them I see cannabis
commerce coming to places that never
even considered medical cannabis
commerce you know talking to some
experts like Amanda where at counter
regs we're guessing that maybe two or
three hundred more stores might join the
mix this year what do you see in that
tempo I think that way I'm hoping that
happens I think when you look at our
population and a number of retailers I
mean I mean really it's you know with
the number of yeah I mean we want people
to have access to legal cannabis and you
can't do that when you have pockets of
the state where people can't access
legal cannabis unless they have to drive
several hours so we want as a state
right we want them to be able to access
places that have their cannabis tested
to make sure they're they're you know
paying their taxes their packaging and
labeling and so it's really I'm hopeful
to see increased access at the retail
level I think that's good for everybody
it's good for your distributors and
retailers right now right right and I'm
seeing again like there's 500 plus
cities or counties even if a hundred of
them just do one or two stores for the
first time it makes a measurable impact
how many we have going right now when
you look back at 2019 what do you
consider the biggest wins of last year I
don't recall you were telling LA Times
that
not a single confirmed case of exclusive
use of a licensed or vape product
associated with injuries last year but
yeah when you when the clock struck
midnight what were you happy that you
know you got done last year well I
obviously the equity grants getting out
there and awarding grants that's that's
pretty incredible and when you look as
California's the leader on that and I
think you're some watching other states
take notice of that so I think that was
a huge thing enforcement I increased our
our enforcement efforts with starting
different techniques we increased how
many search warrants we're serving on
unlicensed places we're getting better
at our tactics of keeping them close to
so we're not going in and they're
opening up the next day but we looked at
tactics like we sent landlord letters
basically warning the property owner if
you're allowing your tenant to continue
doing this we're going to take action
against you I mean so all those trying
to find different tactics and different
things to go after the unlicensed market
and then I you know really stepping up
our public awareness campaign that's
probably been the biggest thing for us
is really trying to get the word out
there to consumers to try to change
those habits to encourage them to go to
the legal market and why it's important
to go to the legal market and and the
and the QR code I mean honestly I I
think we've been just trying to attack
it at all fronts what work do you see is
left undone I think we've touched on a
lot of it and in this talk so far but is
it just gonna be consolidation this year
streamlining licensing what are what
what is the big priorities well
obviously you know our stakeholders are
always gonna be a priority we want to
make Shan I said this earlier and I
can't say it enough I mean you want us
to be very nimble when it comes to
processing your license applications and
getting you licensed and making sure
we're responsive to you but also on the
same time we have to make sure we have
the infrastructure to support that so
continue to stay
but consolidations is a big part of that
but I'm pretty confident we can you know
we can get that done and streamlining
that I'm looking forward to you know
making sure that when you go to a web
you know you go to one website for all
of us I mean who wants to go to three
separate licensing websites to try to
figure out what you need to do so those
are some simple things we can do over
the next few months that I think is
gonna make your lives a lot easier
what is your read on the overall
industry health certainly there's been
some layoffs and some people who have
been moaning into the high tax and
regulation environment here in
California or the lows the slow speed of
local implementation when you look at
the dashboard for the California
cannabis industry the legal side what is
that what is that dashboard reading to
you you know I am always gonna I always
take I feel like we're speed-dating
right now so quickly I I'm always gonna
be optimistic because what happens I
don't know it I'll be honest with
cannabis it surprises me every day what
I think I know like two months ago I'm
like oh gosh I you know yeah it changes
and and so you gotta meet you gotta roll
with the punches so I'm I'm optimistic
that things are gonna look up and and I
think as long as you're engaged and you
keep us and making sure I'm going to say
if I if I ever get asked by any other
state what's the most important thing it
is making sure you're working with your
stakeholders you're listening to your
stakeholder I sort of say you got to
keep your egos in check as regulators
right a lot of times we need to just
listen we don't need to always be the
ones talking and as long as we have a
relationship where there's that mutual
respect I think we can accomplish a lot
of things over the next year a couple
more questions one I don't see Los
Angeles adding any new stores this year
in the city limits due to issues around
licensure there and who gets them and
the speed of rollout there is the City
of LA which is the biggest market in
California and arguably the world
where is the BCC going to help them or
is that really on them to sort out you
stand ready to issue the licenses to who
they license well we stand ready but at
the same time you know they have a they
they don't have an easy process to get
through and so we're always there to
help them they're one of our equity
grant recipients and so we're gonna
start and and one of the other things
you're going to start seeing is us going
around the state looking at doing
workshops licensing workshops to work
with the local jurisdictions and to help
our applicants navigate having the
locals there to help them navigate the
local process than having the state
there to have applicants navigate the
state process so as we see some of these
equity grants getting awarded we're
gonna start stepping in and doing these
workshops and I think it's gonna be
helpful to a lot of the local
jurisdictions so I you know we're there
for any of the locals I don't I don't
feel I'm not one to just stand back and
wait I think it's you know up to us to
make sure to provide any resources that
we have that would assist them in LA a
lot of Angelenos are confused as to
what's a licensed store and what's not a
licensed store there's a long history of
unlicensed operators there and there's
very few licensed ones the Bureau of
cannabis control has a licensee lookup
tool on its website do you know how
effective that is is it working our
consumers going there to disambiguate a
licensed or from an unlicensed one what
more do you want to do to make sure
people know the difference
considering that 80 90 percent of them
is their first time ever walking into a
Spencer E they don't even know what to
expect right so with our public
awareness campaign we did change the
name of our license to church so it's
see a pot check comm and hopefully
people like it's a lot easier than
putting BCC CAA correct and so I think
we are gonna make some more improvements
to our licensing search because you know
that we don't we you can't search by DBA
right now and so a lot of you don't know
the legal name or and you may not even
know the license number so but then
again that QR code is also important so
we're requiring retailers they get a QR
code when they're issued their license
they can post it out in front of the
store and so if you're a consumer you
can just take your camera take you know
scan it and it'll tell you all the
information you need about that licensee
the owners whether it's an active
license and so we're hoping that helps
consumers because they can make that
decision prior to going into the store
because you know you always have to post
your license inside the store but who
wants to go in there and say hey I feel
super intimidated about this guy where's
your license like well but I think more
improvements to our license searches to
make it that much easier if you make
things hard people aren't gonna use it
so I think it it's good what we have but
it can be better
similarly similarly to that we have this
legacy of a lot of medical marijuana
products in the state and a continued
issue with counterfeit products at these
dispensaries you're rating them and
picking them up and seeing the
counterfeits is there anything on bcc's
radar about battling the issue of
counterfeits empowering consumers to be
able to tell the difference I get a lot
of people who go I don't I don't know
where this vape cards from and I don't
know how to tell right in in it is even
difficult for us to tell what the
difference is consumers are it's hard to
tell for us and even you know some of
our you know manufacturers I think we're
looking at the industry itself
especially our manufacturers and stuff
how how how can we label things to to
help not have so many of these things
counterfeited I mean and it's speaking
of the QR code we already having to see
we're seeing labs where they're saying
their certificate of analysis are being
counterfeited right and so now we're
even seeing labs voluntarily doing a QR
code on that CoA that eventually gets to
that label so you can scan that label it
goes right to the CoA so I think the
industry's pretty pretty savvy and I
think we're looking to work with the
industry to help us with how do we deal
with all these counterfeit products and
I think that's something that's that's a
big thing for this next year two more
and then we'll
yeah we did it first one is how is there
a better way to verify Bureau of
cannabis control employees when they do
staff snap inspections some licensees
have wondered is this a real BCC guy or
is this someone trying to roll me
because people have gotten rolled in by
individuals who are you know
masquerading as officials now yeah and
we get people that that you know they
have fake websites that say the Bureau
of cannabis oh yeah we've seen that and
we try to shut those down so there's all
sorts of things so if our folks go out
to a licensed inspection they are
wearing shirts that identify themselves
they also have identification that they
are required to show you if asked and I
have they have to have business cards so
if there's ever something like something
doesn't seem right it doesn't feel right
then we would say hey who can we you can
just call us to verify it and we will be
happy to take that call but our guys are
very professional they're usually going
to come out and at least pairs and so
you ask them for their ID ask them for
their business card I don't know where
with the QR code go to their wrist
ya know lastly two thirds of California
remains a banned town so to speak but
delivery can serve pretty much every
corner of the state at least the next
day some of these delivery services is
there anything on the horizon for
delivery in 2020 I know you guys don't
get involved with the lawsuit that's
ongoing although I will say it doesn't
seem like it holds much legal water but
is there any delivery needs we need to
know about thanks for the support so
when it comes to delivery the that we
have a regulation that says if you're
licensed by the Bureau and and you can
for delivery that you can deliver any to
anywhere in California we are being sued
on that and I know David's gonna be
upset with me but because there's a
lawsuit I'm really not allowed to
comment on delay
so just logistics of delivery those
delivery licenses are out those guys are
rolling any delivery regs to note today
none to note today okay if you have some
suggestions don't worry
yeah like I think people want to lessen
the regulation that I add more I guess
that's the one suggestions from everyone
you know lastly the continuing theme I
hear from people is how do we make
license easier how can you help us in
2020 the industry says they want me to
ask you that so that's the last sort of
question to you is like are we gonna
make licensing easier will you help well
that's a great question I think yes we
can make licensing easier is there
certain things that may always be
required that folks don't like yes cuz
that's in the statute so some things is
beyond our control we certainly being
responsive making things clear making
sure we clear up confusion is always a
top priority for us and we we do want to
help and I know that sound it sounds
corny to say cuz you're always like yeah
right but truly we don't want this to be
an arduous process for you and I do feel
like for a lot of you it does seem that
way well it is that not seem it is that
way and so I think we are like I told
you we're looking at ways on even our
ways that we can be more flexible as
well I think the last couple of years
there there was a tendency like we're
just following everything to the tee and
I think the the greatest thing that we
could do is provide more flexibility in
the in especially when we're seen as
businesses change in and so I think
providing allowing that would be helpful
over the next year well you got a hard
think this job thank you for getting up
every morning and doing it thanks for
joining us here at the international
cannabis business conference everybody
get along with von Klaus to Laurier Dex