it's a very warm welcome that's right
very excited to be here it's my third
time and first of all let's give a round
of applause I CBC organizers and Alex
Rogers they've done an amazing job to
get together check it available mic real
louder I can yell louder but we'll get a
lot of perfect so this is my third time
here and I try and talk a little German
when I come to show respect for local
German friends so when I first got here
that my first German that I learned I
welcomed everyone in my panel I said
who's coming
danke few little shining and then I was
told no no no no no that's not really
how you would welcome so then I the
second year last year I tried something
different I said we'll come in DeLand
dunk does a gecko
site so they said ok it's a little bit
better that's a little bit better right
a little bit better and then this year
because I have such a trouble after he
go to the bars to find a bathroom it's
so hard to find a bathroom in Berlin so
they taught me in shooting good
vous etes de Toilette da so a little bit
better a little bit better there so just
really really special also be sharing
the stage we had a legend here earlier
professor raff film of shulam who was
one of my heroes I'm a cannabis educator
so I've been talking about him for so
long so it's awesome to see him and we
had so many other legends here Hillary
black John Conroy mark we're all legends
from Canada so it's awesome to share
this this amazing stage and we got an
amazing panel which we'll get to in a
second but I wanted to point out since I
was last here a lot of things have
happened since we were last here we now
have medical and pharmacies we now have
extracts and edibles announced we'll see
when that actually happens but it was
announced we had legalization in retail
in fact today in my province of Ontario
is the first day of sales I'm waiting to
see some pictures of all the lineups we
were supposed to have a lot of stores
open some of them were an open little
sensitive subject for certain panelists
here we'll talk about that in a moment
and we also had the amnesty program
discussed where we're gonna remove
people's criminal records for their
cannabis so that should be really
interesting and we'll see how that goes
so maybe next year on our panel we'll
talk more about that but I wanted to
start with a few stats I think everyone
was really interested I gave some stats
last year and I said I really liked it
but try to
a little slower with the stats because
they were trying to write it down I'll
tell you all the stats after but I'll
just want to throw a few out with
patience the last numbers from September
were 342 thousand patients we estimate
there's above 400,000 patients right now
on the medical side with about 124
thousand shipments sent at that point
when it comes to how many doctors and
healthcare practitioners when I got in
the industry in 2013 there was about 40
or so doctors prescribing we now how
last month or the last month of recorded
about January 3500 doctors or healthcare
practitioners prescribe so we're getting
a little bit better an estimated about
14,000 in total have prescribed so we've
come a long way also on the medical side
products from January 9th 2019 we had
about 7,000 kilograms of dried cannabis
sold in that month which is a little bit
down which have some theories on but we
could talk about it later and about 7800
liters of oil which is an increase of 48
percent so we see a lot of uptick in oil
on the medical cannabis side and dry
flour is being kind of looked at now on
the retail and rec side so possibly some
some people were putting it aside for
that and the last couple stats when I
first came here my first year we had
about 40 licensed producers when I first
came on the stage last year we had 97
licensed producers and today we set at
about 143 licensed producers and the
last that I wanted to point out is that
the exports which is a little bit of a
sensitive subject here I imagine so they
peaked in in May of 2018 where we sent
about 339 kilos of dry flour in August
of this year we sent zero and in
September we sent one one liter one
liter of oil so sorry again
118 liters at one point in the peak
August we had zero and in September we
sent one liter of oil so it is
unfortunate we definitely feel the pain
of what we're hearing when it comes to
all this now to get into our panel why
don't we start with an introduction of
our esteemed panelists I'm very excited
every year I bring a great panel but I'm
very excited about this one in
particular even if you want to start us
off yeah cool thanks for the the context
there Alex yeah my name is Ian dick I am
the head of partnerships for regulated
industries within Shopify so I kind of
helped steer the company toward this
this market a few years
seeing the opportunity in our country
the sort of legislative open lane if you
want to call it to apply what we already
do in more broadly in the Commerce world
specifically to cannabis you know we
kind of Ted ourselves as an
entrepreneurship company allowing
entrepreneurs to sell any product to
consumers where they want to buy them
whether that's on an online store at a
point of sale or like through social
channels we're kind of there for them
and then so then more recently we've had
some success success in the cannabis
space in Canada specifically helping
licensed producers verdict vertically
integrated licensed producers sell
directly to their patients as well as
powering some of the recreational
operations both government and private
in country my name is Stephen verbeek
I'm the founder of hello cannabis
medical and education centers it's my
third time in Germany so thank you again
for for having me here we originally
started with a one mandate which was to
help D stigmatize cannabis and to be
able to help educate physicians and
essentially connect three dots that's
the patient's with physicians in product
this started about seven years ago it
has now evolved into eight different
projects in three continents and it's
been lovely we actually have a working
relationship with everybody on this
panel in some degree shape or form
Canada has a wonderful collaborative
effort that's been in my opinion a
moving target that we are all lovingly
trying to navigate through and
collaborate through in that we are
seeing some of the same challenges in
Europe so we are very much hoping to be
able to help the European and other
markets around the world learn from our
mistakes so we can help roll out at both
medical and eventually a adult use
market where everybody is able to
benefit from a plant that I see is one
of the most disruptive entities that our
world has currently seen thank you thank
you hello my name's teri Roycroft I'm
founder and CEO of MC RCI we are a
educational resource center
as well we started about 11 years ago in
Canada being one of the first clinics of
its kind we've been able to you know
stay within the different programs that
have happened through Canada through
Canada we've had three different
programs we've navigated them all to the
current a CMP our we train physicians
educate patients and are currently
looking again internationally here just
bring some of the SOPs and some of the
knowledge that we've had to some of the
countries over here that have not had a
chance to get education and just rolling
into the medical regime right now so
when we started there was one supplier
there was one clinic and we've seen it
now grow to as alex was saying through
the other stats here you know 145 LPS
numerous doctors and clinics using the
same type of model and supporting
patients across the country we do
telemedicine as well as walk-in clinics
so that we can support patients that
cannot make it to clinics and patients
that want to continue with a
face-to-face interview or appointment
with doctors cataria Andrew my name is
Andrew Muir off and I am a recovering
lawyer I have I'm also a cannabis
patient medical cannabis patient I've
been a patient since 2015 I'm the CEO of
stream print technologies we are a data
analytics company in Canada that helps
patients to track their medical outcomes
using technology using an app all data
is anonymous we track basically pre and
post symptomatic State against route of
administration against the dose and then
against the full chemical profile of the
product so we don't care whether it's an
OG Kush or we don't care what you decide
to call it we care what's the actual
ingredients of the products that you're
taking at the time our platform is HIPPA
HIPPA and Fitbit a compliant and will
soon be gdpr compliant we have the only
business analytics platform that sits on
top of a real data set so today we have
over 1.2 million patient reported
outcomes it's the largest set of its
kind in the world
and we feel very fortunate to have grown
that that's tens of thousands of
Canadian patients who are tracking every
single day
and so we power a lot of decision-making
across the industry in Canada licensed
producers clinics clinics are able to
track their patients performance in real
time licensed producers are able to see
what products they should be carrying in
their product set and doctors are able
to see what products are working for
what and we today have the only solution
that's in place in a pharmacy in Canada
and that's that solution basically helps
that pharmacy to deliver the right
treatment recommendations for their
patients and I just want to recognize
for one second if I can a couple of
pioneers in the Canadian industry John
Conroy and Jerry Roycroft here there are
others in the room and I feel that we
should all be thankful that they've put
in their time over the last 20 or so
years to make this industry possible in
Canada and then I think that our
experience in Canada has really helped
to influence what's happening the rest
of the world right now that's a good
point and a lot of people grinded their
teeth took a lot of bullets for us to be
here and I always like to acknowledge
that when so quick around applause for
yes John Conroy dr. mark where when he
was at he was a doctor doing education
that he was gentlemen speaking earlier
he was going to talks when no one wanted
to hear him talk and when I was doing my
education I'll be completely honest I
would actually say dr. mark ware says
and dr. mark swears research so I would
kind of hide behind him he'd be my
shield because they could put maybe try
to poke holes in what I said but I knew
he was very smart and I knew that it
would be very hard to poke holes in what
he said so so let's talk about access to
cannabis access to cannabis has actually
changed since I was last year and we now
have different retail experiences we
have it on the medical side we now have
some pharmacies also carrying it and
then we have the adult use or
recreational side where that's also
another way that's being sold so and
every province has their own rules which
is very frustrating but at the same time
I feel like Germany will can appreciate
this because there's also different
provinces with different rules so if we
just talk about the different retail
experience in how medical versus rec
looks like in Canada and someone wants
to start us off to kind of give their
thoughts on it so I held of cannabis is
actually very fortunate to be involved
on on both sides of this as I stated
before our original mandate was to be
able to help connect the three dots of
physicians patients and product it has
evolved where we were fortunate enough
to partner with
of the 25 lottery winners to open up one
of the first retail stores in in the
province of Ontario so our original
mandate was to try and truly
differentiate between medical and
recreational because it's it's quite
interesting when it's the same plant and
often the same product that straddles
both of those sides I'm a medical user
now I will candidly say that there are
times where I use it recreationally as
well and I don't pretend that I'm
actually medicating the analogy that I
say is no doctor is ever going to tell
somebody that is suffering from pain to
go buy a brown bag of heroin and put it
in a needle and shoot up now I'm not
saying that you are not extracting
medicine from that just like when you
are rolling up a royal joint which is a
dried flower in a bleach sheet of white
paper with glue something else that I
don't think many doctors would actually
would like somebody to medicate with I'm
not denouncing that you are extracting
medicine from that but there's a reason
why over 90% of the patients with hello
cannabis are using sublingual oils so I
do believe that we need to have a
separation between medical and
recreation and when you are able to do
that you're able to facilitate all of
the different medical medical and adult
use users and you were able to start
differentiating different product
selection very great point yeah I mean
those are all fantastic points and I
fully agree as far as shopify is
concerned you know we in terms of like
the software that's involved or the
solution that's involved the the two
experiences we're trying to like make
them somewhat similar and what I mean by
that is when you're looking at a the
customer journey the patient journey
through online buying experience what
we're trying to do is tailor it to what
the what the LP is trying to do is
tailor it to the the patient as much as
they can so that the the products that
they see and the amounts that they can
purchase are conducive to their
prescription information it's a very
personalized buying experience and I
think recreation recreational cannabis
is wants to achieve that same thing they
want to to educate the consumer and to
have these personalized experiences
because you know we were talking about
this the backstage but
you know the the level of understanding
of the product still has so far to go so
that people understand what dosage and
what potency is gonna work best for them
and so you know I really it's it's
really excited it's exciting time right
now because I think there's a lot of
innovation happening in that space you
know you look not to put it on blast but
drew over there is it with strain print
is is effectively trying to do that try
to unlock the secrets of this plant and
allow people to understand how it
affects their body and what's good for
them and what's potentially bad for them
there's there's other those are other
people trying to do this as well for
shop fights part we want to kind of be
this central hub that these technologies
can build into to then be like layered
into the the commerce experience and
overall just like lift up the industry
through education so what's interesting
is this we had a different experiences
with our patients before legalization
came to Canada there was still a lack of
education and lack of information that a
lot of patients wanted but when it
became legal we saw an increase in
people coming to see us we thought it
was going to be the opposite at first
but what happened is a lot of these
people felt more empowered to go and try
cannabis once it became legal even
though the program was in place for the
previous 18 years people still weren't
aware that there was this this access to
it and we're talking a lot about seniors
now so we've seen a huge influx in
patients coming medical they've gone to
their recreational stores and by law
they're not allowed to give any medical
information or even relate a certain
strain to a specific illness and that's
where a lot of people have been turned
around and are now coming back to the
medical side so they can actually get
that information and we've seen quite an
increase in that and usually as the
seniors mark it's a fast and growing
segment that we've seen now and when
they walk into a recreational store ask
for information they are now being
directed either out the door because
they can't be of American or we're
working with some of these groups
putting this together so that they can
direct them to a medical clinic to get
more information on it so it is very
interesting that that amount of
increase in patient flow once we were
illegal it was very interesting we
thought it was gonna be the office of
him we saw the same experience what
after after the program was announced or
after the program launched in October we
saw an increase in in what we're calling
elder care so it's basically yes as well
yeah so an older demographic who's more
open to using cannabis and and
across-the-board are interested in
getting off of part of the poly Pharma
you know that's the concept of having
multiple medications for the same
symptom one to offset the other so we're
seeing a lot of that on our side too
okay
excellent thank you very much for them
great answers and one thing that's also
very important that we find in Canada
and it's gonna be very important here in
Germany is the issue of a compliance
compliance can be your best friend but
it can also be your enemy I wanted some
would hear from the panelists some of
the things that they see what are the
good things about being in have elated a
heavily regulated market and one of some
things that can potentially hurt in a
heavily regulated market an important
thing to note is you can be as compliant
as you want but your partners that you
work with also have to be in compliance
so just some thoughts about some pros
and cons about being compliant and the
importance of making sure that your
partner is complying because anything
they do actually hurts you as well and
roof you want to start us off so we're
working with some of the largest both
government and private entities in
Canada on driving what we call
transparency and and standardization for
products right now we don't actually
have consistency among the licensed
producers on what they label in their
products and what they share with
respect to expand and cannabinoids and
turkeys a very important that we
understand that patients want to know
what's in their products doctors want to
know what are in those products and
that's now gonna be driven from the top
levels down where the pharmacies are
saying we need to know what's in these
products or we're not gonna recommend
them and Health Canada which is the
governing board that actually decides
what gets bought and sold and who's
licensed they also would like to see
that they would like to see the industry
regulate themselves but that's not
happening right now so there will be a
little bit of a push from industry to
drive that end government to drive that
down and we
see from our perspective is when we're
working with LPS and any of the other
peripheral groups that we work with is
sometimes that lack of consistency so
for instance we are working with
patients we recommend a certain strain
the physician does our aftercare
specials help them go to that location
or that that particular LP but if that
LP has some kind of a recall or they've
got mold and mildew where something's
happen to that product that directly
affects the companies underneath it so
as we're working conjunction with them
something like that would really affect
it our reputations as well we'd make
recommendations to a certain group and
they've got inferior product and that is
where you know working in a partnership
everyone has to be on on point and if
one of that pieces of the chain is is
broken well that creates an issue for
the whole chain to supply the patient's
the doctors everyone gets in impacted by
that link being broken and it can happen
on any one of the steps of that chain
that goes around the physician to be
giving wrong information that could be
wrong product and so it's really
important for all of us groups to work
together and have a consistent
understanding of what we're supplying
and our roles in the that change so that
everyone gets the medicine they need and
it's consistent and it's safe at that
point absolutely I have to completely
concur with what Terry's saying here we
are basically the frontline for patients
so if a patient is a upset or unhappy
with their product hello cannabis or mmm
CRC I are the people that have that
hearing so if we recommend a product in
that product is not as its stated or it
runs out and we've run into many supply
issues in Canada we're the ones that
face the brunt of it and unfortunately
our bottom line insolvency is dependent
on that so to come full circle back to
Alex's original question with respect to
regulation and I see a value in somewhat
having an unregulated system but of
course it needs to have a balance with
regulatory systems so when you're
looking at a medical component clearly
you can't have an unregulated market it
opens up the ability for the black
market to take in and you lack that
consistency in standardization which is
required with the medical product now
with a regulated product that are a
regulated industry you can start getting
this over-regulation which limits the
ability
for these LPS to be able to create that
supply chain and to be able to create
that quality that patients want so
finding that balance between an over
regulated market in an under regulated
market in my opinion is one of the
pivotal things that the European markets
really need to look at and unfortunately
I don't have the full answer for that we
are navigating through it it is a moving
target but you need to find a balance
where you are able to keep a
standardized product that is regulated
where you can confidently have
physicians back this product and have
companies and clinics like ourselves to
be able to support this product while
not restricting them from being able to
create a supply chain that could break
because once that chain is broken to any
of the one link in that chain is broken
everybody feels it and that's why we're
all a collaborative effort here and why
all of us work together
good good point to you yeah and I mean
that that's absolutely true I think that
touch on a few points but like my to my
point about consumer education
compliance is required in order to
create a consistent reproducible product
that then when you when you understand
these things about it it's going to be
consistent each time you use it with
with with our for our part we try to
strike this exact balance that Stephens
talking about of you know create as
frictionless a buying experience as we
possibly can
Wow also adhering to the strict
regulations and I think it's a it's sort
of a it is exactly that it's an ongoing
conversation it's a moving target and
it's it's it's that that is informed by
events like this where we all get
together and we talk about it and we
share things that have worked and things
that haven't worked and hopefully
legislators and regulators look to the
market and and try to you know intake
ingest information from that to make
sure that it is this collaborative
process where we're we're kind of
working to the craft this because as you
say striking that balance is key because
the unregulated market the black market
is not beholding to any of these things
and so the it's much more frictionless
so it is a it is a challenge there's a
cross provincial a B test going on right
now in Canada that we will share the
results of when it's a little further
along and we should have some updates on
that next year but to that point we've
learned a lot of lessons we've been at
this for about six years as an industry
started in 2013 and we've learned a lot
and we've made some mistakes and I think
Germany and other emerging markets can
learn from some other mistakes and maybe
Stephen you want to start it off with
some of the mistakes that we've made and
what we've learned it's not fair you
know all about mistakes it's a long long
list so I can say some of the mistakes
that we saw from a regulatory
perspective is again circling right back
to this over-regulation
it's very challenging for LPS to be able
to increase their capacity say you
bought a 40,000 square foot facility
that was not it that's certainly not
enough to be able to facilitate a large
medical market and when you create so
much regulation that you cannot expand
this your supply chain gets completely
broken down I would say one of the one
of the personal mistakes that I made as
a business was one not being able to
facilitate proper funding for
scalability if I can give a personal
experience with respect to my failures a
young CEO a lot of CEOs I find they're
drawn to empowering people and hiring
people that they see potential in and
there's something really special about
seeing talent being able to foster and
nurture that talent and see them exceed
their own expectations of what you
expect out of them as well that that's
one of my favorite parts about being a
leader one big mistake I made is when
you have 13 people that you empower and
you see big talent and they also see you
as a leader in more or less the nucleus
of all of this knowledge and
unfortunately they need your leadership
and your knowledge to be able to do that
so it's completely unscalable when you
have 13 people that are looking at you
to be able to lead them every single day
while you're also trying to scale a
company well I thought you were gonna
say that everything's been perfect and
then we may be full everyone it's April
Fool's but I guess you didn't want to
make that joke that's also the second
mistake I've know mistakes right now so
I'm off to a great start Alex thanks for
reminding me yeah I was gonna say like
that's that I like your story there I
you know tend to try to surround myself
with people that are way smarter than me
so that you know it doesn't all land on
me so that's all I'll add to that that's
a blooper reel yea those blooper Terry
so one of the mistakes that we kind of
participated in very earlier stages was
the the lack of being able to work in
conjunction with the colleges for the
doctors they need to get up to speed
much quicker and get more education and
this is when in the earlier days was
very difficult because the doctors were
being actually reprimanded and told not
to support cannabis even though there
was a legal program in the country to do
that and so when you've got the the
medical body saying this is not a
quantified medicine there's not enough
studies and you've got the ability for
doctors to do it and thousands of
patients asking those doctors this was a
real challenge one of the breakdowns
that we saw in regards to be able to
support those patients and you know as
we go around the country and we're
seeing the resistance we still see some
physicians even with the large demand
for product that is one of the you know
the challenges that we have that I see
that we need to really push forward on
getting more education of those doctors
and the colleges themselves even though
you have doctors that are willing to do
it the colleges need to take a look a
closer look at this so they can actually
support that initiative rather than
resist it in Canada the CMA Canadian
Medical Association was had a statement
the president stated or that the CEO
stated at one time that they were glad
at recreational was coming in because
they wouldn't have to follow through
with the medical program and in fact
they should get rid of the medical
program so this is something that was
very serious in in our side of it to
have someone of that nature come out
with a statement like that because
there's no way medical is going to
disappear there's too many patients
there's too much benefit and what we see
is a direct separation of this industry
the exact same plant being used for two
different segments and a lot of people
think when you're growing cannabis to
growing medical cannabis you're going
recreational cannabis that's not the
cases the same product being processed
at the end of that grow period to
facilitate either one of those markets
and that's a breakdown in the medical
regime that we see and I think you know
anyone taking lessons from that and from
Canada would be would be looking at that
to get the education from the colleges
to get on board more
right and education is the magic word we
are gonna talk about that in a second
and uh I'll talk about the CMA in a
moment but to answer any thoughts on
that question I have to I have to I have
to reiterate what Terry was saying when
the CMA doesn't support the cause it
really puts a damper on the good work
that people are doing too and and the
the improvements that thousands of
patients are seeing on a daily basis so
get your medical associations onside and
educated as fast as possible yeah I got
you've got to remember when that comes
from a source like that patients that
are hearing that are now maybe reluctant
to go down that path when they hear one
of the top authorities making those
statements and that's not fair to the
patients either when they are put in
that position and we have to remember
and in Canada the program was started
not because legislature said yeah you
know we should legalize this product it
was because the court said it's a
fundamental right and freedom to use it
as a medicine and they pushed it to the
Legislature's to create a program and so
you know we've evolved since then
thankfully but you can understand why
the the 80 years of prohibition have
left us with a dearth of research now
there's a lot of research in the last 10
or 20 years that is really starting to
ramp up and certainly the work of dr.
shulam predating that but if we don't
start looking at observational data
today we're gonna wait 10 years before
the doctors are happy with what's coming
out in the last 20 years in Canada and
and and North America there were
numerous studies done on cannabis but
96% of those were looking at the
negative effects of cannabis and this is
where it's changing now there's more
research being done looking at the
positive effects and that was really I
kind of turned and what the Medical
Association's look at our studies and so
that was really a challenge and one of
the roadblocks as well good point the
India but well you know these are all
great salient points for the medical
space just for the recs I'd in terms of
like mistakes or whatever you know I
think it's really important to look at
how quickly as a country we have done
this and it was it kind of had to be
done that way it had to be done so very
very quickly to make sure that it didn't
the path didn't deviate and so when you
do something like that you stand up this
industry that
or you know bring this industry into the
mainstream or into the light it's gonna
be there's gonna be lots of bumps and
bruises and and we're not gonna get it
right exactly we were joking like if the
we had stood up the right side of things
and everything went swimmingly well and
there was not a single problem I don't
know I would have assumed I was
unconscious in some sort of dream state
now there's no perfection I mean you're
still striving for that and one thing I
wanted to point out that Kari brought up
so Canadian Medical Association they did
come out and say that that they don't
actually want a medical system that they
wanted to get rid of it but I want to
put a little context to it and this is
an important lesson I think that Germany
can learn from I think what we did at
first so the government went to the
doctors to those Canadian Medical
Association they said we're gonna
consult with you on this program we're
thinking of having you do the medical
authorizations so they said great let's
have this conversation and apparently
the way I was told and speaking with
them is they said they woke up one day
and they were told that this is what's
happening and they said hey what
happened to all our consultation so
there's a lot of politics involved and
there's a lot of bitterness there and if
a lesson that could be learned is try
and involve the medical community right
from the start like we had to set up
this like alternative medical community
of selling directly to patients and
opening up separate clinics cuz because
doctors weren't prescribing so if
there's a lesson to be learned there
it's try and include the community and
try to work through the community rather
than try to avoid them because by
avoiding them you get other problems and
I remember going to conferences in 2013
when I started and our Minister of
Health Rona Ambrose she would say like
cannabis does not approve medicine
cannabis is not good for anything and
then I would be at a conference a
medical conference the next day amongst
like pharmaceutical companies and people
would walk might be like there and I
just hear you're not even a real
medicine what are you doing here I'm
like well I have a license to be here so
and that dad had the result as well that
all the Canadian pharmacies didn't get
on board right away that's is why we
have this vertical integration direct to
patient system now they're getting on
all right and full circle we do have
pharmacist on board the largest pharmacy
chain in Canada Shoppers Drug Mart is
also now on board so we expect a lot
more to come through and a key thing
that every year I come and it's a key
thing and I really want to touch on
again his education can't stress enough
everyone's so obsessed with like
marketing and promotion
that's not the right way to talk
cannabis doesn't need to be marketed it
doesn't need to be promoted it needs to
be educated on and I just started doing
I just did my first non-medical
education last week because now we have
retail stores and there's so many
similarities between recreational and
medical I think from an outside you
think there's a lot of differences but
still people are trying to find an
effective outcome they want to spend
money they're looking to instead of pain
and sleep management they're looking to
go to a concert or go to a movie or you
know something after a date whether it
goes good or bad maybe a different type
of variety to use but at the end of the
day there's a lot of similarities and I
think that's important and if we can
just quickly touch on education because
it's not I can't stress enough how
important that is it's helped us so much
when we figure it out and everyone here
I know
knows the value of education maybe if we
can start at the end with Andrew and and
what your thoughts are on education
he'll maybe have some advice and how
Germany can do it yeah I mean I can't
tell you how much we've learned just
watching the data grow that we've been
capturing over the last three years it's
it's you know things like how many
sativa is actually are high in Mersin
and cause drowsiness so you know sativa
indica doesn't mean anything right so we
hear that and we and yet people are
still talking in terms of sativa and
indica so we have to teach that there's
more than just the physical appearance
of the plant we have to teach that
there's more than just THC and CBD like
there's up to 450 chemical constituents
in every single plan and it's different
every time you grow it and every batch
is even if it's grown in the same
facility by the same people so there's a
lot that we have to understand in terms
chemical constituents there's a lot we
have to understand about personals and
anybody's endocannabinoid system which
is determined by genetics and them know
many other factors we have to understand
dosing much better you know we're going
to continue to learn as we go and and
you know a lot of Len Bias plug it's all
about data do do you feel like we need
to also be mindful that like the average
consumer isn't like a super science
person that's gonna be able to like
understand all that like to package it
in a more like digestible format yeah so
I you know I think you know what we do
is help to arm the people who are
creating the curriculums like you guys
and put them into the in the hands of
the patients and the doctors but
there's enough data out there now to
create curriculums that will be very
beneficial to doctors and patients so
it's up to you guys you know who or all
have that great education we're on that
background oh that was one of the
biggest issues when we started as again
we started when we started eleven years
ago there was very little information
out there and education was paramount
for our patients
there was a program they didn't know
anything about it people looked at
cannabis from a recreational point of
view of people getting stoned you'll
teach in cheong sort of scenario and
when we started to do the medical side
of it we were didn't have a lot of
education we really had to take that
from some of the original pioneers who
were working with patients through
compassion clubs so we really had to get
some knowledge from there get our
doctors on board start to train other
doctors but that was a real issue
because we didn't have the ammunition at
that point and it was really difficult
in many cases to get it to pass along to
the patient's but when a patient comes
to talk to us they have many many
questions and you can't just learn it
from reading they want to have a direct
conversation with their physician and
again we do training for pharmacists
which again we started several years ago
interesting enough when this program
came into effect in Canada originally
they had invited the pharmacy and
organizations to be part and parcel it
they declined to be part of the
organization at that point and it's very
interesting now that after all this time
has come through we're probably talking
Oh 15 years ago when that program came
about now they're coming back on board
make you see the benefits of it but in
the earlier stages if they would have
been included I think we might have seen
a lot different program than we do now
because this is where people are going
back to even when they talk to their
doctors they still have many questions
for their pharmacists and in many cases
they feel more comfortable talking to
the pharmacist than even their doctor
given some of the things that happen in
the past which helped us create this
program where people were getting kicked
out of their doctors offices for even
asking to be prescribed cannabis and has
changed dramatically since that time
that's right that's how it started for
sure people can't believe that someone
would be threatened to be kicked out if
they say I if I find out you're using
cannabis you're I won't even see you
anymore as a doctor that's people just
cannot understand that that's all what's
going on hold
that never happens here Steve some
thoughts oh my my orthopedic surgeon
actually said the exact same thing and
he is now something that is referring
patients to hello cannabis and that
transition happened over the course of
seven years so it does require quite a
lot of patience nope Wow all kinds of
patience so with respect to education
truly one of our mandates is of course
trying to relieve all of this
misinformation that's out there and
Andrew touched on one of my favorite
ones which is when you go into many of
the so-called great gray area which in
my opinion and the laws opinions is
essentially a black market area they
have this common statement like Oh
sativa is something that's more cerebral
that you want to smoke during the day
and an indica is something that is more
sedative and they want to smoke that at
night and the reality is is that I
they're a sativa is available that have
the polar opposite effect of what
they're what they're saying and we now
have the data that's able to do this so
our original goal was to be able to
actually educate the physician so that
way they were more comfortable when you
go to see a doctor and they say take
three of these pills every four hours
you don't question it I think 99% of
people just do it and physicians weren't
comfortable doing that at first so that
was what Terri was able to pave the way
for many other people like myself to
follow in I was fortunate enough as a
previous role and I as an investment
banker I knew a lot of physicians and I
suffered a tragic injury that uh
unfortunately rendered me as an opioid
addict I quit two months into a lifelong
prescription and I use medical cannabis
to do that so they saw firsthand how it
worked for me but this was completely
anecdotal we now have data and
thankfully because of because of Andrew
as well where we have all joined forces
combining data combined with the
pioneers combining with people that have
a very interesting and powerful origin
story and connections with physicians -
all combined forces in one giant circle
allowing ecommerce to step in to be able
to increase access and this is a very
large group effort where I truly believe
that the education needs to start with
physicians and once the physicians are
converted they will bring their patients
and and then everybody else will follow
if you are able to educate physicians I
think you will be able to streamline
this process and be able to relieve a
lot of the headaches that
we faced here right and and you know
what that's a hopefully something that
people here are taking back with them is
that it it does feel very competitive
but it's important that you collaborate
together you're trying to build an
industry together and sometimes it feels
a little weird that you think you're
giving away your secrets there's very
few secrets in this industry and at the
beginning are also worried about oh
they're gonna learn what I want to do
what you want to do is pretty much the
same thing everybody wants to do so the
faster you realize that you have more in
common start working together create an
industry and then you can worry about
competing now I want to just do before
there's I feel like there's some
questions here will you just do super
quick rapid-fire the future innovations
and technologies are excited but I know
there's two innovations and technologies
up here besides yourselves what other
innovations and technology are excited
about the future just quick bullets and
then we're gonna go to the audience for
some questions yeah I mean not to
continue to say this but anything that
that exactly allows these patients and
recreational consumers understand the
product better we have to get to the
level of where like alcohol and tea is
right now where you like you know the
the the the type and the amount that
works for you we need to get to that
level both from a medicinal standpoint
and from a rec standpoint but also in
general just innovation in the product
someone was mentioning from the audience
in the last panel about you know oils
and vape pens and edibles and and nano
emulsified beverages I think that's what
really excites me I think very quickly
those types of products you like are
going to eclipse flower
yeah and and you know especially
especially beverages we are socialized
to drink and be merry with our friends
and once you can do that in a way that
you know isn't so calorically
overwhelming you can you know you some
really cool stuff happens so Steve quick
with respect to innovations I'm very
much looking forward to regulated
standardized forms of different product
delivery systems we're starting to look
look at a nasal inhaler topicals that
actually penetrate through the epidermis
even receiving things with with elderly
patients and pediatric patients where
suppositories that bypass the liver are
being used and there are many diff
ways to administer this product and when
we look at the medical delivery systems
I think the innovative products that are
there are going to be able to help a lot
of people and avoid a lot of pain and
suffering that unfortunately has
ironically been induced by the
pharmaceutical industry that is using in
my opinion and I believe many others far
more harmful substances administers and
far more painful in that opiate ways and
suppositories although very popular in
hospice and palliative care not popular
parties so it's it's not happening at
the regulation or maybe not the parties
you go to right now I will mention that
club but anyways Terry okay I won't
quick innovation so you know some of the
innovations we're gonna see here you
know very simply you're gonna see a
separation of the medical market and the
recreational market the way the products
are marketed and way they're developed
are gonna be different you see the pills
the patches the suppository is on the
medical side and you'll see a lack of
connection to specific strains whereas
when we see them the recreational market
and we see it going ahead they're gonna
continue to work within the culture
talking about different strains that are
popular and more of the experience
you're gonna have and that's what we're
seeing now is is people looking and and
marketing towards experience is you're
gonna take this joint you're gonna go
enjoy a movie you're gonna do this
you're gonna enjoy that so I think
that's the area we're gonna see as we
push forward for rec and then Medical is
gonna fall right into the typical
medical products that you're used to
seeing on the shelves and I understand
you know in Europe you've already had
CBD here for a while that's gonna start
to happen in the in the TC side of
things where you'll have specific
products and then the names and the
culture will roll through on the
recreational good one Andrew and then
we're gonna take a few questions
so I think exactly right we're gonna
start to see real true personalized
medicine so we're gonna see formulated
full-spectrum products that will be in
whatever route of administration or
whatever recreational form and that will
be true personalized forms okay cool and
just a quick one to add different
cannabinoids and terpenoids seeing a lot
of devices like a vape and I've just
maybe terpenes there's a guy you should
go visit him over there
has it and there's all kinds of
different future technologies relating
to which cannabinoids and chirping will
do different things in research
questions from the audience all right
yes let's hear for the panel one time I
think we have time for one here maybe
two questions here we go all the things
to two questions hi guys it's sunny so
kana new frontier data I was just
wondering what is the physician patient
privacy model in Canada as regards
sharing you know the experience of a
patient tough one yeah I mean it's as
you would expect the highest level of
privacy regulation around so anything
that has to do with the medical record
has to be dealt with in absolute privacy
I don't know how else to answer it it's
it's about any other market it's it's
higher than we call it military-grade
yeah and and there's a challenge right
now where a lot of people are collecting
data and if you don't have the patient's
authority to do the data like in a
stream print they get the data from the
patient but some other people they
collect the data from the EMR and from
the doctors but the patient never
actually gave them access so there's
some interesting technology with using
AI
to answer questions and do that where no
one's actually collecting data it's all
very anonymous so that could be
something very interesting but we have
very high regulations and if you want to
quickly touch on it and yeah for Shopify
we you know we actually stood up a
Canadian hosted version of our product
there's actually really cool blog post
at our production engineering team put
out you can go check out but we also
plug into some of the major compliance
platforms in a completely anonymized way
so we just sort of like get a success or
failure a notification from whether or
not they're a patient and then that's
all the shop I even really sees from the
like seed to sale or like prescription
patient management tool what room time
for one more you got the last question
for us thanks a lot for taking my
question quick one several Canadian
producers own and operate their own
clinics and I'm just wondering what your
thoughts are on therefore the potential
conflict of interest well by law they're
not supposed to they have done it they
try and separate themselves it's a
little it is a little conflict of
interest in that if you own that clinic
obviously you want to direct them to
your clinic supply of products so as I
said it by law they're not supposed to
be doing that they found end arounds we
feel that the patient should have a much
wider variety and much wider choice that
they have and through our clinics we
work with all the with all the main LPS
as well and any patient can choose the
location or the LP that he wants to go
through and we help them with making
those choices as well but the clinic LP
owning a sone clinic you know is it's
difficult for the patients sometimes to
get a wide variety it's a very common
question we get I mean Guiness does
Guinness on their own bar that's a
common thing I get don't know Steve last
les Comet and then we got to go any less
comments absolutely absolutely clean
objectivity especially if you're
actually caring about a patient you need
to be able to direct them to exactly
what is in the best interest of the
patient while maintaining compliance if
you own an LP that clearly is a massive
conflict of interest and we very much
disagree with that model are you saying
that to the u.s. experience where
they're all vertically integrated right
so it's a different lens in Canada the
lens in Canada is Public Safety the lens
in the u.s. is commercial so when we're
around for more questions if you have
any other questions and hopefully we'll
back next year to talk more about the
fantastic let's hear once again for the
panel I'm sure you can accost them in
the hallway and they will be happy to
answer Terrell Smith or something or
ripe at lover boy that's a Canadian band
there you are everybody's working for
the weekend rush there's five of you
rush is a power trio all right let's uh
we're by the way this next panel is
going to be entirely in German so if you
don't speak German you can go back and
get a translator from the translation
booth and that will help you to
understand or you could just not