good afternoon we had planned to be on
for an hour but we have half an hour so
I would encourage all of you to read our
speakers BIOS on the app because the
wealth of knowledge and the years of
experience we have both from the crafts
perspective the regulatory perspective
but helping build industry in this new
legalized regime we are very blessed to
have these three people with us
I have beside me here Joel Podolski
Travis Lane and David Hereford all three
of them we have relied on at both grow
tech labs and at niche Canada the
National Institute for cannabis health
and education because one of the things
that I'm a very strong advocate for is
not only education but communications
that provides an opportunity to tie
government industry health professional
associations all into the mix so people
actually understand how we can get to a
place in Canada we were were fully
utilizing and realizing the benefits of
legalizing cannabis what we have now
with the craft industry I think from
somebody who is an outsider and has not
only been educated by these three and
other people in industry is the
realization that our present government
at all three levels is viewing the craft
industry a with a bit of hesitation but
also in some cases as a bit of a problem
versus what they should be viewing the
craft industry as is a solution a
solution to the issues that we see
around quality the issues around supply
and the issues around economic
development and job creation for our
province and for our country I don't
want to take up too much of your time
I'm first going to ask each one of the
panels to take a brief 1 minute
introduction to talk about some of the
things that they see happening with the
craft industry here in BC and Canada
Joel hi i'm joel porter ski co-founder
the craft can of association british
columbia a co-founder of cascading
agricultural cooperative association a
lot of the dynamics that i see going on
in the craft industry is a regulatory
environment that is very stifling to the
industry a lot of
miscommunication on all three levels of
government municipal land use bylaws and
you know we've been doing our best to
try and educate and I feel like having
conversation getting more people
involved in the conversation telling you
know their governments as well is part
of it I'm Travis Lane
I'm organic canvas grower and I've
applied for licenses with Health Canada
at this point I've been growing for
fifteen to twenty years which is pretty
much half of my life and not always as a
professional sometimes in a closet
sometimes in the one bedroom in my
one-bedroom apartment you know and more
recently on a more industrial scale and
you know with the ability to do some
data accumulation and that kind of stuff
I mean when we talk regulations for
small business people that are
bootstrapping it obviously there have
been added costs and added risks that
come from some of the regulations that
have been created on a federal scale
really the big hurdle that we've had to
jump when we've been looking to apply
for licensing with our small facilities
has been regional it's about getting
zoning making sure that there's water
and power making sure that the local
regional district is willing to accept
you and so now we've just gotten to the
point where we've jumped a lot of those
hurdles in BC the ALR decisions that
have been made in the past have really
held up a lot as well and so I think
we're gonna see the first waves of
micros but I think that you know small
business people that are bootstrapping
an operation cannot afford to wait for a
long long time to be licensed and so my
hope is that we see a proliferation of
these licenses at speed coming up and
that Health Canada can step up and start
to to pump them out a little quick more
quickly they have claimed to set service
standards for these kinds of things
recently and so hopefully we see that
come true but I can say that you know
from a perspective of the the growing
culture in British Columbia it's an
economic driver it produces a lot of
money for our economy more than forestry
you know and it's also something that
the province in the regional districts
haven't really embraced as that economic
driver so that they can encourage people
to get into the space and so whether
it's trying to stand in the way or
whether it's simply they don't
understand what we're finding is that
there's a certain amount a certain lack
of knowledge
standing in our way to allow this to
grow quickly and and we need it we need
it in this province now thanks hi
everybody my name is David Hereford a
pleasure to be here and look forward to
your your questions very sensitive to
the fact that Travis and Joel are the
growers on the panel so it's a pleasure
to be here with them my history is
really 20 25 years in government at all
different levels I started smoking
cannabis when I was in grade 9 and
working in various crown corporations
and so on designing government programs
and one of the the ones I got to design
was in help design was the 99 mm working
for mr. Kriens administration and and
does help design the medical marijuana
program that we have today also the
designated grower program and so on and
the real reason that that program has
stood the test of time a number of core
challenges is because we took a very
proactive approach and actually
consulted the experts before we
developed those regulations so I'm very
grateful to growers across the country
at that time mostly through compassion
clubs that helped design that program
that certainly has been missing in this
current age where the program has really
been designed almost to some degree in
spite of small producers as opposed to
with them so I think that there's a lot
that can still be done it requires a lot
more communication and education I've
also been a political activist through
my career almost recently I was national
policy chair for the Liberal Party
Canada not involved in that role anymore
and was it was proud that the leadership
that our leader took in terms of making
the commitment that he made in the last
election but I'm also here to say I
think the policy is failing on a number
of different levels edibles and various
other things a communication breakdown
but certainly not getting small growers
into the system I think is number one on
the list in terms of problems the
government is not achieving the policy
goals they establish the black market is
still alive and well they have not
prevented the establishment of war
corporate two conglomerates which was
something that they wanted to avoid and
they have not developed a micro
licensing system that can support a
small business so far only six I think
of determined have made it through the
process and only a 200 or 300 or so have
even tried to make the attempt when we
have twenty five thousand growers across
the country that are approved in the
medical system so look forward to your
questions and discussions about
solutions and to what some of those
challenges could be so thank you we'll
go to the floor for the next question
but I just wanted to have a the
panelists comment on we recognized some
of the challenges and the barriers that
have been created for craft growers I'm
sure many of you in the room are
familiar with micro cultivation
regulations and the processes and the
type of resources that it takes to get
into the regulated regime but I wanted
to talk with each panelist about giving
me your number one priority where we in
this room collectively and with the
opportunity we have before us for change
not only are we in the midst of a
federal election where votes count and
we're strong in numbers cannabis
industry definitely not only people who
are engaged in industry but people who
are other recreational medicinal users
but also here in the province of BC we
have UBC M coming up at the end of the
month where all of the municipal staff
elected officials and provincial leaders
gather to talk policy we at neish has a
non-profit for three years in a row and
partnership with Akers and others have
tried to present a workshop and have
been rejected because I really believe
that the myth and stereotypes are still
very strong article in The Globe and
Mail last week about how the federal
leaders don't even want to talk about
the cannabis file including the prime
minister who put legalization in the
forefront in the last campaign so for
each panelist if you could quickly give
me one thing that you think could
pivotally pivotally we move this dial if
we all collectively organized and
reached out and wrote letters and
knocked on doors to get our message out
there Joe
as real
hard to pick just one god we have 30
minutes buddy that wasn't my choice okay
so I would say from an administrative
standpoint the build first policy is
probably the biggest one I'd say that
policy alone without any other policy on
the board is enough to kill the industry
the requirement to build a hundred
percent of your infrastructure to Health
Canada's requirements which is a moving
target is really precludes a lot of
participation you can't walk into a room
with potential investors with nothing
more than an idea and expect to get any
kind of positive results and I find it
really hard to believe that the smart
people at Health Canada aren't aware of
that so for me that that would be the
number one and you know the
life-threatening disease then we can
deal with the quality of
life-threatening diseases afterwards
yeah I mean I think a focus on trying to
educate everyone from policymakers to
the public so when we when we look at
like if the government doesn't listen
then get the public to act right so like
I teach a course at commotions College
on Vancouver Island about just basic the
fundamentals of running a cannabis
business and how it's different than
running another business and the thing
is everything's amplified they've
amplified the risk they've amplified the
cost but the rest of it is still very
much just running a business and so if
we can show the both the economic
positive side of it and the fact that
the sky isn't falling and we can do this
to policymakers and we can do this to
staff and we can do it like I think
that's an opportunity we have now in the
early stages of legalization that we
have to focus on D stigmatizing what
we're doing and we do that through
somewhat traditional means by using
education and Lobby and all of these
things that already exist for other
industries yeah it's a little harder
because the stigma is there but it
always has been you know it used to be
that we just openly broke the law and so
now that's changing a little bit and
what we need to do is we need to show
people that this isn't something to be
afraid of that this isn't we accept much
higher risk activities in society
without batting an eye then and
thing that could possibly be associated
with cannabis and cannabis provides a
tremendous economic benefit and quite
likely health and wellness benefits as
well and so I think it's gonna take time
but it is about pounding that
educational gavel over and over and like
trying to talk to policymakers most of
them politicians are still human most of
them are listen to you right like most
of them if you approach them nicely
they'll still listen and it's not easy
and it's not going to move quickly and
there's not going to be a lot of quick
changes but we just have we have to do
it it's the only way to go forward yeah
I'd agree with what Travis said around
education I would I guess if I was
thinking of one thing to crack growers
is do everything you can to maintain
your independence really do everything
you can to maintain your independence
organized into collectives that have
your your interests at heart you know
we've been working on a BC a chronic
cannabis co-op over the last number of
months and we're getting close to
finishing that off and getting that
going but I think it has been empowering
to have people together who are in
common cause it is a David versus
Goliath struggle I think that the sector
is in right now and you really need to
organize into collectives to maximize
your political clout your purchasing
power and your marketing a clout as well
in terms of making sure when that day
comes that magical day in the future
when we have thousands of crop growers
being able to just continue doing what
they're doing today that you get a
premium price for your product and I
think that that's going to be the most
important thing for craft growers
maintain your independence organized
into collectives and then fight and
advocate for your interests you cannot
underestimate the institutional biases
that are against you the public health
system the police the department of
justice and of course now we have large
corporate conglomerates that are
interested in making sure that craft
growers don't get independent craft
growers don't get a piece of that market
so I think that would be my number one
thing to focus on I'd like to open up
the floor to questions as I said we have
a wealth of knowledge and expertise here
at the table both from a craft growing
perspective a regulatory
effective so I can take over the mic for
a long time but it's alright I'm
bringing the microphone over to them
right now let's see where to get it for
the panel right quick and it abbreviated
form I like that you guys are brief and
succinct thank you Robert korchek from
allergy consulting thank you guys for
being here today
awesome information so far I'm recently
just established myself as Aboriginal
descent recently received that so I'm
wondering what do you guys know about
the economic aspects of access to market
for Aboriginal kind of companies and
that aspect of it especially kind of
more interested as well from David's
opinion being there from the Liberal
Party well I can't speak for the Liberal
Party you know what I try but on the
indigenous side I think again I see a
lot of similarities frankly as we've
been traveling around the province
between craft growers and indigenous
communities they feel left out for a
number of different reasons but I think
they also have tremendous clout we've
seen some examples of that in British
Columbia and around the retail piece of
anchor Isle and in the couch and area so
and I think that also crop growers
indigenous communities see the plant in
a different way I think there's
certainly a lot of wellness pieces
there's a lot of you know spirituality
in terms of the place that it's grown
and so on and I think also First Nations
indigenous communities also have an
advantage around land use I think
there's plenty of partnership
opportunities I'd love to see craft
growers working more with indigenous
communities in BC the job creation
opportunities are significant I think
that the the mindset is very similar
it's a rural economic development
initiative like really nothing we've
seen in our generation you know we
talked about even just getting 900
growers in BC at 2100 square feet two
and a half full-time employees per eye
grow up that's 3300 jobs
direct jobs in rural communities across
BC in a year or two if we can get 900
growers and that's a small number and we
should really be making sure that
indigenous
growers are in that mix and as we engage
municipal governments we should be
thinking of indigenous communities as
governments themselves and there's
tremendous opportunities I think there
as well and we also see some movement at
the national level around taxation and
so on and so forth so I think it's
something to watch and I'm hopeful did
you want to add anything Travis to Joel
yeah again I can idle awesome actually
but a number of colleagues of mine that
are dealing with a number of nations
around the country their feedback has
been of course the government set up
this separate wing to deal exclusively
with indigenous applications and what
I've heard is that it's not going quite
as smoothly as anticipated and that
perhaps there's been a little bit of
misleading on the part of the government
of how how much they were gonna help
indigenous community steward and there's
been a lot of missing for a lot of
misunderstanding between band councils
and especially elders where band
councils are really focusing on the
development of expensive massive
infrastructure for production and I've
talked to band councils members and
elders from Manitoba from here and
elsewhere and the messages that I try to
keep giving them is retail is your best
foot in the door in the marketplace
because it doesn't require the capital
input immediately you have shops you
know already you just need to passband
councils to zone to allow cannabis sales
for medical purposes and so it can
generate revenue very quickly for the
band it can generate a few jobs and you
can develop relationships with craft
growers around the area because you can
simply assert your independence from the
government and but again the message
here is going to be unity because I've
also talked to bands talking about
competing with other bands making sure
the other pen doesn't get the market
first all this stuff and I feel like
unity is really really the key here and
really engaging the elders more on the
spiritual side of things to actually
kind of bring the energy more into
alignment
kind of can heal a little bit of the
schisms that I'm seeing creating some of
these political dynamics within the band
themselves any other questions from the
audience I have a question say someone
has been an underground you know craft
girl for a while and they won they don't
have a million dollars but they want to
get into it what can they do well I mean
it's kind of like starting a brewery a
lot of our craft brewing groups that
turned into businesses started doing it
in their closets and doing it in their
garages which is exactly where most of
us started growing it does like you have
to take the mentality of essentially
starting over you have to take the
mentality that you're gonna find
potentially a new location that you're
gonna raise the money to make your build
happen that you might have to take on
partners to do it right now
you can bootstrap something small like
it doesn't have to be a million and a
half dollars but you're not gonna get a
full canopy and a processor for you know
very cheap and so if you want to start
bootstrapping it and Health Canada's
made clear they accept this you can
start by building one small grow room in
one small dry room and taking a video of
those two rooms and applying for a
license from those two and they if you
get your license then it's a lot more
likely you're gonna be able to raise
money or borrow money in order to
complete the project
that's a good advice I would also add
you know consider a medical license as
well and it all starts to me you got to
go talk to your local municipality at
some point you gotta you know start that
discussion a regional district whatever
the case may be indigenous government
you need to go and start talking to them
because they're gonna be key to your
process no matter what yeah and like a
just to add to that a little bit is like
one of the biggest things that has
happened in consulting with people that
want to do that convert from a small
home grow to do it for a living is that
they need an architect they need to get
zoning they need to hire an electrical
like mechanical engineer they need to
like all its its assembling it from the
ground up is hard when everything has to
be the code and it's not what we've done
in the past and so it's like we build
the code but we don't invite everybody
in and they in the past and so you've
got to do that you get it's different
but you got to do it so make sure that
you get good construction people and
good trades people to work with that's
very important so my question is my
question is well my question is how many
actual micro grow licenses have been
given out in the province of British
Columbia or Canada period six across
Canada and how long has this I recall
like almost a year and a half ago when
Health Canada came out with a chart that
specified micro grow LPS and the hockey
rink
yeah the hockey rink is that is that
exactly when they started opening up to
this idea or because I'm a little
confused on that it seems to me a year
and a half so October 17th we were able
to apply for micro licensing but of
course that was you had to have a
certain amount of work done at that
point so not many people were able to
apply on October 17 2018 those that did
I think like there's a couple of them
eight month nine month turnaround times
for licensing from application to
receiving it but that was under the old
rules where you didn't have to build
before you submitted so now you've got
to have your bill done and you've got to
do your video evidence package before
you can submit your license and so if
we're waiting nine months from there
that means the build which used to be
part of your licensing wait now has to
be done ahead of time and so that
changes the timelines I think part of
the reason we haven't seen more licenses
issued is because there was no
understanding on a regional level of how
this was going to be zoned and so if I
go out as a business man and I'm told I
don't have a guarantee that they're
gonna zone my space and I don't have a
guarantee Health Canada's give me a
gonna give me a license what am I gonna
spend a whole bunch of money with all
that uncertainty and so we've seen a
significant delay and some fear involved
in people not wanting to make that
capital outlay at the start without
knowing they're gonna see returns for
sure right so hypothetically speaking if
you had a personal production license
you already got inspections done for
that license and you've been granted the
permission to grow a certain amount of
plants you could technically take that
and then use that as your platform to
procure a micro license is that correct
to a point yeah so I
Health Canada's also sort of changed
their tone on this they wouldn't they
didn't used to answer this question but
now they've made it pretty clear that
they want those old licenses to convert
over so if you build a compliant
facility around your Mme our space you
can even send your video evidence
package in with plants growing and
transfer those plants to your legal
license the problem is that a lot of the
compliance features that are required
from Health Canada inspectors and stuff
might not be how we did it in the old
days and so in order to retrofit around
your plants you're gonna have to
probably shut down for a little while
and it really comes down to a question
of cost if you're not building from
scratch and you've done a good job
building your facilities so it's like
waterproof walls like they want and all
of the electricals in behind the
paneling like they want and you can
perform a lot of these sanitation
protocols then you might be able to get
in for you know not such a big sum of
money and Health Canada now accepts that
it used to be a thing where they didn't
but they make it very clear that you
can't keep your MMAR or AC MPR ppl
license on the property that you're also
growing commercially without jumping
through more hoops than it would ever be
worth so you probably want to either
cancel or move your ppl once you get a
commercial license so if you go on to
the Health Canada website with all their
guidance documents you can find some of
the basics
there's the license application guide
there's the GP P guide the GP P guides
are most important for cultivators
you're gonna have to infer some things
they're not gonna tell you exactly what
to do but they're going to explain that
you have to have non-porous walls well
that means you've got to put up rfp or
PVC or some sort of paint that's
waterproof they're gonna explain some of
those operational things and then you
essentially have to extrapolate from
that and build they're not gonna tell
you if it's right or wrong until they
inspect you and they don't inspect you a
pre-license anymore they expect you
after the license so you know really
what it is is in my experience is
looking to other people that have been
approved and how they've done it and
then taking those practices and putting
it into play and and so you know you
just have a conversation with those of
us that have been around and we can
point in some of the right directions
but it's the government man nothing's
ever certain we don't know
yeah hey guys you mentioned reaching out
to regulators on all levels of
government is there a more effective
message to be bringing forward to them
I've done some reach out to myself I try
to stay away from the you know please
let us get into your municipality or
whatnot so just curious a few words on
that well I've been elected to political
office at the municipal level for two
terms I've been on the board of the
Fraser Health Authority I've been
political aid and activist by nature my
entire life not only raising your voice
raising your voice as a part of a
collective you know as the CEO of Gro
techlabs we're now taking previa lies
ation companies and supporting them to
get into the regulated market you know
so when I hear people say they're
hesitant to reach out to their municipal
provincial or federal elected people I
really believe that the only people
we're doing a disservice to is to our
cause and to ourselves I think having a
voice reaching out educating the
panelist identified three areas you know
education the economics of building out
and looking at the regulations as a
problem the only way we're going to
change that is a collective voice but
David can you touch a little bit on some
of the things that you learned as you
were traveling across the province with
the coop and some of the things that we
could do collectively yeah no thanks for
the question I think it really is again
organizing and collectives one of the
things that I talked earlier is about
the benefits of that is you really pull
your political clout and you organize
yourself in a transparent fashion and
you come up with policies and proposals
because certainly my experience at
Health Canada when we were bringing in
the medical rules the bureaucrats don't
have a clue on how cannabis works how
it's grown and so on so you really do
have to gift-wrap them the solutions and
you can you get those solutions from
going out and talking and talking to
people so I think that advocacy piece is
critical if you look at the history of
progress on Canada
in the country it's not coming from
officials it's coming from politicians
who are ready to take a risk or courts
who are going to force the politicians
to do the right thing thanks to the good
work of wonderful lawyers like John
Conroy and others who are here those are
really the only two ways we've ever got
progress on cannabis in Canada political
leadership or courts officials
well-meaning God loved them we can't
rely on them to make the changes so you
really need political action and then
you need to come up with some realistic
solutions that can work certainly
through our co-op process we've
published a number of recommendations
that we think easy things the government
can do the federal government could do
in an afternoon to make the system at
least a little bit more attractive to
growers and investors and certainly
we've got some positive feedback from
that and I think through our efforts
we're starting to see some improvements
in the system people are being processed
a bit more we're raising this issue with
elected officials certainly we published
a jobs report
I think the job numbers are something
that speak very loudly especially to
local officials who need a tax base and
when you can publish some numbers that
we did that shows about 3,000 direct
jobs in rural communities in the
province that has a lot of impact as
well I think that as a Canadian citizen
my measure of success and the production
of cannabis is having a safe product and
I am struggling to understand why as
crop producers we have reducing number
one a crop a quality product but number
two why is the government insisting that
we take on all this expensive
infrastructure an additional cost when
we all agree that safety testing should
be the measure really of of how of
whether there's a product out there that
is safe why then do they make us build
all this stuff and go to all this
additional expense what is the
justification for that I honestly I'm
struggling to understand that because I
do not see a purpose for it if we have a
good product and it passes all the tests
what is the issue why do I have to take
million dollar loan why is any of that
necessary yeah that's that's really one
of the big issues and to me what it
speaks to is the politicization of the
process we clearly have a double
standard of enforcement we have
regulations that have double standards
built into them to begin with and to me
that speaks directly to the
politicization of the process without
going deeper because we really could if
we wanted to yeah I mean my one-word
answer would be stigma I don't think
that the government understands what we
do this would be an agricultural pursuit
this would be something regulated under
egri instead the regulating it closer to
Pharma and so part of it is that they
focus so much on the processes which is
quality assurance and that they've put
these certain standards in there that
would be considered pharmaceutical grade
standards or you know you know we
probably treat plutonium with less care
than we treat our cannabis right now no
it's not right and as a cultivator like
do I think that that's a good idea no I
don't I mean I also think their testing
regime has this total yeast and mold
bacterial accounts that are useless
tests and have been shown over and over
and and so like what do we do we submit
papers to the government saying this is
wrong here's how they're doing in Alaska
here's what qPCR is here are these
things but right now we're in a mode
where this is brand-new and it's gonna
take us time and so my choice is a
grower is either state black market or
build a conforming facility and step
into the white market and like I've
chosen the latter but I would never tell
anybody to make that decision that's my
personal decision if people want to keep
operating in the black market I
encourage them to do so yeah and I would
add to the in addition to Travis's two
points I would add a third which is
advocate and change the rules and
congratulations to you Ellie in your
group and the companies for your
advocacy as well I think that again we
can't you know if you were designing a
program to fail this is what you would
design and I think that to the point
earlier about the question about six
like let's just stop for a second and
think of the number six
and just how pathetic that is six right
there's 25,000 across the country
growing under the medical program and I
know when we were bringing the medical
program in we had pressure around
infrastructure and we got to go inspect
and we got to go test and we got to tell
the cops where they're at we got to tell
the municipalities where they're at and
we said no way because no one's gonna
participate in the program and we were
able to do that and we've now had you
know was that two thousand 18 years of
medical growers producing cannabis for
people no one's died people keep
renewing their prescriptions doctors
continue to examine people and say Ellie
it's working for you keep on going so we
do we can't accept the premise of the
current regulations the way they're
presented it is a false choice it is the
way it is and I agree that people have
limited choices right now but we have to
fight to change it you can change it if
we collectively pool our political clout
and demand the changes because craft
producers have the product everybody
wants it's why people are not going into
the stores now our products not there
right the government's are feeling it
they're not making the money so just
keep on pushing organize yourself
maintain your independence and just keep
on fighting the way you've always been
fighting all these years thank you thank
you we're out of time
[Applause]