and the next panel is going to bring a
bunch of knowledge and most importantly
has a moderator whose name I should not
butcher and the moderator has worked for
over 20 years in the music industry
which transitioned into working cannabis
events and then he has joined hello
cannabis educational platform and in
2017 he met he started managing hello
cannabis --is goodbye opioid campaign a
very important campaign and please give
a warm welcome to mr. bin RIS pin hi
good afternoon everybody if you're
following along in your in your guides
you might notice there's a bit of a bit
of a change in in the schedule here
there was a transit issue for the soar
to of the physicians won't be here today
but my friend Bubba's gonna be here and
I assure you it was a transit issue and
there's no procrastination due to
cannabis hi Tamara how are ya so I have
the steam pleasure I also only found out
because of this that I was going to be
moderating this panel last night so if
you'll excuse me I can be referring to
my notes I have the extreme pleasure of
introducing my colleagues here at the
end I have my dear friend Bubba
Nicholson Bubba played an integral role
in bringing the Movember campaign yeah
we arrived where we familiar with
Movember yeah Bubba played an integral
role in the early success of the
Movember campaign in the u.s. in Canada
he is a legend in the networking
hospitality industry he is also the
newly appointed president of hello
cannabis so please put your hands
together for my friend Bubba next to
Bubba is dr. Alan Greenspan dr. Alan
Greenspan is a family physician with
special interest in his occupational
health or in occupational health he has
been instrumental in leveraging many key
partnerships with corporate clients to
maintain safe and productive workplaces
please put your hands together for dr.
Alan Greenspan next to dr. Grinspoon is
the founder and chairman of hello
cannabis medical education centers as
well as founder and president of ger
nurseries and labs a licensed producer
focus exclusively on medical genetic
cultivation and propagation I said that
right
put your hands together for Steven Furby
thank you so much so if without further
ado I'm just gonna hop right into the
question I read in the interview and the
questions if that's all right with you
it's gonna have to be Steven please tell
us about the Canadian Medical landscape
from the patient perspective hello
everybody thanks for your time I've been
a medical cannabis patient for about
seven years now and I did notice that
there was quite a lot of accessibility
problems in Canada I come from a world
where were there second we are the
second largest consumer of opioids and
I've personally seen it ravage a few
families including some of my own
members and I do believe that cannabis
has a massive potential to be able to
curb the opioid epidemic that's now
moving globally seven years ago I had
sustained a very traumatic injury that
had put me on the equivalent of six
milligrams of dilaudid every four hours
for those of you that aren't familiar
with dilaudid it is worth for every one
milligram of morphine dilaudid is sorry
for every five point five milligrams of
morphine is the equivalent of one
milligram of dilaudid
so to transfer that to recreational use
from what I've been told by physicians
as a recreational user would use two
milligrams of dilaudid to get high so
essentially I was taking enough to get
high three times every four hours
I had a three-month prescription and I
truly found that that was overkill and
many people were not able to get off
that type of addiction I was in a
privileged position to be able to do
that and I'd love to touch on that story
in a bit however with respect to the
medical the medical landscape in Canada
we did notice that there was not enough
education there was not enough
accessibility and there was not enough
physicians that were knowledgeable or
comfortable enough to be able to
prescribe cannabis it's still a
relatively unknown substance back seven
years ago there was less than 5% of
physicians prescribing as of last year I
believe there was nine and we are now I
believe not working linearly
but exponentially and starting to find
that we are almost at 20% of physicians
that are more comfortable prescribing so
as I I don't I certainly don't want to
take any aggressive credit for this but
I do strongly believe that educational
clinics and support networks like hello
cannabis and many other clinics that are
available and spreading and growing in
Canada will help these physicians get
educated and will be able to help them
provide better duty of care for their
patients and will ultimately allow for
greater access and dr. JZ had the
perfect segue into this as he was
stating that education is absolutely
pivotal in order to help distinguish
cannabis and to be able to help patients
get access to this and I truly believe
that cannabis should potentially be the
first step to pain medication as opposed
to an exit to medication to deal with
symptoms from opioid addiction which is
often the first step that physicians are
using to cope to treat from from the
doctor Grinspoon the same question but
maybe from from the physician
perspective my interest in cannabis
started when I realized that in my
hometown of Hamilton Ontario at least
one person died every day from opiates
in Vancouver British Columbia up to ten
people die every day from opiates and
the scary number is in the United States
I've heard numbers up to every three
weeks the same number of people die from
opiates that died in the 9/11 Twin Tower
disaster but up to 2,700 people every
three weeks 88 people a day so I knew we
had to do something about opiates the
other thing is our College of Physicians
and Surgeons have come up with
regulations and guidelines and in Berea
they did a study a good study
evidence-based study where they
determined 100 milligrams a day or Fein
or that equivalent is safe so in Ontario
they arbitrarily said if a hundred
milligrams a day is safe in British
Columbia the 90 milligrams will be safe
in Ontario so we have to get our
patients off opiates and
we need we need to use other natural
health products in cannabis is obviously
great opportunity but as a as a general
practitioner I'm a generalist I'm not a
specialist and I needed to rely on
educational clinics to educate my
patients and that's why I've looked -
hello cannabis - help me learn about
cannabis and help my patients learn
about cannabis amazing Bubba this one's
going to be for you pal from your unique
perspective why do you feel that
education is so important for patients
right now with what's happening with
with the stigma of cannabis what we're
finding out is that our patient age is
about 54 to 60 years old as our average
patient age coming into the clinics
right now and so there's a huge need for
information we're taking a look at a
generation of people that have grown up
through this cannabis prohibition who
have been told that cannabis is the
worst thing you could ever do and now
they're starting to turn around and as
we share this amazing information and
the right information educate people
we're having them turn around and say
well maybe I'd like to take a look at it
and in Canada we're in sort of a neat
spot right now as we as we start to look
at legalization there's a lot of
information being shared and it's our
job as well to take a look at that
information that's being shared on
Facebook or wherever it is and do the
research because there's a lot of false
information that's going on out there
right now as well and the problem is
that we're so quick to just press end or
Oh Ben's my friend and I love Ben he
always prints funny stuff so I'm just
gonna send it well we got to start
taking a look at those articles because
we're sending a lot of false information
out there and it's actually setting us
back the more we can talk about it the
more we can have conversation about it
we're just gonna find that more
physicians are getting into it I
recently just had a back surgery I was
on not as bad as Stephen but I was on
gabapentin 1200 milligrams of naproxen
hydromorphone cotan hydromorphone PMS
and
and another pill as well and I started
using the cannabis oils I got off of the
1,200 milligrams of naproxen almost
within two weeks and the hydromorphone
made me so dumb and fuzzy-headed I
started I started vaping a high CBD
cannabis at a low temperature for
breakthrough pain it took me off six
extra pills a day just by being able to
do that so it's having these
conversations everybody telling her
stories sharing their stories about
cannabis and really just opening up that
conversation it's that's what's gonna
help us right now and we're finding I
spoke to two physicians while I was
going through my surgeon is now on board
with us he's prescribing cannabis
he's using hello cannabis to educate his
patients now he's off toxins they're
actually starting a he just sent me this
yesterday they're starting a clinical
study on prescriptions in the orthopedic
settings on cannabis and treating
musculoskeletal
this is just from a conversation where
we started talking about cannabis
educating and now we're getting clinical
studies done right in our backyard it's
pretty amazing
yeah please put your hands together now
that was literally yesterday I cried a
little it was pretty big
I was also what add one more clinical
trial that we're doing actually do
research in the delivery of cannabis but
the reason that there hasn't been
tremendous clinical trials so far is
because and still is cannabis is illegal
and so it's hard to do large clinical
trials however there have been lots of
trials around the world particularly
here in Germany there's there's evidence
out of Australia in Israel we're
starting a clinical trial on using
cannabis for acute pain management
following surgery as well under the
Chief of Surgery at Saint Joseph's
Hospital in Hamilton so we're very
excited about that it's starting and it
will happen these trials are are
happening all around the world and it's
our job out there as the cannabis
advocates in us to start sharing that
information we don't we don't work at
hello cannabis and say we want to be the
only
Cannabis education clinic we want
everybody out there educating so this
conference in places like this are
amazing because we can start sharing
that information a study that happens in
Germany is equally as important in
Canada so we need to start sharing that
information and getting the good stuff
out there so that people can see the
difference Stephen why is education
important for patient access from your
perspective so I I'll touch on a very
personal story in to be candid this is
actually the first time that I've said
it in a public public setting it was a
rather humbling experience if you can
put all of these stereotypes together I
grew up as an investment banker I was a
chartered still am a chartered
investment manager I was a derivatives
trader and portfolio manager for RBC
Dominion securities candidly it's it's
the largest investment firm and in
Canada and was it was quite young at
that captain of the city championship
soccer team again you can my head didn't
fit through doors I was an avid climber
I was very good at one point and a for a
split second I was very very bad at it
and I fell 22 feet the injury I suffered
was called bilateral calcaneus fractures
in layman's terms I shattered my feet I
was by myself I was able to get carried
out i thankfully spent six months in a
wheelchair and 17 screws was was what
was required to put my feet together
that are still present to this day my
orthopedic surgeon who's actually
participating this clinical trial he's
the number one number one person on that
list I had stated that this is arguably
one of most painful surgeries that you
can endure it's essentially getting
nailed to the cross 17 times with metal
screws it's it was rather excruciating
so I came out of this and I touched on
this earlier where I was taking six
milligrams of dilaudid every single four
hours I was literally in a comatose I
had spent seven days complete hospital
bed I was able to get transition to my
home where I was more or less a
horizontal for 23 hours a day and
literally had to relearn how to time
queerly and learn to walk by by crawling
first
had I known that cannabis would have
been able to help offset the damage and
addiction that comes with opioids your
you would damn well bet that I would
have done this so I'm extremely grateful
that we are now working with the
orthopedic society to look at using
cannabis as a way to curb and
potentially marginally disrupt the
amount of opioids that are being
required for excruciating surgeries that
will cause a lot of chronic pain and
chronic arthritis PTSD one thing that
I'm very grateful for is I was in a very
privileged position I had a I was
working in a very lucrative industry I
had some savings my my friends were able
to build a wheelchair ramp for me I had
a I had a family being close and had
friends I were able to take care of me
and I'm not naive to that fact many
people that come out of these surgeries
are nowhere near as privileged as I am
and say I hung on by a thread I barely
actually out of this the vast majority
of people don't and I spent some time to
be able to volunteer at the fracture
clinic to try and be able to empower
people and tell them that they actually
can do this and to say that these people
are at rock-bottom is I think a valid
valid statement because I I myself felt
that I was there as well one thing that
that helped me get out of this is when
you were metabolizing a narcotic and
you're taking it every single four hours
at about the three-hour mark year of
course you're metabolizing a narcotic
and there was less of it in your system
so pain starts at the same time you were
also
you
oh it was about seven weeks into it so
nearly two months when I started
realizing that I was able to tolerate
however my cravings were getting larger
and larger so you as your weaning off
[Music]
some way some
cravings for the narcotic won by their
being to manage pain and the other to
manage the addiction and I recognize
that my dick starting become more
pronounced for the reasons why what I
couldn't wait for those four hours to be
over
I had a surgical wound that became
infected so I had a nurse that was
visiting me twice a day the dress had
and treated with silver nitrate another
wonderfully painful experience and I
realized that I could actually start
tolerating this pain so when I realized
that it was the addiction that was
taking over and not the pain manager I
quit cold turkey I'm sure you gathered I
I'm not a not a large large fella and I
dropped 15 pounds in four days I didn't
sleep for four days I'd like to say that
I don't suffer from any chronic mental
health issues rather grounded educated
individual and you completely lose your
mind you go into a state of complete
delirium the description that I could
give is eventually going completely
anemic which is something that happened
to be from blood loss as well so I'm
really without feeling it's hopelessness
essentially so this wound care
specialist was monitoring me and saw
that I was slipping into a dark hole
literally to the point of brink of death
and said you you need to eat you need to
sleep and I said I can't I would I would
was not physically capable of even
swallowing I could not hold water down
there so there was no chance of even
processing food so she suggested she's
like if you're not eating you're not
sleeping are you familiar with cannabis
and I said I'm a Dutch guy from
Vancouver but unfortunately we got we
got drug tested at the investment firm
and I was naive enough to think that I
was going to be a professional soccer
player one day so he didn't I I I didn't
I didn't use cannabis recreationally
anymore so she's like a dear friends and
I said probably probably 9 out of 10 so
I made a phone call and I'm sorry dr.
Greenspan I I know I know position it
would condone smoking cannabis I'm not
going to argue that you can't derive
medicinal benefits from smoking cannabis
but it's
not a healthy way of inducing this
medicine so anyways that is what I did I
called a friend and he came over with a
bong and some cannabis and I smoked and
next thing that happened is I slapped
and then I ate and then I smoked again
and I slapped and I ate and I repeated
that for about five days and four days
of absolute rock bottom hell was offset
by six days of blissful cannabis and
reading and videogames it was it was
quite a nice change in my life I was
very good at Skyrim by the way I killed
a lot of dragons so I came from a
position of privilege and I barely got
through this and the opioid epidemic is
is real I particularly in North America
it's rampant and we started this
campaign to be able to help educate
people and be able to help bringing more
physicians into this and now we're at a
point where we have orthopedic surgeons
that are looking at substituting the
narcotics like like dilaudid with
cannabis use so access is starting to
get there back when I needed to get a
prescription after the meeting this
nurse practitioner that said you should
get cannabis I had to literally find a
doctor I paid I wired four hundred and
fifty dollars Canadian to them and it
was a Skype conversation with the doctor
from BC the College of Physicians
extremely frown frowns upon this
extremely so it was a a quote unquote
shady deal this was a real doctor was a
real prescription and I still hold it to
this day but that's not access and I
would not have known about this if I did
not have a massive infection in my wound
and had a nurse that was educated on
cannabis and had seen her own anecdotal
evidence that it works so I that is
again why I would emphasize that access
is extremely important and the more that
we can educate physicians and the more
that we can talk about Ray's like this
and go beyond anecdotal evidence that
people like dr. Grinspoon season is back
door backyard and started actually being
able to get clinical trials we can make
a dramatic impact on arguably one of the
biggest epidemics that we are facing in
the medical world
right now so now thankfully in Canada
we've been marginally disrupting this by
educating more physicians and I think we
are at almost 20 percent of physicians
that are comfortable with this and if
they are now comfortable prescribing it
I we have not heard from one that is not
comfortable referring a patient to us to
be able to take on that educational
component and be that duty of care for
for their patient so access was very
difficult seven years ago in Canada and
I believe Germany is probably about
where we are at about three four five
years ago and that can change if you are
looking at people that have experience
in this with respect to education they
have the materials they have the
guidance we learned the hard way by
trying to figure out how patient flow in
traffic works and we've discovered a
bottle that that actually works and we
have seen now with over a thousand
patients in over 30 referring physicians
I think nine prescribing let alone the
the 19 surgeons I just signed up for
this clinical trial that we've made a
positive impact on that and that was the
genuine goal from day one and cannabis I
do not want to be melodramatic and say
cannabis saved my life but if you were
to ask me what the inflection point was
from my recovery
it was quitting alloys and then four
days later using cannabis to curb the
symptoms of quitting opioids and that's
how I'm able to stand here to this day
and still play competitive soccer and
live a life as opposed to being a
synthetic heroin addict so thank you
cannabis and thank you Germany
okay please please following Stephen is
a hard act to follow but in fact it's
not a smart thing to do I don't consider
myself a smart doctor in fact in fact
what do they call the dumbest kid in
your medical school class dr. who
exactly scary so but just some more
anecdotal evidence there's a dr. Lydia
Hatcher she's the head of the pain
clinic at McMaster University she has
somewhere between 500 and a thousand
patients on cannabis she's been able to
reduce her opiate juice by 67% and her
benzodiazepine by 43% further to dr.
jay-z's recommendations more than half
the people that have an accidental or
intentional overdose of opiates are on a
combination of an opiate plus a
benzodiazepine like valium lorazepam
clonazepam it's so important that we get
these people off drugs yet it's my
responsibility as a physician to provide
education to the patients when I
prescribe it and there's lots of you out
there who know a lot more than cannabis
about cannabis than I do so that's why I
turn to Stephen Stephen I want to
prescribe cannabis but I need your help
to educate the patients and to educate
me and that's what hello cannabis has
done for me and that's what
hello cannabis international will do for
everyone here too
[Music]
I'm gonna open this one up to the whole
panel I didn't I'm just curious to know
how would any of you approach a
physician who was a opposed to cannabis
to maybe open their minds I mean and
there's several ways to do it for me it
was just simple conversation with
positions whenever I am going to meet
them sort of feel them out and see how
they are feeling about cannabis the next
step is to just start throwing as much
anecdotal evidence as humanly possible
into the conversation well I have four
minutes in front of them and then from
that point it's hopefully being able to
get another physician like dr. Greenspan
to be able and go and have that
conversation and seal the deal and by
sharing resources and sharing physicians
that's how we're gonna keep building
this community and how we're going to
keep educating and I just really
everybody's been stressing it this week
and it's been amazing it's all about
education the more we talk the more we
stifle misinformation and the more we
get it out there we're gonna make it a
lot easy for all of ourselves maybe you
can talk to us and all of you are going
to open them to the panel but talk to us
about about how hello cannabis has had
an impact on accessibility in our area
and has impacted patients and physicians
in the medical space so I we've touched
on some of these numbers in previous
discussions that we've had today but we
have seen firsthand the impact just
within three hospitals and five medical
centers that we are in as soon as we are
able to get one physician to be able to
open up and start sending patients to us
typically a prescription ranges anywhere
from three to twelve months we've kept
it at three months so that way we were
able to keep on top of these patients
and be able to actually track how they
are doing and what titration methods
they are using and be able to as dr. JZ
said go go low and slow when those
patients come back and all that dr.
Greene's been touched on this I will say
firsthand that we were seeing a dramatic
dramatic positive impact we're seeing a
massive reduction in
in in painkillers we are now seeing
patients using this for insomnia this
was something that I suffered from back
when I was trading on Bay Street I would
not be able to sleep and I would just
use stare at your alarm clock I'm like
holy crap it's 3:00 a.m. I got to wake
up in two hours like this is nuts
and you still show up and you work and
you look like a heroin addict just from
just from insomnia so I was prescribed
something called zombie clone and my
family physician said that this is a
non-addictive safe in our safe
prescription for you it's going to be
far better for you then than any any
other sleep aid and I recently found out
from new evidence that had come out this
is going that was prescribed this 10
years ago is that you were not supposed
to use this this prescription for more
than a week and I had a six-month supply
of it using and they wanted me to use
this daily so when we keep talking about
misinformation these are things that
cannabis has been able to completely
replace my mother who's never been
intoxicated in her entire life he
suffers from hypertension and insomnia
and now it takes a one-to-one CBD THC
oil and quote-unquote she says I have
happy dreams that I've never slept so
well in my life now us getting into
these medical centers and meeting one
physician and being able to talk either
about my own personal story or to be
able to get an in through one of our
strategic partners we have an advisory
board with six physicians that love our
story believe in our story and I've seen
the evidence seeing the impact it's had
on their practice they open up the door
saw their physicians for us
unfortunately physicians aren't overly
open to talking to business and like
myself you do have to have an
introduction from another physician so
that that was kind of our our ticket in
to be able to start helping access and
getting this penetration of physicians
to start looking at this and in our own
backyard we have now seen a dramatic
increase in the amount of physicians
that are prescribing and the amount of
physicians that are sending us patients
for referrals our business has been
growing literally
exponentially and I'm Richard we're
having a time keeping up with the demand
of patients that are trying to get
either get off of opioids or looking at
natural health products to replace these
synthetic products that are in my
opinion absolutely decimating our
population so we our evidence is
unfortunately anecdotal I promise you
when we are here next year we will have
clinical trial evidence and we will be
able to actually show real figures as to
how many people we have been able to
help I promise you that the impact is
massive are we look we come from a city
of 600,000 people and I could say that
we have firsthand already had a material
impact there in less than one year
absolutely just to reinforce Stephens
statement in my old my old position I
did some PR work and for some
dispensaries when the dispensary model
went the way it did in Ontario I moved
into legal work but one of my duties
there was to manage their social media
and literally dozens and dozens of
messages would come in a week thanking
the company in question MMJ Canada it
was allowing access it was getting them
off of opioids it was getting them off
junk that was their their term is
getting them off even alcohol so Harlech
education is definitely key to harm
reduction and that's a good look for
everybody in cannabis everybody who's in
this industry this is something we
should all get behind from my
perspective that being said we're gonna
come to the question and answer portion
of the panel I believe we have any
questions
let's hear it again for the panel once
again fantastic anyone have any
questions
take your time I know you've probably
had an edible or - after lunch there we
go okay I should probably know this and
I will look at your website but can you
can you tell me a little bit more about
hello cannabis how you're funded
structured etc yeah I certainly don't
mind sharing the the business model
behind us as I was saying before in
order for me to get a cannabis
prescription I had to I had to pays a
wire transfer to a physician across
literally across the country and then be
connected via the a Skype broadcast
which was quite strange to me and in in
all of Canada we have we have access to
medication and no HIPPA free of charge I
believe that needs to be conducive with
cannabis as well and that was one of the
major reasons why we still have a
difficulty a difficult time with
accessibility so our services are
completely free we are funded in
financed by licensed producers many of
them are their business model is of
course to be able to help patients and
patients purchase cannabis from them so
as we are sourcing specific products
that we believe have the highest
efficacy for specific ailments and this
is data that we are mining as fast and
furiously as possible to be able to help
physicians like dr. Grinspoon find the
best product for the specific ailment of
each individual person I do believe that
that's a paramount licensed producers
compensate us for those referrals I do
believe that I was taking these for pill
these sorry six pills every single four
hours you metabolize narcotics
differently hourly daily and there are
so many variables that will change how
you metabolize in narcotic whether it's
sleep whether it's how much you've ate
so when people when you were
self-medicating with cannabis as jay-z
doctor jay-z touched on this again cod I
love saying that name it's great Oh dr.
jay-z touched on this as well and to go
low and slow but there are so many
different variables that can affect
how cannabis will metabolize and how it
will affect you psycho actively so
that's why I think having a company like
hello cannabis to be able to help those
people on that journey and be a resource
we have live chat immediately on our
website with patients have full
excessive access to be able to talk to
one of our educators we are all medical
cannabis users we all understand self
medication and I truly believe that you
will metabolize a narcotic differently
based on stress sleep and many many many
other variables so it does require
multiple touches so to provide those
services we get compensated through
licensed producers the company was
founded and self-funded so it was
bootstrapped and
grown literally from the ground up with
just say a few a few decent contacts my
black book of contacts and a cell phone
in the couch and that was that was a
couple years ago and now it's grown to a
hello cannabis international where we
are we're open and I've already started
providing some of our services in Europe
the clouds in the world as to just add
something to that you know when a
patient comes in to see me because they
can't sleep and I decide to prescribe a
form of valium let's say lorazepam to
help them sleep it's it's a controlled
substance I talked to them about the
risks and the benefits and then I
prescribed it I don't charge the patient
for that service it's part of the
Ontario health insurance plan it's free
they they have a number so if somebody
needs cannabis the same argument goes
it's a controlled substance I the risks
and the benefits and then I prescribe it
why should I charge them for cannabis
but I haven't charged them for valium so
the College frowns upon charging
patients for cannabis a lot of doctors
still do and they're subject to a
complaint they're in trouble
hello cannabis allows me to to make the
prescription send the patient to the
educational clinic that does a lot of
the work for me so so that I don't have
to spend the extra time myself I also
should tell you that I've been a doctor
for 40 more than 40 years
I had delivered babies for 35 years more
than 3,500 babies the nicest patients
I've ever met
are the cannabis patients they're
usually a bit older 55 60 they need
education they're the nicest patients
that I have and back to the back to the
original business model and what you
guys are saying is they'll pay $300 go
see a physician and then you're forced
to buy your cannabis through one conduit
and what we've realized is that
everybody's symptoms are different
everybody's ailments are different and
in Canada were so blessed to have so
much amazing medicine from now I think
as of this week 93 licensed producers
that it's actually unethical for us to
force somebody down one conduit and
that's why we started searching out for
these different relationships so that we
can go and find the absolute best
medicine for our patients and take care
of them if somebody doesn't like the
flavor of their CBD oil well we'll move
them over to someone like tilray who's
coming out with capsules we have that
ability and by hitting that touch point
following up holistically with those
patients at three months we have the
ability to say how's your titration
going how are you enjoying your medicine
are you finding that it's working for
you would you like us to switch your
prescription to another licensed
producer because we can do that for you
as well and by doing that we're giving
that extra attention it comes back to
education and those people are going out
and they're having that conversation and
when you have 60 year old ladies at
bridge club on Friday night talking
about what kind of CBD oils they're on
and what their what their next LP is
gonna be like that's that's what we're
seeing happen right now and it's amazing
it's unbelievable hello my name is
Benjamin magic and then have have to
thank for this wonderful wonderful
things you make and if it's possible to
find doctors and pharmacists here in
Germany that will to make this wonderful
thing for the people in Germany we will
sit together and talk together about it
it will be good saying it will be
wonderful let's make wonderful things I
thank you love that
you take me to hello
cannabis absolutely so I I'll I'll talk
a little bit about about the branding as
well a hello cannabis is clearly pretty
a pretty in your face with respect to
cannabis you know what we're about it
truly is a suffix for goodbye opioid so
the whole concept was goodbye opioids
hello cannabis however we didn't just
want a pigeon hold ourselves to only
being able to help opioid addiction we
know that it does help many many many
other ailments but uh yes hello cannabis
is here specifically to be able to help
people get off of opioids and now we're
finding many many many other elements
that this wonderful product is actually
helping with so thank you and we look
forward to hopefully being able to help
Germany and hopefully be able to educate
your physicians to be able to make sure
that you don't fall under the exact same
path that North America's fallen under
which is an opioid absolute epidemic
which is ravaging our countries right
now
well more oh so you guys are you said
your patients all fill out a survey so
you're gonna have more studies and
things how many places do you have right
now I forgot forgive me can you repeat
the comments do you have right now that
they're all filling out surveys and four
levels so you can thousand patients
through the sorry about a thousand
patients yeah so I we had we had gone
through beta testing for about eight
months to make sure that we are actually
our business model had worked and we
were able to sustain the growth that I
knew was going to become exponential we
had a grand opening at our first clinic
about four months ago
this has been about a 24 month project
that over the last year and a half has
finally kind of come to fruition we are
now adding between 20 and 40 patients
today we had just opened up our teleMed
services where we were able to go
nationally and because we had
limitations on advertising which Ben had
started it the goodbye opioids campaign
he's quite well connecting the music
industry we're now throwing events
almost on a bi-weekly basis and that is
conducive of hello cannabis and the the
word is spreading rapidly I would not be
surprised if by next
month we are adding 50 patients a day
the goal is 7,500 patients by the end of
the year I think we're gonna smash that
I should mention that that as a doctor
we do intakes we do measurable outcomes
we actually measure measure their pain
level 75 percent of patients are pain
there's anxiety post-traumatic stress
nausea etc but 75 percent of patients
are chronic pain
we have measurable outcomes we follow
them every three months we make sure
they're getting better and and that's
what hello cannabis does as well okay
I'm coming over there be easier if I had
a jet pack I could just float No someone
said one for next year maybe a
teleportation device hi Steven
you just mentioned that you planning to
go to Europe as well and open some
subsidiaries you have any idea or in
terms of time when you are trying to
approach Germany last week thank you
very much we've already been approached
by four countries so far even just at
this at this event I do believe that we
have the supply the business model and
sustainability to be able to actually
bring physicians out and be able to have
speakers to be able to get them out at
conventions to be able to get them to
start speaking one-on-one the only thing
that would probably slow us down is the
language barrier unfortunately we are we
are a monolingual polyglots like most of
Europe it's rather embarrassing but we
do have physicians that I think are
extremely reputable charismatic and are
well be able to speak at a very high
level to other physicians to educate
them in Europe it looks like Lithuania
Denmark and Germany are going to be our
first stops
any other questions I'm looking
fantastic I don't think anyone has any
more questions you guys want to make a
few closing remarks I personally like I
get that mature I can speak on behalf
the whole panel but I just like to thank
ICBC for having us all out it's really
important that we all got to get
together and build our community and
share information and I'd like you put
your hands together for these this group
right here thank you Alex
all right give it up you guys Canadian
positions this is a big thing a lot of
analogy in German one more time
thanks you guys thanks you guys so much
[Music]