you know it's about two years ago that
everybody was talking about the big CPG
companies entering the space and they're
going through Canada and they figure out
how to get in the United States and it
was really less than a year ago that one
of the Canadian companies bought one of
the larger or didn't buy they tied up
one of the larger American companies and
now the M&amp;A environment is totally
flipped 180 we're not gonna probably be
talking about good stuff in M&amp;A it's
more of the nightmares but I'm really
happy to have with me today on the panel
some of these are last-minute if you're
looking in your book that is not Kim
Rivers it's Emily paksy of poseidon here
in San Francisco
Eric Kaufman of Dhamma financial he's
based out of Los Angeles
Katie young from at she's the managing
partner at ad astra law firm here in San
Francisco and Brent Johnson from Hoban
law firm in Denver and I'm gonna let
everybody just briefly share their own
background and then we'll get started
and we'll start with you Emily Thank You
Ellen everybody Ellen Brock Steen was
somebody that when we first got into the
space was kind of like a rock star we
used to listen to his podcast every week
yeah anyway he was it was it's neat to
be still here with him seven years later
almost so anyway my name is Emily paksy
a co-founder managing partner Poseidon
we have two investment funds dedicated
to the cannabis industry we launched our
first fund in January of 2014 alongside
the opening of the Colorado adult use
market and it's been an incredible
experience from that point forward we've
invested in the US Canada Europe Mexico
and Colombia and we launched our second
fund in September of 2018 that fund is
very focused on just Series A or later
stage private companies and it was kind
of where we noticed a gap in the funding
space when everyone was to Alan's point
earlier just kind of focusing on this RT
o IPO process in in the MS o category
and so we always have found that we do
really well when we place investments
where the crowds aren't running so
that's our second fund ir kaufman chief
revenue officer of dama financial by way
of background dhamma provides the critic
financial infrastructure that the
industry needs to be able to operate
just like it were a non cannabis related
business to of co-founders come from
banking and payments backgrounds took to
companies public in that space but the
important thing to note is that one of
the fundamental value propositions of
both of those companies was moving a
cash based economy to a banked and
digital economy and that's all we're
doing here and so what we set out to do
was provide them a solution to the most
pressing need which was a bank account
which we've done and now we've continued
to both on a whole suite of products and
services including interest bearing
account escrow account bill pay by
cheque ACH or wire armored car cash
process pickup and processing merchant
processing we're powering the back end
of Hilux exchange which is a cannabis
commodities trading platform and
continue to add on products and services
so excited to be here thank you hi
everyone so excited to be here my name
is Katie young I am the co-founder and
now Managing Partner of ad astra law
group in San Francisco we are fighters
not lovers
we handle business employment real
estate and IP litigation for cannabis
businesses if you have to hire me you're
having a bad time so I'm here to talk to
you today about what I see from the
civil litigator angle and can tell you
some real horror stories about failed
M&amp;A transactions and you know what to
look out for so that you don't have to
hire me ever I am also the president of
the International cannabis Bar
Association for the attorneys in the
room camber org we are the only Bar
Association that supports attorneys
servicing the business needs of cannabis
businesses again Katie young a task for
Law Group thank you good morning I'm
super excited to be here and all my
esteemed panelists great to be amongst
experts in the field I'm Brent Johnson
CEO hope and Law Group we are the
leading global law firm 100% committed
to cannabis we have about 50 attorneys
headquartered in Denver we cover 28
states we have a handful of attorneys in
Latin America we're in Israel and soon
to be in Europe as well we cover
basically anything a business needs from
from a start-up to M&amp;A standpoint or
financing we do corporate
securities mergers acquisitions private
equity venture capital we do fund
formation intellectual property real
estate employment litigation tax and I'm
sure I'm forgetting a few but anything
you might need from start to finish we
got that covered
personally i'ma although I'm a lawyer I
can I have a finance background as well
I started my career in Silicon Valley 20
years ago doing startup or venture
capital financings fun formation mergers
acquisitions securities came back to
Denver in 2003 worked for a large law
firm there was associate general counsel
Quiznos during their big growth days we
we exited Quiznos that one and a half
billion dollars it was private equity
exit to JPMorgan left there ran a couple
startups had those exits I ran a 65
million dollar private equity fund for
about three years
did we slowed off that portfolio then it
came to the candidate space because you
know I came in as an investor because
there's tons of opportunity and then I
ran into Bob Hoeven and he sucked me
into hope and Law Group
but it's great we've grown the firm and
we've more than doubled over two years
and it's great to be part of a really
one of the leading global law firms
that's 100% committed to cannabis great
to be here thank you him too in him too
yeah and his well we're about 50 50
percent candidate I'm 50 percent
marijuana 50 percent help you know I
want to start with you Emily cuz I know
you have the right perspective here
about the before and the after but how
have things been changing from your
perspective when it comes to M&amp;A so
we've seen a couple this whole industry
has been going through a few cycles and
it really depends on a couple of things
it's been a catalyst driven industry for
sure and the way that capital flows on
the back end of a catalyst is really
it's really interesting to observe and
it's important to consider the first
wave of M&amp;A that we were seeing really
take place last year or was it yeah
about last year we were seeing MSOs
purchasing product companies was a big
one I would say at that time capital was
flowing very well into that space
because people perceived it to be liquid
space and that there is a premium for
liquidity a lot of the time in this
especially when you're talking about
people who are thinking about how do I
maximize a return in a short period of
time
so we saw some of the acquisitions going
on with some of those product companies
that I would consider to be a pretty
frothy valuations pretty high multiples
traditionally speaking branded products
don't command a very high multiple but
in these instances it was kind of a land
grab and people were doing it and it was
driving stock prices up it was it was an
opportunity to really create more
attention around the companies and so
that was really driving it and then what
we saw was what I'm kind of we call it
kind of the Darwin phase or The
Reckoning where people are starting to
actually pay attention to business
fundamentals if you can imagine that I'm
so thinking about things like revenue
growth of Revenue eBay da all of these
factors that really indicate the health
of a business not just press piece at
that point we started to see more
scrutiny about what people were paying
for these companies and the way that
these mergers were occurring or these
acquisitions were occurring and so now
it's a different time where we're seeing
the multiples come way way down we're
seeing mergers starting to happen
because it's basically too many people
trying to do the same thing in the same
market and so a lot of people are trying
to think about how do we go through a
one plus one equals three scenario where
we can come together consolidate and
streamline our operations and then drive
revenue growth more in an exponential
way rather than just incremental bumps
so I would say that we moved from a
point of exuberance where it was driving
a lot of attention driving a lot of
excitement to now it's almost like a
survival part of the M&amp;A space and it is
a critical piece to it one thing we're
watching for is that let's face it in
every maturation of a of an industry not
everybody's gonna make it failures of
startups are astronomical in every
single sector that you look at
historically speaking so some companies
are not going to make it through this
time and I'm a little bit worried that
we're kind of pushing things together
without contemplating the true upside or
a creative value of that just to keep
some of these companies alive and I
think we just have to go through the
painful process if some of them can't
make it and I don't want to see the M&amp;A
process just kind of carrying dead
weight through into the next cycle
so Eric you talked to people all over
the country what is your take on what's
going on in M&amp;A right now I echo the
same sentiment I think it's not just the
exuberance but the irrational exuberance
has kind of dried up now right I mean
people were we called it dumb money and
while we're not directly involved in the
M&amp;A I think we're a little bit ahead of
the curve and seeing what's coming down
the pike because we're banking the
industry so we see when funds go up or
down or who's being paid or isn't being
paid so we get to see some of these
trends before they necessarily rear
their head to the to the masses so I
also think not just on the investment
side but you saw a lot of businesses get
out over their skis we were talking
about it before I'm a dispensary I'm
doing great I'm making money hand over
fist I'm really tired of dealing with a
distributor or something else you know
I'm gonna get into distribution so you
get a distribution license you get into
distribution without realizing that it's
a fundamentally different business and
you don't hire or bring on anybody
that's got experience in distribution
and then that distribution company
actually sinks the Golden Goose which
was the dispensary so people kind of
trying to get into every vertical not
fully appreciating that they are very
different businesses okay I'm gonna come
right back to you but first break can
you talk about how things have changed
from your perspective the deals that you
you've seen at home and in terms of
amount of cash going in the deals or
anything like that that would have
changed over the last year or two
sure just uh just a couple general
trends that we've seen if you look at
the number of deals that happened twenty
eighteen over twenty nineteen I there
was a roughly about 250 deals M&amp;A deals
that were closed in 2018 that's up to
about 300 in 2019 interesting enough
cultivation retail accounted for about
50% of those deals which actually kind
of makes sense because those are the
areas of the market that are getting
most affected by lack of capital and
regulatory and uncertainty and so those
are those are kind of the bargain
companies right now from another key
point is that probably bout two-thirds
of the deals that are getting done are
getting done by public companies that
are acquiring companies as opposed to
private deals but we focused primarily
on private deals and we're seeing
definitely the deals are getting
challenging
evaluations are getting challenging
we're seeing a lot of companies that
just they weren't set up correctly they
didn't have adequate capital and so
they're effectively they're distressed
and so they're not in the best
bargaining position you know deal size
you know we seen an increase in deal
size you know probably our average deal
size is probably you know probably two
years ago it was in the you know the
five to fifteen million dollar range now
we're seeing them in anywhere from
probably the ten to thirty thirty five
million dollar range
so definitely an increase in deal size
but there's everything seems to be on
pause q4 were definitely slowed I think
everyone is just trying to figure out
what's going on and then I do think that
twenty twenty at some point in time will
see increased M&amp;A M&amp;A activity last
point that I'll make is with the
legality of hemp now we're definitely
seeing more activity on the hemp side in
terms of you know folks buying up
cultivation centers to grow hemp
farmland
excetera in that Katie you already
warned us that you have nothing but bad
news to share a bit can you tell us kind
of you know how much your business is
picking up from failed M&amp;A I guess it's
really sick business development you
guys so you know where is Eric's on the
front end and seeing how the trouble
brewing early on I am on the way back
end dealing with let's say even a very
well formulated M&amp;A transaction where
you know some months later a year later
it needs to be unwound because it's now
same reasons we've heard here right that
they didn't look into it well enough I
see a lot of fights amongst just
personality disputes amongst the owners
you know these are the sort of like soft
things that can't be measured by for
instance you know the lawyer running the
numbers right that's totally different
so my business is unfortunately quite
busy and I was just telling these guys
in the greenroom I'm having trouble
keeping up with the demand which is
really sad and you know for a lot of
these companies you know they do kind of
just need to go away but instead of
doing so they're you know the distressed
asset trying to find someone to come
home you know absorb them and pick them
up and make it work and you know
[Music]
tactics at the front lack of
understanding of how how much the tax
burden from 280e is going to affect you
all across the board there's I mean I've
seen all the different reasons and and
if people are losing their dreams
they're losing their hard work if they
hire the wrong lawyer and they don't
negotiate well enough or they don't
understand the transaction they end up
really surprised later and that's that's
not a reason to undo a contract but that
doesn't mean people don't try Emily if
we had been sitting here a year ago we
probably would have been talking about
all the out-of-state operators publicly
traded especially that we're looking to
buy California companies and I'm sure
there's not you're here in the market
you know what's going on there but
what's your outlook for the exit
strategy for I'm sure some of the people
in the room here in terms of that exit
strategy in terms of exiting through an
acquisition by them so you know I think
that that's still an opportunity that
comes down the line I think California
has got a ways to go to get sorted it's
really hard to be an operator here and I
think egregiously so I think many of the
people in this market have been in it
longer than anybody in the industry has
been in it because of the nature of how
long we've had regulations around
cannabis in California now they looked
at these businesses looked very
different once upon a time but it's it's
been so incredibly difficult and the
taxes are so incredibly challenging and
and then you had all these resources
pushing people into the illicit market
which is basically the biggest
competitor for a regulated business and
that's it's just unfortunate however I
do think there are good operators here
and I think the operators here actually
have become the smartest and the leanest
and they know how to compete in one of
the most competitive and longest-running
cannabis markets in the world and so
therefore I think that once California
gets sorted out there are going to be
incredibly attractive business
opportunities here and I think an MSO
should constantly be keeping an eye on
this market because who would not want
to have a toehold in the cradle of the
Emerald triangle or the cradle of the
breadbasket and the in the wine basket
and all of the wonderful things we have
here in California including the heart
of cannabis and so I think that I do
think that's coming
I think it's going to take a little bit
more time that mess those are definitely
focusing on EBIT positive businesses and
rightfully so because they've got enough
on their plate and these limited license
markets where many of them are focused
but I do think that when they can look
to these California businesses they're
going to see some of the most attractive
businesses in the entire world that I
would also say that some of the MSOs are
finding talent from some of these
California businesses because of the
challenges they face and operating if
you can take that into basically and
I'll go up oligopoly market limited
licenses limited license yeah yeah I try
to mix it up but they I mean then you
can really you can make it rain because
you knew what it was like to compete
against 750 illegal stores in this in
the Los Angeles market and still make
money doing it one of my favorite tweets
this year was somebody was like how did
we take something that inherently made
money and we managed all start losing
money doing it selling cannabis people
so I feel like there's something to that
but so I'm still very optimistic I mean
we when we formed our fund we did not
form it in Colorado which was the
popular concept at the time because
Colorado is where the legal don't market
was we formed it in California because
to me that California still is the
future of this it's the history and the
future of this industry so that is
optimistic what you're saying is keep
your nose to the grindstone the cycle
will turn and you'll be able to do your
deal in the future and if not just go
work for one of these guys and move out
- I don't know Virginia or wherever it
sounds okay focus focus yeah I'd have to
be an optimist to this industry for this
long okay so you might just say yeah go
ahead because I think it's unfortunately
we're having a very painful right sizing
of the market and necessary evil painful
nonetheless but anybody that's still in
this space is incredibly bright you
can't figure out how to be here and
still be here and not be incredibly
savvy and smart about your business
because it is incredibly difficult so I
think that's why those msl's are picking
off people and bringing them on board
and I will just say from a positive
outlook we're seeing and improve
in applicants for accounts meaning we
have a very thorough due diligence
process when we onboard somebody the
businesses are better structured the
paperwork's more in order the processes
going faster and faster so I think
there's been and and and you see a month
on month the improvement so I think
businesses are getting better at the
outset than they were you know you're
catching them and they probably started
several years ago but now we are seeing
an improvement which is a positive
change so things is that in California
or is that across the country you're
you're I like to think is each state of
each state as its own country right
because unfortunately in my experience
we haven't seen States learn best
practices from other states necessarily
they kind of go do it on their own
unfortunately so if you go into Michigan
there's a there's a big learning curve
and some of that's natural right it's a
new market they're just opening their
businesses they don't necessarily these
from our perspective appreciate how
difficult banking is going to be oh it's
legal in Michigan I could get a bank
account maybe maybe not so you kind of
see a pretty steep learning curve but
definitively in California we're seeing
an improvement and then so to avoid
having to see Katie what are you
supposed what are you advising your
clients to do what are some of the smart
things to do on the front end
well one comment on on the previous
topic the you know it used to be a
couple years ago if you just had assets
you get to attract capital and maybe
even have an early exit to get some
licenses you had some real estate those
days are over you have to actually have
a business fundamentals matter you have
to have a strong management team you
have to know how to run your business
efficiently how to use capital
efficiently so it you actually have to
it's like a startup company 101 right I
mean they actually you know have all the
fundamentals that you need to actually
run a business you know from things
things to avoid I mean there's things
that I've seen that are problematic is
everyone wants to get a deal done by
tomorrow and they don't spend time on
diligence they don't understand the
management team they don't do all the
kinds of the background stuff you know
from a diligent standpoint and I can go
a lot of details but a lot of companies
just don't have all their ducks in a row
I mean your ownership structure do you
have documentation for everybody that
actually owns a piece of your business
we see it all the time where we go to do
a deal well it turns out that somebody
put a you know hundred K in two years
ago but they never got it they never had
a contract they don't know the terms
we've had issues come up where you know
they they say well I I want five percent
that was supposed to be two years ago
well now more money's come in so five
percent is now two percent but they
still want five percent and there's no
documentation we have issues where they
haven't done their securities filings we
have issues where they don't have
contracts with their employees we have
issues where they don't have documented
supplier contracts or distribution
contracts so across the board we have
issues where they haven't properly done
renewals so I guess long story short you
know get good counsel get good advisors
get everything paper and get every audio
ducks in row because not only will that
keep you out of trouble but that also is
going to help you sell your company for
a higher value do you have anything to
add to that Katie to avoid seeing you
yes all those things that you listed are
a really great way to end up hiring me
it's very sad so I see a lot of what I
call producers situations and back to
the story about the producers you know
those folks who you know were promised
5% and it wasn't papered a couple years
ago and now all of a sudden they heard
there's a big murder coming up and they
think they're gonna get paid out and
they come out with their hand out and
there's been a hundred and twenty
percent of the interest pledged to
people yes that is going to cause lots
of problems it's probably going to tank
your intended murderer acquisition and
you know disclosing what's going on with
your company is the best idea even if it
takes your intended transaction because
if you don't say that oh by the way this
guy out here the news saying that I
promised him 10% a few years ago don't
mind him put the risk on the acquirer
your co party to contract let them know
what's going on the good the bad the
ugly all of it
let them make the decision and let them
walk away it's better than getting sued
later don't you think
Emily you were involved with a special
purpose acquisition corporation in tech
that bought MJ freeway and went public
we've seen a few other of these facts
and I'm just wondering if you think this
is a positive for the industry and will
these be ways to consolidation and in
retail but on the ancillary side which
is where they're gonna be limited the
ones in the US is this a positive in
your mind or negative so I it's
interesting how we went from this rush
to the RTOS and now I feel like it's
raining spax
having participated in really one of the
very first facts in the industry I
thought it was a very very good idea and
for the following reasons
it was allowing ancillary companies to
gain access to the capital markets in a
way that could create momentum behind an
ancillary company and push it to the
next level at that point there was only
really the OTC markets available in the
US so this was like a real opportunity
to get on the Nasdaq and that creates a
whole new access point in terms of
analysts coverage in terms of the and
institutional involvement all of these
things that can make for a really
positive result i I know now it seems as
though you can't swing a stick without
hitting us back and in the US and it's
it's great in many ways because again it
could create some velocity around
capital flows within the United States
towards these ancillary businesses which
I've we've been a big fan of ancillary
investing since the beginning of our
fund in fact that's how we started
because we weren't sure how investors
would respond to plant touching
investing so we started with a lot of
tech and agriculture tech solutions to
try to improve the efficiency of grow so
I do see a place for it I have seen that
it can struggle to find the right
opportunity to invest and a lot of the
ancillary companies like in our
portfolio we're grooming them we're
waiting for them to be able to actually
just IPO just do a real like direct IPO
either a direct listing or an IPO
process on
Nasdaq or the New York Stock Exchange
we're patient capital so we're willing
to wait a few years for that to happen
but if a company is looking to go like
I've seen a couple of tech plays like
I'm tech is a perfect example of this
which then became Kern or a Corona which
was the seed of that I would say was MJ
freeway and now they're looking to
acquire other tech companies to kind of
create this tech consolidated approach
suite of products for the industry I
could see how that works because when it
comes to M&amp;A if you're a public company
you have different currencies to play
with and in other words you have stock
that you can really use to kind of drive
the transaction it doesn't have to just
be cash or it's not just private stock
transaction and so you have a little bit
more in terms of the heft of the
currency available and you can also
probably access capital more quickly if
you need to do a raise to buy something
out so there's certain benefits to it I
wouldn't say it's the Holy Grail but I
think it was a very in knowing the guys
that put together that first back I got
to understand where they were going with
it and I thought it was a very smart way
to approach a capital constrained
industry and to try to create more
access points one thing that makes me
crazy about this industry is that
because of the way the regulations are
like we can only accept accredited
investors into our funds or or even
higher than that and I think that
democratization of access to investing
into high-growth industries is important
and I think that having it listed on
these exchanges like the Nasdaq where
the reporting requirements are more
strict and I feel like it provides a
little bit more safety around those
investment opportunities for
non-accredited investors to be able to
participate in an industry like this
Eric I think you work mainly with with
plant touching companies but do you have
a view on the ancillary space an M&amp;A
that might be going on there now we're
in the future yeah we'll work with
anybody whether it's a cultivator
distributor or manufacturer retail or
home delivery a jar manufacturer that
sells a portion of their jars to the
cannabis industry we're actually seeing
a lot of those ancillary businesses that
a portion of their business is cannabis
related because they received the check
from a cannabis company put it in their
be of a account and the guy
corporate accounts shut down so if
they're going to have a cannabis part of
their business they're opening up
separate accounts and I am so we're
seeing a lot of that and I think on the
specifically on the M&amp;A side what we're
seeing is just and this is just
anecdotally that people are moving away
from the quote unquote you know sexier
side of the business or the the consumer
facing side of the business and are
looking more at the infrastructure side
of the business because that's really
what's missing you know distribution
financial whatever it may be it's the
infrastructure to support the industry
that really needs to be there and then
you know as companies do do these call
them roll ups or consolidations I do
think people are getting a little more
diligent in defining what is a fit for
their business it's very easy to get
style drift and get excited and buy
something because you think it's going
to work and then you realize wow that
that's not really our business it
sounded it or look good and you can
easily convince yourself that it's part
of your core business and I think people
are taking a deep breath and stepping
back and saying okay does this really
make sense Brent separate from cannabis
in the hip side it's that only a
down-cycle like we're seeing cannabis
when it comes to M&amp;A because of the
federal uncertainty or is there anything
specific to him right now that you all
are seeing on the hem side of it you
were we see a huge opportunity on the
hemp side and I assume everybody in here
knows knows the difference on the
interesting thing about hemp it's now
fully legal at the federal level and it
arguably has 50,000 industrial uses so
more than just hemp derive CBD or CBD
related products but there are truly
many other you know plastic bottles and
batteries and car doors and houses and
and so we're we're definitely all in on
hemp and we're making sure our clients
understand that there's huge opportunity
there you know marijuana was always
going to be there but it's you know it's
got its medical uses people use it to
have a good time but it's all it's all
just gonna be that you know hemp huge
and we're definitely seeing people want
to grow more hemp more states are
adopting their plans under the the new
USDA regulations and so our business
probably two or three years ago is
the 70 75 % marijuana and maybe 20 25 %
hemp now it's half and half and I
suspect in two years from now it'll
probably be 70 75 percent hemp and 20
25% marijuana so asking a little bit
different everybody sitting on the
sidelines right now waiting for the FDA
to ultimately weigh in on CBD do you see
pent up demand from were consolidation
when that happens so with regard of the
FDA I mean it's that's not gonna get
resolved anytime soon right and so it's
one of those things where folks are
cautious but a lot of is just education
I mean educating our clients that yeah
there is this FDA issue but I mean
there's compared to marijuana there's a
lot less risk in terms of hemp derived
products and that's really just related
to CBD
you know think outside the box and
there's so many of the things that helps
going to be used to get you know turned
into and also all the other parts of it
I mean all the genetics and all the
technology around you how do you grow it
efficiently how do you process it
efficiently how do you efficiently make
it into batteries and bottles and cars
and plants and all that houses so people
think of hemp as CBD hemp is so much
larger than that and so you know
definitely think outside the box and
also look at all the stuff that's going
to be needed to be developed in terms of
processing hemp and turning it into
products and scaling so I want to give
the audience an opportunity are there
any questions audience I have more
questions if you don't but I wanted to
make sure if anybody had questions for
the who's got a question anyone do I see
you guys are all incredibly well
informed apparently knowledge you need
all right I'm gonna go oh wait I saw a
small hand wave oh right it was like an
auction you have to be very on it it's
very subtle like an upper-class auction
so one of the things I did not hear I
still think that we're missing in the
industry as a whole when we talk about
risk and risk aversion and we talk about
insurance and you know yes they have
been providing business solutions and
such but they're finally really starting
to look at the industry as a whole so
those of us that have been doing this
for a while I think that there's a big
opportunity to bring that group along
and not just in the investment so maybe
you can talk a little bit about avoiding
exposure and product liability and some
of the other things that are already
affecting us like a lawyer question do
you want to rephrase it so that he can
answer it I'm sorry yeah it was a little
hard to hear you sorry we talked about
the financial part of this but we're not
talking about the backend side of this
right so as we you know and this is
probably - Katie a lot because you're
probably dealing with some of those
things and I think we see the whole vape
gate and what we learned from
unregulated unlicensed areas great so
one way I would answer that would be to
make sure that you are surrounding
yourself with the experts who know what
they're talking about and that means
almost endless specialization right if
you're concerned about your product
liability which you should be everyone
should it be everyone in the supply
chain make sure that you are going to
someone and go retain a lawyer who is a
product liability specialist do not go
to the criminal defense attorney that
kept you out of jail in the 90
right hey that guy is great we're very
happy with him but it's like asking a
podiatrist to do heart surgery right so
the way that you I think the way that I
see that people have the best luck
controlling their risk is when they're
seeking out and spending the money on
the real professionals who know what's
going on and really we were joking about
this in the in the green room earlier
but like it's so much cheaper to hire
someone who's a specialist at the front
end than it is to hire a litigator
afterwards right this is really like do
not be penny wise and pound foolish
really look into your wrist be very
honest with yourself about where it is
and listen to your advisors about who
else you might need to go look towards
and so that that's one of the biggest
mistakes that I see people doing is that
they rely on one lawyer for everything
or one consultant for everything and
that's that doesn't work in any other
industry why would that work here my
name is Helene Servian I'm a partner at
journey one we do early-stage cannabis
investments my question was around
there's two parts of the question what
industries outside of cannabis are you
guys most intrigued or excited about
that you think will start to tip into
near future M&amp;A and the second part is
if those industries alcohol or direct up
your alley we though is it the first
part of the question is that what other
industries am i interested in investing
in that I think near future M&amp;A so the
example like food and beverage yeah I
mean they're all over the space I would
say food and beverage or traditional
consumer packaged goods companies are
all over this industry already they're
already talking to companies already
looking at them but what I'm a little
I'm not even sure that it's going to be
M&amp;A and not build your own product in
many of those cases because we have yet
to see breakaway brands we have some
brand
are bigger in this industry but from my
background of use I used to consult for
PepsiCo and so I understand the way
these groups think about it and there's
a lot a lot of market research and
understanding that goes into new product
development and and launching these
products so if there's a low moat around
it they're just going to do it
themselves and so right now I feel like
CBD would be falling right into that
category and so I'm I'm probably one of
the more skeptical people that
acquisitions of high multiples of CBD
brands are going to happen from
traditional CPG companies or even
alcohol brands I think that from what I
understand constellation kind of regrets
the way that they invested into canopy
growth corporation and I think that they
I mean they've been pretty vocal about
their disappointment and in the
performance and the lagging of the
launching of beverages and so I think
that we've got some pain points to go
and I don't think we're gonna see those
lofty multiples for a while again I
think that when some of the regulations
change around banking and when when
things open up a bit more and things get
up sighs we could see some more interest
around that but I do think that it's so
I know beauty brands like I know L'Oreal
is looking at the space I know that
alcohol is looking at the space I know
consumer packaged goods companies are
looking at the space I know big Big
Tobacco is looking at the space all of
them are investigating it and all of
them are trying to decide if they just
do it themselves or if they buy
companies and they're gonna be slow
until the FDA weighs into on CBD
probably yeah it depends on where
they're located too but testing did
anybody else have anything to add I
think it's kind of interesting because
some some people are a lot of people
think that cannabis is like is this
really really different thing and has to
be treated differently I mean it's
there's some legality and regulatory
hurdles but it's it's a plan right and
and it's gonna evolve like most other
industries and so don't think of it that
differently right in terms of from an
investment standpoint and how it's going
to evolve what and where the
opportunities are because it's you know
we're gonna look back in 15 years so
yeah that's just like everything else
that evolved at some point in time you
know what I think is interesting though
you pointed out about the other
industrial uses of hemp and that is
where I'm seeing some large
multinational
and he's like fashion brands are talking
to those companies because they have
something proprietary and special about
how they can create an actual textile
that's user friendly actually
eco-friendly and something that these
large companies can work with and then
they can talk about this really
interesting story about bringing hemp
back bringing seeds they're calling it
seed disown movement so there's some but
that's where I'm talking about with the
moat that gets really interesting and
that's when the M&amp;A gets that's when you
get the better bio it's great point
because really the only thing that's
concerns people right now about CBD is
the FDA issues there's so many other
uses of hemp that there's there's
literally no restrictions now to develop
products using using that plant for all
these other products any other questions
well I want to thank the folks at ICBC
and our panel as well thank you let's
hear it again for rockstein
[Applause]