well I'd like to thank ICBC for inviting
me back um you know being an economist I
I didn't bore the crowd too much last
year so you know I have uh two daughters
and one of the daughters refers to
economics as not just economics but
boring economics and so hopefully today
I won't uh I won't inundate you with too
many data points um and so my other
daughter is going to college next year
and I asked her if she was going to
study economics she said hell
no um but my name is Bo Whitney I'm the
chief Economist at Whitney economics
we're based out of Portland Oregon um on
the west coast of the United
States um today I'm going to talk about
going to try to provide an overview of
the world the US Europe and then dig
into some Spain data um and so like I
said we're a global leader in cannabis
and hemp research and we provide data um
to governments to
operators um to investors and the
like um and so um I'm going to talk
specifically about Spain um as well
there's there's some really interesting
data out of Spain these days um but just
as an overview and I know that it's a
friendly audience but you know cannabis
is really three Industries in one
there's the adult use there's Medical
coal and then there's industrial and
Industrial is also known as hemp and
then within hemp there's the cannabinoid
there's three Industries in one uh with
with hemp you know industrial and the
are the cannabinoids and fibers and
Grain and so there's lots of Economic
Opportunity in either of these sectors
and so it's just important to choose one
and and run with it um and um a lot of
countries are viewing cannabis ref form
favorably as a tool for economic
development it's different for one
country versus another but they're
looking at this for job creation for tax
revenue for reductions in uh Health Care
spending because of the health benefits
of cannabis as a proactive um medicine
and the like so lots of Interest right
now in cannabis
reform in fact um and giata touched upon
this earlier today there's over 150
countries that have uh legalized access
to cannabis in some form or another from
adult use from medical um or um even
CBD and so various reform um um you know
entails different
opportunities and when you combine hemp
and uh adult use and medical together um
it's a trillion dollar market um with a
half a a billion consumers so lots of
opportunity out
there
now putting together total potential
Market data a lot of the analysts
usually look at the UN ODC numbers the
United sta or the United Nations data
that looks at um um usage rates and they
they do these interviews in country by
country sometimes there's five years
that separate the interiew the the
surveys you know and the Congo from you
know 2005 and then 2010 and maybe 2020
so it's kind of fits and starts and so I
use the UN data as a baseline I consider
that the low-end because it's very
conservative and then I build my models
um um based upon other countries and um
and then um so I've developed a midpoint
and a in an upper bound so um what I've
got here um on the right hand side
on this side um is how things break down
from that legal perspective so um
although there's legal Revenue there's
potential revenue and so in the medical
countries where there's legal access
those markets are huge and they're the
largest opportunity so um if you get in
there and then things go adult use then
there's huge upside potential in that
market and so um medical is by far the
largest opportunity um even outpacing um
elicit and so I found that to be kind of
interesting when I was running this data
um but you've got about a half a billion
dollar market in the in the um midpoint
um and so huge Global
potential now I want to talk a little
bit about the US market um it's it's in
a bit of a state of disarray right now
there's a lot of murkiness about what
the policy should be the federal
legalization there's banking issues
there's taxation issues there's social
Equity issues there's interstate
commerce um prohibitions and so uh you
really have to look at the US in discret
markets state by state by state um and
so it's super fragmented um and their
The Regulators at the state level and at
the federal level are really having
difficulty managing the differences
between hemp and the policies related to
hemp and managing the difference between
hemp and adult use and medical and so
they first separated them and then now
they're trying to put them back together
because they are looking at hemp as
cannabinoids and intoxicating rather
than hemp in those three distinct
markets that I mentioned earlier so um
but as a result of all of this murkiness
this um um
you know toggle between hemp and adult
use um it's actually disincentivizing
consumers to participate in the legal
markets in fact 11 states last year saw
declines in sales rather than increases
in sales and so there was um the level
of growth was um much less than it than
it has been before covid and be and when
the reform really started taking place
during the green Rush um and a business
condition survey that I published a
report that I published about a year ago
said that 24% of cannabis operators in
the United States were profitable
24% so that means 76% were either
breaking even or not and so it it talks
about the health of the US cannabis
Market um and then I just am on the cusp
of publishing a report on delinquent
payments
um and basically in the United States
operators aren't paying other operators
and so there's an incentive because of
the high cost of capital there's an
incentive just not to pay each other
because you're you can finance that debt
for free rather than going to a bank if
you can get one um and paying 35 to 40%
interest rates so the way that the
system in the United States works is
that it incentivizes businesses not to
pay each other
and so this is this has never been
published before but the amount of
delinquent receivables in the United
States in at the end of 2023 was $3.8
billion now that's almost two months of
Revenue in the entire legal Market in
the United States it's 1.6 months so
this is a huge existential threat that
very few people are talking about so if
you don't pay each other then it's tough
to pay your own bills it's tough to pay
your own Debt Service it's tough to
tough to pay your taxes um and so I'm
going to publish a report next week on
this U with more details but that's kind
of late breaking news um and uh so it's
it's a policy issue that needs to be
addressed and the policy makers right
now are so focused on intoxicating hemp
that they're not taking care of their
own markets from adult use and medical
regulatory uh perspective now this is a
lesson to be learned for Europe because
it's important that if you regulate a
market you should try to not only
regulate it and continue to stay on it
but also um consider the health of the
operators that you're trying to regulate
and right now um there's a health issue
associated with operators in adult use
and can and Medical in the United
States now we put together a forecast
this is a refresh forecast from last
year we actually took down the 2024
forecast by $3
billion um and be and the reason that we
took it down it's still showing growth
9% growth but just not the type of
growth that you would expect um
postco and the reason we took it down is
that higher interest rates there's
inflation um and there's just not enough
money being loaned out there in order to
get businesses opened up and ramping and
so those ramps are kind of muted and so
we're forecasting that this growth rate
will be lower um than normal in
2024 2025 and it'll start accelerating
in the back half of 2025 so still pretty
decent growth any industry would want
10% growth or 9% growth um but in
cannabis in the United States is a bit
of a disappointment and a lot of the
growth is going to come not from the
mature markets like Colorado or Oregon
or Washington but will come from new
markets that have just deployed their
program and starting to
ramp so um I took down the I just
published the global forecast as well
and the European market is like the
second largest market in the on the
globe um from a potential Revenue
perspective um it's it's fourth or fifth
fth from a consumer perspective um but
the um the total addressable markets
about 53 billion On The Low End um giata
earlier today published 68 million or 68
billion that was in more in the middle
of my forecast and then um there's an
upper bound as well which could be in
the hundreds of billions of dollars it
just depends upon which countries you
consider um and so the this I take some
of the statistics from the World Bank
and so they consider Russia as part of
uh the EU or the part of Europe and so
um so they tend to um bring up the
numbers a little bit um now there's
Germany is in Focus right now because of
what's going on next week um but if they
continue to Waffle back and forth on
their policy there's a good chance that
um Spain and other countries could start
influencing the European Reform movement
um more so than Germany and so it just
depends upon the timing um but when
these large countries like the United
States or Germany tend to Waffle then it
opens up opportunities for other
countries to take the lead um and so um
there's very little data in the about
the European markets um but it's getting
better um and we're here to help so if
you need any data or insights I'll have
my cont contact information at the back
half of this um
presentation so um five countries make
up majority of the demand um that's 53
billion now that's on the low end um and
so Spain you see and there is right
around5 billion dollar I'm sorry I
didn't put this in Euros um I'll when I
speak in Berlin I'll put these in Euros
but $5 billion is a pretty decent Market
um now for perspective um um you know
that's maybe the size of some states in
the United States like New York um and
so but still a pretty decent market now
that's total Market that doesn't it's
that's illicit plus legal or whatever
you really call legal here in
Spain now um there's based upon the UN
numbers there's 3.3 million consumers of
cannabis in Spain um and it's a very
popular reform is very popular um and so
the citizens want reform at least for
medical um 84% based upon recent surveys
um but there could be as many as seven
or eight million consumers in this space
now right now that's not being serviced
by the legal Market obviously and so all
of this is elicit and and so the supply
is coming in both domestically and from
Africa and from the rest of Europe um
and so what I have here is also the
amount of total consumption from a
output perspective so total amount of
pounds um of output that you would need
to satisfy all this demand and so it's
um 824 th000 kilos um and so that's um
824 tons now for perspective this last
year there was roughly 24 tons produced
and maybe 36 tons this year so only 4%
of the total
demand um is being produced from a
supply perspective now when you talk
about cannabis a lot of people talk
about the demand but they don't talk
about Supply but Supply is super
important if you don't have enough
prices stay up and consumers remain on
the elicit Market if you have have too
much then prices collapse which is great
for Consumer and and
participation but it's not good for The
Operators because it compresses their
margins so striking a balance of supply
versus demand is is super important in
any Market that you go into now Canada
started this the US followed suit Europe
maybe right behind them but um nobody
seems to have learned from the mistakes
of other countries
and so um Canada they
oversupplied prices crashed they
actually ended up destroying a lot of
cannabis they were hoping to ship it to
Europe and it didn't quite work out very
well they were hoping to ship it to the
United States but they didn't legalize
but then the United States they are over
producing right now in fact there's more
capacity legally authorized in the
United States then all of the consumers
elicit and legal in the United States
there's already more capacity so this is
you know has a potential of uh crashing
uh prices oversupplying markets and then
really hurting potential opportunities
for other people who want to enter into
other
states now I talked about industrial
hemp and so I just wanted to comment
that even with just a few um sectors
automobile um construction Plastics with
a sco of cannabinoids in there uh the
hemp Market is actually bigger than the
adult use of Medical Market globally and
so when people talk about cannabis um
there's a lot of influence that could be
made by the hemp industry um and hemp
may be The Driver of cannabis reform
more so than a medical to adult use
conversion um but um just wanted to talk
about this now in some countries they
view it all as Canabis and then in other
countries they like in the United States
they try to differentiate based upon THC
content um but um regardless of um oh
and and this differentiation can create
conflicts between the hemp industry and
the marijuana industry especially when
it comes to intoxicating Canabis noids
and um but there so that conflict I
think is unfortunate and I think hemp
and marijuana can coexist and they
should because it's all basically the
same
plant um now just like and one of the
panelists I think it was uh Jamie pson
mentioned that um uh the EU is similar
to the US in the fact that EU rules over
IDE countries and then countries
override their states or provinces or
what have you um the same thing um
applies the United States from a federal
to state to um County to City
perspective um but a lot of the
countries in the EU are defaulting to
the EU policy and they're not
challenging it um now there is a a rule
that says if it's legal in one country
and it's not for medical
purposes then you can it's it's legal to
be sold in all countries in the EU and
so that's an interesting concept that is
worth exploring because it's like I
think there's somebody from Portugal
here right so you produce in Portugal
and then you can ship into Germany or
ship into other
markets okay so it it's the concept
that right okay so there's nuances to it
but the concept is the same um if it's
the principle of of shipping into a
unified Market versus uh carving that
market out um with individual um rules
and regulations so um if as a investor
or as an operator you get set up in one
country then there's opportunities
because of the size of these markets
there's opportunities later on if you're
able to establish a good brand a good
quality product and you can conform
within the EU uh specific
ation um and so a lot of people are
looking to the EU here in the uh in
these European countries uh the EU is
looking to the US the US isn't really
doing anything and so it's kind of like
which Domino will fall first before
there's a rapid acceleration of Reform
um and that's tough to predict I'm not
going to opine on that but um if if um
some of these larger countries like I
said don't get
um um don't make some clarity on their
policies then they may be supplanted as
world
leaders so and I wanted to blast through
this um presentation so that I could
take some questions later on because I'm
sure there's lots of questions on the
data or at least I hope there are um but
if you're too shy to make any questions
then um feel free to reach out U with my
contact information and um I'd be more
than happy to share this presentation
and some of the data with it um but in
terms of prediction um Germany is on the
cusp of being the first um and then I'm
anticipating a a rapid expansion of
Reform um these pilot programs and
Social Clubs it's a novel um idea um and
it's worth
pursuing um
and um look for a regulation around
certified seeds because
uh you have to start with stable
genetics and right now in the United
States you don't have that but in Europe
um it's um pretty established it's a a
very established Market the certified
seed program um and Public Safety will
remain foremost in the eyes of the
policy makers and so as business
operators it's important to consider um
Public Safety and build that in and uh
hemp will be a major um Market not only
in in the US but in Europe as
well so recommendations um
communicate
educate know everything about your
business and your cost structure because
when I talk about over Supply what that
does is it compresses margins uh right
now there's inflation so when you have
falling prices and increasing costs that
really squeezes the profits out of your
business and so if you don't know your
cost structure then you don't know when
to make um critical decisions about your
business so understanding cost structure
is really really important and then also
staying focused on your core competency
you can't be um you know uh everything
to everybody it's just it's not possible
and it hasn't proven to be successful in
the United States for example uh
vertical integration was a big uh was in
Vogue for a long time um but in my
delinquency report I'm finding that even
if you're vertically integrated and
control all the costs within your
vertical um they're still one of the
largest contributors to delinquencies um
in the entire space so there's still
delinquent payment issues um even in
vertical integrated companies so it's
important to carve off what you know and
what you're good at and then pursue that
with Vigor and passion and so uh another
thing is is that although we're in Spain
and a lot of the focus is on Spain at
your business when we're in Germany
Focus isn't on Germany and so uh
cannabis is a very local issue but
really remember that this is a global
market and so it's important to act
local but keep the global market in mind
because it will have an eventual
influence on your business and on your
success so with that um you know feel
free to reach
out um lots of data lots to digest and
so just uh let me know um and so I'm
happy to take questions thank you
again does does anyone have a
question all the way over there let's
hear it for Michael kot I run I run
doing all the walking and running he's
very quick it's very fast for a man in
his 50s hello thank you very much as
fast um thank you for this I'm Tyler
Secor and with reassure um we're based
out of Michigan in us um just my
question in general is this data
especially the delinquent payments is
this among um more cannabis to cannabis
say B Growers to producers or do you did
you in factor in the safety compliance
testing aspect of this as well so my
delinquent report that's coming out next
week um on my website um it's a a free
report um it looked at not only all the
uh sectors and sub sectors within
cannabis Laboratory Testing included but
it also looked at ancillary businesses
and so I was presenting at a a group of
uh CPA certified public accountants now
who's more boring economists or
accountants I kind of vote accountants
um but um in that uh the accountants the
CPAs were saying that they're not
getting paid
and so the the um so these ancillary
businesses lawyers aren't getting paid
and so the question becomes an ethical
dilemma for them do we not pay or do
their taxes this season because they
haven't paid us for last season or do we
go ahead and just you know put more
Revenue at risk and so there um needs to
be some discipline in here but it looked
at all sectors retail had it the easiest
because they are closest to the the
consumer and so they tended to be the
ones that didn't pay uh through you know
through the uh product manufacturers and
the cultivators cultivators on a
percentage basis took it the hardest
meaning that they had the toughest time
getting payment from others um and then
the vertical integrated companies were
also big contributors and multi-state
operators
unfortunately um the average um per MSO
was like $32 million in delinquent
payments so it's you know everybody's
contributing um and so there could be
some um regulatory intervention that's
required to um mandate payment adherence
or cash on delivery or what have you so
uh bit of an extended answer to your
question but um Michigan is a tough
Market because there's lots of
operators um falling prices you've got
huge legal participation because the
consumers like the smaller the lower
prices but it's tough to be profitable
in that type of environment and then
when you're not getting paid on top of
that um you know 10 months of of cash
flow for a 12-month business that's not
a recipe for Success so thanks for the
question I'm
running thank you for your discussion is
very very interesting I'm Victor Herz
independent visor uh principle uh I
found your comment about how in the
United States uh through the farm Bild
they they defined hemp versus uh
cannabis or marijuana as um as a
pivotable move but now it's a
problematic move obviously with THC 8 n
and all of that uh one question I have
for you is um that in
1718 CBD was present in so many consumer
products in the United States
and with the definition of hemp as
distinct and it going from uh DEA to FDA
it's run into Thicket I'm just wondering
if you could share uh with the audience
uh some of the learnings of that
experience and if there's any
applicability to uh uh the market
development here in Europe thank you so
when it comes to the evolution of the
hemp
industry early on in between 2014 and
um there was very few um Farms that grew
hemp and when they did they grew up for
fiber and for grain and as a result
there wasn't a lot of canabo um plants
and raw materials available and so the
cost of uh CBD isolet for example could
easily run $40,000 a kilo um then people
seeking Riches of seeing those high
prices they entered into the market due
to one of the um agricultural reform
bills called the the farm bill and so at
one point 500 25,000 Acres were licensed
82% of that was for cannaboid
production um there was no
infrastructure there was very little
processing little drawing and little
Awareness on how to grow this stuff and
so there was a surplus of cannabinoid
raw materials in the
market that drove prices down the very
next year year um people didn't learn
from their mistakes other states entered
into it and doubled the amount of excess
inventory so you had this 201 million
pounds of excess cannabinoid raw
material 2 million kilos of CBD isolate
just sitting on the shelves so somebody
had to figure out how to monetize that
and so that brought in some emerging
innovation in the Delta 8 Delta 10 hhc
markets and so they were able to um
develop products that were intoxicating
that were had market demand and they
were able to consume a lot of that raw
material well now that um a lot of that
um U raw material inventory has been
consumed a lot of the farmers have
gotten out of the industry so instead of
having 525,000 Acres you're back to
prearm bill at 30,000 acres and a major
of that now is fiber and grain so
there's a common theme here where you
have this huge Spike on cannabinoids and
then now it's going back to its roots um
in the fiber and grain sector so um but
policy makers have been trying to
address the influx of cannabinoids into
and competing with the medical and adult
use um products and so when I did the
analysis and published this late last
year the total addressable mark Market
in the United States for cannabinoids
derived from hemp was $28
billion well last year the sales of of
legal adult use and medical was $28
billion so there's a huge Market which
may or may not be able to be sustained
um with the current amount of acreage
right now that's being licensed in the
United States now can Europe learn from
that well they've already have kind of
taught the US lesson where they've
controlled the production they've
insisted on certified seed they have
good regulation um it's tight control
but there's still opportunity
nonetheless for hemp in the United
States especially on the fiber and grain
side for industrial applications 20% of
of Mercedes cars are Parts derived from
hemp and so there's already these
industrial applications in automobile
industry and Plastics and the like that
go beyond the cannabinoid side of the
hemp Market
okay maybe one more and gu or do you
have time for one more question sorry we
out of time okay I'm sorry we we even
went over by like a minute and a half
because I'm a benevolent and
kind MC let's hear it again for Bo
Whitley and if you have