and our next speaker coming to the stage
right now
we're very excited to have them
please if you have conversations please
have them outside
I'm looking at you guys
[Music]
here he is all right we're going to
discuss cannabis in the European market
the chief Economist of Whitney economics
let's hear it for Beau Whitney
foreign
hey it's a pleasure to be here today
um thanks for everybody for traveling
coming a long way
um so I'm an economist and in the
Cannabis space and there's not too many
of us around
um in fact I was
at the grocery store the other day and I
had this
sweatshirt on with a cartoon character
called Scooby-Doo on it and the caption
said Dooby Dooby Doo and if this van
smoke and we be token right and uh the
the person at the checkout counter said
hey that's a pretty cool sweatshirt
and uh she said uh you know where'd you
get it and all this and eventually it
came around to that I was an economist
in the Cannabis space
she goes what is that
and I said well you know I look at the
numbers I track the market and the
trends and stuff and and she said oh
that's very interesting and so I paid
for my groceries and as I was leaving
she said hey good luck with that made-up
job of yours
[Laughter]
what anyway so yeah there's uh I'm an
economist I'm not making this up
so today I'm going to talk about the
European market I'm going to give a kind
of a global and a U.S update because
everybody wants to talk about the U.S
numbers and then I'll
um look at this in terms of the EU
Market give a little bit of data on spin
and then compare and contrast a little
bit of the policy going on between the
U.S and and the EU
so Whitney economics is a consulting
firm we do economic Consulting we
provide data to the industry we have a
forecast a total addressable forecast
for every country in the world where
clientele on practically every continent
so you know I've been in the industry
now for about nine years and so if you
need any data just let me know
um and so like I said we're just going
to do a little compare and contrast
after I give you some data
um now just a level set cannabis is
really three Industries in one it's it's
the adult use it's medical and it's
Industrial
and Industrial is then also broken down
into three markets the fiber and Grain
and then the cannabinoid Market
and I think it's important to note this
because people don't understand I think
hemp they think CBD or minor
cannabinoids or whatever
but it's important to educate people on
this and and differentiate between the
two more or the three markets but a lot
of countries are reforming right now and
they're looking at it from an economic
development perspective from a jobs
perspective and the like
um and you know based upon our numbers
it's a combined it's over a trillion
dollars and if you think about that
trillion dollars you know the U.S market
total addressable is about a hundred
billion if you add in hemp you add in
the medical Market the European market
the Asian market a trillion dollars and
and so people really have difficulty
putting their arms around that a
trillion dollars
um but what's going on is that a lot of
these these countries want to embrace
cannabis but they're kind kind of
waiting for the U.S to set the trend
give them the okay and then then they'll
follow suit now what I think is could
end up happening though is that as the
EU starts deploying legal cannabis
especially on the adult youth side like
in Germany in the Czech Republic and
elsewhere then the European market could
flip this around and actually become the
Big Driver in cannabis reform around the
world
so there's over 30 or sorry 70 countries
around the world that have some form of
legal access to cannabis and there's
massive numbers
350 to 500 million consumers
and these are conservative numbers
because a lot of the you know
researchers
look at surveys and they deploy these
surveys and the surveys go like this hi
I'm from the government do you smoke
weed and in states and countries where
there's prohibition then the responses
are uh no I don't know what you're
talking about even if they are consumers
and so a lot of the numbers are actually
lower than the reality of the situation
but
with the total Market of 350 billion
dollars for medical and adult use total
addressable Market illicit and legal
combined combined with hemp that's that
gets you to a trillion dollars really
quickly
um and like I mentioned countries are
looking at this for economic development
they're looking at it for jobs they're
looking at it to reduce Health Care
expenditures
to reallocate law enforcement and the
like so there's a real compelling
argument for legal cannabis
so in terms of the U.S
um little-known fact 10 states out of
the 38 that have legal cannabis actually
saw sales declines last year
growth was really low it was anemic at
4.5 percent
and a lot of the industry thought that
this The Surge that came from covid and
increased the demand over 2020 21 22
that that was going to continue
indefinitely but as people came back to
the market and are back to work and back
to school then they didn't have as much
of an opportunity to consume cannabis
and so sales dropped so that really
suppressed demand in the first half of
last year on a global basis
and then in the U.S in particular
um inflation started taking a bite out
of people's paycheck and the consumers
were resistant at first they they spent
about the same
if they had a discount on flour for
example they would backfill with Edibles
or pre-roll what have you and they'd
spend about the same but as the year
wore on inflation started taking a
greater bite out of their
um you know income and so they started
spending less and so pre-covet or
post-covid decline combined with changes
in consumer Behavior it really had a
devastating effect on the market overall
and it kind of spooked investors it
spooked operators a lot of people
operators did more with less they didn't
hire as many people they didn't deploy
some of their
operations on schedule they deferred and
delayed and like
um and so
um so this really hurt profitability in
the United States and so we deployed a
survey in Q4 of last year only 24
percent of the respondents were actually
making a profit and so if you think
about that that means 76 of The
Operators were either breaking even or
losing money and so this is you know
kind of alarming when you're an investor
or when you're an operator and nobody's
making money
and and demand is going down so the
industry really struggled in 2022 I'm
not forecasting that it does much into
to improve until 2024 2025 in the U.S
um and there's some inhibiting factors
there's policy issues like safe banking
which gives access to finance gives some
protections on bankruptcy and the like
taxes are very heavy in the United
States and so this is suppressing the
growth in the profitability of the
industry interstate commerce would open
up a lot of opportunities for producer
States for Consumer States would level
level profits I mean excuse me level
prices out and make it uniform across
the country to a certain extent and so
there's a lot of policy issues Brewing
but there's not much in terms of
forecasting that this is going to be
resolved over the next Years it'll
probably
either push out into 2024 or Beyond
there will be a presidential election
and then even after that even after the
reform occurs then
um it'll take a while for these policies
to be implemented on at a national level
there is a comment in one of the
previous panels about
um you know
protectionist policies and access to
markets that's really interesting
comment it really resonated with me in
some of the federal legalization bills
that are being bantered about in
Washington DC a lot of this opens up the
U.S market to foreign competition almost
immediately and this could have a
devastating effect on the market on
operators in the U.S because they have a
kind of a higher cost of production and
you know other International competitors
could come in at a lower cost and now
compete with a pretty substantial Market
already
um over 40 000 licensees in the United
States
and so there's a lot going on like I
mentioned people are waiting countries
are waiting for the U.S to reform even
Mexico when constitutionally it's legal
but they haven't deployed their rules
and regulations yet
and don't look for them to deploy
anytime soon until the U.S gives some
type of indication about what's going on
so I've got a forecast here I just
refreshed this we track data from every
state
and some of the ramps and the deployment
of the regulatory systems in some of
these key states are lagging right now
and so I've had to take down my
forecasts and near term
um but look even though there was only
4.5 growth in sales last year there's
still going to be about 12 growth this
year but that's far below what was
forecasted even six months nine months
ago
um and like I mentioned you know we saw
negative growth in in 10 states
um and the new growth is predicted to be
in the bigger States like New York New
Jersey but they're really struggling
right now with the deployment of their
legal programs
um and a lot of the product categories
like flour Edibles tinctures and like
are actually facing deflation so a lot
of the conversation globally and in the
United States is talking about inflation
um hurting consumers uh it's just the
opposite for cannabis operators they're
seeing deflation uh lower prices and
lower profitability so this is a an
issue to really you know keep an eye on
as you look at the markets either the US
market or European market and then
inflation is starting to impact startups
and so if you think about it interest
rates are rising the cost of your loans
is increasing and so it's taking a bite
out of your budget and you have to kind
of earn more generate more Revenue in
order to cover those increased costs of
your capital and so startups are not
getting out of the game it quick enough
and this is also suppressing the growth
of the overall Market
in terms of European market it's about a
70 billion dollar market for 62 to 70.
if you add in
some of the other European nations
include Russia it could be as much as
260 billion dollars
and it's by Revenue it's maybe the
second largest market in the globe but
from a consumer perspective it's like
the fourth or fifth Asia and Africa have
more consumers but they just spend less
because they don't have as much money
um in European as you all know is
looking at reforms I put Spain here as
as a courtesy but not a whole lot of
Reform going on in Spain right now but I
think where things are really the action
that's really happening is in Germany in
the Czech Republic
um and so if you get legalization and
adult use rolled out successfully there
it could have this domino effect
throughout the West the rest of the
European market and then that could in
turn influence
um the rest of the globe
and
even though there's consumer markets in
Germany and Czech Republic and Italy
even some of the periphery countries are
looking to be the producers and the
suppliers into the central European
market so there's opportunities in the
periphery countries just as much as
there's opportunities in in Central and
you know you're starting to see this
through the medical programs and the
medical supply chains
um there's very little data on this so
as key stakeholders in this space any
chance that you can collect data and
share data amongst yourselves the better
off you're going to be you'll just make
better decisions more informed decisions
and and you'll demystify what's going on
in the space we collect data all the
time but it's just hard to come by
especially at the consumer level
so there's five key countries that from
a total Market that solicit plus legal
that make up the EU
a majority of it comes from just five
countries and so Italy is some people
say well what about Germany shouldn't
that be at the top but from these um
surveys there's more consumers of
cannabis that will admit to governmental
survey takers that they consume in Italy
more so than they do in Germany and that
kind of makes sense culturally
um and so there could be as many as 150
million consumers
um in the European market and so that's
a pretty substantial Market if you think
about it it could combine even be larger
than the North American Market
um in terms of supply
so I took a look we have a total Market
forecast for Spain I looked at it from a
consumer perspective about 3.5 million
consumers so it's a big Market here and
that requires about 880 000 kilos of
cultivated output that's not just flour
but that's you know cultivated output
required for tinctures and oils bombs
and the like but if you think about it
there's only 24
uh kilos authorized in 2023 that's an
ICBC stat that they just published out
that's a that's a real good number for
perspective it was 6 000 kilos just a
couple of years ago so the Spanish
Market is very very underserved with
their current infrastructure and so
there needs to be if it's going to go
adult use or if there's going to be an
expansion of the medical program then
there's going to be a need for increased
cultivated output and this is a common
mistake that countries have when they
deploy legal cannabis is they tend to
focus initially on the retail side and
then they go backwards but they don't
realize that cultivation is the longest
lead time item and so really they should
understand their supply before they
start trying to sell it and process and
the like
um and so Spain 880
000 kilos
now as things mature
um you know there's going to be
increased competition from Africa
um from other European markets but
um Spain is positioned to such an extent
similar to Malta to where they could be
a conduit from Africa and into the
European Union especially on the medical
side
and so I wanted to talk a little bit
about industrial cannabis
so I looked at 10 product categories and
looked at the total market and then what
could be peeled off and supported just
very conservatively by industrial
cannabis
and when you look at automobile parts
and alternative Plastics
and foods for animals and human
consumption the and lithium battery
Replacements you can actually do
batteries using
fibers from hemp
plastic Cutlery in bags
at the market for hemp is actually
larger and the opportunity is actually
larger than the adult use in medical
combined and so that's kind of stunning
that's why I started off by saying that
it's three markets and then three
markets within three markets because
people don't realize that the real
potential of industrial cannabis
especially in in the United States
but they're they're starting to realize
it and embrace it more so in in the
European markets
um and then there's also some
environmental and climate related issues
that could be addressed with industrial
cannabis as well
so there's some differences in the
market and it's pretty interesting to
think about uh in the U.S they say hemp
is legal
cannabis on the adult use of medical
side is federally illegal
and it creates this Havoc from
Regulators they just don't know how to
handle that legal versus illegal and so
they really muck it up on both sides of
that fence of the THC fence that
delineates what is legal and what is not
and so they're adopting these policies
at the state level
um which just aren't very effective and
they're actually hurting the growth of
both markets and then there's some
infighting in the United States between
the adult use and medical side and the
industrial side because there's some
competing
um you know Supply
especially on the intoxicating
cannabinoid side
and so you've got this competition this
fragmentation and you just don't see
that as much in Europe what the you know
the differences are here and my firm is
studying all 27 countries here and we're
doing country reports due out later on
the summer for every every country
and so we're looking at a dog as we're
looking at Medical we're looking at
industrial opportunities and the rules
and regulations and Europe treats this
much differently they're they considered
all cannabis and then they try to figure
out how to regulate it from an
industrial perspective from adult use
perspective and the like uh the one area
of kind of
commonality is how to address
cannabinoids that are derived from hemp
you're seeing some products come in from
the U.S on the cannabinoid side but not
a whole lot right now even though
there's this real intense demand
um so if if you think about it if
if there's this well on CBD there's this
policy that says if it's legal in one
country in the EU then it's mostly legal
for distribution and sales in all the
countries and so if you apply that apply
that to adult use and medical then there
could be this rapid changeover in
deployment of adult use products
post-german and Czech launches into the
other countries
and if that happens then you've got a
quick turn
on your
Market opportunities here and it's going
to drive policy back into North America
and it's a little bit of a counter
narrative but I think that there's a
real possibility because the U.S is just
dragging its feet it's still dealing
with banking
interstate commerce and all that and the
EU has that already wrapped up and so
they don't have to deal with that so
those are some of the
key differences in between the U.S
market and the European market
so if I were to break out my crystal
ball and that's what economists do
then I think as Germany
sets the tone it'll set the tone for the
rest of Europe a lot of even the
industrial cannabis countries are
looking to Germany for guidance on this
and there's going to be an acceleration
of the market there is mentioned earlier
about
Gap and EU GMP I think certified seeds
and stable genetics are going to also be
an opportunity here and and those will
set the standards and it'll really be
more on the medical side things will be
kind of centered around the public
safety focus and more Medical in nature
rather than social or adult use nature
um and then you know things will just
kind of normalize once things get
deployed so
um and then hemp will come on strong as
well so lots of exciting opportunities
in the European market
um and so
in terms of recommendations
um you know go to Gatherings like this
start your network now before the
markets change and change rapidly
develop your supply chains and your
contacts within the supply chain so that
you can establish these relationships
and then expand on them and leverage
them to increase your revenues your
profits your capabilities
um but be very very conscientious of
your cost structure and don't get too
far out of your skis over your skis
because
um you know costs will come down prices
will come down as the market normalizes
it's very competitive here because
everybody wants to supply into the EU
right now because it's the only place to
supply medical so you've got South
Americans you've got Asians you've got
Australians North Americans they're all
trying to provide for this very same
Market that the EU to players are also
trying to supply in so being disciplined
about your internal cost is really
really critically important
and use data if you need data I know
where to go and and really you know act
local because cannabis is a localized
issue but then think Global because it's
really a global Marketplace
so that's what I have for you today I
wanted to if we have some time for
questions oh
darn we don't have time
one more time there you go uh we don't
have time for questions but I'm sure if
you want to accost him in the hallway he
would love to talk to you one more time
for about Wendy
game mode