let's let's start our next panel are you
ready all right we're going to discuss
canabo science we have a giant panel up
here and to lead us in that uh we have
biochemist a researcher from the
National Institute of biology in lublana
uh let's welcome Professor Dr Tamra
laek
[Music]
so good morning
everybody uh ladies and gentlemen so um
let me start with the words of Rafael
mulam who was already mentioned in the
previous lecture and uh he said that the
plant that had been used us for
thousands of years uh all around the
world actually uh from this plant we
discover a new pharmaceutical
pharmacological system that is um really
of immense
importance and so uh unfortunately he
passed away as we heard but a lot of
scientists research institutes
universities and Industry is following
his research because he is considered as
as a Godfather of uh Canabis science and
medicine so also this session will be
dedicated to uh actually um medical
research actually research science-based
uh medicine which is and it will not
only be on research but also how to
facilitate the research into clinical
application and how to actually transfer
this knowledge to uh people so um um
here in Slovenia we have a lot of good
scientist especially in Natural Sciences
especially in biom medicine and clinical
medicine but very few unfortunately for
several reasons that we are going to
discuss today as well are following the
Canabis Research or are focusing on
Canabis Research and that's why it's
very very slowly Paving the way to the
medical application so today it's my
great pleasure to introduce three
panelists um first is uh our guest from
Israeli uh Dr Ilia Resnik and the second
is Dr Professor David noow and uh last
but not of course least important is
border trer the pharmacies so um Dr IL
resing the floor is ours yours now uh
you have a presentation please uh iler
Resnik is a very welln uh not only
scientist but a medical practitioner in
Israel and we can learn from him what is
the practice in Israel compared to
Slovenia and where is Slovenia in terms
of international uh International
picture of medical uh use so please
thank you uh this is my great pleasure
to be with you I love Slovenia I love uh
Slovenian people I had been here for
several times uh for different occasions
usually with a series of seminars
organized by patients and activist
organizations of demystification of
cannabis it was very successful and many
people uh in the hall participated in
this uh seminars and this is my great
honor to be with you this time and my
appreciation to uh your Parliament
member and the uh uh Health Secretary of
Slovenia to be at this uh convention
this is a great moment where we are now
so we should decide if we are going with
cannabis as a medicine or we should
continue to consider it to be a drug
maybe narcotic drug maybe dangerous
narcotic drug like it was established
for the last 80 years so uh may I have a
next
slide there is a matter of fact we have
a a lot of people that using can for
different medical purposes but what kind
of research we had been made uh till to
to till tonight uh almost zero uh just
for last 15 years we have some good
clinical research for some
uh illnesses and we do not have any
conclusive results European mediter
agency declared that they could consider
cannabis as a medicine probably after
receiving the significant number of
conclusive research but they never
defined what what they are considered to
be a conclusive research so the matter
of fact that the research in this area
is underfunded but we have some good
clinical trials usually had been founded
by the companies such as Jazz
Pharmaceuticals pre previously GW
Pharmaceuticals Etc so we are performing
a lot of clinical research for example
in
like you asked me and uh for different
disorder multiple sclerosis Parkinson
disease epilepsia H D syndrome
post-trauma post-traumatic stress
disorder do we have conclusive results
till not till now maybe not but we could
who could decide and who should decide
what is being considered to be a
conclusive results or conclusive
research another fact is that we we uh
now in the in the transition in Israel
we in transitional space uh perform
going from the plant to Med to Medicine
our Ministry of Health declared a reform
saying now we will have cannabis as a
medicine is it real is it for real how
we can medic how we can perform
overwhelming medicalization for cannabis
and cannabinoids because this is a plant
and plant does not hear the orders of
our Ministry of Health or director
General so this is a some facts and may
I have another fact another uh
slide so uh pH pharmaceutical industry
providing some good examples how they
taking cannabis to different directions
so they could use or canab drived
components or they can use different
side of components H making some
medicine like saix or epics uh B deriven
uh cannabinoids from the plant so this
is one of the answers that we have been
provided by the industry and now next
slide so we know that cannabis and
cannaboid compounds could be treat used
for different disorders we just need to
understand the nature of the plant and
how to adapt and adjust different
cannabinoids to the different patients
and to his different diseases some
patients has several diseases in
together could we treat them with the
same plant or with same uh canab based
medicine we do not have clear answer
till now but we are trying to provide it
in the short future next
slide and this is a Israeli system that
saying we are going to the overwhelming
medicalization of cannabis based on the
uh two system so they are looking for
only for THC tcbd ratio and also they
are looking for H Inda or sativa
predominance is it enough for to to
decide that now we do not have a plant
we have a medicine I'm not sure and we
suggest that maybe another system like
we called cooptation so putting together
cannabinoids and
plants together we could uh make a
cannabis plant as a medicine as a
medicine but medicine don't without
destroying the nature of this plant this
is our idea and I hope we have another
uh views in the panel and maybe from the
questions from the auditory thank
you thank you very
much so I will just uh ask you a short
question um responding to your uh
comment that you were actually financed
by the Pharma industry more than than by
the uh public health system or public uh
research um funds uh what do you think
is the future will we need the more
public research or the all research and
application will be um financed by by
the big farmer or the Canabis farmer as
I aware that uh National Institute of
Health in US funds only studies that's
that Target to negative effects of
cannabis only they who could only such
studies could obtain grants from
National Institute of Health
unfortunately this is why I and this is
a example how Public Health System
relates to Canabis and Cano research so
my my hope that private sector and the
companies and uh different consortion
could rise a good quality uh studies uh
that may probably will serve as a
conclusive elements to European
medicinal Agency for FDA Etc so you
think the combination or the cooperation
between the public and private um sector
will be uh public sector I I do not hope
for public sector in Israel we have all
studies uh that uh we had been made in
Israel they mostly of them funded by the
P private sector thank you very much on
that uh issue
will'll then try to explain how is now
how is now in Slovenia maybe you should
start later so Bor is a pharmacist as he
said he's a leader of uh pharmaceutical
biology at faculty of Pharmacy of
University of lulana so board please
present your work and yourself like well
thank you very much first of all I would
like to thank the organizers uh I'm
really glad that I'm here because
Slovenia it is the leading one of the
leading uh member states in terms of
science and Canabis but unfortunately
the regulation is is still behind so
allow me to introduce myself very
briefly I'm professor at the facult of
Pharmacy University of Liana to link
with pharmaceutical biotechnology and
plant science uh beside I am unido
Senior um health expert in Vienna
dealing with the technology transfer to
um developing countries and very
recently I become a consultant for
Herbal pharmacopia at the wh uh which is
again a part of uh broad uh area of
research and you know plants and Canabis
and so on so I'm really uh looking
forward for these two I mean positions
and opportunities okay uh let me go I
will do it by myself so uh yes First
Steps regarding our group at the faculty
of Pharmacy dealing with Canabis you
know for for my humble uh experience and
opinion is that education is the most
important Point education at the first
not only for the health professionals
but uh predominantly for a native uh
individuals and patient as well as soon
as we'll be able to convince uh the
whole positive effects of Canabis or
compounds from a comination of their I
mean all these compounds uh to the
public this will be the ultimate goal in
order to make the final regulation so
okay there are many this kind actually
not only congresses but um I traveled
through all Slovenia and Croatia I
delivered a lot of talks uh among uh um
Nave and uh um public uh and some
patient as well and okay this was uh was
because I'm not active anymore in this
field in terms of Education this is a
task of my colleagues The Faculty of
Pharmacy uh regarding the Canabis
Research at the faculty of Pharmacy uh
we are Focus that means our group we are
focused on the analytical point of view
why because simply we need to
standardize material in this or that
manner or we are talking about the
flowers or we are talking about um okay
something's wrong I hope not from my
point of view but never mind so I mean
analytical point it is the focus of our
group beside uh now we would like to um
um simply to go further with the
research that I going to talk uh this
will be my my latest slide but now here
I'd like to focus your attention I'm
very proud of this International
dissemination together with Tamara we
attended at least two or three
conferences and meetings um around I
mean apart from the Slovenian um
territory but this one it was something
special why guess where is this country
that organized this very important this
Eurasian uh forum and this was in
Kazakhstan could you imagine in
Kazakhstan uh this was in 19 no sorry 20
uh 19 and it was under the patronage of
the thega newa
uh daughter of former uh president of
Kazakhstan n Sultan Naro so they were at
that time uh I mean they were really uh
focus on this point whether to uh make
Marana and
Canabis legal or is still illegal in the
country which is not the most developed
country and in the country which from
the economically his historically and
even um I don't know uh uh religious
point of view uh is something in between
so this was a very good conference and
here are some statements that I try to
uh Focus now I mean okay we are talking
about um recreational use and we're
talking about medical Canabis medical
use fine with me both but it should be
separated it by two different regulatory
uh uh guidelines or laws or
whatever it could goes in parallel this
is important to know it's not necessary
to be consecutively developed and this
is our ultimate goal to win with both uh
lows in Slovenia and uh very last slide
so yes now uh we try to find out
together with the Italian uh
partners and guys from Belgrade as well
what is the impact of CBD THC and the
combination of other cannabinoids on the
longevity or anti-aging if you wish
anti-aging is something that we would
all of us the more old we are the more
Focus we on this uh kind of or this area
of research and I was really uh
extremely positively shocked let's say
this was very fascinating keynote uh
presentation hibernation Canabis and
anti-aging you know that that uh
heartbeat of turtles there it is perhaps
12 per minutes the less heartbeats per
minut is present in the animal the older
in in terms of age these animals could
live so I mean this is something that we
would like to to uh to uh re for the
research not only with the CBD but also
with THC and preliminary findings that
there
are under expressed of pro-inflammatory
cyto kindes Gene coding from
pro-inflammatory cyes and overexpress
genes that are directly or indirectly
related to anti-aging and by this I will
stop and I'm open for any kind of well
thank you very much U Bor um
here it's also my question because as
you all know or don't know actually the
Canabis treatment is very beneficial for
all uh diseases that are associated with
ages such a neuroen degenerative
diseases Alzheimer Parkinson disease
cardiovascular diseases uh chronic
inflammation also multiple sclerosis and
so on and especially cancer which and
all this increase exponentially during
aging so this is a very good news that
we can also use
canab both to prevent or uh to uh
actually slow down aging process at the
same time the associated diseases with
aging will be also could be also treated
so it's a big hope for that and I think
this is a very important finding and in
future you know uh we know all know that
longevity is um is a perhaps a problem
for some people but actually it's not
because what we want is to keep older
population active and healthy and
thereby contributing to uh economies to
a great extent especially this is called
so silver economy and that's why order
people keeping them in fit it's it's
very important so do you think that we
can perhaps use this then in Elderly
Homes or something just to you know to
treat the patients or diets or something
thank you very complex very complex
question actually yes but you know if
you are asking our uh medical insurance
uh companies they are not very happy to
pay for pensions uh till uh uh when the
individual is 120 years old so in this
case this is very uh an economically but
let let me be very serious yes I I
really believe on this actually uh our
foundings not only our but uh it's look
like that inflammation
it is yes inflammation it is one General
degeneration over the years and by the
way you know that obesity the new um
definition of obesity it is mild General
uh inflammation so as soon as we are
able to decrease not all of them but at
least some more the most important genes
coding for interl looking Alpha um then
uh 12 23
uh um 17 all these proinflammatory cogin
are related with um chronically diseases
that are present
predominantly in the older generation so
I mean yes I believe but you know we are
all the the bottleneck is regulation and
on the other hand um we do not have a
very clear indications are the list of
indications that might be treated with
but perhaps this is the topic that will
this is the future the future of no B is
right person to Professor no b um he was
for 20 years the head of the pediatric
neurology neurology department and uh
now we switch from
older population to children and he is
treating epilepsy uh in very
successfully for 20 years and he will
tell you about that plus he will present
uh himself as
well thank you very much um thank you
very much Tamara for
invitation um and um I'm uh actually
professor in Pediatrics but also a
senior consultant in child neurology I'm
also visiting Professor mainly to the
Middle East countries like Kuwait
Bahrain
Dubai um but also to
Kazakhstan and Croatia and Zambia and so
on um I have just three slides three
different um um researches we we did it
in this um last uh actually nine years
that we are um uh using uh different
cannabinoids um for severe um childhood
neurological problems the first one and
um the largest study we did is um
treating resistant epilepsies um in
children um resistant epilepsy that
means that at least two standard
anti-epileptic drugs are not um
successful and um the group we have um
taken are 66 children with severe severe
resistant epilepsies um which we call
now developmental epileptic and copes
that means that the child is having so
many SE maybe at the beginning the child
can be um normal completely normal but
he's having so many epileptic fits
epileptic seizures maybe even 100 per
day that his mental uh state is going
down he's more and more mentally
[ __ ] and even his motor abilities
even if his structure of the brain is in
the neuroimaging completely normal is
less and less and in these children we
used um first um canabidol it is 100
well
98% natural canabidol um and the success
rate was um extremely good it is
um this is not working but you can see
at the at the um upper part the seizure
free was in um 1/5 of the children which
is um
21% and in more than 50% the reduction
was for more than 50 um um amount of the
seizures no and um also in the others
there was some improvement um during the
study two children died because of this
severe epileptic and copies and now it
was um we started in 20 2015 and the
publication was in
2018 um however now we are treating more
than 200 patients with CBD um and some
of them they were those included at the
beginning so um the the the period is
now uh nearly 9 years of followup um and
um in some of them we um switched from
the 100% canab to uh cannabis products
um which usually our parents are getting
from the states this is haly Hope and
Charlotte web and um the results are
also um very good the second one um is a
recent um trial we did in uh severely
behaviorally changed autistic children
they're not having only the autistic
features but um the the main reason that
we tried this cannabis product uh was um
their behavioral outbreaks that they had
severe outbreaks of some sometimes they
were um aggressive mostly to themselves
so um self aggressive but also to their
um family so they were quite and um uh
we we were using the Cannabis products
which is um CBD THC ratio of 10 to1 and
the doses are up there
um we never go more than 1 milligram per
kg per day um according to the THC um um
do and as you can see the Improvement
was actually perfect in all the 15
children and um there was a lot of um
Improvement in their behavior in in
different
domains um the product was supplied by
pharmahemp um however um when we just uh
finished the study um the drug agency of
Slovenia um prohibited um um the this
company to supply us um and um we did
this way we did a kind of trial of one
study which means that uh each patient
um you asked the parents how it was when
he was receiving the product and how is
it now when he's not receiving and it
was Terri
so the parents were um phoning and
emailing me when the product will be
again available and we do hope it will
be soon and the last one is um the same
product we used um this is cbd2 THC 10
to1 um and the the doses are the same as
for these autistic children never um
going over um 1 milligram per kg per day
and these are for the cerebral policy
children these are the most sever
um
oops something wrong um these are the
most severe um cyber poliy children
those who are um bound to wheelchair um
and um the results are very very much
promising I cannot uh give the final
results because it is part of the PHD
study um of one of our younger
colleagues but um the the the spasticity
is much much less and some of these
children are even sleeping during the
night because they they couldn't sleep
because of this plastic seizures um and
the parents were also um um extremely
satisfied thank
you thank you David very much for this
also for marvelous work what you're
doing with children and how to you know
also help them and help the their
families but uh you said that you had
problems now with
regulatory uh actually with with kind of
nearly
prohibition I may say so in Slovenia the
situation and the restrictions in
regulations are very very very very bad
in terms of our agency ym which is our
public medical agency as well as our
National Institute of Health who all are
which all are um trying to really
restrict even in such a studies that are
so successful and so
effective well yes yes this is true this
is the um drug agency you know from
Slovenia which prohibited this product
uh to be given um further for the
studies and for the treatment actually
we did um clinical study know of this
treatment because they don't have all
they they had these analytic
certificates and I I don't know what the
good good product of growing the
Cannabis and so on but they didn't have
the the GMP they didn't have no this is
the last one uh yes this is the um good
medical product certificate which is
very difficult to be to get it and they
say at this Pham company which is a
Slovenian company that they will get it
may maybe within 2 years uh so um now
because we were um uh um without the
product for the clinical use because we
we wanted to do a short study or short
trial and thereafter to give this
children possibility to be treated
further no so we asked um the um company
abroad if they can bring us um and if
they have GMP product and they said yes
yes we do have it but still we had um
for two months or three months
negotiations with the drug agency it
seems that now now um for a short period
of time they will they will prove
um medical cannabis to be um um imported
to Slovenia so we can go further on we
really have a very difficult situation
and this has to change and that's why
also we are having this meeting here to
try to find the ways to facilitate the
uh the drug use in uh like it is for
example in Israel and how how is then in
Israel with the regulation compared to
let's say Western countries or compared
to Slovenia I guess we use cannabis for
medical purposes in Israel for the last
15 years it is allowed and the
regulation but the regulation is uh
unstable and going to the different
directions I already showed it in my
slides that U uh previously we had a
very good system where each patient uh
will
connected with some particular company
and uh he he has his cannabis uh
prescription each month that uh
permitted him to uh to buy cannabis with
different strains and how each patient
had a CH a chance and a right to choose
which strain is appropriate to him and
to change strains each month it was very
good system and uh it was a some
particular uh funding that each patient
paid by himself but the uh but the price
was the fixed for each each amount of
cannabis that was uh very difficult to
to companies because companies were
forced to subsidize cannabis uh for
patients who had more than 50 gram of
cannabis a month so now they changed the
system and regulation in Israel saying
that each patients and we now have 130
thousand active patients Vis A licenses
so this is the largest in the world
number of the patients treated with the
Cannabis per capita in the world in
Israel now and we so we are still
leading uh in this uh in this point but
uh uh each patient now uh has his
prescription for 6 months or one year
and he is going to the pharmacy and uh
paying much more than he paid before uh
approximate uh price in Israel is about
about 300 Chels so this is about
$70 per 10 GS is it much I don't know is
it uh expensive yes probably yes uh but
our our pay Patients First to pay it but
we have some several groups of patients
uh who subsidized for this uh uh for
this price for example Israeli army
veterans police veterans uh terrorist
acts casualties and uh um also gr also P
people who suffer from the work
accidents car collisions so they have a
insurance paying for for the Cannabis
and also for Visiting Physicians because
now uh cannabis now belongs in Israel to
private sector so um mostly most pres
prescriptions were issued by the private
sector now uh regulation is changing and
it's going slowly from private to Public
Health System and public health system
is UN ready to accept cannabis as a as a
treatment and then is not ready to pay
for it and is not ready to provide
doctor attention to these patients so we
have unstable regulation but the steps
being made by our Parliament and I'm a
senior advisor for our Parliament for
cannabis regulation committee for
cannabis regulation they making good
steps in proper direction so I agree
with them but the system the whole
system should be prepared to the this
and of course I agree with my colleague
that uh doctors should be educated
because majority of Israeli doctors are
standing against any can any kind of use
of cannabis they just do not see
cannabis as a medical uh medical use
they consider to be part of the
addiction uh program for such patients
so so they need to change their mindset
it usually takes more than 10 years uh
me and my friends we try we changed the
general attitudes of uh medical
community a little bit but we it took us
15 years now we when the Cannabis will
go to P from private to public sector we
will need another 15 years uh this is
what I think and uh but you see a good
head and I am optimistic and I wish that
Slovenia will go to the proper direction
learning from our mistakes and building
their own uh proper system that will be
applicable to your to this wonderful
Country and this people thank you well
thank you for this
answer and um education was already
mentioned by borut and what do you think
how should we promote education also to
the medical doctor here I see most of
the problem because they are not
educated they are not aware and they're
not interested so what do you think well
this is a very good point yes well we
tried in the past uh several time first
to start with the M this with the uh
medical professionals and I believe yes
uh particularly young younger generation
that uh they are quite open to this but
let me uh go back I would like like to
recall what um professor nobar said
about a um medical or drug agency uh I
am not player the advocate of these but
you know from the very strict
pharmaceutical point of view uh all kind
of um um components isolated or
synthetic are APS AP means active
pharmaceutical ingredient and they
should fulfill all the criteria in terms
of GMP and so on so on so on but what
the problem is uh very slow reaction
very rigid reaction and our goal here it
is to boost to strengthen the system how
to regulate how to how to allow
regulation but first it is education so
education Hand by hand with the regation
and I believe that this is right time
now otherwise we'll be a member state
with the less regulated system in what I
think we already are we are at the
moment so it's it's way so what do you
think uh also about the students program
medical or your pharmaceutical faculty
they do they learn about that in sure
sure me personally I deliver uh two or
three lcons topics on the can Beno
Andoid system as well as um Professor
tamarak establish an um and sub uh not
only on this uh particular manner I mean
I'm talking about Canabis but in general
one yes and again uh younger generation
it is very open for this and as soon as
we going to have this one or two laws I
am for two laws we have to separate
medical use and recreational use
otherwise they will be a mess so when we
will do that uh with all this kind of uh
regulations and guidelines that would be
open open space well that sounds good
and hopefully we will um go faster than
uh like 15 years because you know we are
I just I I just wonder how you trying to
do it practically I because I'm a
practical physician I'm working with the
patients yeah so my patients coming to
me is asking how how much cannabis I
should use every day and I saying please
try not to exceed than one or two gram a
day according to your prescription so
but for some of them one gram a day it's
not enough and some of them would like
to have a fun so the first uh the first
uh half gram will be uh for medical use
and another half of gram will be for
recreation how you distinguish it please
no this is a real problem that is rising
from medical community they arise such
questions because saying we do not want
to play with a recreational why because
uh people could be addicted but we
should say them that only five to 7% of
people ever could be addicted and they
ever get addicted in each Society about
5 to 7% so we we should not encourage
any kind of addiction and I belong to
very very you know cautious and
responsible doctors I I'm looking for uh
mode of use of cannabis in my patients
because I consider them the safety of my
patients is a upst uh the goal and I do
not uh want them to be addicted but we
should be appreciate also they right not
to so the boundaries between
recreational use and uh strict medical
use are not clear so so yeah if I me IIA
is the same situation with um let's say
all painkillers uh there are limits and
you could be addicted of this of this
some opioids like fentel so who is
responsible for this yeah but okay
so good point but uh what we have to
have in our hand it is standardized
material first standardized material
patience are not standard okay a
personalized approach should be but
about abuse yesterday I heard that it
was a very good party uh there there is
a limit with the alcohol it could be use
or abuse uh so in this case you know
this is again education and tiation of
patient I believe that you tiate your
patient before to have to to to get an
impression of the optimal dose and so on
so on so on there we have devices that
could do instead of us but yes it's it's
an issue it's an issue it's a a personal
approach and how we would personalized
the treatment of the patients is that
the most important thing that who are
the patients because yeah of course but
how do you study that in in Israel we we
have patients that are very very
experienced users and they began that
this topic to be said aloud uh patient
who used cannabis uh and they uh even uh
provide us some education because nobody
educated us from the beginning now I'm
an educator but I educated myself and I
previously was educated by the patients
by the patients who use cannabis for
their medical reasons we so we need to
appreciate this chain who educate the
Educators and who provide us knowledge I
also was uh educated by master master
cannabis master class in cannabis by the
bedan in in Holland but but first my
patients educated me what is bad and
what is good for them and uh my
responsible approach is saying that I
should learn this nature of the each
patients of course possessing the
personalized approach but patients are
so different some of them absolutely
cannabis naive and we should very we
should take very care careful and very
cautious approach to them and some
patients are very very experienced with
different strains of cannabis and they
can't tell you whatever happened with
them when they are taking this one or
other one which we should different
approach to each patience and appreciate
the right to use medical cannabis for
their illnesses without preventing them
but being making it in the very
responsible way this is what I okay
thank you very much uh I think we should
stop here and give also the opportunity
for some question from the audience to
this interesting uh topic uh especially
uh on the uh how should we uh approve
improve the uh the uh the treatment are
this pilot uh studies or are this
actually uh clinical trials like
classical clinical trials or are this
other trials and I would like to uh
maybe sure thank you ask um Dr Cher is
she here that she may have some
yeah can you please talk about that
because you have a lot of experience in
oncological
patients we have a microphone for for
you right here let's hear it again for
the panel right quick while we get it
together very interesting
[Applause]
stuff uh hello yeah uh hello I'm at Cher
I have been working with uh with Dr CH
which is also my grandmother for 10
years in cannabis
research um so I'm not I am also a
doctor but not a practicing clinician
and I would have a question for uh Dr
Resnik uh in Israel when you have the
treatment of patients here I know
there's probably a lot of need to get
further Evidence about the
effectiveness because I would guess
there's also some push back from some
parts of the medical society in regards
to the actual effectiveness of cannabis
and uh I would like to ask are you are
the questionnaires uh uh uh like The
crucial part of following the
effectiveness or is there how do you
monitor the effects and collect the data
of or the effect effectiveness of the
Cannabis in
Israel thank you for the question uh in
Israel each Doctor Who has his practice
uh with the can medical cannabis uh use
his own system it is not standardized
and it's not randomized so my uh my
Approach is quas scientific approach I
use questions like quality of life
questions anxiety questions
questionaries but you see it is very
difficult to apply in the private
practice uh we do not have a govern
government uh adopted medical cannabis
clinics uh this is why in my previous
career I was I was scientific
psychiatrist I was a chief of research
in our Mental Health Center so I use a
lot of questionaries because I am very
familiar with them it is is not over it
is not a practice at all but I'm also
working for some British uh chain of the
medical cannabis clinics and there from
the very beginning we decided we use
questionaries in order to follow up an
outcomes and the results intermediate
results uh from Baseline to uh to
outcome uh so the the this is a very
good point to assess the quality of
treatment that quality of the
intervention using the Cannabis and uh
in late we will could have it as a
publication so we need to derived a good
Knowledge from everyday practice thank
you thank you if there are no question I
would like to actually at last oh you
have a question here uh I'm sorry yeah
his hand raise was so small I
didn't go forther uh I have a question
for all the speakers um what what is
your advice on how to connect the
slovenia's private sector with the
public health and um just to open the
topic thank you maybe you can answer
that well um I'm working in the public
health system so um usually we say that
um prescribing cannabis products is in
the hands of the tertiary care um
institutes that means university medical
centers in Slovenia have two one in Li
public yes one in lublana and one in
maribor and um we we do believe that um
it is better to stay within the public
health system and just to answer M um
well I'm a pediatrician that's why we uh
use questioners for parents now because
the children are too much handicapped
that they can fulfill it we use two one
is the PA SS which means parental
satisfaction score um which is very good
scoring system and very simple and the
other one is uh CGI which is clinical
Global impression CGI e cgii which means
um clinical Global impression
Improvement and at the beginning we give
cgis s which means uh Global um clinical
Global Improvement severity scale so we
just compare the beginning of the
treatment with this severity scale and
um at the end of the treatment let it be
six uh weeks or two months or three
months um the Improvement scale and you
will get very very nice scaling and this
is what what I showed uh like
Improvement now this is this is simple
of course you have others which are much
more complicated but maybe um this is
for for this um practical uh guidelines
it it is enough now to to to to give you
the impression whether it is better or
not so thank you very much I would like
to
conclude uh okay yes well um this the
last question I would not distinguish
between the private and the uh public
health system in terms of treatment in
terms of production something completely
different but what is important is that
individual um MD or the clinic is going
to go through a very uh uh strict
training before and to uniform to have a
a so-called National guideline not like
in Israel but National standardized
guideline in this case it really doesn't
matter that if the patient uh um choose
this or that clear I'm
sorry just one one minute we have a so
we so we have a so-called green book
that was written by by Israeli uh uh
Ministry of Health that this is a book
that uh produced by the clerks for the
clerks it has nothing to learn from them
it is uh speaking about imaginary
patients with about imaginary cannabis
uh uh so they uh they put the name of
Professor late late professor mulam as a
as a chief of the staff of this book and
when I asked him did he read the book he
said never never never never this is the
way so I agree with you that each
country should has its rights to to uh
to use canvas for the medical issues I'm
very sorry that uh providing it to the
clerks of the Ministry of Health it does
not enough because they are not losing
listening to The Experts they are not
listening to the doctors it should be
adopted to be personalized treatment
thank you as you said before so thank
you very much I would like to just
conclude it's not the end because at the
end I would like to present my work
myself and if you can just put
microphone please oh sorry if you can
just uh put this video because what I'm
doing is cancer biology and trying
different cannaboids in cancer and we
are working on two cancers breast cancer
and the glow blastoma and so you can see
the in breast cancer we study the effect
of uh cannabinoid on the
chemotherapeutic effects and there are
either additive effects or there are no
effects and this is very important for
the clinicians to know if they can use
cannabinoids along with the other
chemotherapeutics the goal is that we
will reduce the
chemotherapeutic and concentrations and
instead of that add more cannabinoids or
maybe do not use chemotherapeutics at
all because you all know that
chemotherapeutics are really very very
have very severe adverse effect and my
work on uh our work on G blastoma we are
using fresh organs fresh tissue isues
cells and we are using different types
of cells and spe specifically we found
that the stem cells the origin of the
tumor and the cells cancer stem cells
that are more more resistant to
chemotherapeutics are less resistant to
cannabinoids and this will be shown in
the last video that I'm going to present
and please uh turn on the
video the work was financed by a private
company mgc pharmaceutical from has been
fighting a long battle with one of the
most challenging and fatal diseases of
modern times cancer is still the second
Global cause of death due to Modern
oncology Achievements not all types of
cancer are deadly but some like brain
tumors called glioblastoma are highly
resistant to therapy despite more than
three decades of intense research and
treatment approaches there has been no
improvement in short the survival rate
is about a year and a half on average
National Institute of biology is the
leading Slovenian institution in various
fields of biological sciences including
biomedicine at nib our cancer biology
research team is working hard to break
this grid lock and help finding the new
more efficient way of fighting cancer
our approach is to use combinations
actually a defined combination of
cannabinoids along with standard of care
therapy protocols to treat most deadly
brain tumor Alber stoma and to improve
the survival of patients we believe that
this is possible by our Innovative
experimental approach using fresh
patient derived tissues and cells to
test this new anti-cancer combinatorial
drugs in glioblastoma the researchers at
NIV have been trying to answer the still
open question which is the right
combination of certain cannabinoids and
in what doses to Target abundantly
expressed receptors on the malignant
cell cells this was found to inhibit
glioblastoma and some other cancer cells
Invasion and forcing glioblastoma cells
to die having expertise in tumor cell
manipulation and Analysis we are pleased
to announce new research results from
the ongoing pre-clinical research
program that supports and directs novel
cannabinoid formulations in the
treatment of glioblastoma the most
aggressive and therapeutically resistant
brain tumor the winning combination was
a certain ratio of two cannaboids
canabidol CBD and cannabigerol CBG this
mixture successfully eliminates
glioblastoma stem cells most therapy
resistant subpopulation of glioblastoma
this process is called apoptosis
so-called program cell death this
progress was possible in close excellent
collaboration with neurosurgeons and
oncologists on one hand and partners
from the industry on the other
especially the pharmaceutical company
mgc Pharma a statement from a
representative of mgc Pharma mgc
Pharmaceuticals is a multinational
Pharma company with a focus on the
significant potential of plant-based
medicines with a robust pipeline of
phyto canabo based products these are
designed to tackle neurodegenerative
diseases symptoms of Co 19 and more
where the company places significant
importance on preclinical research and
Drug development our partnership with
nib was one of the most fruitful and the
ongoing preclinical research program
which supports and directs novel
cannabinoid formulations in the
development of cancer treatment that has
been one of the most interesting
projects mgc has been involved in and
one that we believe in deeply further
efforts we explore therapeutic targets
within Goma organoids which are the most
advanced inv vitro cancer model
mimicking the tumors in patients these
recent models are commercially
attractive for the Pharma industry for
drug screening that can lead to more
efficient patient treatment we can offer
a screening platform of 3D cancer models
and we are interested in expanding a
list of candidate compounds for advanced
Goma therapy we're looking forward to
share insight about advances and next
generation of cancer treatment with you
want to collaborate with
us
[Music]
[Applause]
maybe I'll get it
thank you all so very much let's hear it
again that was great very
enlightening