I will introduce the moderate and he'll
take it from there
he is a horticultural scientists court
certified expert and a teacher and he
serves as a director of kin research
please give a warm welcome for mr. Todd
at dalat oh oh thank you so yeah so
cannabis testing for quality control for
safety for potency has been an integral
part of Oregon as well as just about
every other States regulated systems
Oregon did some of the some of the
earliest work on on developing testing
requirements and such and it's been a
long long process of of changing and
adapting to the needs to assure quality
and safety and so so it's been an issue
that's been very intimate to to myself
and we're bringing we got three
panelists here today testing goes a lot
more beyond um testing labs
you know the Oregon farmers farmers are
basically every the whole industry is
downstream from the farmers and so we've
got a farmer Tom Lauer men here to start
to tell us about the you know some of
the cultivation aspects of quality
control and how that eventually goes
downstream to the testing labs we've got
Matt otua from Jefferson packaging and
he takes his business is taking things
from the from the grower to the retailer
providing harvest services drying and
curing and such and then we have a
Wesley McGuire from Pyxis labs and he's
an expert in analytical chemistry in in
one of the one of the biggest labs in
Oregon which actually goes back many
years as an agricultural lab way before
they started testing cannabis so we're
gonna give each of them a few minutes to
to tell us about their perspective on
cultivation and testing then I'm gonna
ask the panel a few questions and then
we'll open it up to you guys ask
questions as well so how about we start
with with farmer Tom hello thanks thanks
for having me as far as a cultivation
goes and pesticides well everybody wants
to be organic so you've really got to
know what your neighbors are doing a lot
of blow over is caused causing problems
in the testing realm you know in America
were pretty more reactive than
preventive as far as testing goes on all
aspects we can start in the food
industry in Japan it's zero parts per
million of any kind of bacteria and in
South Korea it's three parts per million
in Europe it's five parts per million
for the United States it's 5,000 parts
per million so we really have become a
reactive country where it favors the the
growers and the processors and not so
much the consumers so we think we really
need to change that in the cannabis
industry we there change of laws around
the state like Washington State a couple
years ago they were having 30% failures
due to mold so what happened was one of
the lobby groups came in they lobbied
them and now they have zero percent
failure rate so that means that there's
mold out there in the system and what
usually happens in America is a group of
people look at SiC and what they'll do
is they'll go after the processor and
that grower and not really deal with the
bigger picture you know the five
thousand parts per million of any kind
of fecal back to her or any kind of
bacteria
in the end product so we really need to
be more proactive than reactive and I
think that's a great place to start
alright and Matt HOF hey my name is mojo
and Jefferson packing house is my
company we have a fairly unique position
in the market and that we work with a
lot of farms in the area we're down in
Southern Oregon where a lot of our
product comes from and I think 70% of
the producer licenses are within 72
miles of our warehouse and what we see
is kind of the results of everybody's
idea of how to cultivate we we as an
industry for the last 30 40 years the
thing was to be in a vacuum you know
everybody was in their own little silo
doing what they thought best and and it
was really important to not communicate
with other people about what you're
doing and it's a big transition in the
culture of the market to have it all be
out in the open and all be tested and
seen and so you know it's it's going
from everybody's personal view to what's
actually working and so a lot of what
we're sharing with people is it's just
the result side we're seeing that now
it's it's all about unit cost you know
it used to be just produce as much as
you could and as much as you could
produce with me gone and and now it's
really about like cash flow is super
important like are you are you laying
out too much cash for what this market
constructed and constricted and organ
can actually get back to you and so like
as a result a big focus for our model is
helping people with efficiency and
helping people see what really works and
you know it's in one way it's really
awesome to see it all coming through
it's awesome to see the the legal market
happening and it's and it's
it's a really painful market right now
for a lot of people there are tons of
high hopes and dreams everybody thought
they had the secret to success here and
and that might be more true when there's
more opportunity for sales but right now
you have to be really be a tight
operator to function in this market and
yeah I mean I think I think the industry
I was in a sense of kid and you know
pain and difficulty was always a big
part of it I think as we're going
through this transition we're seeing a
lot of the newcomers fall back off
because they're it's they're expecting
it to be something it's not it's not you
know I got a message from a farmer and
straight up saying like can I take over
his farm because he thought it was gonna
be like hanging out on his tractor and
going fishing you know it was never that
like everybody I always knew as a
producer was working hard making a
living and I was kind of always in the
same position as a wholesaler and you
know we we got a ways to go before this
this makes it through and on one on one
side it's really beautiful to see the
community that arises out of difficulty
people come together and people drop a
lot of their resistance to you know
sharing what's going on and so the
beautiful side of it is that people are
supporting each other and I know my
company wouldn't be here without a ton
of grace from last year like we had a
ton of understanding and patience with
us while we went through our growing
pains and uh and I really appreciate
that part of it and I'm glad to be a
part of this thank you
great thanks Matt so Wesley McGuire I
want you to tell us a little bit about
the analytical chemistry side of things
so I've been an analytical chemist for
about ten years doing testing in food
and environmental and agricultural
fields the interesting thing about being
involved in cannabis here in Oregon is
I was just speaking to a colleague
outside before we came in here this is
the first time that I have been involved
in a testing market where you're
required to test for all of these
parameters cannabis growers and
producers are required to test for
potency for pesticides for residual
solvents in their extracts and so on and
well I think this is really good I think
that there are times when it puts a in
order to no amount of pressure on small
cannabis businesses and I wouldn't
advocate for that to be changed but as a
comparison if you look at the the food
industry nationally FDA sets standards
or rather EPA sets tolerances for what
what residues are allowed on crops and
FDA enforces them
no one's required to do that testing but
anyone could be liable and that creates
a pressure that you know pushes testing
in the interest of not only
self-preservation for those companies
but in the interest of public health and
I definitely want to give props to
farmer Tom for bringing up that public
health aspect because it's a it's an
important passion of mine which is that
I think that we should really be
focusing our regulatory and our testing
efforts on things which could present a
health threat to the consumers of this
product now interesting thing about
cannabis different from other
consumables is that many cannabis users
are medical patients this is not simply
a consumable that people are using
recreationally although that has
definitely driven a lot of this market
but people with sometimes compromised
immune systems they may be cancer
patients undergoing chemotherapy using
cannabis products to help medicate their
nausea
they could be people suffering hiv/aids
and using cannabis because of the
anti-inflammatory benefits and the
benefits that they see for their immune
system response were to counteract the
effects of harsh medication these are
people that really cannot Brook
additional threats to their health in
the form of toxic residues and so I
think in some ways organ has set
themselves up to go above and beyond
what other industries do require for
testing but in some ways we also have a
long way to go in Oregon in particular
we have a list of 59 pesticides that we
test for residues and they were selected
based on known use and based on
potential health effects but at the same
time there are a thousand pesticide
products available out there and more
and and routine testing in the food
world often incorporates hundreds of
pesticides into their resident tests so
it begs the question once we know that
there is a static list required for
testing you know are there because of
these economic pressures in the oregon
rket are there unscrupulous growers or
producers out there that are using
products that you know they know aren't
being tested for I've done some research
in this area and and I found the results
kind of interesting but the one thing
that I would say is that we have the
capacity and the analytical capability
to test for more residues and to ensure
that our product is cleaner and safer
for consumers and patients alike and I
try to advocate for that I try to
advocate for even in the absence of
regulation for us to go above and beyond
and demonstrate that we are providing a
safe product especially for people who
may be using it but dissing alee
good thank you so much so I'm gonna ask
the panel a few questions and so in the
meantime why don't you guys think of a
few questions yourself because you'll
have the opportunity to ask them as well
so starting with with farmer Tom you
know this last 10 years or so we've seen
probably the largest scaling up of
canvas grow cannabis grow operations you
know we started you know maybe 10 years
ago a lot of people had you know a 100
or 200 plants with people going barefoot
and making love to every single plant
not wearing rubber gloves or hair nets
or even lab testing and now we're
building multi-million dollar facilities
you know with a lot of standard
operating procedures and so can you tell
us a little bit about some aspects of
scaling up that's important for growers
to pay attention to that that we may not
have realized from the way we did things
ten years ago well there's so much
recording that needs to go on for the
oil CC and the different you know
government agencies that that takes up a
huge amount of time and then there's the
taxes that they have to worry about and
then there's the employee and the
employee unemployment and all these
different taxes and regulations and the
small farmers really been burdened with
the ton of that stuff and like these
guys are most of us we're just good guys
who love the earth and who loved a girl
good cannabis and have a good product so
much of us really don't know anything
about about scaling up you know right
now we're in a corporate world and the
the mom-and-pop small farmers are going
to be following up I mean you know like
they said they're gonna lose 80 to 90
percent of them here in the state of
Oregon you know over the next few years
you know that's why they're working on
out of state Commerce and and these
types of things and and they'll help you
as far as the small farmer goes and
scaling up you know you really can't do
things like you did in your closet you
really need somebody there
you need a bunch of different extra
people there you need somebody who's
gonna do inventory control and take care
of all the tagging of all the plants and
and all this stuff and they really need
a large workforce and it's really super
hard for them right now since the price
is driven down so low I know a lot of
farmers are paying their employees out
of their pockets and they can only do
that so long so scaling up you know
start off with what you know you can
sell and and just continue and continue
down that road I think in the end of the
day here and in Oregon and in California
it's not going to be so much the small
farmers we're gonna have a handful of
craft organic farmers throughout the
state it'll be you know in Eugene you
know and then down it's in Southern
Oregon and kind of what I suggest is you
know we need historical centers we need
some young guy to go out there and
document the last 40 years of cannabis
growth in these industries areas and
then I see you know because content is
king
so we get somebody out there documenting
all these video documenting all these
have a place where people can land
broadcast of wide over social media
across the country then you've got a
place for people to to land and to come
and visit the historical centers of
cannabis here in Oregon and California
and I think that's the way it's gonna go
because all we have to do is look at
cut flower industry used to go from here
the Willamette Valley all the way to
Mexico the Tijuana border and they're
not here anymore
they all went to Colombia Bolivia and
you can guarantee that's where cannabis
cultivation is going it's only going to
be here in the States until they open it
up internationally and then the whole
ball is chant the game has changed and
it's a whole different world and we're
right in that position now where we see
big money coming in from Canada the
corporate world everybody's getting
excited they're doing a lot of buyouts
in California of small companies and a
lot of these companies will do pretty
good its own for five or ten million
dollars I mean they'll be able to retire
but their dream of you know being on
national brand and taking their product
all the way is gonna be a lot but a lot
more difficult path so my suggestion to
Oregon and California is to create this
historical centers have tourism wrapped
around it learn about all the the oh
geez who you know paved the way so we
can all be in this industry
bring them have them out of the darkness
and into the light documented create a
historical place where people around the
world I've spent a lot of time in Europe
and these Europeans will eat this stuff
up they will travel from all over the
world to go to Williams or to go to
Eugene and to learn about the history of
cannabis and how we all got here so it's
it's gonna be a tough path where all
your small farmers out there
I see diverse yourself building it brand
you know and it's tough for a farmer
because a farmer's job is 365 days a
year
and there usually aren't days off and
you really don't have that much time to
go out and do branding and marketing and
all the other things that go along with
creating a realist
very good nobody can do it alone huh
that's right so I really love the
California model they've all grown
grouped up into like collective gardens
for these little micro regions down
there the terroirs and I see that being
a huge but a benefit to California
because they were able to keep the small
farmers in the play funnel it through
one processing facility and then it goes
out on one brand see it look at the
California I mean the hub old son
growers guilt they've got true humble
they've got like 250 farms that feed
this machine and they were able to keep
the state plenty in good humble cannabis
so tea bad Washington Oregon and
Colorado we didn't really think too far
ahead you know it's kind of the Wild
West out here we're all you know
individuals pulling themselves up by
their bootstraps that kind of stuff so
yeah good example thank you very much
tom yeah good I wanted to ask Matt you
know businesses like yours serve a lot
of different producers and and so one
you know issue that comes up is
cross-contamination you know maybe you
know client a you know process it you
know you process something for client a
has some residual contaminants on it can
affect client be nos you have the
protocols to mitigate that so can you
just tell us real briefly just some of
the protocols that are necessary for for
preventing cross-contamination yeah
going into the business model we had a
lot of questions like is if some mold
comes in on one plan is that gonna
spread everywhere else the the
infrastructure in systems in the in
place have a lot to do with it
a lot of like your mold and everything
grows in the right conditions so our our
system is to control the temperature
keep a lot of air flow up one of the
main things that I see is just
overcrowding a product and so one of the
big things we did is leave leave a lot
of extra space in our warehouse there's
which gives access to everything and you
can monitor everything see what's going
on but we really didn't have the issues
everybody was afraid of I mean we never
had mold go nuts and we never had you
know of course you have to clean up your
equipment between jobs you you always
want to do that anyway aside from just
keeping things clean and tidy and making
sure that good good yeah before we open
things up to to the audience hope you're
thinking of some good questions for our
panelists Wesley is there any aspects of
testing that that are often overlooked
in the industry or that you would like
to see either voluntary testing or or
required well in the u.s. cannabis
testing regulations vary quite a bit
state to state now there are states
which have copied the regulations that
other states have put into place and I
think everyone is striving to reach a
best practices but I think there are
some holes one of them I mentioned a
little bit earlier which is I think that
our scheme for pesticide testing is
nowhere near expansive enough
particularly as farmer Tom mentioned
everybody wants to be organic right in
the cannabis world we would love to
believe that our product that we produce
or consume is clean and healthy and
natural but the only way to know that is
to test and when we do organic testing
on other commodities we do much more
expansive testing than what's currently
required so I would like to see whether
it's driven by regulation or by
the industry leader is wanting to
demonstrate that their products are
cleaner than the competition I'd like to
see expanded testing in that regard
in the same vein organ does not have any
requirements for testing of mycotoxins
which are the toxic metabolites left
behind by certain mold and fungus
species in my opinion I don't think that
the states that are doing mycotoxins
testing are looking at the right
mycotoxins but that may be a discussion
that's a little bit longer than we have
time for here today but I think
mycotoxins testing is important I also
think that heavy metals testing is
important cannabis and hemp are known
bioremediation 8 all sorts of things
from the soil that they're grown in and
from their environment and heavy metals
testing I think is an area of concern
that we should be focusing on
particularly with all of these things
when you take a plant and you
concentrate it into an extract all of
these potentially toxic elements come
along with it so since we're using this
stuff frequently for recreation and as
well as for medicating ourselves I think
we owe it to ourselves and to the
consumers and patients to make sure that
it's as safe as possible
great thank you thank you and yeah you
know as a horticultural starting to run
out a little bit of time now you want to
take questions we're getting very good
indeed we're yep we're right there yeah
as a horticultural scientist I also have
a great desire to see a lot of you know
we've nutrient analysis soil nutrient
analysis microbial biomass and such just
to throw it out there anyway um yeah
it's time I hope you guys got some good
questions for a panelist and guy who's
got the mic let's hear for the panel one
more time
anyone have any questions once again you
guys are so thorough or everybody's so
stoned full of ice cream yeah there's a
question over here okay here I come I
thank you all for your thoughts and I
think the question might be directed at
Wesley I appreciate your comments on
expanding the pesticide list and maybe
looking at additional contaminants are
there any ways that you would see that I
guess what would the cost implications
beyond that you know looking at the
batch size of 15 pounds in Oregon a 55
50-pound batch in California it would
representative sampling allow us to
maybe enhance enlarge the batch size and
then you know be able to have additional
analytes or are there other ways that
you would anybody on the panel see as a
creative way to expand the testing but
also keep cost the same or reduce it by
either expanding the badge or moving a
duplicated so on and so forth
well I think that's a really relevant
question and as both Matt and Tom
touched on because of the way the market
and organ has developed it puts a lot of
pressure on growers particularly small
growers to try to be profitable and to
try to stay in business and the more
testing that we do you know testing is
not cheap yes the pricing of testing is
being driven down but at the same time
there is a certain level of expertise
expensive instrumentation and facilities
that need to be maintained and and
there's a point past which labs can't
lower their prices any further I do
think that you may be on the right track
in terms of lot size I think
the 15-pound lot makes sense from
perspective of small batch grower but
from the perspective of industry so I'm
not sure what the right approach is from
a regulatory side to limit that cost
however I do know that the that better
testing services are available for those
who want to be conscientious about the
safety of their product and and I think
that if you build a good relationship
with a laboratory they can do a lot to
work with you on pricing we don't have a
whole lot of control over the
regulations that specify how much of
each lot needs to be tested but I think
if you compare cannabis to other
industries that 15-pound lot size may
need to be reconsidered I also think
that the state tax system should pick a
part of the testing bill for sure
because you really can't pour all of
this responsibility onto the farmer I
think that they should be using the tax
dollars that they generate to help
subsidize the testing that's needed to
keep the public safe really quickly to
add to that I would say again in
comparison to food it's not just the
growers that are testing distributors
tests retailers tests and ultimately the
the job of policing and enforcing
potentially toxic residues is on the
regulatory agency
so what farmer Tong saying is not
without merit
you know if we want in Oregon or
elsewhere to know that we are
distributing clean product organs it
bears some responsibility my question is
about laboratory testing and how there
is a lack of oversight and
I believe this cannabis Commission in
Oregon is talking about creating a
laboratory that would oversee the or lap
labs how do you guys feel about that do
you feel like there's a real need for
that I absolutely feel like there is a
need for that and I wish that we had
more than a minute and a half to talk
about it because it's something I'm very
passionate about there are a number of
laboratories in Oregon that were
basically built entirely to service the
cannabis industry in the last couple of
years my lab is not one of them we've
been doing food and environmental
testing for a long time but one of the
things that makes it really hard for
labs like that to compete is that they
are dependent on cannabis business in
order to keep their doors open and what
that means is that when they are
pressured by sometimes big and lucrative
cannabis business to give to deliver the
numbers that seem favorable they may be
required to fold and Bend to that and I
think that compromises our scientific
ethics and I think the only real
solution for that is oversight now or
lap is supposed to be delivering that
oversight for organs cannabis
laboratories but they're spread way too
thin and one of the results of this is
that laboratories are unfairly pressured
to compete on potency numbers and there
is an ongoing issue in Oregon with a
pretty rampant potency fraud since those
THC numbers do drive sales I think
education of all levels of the market of
the industry is going to help with that
educating consumers educating business
owners even educating regulators to a
certain extent but oversight of the
laboratories and making sure that we're
committed to quality data systems is
absolutely essential for all of us to
keep doing what we're doing and
delivering safe and healthy products
good all right well thank you so much
for being a great audience with great
questions and thank our panelists
for sharing with us and don't forget to
get up and breathe and stretch a little
bit or something I like to see healthy
people here and remember when it comes
to quality control and prevention and
ounce of prevention 's grows a pound to
cure nice one more time for the panel
and the panelists
[Applause]