well the panelists are entering the
stage I want to thank you for coming to
our extraction panel and may introduce
to you David LaRussa from sales director
from ethics hey David
then we have bins I know we have we have
Zack is from SL a companies then we have
P Pettersen from Vitelli extraction hi
Pete at last what the LeaseWeb mikemaya
from lab Society in California hi Mike
and before I introduce the panelists in
detail to you I want to a give a short
overview what we're going to talk about
now in the panel before you had a lot
about extracts you're at a lot about
standardization we have a very specific
problem here in Germany because the
whole plant extracts did not reach our
pharmacist yet what we have in the
pharmacies is does a modern one we call
it mono substances which is a drawer
nominal which is a mono substance and as
it was mentioned before we have Sativex
and we have just one whole plant extract
which is very new in the pharmacies or
now it's two offered by a Canadian
importer by a Canadian producer but
except that only private persons know
anything about extraction there is the
knowledge within the cannabis industry
here the extraction knowledge is not
very widespread and so far different
from the US and from Canada it's on a
very private level which gives which
makes a big problem when it comes to
through the medical use of extracts a
lot of patients know better than their
doctors and know better than their
pharmacists because they know the
extracts from the private from from the
black market or from extracting the
medical weed they get privately I know a
lot of people privately who do make for
example who extract their bedrock on
cannabis make a whole plant extraction
because this is not offered in the
pharmacy and they
only can get that strain that
specifically trained in the form of bats
and if you need an extraction you have
to do it on a private on a private level
so I'm very proud to present you five
expert four experts on extraction any of
them using a different approach to
extract medical cannabis and I'm a
little sorry if I used to have to read
that I have to use my crib because I had
a second I have two panels today and to
introduce anybody as he deserves I do
have to use microwave I'm so I want to
start with a David and David love itself
director epic super critical a leading
seals co2 extraction manufacturer based
in Ohio
Dave directs the sales team at epics
help streamline and implement processes
to help improve the customers experience
and as we talked in the green room
before the meeting here before the panel
you cannot you don't have products in
your state yet but you're actually
focusing on producing or on the other
technique behind it and my first
question goes out to you and your
companies specialize in focus on
developing supercritical co2 technology
on an industrial level and a lot of
especially in Germany we're not so
experienced with extraction can you
maybe give a short overview what is Z or
to extraction how does it differ from
the alt place of instruction we know so
far so co2 extraction is the extraction
using co2 solvent taking co2 from a gas
to liquid at high pressures thus
extracting the oils the waxes and the
lipids and then removing those from the
actual plant material at Apex we focus
on introductory systems but also
scalable to industrial size and with our
systems we actually operate them on the
same platform so as customers scale
their business and grow their business
it's it's an easy transition from going
from a introductory system
to a medium system to the large system
so as a producer of extraction
technology you don't only you have a
bigger overview what's going on so how
did the demand for cannabis extracts
develop in the US and the Canadian
market within the last year's so the
obviously I started off on the west and
with the demand for cannabis and hemp
actually and II was approached by the
select customers and they wanted another
method of actually extracting through a
cleaner purer process which would then
ultimately reduce the amount of post
processing time and refining it and to
come back to what I said in the
beginning this is also a technique you
cannot use on private and small level is
that true correct and which is very
different from your technology attack
isn't it and let me introduce that first
Zak is based based in California and
he's the VP of frozen tech for their
products a California based industry
leading solvent liske extraction company
solvent list what does that mean solve
alice is just heat and pressure so we do
rosin presses rosin tech products and
you take your flour or your dry sift
your ice water hash and you are setting
your temperature your time putting your
material in a filter bag within the
parchment paper and then you're pressing
for about 30 to 60 seconds and you're
getting your solvent les hash oil or
your rosin so with with the rosin it's
full-spectrum and it's just a matter of
taking your material and then whether
you're whether you're doing co2 or
you're doing BHO you're always using a
solvent with solvent lists you don't
have to worry about that at all and when
it comes to the medical team and yet in
Germany this honey technique is act
unknown when it comes to medical
production what about your home yes so
with rosin it's very affordable
in terms of extraction it's very easy to
get started and Germany to actually is
one of our largest countries that we
sell rosin presses to a lot of patients
want to be able to make their oil and
it's very easy and a rosin press is
pretty small so you can keep it on your
counter and you know as as it basically
rosin started about ten years ago maybe
even a little bit longer
people started with hair straighteners
and now we've developed presses that are
just a little bit more pressure but that
allow you to get the oil with less time
under the heat which allows for greater
terpene and retention
so with rosin you get a really tasty end
product that with ice water hash is some
of the best oil out there on the market
ice water hash would be washing your
material putting it a freeze dryer and
then pressing it and getting her ice
water has frozen okay and this is also a
technique patients can use and they're
very small very small scale lookup thing
yeah you can do it's a it's pretty it's
pretty much a connoisseur product out
there but we do work with a lot of
processors all over the world who who
are attracted to the idea of doing
solvent list like when you go into a
supermarket now and you look at your
shopping cart everything's organic with
solvent lists and consumers and patients
are excited about the idea of having a
clean tasty turkey end product okay Pete
it's great to have you here you found it
Vitalis extraction technology back in
2016 and before you have 15 years of
experience in varying industries in
legal or retail manufacturing in
healthcare and when I did some research
on your homepage I found the following
before opening the doors on what what
become the leading manufacturer of an
industrial sized tube material
critical co2 extraction systems three
partners three partners who went out to
extract us and asked wherever that very
question the answer took them on two
year journey of research ideation and
development men may ask you to mention
the cornerstones of the answers you
found this is a sport there we go
so I came out of the private equity side
I don't know if we have anybody from the
finance world in here anybody interested
I guess everybody's interested in
extraction that's why you're sitting
here today I was a customer buying these
systems we looked at the space we want
to build just big gigantic machines is
kind of the approach that we took and
when we looked at so the determining
factors for these systems there's a lot
of information that's out there there's
you know with the APEC systems and Eden
and precision and all sorts of different
types of extraction we tried to say okay
how can we normalize that a little bit
and make it a little bit more
understandable so we looked at just the
pillars of extraction being temperature
pressure and flow over a certain amount
of time right so temperature and
pressures you can vary those depending
on the type of output that you want and
then increasing or decreasing your flow
rate so the amount of solvent that
you're adding to the equation to again
get a different type of result so our
talk track our acid bases of extraction
basis of research and design has been
around temperature pressure and flow and
in order to decrease the amount of time
that it takes to facilitate the
extraction and your company announced
the cooperation with America's CBD a
very because CBD oil producer and
despite hand farming in the USA is more
an exception than a rule and you can
produce on a a very large amounts and
how come and you explain big flow big
systems big vessels you guys are
probably seeing it as well I would
imagine since the the farm bill just
passed in December in the US that has
created a monster demand on the say CBD
extraction side of it
and we're also seeing that across Europe
right now CBD is becoming far more
popularized it seems to happen in tandem
when cannabis or marijuana is being
discussed and all of a sudden CBD is
just his brought up along the way even
though it's been available for quite a
period of time there's hundreds of
products as we've seen by a number of
different panelists there's hundreds of
products already in the industry yeah
really just when our customers
approached us especially with these
large hemp systems are looking for large
volume they're looking for just clean
efficient extraction processes and
that's that's really what's allowed us
to service that that side of the market
pretty significantly how would you
describe the ratio between CBD the
demand for CBD and THC so your personal
experience from a company so right now
I'd say 40 percent of my customer base
is extracting from him and they're lying
the the much larger systems so we call
it the our 200 which is a hundred liter
extraction vessel and some of them will
stack you know three or four or five of
those side by side by side to be doing
you know a couple a couple thousand
kilos a day of hemp extraction oh thank
you thank you very much now I come to
our fourth toe of hot expert we he is
representing an other a technology
another method to make extraction
Michael is my Roth has graduated in
environmental chemistry and has been has
served his passion for developing kind
of a specific level laboratory equipment
into a multi-million dollar company and
yeah congratulations for that
and despite ease of quite young age he
already found it yeah a lot of companies
and the your recent project is for
focusing on short path distillation and
how does that differ from the techniques
we we've had from so far and may I ask
you to explain that short path
distillation sure so um short path
distillation really is actually a method
of refinement so it actually works
really cohesively with all the
extraction methods that
discussed here today as well as other
methods of solvent extraction the nice
thing about distillation is that you can
essentially render any substance any
sort of extract solvent free in the end
which is great especially for
large-scale processing procedures so
through the distillation process we're
using heat and vacuum specifically deep
vacuum to lower the boiling point of
cannabinoids since they're typically
very viscous and very heavy so in order
to boil them off we lower our boiling
point using vacuum and then from there
we can use fractional columns or wiped
film distillation stills on the
continuous side especially with that
like Pete was saying with the farm bill
the scale has jumped tremendously we
started off with small units that we're
doing you know 1/2 kilo - you know our
largest small-scale system does about 12
kilos per batch to a system that does 10
to 20 kilos per our feed rate so
obviously it's a substantial difference
and then from there we're also looking
to scale from 50 to 200 kilos per hour
so we're talking about much larger
systems but the the true benefit to
distillation is the creation of a
standardized product so through product
development you know I believe in the
last talk they were mentioning that
there's just so many different
cannabinoids there's so much that we
need to know from the plant a nice thing
about distillation is that we can render
a cannabis extract that normally would
have terpenes and all these other things
in it we can render it as a sole
cannabinoid fraction which will have all
the candles present in the initial
strain the initial phenotype typical
expression of that plant and then from
there we can reintroduce terpenes and
other flavonoids and other compounds to
actually create an extract or a medicine
that is more directed towards a specific
illness the other great thing about this
delation is that you can work from a
distillate into isolates and using
isolates obviously there's some bad
connotation to that with depending on
what you're talking to on the medical
side which I completely agree with the
entourage effect is definitively a real
thing but the benefit of distillation is
that you can start with a very pure
product prior to these processes what
leads me to my next question because
done is started ization is a very very
important thing as we heard before if a
german patient enters a pharmacy and he
wants to have an extract he only
get to know the CBD and the THC content
that's all is your company able to
produce a whole spectrum a profile
absolutely so we we don't specifically
produce the products obviously we help
manufacturers and and prod and consumers
well really and processors produce
products for end consumers that would
have a wide spectrum of different
products the biggest issue right now I
think especially in America is just the
lack of standardization of process and
the analytical side so as a company
we've kind of pivoted towards analytics
standardization processing just really
trying to dial in our SOPs not only for
the GMP side but also for just the
analytical side there's a wide spectrum
of cannabinoids that all should be
recognized in medicines not only that
but the residuals solvent the pesticide
content the heavy metal content all
these things are really important for a
patient because if you're gonna say hey
this is a medicine well you know it
better be treated as such and in the
medical world these things are all
extremely important Dave let me ask you
a another question about standardization
your state you're coming from Ohio is
just in the phases of regulation you're
just regulating the medical cannabis
market correct and how important is
standardization for your company how
important is it without authorities for
the dialogue without authorities so it's
really important so one from the APEC
side selling the equipment we want to
make sure that we put the equipment in
the customers hands but they're getting
the right equipment so understanding the
standardization understanding of
regulations you know in the States right
now because it is federally illegal for
cannabis but states are legalizing it
they're making their own rules so we're
kind of taking a shot at the dark to
find out okay what rules can we follow
what rules do we have to abide by so the
idea of a standardization process will
help us you know provide the right
equipment to the customer and what would
you say if you look at the German
regulation system and compare it to the
American to the US regulation system in
Germany we have
good standardization but we don't have
any products in the u.s. the
standardization is not perfect but you
have products what is better in the end
what what do you say I think that the
standardization first and foremost then
this way we can follow the regulations
and then this way is it's consistent
across the board versus having variables
in different regions if I may add to
that being in Canada we've seen a little
bit of a mix between what's happening in
the European market as this market
evolves and then seeing on the US side
of things where you really estate by
state by state it's opening up how do we
approach this you know what levels of
standardization must be reached and then
in Canada because the Canadian market
really wants to reach into Europe and
start to sell there we was seeing kind
of a little bit of a hybrid model I can
tell you every single time I come over
to Europe I'm always impressed with the
the people that I sit down the customers
that were we're chatting with and
discussing extraction with it's not a
cowboy approach by any means of bringing
pharmaceutical experience to the table
and so they're asking questions about
GMP they're asking questions about
equipment certification with be IDI
they're making sure that you know
they're asking stuff about IQ &amp; oq and
PQ so installation qualifications
operational qualifications performance
qualifications and making sure that
their equipments gonna pass the stages
of the standardizations that your German
auditors are going to require to not
only make that medicine but to operate
the equipment that's going to make that
medicine at a standard level so
understanding what the what's
requirement to the European side of
things you the Europeans and some of the
Canadians were in the room and us in the
room but really the Europeans are
stepping up that level of same
manufacturing and that level of
compliance that the globe is now looking
to so it's really impressive to see
what's going on over here I'm when my
last next question goes out to expert on
the Canadian market as you maybe know we
have I think meanwhile 25 different
cannabis French and the pharmacy but
only one
all plant extraction from Canada so far
or not - why is that so it's just it's
just the like in Germany it's it's the
German regulations and the German laws
we typically see regulations start
wherever it may be it's the same thing
in the US when it starts state by state
by state and Canada started the same way
we start with flour it's easy to
understand it's easy to cultivate and
it's a Minimum Viable Product and so
that's introduced to the market first
and then from there you get some pretty
basic extracts if you look at the
Canadian extra action market the most
popularized ones are these little
tinctures where you have you know three
percent THC or three percent
cannabinoids and then the rest is
coconut oil or propylene glycol so the
patient in Canada actually has to
consume a lot of fluid to get they can't
have but knowing that they're looking
for however you know in a little bit
more of a conservative even we have a
liberal government and a little bit more
of a conservative society it is an
approach it's a step to administering
that medical cannabis and then we'll
start to see in Canada we'll start to
see that portfolio of extracts evolved a
little bit further but because it's
government lead it's federally led it's
very slow and it's very conservative and
Romney we say or some people complain
government is over-regulating the
medical cannabis law would you say huh
cannot us I mean yeah I'm not regulating
it no how can it is over regulating it
if there's any LPS in the room you guys
would also nod your heads there's a
heavy of a regulation however they are
commissioning committees and basically
public opinion to try to understand what
the public does want to see from that
component and also Health Canada I've
seen and and seen some of the Health
Canada regulators and representatives go
down to the US and go down to Colorado
California Washington Oregon for example
are some say some very established
states when it comes to the medical and
recreational markets to talk to them
about different products that have been
released it may be on the side where
maybe the US isn't regulated enough in
terms of you know some of the extracts
that may be allowed you can have a gummy
bear in the US that has a thousand
milligrams of THC if you eat that you're
you're on your ass for two days it's
so it's it's it's a conservative
approach as a patient I don't I to be
completely honest I never I've never
rolled a joint my entire life so edibles
were also scary to me I didn't know like
if I had one when was it going to kick
in what was it going to be like and
that's that's very normal for people
that don't consume cannabis and so
having a small approach a conservative
approach I think is going to build that
trust within that consumer brand or the
consumer market Zac when it comes to
consumer trust to building a brand and
we have seen that the other kind of
extractions are already available
somehow here on our market you're Roslyn
tech is I've seen it in Spanish social
clubs a lot meanwhile so that's a really
small revolution going on but actually
your product is not in the pharmacies
yet and it's not on the market here yet
so how do you see that what's the future
of frozen tech or frozen extraction in
Europe yes so overall right now it is on
the end consumer side and in the
cannabis clubs we're seeing a lot of
clubs in you know in Spain but also
interests in the Netherlands and other
places but we are seeing a lot of like
originally when we were getting started
in Europe about two years ago it was the
patient's reaching out patients you know
a stage four cancer looking to for an
affordable weight and get their oil
would contact us and and you know and
then tell their friends and that's kind
of how we got our start in Europe and I
think you know going forward rosin has a
very affordable way almost like having a
you know a juicer in your kitchen or
something like that that's how I
envision you know rosin in the future
for Europe being really popular for the
end consumers but also you know as we
head more towards the recreational side
in Europe down the road I hope to have
the salt and less experience like we do
in the US where you can bring your flour
well press for you for free and it's
just all out in the open and
all about education so yeah I think I
think down the road you're gonna start
to see more shows where you know there's
more pressing going on and people
bringing their buds and you educate them
whether it's CBD flower or with THC
yeah I've seen in it I've seen it the
envelope in Barcelona their father was
one booth this year I think they were
horrified Buddhism they were all crowded
and my last question because time is
really pushing us goes out to Mike we
never talked about terpene extraction so
far Mike and but terpene is also
something you can extract it's not only
caliber Nuits you also connect structure
pins well tell us something about that
please so terpenes obviously the boiling
point is going to be very different than
that of cannabinoids they're gonna the
reason that you smell them is because
they're boiling off they're you know
they're volatile so the extraction
methodology for that believe it or not
co2 actually is a fantastic way to
extract the terpenes I've seen some
extremely good terpene products come
from co2 extractors I would say that
equipment on scale which is really what
my business is focused towards is
difficult because when you start to talk
about terpene extraction at scale you're
involving heat you're involving pressure
which changes the actual terpene
structure itself so at that point it's
really a question of what scale who's
who's actually manufacturing this
terpenes and they are a very viable
product they also have medicinal aspects
to them and they I would say that
terpenes plus cannabinoids are really
the key to the the medicine itself but
as far as the extraction methodology
goes I would say the best extraction
techniques for getting the terpenes
would be co2 hydro carbon and actual
steam slash vacuum distillation
themselves
thank you very much I'd really really
like to go a lot to depend to the
materia but time is pushing so hard so
sorry let's hear it again for the panel
I do have one quick question
just because you mentioned the terpene
extraction and I've seen a lot of new
companies who specialize in terpenes but
they're not cannabis derived terpenes
they're like artificially not
artificially but creative they get
terpenes from somewhere other than the
cannabis plant are they the same is that
the same thing is it different or the
molecules different that's a fantastic
question the cool thing about cannabis
is that it has an array of terpenes
honestly to the for analytics on that
side we really have trouble determining
which terpenes are in the actual plant
because there's so many I mean there's
hundreds there might even be some that
are unique to the plant itself but what
you're discussing is that yes absolutely
they are the same molecules rosehips
orange peels eucalyptol eucalyptus
pretty much any plant that has a good
smell those terpenes may be found in
cannabis so what a lot of companies are
doing is they're taking extracts from
other plants that can be done at a much
larger scale efficiently mixing them
together to mix or to mimic Turkey and
sure clothes from smell the same it
tastes the same but will they have the
same effect that's that's the question
right so when you actually look at the
profiles on cannabis there's so many
small amounts of these terpenes that you
can't really get from other plants that
one in conjunction with each other they
make different effects so it's really
hard to say it's a really great field of
study I think that's gonna be something
that we really need to as an industry
push towards thank you thank you all
very very much I really appreciate it
let's hear it again for our panel very
informative