[Music]
[Applause]
and jim
belushi there he is
[Music]
i just won't make love to you
hello
how are you
i like this
yeah i'm making chocolate
blue's brother's chocolate right here
bang
it's cool
how you doing man
welcome mr villarreal jim belushi please
uh warm applause again
okay i think everybody of uh
you knows mr belushi he's a famous actor
hollywood from california
um
playing in films like whack the dog he
was he's a member of the book so you
picked the film that i had the smallest
part in
yeah but i liked the dog it was
exactly um
but uh you also so easy to make fun of
i'm so sorry please forgive me
but actually i first knew as a member of
the blues weather band
yes
i'm a member of the blues brothers
and which is uh from your brother it's
kind of your brother was a was a kind of
my brother was the original blues
brother with dan aykroyd they did in
1979 1980.
they started on saturday night live
and
it's just one of the most beautiful
movies it was actually
probably the first
music videos
because all those little
vignettes in the movie where they were
doing songs were essentially music
videos
and uh also it was probably one of the
most diverse films
uh made at that time
so yes the blues brothers it's a great
film
but at that time as you told me before
you were not involved in the in the
show business at all and that started no
i was i was involved in show business
yes absolutely
in 1976 i was at the theater
called the second city in chicago and
before that i was in college
and is there another interview going on
over here
oh i just heard somebody talking i just
want to make sure i heard their answer
[Music]
it must have been interesting
anyway
so in 1976 i was in the second city
improvisational theater
and then
see 1980 i did a movie
called thief with james kahn
michael mann directed was his first film
and at the same time i think john and
danny were doing the blues brothers
and
how come that you are a member of the
blues brothers band then is that any
anything to do with danny did he involve
you later on well yeah you know it's
funny because i i you know i had kind of
a separate career from john
you know uh separate but together
because john was originally in second
city and i went there when i was 16 and
i saw john and i thought
wow
this place is magic
and so
the next four years
i was like
i've got to be in second city so i went
to second city and learned to improvise
and john was doing saturday night live
and he was
famous for
you know cheeseburger cheeseburger the
samurai
the blues brothers
and so i was a fan you know like you
were you know i mean they were so great
on saturday night live and the blues
brothers was such an amazing film
and then john passed
and then in 1992
maybe three
dan aykroyd wanted me to join the blues
brothers with him
and i said danny i can't i can't do that
you know that was you and john i i got a
separate
kind of thing going on
and he said oh absolutely not jimmy it's
like a law firm you know when uh when
the partner passes away the son or the
brother or uh
cousin comes up and takes over the role
and i went no danny danny no that was
john and you it would be really strange
for me to do the blues brothers
absolutely not jimmy it's one of the
classic parts of it made it it'll keep
the legacy of jake blues alive keep the
legacy of the american folk music
library alive keep the spirit of the
mission of god alive you must become a
blues brother and i said danny
i can't do john he goes no you wouldn't
do jake blues you'll do you'll do
you'll do brother z brother zurich
we'll call you brother z you'll be
you'll be the lost albanian brother lost
in the caves of southern albania and i
will search for you and find you and
bring you into the blues brother's band
and i go you don't think it's weird
and he said i'm not at all jimmy you
belong as a blues brother there's only
one brother that can play a blues
brother that's you jimmy belushi brother
sir china brother z
well if you don't feel weird about it
danny i don't feel weird about it
so i started doing the blues brothers
with danny and we've been doing it since
uh 1994
95.
we play all over the united states i'm
trying to get them
i'm trying to get them to play here
and in germany
and i know the big blues brothers fans
in germany
and and here in italy and yeah
and every every year danny goes uh
absolutely
we should wow yes
we can tour we can do germany we do
berlin
munich and then we can go to france and
then we can go to speed and then we can
go down to rome and i went yeah yeah
yeah yeah
let's do it let's do it absolutely jimmy
it'll be a big hit
and then i start to
talk to people about booking a tour
and i go deeney i got these people
interested
and he goes ah what is it
i said the summer
uh
summertime
yes that's where all the festivals are
he goes oh no jimmy i'm on the lake in
the summertime
every every winter
we talk about doing a tour
in europe
and every summer he goes i know jimmy
i'm at the lake with the family
in the time
so i don't know if we'll ever make it
but
i try every year i would really
appreciate it to have the blue to see
the blues brothers in germany one day to
see the blues or others
in spain or somewhere i would i would
travel
i would fly all over europe and uh
in albania what about the blue star i
was playing in london killing albania
played toronto blake
we would tour europe but danny
likes to be by the lake in the summer
say hello to the people from icbc to
danny and ask him i will i will you know
look into the camera and say danny come
to germany
danny come to germany please you in
germany danny come on danny come to
europe to germany or and two spain
please we want to the blues to be in
europe
honestly the blues brothers is one of
the great great
uh well you know what it's uh
it was magic
what john and danny did
and the mission is so great because it's
it's
music
and you know
is
spiritual it's the closest to god that
you can get
is music
the sound of means whether it's
beethoven
or a baptist revival in georgia
the singing that brings you closer to a
spirituality
and that's what's so great about
watching that movies you can feel
you can feel it and the movie also
you know it had fun
it was fun it was funny
and the most important part to me
was
that little phrase that danny came up
with
and that is a mission from god
so those three elements to me
i thought made a
is what cannabis is about
there's there's a spirituality to it
there is fun to it
and
deeply for me is a mission from god and
the medicine involved with cannabis
the healing the pathway to healing and
cannabis
so as a brand i thought you know what
blues brothers is a brand
it's not just a name
it's a brand it has meaning to people
people connect
to
some kind of personal connection with
the blues brothers
and i think
cannabis is on a mission from god also
in the pathway to healing so i thought
it was a perfect blend
to bring cannabis and the blues brothers
together
so you are very very passionate about uh
music you're also very passionate about
your uh
job as an or your profession as an actor
and um
when it comes to cannabis uh what
you're born as a musician
and as an actor but cannabis did it it
came later what did uh what did make you
become a cannabis entrepreneur well you
gotta understand something that that as
a
i gotta stand up these chairs are really
confining
uh you gotta understand something with
with acting
the purpose
my purpose has always been
to entertain
and when you entertain
you are when you make people laugh
they re release endorphins
which makes them feel
good when you come to a concert with
your partner or your girl or your wife
you know you might have had a little
fight in the car
but after you experience
a performance you might be laughing and
feel good and you go home together with
your head up
and so the mission is what
to make people feel good
cannabis
is the same
the wellness encampment cannabis
includes
helps with alzheimer's headaches
ptsd
back aches pain but it also enhances
the taste of food
it enhances the touch of your lover's
skin
it also
makes you feel good
and you should never feel bad about
feeling good it makes you light
brings you closer to the light
which is enlightenment
so
i think i'm right on purpose
as an actor
performer to try to make people feel
good
i've naturally moved into cannabis
which is another
type of vehicle to make people feel good
so
it's a natural extension for me
so when it comes to belushi's farm which
is your
place where you grow your cannabis
how can we imagine that place
is it
you make me nervous
am i making you nervous
[Music]
wow
they're different than the united states
mine are flat
yeah yeah you're the flatman yeah mine
are yours are kind of like four-sided
how much for your shoelaces
how much
how much how much
you can have them i can have them
immediately yeah i think it would look
good one brown or one gray i think we'd
look cool together walking down the
street with different shoelaces
so anyway
belushi's farm
is a farm in southern oregon
about a mile i mean about an hour from
the california border
and
it is the most beautiful spot to grow
cannabis
because
i live right next to a river and i pull
the water from that river and it's
almost a perfect ph like between a six
two and a six seven
it's like feeding fiji water to the
plants
it's loma soil we have about 292 days of
sunshine
which is perfect
now i'm in what they call the banana
belt that's shaped like a banana leaf of
a perfect growing situation
for grapes
peaches
pears
and cannabis
yeah yeah so the the
latitude longitude
i mean i think god's
when god was done creating the earth
and on the seventh day when he was
walking home
he dragged his hand as he was walking
because he was so tired
and his fingers just kind of crossed the
soil across the globe
in this beautiful growing area
across the world we are in the same
parallel
as bordeaux and burgundy
and across the united states the corn
belt
so that from napa valley up to about 20
miles past my farm
is just
it's like
havana is for tobacco
so the cannabis that we grow in oregon
and northern california
and i'm going to say it
it's the best cannabis in the world
it is rich with terpenes
rich with terpene values
thc values can get very high which i'm
not really
big on
high thc values
i really believe that the combination of
maybe a 19
thc and a 3
to 5
value in terpenes
creates an entourage effect
that
doesn't leave you with the back end of
feeling a little anxious
or paranoid it's just
perfect
there's a stream that i have
it's called cherry pie
that's a 19
thc
and the last test was like 275
of terpene values
that combination
you know i'll tell you a story
my wife i came downstairs one night and
my wife said are you hungry i said yeah
she said what do you have a taste for i
said a cheeseburger
she goes oh jim
that's that's a little too filling for
me
a little heavy
anything else
and i want y'all yeah how about some
sushi
oh jim
i hit some sushi with my mom last night
anything else
and he said why are you wasting my time
asking me what i want to eat when you
know we're going to go where you want to
go and we're going to eat what you want
to eat
and boy she gave me a look like ah
maybe you're hungry right
the next night i came i took a hit of
this cherry pie
and i came down the stairs
and she said
are you hungry i went yeah
do you want to go to eat sure
where do you want to go
i said baby we can go to taco bell as
long as you're sitting across from me
and she looked at me like
aren't you being charming
and i'm thinking am i but i'm really
thinking cherry pie
the cherry pie is the marriage counselor
so this cherry pie i have an organ just
sold out in like two months
and i can't keep it stocked because
people come into the stores going
where's that marriage counselor he needs
it
so
the combination of the thc in the
terpenes is really
i don't even know if they test for
terpene values here
not yet yeah
that's really one of the things to look
for opposed to the high thc levels
so anyway police chief's farm yeah so
it's 93 acres is on the river i have
four greenhouses now
and i documented it in a uh
a
reality show called
growing belushi
is that broadcast that you ask quite
that
well it's on discovery plus
and i believe discovery plus is
an international platform
so but you have to buy discovery
plus whatever that is
but we also are releasing it the
different distributor
i think ant
is disturbing in different countries
but it really documents
the farm
uh i think i really believe it's the
first cannabis show that
shows us for who we are
it's not like a stoner show nobody's
getting stoned on this show
nobody's getting too you know high and
goofy and stupid
it's really about cultivating cannabis
but
my mission
on the show is creating
confidence in cannabis
so in order to create confidence in
cannabis
for the new consumer or
they need to know
how it's done
we show them that how cleanly the
cleanliness in which we grow
the water which we use the testing which
we do the cleanliness of how we grow
the nutrients that we use that are
natural
and they and then i literally show them
how to buy in a store
uh how to use a vape pen
i talk about cbd thc and terpenes so you
don't know
you're not only a performer and a
musician you also go very deep into
growing now
oh i'm a damn farmer man
i mean i am like
you know i
i didn't know what i was getting into
i thought this was going to be a fun
thing
and i'm a cross between bill murray and
elmer fudd
i am out there chasing squirrels and
gophers and aphids and rustic mites and
grasshoppers
and i'm like you leave me a gear
i'm like leave my girls alone
i'm like a hunter killer grower
i mean
i'm a farmer man i'm
weather i'm checking the weather i'm
checking the humidity
oh man i had some strains that i got
from colombia that were 14 weeks
and
it went into november and we had three
nights of 22 degrees and killed him
froze my plans
i mean this far i know why
i know why the united states subsidized
farmers and helps farmers
because it's a [ __ ]
farming is not easy
and when you get
a pre-roll
of a cannabis joint
from my farm
it's been touched
25 times by human hands
from the planting to the pruning to the
harvesting to the curing to the bucking
to the trimming
to the grinding to the and putting it
into the raw wrapper
to the rolling to the packaging to the
ceiling
you know you're getting a lot of loving
care this is like rolling
cuban cigars
but even more so so there is so much
craft
care
cleanliness because everybody on my farm
believes
in the mission from god
in the medicine
and i can go on for
hours about the stories of how this
medicine works
i mean this is just one story
this medicine
cannabis
is so good
that people take it for the side effects
now you see how they got it rule that
was funny you guys got that but it's
true
okay i'm sorry i'm just going on and on
i got too much coffee
yeah but uh main chocolate is very good
what
very good chocolate
jamie pearson is is
i don't know you know here but in the
united states she's a star
she's just one of the great leaders in
the cannabis industry
from medicine to the science of this
chocolate to the healing and and i've
collaborated with her because
her heart and my heart aren't the same
mission from god
and
this is great chocolate so anyway
did you have any um
was there a day or
something that happened that made you
be so convinced of cannabis i mean you
were not always into cannabis
so in california where you live it's
legal since six years and medical
medical since i think 10 years about or
even longer
i think yeah sorry i'm sorry
in california yeah um so
well i think everybody starts in this
cannabis business because it's a gold
rush and you think there's a lot of
money in it
i personally did very well last year
i broke even
home run people are jealous okay i broke
even
and that's with five years of losing so
i know i borrowed you with
everybody on my farm
got paid they made their mortgage
payments they've fed their children they
made their car payments they're happy
and that makes me happy because it's a
real family experience on
the
farm
but
there was one moment
when i was in oregon and we did our
first
grow our first crop
i literally i still do it i go to
dispensaries myself
in oregon
and deliver the cannabis
and i do a personal appearance
and there was there was a
parking lot that was filled with people
waiting to meet me
and as i go through the parking lot i
try to say hi to everybody and i can see
inside and
show them the cannabis take photographs
with them you know
by the way that's why i learned
everything about cannabis is from the
consumer
i ran into a gentleman who had long hair
blue blue eyes
skinny and he had a little look on his
face and i just stopped
and i said
you are right
and he looked at me and he said you know
i was a medic in iraq
and i saw things that happened to the
human body that nobody
should ever witness in their life
i have what the veteran administration
said i had triple ptsd
he said i don't know what they mean by
that
but they gave me a bottle this big of
600 oxycontin
and i have a wife and kids
and
i can't sleep i can't talk to them
and i was scared of the oxycontin and i
came to cannabis
and he said your strength
black dog
black diamond og
is the only strain i can use
where i can talk to my wife
talk to my children
and sleep
and then he kind of teared up and he
hugged me
and i said hey man i didn't make this
and he said no but you're a steward
and that day when i wrote my cousin
chris to our next delivery
i i just was so moved by this man that
was the paradigm shift of why i'm in
this industry
the number one fear in life is death the
number two fear in life is the collapse
of family
and families collapse because of
a death in a family like mine
severe illness someone in the family
divorce a loss of a job
a loss of a home because of that
families collapse
people fight to keep their families
together when they collapse it's
traumatic and i believe that everybody
is suffering from some kind of trauma in
their life that's been guiding their
decisions
and there's if you trace it it's about
some collapse
and when this gentleman was telling me
he was
with that black diamond
and when he consumed it
he was able to participate in his family
again and the fear of the collapse
subsided
but i believe that we all suffer from
collapse
of a family somewhere along the line
and everybody reaches for medicine
everybody is struggling you know people
who are struggling whether it's your
father with dementia or your aunt who
who's suffering
from
arthritis or
a veteran ptsd or divorce or people
suffering laws everybody is struggling
somewhere along the line everybody is
screaming
inside
so they reach for medicine
and what is the medicine
what are our choices
alcohol
number one choice
prescription drugs
going to a doctor
their job is to soothe the symptoms they
just give it to you
all i'm seeing is that the medicine
in cannabis
is a better choice for our bodies
and our spirit
and like i said the medicine is so good
people take it from the side effect
jim what would you say a
european doctor we thought we are not as
far advanced with medical cannabis as
you are in california because we're not
so experienced here
the european doctor would say okay
cannabis has this positive physical
effect and this positive physical effect
uh but the wood enhancing effect is not
therapy what do you agree
well it's not a particle it's not
it's not medical the mood enhancement
what do you mean that's why
what are you talking about yeah what
would that's what i hear from the oh
it's [ __ ] i mean people are thinking
prozac and all those mood affecting
um i'm so sorry did that when i said
[ __ ] did i upset you
i'm sorry i'm sorry
it wasn't the [ __ ] i said [ __ ] right
i'm so sorry
god bless you god bless you
god bless [ __ ] that you left man
you're missing the harmonica solo
i'm about to do harmonica solo
pipe piper they're coming back in you
see that
[ __ ]
[Applause]
so mood enhancing
of course it's mood enhancing
that's the point the point of living
through trauma
ptsd or
illness that makes you
feel bad or like even with my wife it
was like
it enhanced my mood and
the communication and the relationship
there's nothing wrong with feeling
good
we don't have to feel bad all the time
i mean yes we should be introspective
and
we should use those times of
feeling bad to
process the growth
but
you know
i say [ __ ] you should feel
it's nice to feel good
but again i'm a micro you know i'm i'm
not a
pothead
i'm not smoking all day you know
i'm like i take a little bang chocolate
at night
to help me sleep or a little bit of
chocolate or a little cherry pie in the
evening so i don't get in a fight with
my spouse
because the day builds anxiety you know
men and women who are responsible for
family
you know trying to raise a family trying
to provide for them you know there's
anxiety with responsibility
and instead of
drinking whiskey
yeah you know take a little bang
chocolate or a little
hit off a joint and
it's peaceful
you know i always said you know i was a
bouncer in chicago you're a bouncer
yes i do
and i never broke up a fight between two
potheads
just drunks
so it's a non-violent generous kind
spiritual
mission from god
so what i experienced from the u.s what
i do not experience in europe yet there
is not such a strict distinction between
medical and recreational it's more like
a yeah
the difference between medical and
recreational united states is taxation
i mean it's all medicine i think
i i i just think it's all medicine so
recreational
you know they tax the hell out of it
and medical the people who really need
it
who take
will take a pound of cannabis and make
their oil out of it in order to help
them with
you know 106 bones that were broken from
a car accident the pain they suffer or
cancer
[Music]
you know they give breaks to in taxes
so what our that at least our european
audience might not know in oregon
cannabis for medical use is taxed
differently from recreational cannabis
uh yes
yes absolutely
they're giving they're giving
these medical patients
a break on the cost
and also
it's tested
and testing is very very it's the
bottom line for cannabis for me uh you
know illegal grows people are making
not all legal growths
some of them are beautiful farmers that
are trying to make a living for their
family
but
you know there's a lot of cartel
or mafia that are involved and they're
growing
auto flower and you know you don't know
what pesticides are using you don't know
the
terpene values the thc valleys you don't
know what it is
so
the the medical cannabis and
recreational cannabis is very well
tested so you know what you're consuming
and let's go to
let's go back to south oregon um this is
where your farm is and i don't know if
the audience knows that icbc is also
coming from south oregon original
from ashland
and yeah actually yeah it's about that's
about 30 minutes from my farm yeah the
icbc is born in ashland so to speak alex
rogers who is the ceo of icbc the
founder of icbc he lives in he lives in
ashland he comes from ashland that's why
i wanted to say i tried wheat from
southern california and i have to admit
it was it was ground outer it had very
very high thc
levels
and
and it was
high on terpenes and it was all bio
also there was no no pesticides in and
it was the let me say the best tweet i
had on my trip it is i mean it's it's
going to be and
you know
the legalization of the united states
federal legalization is
is a tough
it's a tough road because now
not only have people who don't
understand cannabis and why it should be
legal
fighting it you have states that are
that
are loving the taxation
they taxed the farmer they taxed the
distributor they taxed the dispensary
they taxed the consumer
there's permits licensing
you know there's about eight different
revenue streams for the state
so once they legalize it and the state
borders come down
they all know that oregon and northern
california grows the best weed in the
world
and they're
we're going to be shipping it to
everybody and they're going no no no no
we don't want to give up all that money
you have to promise to ship some to
germany as well please because oh my god
i can't even see that please i cannot
send anything to germany across state
lines that is completely illegal
and i am a licensed holder of
cannabis wholesale and cultivation
and i am the poster child for compliance
in oregon
i believe that when they give you the
legalization they give you the license
that they are making you their partner
and you have to be an honorable partner
and stay as
legal and compliant as possible and this
partnership will grow
i have no complaints about
the regulations of cannabis
so what do you think is my last question
about uh
cannabis uh
administration things uh what do you
think about federal legalization which
means that you may ship your uh
wheat from hurricane to california one
day is that coming or in that coming
i i feel like it's really close
until
you follow the money
and when you follow the money the states
that are legal i just said this the
states that are legal
want to keep their tax dollars i think i
don't know if they're gonna
i think it's farther down the road than
we'd like but i do think there's a
possibility of them
changing some banking regulations
so they can help the
the dispensaries and the farmers not
deal with so much cash because when
there's a lot of cash around
so welcoming
to cry
and
we talked a lot about oregon about
california but
we are sitting here in spain right now
and spain also has kind of a nice
system for cannabis
because it's decriminalized here and
did you try any spanish i know you're
not a stoner but did you see did you try
to choke
did you see or try i mean
choco yeah
the club yeah and did you enjoy it how
was the menu
i i enjoyed it the people were very nice
reza was very nice vincent the manager
was nice janet
you know in the united states they have
pre-rolls so we've gotten very lazy
and here you have to roll your own
yes
[Laughter]
so janet was very nice to roll the joint
for me
but i didn't partake
my friends did i was surprised of all
the europeans mixing tobacco with the
wheat have you seen that uh i like that
idea you do yeah i really do i've never
had that from american surprisingly well
you know when i was 16 we used to take a
little weed
we'd take a cigarette and we'd kind of
roll out the tobacco and
put the weed into the cigarette to smoke
it so i don't know
well i i started smoking in the u.s
when i was 16.
our first cannabis experience
in the us
and uh
because i have seen i had seen it in
germany they mix it with tobacco and i
wanted to do that and they tried they
were they wanted to kill me my friends
at high school now oh
i was like how can you mix tobacco and
cannabis it's a it's a that deadly sin
considered as a deadly sin i thought
really yeah i thought well that's pretty
self-righteous of them you know what i
say
[ __ ] again you tell them to smoke
their weed the way they want dude you're
going to smoke your weed the way you
want to that's [ __ ] okay finally did
i lose anybody
jamie you're still here you're not being
offended by that okay
sure man i hate offending people
bullshit's a big big word
you know i mean i think consume it the
way you'd like i mean uh everybody has
their
preference just like
so don't worry i don't really like
watching somebody put
ketchup on their scrambled eggs
and i do the same thing how can you put
ketchup on your scrambled eggs
and they're like
shut the [ __ ] up belushi
you eat your eggs the way you want to
eat them all right all right all right
so you don't think there's a necessity
to over regulate anything on cannabis or
to uh regulate it too
too detailed
but i didn't quite understand what you
asked
what did you say
i asked you if you think there's if
there's a tendency to over regulate
cannabis
and recreational medical cannabis to do
to have two strong rules i don't know i
you know i i do believe states like
colorado
and oregon
even washington
they've been in the game for a long time
and especially oregon they're very
amenable to understanding cannabis
and they change their regulations as
they
grow
with the understanding
of the cannabis recreational market
i think states like california
should have
talked to oregon
and colorado i think they did talk to
him but said yeah we're california we're
going to do the way we want to do and
their regulations are very conflicting
and
and the taxation and some of the
regulation is
it's just anti-productive at times and
there's a movement
to try to get them to straighten it out
but they're a little stubborn
california's
i'm not even in the california market
because it's just
it's a little screwy right now but
hopefully they'll get it
so
anyway europe should look at oregon and
colorado and
see how they do it
because the testing and the safety and
the protocols and the metric
the tracking is
sensible
and responsible and protects the
consumer
okay i think that was a very good final
word and yeah we are close to finish we
are close to yeah it's we're nearly
finished
um
is there anything you want to tell the
audience before i think i've been
telling you
anything else anything special anything
special what's your best train for
example well i would like you to see
growing belushi
uh is it's a wonderful show and
simpatico to our cause
and purpose
um
on discovery plus and
i'm looking forward to walking through
the convention tomorrow
bain chocolate will be there
uh lighting which is an led
uh lighting system that we just put into
our grow that increased our growth
the yield by 30 percent and the terpene
values so you do a hybrid growth lights
and soil we're in the soil
uh beds we're in beds in a greenhouse
i couldn't take the aphids
and the rustic mites anymore and the
gophers
so i went into greenhouse because
greenhouse still has
the spirituality and the power of the
father's son
uh but it's also a nice protected
environment from the elements
and we're having great success in this
this lighting system
and we switched to advanced nutrients
which
really
i'm very pleased at
the results because
the results aren't subtle
it's like this last greenhouse we grew
with
advanced nutrients next to our other
greenhouse
was like i'm on two different farms
so this this this nutrient advanced
nutrients is
spectacular
so you know between the light
the sun
and the nutrients and of course the
water we use from our river
we believe we're growing the
some of the finest cannabis
uh in oregon
i believe that uh
but you know what
every grower says that so don't listen
to me
i'm i'm i'm i'm full of [ __ ] i'm
[ __ ] is what i am
jim i thank you very much for the
interview and oh thank you i hope you
guys got something any questions you
guys have any questions
anybody have a question
yes
hello
i have a question i've written it down
so i don't forget it so as a
high-profile cannabis farmer to what
extent do you feel a responsibility i
guess for one of a better term to kind
of push the legalization agenda sort of
in the u.s and internationally
i'd leave that to steve de angelo
steve d'angelo is the godfather of
cannabis united states and he is really
the most articulate and active guy
i'm still chasing gophers
but i do believe in the last prisoners
project when steve started
the united states which is
a program where we are working
diligently with lawyers
states attorneys to release
some of the 40 000
non-violent
cannabis
people that are incarcerated and we've
been having some great success
but these men and women that are
incarcerated
we're the pioneers in our business
and they are in jail with collapsed
families
because when someone is incarcerated it
collapses their family
and we are
making money on that you know
somebody's telling a better joke than me
out there i don't know
who that might be but they're having a
good time
they must be dabbing
did that help
any other questions right here yeah
thank you jim for this
passionate
statement on cannabis
you you say mood and enhancing i really
like it i really love it
but my question is will you be ready
to support maybe a trial a clinical
trial
to prove it
according to the principle of
evidence-based medicine as known in the
scientific world for a while
i mean
we know that i i want to take the
example of aspirin
years and for the last decades
around about one billion dollars sales
average sales per year
so making something like that
could give the pot the possibility
to make sales worldwide and support
lots of people
who need who need that we know that okay
and we
all of us are convinced that cannabis
really have lots of of of potential
so if you could be
the one supporting some something like
that and and you know and make this
revolution happen
i don't quite understand that long
question
um
would i support the legalization of
medical cannabis
expanded testing what is it expanded
testing for cannabis to put it on equal
footing would say
that would be great i don't know what
the laws are
here in europe but you know the united
states because it's federally illegal
uh
people that receive their licenses from
the federal government
doctors
if they dabble in cannabis
they can lose their license
so
most doctors don't even know the medical
benefits
you know they have
informative seminars a year on all
different kinds of drugs but there's not
one for cannabis
they don't even know what to recommend
to their patient with brightest
cannabis they wouldn't do it because
they'd be frightened to lose their
license
so the testing is really
behind
but there is some headway
what i can say for europe in europe we
have
we have testing is regulated by
by
the federal government
mostly it's the same in
in countries as a medical color with the
legal medical cannabis they test it for
thc in germany and in other countries
for cbd
for mold
and that's about it
you can as a company you can test it for
two of turpins and you also can test it
as a company for other
cannabinoids but you are not allowed to
publish those results because it's a
medicine and you're not allowed to
make advertisement for a medicine in
germany and due to that you're not
allowed you lost them
too
we lost them
but i didn't say [ __ ]
was it was it
was something we said
your heart your heart you have a heart
attack
if you're right but peace peace
that [ __ ] that's [ __ ]
any more questions from the audience
okay i think we are close to
thank you
and you are real and you say i want to
give you a present if you speak about
nutrients
i want to give you that from big mike oh
like big mike and thank you to be real
and forget to to keep marijuana human
well thank you
[Applause]
thank you big mike thank you thank you
so much okay uh thank you very much for
being at the icbc come to berlin thank
you come to berlin one more time jimbo
notes
berlin is in july
you can get the vip ticket for 420 euros
thanks again man appreciate it always a
pleasure we'll see you in berlin we'll
see you in zurich we'll probably also
see you in spanish we'd like to thank
the auditory cornea we'd like to thank
the entire staff of the international
cannabis business association jesse
randy noel
uh
miracle
and
uh and mika and me
and garon and everybody and that's it
we're all so tired and burnt
thank you all so much for coming out and
spending the day with us here at the
international cannabis business
conference and we'll see you in berlin