I would like to run down our panel here
and do a little quick introduction to my
to my immediate left Tara Carver Jared
Kyle Oh Rebecca fray and Ruben Hoenig
and to start us off and this is my this
is my maiden voyage here as a panel
moderator and I was told my first
question was terrible so I'm gonna cross
that one out but I would like to sort of
go just go down the row and have
everyone have a chance to sort of give
their background where they're from and
and how long they've been involved in
the industry awesome can you guys all
hear me thank you Alex and I'm excited
to be up here with the three of you um
hi my name is Tara Carver I'm the
executive director of the Humboldt
County Growers Alliance we represent 250
plant touching members the vast majority
of them are cultivators or farmers but
we also have manufacturers retailers
distributors testing labs in our ranks
as well I come from the industry I'm a
cannabis farmer by trade became a policy
wonk by necessity
legalization kind of blew through
Humboldt and we all had to really step
up but when we think about communication
we didn't think about communication
honestly like I I was brought up in an
era of the less communication the better
because you stayed safe and so we've
swung the pendulum on this whole
legalization thing and having to
actually talk about what we do and what
regulation does and how it impacts us
and so I I probably have the least
amount of experience in communication
but I've found that if you have fun with
it it actually works and so far we've
been pretty successful in Humboldt so
I'm here to say thank you thanks Sarah
Jared Kyle oh and the president of the
United canvass Business Association we
are a trade organization comprised
mostly of retailers but you know like a
lot of retailers there are quite a lot
of other points inside the supply chain
that they take on but we definitely
prioritize and wear the hat of retailers
most of the work that I've done when I
started here in San Francisco about 18
years ago so it's nice to still
in my hometown and still doing this but
I I do operate in Los Angeles quite a
bit which I enjoy but I definitely enjoy
coming home and also being a part of
this industry you know Communications
has been the biggest part of a retailer
because we had a Green Cross on us tree
for quite a few years you don't get the
opportunity to hide I mean I sat on the
medical marijuana task force here under
Gavin Newsom years ago it was awesome to
have someone who believed in us enough
to give us a space inside of City Hall
to actually have communication have
public hearings and really try to go
through really good standard operating
procedures and give best business
practices so that was a way that we got
to communicate to our you know to our
regulators and we got to tell them what
was needed and what the best business
practices were gonna be and having
subcommittees that communication has
been you know pivotal in being able to
run a trade organization because now I
had the foundation of how you can
communicate with a with a kind of a
legislator that really wants to listen
and it seems like ever since then we've
kind of been pushing an agenda to try to
make sure people listen and this is now
an opportunity where everyone is here
trying to find out what the stakeholders
and legacy operators have done over
years and how do we protect that legacy
so I just appreciate the opportunity to
continue to communicate to people and
trying to get our message across so
thank you for the opportunity of this
panel hi I'm Rebecca 4a I'm the
communications manager for the
California Department of Food and
Agriculture z-- Cal cannabis cultivation
licensing division it's quite a business
card and the cannabis farmers that's our
job
we are here to help them get through the
licensing process we know it's not easy
as Laurie mentioned earlier it's a
process for constantly reviewing and
trying to improve and the stakeholder
feedback we get is so helpful to that
this morning I just thought I would
share that we have licensed 5214
cannabis cultivators in the state and we
are down to about 600 pending
applications so we we've made a lot of
progress before I came to Cal cannabis I
worked in the Senate as their
communications director in public policy
on many areas including agriculture and
I've worked at the Sierra Club and
communications director of companies
divisions of amazon.com and book
publishing so I have a long
communications background but this has
been one of the most exciting constantly
changing communications positions I
think that Alex and I have probably been
in because it's just that the ground is
always moving and the laws are changing
and we're trying to keep up just as much
as as everybody else is so thank you
good morning everybody my name is Ruben
Hoenig I am a co-founder of Cirrus
strategies it's a consulting firm that
has been around since 2016 I have been
in the industry for five years
originally moving I'm from Massachusetts
originally but moving from Florida
five six years ago is actually five
years of this past December for actually
safe access as a medical patient so
originally got into the industry you
know with extreme concerns that people
weren't getting in other states or
California you know moving as I moved to
California where they have had a very
long-standing medical program I kind of
stepped into that but then looking at
other states seeing that you know there
wasn't that that kind of access and
people you know really needing to figure
that out you know and I remember you
know going to dispensaries when I just
showed up in in Los Angeles and I know
Jarrod spoke about this about
dispensaries you know kind of being the
frontline and communicating with
patients but I was interesting and I
would start started to see you know how
but tenders how people were actually
communicating with people you know it
was wild the people I would see would
come into a dispensary and say this was
my my wife had stage four cancer this is
our last opportunity this is the last
thing
you know that we can do and what do you
do and what do we do and then there was
kind of this you know depending on who
you speak to depending on who you do who
you who you're getting advice from it
was kind of you know it wasn't
standardized right um I do more work on
local licensing policy work at the state
locally in the city of Los Angeles um
I'm based in LA I've done a lot of trade
associated associated is key
communicating with policymakers
communicating internally with membership
and you know I appreciate this
conference and our moderator Alex
traverse' so so I was given the sort of
the the leeway to select what the panel
was gonna be who was gonna be on this
panel and so obviously I picked the
people that I am a fan of their work and
so and I think that they all represent
sort of an interesting and they all come
from interesting backgrounds and they
all have to communicate with with
different audiences and so as I think a
lot of us know the way you reach a
grower versus a retailer versus you know
just a general stakeholder there's
there's many different tactics many
different ways of communication and so
I'm really interested in just kind of
hearing some of the different challenges
that we all sort of face in our
day-to-day lives and trying to
communicate with folks so I mean I think
you know as much as I want this to be
sort of freewheeling and everyone jump
in where they can I think I think I want
to start with with Jared on this one
just because he's not only a business
owner but he does represent a trade
association and I think there are
different challenges that come with that
so and I'll let you take the take it
away well I mean when we're trying to
deal with a market that is now
transitioning you went from absolutely
no regulations and in the attempt to
hide and now when you transition to
probably the most regulated product that
we can think of now in California trying
to get those people to transition has
been one of the most parts because
they're trying to keep their business
going they're trying to understand OSHA
certifications they're trying to make
sure that
they did the sexual harassment you know
like studies I mean like we've got all
of these things to think about and then
I come in as a as the president of this
organization talking about regulations
possible labor unions what labor peace
agreements are there and it is
overwhelming for most to even try to
hear all the things that we have to
trans transition to them and so when you
try to give them a safe place to say
okay how can i boil this down to what
your biggest needs are and how do you
create priorities now our organization
has done a good job of keeping three or
four priorities at the top of our list
saying we have to deal with these first
before we move on and that's been a
great way of communicating to people who
feel like they're frazzled by all the
information they need to absorb and then
they start to look at how much they're
spending on legal legal counsel and on
consulting fees and so trying to be a
trade organization that funnels all that
information lowers those costs and
reduces those barriers because I'm
sitting in a seat that says I have the
exact same issues you do as a retailer I
also have to survive and here's the
things I'm doing as a retailer and when
you sit in a room of everyone having the
same needs a lot of conversations from
that is what really builds up kind of
kind of a community and that's what I
really wanted in Los Angeles now being
in Northern California community was
just was just how you lived I mean you
didn't you didn't have people come and
trim at your grow-op unless you knew
them or they were a friend of a friend
and so trying to establish that Northern
California style of community in
Southern California was a little
difficult everyone's like what are you
doing here like why are you in Los
Angeles I'm sorry but we usually fight
with each other
how are we gonna love each other and I
realize that that may sound a little bit
soft and like you know but the point is
we all want to feel comfort with each
other and so being in a group and
allowing each other to express each
other's needs and then offering possible
solutions has been what this group is
why we've stayed together I mean we
spent millions of dollars passing an
ordinance in the city of Los Angeles
measure em and like as a trade
organization trying to get people to
pull millions of dollars out of their
pockets telling them that this is the
pathway to their future success is
not an easy conversation explaining how
to get a hundred nine thousand
signatures to qualify an ordinance in
the city of La is not something that
most people understand and so that's
been the hardest part about running an
organization of of transitional business
owners was how do I prioritize what is
most important to them how do i allocate
their resources and funds to the most
important parts and really transition
them into a space where they feel
comfortable and putting that kind of you
know publicity out most of my members
wanted to hide for the first five and
six years of being in this organization
and how do you get them to come out of
the shadows and really stand up for
their business stand up for their
industry and also stand up for their
community that we built and now that we
have this nice community we feel there's
a sense of comfort
once that comforts there now we try to
go okay here's the hard questions we
have to answer again today like what
labor unions do you really want to work
with which ones do you think you're
gonna represent your needs the best and
you know it's not easy to talk about
politics in front of a group of people
who have never voted and that's that's
sometimes a problem too because we
stayed out of the limelight for so many
years then to expects to expect all of
these people to engage fully it's been a
really difficult process but you know I
think we're in a place now where people
are proud of the work they do they're
proud to like tell their parents and
everyone that they own a dispensary we
don't have to hide anymore remember when
people used to ask me what I did I used
to tell them everything else but
cannabis and now it's like the first
thing I say when some people say what do
you do is like I'm proud of the cannabis
work I do I'm proud to be in this
industry and I think what happened now
is that communication of pride is what's
really pushing a lot of my members to be
out there to go hit the streets and make
sure their neighborhood councils
understand the good work they do that is
truly what did this pride an ownership
of a legal industry and feeling like you
don't have to look over your shoulders
wondering when the police are gonna come
back that has changed the view of a lot
of people inside inside the retail space
we we've been the front lines for a lot
because you know in Humboldt it was
helicopters in Los Angeles
it was anytime a police officer drove by
everyone clenched up because you never
knew if you were gonna be subjective to
them coming into your shop whether you
thought you were legal or not prop D in
Los Angeles was a mess and left everyone
in this gray area for such a long time
so now to feel like we're supported by
our city to feel like we're supported by
our state and also to see the country
move that communication has become so
much easier because I don't have to
convince people that we have something
good to build from it's being built
right now and these regulations have
really helped so that's probably the
best thing I can say about like the
communications now right now so I have
so I have a question specific to two
growers that I want to ask but I took
cold medicine before I came here and I
have a question that I want to ask Ruben
that I'm gonna forget if I don't ask him
really quickly here so the question is
really more about if you're if you have
clients that you're representing
sometimes I think based on the state of
the industry and where we're at right
now that the things that things are a
little difficult communication can
sometimes be a nice-to-have so I'm
wondering if you what do you tell a
client who maybe doesn't have the
resources to bring on communication
strategy or a communicator and how do
you how do you advise them to sort of do
that work on their own did you take
dayquil or nyquil
I believe it's daytime so I took they're
very good it's it is it's very
complicated
I mean I don't know any other way to say
that we're dealing with a unprecedented
landscape where well when it comes on to
the communications side I don't
necessarily see the value right now for
for businesses on the business side
there are so many things that businesses
you know as we're seeing the industry is
kind of contracted we're seeing a lot of
layoffs in the industry we're seeing a
lot of a lot of issues going on now and
we're seeing a lot of successes at the
same time I think it's it's easy to to
lament and really pile on right and and
say oh everything is horrible it's a
crisis it's the worst we're all gonna
die and everything is you know what
you know going going out there and
talking to people um there's a lot of
stories out there there's a lot of
people you know that aren't putting out
press releases when they raise a bunch
of money right they're not putting
saying oh I have $100,000,000 oh I have
two hundred million dollars you know
they're there quietly you know building
their businesses one two three steps at
a time and not you know necessarily
getting ahead of things you know
communicating with local governments
complicated again you know as we
probably all know here there are there
are there is a is a shortage of license
dispensaries across the state there are
areas that don't have them you know we
do see a lot of dispensaries in
municipal bigger - municipal areas but
also you know on the other side of that
coin we're seeing that that those stores
you know depending on levels of
enforcement and levels of Taxation and
different inputs we're seeing you know
stores barely touch the the the outer
realm of their ability of their capacity
it's it's unfortunate to see people not
wanting to go to stores I think Los
Angeles has a great opportunity to
communicate with the public through
public education we have seen we'd wise
at the state the city of Los Angeles
still has seven hundred fifty thousand
dollars sitting inside of some sort of
thank you for that campaign plug every
day you know they're you know when are
we going to communicate more and more
effectively with the consumer with the
public eye you know maybe I'm on my own
Island over all the way over here but I
think that there's a large majority of
people that think since prop 64 passed
everything is legal right and I think
and I think that segues into the
question for how to communicate with
with growers - and I want to get terra's
thought on that and then I want to talk
to Rebecca a little bit that about that
as well because Cal cannabis has its own
PR campaign that is focused on on
reaching cultivators and it's it's not
as easy as potentially the one that
we're talking about with weed wise and
and reaching you know
retailers because there's so much more
out in the forefront of things so
speaking to growers I think the Humboldt
County growers Alliance does a great job
and their communications member
appreciation posts are always fun so you
know so Humboldt County is has a long
history sixty plus years of rebel
outrageous outlaw cannabis farmers and
we're very prideful of our work but
being a rebel outrageous loud cannabis
farmer now I have found like we've have
to kind of tone it back a little bit
when we're talking to the policy makers
and so my struggle sometimes with
communication is is taking my amazing
membership and all their outrageous
stories and asking them to be very
professional when you go in and talk to
you to your local government about taxes
instead of coming in with protest signs
and you know banging down the door and
locking yourself to to the chair it's
we've had to rearrange a bit of our
strategy but I guess when when I think
about growers and communicating with
growers from heritage regions in
California humor is the best way to get
across a message across in my opinion I
again because we can be so serious and
outrageous and loud if you can tone it
down with a little bit of humor it
really makes it the communication style
very personal and I like to kind of
think of our members there they're very
passionate they're artists and so if you
can communicate to them on a level of
basic humanity they respond really well
so that's that's been my mic trick and I
think that that that's great because
that's that's ordinarily what I would
shoot for as well at the bureau is sort
of a fun conversational style
unfortunately that the state kind of
frowns upon that sometimes you can't
have too much fun because that that's
it's not approved so in that and that
I'd like to hear Rebecca's perspective
because she I know she feels my pain on
a regular basis as well so getting her
perspective on their the regulator side
of things and maybe talking a little bit
about the campaign that you guys have
with with food nag
can we have an industry awareness
campaign that is going to unroll very
soon there'll be an announcement in a
few weeks where we're going to talk
about the merits of being a licensed
cannabis farmer in the state and talking
to other farmers who are licensed who
will share their stories up and down the
state and we are been working very hard
on that and we're looking forward to
launching that soon I wanted to add that
and Alex and I are always on the front
lines of breaking with the reporters who
do a really good job of keeping on top
of everything it's it's a it's a
demanding beat covering cannabis but as
as former journalists and reporters we
also know the importance of getting back
to people really quickly finding the
information that's needed so that
everybody out there can get the latest
breaking news we've also had surveys at
the department food and AG asking
farmers how do you want to get your
information what's the best way to get
it to you and social media has been very
popular we have now at food and AG we
have an Instagram channel which food and
Agri celebrated its 100th anniversary
last year they never had an Instagram
channel but the cannabis farmers said
they love to look at the beautiful
photographs of their their plants and so
we added Instagram to that collection of
social media channels and then we also
recently added a twitter espanol channel
and we have bilingual person on staff to
reach out to some of the spanish farmers
and we've been doing more with mom
farmers as well and again that's from
the stakeholder feedback that we've been
getting so we really do listen to the
feedback that we get from you there's a
lot of material we put out for people to
read fa Q's fact sheets and but not
everybody is a reader so we're also
doing more short videos we're doing
podcasts we're doing more photo essays
and things like that so we do listen to
how people want their information
and we do radio talk shows we do news
shows on television and we just try all
avenues to get out there and get the
message so this so and speaking about
sort of feedback and in your in your
communications and maybe some some
things that you know I would like to
mention in our in our in our realm at
the BCC so we started out and this is
I've been at this for a little over
three years now
and so we set up our social media
channels and I think initially when we
started out I think there was sort of a
the general feeling was we're gonna
we're getting the benefit of the doubt
alright let's wait and see how this how
this thing rolls out and over the course
of three years I think the tide is
turned a little bit on us and so so so
in terms of speaking about challenges
and some of the feedback you receive in
your communications I think one thing
that stuck out to me the other day and I
read everything so I see I see
everything that people comment on our
posts and things we put out there and
somebody just said you know you've got
to hand it to the BCC they continue to
put this [ __ ] out even though they're
everyone's killing them right like
they're just we're getting lit up on a
regular basis everything we put out
there you're terrible people all this
stuff those are those are the challenges
we deal with on a regular basis because
you have to continue to put information
out there you can't just go dark because
you're getting this negative feedback so
I'd like to just sort of run down the
panel and talk about some of the
feedback you've received some of the
feedback good or bad that you've
received in your communications programs
and maybe some some of the challenges
that you just based on a regular basis
sure so I think I'm just gonna say it we
can all agree that the input of
information that we have to turn around
and turn out is a lot and so whether
it's the BCC Cal Canibus other trade
associations news articles it is a
constant move for us we're a scrappy
grassroots organization like we don't
have a hundred billion dollar million
trillion zero budget like there's three
of us and one of our biggest challenges
has actually come down to finding a
graphic designer who will who's not in
house and so meaning that we can't get a
graphic designer to be able to be on
call and we've been doing this for three
three and a half year
and we started local and then the
outsource to San Francisco and then we
outsource to New York we literally have
a gentleman in Serbia right now turning
over our graphic design work because I
can't find one in the United States
we'll talk later
I've got some things to say on this
issue that I have this is great we're
making connections right now I like this
I mean Alexia's gonna be really bummed
he's great and but nonetheless so
turning over that information and so if
I if I can't get the Instagram post
because that's how our rural farmers
communicate and thank you so much for
hearing us on that it's been such such a
big deal for us if I can't get that
Instagram post out with within 48 hours
sometimes the policy will change and now
I've paid for it it's not relevant
anymore and I have to go pay for it
again and then I've had issues that have
changed so rapidly that I've had three
posts that are that are all worthless so
that's that's our biggest issue yeah I
think it was interesting because we
stood out really quickly in Los Angeles
and trying to make regulations like
legal dealing with that gray area for
such a few years quite a few years we
kind of went like okay we're gonna jump
out and make this happen so we wrote an
ordinance and immediately as soon as we
wrote an ordinance we were the target of
just about everyone we were called
monopolistic we were called deeply
entrenched and trying to make sure that
no one else could enter the market what
happens is when you stick your neck out
everyone loves to point a finger that
you're the bad guy you're the bad girl
you're the one who's come out here and
trying to take over the industry with
your words and your ballot measures and
so that was initially how we got started
the first thing was like wow here's a 53
page ballot initiative in the city of
Los Angeles and we're being called
monopolistic we're like we're just
trying to make sure that the legal part
of this industry continues to grow and
even to the even to today even when we
have you know a retail expansion bill
that we've been we've been trying to run
this whole you know this year we're
still being called monopolistic as an
organization because because we
represent a small section of license
holders inside the retail segment and
the thought is is that we're in
trying to grow this industry because we
want it all for ourselves which is it's
a difficult part to have to try to
communicate to people like it's hard to
be monopolistic when you have a
dispensary in Los Angeles am i really
taking over the Northern California
market with my dispensary in LA and it's
like I think the communication is like I
really only have reach about five or six
miles from the center of my dispensary
so how can I be monopolistic and I think
the thing is with with this kind of
communication style people love to break
you down and say that you're bad so they
can elevate themselves and trying to
kind of elevate yourself above that
chatter because in the positions we're
in elevating yourself over people who
are trying to just hate on the work that
you're doing
you can't just dive into that every time
and lose sleep or the fact that people
don't like you you have to stay focused
you have to keep your group focused and
whenever someone says something negative
about you you need to take it in and see
if that's true and if it doesn't feel
true to you you have to shed it off and
not feel like you have to continue to
answer that same negative feedback so
that's been the biggest like challenge
for us especially in Los Angeles is to
really take that negative feedback and
push it out and really just try to be
productive Tara I wanted to let you know
that we have a lot of free graphic
artists responding on our Instagram page
they're getting very creative with
emojis and they communicate very well
what they're not happy about with with
sometimes r-rated emojis and a lot of
fun looking at those but we we want to
hear the good and the bad we want to get
all the feedback because we do go back
and figure out okay a lot of you aren't
liking this how can we make it better
how can we change it and the change
takes a while sometimes but we are we
are listening and we always welcome the
feedback whether it's on social media or
calling food nag we have a toll-free 183
3 Cal grow phone number we we do invite
that we appreciate talking to the
stakeholders and I just want to throw
also some people just like to have
one-on-one conversations with the
experts and licensing
and thanks to my partners at Fish and
Wildlife who were here today and the
water board's we are doing about a dozen
free cultivation licensing workshops
across the state just for the first half
of the year we will have more
we've tried doing online workshops we
did one we're gonna do another one on
February 21st and that allows people in
remote areas to also look at maybe they
can't make it to LA or San Francisco or
or some parts of Humboldt
wherever we might be so we're trying
this and it was very effective the first
time so we're doing it again and all of
this is posted on our social media and
it's on our online calendars so you can
plan accordingly but we do welcome the
feedback you know good and bad so thank
you for everybody's comments left me at
the end didn't you all right so I think
that one thing I wanted to bring up is
and this actually was interesting you
know in in another trade association the
LA cannabis taskforce that I helped
found and you know really kind of got to
know the ins and outs of cannabis got to
know the ins and outs of LA local
policies some state policy but what I
learned you know many years ago which is
in cannabis years not in human years but
they it you need to communicate with the
state you know the way that you
communicate what the state is different
than the way you communicate with the
city of Los Angeles is different than
you communicate with the city of San
Diego they need to communicate with San
Jose you know you know we got into a
position where you know we we placed an
article or had some quotes that were you
know a little bit inflammatory in the
city of Los Angeles and you know when
you do stuff like that then the
councilmember just cuts you off we're
not talking to you anymore
and that's it at the state you know you
know we were with my former business
partner she came from the state and she
was you know more aggressive with with
kind of her positioning and it was
almost like oh come on these people are
being babies but at the same time you
know the you have to be very conscious
of your audience and you have to you it
is very very easy to make a
communication snafu
and you know people are sensitive people
are emotional you know the cannabis
industry I think it's it's tough right
now because when you're in it every
single day and you're working in the
industry be it you know ancillary
licensees it's just it's hard to to kind
of take a step back in NC perspective of
you know well if I care so much about
this to the people to stay care as much
as I do and I think to your to your
point I think all of us on a regular
basis are so sort of entrenched in what
we're doing that sometimes there may be
are there opportunities out there for
different different tactics or different
ways of doing things that we may not be
able to capitalize on utilize whatever
it is and case in point a couple weeks
ago we're at a different event and there
was a regulator from Oregon there and
they were talking about their they have
a podcast and and so my my boss
afterward comes to me and says what do
you think should we do what we had a
California podcast and I was like are
you are you serious when that thing goes
through the editing and the review
process it'd be like a valium at the end
of the day right it put people to sleep
so so maybe but these are things that
you think about as possibilities right
these are some of these are things that
are out there so this will be the next
couple questions are just gonna sort of
serve as the lightening round here
before we before we wrap up so in terms
of opportunities are there opportunities
that that you would like to explore and
what might they be going forward
sumo-wrestling at the state capitol for
stakeholders on issues I think it's a
great idea we can fundraise off of it
and donate to charities the this
industry is extremely emotional reactive
and hyper engaged which is good it's not
a bad thing so as far as state
regulators yeah I think you should host
those those sumo wrestling matches done
cool I think it's tough to have
everyone's voice be heard it would be
really nice if we could kind of do some
more like video conference calls so that
the BCC and people can ask questions
directly
laterz in kind of a digital format so
that we don't have to come to you know
drive find parking get a hotel room to
ask you know our regulator questions and
I think sometimes in the group setting
it is nice to hear other people ask
questions you probably were fearful of
asking because you think it's stupid but
then all of a sudden that question gets
asked so I think that kind of larger
group video conference would be really
nice for for people to ask questions
just calling someone on a phone you
don't get to see facial expressions or
or anything so you don't know how to
judge if your question is well received
or heard so I think I think some video
stuff would be really nice for us and
we're actually going to be doing more
videos short videos on social media
because we found that they're very
effective people are really busy they
don't have a lot of time so we really
analyze what are the questions that are
most often asked and we can get those
out there like the top three and the
answers and if you need more information
where to go trying to make we just
redesign our website recently trying to
make it easier to navigate where to find
what you need
absent making a call or sending an email
which of course you can also do but that
that's something that we work on very
hard at the food now I do want to vote
for sumo wrestling first though honestly
every issue we just throw down I heard
the question then Tara said sumo
wrestling and then I lost the question I
don't think it matters anymore really
fine it does not matter I would like to
see more collaboration that's I think I
think that you know between trade
associations between you know
stakeholders and the state you know BCC
CDFA CD pH the consolidated version of
whatever we're gonna see next year
potentially yes I think that who knows
who knows work and even like like give
you know there's there's just it's it's
it's very complicated there's a lot of
regulations there's a lot of compliance
issues there's a big drop off right now
with metric you know people are having
you know the state is politely you know
being a little bit lenient with it but
at the same time
it's fair to say you know that there is
all these different things that are just
complicate just run a business so I
think that more collaboration between
the state and stakeholders to put more
information now so people can have a
baseline understanding of of things so
they don't have to necessarily hire a
high-priced or mid-priced or local price
consultant or they don't have to you
know you know deal with their you know
their lawyers and I understand people
have to run their businesses too with
ancillary businesses or people that uh
you know or not licensees but you know
there should be a you know a level of
just a baseline of this information that
people can get and and it can actually
you know they don't have to hire
multiple people and just this is all
good feedback thank you asking the
critiques come in keep them coming like
collaborate so so obviously with this
particular panel I'm fans of all the
work of these folks on the panel but I
want to also give everyone the
opportunity to to talk a little bit
about like who who's who's doing a
communications program that you actually
pay attention to and think is doing a
good job and not everyone needs to say
the Bureau of cannabis control at the
same time so it's fine but who do you
think I mean who whose communications do
you follow and say like these people are
actually doing a great job and this is
if I was telling someone or if I was
advising someone on you know how to how
to run an effective communications
program who would I point them to you
start this time that's fine fine I have
actually no one to give you that's doing
it and not in a bad way but it's like
what were I think that what we're seeing
now is with businesses that are not
doing well laying off employees you know
they're signalling to their investors
signaling to the Canadian stock market
signaling to whoever you know they're
there all their businesses their
employees that you know they you know
they're it's nuanced and I think that
crisis communications actually is is a
in you know I use that term loosely but
you know the way that you message you
know be at ease or be it weed maps or be
it you know whatever it is or whatever a
company there's a you know in a nuanced
way to commute
okay and there are ways to you know to
put the truth out there and not kind of
skirt around it but at the same time you
know be be savvy about it so I think
that that's you know that's that is I'm
not not to judge anything that's out
there right now but it's just it's it's
an important part I think of businesses
right now in this downturn to be able to
communicate with the public
effectively and not necessarily you know
say oh we're in the gutter sorry that
sucks you know that's Rebecca what do
you think I look a lot at the New York
Times I love the New York Times
briefings this is what you need to know
right now and if you want a really deep
dive click here we're doing more of that
we're giving you that bite-sized bit of
information and then if you want to know
all the nuts and bolts we'll have a link
that takes you there and we're doing
that on social media we're doing that on
our website we're doing them with email
alerts we work with the bureau and
Department of Health and doing that as
well but they just do such a great job
of that and so that's something that I
look at constantly we don't have their
budget but we still aim high honestly I
think David downs and Leafly are killing
it right now for all the investigative
reporting agreed and so honestly I mean
I can't even tell you how many times I
quote Leafly and David Downs is like
articles it's very helpful when I go
into regulators we all have some of the
same information
it's a trusted source they have they
have taken all the illegals off their
site March and 2018 really leading the
kind of advertisers so I have my hat's
off to Leafly and David downs I really
appreciate your work yeah I would second
that I mean just even outside of
cannabis like there's so much
information being thrown up all of us
I'm looking out here right now and it's
you know each and every one of you who's
got a cell phone you're in your your
downloading information and the
platforms are so vast and they it's just
overwhelming and so credible journalism
is what I have found to be the savior so
far of keeping our mental
okay in this space because there's so
much misinformation so much and there's
so much opportunity to have
misinformation and that can make or
break a business a trade association or
the reputation of a government agency
and so credible journalism all the way
so on that point and I want to sort of
maybe maybe we conclude with this but in
terms of I mean the whole the whole
point of this panel and discussing the
fact that words do matter right and and
the level of information that's coming
out and things are changing and
happening so quickly that there is you
know you have to be hyper focused on on
what you're putting out there because
things can mean different things to
different people so if there anything
that any of us right now would like to
sort of misconception that we would like
to clear up in front of this fine cast
of characters in the crowd starting with
miss Carver
I don't hate hemp there's a
misconception that I hate him
I don't not at all I didn't raise her
taxes either been doing I didn't do that
no you didn't and I've been trying to
tell people that they they don't want to
hear it
they still believe I come from humble
County we strongly believe in hemp
production we truly believe it can solve
a lot of the world's climate crisis
issues right now we just absolutely do
not want it grown in Humboldt County
we will not cross pollinate our genetics
so there's a misconception that we hate
I hate specifically me too I'm hearing
it out in the ether but no I love hemp
just not humble well I'd love to build
on the hemp conversation because a bee
2:28 was something that we stopped last
year because they would not give testing
parity to cannabis I was not gonna allow
a product to sit on my shelf that was
untested like the product right next to
it you know I'm trying to build for my
for my consumers health and safety was a
big deal and so I hope this year Aguilar
curry takes a bee 228 and looks at it
and do it gets parody for testing
because I don't I would love low-cost
CBDs to be available to every single
patient that wants them and needs them
we need higher production of it but we
can't let it slip into the state of
California into the ruse that is just
gonna be safe for human consumption it
needs to be tested the same as as
cannabis I think it's the right thing to
do and I think we need it here so and I
hope we I mean that's a misconception
- it's like I I'm trying to keep hemp
and CBDs out of the market I'm just
trying to provide for my consumers in a
safe and effective way and since I've
been doing that for 18 years for
cannabis I I would hate for someone to
just slip in and in a couple of months
be able to get underneath all the
testing regulations so that's that's
another misconception I think that I'd
like to kind of get out there one of the
questions we get asked the most often is
for those who have a provisional
cannabis cultivation license do they
need to get credentialed into and learn
how to use the California cannabis track
and trace metric system and I think
there was some confusion early on
because with temporary licenses that
wasn't the requirement but now with all
provisional and annual licenses you do
need to get credentialed into the metric
system this is a program that is managed
by the Department of Food and
[Music]
Agriculture comment' live on as
scheduled on January 2nd 2018 but I keep
seeing 2019 I keep seeing January 2020
it just went live and it was January
2018 and the team that killed themselves
to get it live was very very proud of
that fact but it is an area where we
have a lot of questions so we're
focusing on that quite a bit I think
that misconception is that medical
cannabis is dead
the there are some amazing and I'm you
know I'm not biased but my sample is Los
Angeles more I know I know lost Los
Angeles market more than I know the
Northern California market but there are
some amazing dispensaries there that are
actually aggregating data studying
talking to people doing intakes and
actually putting their hearts and their
souls into helping people I know that
you know it has been tough for this
small operator and the medicine
Aker to get those products into stores
and I I urge you know us to figure out a
way to strengthen the medical market and
bring it back to to true medicine and
you know you know we need to have a safe
place where somebody can come to
California and they can get make
informed decisions about you know the
best they can do for their for their
medical condition you know how would I
know that care by design would put my
Crohn's disease into remission
I was living in Florida and I just heard
CBD in the wind and suddenly Los Angeles
this is where was happening a company
like canna Kraft was putting making this
medicine for such a long time so I you
know I urge us not to go down that that
pipeline of oh it's all recreation
that's all adult use you know let's
start being more conscious of of the
medical market and you know I think we
should we should praise and honor the
the true medicine makers you know not
these monopolistic crazy people in Los
Angeles about the people they were
actually providing medicine to patients
all right well I think I'm sure I forgot
to ask something awesome but we've long
outstripped the cold medicine at this
point so I think what I would like to
say is I would like to thank everybody
for listening I'm not sure if anything
was to be learned here but I just wanted
to have sort of a fun discussion and and
I thank you all for sticking around for
it and I want to thank our esteemed
panel
[Applause]