welcome back did you enjoy your lunch
I said did you enjoy your lunch
all right I know some of you didn't need
you just sat in the
give it up for our MC um
keeping it funky and fresh all the time
he's so funky fresh look at that come on
we love you and guy look at that
you're like a supermodel
Blue Steel
that's Alex Rogers by the way he put
this whole thing together that's it for
Alex was here for the whole team with
the ICBC
right we're International man we thank
you all for coming out we really
appreciate all of you
this one will be in English if you need
a translating device uh we have them
over there by the coat check don't
forget the party tonight nine o'clock at
the Ritz Arts Hotel also uh discount
tickets for Berliner until and please
please I'm begging you please please
pretty please go upstairs and check out
some of the exhibitors up there as well
right they get lonely and uh there's you
know there's more food up there than
there is downstairs so
just trying to give you an incentive
okay we're going to discuss comparing
medical uh cannabis regulations in
Europe and here to lead that discussion
the
SAE fa avogados let's hear it for
Guillermo Fernandez
[Music]
[Applause]
let's do it
hello hello
excellent just kidding
so good morning to everyone it's a
pleasure to be here one
Yanmar and let's talk and enjoy talking
about medical cannabis we want to learn
about
um how's the situation in different
countries like Canadian Portugal
Switzerland and United States
I think it's gonna be very very
interesting so let's um let's start
first of all uh I'm gonna let my
colleagues to introduce uh themselves we
can start acting from Alex please
all right thank you uh really nice to be
here thank you everyone for coming I've
been in the medical cannabis space since
2013 uh working with many different
companies over there over my time and
now I'm a partner in an Edibles
manufacturer called loose Brands we're
sitting right over there and uh hybrid
Farm we're one of the first pharmacies
in North America to have medical
cannabis and uh hot off the presses we
just launched a new trade association
called the global cannabis trade
Association in Canada helping facilitate
international business so very excited
about that and excited to be here with
you all thank you thank you so much
Alice Carlos please thank you very much
for to be here I mean the opportunity to
be here with you all my name is Carlos
I'm from bangoland Solutions one of the
the first consultancy company in the
medical cannabis in Portugal
so we are helping the the investors and
The Growers to build their project in
terms of developing the all the
technical part and also following all
the guidelines to guide certification
also the the license process and we are
doing this from since 2018 and yeah
that's it thank you very much and enjoy
now thank you so much Daniel
I'm a lawyer in Switzerland in life
sciences as well as in corporate law
specialized in cannabis as well I'm the
co-founder of the international cannabis
Bar Association Europe section together
with Kyle sitting back there
and father of three
that's also important a small Hobby and
apart from that very active with various
companies in Switzerland in in the
Cannabis space also including with
government and new legalization efforts
that are taking place at the moment
yeah that's
it thank you so much
hello everyone pleasure to be here again
my name is uh Santiago on guy I came to
the Cannabis industry in 2008 as a
hobbyist cultivator and uh
distributor and I then entered the
software traceability space once
regulations started to be released and
the need for traceability was apparent
so I've been working there for the past
eight years and as of recently
um I co-founded a
mycology company in the psychedelic
mushroom space
here to talk about mainly the U.S
medical cannabis industry and the
traceability within that
pleasure to be here thank you so much
and about myself
um
we've been working in the
cannabis industry for almost 15 years we
work in all the sex stores from criminal
law to licensing going through to
economics Club so anything we can help
here we are let's start first of all
I think we're going to start from
Alex
briefly please how's the medical Medical
Market going medical cannabis Market
going in in Canada well I'll try to do
it as briefly as possible and say pretty
good we've come a long way but since the
regulations kind of came out we've kind
of worked within them and slowly
stretched them out to a decent
regulation and you know the sort of
sensor I would describe it as we're
probably better than pretty much
everywhere else but still have a lot of
way to go
okay great I know Carlos how is
everything going in Pokemon
um yeah I mean we uh we have the the
regulation I mean the new regulations
were were released in uh 2018.
um I mean it's illegal to to grow
medical cannabis since 1993 but with the
Big Industry with in fact from the the
international companies especially from
Canada that they would like to come to
to Europe our authorities started
looking for how they can help those
companies to build and license their
their activities there in in Portugal so
the neural regulation was released in
2018 which helps a lot in terms of how
we can do it it was more clear we know
exactly what what is the path that we
can take
um so I believe that in terms of
getting the license or build your own
projects it's it's more solid at the
moment what is uh it's not too clear for
us in Portugal is the products that they
have available on the pharmacy I believe
that that is one of the the main issues
that you have at the moment in Portugal
okay we will talk about products after
great
um Daniel
um framework opened up in Switzerland
last year how is everything going
a good question I am also going to try
to be brief but essentially the
framework before
it opened up last year was that you
needed a special permit from the federal
Office of Public Health to be able to
procure and get cannabis prescribed by a
doctor in Switzerland was quite uh
complicated from an administrative
perspective process so this changed last
year still complicated but what changed
is that cannabis was reclassified from a
prohibited narcotic to a class to a
controlled substance and now every
doctor in Switzerland can freely
prescribe medical cannabis which was a
huge step forward for for the medical
Market the problem is that doctors are
faced with a lot of challenges one of
the challenges for example is that they
don't know the biggest challenge they
don't know much about medical cannabis
don't know how to prescribe it there's a
lot of administrative burdens that their
with so it's going well and there is an
interest
however there hasn't been Mass adoption
by doctors yet but there is full and
full therapeutic freedom
for doctors to prescribe for whatever
ailment they they wish
but there is a lot of Education that
needs to happen and so I would say we're
a very big step forward but we're far
away from where we want to be you just
start at least you're starting
Switzerland or like in Spain that we are
still waiting for a politician to take
the first step but may I just ask Google
I mean it's uh good for you guys the
doctor can they can prescribe for the
first time and then they there is any
kind of uh
ranking in terms of medicine they can do
in the past there was a ranking you
basically had to be half dead and try
everything else first before you got
medical cannabis and today there's full
therapeutic Freedom which means it's in
the assessment of the doctor himself to
or herself to prescribe medical cannabis
however
they're also confronted with liability
issues so they still carry full
liability and I think that's one of the
reasons they're actually very reluctant
to prescribe cannabis and also in
Switzerland
the market really is not on I'm already
talking about the products but you know
in in Switzerland there is no real
market for cannabis flour so it's the
same in Portugal yeah
um so even you know thinking about
flower and smokeables uh we're far away
from that yeah I mean I was telling that
because in Portugal I mean there are
some some brothers available but it's
it's only I mean it's only possible to
prescribe as a last resort it doesn't
make any sense but it is what it is at
the moment and in terms of products you
have only two available which is nothing
comparing to what we can get in other
markets
um but again it's uh it's too short for
the the patients that are looking for
this kind of product and they and one
another thing that you said and I
completely agree with you we need to
have more more studies or more knowledge
for the the medical community so they
can be more confident
this is something that we all of us
should push a little bit more to be and
feel
okay can I add one more thing actually I
think it's very important to include
associations for example there's the
Swiss Society of cannabis in medicine in
Switzerland that he was mandated by the
federal office of public by the health
Ministry in Switzerland to basically put
together therapeutic guidance or
guidelines
that doctors can take and see for which
indication which medication setup would
make sense in which dosage and so on so
that's something that I would really try
to encourage in countries where it's
only just starting same as in
Switzerland now in its infancy I agree
okay thank you thank you guys and
Santiago can you tell us um which
requirements um
patients needs in in the United States
to become a patient yeah so in the U.S
we have more than 30 micro Industries
right it's not legal at the federal
level yet it remains a schedule one
substance so every state has its own
regulations the medical industry I would
use a different term I would use
therapeutic right because it is very
different from your typical medical
industry you don't go to the same doctor
you don't go to the same Pharmacy
et cetera et cetera so the first thing
that you need in order to become a
patient is is to be under the correct
ailment so usually when a Market opens
up in the United States it'll be similar
right you gotta be half dead in order to
to get a medical license but then as
soon as they become more comfortable
with the market they add something like
chronic pain
to the list of ailments which
significantly opens up this therapeutic
Market it's almost a way to test the
recreational Market still making people
go to doctors which the doctors
prescribing are usually doctors that
were retired and come out of retirement
in order to charge a hundred dollars per
prescription that they write so it's
it's fairly easy to get a a medical
license in uh in the states the
incentive to be a medical patient is
really just where there's no
recreational industry right other than
that one both Industries are available
or Alive then really the only incentive
to be a patient is to pay less taxes
but that's a little bit of the U.S
industry good and I would like to know
about Canada because just real real
quick on Canada I wanted to point out
that when we started it was also a last
case Resort you have to show you've
tried like everything else but we found
a way around it and one thing I always
try and tell people who are building
International markets is work with the
crappy rules you're given no matter how
crappy they are because we started
really crappy and we've kind of expanded
it to now it can be a first line of
treatment and and two things like pain
which is a little more subjective rather
than measured so I I would really
implore people to kind of work with it
even no matter how bad it is because
we've been there before
let us know Alex also about the which
kind of products patients can get in in
Canada yeah like when it started it was
only dry flour and uh I have a close
friend of mine whose daughter has a rare
form of epilepsy and he was converting
his flour into oil and that was actually
against the law and he could have been
going to jail and had his kid taken away
it's crazy to think about it now that
seems like a lifetime ago but it was
only flower we've come a long way now we
have oils now we have Edibles we have
all kinds of extracts I mean we have
limitations on it which we can get into
a little bit later when we talk about
that but uh it's we we have a lot of the
products now and it's come a long way
but there's still a long way to go uh
and yeah I'm interested to hear about
the kind of Portugal and swiss I know
Switzerland is really CBD only from what
I'm hearing uh but yeah every every
country is kind of starts very similar
and then just explodes in their own way
so I would love to hear some other yeah
for now for example in Portugal only
have available side effects and and the
flowers from from tilray and and that's
it I mean I know that there are a lot of
companies that are trying to license and
get the special authorization for their
products but that kind of process will
take at least one two years to get it
done which is a lot of time for any
investor to wait and especially because
I mean Portugal is a small country so
perhaps there is no no kind of advantage
of looking for our Market to license and
take so much time to to to do it but at
the same time it could be something that
then then you can expand for the rest of
the European countries
yeah I mean you can start in Portugal
and then you can try to adapt the same
the same authorization for the other
countries but anyway it will take you a
lot of time and I believe that that's
why it's it is taking so much to to get
new products in the in our Market
yeah so Switzerland is not just a CBD
Market but it's really well known for
being you know for the consumer markets
a big CBD Hub CBD producer of oils and
so on
um however on the medical sphere there's
also CBD that is actually prescribed by
form of magisterial preparation in
certain there's not many pharmacies that
do it but the few
CBD and obviously THC now as well and
we're talking mostly full spectrum in
Switzerland there's only two fully
licensed drugs which is epidiolex and
side effects in most cases they're used
off-label
however these so these and and also not
necessarily and always reimbursed by the
health insurance it's another subject
that we can touch upon but basically
most cannabis in Switzerland is
prescribed now with THC I would say and
by way of magisterial preparation which
the pharmacies have to be involved
his name is German and the U.S is all
over the place the U.S is great yeah I
mean if we're talking medical products
that have gone through clinical trials
and have FDA approved then we're talking
that sativax and epidiolex I personally
have never seen those products and if I
never see them in my life I would be
totally fine the medical industry which
again I would name therapeutic has any
type of product under the sun right a
lot of the Innovation comes from there
so you have
um also being micro Industries you have
states that allow everything then you
have other states that because of the
medical argument they wouldn't allow
flour and then the next step is to allow
flour but not smokeable only vaporized
so those States might not allow pre-roll
sales for example they will sell you
flower but technically you cannot roll
it and smoke it you need to vaporize it
I'm just curious because you said before
that cannabis doctors basically are
specialized doctors in cannabis would
they also prescribe other medication if
you have a
you know I'm just thinking about
neuropathic pain patient for example
that has a mix of maybe three four
various medications that the person
needs to take I would say specialized is
a loose term these are just doctors that
are coming out of retirement so they can
make a few hundred dollars a day so
they're as specialized as they need to
be in order and they will only prescribe
cannabis then they don't prescribe
cannabis they allow you to get a license
that allows you to enter a medical yeah
we say they authorize the use of
cannabis because cannabis doesn't have a
drug identification number so can't be
prescribed so we say it's they authorize
your the use and quickly just to point
out why are all the retired doctors
doing it because I was also wondering
why are all these old doctors doing it
the reason is they're not scared of
losing their license they don't they
don't care so it's these young guys
they're like oh I don't want the stigma
and I don't want people to know me as a
cannabis doctor these old guys are like
whatever will just cover my beers at the
golf course and they just they just go
and do it but hey that's how the
industry started
[Music]
in the US it's still a scheduled one
substance so it's still federally
illegal yeah yeah okay we've had a lot
just to point out we had a lot of
threats of doctors losing their license
but I could tell you in Canada no one
ended up losing their license no matter
how much investigations and everything
everyone's so scared it never happens so
you know it's more just threats
and another important issue guys what
about the insurance or Social Security
does the insurance cover the medical
cannabis
altar because I kind of made a career
out of this insurance uh thing I helped
a lot of military veterans uh help with
cannabis and I'm very proud of it and it
helped with a lot of conditions of PTSD
and removed a lot of their other
medications I mean that's a whole long
story but uh it made a lot of money for
the company I was a part of and then
people right away were like oh you're
just doing it for the money and some of
us were only doing it for the money to
be honest but I actually always really
cared about the veterans I knew them all
by name and I know how much it helped
them and and it changed their life so
military veterans are getting coverage
now we're starting to see some police
people get coverage
private insurance is covering the up to
two thousand dollars with Health Care
spending accounts which you can use for
like massages and other things so we're
starting to see a big move in that and
that's going to be a big game changer
when we talk about medical versus wreck
a little later I'll kind of explain a
little more but I mean we're all waiting
for the insurance train to come along uh
it's almost arrived but it's gonna come
like for example Germany Germany has
pharmacare already so insurance is going
to be a real big push of medical
cannabis Market internationally
eventually with more research of course
well
um as a matter of fact I mean we don't
have any or too much experience in the
with the product itself so I don't know
any kind of insurance company for
example that a private insurance company
that can uh help the the patients in
this matter I know that our health
authority can co-found this kind of of
products but until now there is no
no support in this internal products
unfortunately
now just before I come to Switzerland I
have a question for you Alex because you
mentioned it depends what kind of
basically patient population you come
from is it more the patient population
that matters whether you're in the
police force or whether you're a veteran
rather than your personal so what
happened good question it all started
with post-traumatic stress disorder the
veterans it showed how much it helped
and now others are like wait a minute we
have PTSD so RCMP Royal Canadian
mountain police there are certain type
of police so they're now trying it and
uh again the results are so amazing
there's something called polypharma
where you take 12 medications to help
with like two conditions cannabis
replaces that and we watched that happen
so I think what's happening is once
people are seeing it we're starting to
see more insurance coverage and that's
the importance of like research and
education because once people see it
they see actually it could be very
beneficial and save the money because
they're all about making money insurance
companies and that's okay we have to
show them that cannabis can actually be
cost effective for them and get people
back to work faster
it's it's similar in Switzerland where
we see that medical cannabis can replace
one of the pitches basically of the
industry to say there's a possibility
with medical cannabis to replace other
medication in a multi-medication setup
um but and that's the economic
background that needs to be shown and
evidenced
um but in terms of health insurance it's
very important also to show the
individual patient journey and to
document that Journey with strong data
and the better you can underwrite that
data and send your special because the
basis is it's not reimbursed that's
where it starts so you need to convince
your health insurance on an individual
basis that it is actually helping the
patient with with health and that it's
also economical
please do collect the data that's so
important we weren't really doing that
that much yeah I think that could be a
really good good start because the data
speaks for itself you can't argue with
the data exactly and we've been doing
that with with a client of mine in one
specific case and it's been working
really well and we wrote down all the
data and so on and the patient got
reimbursement there's also a patients
Association that helps with the
processes
um which is very important as well but
we're getting there and the insurances
are opening up they realize that this
could have economic value for them as
well
I knew it
okay thank you and Alex I would like to
ask you um how do the recreational and
medical markets collect six and
how was the transaction yeah so this is
a question I get asked a lot uh you know
when I'm in Germany and even here uh
people are saying like what happens when
you go from medical to recreational and
I'll try to kind of give you a very
brief answer to this is that
um it was very tricky a lot of people
who were pretending they were medical
quickly took off their medical head
burned it and just put on the wreck hat
and he was like yippee let's go make
millions it didn't work out that way but
you realize what people's kind of
intentions are very quickly
um and like there's a few kind of
examples like for example like
milligrams of THC for for medical uh is
the same as with recreational like it's
still the 10 10 milligrams for Edibles
as an example and the way things are
sold that's another big difference like
with medical we were selling it directly
to patients from licensed producers now
with recreational we sell it directly to
the government so for example with my
Edibles company loosh what we do is we
sell it to the government and then the
government sells it to the recreational
stores on the medical aside we can sell
directly like for example with my
Pharmacy hybrid Farm we sell directly to
hybrid farm so medical does have a lot
of advantages but we need to educate
people on it like you can get reimbursed
on your taxes by doing medical so
there's a few things like that but we
believe with insurance coverage with
increase of milligrams of THC for
Edibles as an example uh for uh there's
just a few things that we're waiting for
like uh taxes we're taxed equally for
medical and recreational but if
something is a medicine in Canada there
are no taxes on medicine so it feels
very weird to say all medical is not
taxed while medicine is not taxed except
cannabis so these are some of the kind
of growing pains that we're going
through from that transition but it's
still great and really like Germany and
all these other countries that are doing
this transition I think can learn from
it and it's it's very exciting to kind
of see and now medical is going to
slowly pick up again and Rex is going to
Plateau off and hopefully we'll have a
good Market fingers crossed thank you
thank you what about in the United
States Santiago in the U.S I think it's
very similar to Canada since again it's
not a medical market so you don't have
to take any products through clinical
trials the standard of quality for wreck
and Med is very similar I'll talk about
Colorado as an example so there's some
states that like it's hard to understand
the difference right no difference in
milligram percentage no difference in
traceability in Colorado they decided to
separate medical and recreational at the
seed which makes business Logistics a
little complex but you have to decide
when you plant that seed or take the
Clone if it's going to be medical
throughout its whole journey and only be
sold in a medical dispensary or if it's
going to be recreational even though the
product could be exactly the same in
Colorado there is a difference between
milligram for example an edible on the
medical side can be up to 500 milligrams
whereas on the recreational side it
could only be up to a hundred and tax
are different as well medical does get
taxed that's important lower than the
recreational yeah and that that's really
important you know one thing that was
driving us crazy is that you can buy a
bottle of oil that has a thousand
milligrams and just chug it down but we
can make we make like a loss energy this
has 10 milligrams and the government's
really scared about how many pieces but
I said wait a minute you have a thousand
milligram oil you can chug you have to
eat you know 100 of these lozenges to
have the same amount think about how
much work that is and you're worried
about protecting so you know I think one
thing that's if you've been here all day
you've heard about Spain and all the
different countries you know the
government they make rules that don't
make sense and that's normal you're not
going to get away from it but we almost
have to work with our stupid rules and
slowly let them figure it out themselves
that what the right answer is banging
your head against the wall and spending
money on lobbying could be helpful but
ultimately the only way they're going to
change is by seeing that the sky is not
falling that's kind of what happened
when wreck happened feel like oh now
everyone's going to get high when
medical happens oh now everyone's gonna
and they realize the same people who are
getting high before are still getting
high and the people that weren't before
are still not that interested so you
know that's kind of what happens
requirements to to get a medical license
um yeah I mean it's uh in fact our uh
our regulates are really solid I mean we
know exactly what we can do in order to
achieve the the license I mean you need
to comply with the ghcp or the GMP
depending depending on what you you want
to grow or to manufacture
um getting the the security done I mean
traceability also is really really
important I mean our health I mean the
health authority is looking for
traceability quality of the product and
making sure that you are not doing it
for the black market for example
um so I would say that the security the
quality and the traceability are the the
key factors to get the license obviously
you need to have a really strong team
the knowledge of what you are doing next
because otherwise you will just be there
and your your your projects will be on
hold for eternity for example it happens
it is happening actually at the moment
some companies are trying to figure out
how they will move forward with the with
the project but yeah in terms of
requirements it's quite quite simple
um but yeah anyway it takes a lot of
time again to to do everything because
even if you have a project and a
business plan you know exactly what you
are doing you need to go I mean you need
to build all the project all the
facilities getting the people there
working really hard on the Sops to to
comply with the ghcp or GMP
um and only after that you get the
license and you can start growing and
you can start selling so I would say
that the business plan is really
important because you'll spend a lot of
money in the meantime and you don't have
any kind of Revenue so but in terms of
from the requirements itself it's uh
it's quite tough understandable and
um achievable and like in Spain you you
need to have the the product sell salt
already yeah yeah I mean you need to
have someone uh from the the the Medical
Market I mean they need to be already
licensed it it have someone that it
intends to buy your products I mean it's
not a binding contract but again you
need to have someone that it is
interesting in buying your product as
well yeah okay actually the same as in
Colombia uh Colombia also made a similar
rule which we won't get into here but it
doesn't make sense it doesn't work
people can't buy a product eight months
in advance when they can they need to
buy it today they don't know what the
price is going to be in eight months
exactly so you know unfortunately
sometimes people make rules that they
don't actually intend on working and we
have to always be very careful of that
uh this is this is at least in Portugal
is a is a pharmaceutical Market you know
so they want to what we try to tell is
they want papers you know they want the
seops all the the non-binding contracts
all the the concerts with a lot of the
the people that are working on their
facilities so they like papers that's
easy just roadblocks and not to get all
conspiracy theory here but like for
example Germany uh the pharmaceutical
industry has a seat at the table in
cannabis legalization so when you put
someone at the table that has a vested
interest in your lack of success it
creates a lot of problems so whenever
people wonder like wait why are they
making these rules these are stupid it's
not going to work it's because usually
they're made by people that don't want
them to work and we have to understand
it and work with it not just say ah and
Sue and get pissed off and just say okay
we're going to make it work and slowly
change it the other way exactly yeah
okay but they introduced a new system
which is like two tiered so you have to
get the general license to be able to
produce and cultivate cannabis and then
a single cultivation license on top of
that for each grow which makes it a bit
more complicated but it's it's actually
a good system and then you can transfer
and sell that to another company that
also has a license to handle narcotic
drugs and from there you can actually
start do distribution you need an extra
license to export and this is maybe
where an interesting thing happens is
where the various terms of what medical
cannabis means in Switzerland and in
nearby countries diverge so in
Switzerland the production of medical
cannabis has to be under ghcp
rules at least the flower
but the interesting part is that the
drying then and the drying part is is
considered a GMP step okay and in some
other countries the drying process is
not considered GMP so but essentially I
would say if if one if you want to be a
serious player in this market you need
to have a GMP set up you need to be able
to dry your product you can Outsource
that step and then from there on you can
go into distribution that's one of the
things by the way that changed in this
legislation last year is that
Switzerland now is a or swiss producers
can now export medical cannabis okay
which I would like to know and as just
one thing so yeah in Portugal for
example you can you can be ghcp
certified and you can do all the process
from seed to cell so we don't need to be
GMB certified to to try the pro to try
the flower but obviously if you want to
you can do that although it will take
you an extra time an extra license so
normally the companies will start with
the jacp and you want two years they
they move forward with the GMP but it's
it's hard to to get it and what about
the final products you can produce in
Portugal is flower instructions I mean
in Portugal you can do I would say
whatever you want with the independently
of the level of THC or even CBD it's a
matter of telling the authorities what
you are you are growing or manufacturing
and after that they will they will grant
you the the license okay good
um and for um Alexander and Santiago and
because the regulations in Canada and US
they've been going on for for a long
time what would you change in the law it
is something you would yeah so I'm gonna
go before Alex because I think he'll
speak longer than me but uh in the U.S I
think the majority of people don't or
didn't know what gacp or GMP meant
because they didn't need to right
they're different across States and
Florida they gave out seven licenses to
begin so you needed like 30 years of
agricultural land 50 million Escrow in
the bank in order to get a license
obviously it's uh you know only a few
people can play in a state like that in
Oklahoma you needed two thousand dollars
in a dream and anybody could get a
cannabis license and the products you
can produce are pretty much uh any
products so in the US it's definitely an
interesting an interesting mix of of
Dynamics and what I would change to your
point is probably raise the level of
professionalism in the medical industry
without completely killing it the way
that other countries are are doing right
but we we definitely need to at least be
under gacp and GMP standards if we're
going to call the industry a medical
industry so I would I would
at least want a little more
differentiation between recreational and
medical now I'm grateful for the way
things happen because it opened up the
market significantly for for good and
bad mostly good
pioneer as well I think in Switzerland
also there's going to be some
differentiation in terms of products
because you've been asking before about
the legalized market and so we're also
doing that in Switzerland we're in on in
a process of legalizing uh non-medical
adult use yeah
so that's gonna happen but
I think one of the differentiators will
probably be that cannabis flour for
smoking and also for vaporization will
probably be more uh pretty prevalent in
the um in the recreational you know
non-medical markets that makes sense and
and other products like oils tinctures
you know capsules and and all other
forms maybe even Edibles at some stage
they will be reserved for the medical
Market yeah as it should be and just
quickly on that 85 of all our products
at the pharmacy are sold are not flour
and I'm so happy to hear that it took a
long time so super fast rapid fire I had
to make a quick note on it because
honestly I can think of a thousand
things that I would change but just
super quickly uh dangers of the wrong
investor you talk about how expensive
this is if you find the wrong investor
you're screwed you find an investor who
wants their money ASAP or pretends they
do oh we're going to give you time but
then as soon as they invest they start
whipping you that's going to kill you so
one thing I would change is maybe better
access to the funding for this because
that's very important we're finding ways
to make it less expensive to do uh also
the challenge is the illicit market and
the government I think a lot of times
people are looking at competition there
is no competition when you're building a
market you need to actually be friends
with the competitors and build this
together because your competitors are
really the old way of doing things and
also uh the government so working
together and making the pie and then
cutting it up so I know we'll have too
much more time but changing of
perception is really important 75
percent of people are buying legal
cannabis now it used to be 35 in 2019
2018. so we've come a long way and
that's also going to help change
um so hopefully we left some time for
questions from the audience
[Music]
yes
yes of course okay everybody in the back
she's got she's been waving her hand
in five minutes so
you always gotta leave time for
questions for these fine people to to
see what we can tell them
and we're available after also and at
the after party but probably talk to us
early at the after party uh for best
answers yeah if you have any questions
go to Alex yeah I'm joking I'm around as
well
hi
um uh I'm Laura I come from
you and I just moved to Spain this past
September I was an acupuncturist and I
work with people with cancer for the
last 10 years
a lot of my people did the RSO oil
protocol they decided not to do the
chemotherapy
and some of these people are still well
and alive so I can't wait
until there is enough research to
realize that we have a medicine
to stop cancer
so where are you guys with the data the
people
is this been talked about with the
chemotherapy companies where are we with
all of this thank you all done with a
real quick answer on this in general I
never talk about curing cancer with
cannabis because obviously there's not
enough research but we help a lot of
side effects of treatment and uh symptom
management and like dealing with like
sleep pain things of the treatment so
that's the first thing I there's a Dr
Sanchez out of Madrid that has done some
unbelievable research about cancer cells
committing suicide with cannabinoids but
again super preliminary and the problem
is we can't build a business of an
industry of cannabis with stories like
this because the right away the doctor's
like ah you know so I never talked about
curing anything it got us to this point
I'm super excited to hope that this is
going to be something but it it's
yeah yeah no it could be very useful in
RSO shout out to Rick Simpson Canadian
uh who uh you know that's named after
him who still survived I told him he
only had a few months left to live and
he's still alive and they named an oil
after him so there's obviously something
very special there
um and we need to talk about it but we
don't lead with it if we lead with it
right away people are like ah yeah this
is all snake oil I don't know snake oil
means anything to anyone here is that is
that a European thing too or no is that
just us so anyways so just people think
it's [__] I would comment real quick
I think unfortunately the United States
is not the right industry to collect
that type of data because they're too
far gone in their therapeutic quasi
recreational medical industry so they
don't have the incentives really to need
to collect this data and do these
studies but they do have enough people
consuming and enough similar stories
like this where if the data were to be
collected it could be completely world
changing but I hope that other countries
that are still trying to push these
regulations forward do put these studies
and this data first in order to change
that stigma quicker yeah I would I'm
half Israeli so I'm a bit biased here
but I would also recommend to check out
some of the research of uh
Professor daddy made at the University
of Haifa maybe there's a few others as
well but I know there's uh being for
example he's been talking about and a
study that he made for colon cancer and
where the use of certain strains led to
a retraction of metastasis in the body
and stuff like that I mean I've heard a
lot of stories but obviously and I agree
fully with what Alex said that
that's not how the industry should
position itself now there's there's so
much research that needs to be done
there's lower hanging fruit with things
we know for sure like chronic pain like
sleep like nausea increase of appetite
these are like for sure easy ones and
the doctors are behind it so that's why
but Laura happy to talk to you after I
have some more thoughts on it and find
me for sure also from personal
experience with friends of mine who have
been through chemotherapy and have used
cannabis extensively and it really
helped them during
um yeah during during that time
fantastic we have another one over here
yeah
hello I have a question for Daniel but
also for all the panel
um I would like to know specifically for
Switzerland but I can see that Germany
also is taking the same direction why
for the medical Market the government
allows importation of products from
outside from Cannabis but for the
recreational not I mean the the testing
that is done in the recreation is the
only local production Germany when when
they draw the first proposal of the law
it seems to go in that direction uh why
is that I mean because it should be the
opposite because the recreational
consumers would like to have some
variety yeah I can answer that pretty
quickly in Switzerland recreational
Cannabis or I would say non-medical
adult use cannabis as I've been taught
is not legal yet so in the context of
scientific studies there are now pilot
studies that were opened up there's the
first trials in Basel where you know
cannabis red cannabis is being dispensed
in pharmacies it's essentially there's a
a substitute there's a clause in that
ordinance that says if not enough
production can be procured locally to
satisfy those trials in the context of a
scientific study then it can resort to
importation and we're not there yet
because Switzerland obviously is in a
position and has enough companies that
can procure relatively low levels and
low amounts of of cannabis and in a
medical space obviously it's it's an
open market because it's medical and we
also have the international legal
Frameworks to facilitate these
cross-border movements of of medical
cannabis and also just really quick the
answer is very simple for you and we can
talk after longer version but it's the
answers business and they're protecting
their business I come from a country
where we're protecting our business
right now we don't allow for importation
of cannabis and a lot of people are
pretty upset that Canada is exporting
but we're not allowing for import we're
protecting our Industries which people
spend hundreds of millions of dollars on
and many investors already lost so much
money so it's a way of protecting the
industry and the German tender hasn't
even come up yet there's rumors of this
we'll see what happens but you know what
whatever they do will start that
Germany's capable of producing all the
varieties you've ever dreamed of at the
best qualities may be a little more
expensive because they have a higher
cost there but everything is possible
don't let anyone tell you otherwise
that's for sure I can just chip in one
more salt as a previous Commodities
Trader I'm actually very much a
proponent of cross-order trade I'm not a
big fan of protectionism I don't think
it's something that that will last for a
long time but in these industries I
really think that you have to brace
yourself for a period at least a period
of some form mixed or full protectionism
when the markets open up and in Germany
it seems to go in the same direction I
would like to say as an enjoyer of
Moroccan hash
and Spanish wine I would also like to
see global
you know what I mean right African
sativas I like Moroccan hash I like
California weed you understand why well
that's why that's why we're here I can't
wait I can't wait to go to the store in
California and buy a temper Neo and some
Moroccan it would be great we're out of
time let's hear it again for our panel
Guillermo hey everybody thank you so
much and I'm sure if you have more
questions you can talk to them outside
the hall