and uh I just want to thank you all so
much for being here today at beautiful
Lake bled I've got to tell you guys all
that I envisioned this the first time I
thought about this event was five years
ago
and I thought uh it's time it'll be time
soon to come to Slovenia and help
Slovenia my wife is uh Slovenian yes
so uh it will be better I promise and
stop you slovenians are so cute uh but
uh uh uh yeah so
um uh so we have a great event for you
uh I'd like to say a couple things I'd
like to thank the Tallman group um
that's that's our yep all the people in
the Tallman group that helped help uh
put this event together I'd like to give
a big shout out to the director of the
event a lot of you uh had uh
Communications with her Elisa Vietnam
please give it up for Lisa
um
and I also want to thank uh our uh
development director for Tallman group
who's running media today yakayej uh
let's give it up for yaka he's making a
lot of things happen here today
but most of all I want to thank you guys
because you're here and what are we have
a goal and that's to modernize cannabis
policy in Slovenia
and I think we all know in Slovenia what
uh some of the circumstances are or have
been in the past Slovenia has been maybe
a little behind on their cannabis policy
reform but that all changes now and it
changes because we are all here together
as an industry as a community pushing uh
this public policy forward so it's very
important that when we push public
policy forward for Slovenia that we
understand slovenia's sensitive
ecosystem that's not just ecologically
that's socially we're a small country
we're a special country and everything
we do has to be special so people don't
know that when they come to Slovenia and
everyone seems to be oh my God they
think it's uh uh some Outback uh Far
East Outback and here you come to
Slovenia and you get this and
everybody's very impressed with
everything Slovenia does
it's not it's very safe everybody is
very friendly and it happens to be my
favorite country in the world so I just
want to thank all you slovenians for
letting me live in your country and be
part of your culture just thank you very
much for that I really appreciate it
pinch pinch me because I feel like I'm
dreaming every day in Slovenia it's
absolutely amazing you
can get an event for you get ready we
are taking things to the next level and
I'm about to introduce you so I'll see
you over there you guys I'd like to
introduce our emcee for the day
um he's our MC and brand ambassador for
ICBC for 10 years I've no I met him in
1994 in San Francisco when we were in
bands and played basketball and did all
those fun things kids do but without
further Ado please give a warm Slovenian
Welcome to our host and MC
um
[Music]
thank you
that's it that's all I know
uh thank you all so very much for coming
in Alex said a bunch of things it's
fantastic I just want to make a couple
of quick announcements if you need this
uh this conference will be in English
for the most part uh so if you need a
translation we have translators
available you get the headpiece and uh
you know but listen here everyone here
your English is better than mine so I'm
always impressed
um also we're accepting donations to
help the flood victims from other parts
of the country if you go into the
exhibitor hall there's a place where you
can donate and that would be great and
uh we'd like to thank the Tomlin group
again and uh party tonight
at the castle
right there'll be a shuttle it'll take
everybody up and then you have to find
your own way home but no no
dagger down the hall no but you'll be we
have shuttles that'll bring you back too
and there's gonna be a great time
magnifico is going to be there
he's fantastic