to the ICBC this is our third iteration
in uh Barcelona we started this out
about seven eight years ago I started it
in Oregon and I thought one day we're
going to become International and
eventually we became International our
two big events are here in
Barcelona and our Flagship event is in
Berlin uh this summer June 29th and 30th
and that will be our sixth edition in
Berlin uh the ICBC
we only have one rule and that's don't
be a dick and treat everybody with
respect and love because the ICBC is
more than just a conference we're a
family and we are
we're very we're in honor of the plan
right the plane the cannabis plant
because if it wasn't for the cannabis
plant we would not all be here together
so cannabis does a lot of things for the
world whether it's medical whether it's
environmental
um whether it's just to be able to chill
with your friends and have a good time
and of course we know incarcerating
people for using cannabis is a
ridiculous idea and prohibition does not
work
we're here for business and the business
I found out the more you perpetuate the
business the more you perpetuate the
politics and move the public policy
forward and that's what we're here to do
we're here to do business to approach to
talk to each other to uh uh to create
with each other and today there will be
tens of millions of dollars of business
that gets done and manifest itself
immediately or residually so I just want
to say thank you my name is Alex Rogers
I am the founder of the ICBC and I want
to give my heartfelt thanks to you guys
and I'd like to have you guys give
yourself permit a round of applause for
being here
it really is an honor to be here in
Barcelona um without further Ado I would
like to introduce our MC for the day and
he is our emcee for all ICBC events for
the last 30 we have done over the eight
last eight years ladies and Gentlemen
please give it up for um
[Music]
[Applause]
one more time for Alex who put the whole
thing together man it's his idea his
genius
I don't I speak English
um
right you're more all right but uh
couple quick announcements first of all
so that
gotten a ticket yet we're selling some
here you can get them for like 200 Euros
you can get it off the Eventbrite app
you can talk to Jesse she'll hook you up
um also tickets for Berlin are on sale
for uh Barcelona for since you've come
out here today you can get a discounted
ticket for Berlin which is going to be
in late June and it's twice as big as
this it's our biggest event and it's
fantastic and we'd love to see you
everywhere just follow us around the
world we'll follow you as well
what four times as big according to Alex
so it's it's it's big it's big big big
big big big big four times as big big
four I said four bigs big big big
there you go