all right and so we're ready to begin
now I think uh man when Alex told me
about uh our this first Speaker we were
all very excited uh no for real for real
it's an honor it's a big deal it's not
every day that you get the secretary for
help for the entire country of Slovenia
to come up and give some welcoming
remarks so it is an honor and a pleasure
and a delight and a special thing and so
please put your hands together and
welcome Dr Mecca paragi
thank you
thank you Alex thank you tall so dear
participants of the international
cannabis business conference is teamed
organizers we are pleased and honored to
host such an important conference on the
topic of cannabis here in our beautiful
country
and that is why I want to present and
especially warm welcome from the cabinet
of prime minister of the Republic of
Slovenia Dr Robert golub
we can confidently say that this
conference is being held at the best
possible time according to our data
around 40 percent of slovenians have had
experiences with products derived from
the cannabis plant
as you know we have reflected this fact
in our Coalition agreement and decided
to include the implementation of use of
cannabis in medicine in our program
our wish is to demolish the black market
with the introduction of new legal
regulations which would subsequently
create a legal way for slowing patients
and other
users to purchase and consume cannabis
products that will be safe and
irreproachable from the medical
standpoint
furthermore the production of such
products will be regulated and
controlled under watchful eye of the
Slovenian government
we have had several important Slovenian
associations advocate for this change in
legislation to us for instance
Association of oncology patients of
Slovenia the association Europa Donna
several Slovenian pediatricians and of
course several patients and users who
have identified that the overwhelming
health benefits of cannabis outlay
archaic criminal viewpoint on this plant
this old perspective needs to be changed
especially due to Scientific evidence
that the health benefits of using of
cannabis
we wish that we would hear less and less
medieval accusations about the use of
cannabis products and we hope that
Common Sense will prevail
I'm personally most interested about the
scientific research on the topic of
cannabinoids
and we'll be listening with interest to
all those panelists lists speaking today
you truly have gathered the best experts
to shed light on this topic I wish you a
successful and knowledge field
conference thank you
thank you so much
40 of uh
slovenians have tried cannabis
so I feel like I know most of them
and that's just I've been here two days