uh to bring conference greetings from
the office of the prime minister of
Slovenia we have the state Secretary for
public health care and Public Health in
the office of the Prime Minister please
welcome Dr Meta
[Applause]
paragi dear participants of the
international cannabis business
conference esteemed organizers it has
been a year since since I greeted you at
this leading Global business conference
of the Cannabis industry I am sincerely
pleased to once again greet you on
behalf of the Office of Prime Minister
Dr Robert golob and extend a warm
welcome to you all last year I promised
changes in the field of cannabis
legislation here in Slovenia and I am
proud to say that in the past year we
have made significant strides towards a
more modern European cannabis regulation
something that was not possible in the
last decade due to various reasons and
interests of course it is also result of
developments in our country as well as
in Europe and in the world after Decades
of rejection Europe has fully restored
cannabis's legal status as a medicine
this year with the historic inclusion of
the Cannabis flower and canabidol in the
European
pharmacopea at home numerous
organizations cancer patients
Association Europa Dona many other
patients as well as the informed public
and medical professionals have
increasingly been calling for the
regulation of cannabis for medical
purposes medical cannabis use is topic
that is
gaining uh more attention worldwide as
cannabis represents a real supportive
medicine for many people facing
conditions such as chronic pain epilepsy
multiple sclerosis and the side sight
effects of
chemotherapy why would we deny patients
and scientific Community Access to
Resource that could improve the lives of
many by fully regulating the use of
cannabis for medical purposes we will
provide Slovenian patients with easier
safer and more accessible paths to this
form of therapy currently due to the ban
of cannabis cultivation we are dependent
on importing these products which limits
access treatment and raises
costs however since cannabis is still
highly criminalized here in Slovenia and
the fact that there are numerous often
conflicting expert and non-expert
opinions about its use we decided to ask
slovenians about their views on this
issue through the use of
referendum as you may know in June of
this year we voted in referendum on two
questions the cultivation and processing
of cannabis for medical purposes and
cultivation and possession for personal
use voters approved the cultivation and
proess of cannabis for medical purposes
with
66.5% of the
vote the results of the vote on personal
use were closer with
51.5% voters voting in
favor based on the will of Voters we
immediately began working with the
parliament members and esteemed experts
to draft a modern European outline for
legislation on these two issues we
established a group of experts from the
fields of medicine Pharmacy
biotechnology legal Sciences with the
goal for ensuring multi-disciplinary
approach to resolving cannabis release
related issues and ensuring that the new
legislation is professionally prepared
consistent and aligned with the latest
findings both domestic and foreign
experts in the legisl legislative
approach we will follow the examples of
you member states that have already made
the necessary changes in their
legislation slovenia's current uh
legislation does at least in theory
allow the use of cannabis products for
medical purposes but this has never
truly come to fruition in practice this
is evident through its very limited
scope and numerous obstacles among other
things the position of agency for
medicinal products and medical devices
also poses a problem as it claims that
the use of cannabis for medical purposes
is permitted in accordance with medicine
act pH Pharmacy practice act as well as
regulations which is correct however
agency argues that that due to the lack
of prescription guidelines except for
terminally ill patients the prescription
of cannabinoids for other medical
condition is not permissible in our
opinion this tense is incorrect as there
are extensive prescription guidelines
prepared by countries with comparable
levels of health care for instance
Netherlands United Kingdom Canada
Australia and so on here I must also
emphasize the past un just disregard for
professional guidelines prepared by the
pioneer of cannabis treatment in
Slovenia oncologist Dr yina
Cher with the updated legal regulation
we will also accelerate scientific
research in this field Ian research
institutes have immense potential which
we are not utilizing enough instead of
straightening domestic science and
developing Innovative medical approaches
we are dependent on imported products
which are not only a missed opportunity
but also hinders progress in scientific
understanding of the risk and benefits
of
cannabinoids it is a fact that cannabis
use was never sucess successfully
prevented by prohibition rather the
opposite is true therefore we must
appropriately adapt our legislation in
more sensible and pragmatic way with
appropriate legal regulation we can
better protect patients from the black
market and educate young people about
its
use the new legislation must therefore
comprehensively regul the field of
medical cannabis from cultivation
processing possession and distribution
to prescribing methods as well as Define
the limits of using can for personal use
as far as personal Calibus is concerned
the experience of other countries
clearly shows that sensible regulation
is crucial instead of risking the
consequences of unregulated Market which
is often associated with illegal
activities and dangerous products
legalization would reduce health risk
and most importantly more efficiently
more efficiently protect young people
with full responsibility we are
fulfilling our prom and preparing a new
modern legislation in light with other
developed European countries which will
allow our CI to legally access safe and
professionally supported cannabis
products for their health and personal
well-being thank you
[Applause]