here to discuss uh can uh continental
and international cannabis policy we are
pleased and
honored to have the National Drug
coordinator from the Czech
Republic right and so let's hear it
for
yri let's hear it I do my best
good morning
everybody I have a
question if you allow me to to have a
morning exercise to raise the hand who
in this room
thinks that prohibition actually should
remain okay
what do you think do you does this
prohibition serve any good
purpose maybe maybe not I think it's
quite important to to speak about the
fact where we
are um I've been around for 35 years as
a practitioner working with people in
addiction and prevention and 15 years in
policy
making uh directly accountable to the
Prime Minister some with six prime
minister uh
uh giving reports and monitoring reports
of all drugs but alcoh Alcohol Tobacco
gambling as well in my country and
digital addictions at this
moment uh so looking at data I have a
Monitoring Center under my office as
well um so I've been looking at the data
over and over and over and over and it
took me several years to understand
what's act what is the the the the
situation with prohibition what what
actually
prohibition did to to the whole
situation I think it's quite important
to to
analyze uh what is actually possible and
what is not
um this is the UK cure I'm not sure if
you uh have seen this it's uh it's uh in
several reports it's written by uh the
emcdda Monitoring Center you might have
heard about this uh Monitoring Center
it's a agency uh run by European
commission and it's based in Lisbon and
actually it says that when we look any
at any regulation
we have two extremes one extreme is
unregulated
Market absolutely unlimited access and
we used to have this with alcohol
even sell
underage
uh uh with tobacco as well it's I grew
up in the in the time where as a child I
was able to go to a shop and buy
cigarettes and buy alcohol no problem
was not allowed in restaurants but it
was allowed in chobs today it's not
possible I mean not possible in inverted
Comas because sometimes it's uh it's
very easy for
teenagers and on the other hand it's the
uh prohibition prohibition Prohibition
in terms as we as we know it in illicit
drugs and we experience in other parts
in the world with
alcohol which is under criminal
sanctions can have prohibited uh items
or Goods or or food for example which is
not uh prohibited under the the criminal
sanctions but with cannabis and Other
Drugs we have it under criminal
sanctions Czech Republic as as many of
you might know is the one of the
countries with the most liberal um
liberal laws we decriminalize position
for personal use a few decades
ago but on the other hand we still have
14% of people in prison for drugs
offenses how is that
possible
uh it doesn't mean that 40 14% of the
people who are in
prison is represents the the amount of
criminal activities it's only three drug
drug um uh drug criminal activities is
only 3% but 14% of of the people in
prison is because these people serve
longer sentences than many other many
other prisoners longer sentences than
sexual assault child abuse uh domestic
violence this is the the the fact of
current state of plate still today more
than half of these people are for
cannabis
that's across the the the EU EU and it's
across the world because it's very
simple when people are caught with 20 30
40 plants it's kilos if you for example
in Czech Republic we produce
methamphetamin people are caught with
with methamphetamin with few grams they
get two years in prison if you have 20
kilos you get you are in higher uh
paragraphs and you get five years
so uh
but in fact in Czech Republic for longer
time already we have medical cannabis
since
2013 I believe we are we were globally
the the the the first country allowing
medical cannabis according to the law I
mean of course you know that Holland and
few other countries did it before us but
legis first legislation was uh approved
by the incb inspection which is the
inspection for un bodies un
ODC uh on CND
2013 2021 we we allowed 1% of thhc in in
so-called technical cannabis or
hemp
uh this year we passed a bill uh through
the Parliament and it was notified by
European Union which we call psychom
modulatory substances which is empty
list actually we created a new category
we have uh for products which are for
human consumption uh you have food you
have medic medicines and then now we
have third category in the EU uh which
is psychom modulatory substances and
under this bill I mean this is an empty
list and the government will put
substances on on this list after some uh
some
evaluation it's actually two list one is
the evaluating list for for maximum two
years and then there is a permanent list
uh which will allow probably first
instance will be Crome and uh we we
talking about the thhc I mean the
products with thhc up to one or maybe 2%
and uh and uh we also talking about hhc
for example ex and other products of of
similar
sort um we ban hhc recently only until
the end of this year waiting for this
bill to come and after we we say okay we
will probably regulate with specialized
shops uh and very strict regulations
stricter than than alcohol I stricter
than
tobacco
uh and we are waiting I I uh drafted a
new bill
for
um
regulating nonmedical use of cannabis
more than
1% uh we talking about 20% of
THC and that should be introduced to the
parliament this this
year and I'll explain what's the
troubles around
that but before before I'll get into the
legal
battle uh I want to also
say we have to be aware that it's not
only legal battles that we fight in and
it's not
only um it's not only ideology that we
fight in we also figh in or battling I
don't know how to put it we
are standing in the whole process
against other in
Industries legal and
illegal of course most obvious one
alcohol uh I mean I remember a couple of
years ago my colleague sat with alcohol
uh Industries and you have uh of course
beer you have wine and you have uh the
spirits yes they are usually divided
they fight against each other when but
when it comes to to cannabis they're
very United and one of the leaders of
the spirit industry said
we will make everything and we put all
the possible money to stop your your uh
cannabis
regulation without shame uh directly
told us in in in a in a public u in a
public
debate uh of course we have illegal
industry which is
extremely
rich and um I have
a maybe some some of you already heard
me speaking about it I have this
Declassified EU I mean EU CIA report
which speaks about people like vikor
ianov I don't know if you heard about
vikor Ivanov vikor ianov was uh um my
counterpart in Russian Federation the
National Drug coordinator which clearly
speaks about this report C speaks how
and he was the chief of staff at some
point in in Putin's office office and
this reports clearly speaks how since
80s when he became the the the the boss
of the department and then Putin was the
boss of the uh the
KGB uh how they started
um to the disgrace of many people I me
to to dislike of many people in the KGB
so I don't want to blame KGB as such but
to to to the to the dislike of many
people in kgv these people started uh
organizing uh the whole the whole um uh
shipping through St Petersburg cocaine
uh heroin from from uh from
Afghanistan I I have to I don't have
time to speak about it I spent uh a long
time in Afghanistan myself and in
Colombia Bolivia so that would be long
stories to speak about this one if
anybody is interested I have the report
here so we standing against legal
Industries very powerful legal
industries of course you will hear some
of the industries from Big Pharma as
well uh not been very happy about it we
have um alcohol industry and then we
have illegal Industries which are as
power powerful as the legal ones using
also legal um legal um uh instruments
against it like campaign for
example um so that's not easy
and
then uh of course we have sorry I'll
skip this then we have um
uh then we have uh the the international
uh International laws and then we have
European laws which is which is even com
more complicated for
us stand
here so uh
I'll I won't go to to all
the
uh so this is a council
conclusion the framework made by the
European Union which actually says that
apart from personal possession for
personal use it's not allowed and it
even sets a number of years or or it
says the legal standards how countries
in the EU should criminalize possession
of of what drugs of course sale and and
production so apart from personal
position all the other activities
according the EU law is not allowed and
it's supposed to be criminalized
so that's this is where we are at this
moment Al but uh uh we have some
hopes
uh in check views we said that uh we
should look at it differently and that's
what we push in we are not the only one
in in the EU as you know and our
first uh
highlighted idea uh idea I would say
it's not only idea because we know what
to do we have all the data we have all
the best practice how to regulate
substances that pose any risks in terms
of of psychotropic
effects so we said the first thing
should be regulating substances
according to their
risks whether they are legal or illegal
today uh if we look at risks uh levels
of alcohol and comparing it with
cannabis I think I don't have to to to
go into details about this
uh of course we we need to look at
preventative prevention of of the
effects of illegal Market we know in
alcohol we know in tobacco the illegal
Market would be the worse why do we
think that with cannabis it's it's
different that prohibition could help in
any way so of course illegal Market has
lot of
enormous problems one of them is the
next next
uh next
sentence uh that money flow from illicit
Market are actually more risky in terms
of security than drugs
itself we all know where the money goes
we know that it supports uh uh uh not
only Criminal activ this it supports
totalitarian States and it supports
terrorism we know it it's not not secret
so money flowing from illicit Market are
actually more risky to the security
which is always the the M argument
security security the security is
actually compromised but M by money
flowing from illicit Market to to any
kind of
enormous Global organized crime
of course we we know that cannabis is
also a substitute to more risk
Alternatives we know it we have all the
data positive effects of economy and
Public Safety of course I don't have to
talk about this one
uh and we say that actually regulated
market we have all the data regulated
market is better
tool than in prevention
is better tool than prohibition We Know
It We Know It with tobacco we have all
the data we know it with alcohol We Know
It with other substances and we already
seen the data now with cannabis and of
course we should mention the human
rights uh the the the commission uh the
the highest commissioner for human
rights last year you might have come
across with that said uh released a
report and said that the interpretation
of 1961 convention uh U pushing the
countries to to send people to to long
sentences life prison imprisonment and
executions in many countries hundreds of
thousand people have already been
executed uh since we started a
Prohibition since that time the the
Cannabis Mark illicit Market is only
growing across the world so and it says
clearly this is again the charter of
human rights of the UN which we are all
based on so I think this is so important
to to
to uh to speak about decriminalization I
know that you're talking about science
you're talking about use of uh cannabis
for medical purposes but I think it's
quite important to speak about the whole
thing in terms of decrim because
decriminalization is one of the main
tools to actually be able to to
operate uh
so I mean I I'm not going to because I
don't have so much time I we want to
have some questions uh so what actually
at this moment we are allowed according
to the European laws if I forget the the
international law because internation
law is only blame and shame but
according to European law which has some
tools to to actually put sanctions on
countries they if they are in Bridge
with with the European law so we are
allowed to do hom growing we are allowed
maybe cannabis clubs that it's on the
edge or any kind of as we call it
delegation of homeg growing to other
person we are allowed to to to of course
to do uh medical use I mean production
and and sale for medical use strictly in
medical setup we actually according to
to a current European law it's not
possible to to to to have regulated
market which would be the most
beneficial uh part
regulation uh I'm not going to bore you
with all this uh legal
situations
um if we want to if you want to ask me
the questions I think that's that's
complicated uh so we know that today uh
the difference is
are there I mean in in US you have
commercial Market on in different states
not not uh uh uh not uh Federal Canada
there is a federal uh Poss and and
Uruguay you have a uh you have Market
but it's not allowed in in European
Union so in European Union you have what
you
see uh most currently Germany and Mal
Malta uh introduced the laws for for um
possibility of accessing cannabis for
non-medical use but again the same
situation that we are facing in Czech
Republic trying to push the law for
Market uh that the European commission
will meet with you informally and say
informally don't use it don't use it
formally I did all this uh me meetings
but we tell you we are telling you if
you uh if you open the the market you
will be in Bridge of the of the EU law
and we will have to act so that's same
happened to Germany you might have
follow the the the the bottle they had
they wanted to open a regulated market
at the end they have it in some some
cities as a study so this is how we have
to uh to work in the current
state so I would I would like to to to
finish end with u with a sentence I know
that uh here we are not in an activist
meeting uh and I'm not an activist I'm a
I'm a policy maker and it took
me I will tell you seven years to come
to this conclusion since 2010 when I
started in my office and I was looking
at the data over and over and over and
over uh remembering in some some
situations such as
1998 uh the the the the the Declaration
of all heads of state of un claiming the
world be will be free of drugs 2008 and
we can see that the the the the the
drugs Market quart tripled since since
prohibition is a cruel
and failing social
experiment we need to find other options
we need to start something else uh we
will have a ministerial conference in
Berlin in November so in a couple of
months and uh one of the outcomes we
hope will be that we will uh decide and
agree with uh number of of countries to
start the process of changing this
Council decision of European Union so
changing the European law in terms of
opening the possibility for states or
for countries for member states to to
regulate according to to their um level
of knowledge of the risks of different
substances and especially with cannabis
uh uh this will happen and I'm I'm sure
we only don't know when and how and who
but this will
happen thank
you thank
you we have time for questions does
anyone have a man your hand shot right
up okay here I come all right pardon me
if you'll excuse me Bigg your pardon
pardon me excuse me big your pardon
thank you uh hi so U my question is what
is your opinion which country country uh
uh have the best uh
regulation um regarding safety regarding
the less of use of heavy drugs less
criminal criminality in uh in this uh
meaning and um what uh think you also
about now the Germany system is uh for
your opinion good it's a how it's okay
yeah um it's a very uh complex question
of course thank you for that uh I'll
start with cannabis I think cannabis
regulation so far uh seems to be in from
my eyes and from our views when we look
at preventative measures because my role
is prevent prevention of
addictions uh e Canada seems um because
if we look at the
data when in terms of for example
underage we're looking at a cohort of 15
to 19 year old it's dropping
down uh we know this from Holland for
example for for for decades that the
Cannabis coffee shops didn't didn't
raise the the problem for
underage
uh in terms of
all as media I would call it hard drugs
we don't call it in our field hard drugs
and soft drugs it's complicated to to
distinguish because it's alcohol hard
drug
uh well depends on what the society
wants because uh as as I said I'm
looking at at addiction problem as one
issue alcohol gambling tobacco uh all
drugs that we have to currently under
prohibition we also look at digital
substance digital addictions
so any any strict regulations we have
all the data any strict regulations for
example we know regulations uh with
alcohol in in North America or
Scandinavia it
works the same works with other drugs it
does so strict regulations such as
specialized shops uh such as specialized
license for the people who s sell those
substances which can be taken away when
when these people break break the rules
for example cell under age uh it's not
everywhere it's it's limit in limited
places and there is strong prevention
not not advertising allowed uh high
price uh because of excise taxs etc etc
so this uh um kind of um bun of rules
but it has to be hand to hand with um
prevention and help so if this together
is put together that in then it works in
terms of uh number of problem drug users
when we look for example in injecting
drug use uh European Union comparing to
the rest of the world is better in in in
many ways yes so have lower number of of
injecting Dr uses comparing to Eastern
Europe for example Ukraine Russia or or
other places us uh I think it's because
uh we decriminalize at some point so
people were were able to access Services
we early on in in in introduced
so-called harm reduction
approach uh which doesn't push people
only for abstinence but uh what allow
people for example uh substitution
programs and as we know
substitution whether it's substituted in
in Market or but with doct from medical
hands uh is one of the best tools
substitution to to to the uh uh drugs
which are on the illicit Market
substitued with less risky risky uh
drugs that actually works for example we
we're looking at the at the tobacco
epidemics now when we uh see very quick
very fast drop off of lung cancers heart
diseases premature death because people
switched from from smoking because the
SM the smoking the most I mean whoever
smokes cannabis I don't I'm an abstinent
I I don't even drink alcohol but whoever
smokes cannabis so I would uh I would
recommend to switch from smoking to any
kind other type of use because uh the
the the tar that we use from from burnt
anything burnt especially the paper that
is what is killing us so we see the
substituted Market is very uh very uh
useful tool so I think so these two
things uh has to work prevention and
help and in a very strict substituted
Market with less risky drugs I me sorry
I'm uh it's very difficult to to give uh
to uh answer to to to this complex
question and you have you ask another
question about German ah the German the
German model of course the Germany knows
that the model is not the the best uh
they the initial draft was was much much
more complex and much more uh uh kind of
um work through but they they they they
uh they crushed against the wall with
the European law so that's why we have
this meeting in in uh in Berlin uh on
the ministerial level in 17 of November
I think fantastic I I hate to cut you
off but we have we have time for one
more quick question right here yes hi
when will the psycho madatory Substances
Act will go into force and can you
already apply for
licenses uh
I you asking about the time when it
starts yes uh so it should we aiming at
first
January of next year so few months from
now
uh the license system is going to be
regulated by by
bylaw so I have the paper already of the
bylaw written but it's not officially
yet but uh we aiming at starting with
the whole process from of January but uh
we need to First discuss which uh
substances are going to be the put F
going to be put first in the in the list
so it's probably going to be katom uh
THC with higher uh I mean the the
products with thhc round of 1% above 3%
above 0.3% to to 1% maybe two we'll see
and uh and uh we'll see what's going to
happen with uh um with substances such
as HC has to it's it's a government
decision so it might actually be be
um uh practically in action uh I would
say the end of M the end of uh February
maybe March maybe April as well yes but
we are pushing to start as soon as
possible I mean the law will be there so
we want this to be active and we want to
pull all the substances from The Gray
Zone because for example katom is sold
as uh I'm finishing already the Grom is
sold as decorative subjects we don't
want it so we want it
January government decision and February
to be uh psych substance not decorative
subject great thank you so very much one
more time
[Applause]
I look forward to hearing the results of
the the ministerial meeting in November
uh the country is going to team up
here um fantastic all right we're just
going to keep moving this oh thank you
this is the international cannabis
business conference in Slovenia it's the
Science and Technology Forum brought to
you by title sponsor Laurel Crest i'
also like to shout out metaflora for
sponsoring the party tonight at the
Grand to
toit close enough all right topit