and our new panelists are moving in
we've had a small change uh GI de is
feeling a little under the weather so in
her place to moderate this panel on
conventional Industries uh shifting to
food Fara and consumerism the one and
only the head of loose Brands Toronto a
can Canada's favorite torontonian is it
torontonian tonian that's right that
doesn't play for the Maple Leaves that
doesn't play the f Canada's favorite
non- Maple Leaf torontonian let's hear
it for Alex revage what's up everyone
good morning good morning I know after
the Afterparty it's always a little
tough but hopefully everyone had their
coffee and they're ready to
rock It's a very interesting panel I'm
very excited to be able to jump in and
and talk to these great people I mean I
know some of them and got a chance to
meet some uh some new people which I
always love and uh this topic is a very
interesting one we're going to be
talking about you know conventional
Industries and like the shift from food
Pharma and consumerism because we've had
so much changes in it um and uh I think
we're going to find it very interesting
especially with this great panel that I
have up here and I'll let them introduce
themselves I'll introduce myself and
then we'll jump right into it so why
don't we kick it off right here no
problem good morning everyone my name is
Paul long um CEO at little green farmer
so we are a medical cannabis company
based in Australia and in Europe we um
sit across the entire supply chain so we
we we provide medical products into uh
as I said the Australian Market where
one of the larger
brands in in that market and we've been
pretty active in the in the European
market for the last four or five years
and we had have a big Side Up in up in
Denmark that we're producing um the
topic of commoditization I think we're
going to touch on today I think it's
very interesting for us as a company um
very interesting here in Germany but
also also in Australia and I think for
everyone in the audience you know
understanding what what that means and
and how that will play out in a market
that's legalizing is going to be an
interesting
topic very good morning everyone I'm
Bernie young I'm the CEO of Atlas Global
Brands we're based out of Canada um
where we have an eug GMP Hub based out
of chatam Ontario as well as the second
facility in statford Ontario where we
sell G EU GMP flour extracts Vapes Etc
and I've been the space for seven plus
years and you know I'm very lucky to be
with this panel as we look at the
opportunities and take some learnings on
you know what's changed over these
several years and especially us all
being here in uh in Germany as as well
as all the international markets how we
continue to see Trends and and a lot of
the growth and the opportunities so
looking forward to speaking more on that
thank you hello good morning my name is
suzan kaspa I'm the CEO of
Hela uh we are uh extractor of um
plantbased apis uh we are uh not startup
like lot of companies here in uh in uh
this room uh we are in the market for
more than 40 years and we are producing
apis and in 2014 we decided to go as
well the route for the cannabinoids so
we are producing now CBD CBG and THC as
isolate and uh extracts uh and yeah this
is my start
Ben hello everybody my name is Benjamin
pook I'm not the CEO of B so I don't fit
in that panel maybe I have to ask for a
promotion after is but b or Bida or Bida
in Germany we're producer of these
little brown humidification pouches if
you don't know them find us at our booth
you can have samples hopefully we can
change your life to the better for um if
you don't know it so it's a it's a
two-way humidification you can put into
any closed container it will regulate
the relative humidity to an EXA level
regardless of the surrounding conditions
um we do this for 25 years too so we're
not a startup either and we do this in a
multitude of Industries we started in
tobacco industry cannabis today is our
biggest industry the most fun one too
but we also you know we sell to people
who breed alligators you know and we
sold some to the UN who ship larva eggs
to Africa everything that needs to be
stored at exact humidity conditions
that's what we do um happy to be on this
panel yeah and I definitely use those
packages to to keep my cannabis fresh
back in Canada and my name is Alex
revich I've been uh helping start this
ICBC in 2017 uh it's amazing how far
this has come and uh back home my day
job when I'm not helping organize ICBC
and moderating panels I have a a company
called L Brands where we make edibles
contract manufacturer of Edibles and I
have a pharmacy called hybrid Farm
that's medical cannabis so uh very nice
to be here with you all quick Round of
Applause for our
panel awesome so you know we're going to
start uh you know we're talking
backstage with Paul about the the
background of this topic and why it's so
important uh why don't we kind of start
it off and we'll each one of us will
talk about why this such an important
topic and and why these people should
care about it yeah sure I think you know
there's some interesting parallels when
we look at the Australian Market which
is our our core Market to to the German
market and I think in Australia we've
now got
700 flour products in the market so
heavily commoditized Market at the
moment in the last 12 weeks we had 58
new products so in the high THC category
in the last 12 weeks in the Australian
market so um I was I was thinking and
hoping that we might have may have hit
an inflection point last year but it
seems that's not the case in in in our
home market and when I talk to our
partners here in Germany we we're
hearing exactly the same thing so um by
definition of commoditization it's um
we're going from from high value high
quality products um or more Niche
products into into generic really if
we're talking in Farmer land and I think
I think you know we accept as a company
that that's that's the markets that
we're playing in it's not it's not the
markets we see across the globe in in
across the markets we we work in in say
France and Poland as an example but
certainly when we look at Germany and
Australia the the the theory of um
commoditization is is is prevalent um
for us it's got positive and negative
like it's you know you know on a
positive sense we can see in Australia
there's been a real shift to um
accessibility and when we spoke about
medical cannabis in Australia five or
six years ago the problem it was Patient
Advocates saying that we need access and
it's too expensive but now we can see
that Trend really really shifting so the
cost for a patient has now dropped
significantly um and and in our Market
we're dealing with with patients and
it's a it's a last resort for people
with chronic Health needs and and those
patients of often cannot work full-time
so you know there's a there's a real
positive behind the commoditization um
and I think we're also seeing a shift
from the black market in in Australia
the there's a survey that's run in
Australia every four years that looks at
um it asks some interesting questions
around around drug use in a very non
deidentified way to to Australian public
and in 2019 they asked the question they
said um for those people that are using
cannabis illicitly what percentage of
those Pat those so patients using elicit
cannabis for a medical reason what
percentage of those patients actually
got a script through our medical
framework and it was 1.8% in 200 19 and
in 2023 just the back half of last year
it's up to 22% so on on another positive
frame where we're taking we're moving
we're shifting away from the black black
market to to the legal Market I think
commoditization has driven prices down
which means that you know less Black
Market activity more more medical
activity and and I think ultimately in
Australia it'll be no different to
Germany there will be a shift from
commoditization lower pric product
legalization my personal opinion is that
that's where we're heading you know and
very similar parallels to what we're
saying here in Germany fish yeah I could
Jump Right In because if you look at the
flower price in Germany I mean there are
now websites where you can check flower
price in pharmacies for the same strains
and you know like the entry point is as
low as €3 for a gram of flour right and
and I talked to many because we work
with many of the importers some of you
know some of the producers as well um
and they really see also like an like a
spike just in like all the new stuff
that's coming in right so the the
proportion of products that they bring
in that need to be everybody in the
beginning was like oh we need stable you
know stable cultiv ours like stable
stable stable it's not so much that
thing because they really see new stuff
coming in big sales and then it kind of
like Fades out next thing comes in new
sales so that's a consumer Model Market
even though we're in the medical field
technically speaking and you know what
that's a great point so Atlas Global
Brands we export to seven International
markets and you know it's exactly that b
like you said there's so much changes
but again you know me coming from cpg
and Jack Daniels and Dr Pepper like it
comes down to portfolio management so
there is commoditization but I think at
the end of the day how do you
differentiate yourself right and you
create the brand positioning it's all
the fundamentals as we look at it to
really create a differentiation so for
example at Atlas we create a uh we have
a nursery program and we pheno hunt and
we make sure we have the best genetics
so that on sites like that our partners
you know you know we're here in Germany
one of our partners like anua as an
example you partner with them and you
and you create a compelling proposition
where it's the only unique cultivar and
and it's not a me too the moment you
have a me too it's commoditized
everyone's going to have it you're
driven on price so how do you create a
positioning with your brand whether
medical or consumer I mean let's face it
it's cannabis there's a market in for it
there's there's something that
everyone's looking for so that's really
uh an evolving space that we'll see
here I would like to highlight that this
uh Market is not only a flower market
you're only speaking about flour but we
are speaking about patients we are
speaking about medical market and there
are a lot of people who don't want to
smoke and uh and therefore I think we
should see the market as well that we
that there are uh extract that there are
isolate that there are maybe finished
product at uh at the end in the future
and this is very important for me is
important the the plant the plant from
is so powerful I really believe we have
we have a lot of indication where we
don't have any chance uh for um to to
find a product of far and I believe that
cannabis is the plant who can deliver
new uh medication for new indication and
we are working together with
universities and um uh together with our
clients we are doing clinical studies
and I really hope for the future for the
uh for patients who will have there this
plant will be
so suzan what's your view on that cuz
you know let's talk about the future cuz
I think a lot of us have a lot of
thoughts around you know the Cannabis
Health Products you know when I think of
you know um topical rubs like the A5 35s
of the world you think of you know even
years ago the the big tobacco and Pharma
this is a very important input and uh
and I think there's a lot of to your
point different ways to utilize a
product Beyond combustibles yeah I think
the market will change a little bit in
future so I think there was yesterday as
well a discussion I think in in future
there will be maybe big farmer I don't
know I know big um um tobacco um
companies are looking as well into this
field they will develop finished
products with clinical studies and then
a lot of products will no longer be can
no longer be prescribed in the medical
Market because then there are finished
product and as soon as there are
finished product registered by the local
authorities um then the market will will
change uh completely and I think we are
going into this direction um with this
and this maybe you said positive
negative and with this LW change maybe
in Germany uh it's maybe easier uh to to
get access uh to the medical Market in
that way that companies will think about
okay now maybe I invest because it's no
longer a drug product I'm no longer in
this uh um Corner which is um more
cannabis it's it's not supp positive now
I have the impression that more
companies are thinking about to develop
product and this can take five more
years because in this market you always
need to do clinical trials and get a
registration but it will come and then
the market will change uh totally yeah
no I I double that so at the end if we
really honest right now we using
cannabis flour in a medicinal context
for the lack of better alternative so we
give them like all of the 500
biochemical compounds that are in there
because we don't know which 5
2535 you need for your specific case
right but at some point we will able to
decipher that and this would be made
into an application at the end of the
day yeah yeah I think it'd be
interesting to Bernie understand your
perspective on commoditization
legalization and what what happened
happened next in your Market but I think
what we see both here in in Germany and
Australia is in some ways the negative
side is actually quite disappointing
because there is a conversation around
flower and it's high THC flour it's not
it's not the doctor it's not the
companies like ours making those
decisions it's the patient walking in to
the doctor with a 7-minute tele Health
consult even less maybe saying I want
this high THC flower so we're reacting
one now we're reacting and the markets
reacting and it's responding to to what
the market wants and that is an
inevitable step from commoditization
legalization and and that's the way the
Market's heading and yeah there's
definitely some negatives to that we're
not you know as an industry we're not
doubling down and investing on unique
drug delivery we're not looking at new
formulations we're not we're reacting to
a market and we we're all in a really
difficult Capital Market there's no that
might be a little bit different over
here maybe there's a bit of optimism
around you know the changes that we've
seen and some Capital available but not
in our world probably Limited in your
your part of the world too so so you're
reacting to the market chasing chasing
Revenue quarter by quarter chasing
profitability as a business so
inevitably the downside is that there is
a lack of innovation for for real
patients with real product Solutions
unfortunately that's an interesting
point Paul cuz I think you know that's
where we have to all really collaborate
and I think this is that time where you
know we got to take learnings from
Canada and other markets where you know
we've made mistakes and and take those
best practices and adapt them over like
when you think about the product
portfolio you're right everyone's
chasing quarter to quarter you're trying
to find sustainability run a lean
organization but I think I think at the
end of the day when we think of what we
all do together in the shift towards
Pharma and consumerism is you know I
come back to even at Atlas it's like
what are we great at right and all of us
have to find our lane that we want to
own and you know in our case it's really
being a hub and exporting UGM for our
partners in in these types of markets
and and that I think is key but when you
want to try to do everything you end up
not really being an expert and that's
where I think the value chain breaks
down and I encourage you all to think
about that because you know whether it's
in the conversations we're having today
around you know consumerism and Pharma
and medical it's just think about those
key pieces because the
commoditization is is happening so let's
make sure whatever Lane you pick you're
very very efficient at it and productive
at it uh I would like uh to come back to
what Benjamin just said uh here in
Germany now there are
Trends and I I think this is maybe a
lesson we haven't learned here in in
Germany there are trends that you can
get now a prescription for1 Euro and uh
they are doing advertisement with a
reper in a pharmaceutical company I'm
happy to smoke I'm happy to smoke I
really think this is too much uh this is
I we we had a long fight I I have seen
what is was going on in Germany there
was a long fight and there are parties
they don't like this law and they
directly say within uh um votation next
year we will bring everything back uh to
to the status as today and with this
advertisement I think this is not
helping the market so I really have the
fear that that now maybe politicians say
no this is not what we want uh for for
Germany or that farma um insurance
companies maybe say if this is the
market we will no longer pay uh for uh
for the products we we actually saw that
in the US and uh what happens is if you
kind of make medical a joke kind of with
your dollar joint uh dollar gram uh what
happens is when recreational will happen
eventually you'll start to see
recreational people go to recreational
and the medical people will actually be
professional and medical and until you
have legalization unfortunately this is
what's going to happen we saw there in
the US we saw there in Canada and
something else we're seeing in Canada
what you said about people just want to
how high can I get for the cheapest
price was a very common thing we saw in
Canada and Paul you were talking about
like all these new products in Ontario
my Province we have 3,000 products in
the market and they're talking about
increasing it to 5,000 Bernie's notd in
his he knows how difficult the Canadian
Market is with so many different
products but at least we're diversifying
from flour and I always say that when
the prices come down and the access
increases that's when you'll get rid of
the black market you can't get rid of
the black market by policing no matter
how much you try it won't go away the
only way it'll go away is by giving the
people what they want at the right price
and an easy way uh and with that in mind
and bringing the price down it becomes a
commodity and that's a very important
topic that we're talking about here
sorry Susan before we get into our next
topic you wanted to say something yeah I
want uh yes you're discussing price but
what we can see is that product in the
market the quality is very low so you
really you saw you see uh especially uh
flowers but as well in in our area the
exert area the product quality is is so
low that uh let's say we we know there
will be there are products in the market
let's say CBD 5% if we Analyze This
there is sometimes there is no CBD
inside there is a t t see above the
level so there are are product false
they're false labor totally totally
false and and because the more nobody is
controlling the market so far and as
well for the for flowers um the the
flowers are sometimes really really bad
quality and so pricing is one thing but
you know if if you want to get good
quality price sometimes needs to be uh
as well I think it's the price value
relationship like you said right but I
would say you know I give credit to the
EU here and Australia's you know it
wasn't like Canada where it was like
grow it and sell it and it's going to
move in the beginning when we had
legalization I find the product quality
curve has shut up exponentially and I'm
sure you agree as well here you're right
on some of the quality dumping and and
commoditization that's shifting some of
the products but I mean patients are are
smart and you know we're all consumers
and you you know you buy at once if it
doesn't meet your price value
relationship you're not going to deliver
that's why it comes back to consistency
and quality of what you want to deliver
and own and be great at and just
consistently do it and you'll tell your
friends about that it's not good and
that's word of melt is very valuable Ben
you wanted to say something yeah but
that's that's a consumer mechanism right
because if you think of if it was a
farmaceutical product the quality would
be the effect that it has on your back
pain you know and I think the issu is
also because right now in medicinal we
only look at THC CBD is the only two
active compounds that we really care
about and we don't know about the rest
yet right so that's the this is I think
one of the issues and all the mechanism
we see this is this is consumer Market
mechanisms right because at the end is
well if I get a medicine you know and is
what's the quality of a medicine does it
help me or not it's not about how does
it taste you know and all this I mean of
course there is the adherence part of it
of course you know if it's too bitter
your cuff syrup is too bitter you won't
take it bad for you okay like that's
there but the rest of it is just pure
and out and between the strains the
cultivar I exchange it because I like
the flavor better you know a lot of it
has to do with humidity actually too so
we have um like a study of like 1100
data points and the the legal limit was
10% moisture content the average was
seven somewhere in at four you know and
that's really low it's dry that's s is
bad you know but at the end it's will be
interesting to see how that then
translate into legalized Market I agree
with you Alex I mean that's that's how
you get that's right now that you see a
rush into the medicinal because of the
lack of a of a recreational alternative
right that's see that for sure Paul last
stop before we get into our next topic
yeah I actually just have a question
probably um Bernie and Alex for you guys
that that I'm interested that I think
other people in the audience might
around um Beyond you know Step Beyond
commoditization commoditization
legalization and what's a you know are
there some good examples out there in in
US and Canada that you that you would
guide you know companies like ours or
startups or whatever that looks like in
Australia and and and Germany example I
don't know Bernie good example you know
what I I say it to everyone is like you
can never you know whether it's medical
and cannabis is in medical spaces you
can never never um trick the consumer or
the patient you know what I mean deliver
on what you want to have and and I think
there's been in our space
even in the early time is you think you
know hey just get it out the door get it
out the door and it's just the
consistency the quality the price value
relationship many of you highlight the
humidity and quality of the product like
all of the stuff kind comes in handy
like I always use the analogy of the
five senses with cannabis right like
it's you know you open it and you see it
and you touch it you smell it you taste
it It ultimately evolves and and I think
the key learnings is just what you put
in the bag is if you were to buy any
product off that Market would you be
proud of its consistency and I think it
comes down to that for sure the question
is if the consumer or patient always see
the quality sometimes maybe they think
oh it could help for this disease or for
this pain or I don't know and and oh it
doesn't help so no cannabis is not good
uh and uh and I will tell this uh to my
colleague so it can really reduce the
market because if if the quality is not
there if the product is not inside what
they are
selling putting on on the package then
this can ruin the the full Market
because then people are thinking okay
this is nothing for me but I think uh we
have done a big big step ahead uh in in
the European Union because there was a
creation of a monograph uh this year for
the CBD isolator and I think this is
perfect for for for patients for for the
quality because now we have a monograph
and and every product in this market and
everybody every Pharmacy who's who needs
uh to take um to formulate with with the
um isolate of of CBD now needs to follow
this regulation this specification and
this will be perfect so a lot of
products will need to get out of the
market and I think everybody who would
like to think about oh I will develop a
product and do stability data they
really now need to think about which
product to start with this need to
comply to this mon graph this is uh I
think it's a step ahead and I think this
will follow and this is not only good
for Europe I think as well other uh
authorities will follow uh the example
it's it's going to really take it
doctors to take it seriously uh I've
been doing a lot of doctor education
throughout my career 10 years and at the
beginning they said there's not enough
information there's not enough evidence
there is no monograph like I heard that
all the time so the fact that it does
have it will really help in its
credibility and you were kind of asking
the question I think one of the big
parts and the challenges around our
industry is in the regulations there's a
lot of expenses in in being a legal
company eug GMP all these costs with
these costs require investment then you
take investment on and then the clock
starts ticking of you got to start
paying the back of that investment so
you're really rushing to try and be able
to survive long enough until you can
give the customers what they want and
the patients what they want and that's a
big Challenge and that kind of goes into
our next topic around the
commoditization of this product so
there's good and bad with it yes the
patient get a cheaper more affordable
product but then how do we make our
money back to pay back the investors
because if the investors aren't
interested they're going to go put their
money in something else uh and then we
can't even operate these businesses
because it's so expensive to operate so
commodity the good and the bad uh I I
know Paul you had some thoughts on it
and some others as well backstage uh you
know give give the audience some pros
and cons of what this looks like uh
commoditizing this product you have
probably touched on a few already but
one to add might be just just you sort
of touched on it around U how business
can operate in that space and I think
you know with commoditization we've got
you know proliferation of of Brands and
businesses and new startups every every
week by by the sound of it you know in
in the Australian example it's very easy
to to bring a product and put a label on
it so um it it does make it incredibly
difficult to to operate um and it's a
different layer of thinking for
businesses I mean we as a company have
started from a from a pure farmer
perspective because we were we were that
that was the environment in which we
operated and we still continued to
operate in that in that environment but
um we've been we've been you know we've
had to start to think more fmcg as as an
industry as a as a company um but yeah
that that that's a different um
commercial proposition for us as a
business and our strategy and our
shareholders so I think I think we're
seeing you know we probably haven't seen
it too much over here and um there may
be some some different views but
certainly in Australia we're seeing
companies not not being able to to
operate in that space because it is it
relies on volume it relies on margin it
relies on branding it relies on
Obviously good quality product to to the
patient um so yeah on the on the
negative side it's difficult to operate
in that space But but you know we all in
this industry should think what's right
for the patient and and ultimately I
still think on the balance of positive
and negative that you know there is some
there's some some real positives behind
access for patients and affordability
for patients so um you know overall I
think that we're we're trending in the
right direction I do hope that there's a
there's a future where there's a bit of
a carve out for in our in our part of
the world there's legalization that that
medical continues to have a space
because I think that the medical part
and what what you know we were
previously delivering and thinking about
was was producing you unique products
and and drugs thinking about drug
registration thinking about solving real
patient problems um and it's a different
Strate strategic thinking in a boardroom
um when you look at both of those so I
do hope but there's a there's a future
world that there is a split between
legalized legalized pathway medical
pathway and that the medical pathway has
the right investment to invest in
research and development and really
focus on those that's a good point
they're very different you know medical
is one side very Pharma and then there
cpg which is very different something
that Bernie knows a lot about the very
different worlds for sure uh some other
thoughts on the good and bad of
commodity housing it so because I mean
we have like our product is a
commodity do you like do you know what
our biggest competitor is in a cannabis
space it's actually people people using
nothing right they just know they just
like dry weed sucks that's and that's it
they still smoke it you know and in
other places in uh in the cigar space
where we we originate from 25 years our
biggest competitor is basically a
sponge right so it's a highly
commoditized business so but at the end
of the day is and that's like for every
consumer Market is is you have to build
your selling proposition right and your
brand in order to convince people that
you have the right solution for what
they need and we are the most expensive
solution in the
market but we are also the best solution
in the market when it comes to you know
delivering on point um and it's IP
protected so everybody else who we
created this Product Industry really and
we've seen last 25 years a lot of me too
products they're here at the show as
well you know but in the last 5 years
we've seen a lot of them come and go
yeah so it's for us and it's interesting
to see and then my question would be for
you guys um how easy would it be for you
to like pivot you know because flower
could be a recreational product yeah so
how easy would it for you to to Pivot
for you it will be a little bit more
difficult you know but then so in theory
there's a way right either and in each
uh industry for you guys at the end I
mean I I find the biggest change if you
think about Canada we were medic first
and then we shifted to Canadian
legalization but excuse me I think the
the thing that we got to think about is
there's the rapid growth of the macro
industry the behaviors of our patients
and what they expect and what they want
from Cannabis is has always been there
like you got to remember we're yes we're
creating some products but we're also
converting the illicit Market over to
Medical for consistency and quality of
product and that's kind of the thing
when I think about Brands and whether
it's on the medical side like yes you've
got the traditional Pharma the API you
know the apotex is when we're in in
Canada and whatnot and other large ones
but really the key thing that I see here
is you can still brand and you can still
create a brand affinity and and what
does that product deliver and I think
consumers and the medical space and
patients they'll continue to do that and
have expectations so again it's
portfolio building it's understanding
how each one of the um pieces segment to
your actual patient I think are very
very important and yes a lot of it's
from fmcg but you know even in a lot of
the partners I've worked with in the
past in the pharmac set is like what's
the solution you're delivering what's
the need State you're meeting and if you
nail that every single time you're going
to have a patient base and yes there's
commoditization and on on me too but
it's those that are going to be able to
balance the volume the quality the price
value relationship and ultimately that
product that the consumer and patient
wants is going to win every time and
Susan I know you you have an interesting
perspective here cuz actually this
commoditization might actually be a
benefit for you because you have a
product that creates standardization and
quality and it it doesn't require
growing maybe uh you know with the same
type of cost so maybe this
commoditization could be good and by the
way think about some questions from the
audience uh so Susan will give her
answer and then if anyone has any
questions we'll uh we'll take them there
go ahead I I would like come back to
your question um people need to earn uh
money uh and maybe investors are no
longer willing to to to spend their
money and I have the feeling the
industry is changing now a lot of
companies start uh to to leave the
market I believe there will be more
companies uh leaving the market and
quality and and what we said um
standardization it's it's not it's not
cheap so you really need uh to have the
money to do stability data we have
stability data for five years but this
is an investment of hundred of thousands
of uh um of uh Euro and I I believe a
lot of companies will leave the market
and therefore there will be if if you
really think to to start to do something
in the long run you need to see which
company will be in the market in the
future yeah and we saw that in Canada uh
so many companies started and now every
year we have more companies leaving than
joining so that's something that we're
seeing and and one of the big things
around commod commoditization is the
marketing restrictions really make it
difficult for us to differentiate
ourselves from everyone else so how do
you kind of separate plus customers only
really understand THC so we have to
really create a more knowledgeable
customer uh and allow for some education
around products you know not marketing
obviously advertising is not going to be
allowed ever but uh finding other ways
to educate people on why your product is
better and I think that's going to be a
way to differentiate yourself uh and uh
I don't know Ben you look like you have
a I just I'm just to finish that you're
right I mean at the end of the day the
good thing about commoditization is the
consumer has now a choice and if that
choice is I want to sacrifice quality
over price that's the choice and the
challenge is of course as you said where
do you fit in and all that entire
spectrum that is how do you make
yourself stand out and explain right
education why your product is worth what
you ask for otherwise you're just a
commodity and then you're you're
compared equally to everyone else and
then people want to know what's the best
price on that commodity uh any uh any
questions from the audience I have a few
other questions here for the panel but
wanted to open it up if anyone has any
questions first I see one right
there don't don't be shy we got a good
group up here hello
um look I am from Russia Yuri and I plan
hemp before before in the Russia hemp
uses only for fiber and four seats now I
here find out that CBD is very popular
in whole
world and uh a lot of Advantage we are
talking about CBD here THC I don't touch
at all so and if anybody think how CBD
destroys the body in future how it's
nobody talk about disadvantage of CBD if
any disadvantage that you are uh
declare uh are you are you uh saying
that you've heard there are some
disadvantages of CBD uh yes yes so I
mean I can speak to one in my Pharmacy
we do med checks there and we found that
certain blood thinners if you take CBD
it makes the blood thinner less
effective so uh I always tell people we
don't really say that CBD is completely
safe it does have some negative things
especially for people on certain
medications uh and also the other
negative with CBD is what carrier oil
it's mixed with some people with like
MCT oil or coconut oil can cause like
diarrhea so it makes like stomach upset
uh but that's not the CBD that's more
the carrier oil I don't know if anyone
else on the panel has any kind of
thoughts on that yeah yeah I would uh so
so for me you you see this is maybe this
is not commodity so for me this is It's
a product that works like any other
pharmaceutical ingredient but it's a
pharmaceutical for me it's a
pharmaceutical ingredient and if I take
something sometimes you have as well
some negative output but I need to say
our products we are delivering to Brazil
and um and in Brazil um the the CBD is
given to children with epilepsy and it
works so good so and and so effective so
that uh maybe this is not oh I I like to
have uh this only to to feel a little
bit better but you should see it like a
product that really works that really
helps but maybe you should not take it
uh only for fun and and then uh you you
need uh then nothing fun about CBD it's
a it's real medicine actually maybe one
negative I want to say about CBD that's
very bothering me is in the the Us and
other places how it's like a novelty I
go to the US and they put in hamburgers
and and tampons and they're like they're
putting CBD and everything and it's
become more of like a a novelty than a
real medical product and that really
bothers me and that's that's probably
the biggest negative of CBD is because
it's legal in these jurisdictions people
have kind of put them in funny shaped
gummies and oh buy your CBD flow and
it's like no this is not what it's for
smoking CBD is probably literally the
worst way of getting your CBD so and and
just one more to add from from my
perspective we' we've supplied I think
over 70,000 units of our CBD 50 oil in
an MCT carrier to the French pilot study
and and under that study that we're
measuring Pharmaca vigilance we have to
do that through through the uh the
French regime and and there was no
serious over that threeyear period there
was no serious incidents um but there
are you know there's quite a few on
record of of minor incidents which I
think um Alex has mentioned so diarrhea
vomiting but but again often link to the
carry oil but nothing nothing major that
we've seen in that
market no good good question thank you
and yeah very interested to see what's
happening in Russia I don't hear too
much about it but I love seeing new
countries uh come to ICBC and hey you're
the first Russian I meet here at ICBC
hopefully we'll have a chance to chat
I'd love to learn more um any other
questions right here I have a question
for Bernie you briefly mentioned working
before for Brands like Jack Daniels and
Dr Pepper and there's a lot of
similarities between that and the
Cannabis industry what would you say are
the biggest difference between those
kinds of Brands and products and and the
Cannabis industry I say we I think we
definitely and that's a great question
we definitely forget how long it takes
to build a brand and trust with patients
and consumers like you know I think Jack
Daniel's now what 160 170 years now
right it's synonymous with whiskey I
mean it's a very challenging I find
building brands in this time that's why
it's really the step by step and Alex
mentioned it too around you know what
you upset one consumer the ripple effect
of Reddit and all of that its
implication so that's kind of why when
when we all look together you know it's
changed so much I've been in the space
now for seven plus years and what I say
now is we need to find our Partnerships
we need to be you know real honest with
each other and say again what are we
great at let's work together and build
and shape the industry now and and I
think that's what we're seeing a lot of
even here at the ICBC when I talk to a
lot of uh great people it's just how do
we do this better and how do we have a a
consistent Global Supply Chain we talk
about CBG like let's talk about
McDonald's the French fry whether it's
here Canada China wherever it's the same
it's consistent and I think that's what
all of us want to get to and we really
just got to be thoughtful on that
approach hi everybody great panel my
question relates to what uh consistent
and successful consumer product
regulation must offer to companies in
order to make it work because I think an
impression that a lot of people in
Germany have is that that market Dynamic
of bringing in new products that deflate
rather quickly and companies that have
an ultra high cash burn rate who are you
know must make this kind of money to
keep up with this circulation but
cannabis and or THC as an ingredient is
the actual interesting thing assuming it
follows the same logic as tobacco where
we're getting away from tobacco products
and more towards a nicotine based
regulation and different forms of
consumption that must be the goal in my
personal opinion for cannabis to be
successful in the long run and
Achieve High Revenue per unit uh sales
that are sustainable enough how can
Regulators enable industry and set them
up for success and at some point uh
drawing from lessons from Canada which
probably don't need to be replicated in
other parts of the world
to at the same time open a market but
also protect it from the Dynamics that
makes it eat itself or destroy itself in
the long run I I want to ask this panel
because that's an interesting question
because there's a theoretical view right
and there's a practical View and you
said it too cash burn managing your
day-to-day operations and whatnot is
it's really finding the right mix of the
portfolio I find like let's face it in
the next near term you got to sell flour
like you can talk about the API very
important and there's the medium and the
long run development but if you want to
survive and sustain like even in Canada
today you got got you know in a more
mature Market where there's 2.0 products
can't you know flowers just under 50% of
all the volume still right now it's
pre-rolls and that's and then Plus
pre-rolls on top with the 18% like so
when you look at it there's a lot of
those pieces but where I want to get to
is really around uh the balance of yes
there's a longterm in helping making
sure we're all contributing as a group
shaping the space and making this a
really long-term sustainable Market on
the global front and I think uh there's
a lot of uh pieces that we have to run
but you know that's a probably a
separate topic that that can have a lot
of dialogue I'm interested in everyone's
view because you want to build it but
you got to keep the lights on and you
got to balance that and that's a tricky
balance for sure we can definitely talk
about it for a while I see Ango over
here it looks like maybe our our time is
uh our time is up our panel was
fantastic let's hear it
again Alex
Revit Bernie young Suzanne Caspar and
Benjamin
that was wonderful that was fantastic
and I'm sure you can talk to them in the
hallway if you'd like to talk to them
some more