we're just going to move right along to
discuss cracking the international
cannabis Logistics chain code the cem of
cannibal log let's hear
for hi guys so we need some energy
around here it's late after lunch so who
is here from
Canada who is here from
Germany yay who is here from
Portugal and who is here from Australia
they're sleeping now okay so um good
afternoon everybody thank you for coming
thank you for staying what we want to do
today what I want to do today is
actually give you a lot of
practical advice a lot of practical uh
things that you have to think about when
you want to do International Trade of
cannabis Import and Export cannabis
around the world this is what kabog is
doing and this is what I want to share
with you what we learned and we learned
aot during 2013 and what you should
expect going forward in the coming years
yes I'm talking about logistics
Logistics is sometimes something that
you think it's like uh moving by itself
right but it's not so we will learn a
little bit about what you should do what
you should be aware about and now
actually all those uh presentation
before when we talked about all these
opportunities how we actually execute
that so this is the my presentation
myself 14 years I was the head of global
supply chain and logistic fora I'm
coming from the farma industry I know
the industry in and out coming with all
the experience the knowledge the
understanding of quality Pharmaceuticals
markets 85 production sites then I
retired from tea and decided to come to
this amazing industry the Cannabis
industry and actually to bring all my
knowledge from the Pharma into the
medical cannabis so this is why I made
all those connections and this is why
I'm here today to share with you
and one slide about the company canab
log we already moved more than 880,000
kilos of Canabis in the last two three
years from many countries to to many
countries I'll share with you a lot of
operation a lot of movement and what 98%
of what we do is moving cannabis
products from one country to the
other um where a little bit in the
distribution of cannabis but mainly in
the international trade and this is what
I would like to show with you today so
this is the agenda I'm not going to walk
it step by step you will see that I'll
talk about all those points during my
presentation so what's new I was here
last year and I said what's new this
year so first of all we see that there
are new regulations if you don't know
you know Germany we will talk all day
about Germany but also Greece there is a
big reform in Israel big change the
market is going to grow dramatically and
I just want to uh encourage you to find
out what are the opportunities out there
there's a big number of new eug GMP
facilities in Portugal in Canada in
other places so if you're looking for
tolling if you want to sell your
products in the in Europe there are more
and more opportunities doing that same
thing about
Australia sorry
um industry challenges yeah we see
what's going on with the big companies
both in Canada in Israel in other places
companies are disappearing big companies
that made a lot of investment are not
there in the market anymore so be aware
of those
changes new markets really how many
markets real markets of Canabis medical
cannabis products there are in the world
who think
two three
four
five raise your hand who thinks five
about Five Guys that's it medical
cannabis markets as such five
markets six maybe so a lot of stories a
lot of H you know people think that a
lot of countries are joining the party
there's not a lot of markets Market I
mean doctors write prescriptions you go
to a pharmacy and you get your product
not a lot of market so everybody wants
to sell to Germany to Australia to the
UK to Switzerland to
Israel that's it okay not more or not a
lot more than that and of course new
import export opportunities in Thailand
by by the way not just Thailand there's
a lot of stories about many countries
you will hear that there are imports
from Thailand to Thailand or export out
of Thailand
the answer is no there's no clear
regulations over there there's a lot of
gray issues so be aware to that there's
a lot of stories but when it comes to
execution make sure that you do
understand the regulations so Logistics
when you talk about logistics you have
to remember these five pillars one is
the Regulatory
Compliance unfortunately with cannabis
there's no or I would say differently I
would say that each country has its own
regulations so whenever you do
International Trade of cannabis be aware
that your the exposing country
regulations are not exactly is the
important country regulations and you
have to ad to both so regulatory issues
are mainly or probably the main thing
that you have to take care of
security okay it's a drug it's narcotics
it's a attracting a lot of attention
security is an important point there are
some countries that we are not moving
even one flower or one LEF unless we
have a armed guard together with a truck
sometimes it's the regulation sometimes
we're just doing it even if it's not a
regulation so be aware of
security quality insurance guys it's
medicines it's exactly like Pharma
medical cannabis is exactly like
any molecule that you can think about
paracetamol or anything else it's it's a
medicine this is why you have to adhere
to all those pharmaceutical requirements
GDP and other GMP
regulations expertise yeah cannabis
excuse my language cannabis is not
garments from I don't know from from a
country to ship cannabis it's a highly
regulated issue and if you ship it and
you don't do it right you can Kiss It
Goodbye and I'll say it several times if
you arrive to the country of destination
and you cannot clear it no way back it
you're going to be destroyed and you'll
have to pay for it so it's not a regular
thing that you just send it DHL or FedEx
or whatever and it's there it's not and
the last thing is global uh I think the
one the lecture before me said act local
think Global if you really want to be
there if you really want to do you know
International Trade think
Global what we had in 2013 these were
the main Lanes I told you before there
are not that many markets so I think
that the strongest exporter exporting
country is Canada you know that then we
saw some a lot of um movements from
South Africa either to you EU UK and
Australia Portugal
Uruguay and a lot of inra Europe
movements of medical cannabis within
Europe from Portugal to Germany to
Switzerland to others each one of those
Lanes required a completely different
logistic solution and we will talk about
that in a while I you don't need the
numbers there's a lot of H charts that
we saw today but you can
see the
potential Australia look at it they're
going to grow dramatically so again
numbers and numbers I just want to show
you the the trend that we are going to
face more and more and more sales in
different markets which will require
logistic solution at the end of the day
you have to move it you have to pick it
up in the site and you have to bring it
to the market whether you like it or not
you have to move it and you have to move
it right because if it's not it's not
going to help
nobody let's talk two slides about
regulations okay I can bring you I can I
I could have bring here dozens of charts
okay look at Google say cannabis legal
something you will get a lot of
charts this is for the legal status of
cannabis Recreation this is medical this
is another map just name it the reason
I'm putting it here because I want you
to make sure that you understand that
regulations are moving are changing
every week every week we see some
changes in regulations more countries
more changes in the regulations last
year it was Australia this Ser is
Germany Greece Israel it's moving Target
all the time so make sure that you don't
stick with one map but you understand
the changes that we see every almost
every week
Europe
really one of my the Prest presentations
where when someone show a list of 12
countries in Europe
Malta Portugal
Germany U
UK who understand the
the regulatory environment in Europe
please raise your
hand legal not legal half legal
decriminalized
criminalized another map of Europe
right is it right
or maybe this one is right same thing
it's confusing not like in the farmer
world in the fmer world you come to
Europe there's one rule with cannabis
changing all the time CBDs or not THS or
not above 0.2 above
0.3 whatever okay so Europe is actually
different countries in Europe and each
one of them is different than the others
so make sure that you do understand that
what what you know today is not
necessarily what will be right next week
or next month or whatever so the
regulatory maze in Europe is amaz is
amazing can say it this way okay so
again this is the regulatory to make it
even nicer you know that according to
the UN regulations if a country want to
legalize or to actually to approve
import or export or or um consumption of
cannabis they have to create a local
agency each country have to create a
local agency to deal with the Cannabis
licensing this is the UN rules so when
you deal with a shipment let's say from
Portugal to Germany so you have to
adhere to the
Portuguese H inframed rules but you also
have to adere to the B Farm
rules not the
same and you have to have license import
license from Barm and you have to have
export license from inframed or any
other agency in the world good luck it
takes time sometimes they delay the
decision you don't understand why
sometimes it will take you a week to get
an input permit sometimes it will take
you three weeks to get it and sometimes
six weeks to get it h Canada okay just
to name few so remember if you want to
move even one leave of cannabis you have
to deal with the local a with the not
local well the Country Agency and there
are many of them with different rules
with different timelines with different
service
levels sometimes it's even not fun okay
but they are setting the rules and we
have to understand
that what is cannabis products okay so
we are dealing with a variety of
products let's start with genetics
genetics can be seeds can be tissue
cultures can be cuttings from a logistic
point of view to move cut Cs and we
moved already dozens of thousands of
cuttings okay cuting right
clones so I guess you know that in most
countries in the world they will not
accept rooted clothes they will accept
just unrooted clothes so when what is an
unrooted clone you cut it and if it's
not if it will not meet water in 3 4
days it's dead there's no roots so all
you have is 3 4 days to to bring it from
the cultivation site to somewhere a
laboratory or a site that can uh put
them in the water so logistically you
have to control from the cutting up to
the delivery with a very tight timeline
4 days it's dead by the way we have a
100% success with that dried flowers
apis what I call apis and you will call
extracts completely different logistic
Solutions completely different way to
deal with that PE finished semi-finish
cannabis products herbal medicine we
heard a lot about it CBD
products do they need temperature
control do they need any type kind of
control good questions because some
countries will say yes some countries
will say no and smokable products okay
same
thing so what we really need to know
from the quality point of view so
remember medical cannabis is a medicine
the problem or the first problem you
have to think about it's a plant based
medicine so it's not the tablet that you
go to the pharmacy and buy it although
there are tablets for cannabis but the
idea that if you're moving flowers it's
a it's a Agricultural Product it's like
moving Tomatoes but you don't have
medicine Tomatoes This is medicine so
anywhere you go you have to adhere both
to the from pharmaceutical side and also
to the agricultural side and both
authorities will be involved I'm talking
flowers always is a little bit different
so it's a it's a plant-based medicine
which require much more attention than
just shipping either Pharmaceuticals or
tomato second issue of course you have
to adhere to the farmer standard quality
management GDP you know the whole thing
maintain the product
Integrity okay safety safe security and
of course temperature control okay if
you put a Data Logger on the origin and
the guy on the other side have to read
it and there is a temperature Excursion
no way you can take it to the market
unless you go through certain procedures
so you have to make sure that it's a
medicine you have to make sure how to
maintain the temperature along the
supply chain
GMP GDP applicable
regulations sometimes it's country
specifics sometimes it's General
sometimes it's country specifics that
you have to
understand packages I just brought you
here a picture of uh of a pette a nice
pette covered with thermal covers It's
Not the Only Solution there are
different solutions how you maintain
temperature okay this pet goes or
travels within a temperature control
truck what we call tcv okay temperature
control truck with the with um a thermal
protection a lot of types of that just
to show you that it has to be packed
properly and you have to put the Data
Logger under the the the thermal cover
and not on top of the thermal cover
because you put it on top of the thermal
covers you measure the outside
temperature you don't measure the inside
of the product temperature this is why
it's very very important to have a very
strict packaging protocol and to
understand how you protect those
products along the supply chain and this
pette can travel 10,000
miles okay how you protect it how you
make sure that it's working
properly and the last thing it's a good
advice for you when you are selling your
products to a customer on the other side
make sure that you understand their
acceptance criteria not yours their
acceptance criteria whether Laboratory
test whether other tests because you
have to adhere to
their acceptance or rejection criteria
if you don't know it in advance and you
don't bring you know the right covas or
the right documents they cannot clear it
in their market so in your Market it
might be okay but in their Market it's
not going to work this is why make sure
that when you negotiate a deal you
understand those criteria and you make
sure that you can adhere to that I saw
too many cases where it was not
aligned and it creates a lot of
issues so sometimes it's not about the
price it's not about the quality it's
not about the size of the of the flowers
or whatever sometimes it's just
laboratory tests heavy metals or
whatever the case
is this is a
very uh
schematic chart how we ship cannabis by
the way how we ship Medical Products
anyhow we pick with the temperature
control truck we take it to the airline
we take it to the airport we special
measured at the airport we use special
special service with the
Airlines and on and on and on now you
want to talk about ontime
delivery you have to plan it very very
carefully and I'll talk about it a bit
later somehow I don't know why a lot of
cases in this industry is like you're
waiting 5 days before the expiry of the
of the permit and then you [ __ ] why why
canot do it months before why to be
under pressure and now you can
understand that sometimes there will be
delays there will be issues Customs or
whatever and then you are very close to
the expiry of your of your license so it
takes time and you if you want to meet a
deadline you have to plan it
carefully
security so you see there special
vehicles to maintain security I told you
already that in some cases some
countries we are not moving it without a
armed guard whether in the truck or
following the
truck of course GPS um you know GE
fencing all those the solutions but make
sure that you have a good insurance
coverage because sometimes things may
happen and by the way most of the things
we we didn't have even one case of theft
most of it is Damages or temperature
Excursion or things like that so make
sure that your insurance cover that we
provide special insurance policy for
cannabis make sure that you have such
it's a little bit more than just regular
pharmaceutical but you better have
it operation challenges well I can talk
about until the
evening so first of
all exportation procedures okay some
countries like for instance Canada you
have to be registered as an exporter and
we found cases where we already
collected the the goods and the guy was
not registered as an exported by the way
it's 2 minutes on the computer but you
have to do it once or you have to
register yourself with the with the uh
um Ministry of Agriculture Authority
local sorry I think it's C exactly so
you know exploitation should be be
simple but sometimes the procedure are
heavy sometimes they want to examine it
some sometimes they want to test it by
the way if it's within the EU it's
relatively easy but most of it if it's
coming from Canada Australia a lot of
issues custom clearance process okay be
aware that in most cases not always
customers may open your uh not your
boxes but your P to take a look physical
examination which may cause delays
usually not damages although we saw that
but you know highly
regulated documents and documents and
documents okay it's all about
documentation licenses permits feto
sanitary certificates
covas all kinds of declarations if you
don't have the right documentation it
will be stuck so you better have it and
by the way in kabog our practice is
where I'm not picking up even not one
flower before we get all the documents
and we make sure that we can clear it on
the other side I'm just encourage you to
take the same approach because there's
no use to ship it if you cannot clear it
so make sure that you can clear it
before even you pick it up and take it
to the airport or
whatever and other authorities okay it's
not just customs in Israel if you want
to clear a cannabis shipment you have to
go through three agencies Ministry of
Health Ministry of Agriculture and
Customs okay Germany is a little bit
different Canada is well not import to
Canada but a bit different so anyway
other agencies that you have to go
through physical examination already
spoke about it strict full endtoend
control in Pharma and I'm telling I'm
saying again it's a medical medical
product so the farma world and the
Canabis World require you as a shipper
to make sure that you control the old
chain you cannot say yeah I ship it and
that's it it doesn't work this way if
you have an audit from the authorities
that you will have to prove that you
know how to control the whole supply
chain there's no stories about that this
is the requirement so you have to make
sure that your logistic service
providers trucking companies whatever
you can control the whole way
through and we are very much
recommending on time real time data
loggers so you can track the shipment
all the way through and if there are
delays or if there are issues you can
know about it
immediately something that we developed
in the last year is a very very
reliable um Land Transportation within
Europe I brought you an example of a
shipment going out from Portugal to
Germany by temperature control vehicle
GDP certified company and you can see
perfect temperature control everything
is around 20
20° less than 36
hours don't try to see where it came
from okay leave it everybody's looking
at the map you know to see and H secured
okay you can see few pilots in the truck
and those poles are keeping the the
freight so it will not fall or move or
whatever so limited there not that many
companies can do that so you have to
find a very reliable GDP certified
provider Pharma grade
service spoke about that online GPS you
can see at every point where the truck
is and what is the temperature inside
the
truck
reliability reasonable cost
responsiveness if you wish required
documents remember when you move in
Europe you cross
borders now if you look at this
example they went from Portugal where
it's legal through Spain which is not
legal France which is not legal and then
Germany which is legal but you know
crossb within the EU is is possible but
you have to have the right H
documentation and don't hide it don't
write Pharmaceuticals write cannabis
it's okay but as long as you have the
import permit and the export permit and
your documents are good you're good
although you've passed those bord ERS
okay but you have to have a very
reliable provider that can arrange the
whole thing by the way pre-arranged it's
not that the truck is the living and and
you sit down and pray
no uh that's what I said
pre-arranged air fre so most of the
Cannabis goes by air fre right so first
of all I just want you to know that
there are very limited number of
airlines that will carry cannabis not
every Airline will carry it just very
limited number of Airlines the second
thing is high cost sorry to say that the
airlines are taking advantage of our
shortage and the cost to ship cannabis
is very high much higher than than other
things when you come with to an airline
with a cannabis shipment you will always
have a delay of 2 three days before they
approve it because they have they have
procedure to improve the Cannabis
especially when you for instance
shipping with u let's say Emirates
General I mean those airlines that are
going through the gulf so you know the
gulf is canist is not legal so they have
to approve it in the origin station they
have to approve it in the what we call
transip Trans shipment station and then
in the destination takes two three days
so before we have this uh this we call
it okay to forward so before we have
this uh confirmation from the airline we
cannot move it so remember it's not that
we pick it up and ship it we have to do
some arrangements before we can ship it
on okay of course direct flights are
easier but it Australia right to
Australia almost no flights or not
direct flights especially not from
Canada in Europe very
limited so it's an issue tamak time you
know that more most of
W goes
fast so um okay so there's a be aware of
two things first of all the trans
shipment Point have to be
rearranged never ever ever touch a US
soil with cannabis shipment they will
conf confiscate it don't use American
American Airlines I know I I don't mean
the American Airlines company don't even
think think about Landing in the US with
cannabis shipment with
THC okay I just want to go with the
lesson learned first of all packages
make sure that your packages first of
all optimal
size if you look here in this pallet you
see that this shipper paid a lot of
money for for nothing right because the
the boxes are not completely on the
pallet but you're paying for the air as
well
by the way something about this uh
thermal covers but
nonetheless um licenses validity day I
spoke about it avoid weekends try not to
Stu on weekends because then you will
pay more storage and you cannot clear it
try to do it before the weekend or after
the weekend and original documents
that's my last
one do and doesn't let's hear it let's
hear it for your let's hear it for your
mall it's 255 it goes fast that's
incredible finish that plan your flight
carefully don't ever [ __ ] before you
make sure that you can clear it and
don't go through the US don't go through
there you go those are the good rules
one more time for Mr ashel I'm sure if
you have more questions about the
logistics he will be outside waiting for
you there at St 426 thank you very much
this is the international cannabis
business conference Berlin 24 shout out
to our title sponsor Tom group shout out
to all of our other sponsors and shout
out to all of you