we love her so much she's the founder of
the MJ Universe she's amazing all over
the world and especially in Germany
let's hear it for Lisa
hog hello everybody and welcome to this
panel on creating Learning System and
back practices for the global cannabis
industry let's have a warm welcome for
our
panelists um today uh we have on this
panel um Deepak um Anand and you
potentially know him he's been in the
Cannabis uh industry for a very long
time um just one second sorry here he's
a principal um at the ASD consultancy
Service as business strategy company
focused on Consulting businesses in
Alcohol Tobacco pharmaceutical cpg
Industries um deepak's uh experience
spans in a decade of cannabis industry
including as an operator and advisor to
companies in North America Europe Africa
and Asia and um he also actively uh
contributes to patient advocacy and um
as a vice chair at medical cannabis
Canada and is also involved in the
advancement of a global standard within
the Cannabis sector as a member of the
ASM that's um Association that's working
with global standards then uh I'm
pleased to have Dr shaav V here on my
panel um she's the head of research and
toxicology at du turpins uh she received
a PhD uh studying chemistry of vaping
and developing a toxicology program to
review all the ingredients used in true
turbing products additionally she's
actively contributes to the advancement
of global standards um also with ASM um
and then I also have here on panel John
Slaughter I'm CEO and founder of North
High since 2016 um High North or high
North sorry um has worked with over 900
cannabis companies around the world and
performed over 460,000 tests on cannabis
and for the past three years um High
North has been recognized as uh the
analytical laboratory of the year in
Canada
um so a round of applause for the
panelists and before we dive into this
let's have a little bit of a look into
what a learning system is a learning
system is a system that allows you to
create manage organize and deliver
knowledge so um as we all know education
and educating on the cannabis plant is
one of the key factors of success uh for
our industry and also maybe um just uh
as a good example for a learning system
is the ICBC itself um because it's a
place where people can actively engage
and uh cultivate their knowledge um so
I'm very excited uh to for our panel
today and my first question of the day
goes to Deepak Deepak uh can you go a
little bit maybe explain to the audience
what kind of learning systems currently
exist in the Kus industry what is
missing and why are learning systems so
important to accelerate sustainable
growth
yeah look I mean thanks for having me
and and thanks for putting this together
I think that just a step back I think
education and learning is so important I
think as countries start to legislate
and legalize cannabis both for medical
and and non-medical purposes I think
it's really really important to have
knowledge sharing and information and
education uh there is a lot of Education
there's a lot of people that need to be
educated everyone from Regulators to you
know stakeholders to shareholders to uh
doctors to you know literally every
every single part of the value chain so
what exists now I mean there's a lot
that's happening across uh across the
world right so I think often when you
stay in Europe you you forget that there
is a number of countries you know Canada
the US that have gone down the path of
legalization and and have a lot of
experience in this and so there's a lot
that is actually available in terms of
educational content there's a number of
programs on a variety of different
sections of of the value chain whether
it be cultivation extraction testing
processing uh there's a lot that that's
available so it really depends on which
Market you're focusing on and it's not a
one- siiz fits-all solution but there is
quite a bit that exists so I think you
know the perfect system is really
blending what exists with what's
different about a market that you might
be
in thank you so let's move over to
Shauna um Shauna one of the uh things
that people often mix up our standards
and regulations can you maybe explain a
little bit what the difference is and
can you also maybe comment if there if
you think is there a global cannabis
standard or is it just like a set of
interpretations of
regulations yeah so very often times
when we talking about standards um a lot
of the partners or other cannabis
industry
members are concerned that these
standards are going to become
regulations and they're very confused on
what the difference is um a standard is
just a way of doing something a lot lot
of times they can be like bare minimum
requirements and sometimes they can be
more than that but a lot of times
they're very voluntary and a lot of
times there are things that you're
already doing it's just directing you to
do it uh a certain way over another one
so you know a great example is there's a
standard for the shape that a stop sign
should be right that's not specifically
written into a law like every stop sign
has to be a hexagon it has to be this
shade of red but it's written into a
standard so you're already a city is
already creating stop signs so might as
well create a stop sign that's the same
as the city next to them that's the same
as the state or country that that
borders them um so that's kind of how
standards are are implemented right it's
just like cohesion across uh different
locations um so everyone can kind of
understand it do you see a lot of Def
fragmented rules for that or is it like
one harmonous standard that you also see
develop or we can maybe talk also about
the segments a little bit so I think
right now it's very disjointed uh cuz
cannabis is a very new industry um we
haven't been around for very long like
as a regulated industry um where if you
look at other Industries you know like
Ceramics or uh construction they have
standards that everyone follows but
they've been around for over a hundred
years so it does take time for these
cohesive standards to get created um a
great platform that is creating them ISM
which and I are both a part of and
anyone can become a member of ASM it's
also a very low cost uh of Entry which
is great um and all the members
contribute to standards so you have to
get buyin from consumers and from
industry manufacturers um and there's
even Regulators that join so it's a very
valuable platform to get cohesive buying
so that we will all be following the
same standards in the future but for
different
areas yeah yeah it's all broken down
into different areas yeah so John where
do you see the testing standards uh
moving globally which countries have
good testing standards uh which do not
uh or may need some improvement and um
for which segments of the Cannabis
industry do you think uh standards are
most important to be set yeah that's a
first of all thank you for inviting us
here to to Canada from Canada here to be
able to speak the European market it's
you know as we look at it you know deepo
talk talked about it right there go and
get a license right now you now have a
German medicinal license your cannabis
is probably coming from Canada and it
was probably tested through high North
and I probably have the COA so it's
we're seeing these standards as they go
around the world and change you know for
us in Canada we have 17 pharmacopia we
test to that's because all the countries
around the world in fact aren't going
together they're actually drifting apart
if we look at the difference between uh
sending something to Israel or send
something to Australia the difference in
not only the pharmacopia but the testing
needed are drastically further apart and
I don't think for me in Canada it's fine
because I can be this Swiss army knife
that can be whatever you need it to be
and Export to every country but I I
really don't think The Regulators have
really thought about and taken a step
back to say I want to make really strict
guidelines for cannabis for this country
it's like great but now not one lab in
your entire country can actually test to
those standards without millions of
dollars of investment during a time in
which it's in its infancy and nobody's
going to want to do that investment so
you almost hamstrung every single one of
these cultivators that's trying to get
this 2 million squ foot operation off
the ground using a lab that they can
barely get access to that they're
getting data back from that they
question every time that's often like 25
30 days later than they need to be
getting it and it's those regulations
seem smart off the bat but just e adding
something like bromide to your pesticide
testing that just caused a $1.5 million
investment to whatever laboratory now
has to test that that's because you're
doing a second run you're using another
lcms your most expensive machine is now
being run and if you think about how
important a laboratory is especially in
those early days that's your dashboard
of your car every morning you get in
your car the speedometer as people know
in Canada it might say it's 80 you're
actually driving 62 and you need to
think about that calculation cuz my labs
always give me back THC scores that are
higher it's like coming in in every
single one of the lights being on in
your car and you just ignoring those
lights well those lights could be hop
lat and virus spreading across your
entire lab entire facility but if the
lab is giving you back results saying
it's clean it's clean and there you go
you press on not having that data I
think it it not only it seems like a
good idea it seems like you've added
good standards but what you've really
done is you've limited The Limited the
Laboratories and literally blinded The
Growers and I think it's just you're set
up to cause the longest curve to able to
get up and actually get functional in
that market not happening plain is
simply not happening and if you want to
talk about where this goes bad it's the
Legacy Market taking over it's products
coming in that are 100% untested because
the only ones that are hitting people's
hands that are actually being smoked are
not from your legal market so you feel
like you've added good standards but
what you've really done you've lagged
the legal clean industry and you've
given a jump start to the backside of
the industry the worst example is the
Netherlands love to dunk on them for
this because go into any place in there
any coffee shop you feel like what
you're getting is good weed whatever it
might be good weed it's not tested it's
plain and simply not tested and and
every single place you go to none of
that stuff is tested so great place to
go for vacation and smoke some weed but
your your pesticides could be off there
could be heavy metals they could be alot
toxins you have no idea I think it's a
requirement for the new uh cannabis that
is provided through the pilot programs
that they do testing yeah but agree with
the Cannabis that is from illicit
sources and the thing is right now if
you look at past what 20 30 years have
you've been going to a coffee shop in
Amsterdam you're you're smoking 100% on
tested
cannabis I mean um we're talking about
also different uh areas where um
standards and testing standards like
become relevant for cultivation for
manufacturing for all those kind of
things so um I know that they have been
discussing Global medicinal cannabis
standards in the international narcotic
control board in 21 but I have not
personally seen a lot of development um
so shaa uh who is really developing the
global cannabis standards are we as an
industry developing those are The
Regulators who who are the people really
developing the Cannabis
standard so the people that are
currently developing standards have been
The Regulators um there are you know
global standard groups like ASM that I
mentioned um but those standards take
time um because it's such a thorough
process um so they take time to come to
place do I think Regulators are the best
people to create standards no um
oftentimes we see Regulators don't have
a lot of knowledge on the Cannabis
industry nor do they have any firsthand
experience in the Cannabis industry um
and so I think we're going to see a lot
of regulators are writing laws that are
often times different than
what has already been placed in other
countries or other states they think oh
we can do it better they saw pitfalls
here and they're like let me try it
differently um so I think what we might
see in the future is Regulators try what
they think is best it doesn't work out
they realize it like it takes time for
them to admit that maybe I don't know
what's best and then they'll direct to
these Global standards um and you knowm
is one but I know there's other ones I
don't know if deug if you know other
ones yeah I think from a European
perspective it's important to understand
right so far there's been no single
monograph even on flower right and it's
been a long time coming I know now
there's a lot of work that's going into
creating you know a monograph to
Sunflower so there certainly seems to be
more harmonization occurring I mean
that's the whole fundamental of the
European Union generally so it's
unfortunate that we still see a very
much a country bycount approach within
Europe uh and that's you know one of the
one of the biggest challenges because if
you're a cultivator in Canada or
Portugal or or anywhere and you're
trying to service you know Denmark
Poland Germany and the UK you have four
completely different set of regulations
that you need to follow just because
there's no harmonization of regulations
or even you know a monograph right so I
think having a monograph which now
there's a lot of work happening at the
the European uh Union level and finally
hopefully we'll see a monograph on
flower but those sorts of things
actually need to happen because it
creates a lot of pressure on the supply
chain right so for example you look at
Denmark no one's supplying to Denmark
really now because at one time there was
a lot of hype but really if you
understand the Danish regulations you
actually need to reverse engineer your
your cultivation room to be able to
exclude certain pesticides an example to
be able to sell in that market so
there's a real requirement for
harmonization unfortunately in the EU I
do agree with China Regulators aren't
necessarily the best placed but
unfortunately in the EU the way things
work is it is regulator driven uh but
there's a lot of companies now that are
giving feedback to the European Union on
Flow and I think more of that actually
needs to happen um the next question
would have been also in that regard uh
like I have my background in facility
management for me it's every light
switch has a code basically and
everything is standardized so uh coming
into the Cannabis industry um I saw that
there are not many standards and I mean
also from your experience as an
entrepreneur um we often see do you also
see that that like these pharmacological
regular standard systems like to many
they are a book of Seven Seals that have
to be
learned and don't make sense right like
for example you look at Switzerland this
you know whole organic requirement on
cannabis cultivation you know there's
certain things from a regulatory
perspective it isn't clear what The
Regulators were thinking when they were
going to start to launch these products
often times they self- serving but like
that is definitely part of the challenge
is that regulations sometimes are shaped
in a way that aren't necessarily
fostering to cannabis as a product
because yes it's a pharmaceutical
product in some instances but it's not
exactly the same as tobacco or the same
as Pharma it's you know it's a unique uh
kind of plant and it needs a unique set
of Regulation sometimes and and that's
one of the things from on the testing
side you see that all the time you could
grab any one of the tests heavy metals
for example you know it says use a
pharmacopia for your heavy metals and
justify it okay there are 10 so could or
am I going to go the high side the low
side it is how many grams per day am I
doing am I using tea as my analogy and
saying well it's like tea well how many
grams of tea am I having in a day
equivalent to cannabis therefore what
that would that be for my heavy metals
then as you take that and go to export
the broker might say no actually I
wanted one tenth that because I'm taking
that 10 G instead of one it it you're
you're giving because of the lack of of
like nailing down these things that deac
was getting into you've literally put it
back into the industry as a question
that the broker essentially has to
handle because they're the one that has
to get it into the country so they'll go
back to the health CID person go like so
is it this is it that okay yeah guess
what guys you're testing zinc now and it
needs to be over this level it's like
okay well I guess we're testing zinc now
right so it it it really is it is so
fluid right now and and it's not really
that fluid is going in absolutely all
directions uh I mean it's interesting
that you say that because we have that
discussion here a lot for the clubs in
Germany um is it going to be food
standard is it going to be farmer grade
standard or agricultural standard that
we're sticking or we have our own
solution how important are analytical
testing standards especially for the
start of the legalization and maybe what
are some lessons learned that we can
take here when uh when lobbying for
those causes what is important and what
criteria should be used I I I I think
it's the the you know to kind of build
on that point there of pharmaceutical it
cannabis is a living plant it's going to
have micros on it so if you try to go no
microbials no nothing on top of this
this thing's going to be a dead plant
you're leading down to radiation if
you've done that you've now created a
whole other industry of a radiation that
needs to be coming up out of this you
know wherever you are if it's whatever
country you're in you now not only need
labs to be putting in massive money to
be investing into more testing standards
but now all of a sudden you're adding a
radiation facilities all the way across
your place so that you could be close to
an a radiation facility to get it down
to zero microbes so you can get it out
the door some of these things just plain
and simply don't make sense and I think
it's because we have to go back to a
pharmacopia that makes sense to us but
inside of that you're like 98% of that
pharmacopia makes sense but 2% doesn't
but that's the best one I can can go
with right now until there really is one
that matches cannabis you are you are
setting people up to grow in different
completely different standards and this
is one of the things that I worry about
when I hear um you know a top Canadian
grower has just moved over to wherever
new country of of of whatever it is it
to some of them it's like you've taken
an F1 racer that was in an F1 car and
you just dropped them into a l with all
the gauges flashing and you're saying BN
F1 racer it's like buddy like I don't
even the gauges aren't working like it's
the track looks different like how do
you expect me to be the F1 racer that I
want me to be right so that that
definition really does it sets the
Cannabis facilities especially the
Growers up for failure day one
absolutely day one if I can just add one
more piece to what John said I think you
know you look at irradiation even as one
example you know in Europe you need to
comply with uh you know safety for
inhalation which is typically on the
monograph 5.1.4 and there's different
ways to reach that right so in Germany
for example if you're trying to sell a
product with that compliance you you
need to irradiate and then you need to
be able to get something called an amrad
F an amrad 5 license and that takes you
know anywhere from 9 to 12 months to be
able to get but now people are actually
trying to see ways to get around that
process and you know some people are
using steam some people are using you
know a variety of different things and
it leads to non-compliance in some in
some cases and actually fooling the
regulator in some cases so really you're
not creating best standards for the
industry cuz people are just trying to
figure out how to get around 5.1.4
they're not best practices but best work
around exactly exactly and and that that
that exact literally you you literally
nailed on that inhalation one it's a
perfect one it even if you could create
a cannabis operation that could work
under this legally great you're under it
who's going to want that product around
around the rest of the country so great
you've created something that only your
local Market's going to want to consume
and it's never going to be exported
every country CU you're going to go to
other countries and you're going to Beed
against people that aren't using
inhalation as their as their monograph
which means that the product's not going
to be radiated which means it's going to
get to you faster it's going to be
fresher it's not going to be as dried
out like there's a lot of little things
even if you said my radiation barely
even degrades my product it still added
6 weeks to everything and 6E old weed is
still sixe old weed and it's not like it
was handled well during that process
it's going to be a degraded product on
the global market versus other people
that don't have to sit under that
standard again you're setting your
country up to fail yeah what they're
talking about is essentially unintended
consequences right Regulators come in
they say something and they don't have
an understanding of the big picture so
like um John mentioned adding bromide to
it and or or maybe lowering an action
limit of something and they don't
understand that that means now the lab
has to redo their whole analytical
methods maybe they need to get new
analytical instruments and then they're
farther and farther behind from
providing compliant products to
Consumers and the whole idea behind best
practices and learning systems should be
to allow consumers to participate in the
regulated Marketplace that should be the
goal and often times they don't match
that goal that's very true I mean um sha
you are also working with tpin a lot uh
in the German phop cannabis is basically
THC and CBD and that's it um should um
tpin and other cannabinoid um content
also play a more wide role in this or
would they limit
us I would say Turpin and other
cannaboids they play a role in the
product and uh consumer choices and uh
consumer experience of the product um
but I I wouldn't want to see Regulators
come in and try to regulate based on
those materials it's very complex
there's a lot of compounds in there um
and you know Regulators will more often
than not get things wrong but what I'd
love to see is for
manufacturers to take a voluntary
approach and do tpine analysis and maybe
list the top three or the top five tpin
on the product packaging and that just
allows the consumers to have more
information and to make a choice um that
you know fits better with what
experience they're going for Deepak what
are some other Lessons Learned for like
especially in that regard yeah I think I
I think I would take this back right I
think uh often Regulators are looking at
THC and CBD because it's the big thing
but not looking at what consumers
actually want and if you look at what
consumers want the trend is towards CVG
and CBN and thcv and you know a variety
of other new cannaboids right and so
consumers are always going to get that
whether it be from the the Legacy or the
or the legal market right so I think
it's very important when framing
cannabis regulations to understand that
this is very much a process and not an
event so you you as a regulator need to
keep on top of what's happening in the
industry and be able to go through that
process and improve and be able to add
other cannaboids so I don't necess think
regulating them to the same level is
necessarily the best thing because
there's different risks with different
cannaboids you'll see workarounds in hhc
which is a really hot topic in in Europe
now and yeah exactly so I mean started
don't get me started oh you have to keep
on top of consumer Trends and be able to
give consumers what they want because
otherwise they're just going to get it
somewhere else that that is a perfect
example of a work around hhc and all the
rest of these things you have forced
people to to play with wacky chemistry
to be able to get to something that
delivers the same in the end you have
just inside of that process you have
introduced new chemicals that are not
being tested they're flying through the
product tell me that that hhc product if
it was truly created hhc it's going to
have additional analytes inside of it
you've just essentially added something
to a very natural and gorgeous product
so no yeah agree under no circumstance
no thank you Thank You
Preach so uh maybe as a last question
before we open the floor for the
audience um is uh to all of you um how
can we as the industry enable more
learning systems and how can we actively
engage in the development of standards
and why should we be motivated as
stakehold us to actively engage maybe
start with you
shaa um I think the first step of
creating Learning Systems is to share
your information um I know this is like
a for-profit industry and so you want to
kind of keep your secret sauce to
yourself but the only way to educate
Regulators or um you know create these
Learning Systems educate consumers Etc
is to share the information that you
have like there's a lot of knowledge
people have been working with cannabis
for decades um you know before the
regulated market came to play and so
there's knowledge that needs to be
shared um
and and accessible a lot of uh
information is hidden behind pay walls
unfortunately um so I think it would be
great if people created like a database
that had these you know PDFs to these
papers that are typically hidden behind
pay walls um to be accessible to
everyone that'd be fantastic um but yeah
but many scientists also hand out the
papers if you contact them usually they
give you the paper yeah I've done that
I've direct emailed professors and said
hey can I can you send me your paper and
almost every single time they do no
problem so deak what do you think how
can we create better learning systems
for the Cannabis industry yeah look I
think it's all about working together
right I think what happens and what I
see in this industry particularly is
people start to get competitive very
quickly and meanwhile we haven't even
started you know scratching the surface
with respect to where this plant is and
where regulations are you know I think
we can all agree that the Cannabis
industry is only going to grow from here
where we are at today in 2024 is very
much the start of the industry as a
opposed to you know being a mature phase
there's going to be way more consumption
of cannabis that occurs on a global
basis so we got to be able to work
together as an industry I agree with sha
completely it's there are certain
competitive aspects but if you're not
going to start to engage regulators and
not going to start to create learning
management system and education
platforms and share information it's
just going to make everyone's job harder
particularly the regulator and when
you're coming forward as an industry you
need to have a collective collaborative
voice so that you're able to make
meaningful change with regulators
because the last thing Regulators want
to see is an industry that's disjointed
and not speaking from a from a single
voice I think it's very important to
share learnings with each other and
actually be able to have conversations
like this and others uh to be able to
bring out that information yeah yeah I
always say we need trust honesty
collaboration
THC so I'm using that I'm using that
nobody else heard that from Canada I'm
using that um it's it's it's funny that
it when I think about the groups that
I've seen historically that have put
together some of these regulations
there's someone from the lab side on
Pharma useless sorry useless the two two
analytes go inside of a pharmaceutical
product the obsp and the drug it's the
easiest thing in the world to test wrong
person to be on that panel there should
be one person in a hoodie I'm sorry that
there should be a master grower from
somewhere that is in a hoodie that gets
it that has been there growing it for 20
years there's not one person on that
table in a hoodie guy or girl I've seen
amazing female Growers out there there
should be one because that is the one
side of this that I think when you get
to the end of these regulations you go
this is the rag I want and and then go
back to zinc and they'll go but every
plant has zinc so let's just throw that
law in the garbage you know every every
plant has microbials so you know it
would be good to take these regulations
go back to a grower and say show me you
can grow this before I tell the world
that this is the regulation show me
you're an amazing grower I have no doubt
in your skills you're so tuned in you
have a great operation prove to me you
can grow to this standard cuz right now
if you can't I have list literally
created the possible scenario that
nobody could grow into so that's the one
thing I think we we do have a rich group
of people uh inside of over the world
that I've talked to and I'll tell you
every once in a while I'll have a
conversation with somebody that starts
you know in a weird tangent by the time
you're done you're like that's brilliant
I don't know how that has never come to
light and how do I bring you into bring
to this conversation because you've gone
down a path for 25 years growing
outdoors in this scenario with this and
that and you found ways of getting
everything to work you need to be a part
of this conversation so more hoodies at
the round table that'll
help yes
yes so um ah yes Z I'm right here let's
hear for our panelists first of all
question yes questions do you have a
question no the audience I see this
person has their hand up I always tell
people all the time uh you know if
you're a suit find a hippie if you're a
hippie find a suit correct and then we
can all work together yep everybody all
at once thank you um hold it close to
your face yes sir uh one of the things I
want to ask is uh we're speaking about
for example the uh
SCM and teaching a teaching platform uh
and what John just said earlier you need
somebody in a hoodie um but not is
there's a disconnect between the
industry and the consumer um there's
also not everybody speaks cannabis okay
uh uh please don't uh some uh doctors
don't speak cannabis so is there a way
other than you know just teaching uh
grow uh Growers or the um
Regulators um I'm sorry uh on how what
steps or what they need to take into
account uh for the reg regulation to go
through as far as you need to have
everybody not just somebody in a hoodie
you need somebody in the uh in police in
Department you need uh yes you do need
far but you also need a priest you know
uh I would love the pope to say cannabis
is okay and it's just a domino effect
but that's another subject
for what are your thoughts on that I
would like to get high with the
Pope it's we can solve a lot of problems
like I think I think what you're you
kind of get back to this big problem
that we talk about in Canada which is
removing the stigma and I think you know
if you want to say where does where does
the the removal of the stigma start it
starts with you and you and you and you
and you and you and you it starts with
uh telling your grandma she be take she
should be taking CBD oil it you know it
it goes to that person who can't sleep
at night you know what CBN really works
really well like I think you know
keeping that conversation and keeping it
um a serious conversation at that level
helps for that kind of remove the stigma
how you get to the Pope I I'll throw
that down the panel cuz uh I myself am
not a religious person so I don't know
much but there you
go yeah I mean in general it's super
important that we like um I always say
the people who have the money should
give the money to the people who do the
work AKA your local activists so you
should all Support also engaging those
kind of in initiative who engage and
people who do the education like Misha
yeah and maybe support some of those
activities and that we we can really see
where the information gets into the
system and so we can create the learning
systems at all yeah if you if you if you
look at the nutriceutical industry a new
neutral comes out every couple years but
it takes s years before people are like
you know what Kirin actually works it
actually works but Kirin and turmeric
have been around here for 20 years Kirin
was was isolated about 10 years ago
inside of products even that product
that has no Stigma before before it
actually sinks in and people go yeah it
works it takes a very long time and I
think the patient side of it and the
kind of uh the constant hit of water is
you know water defeats Rock not by being
strong but by being consistent so and I
think that's that's kind of the the path
we need to take here as we look at that
stigma and breaking that down I think
just sharing personal stories is so
valuable um you know I come up here and
I talk about regulations and safety and
all that jazz but what really hits home
is hearing stories of how cannabis has
helped people um so share your story and
that'll encourage the next person to
share their story and that's how it
spreads and that's how you get Buy in
from all different groups of individuals
can I just make a Counterpoint to that I
think you know education is more about
you know teaching and learning and I
think as much as we need to be teaching
which I agree
I agree with I think we also need to be
learning we know that cannabis is not a
benign substance we know that has some
risk I think we as an industry need to
be open to be able to also having that
conversation let's actually properly
understand the risks right that are
associated with cannabis because you
lack complete credibility when you're
coming from a one-way perspective in
terms of how great everything is and
certainly there's a number of great
things but I also think we need to be
receptive to learning about some of the
risks right and that's where countries
like Canada are doing a lot of work in
terms of gathering data what has the
impact been into driving what's the
impact being underage access you know
and and and it's it's there's pros and
cons there I think generally things are
moving really well but there are certain
aspects that we may need to tweak such
as age of access so I think it's
important to be receptive and also learn
from others uh in this industry I agree
uh 100% um there's something I call it
uh the educated decision so we should
enable an educated decision and that's
only possible if you know all different
aspects I mean there are a lot of
studies from all over all the time I'm
constantly going back 20 30 almost 40
years U showing the E efficacy of
cannabis and I think when you're dealing
with the scientist you maybe want to get
these studies into their hands but also
you know it's just an uphill battle you
got to fight 80 years of propaganda
every time every time and and it's so
you have to go so individually there's
no magic wand that you can wave and
everybody will get it right away but you
know I if it were easy I guess it would
be done
already all right we have two more
minutes you have two more minutes is
there would you like to sing a song can
no but maybe we have one more question
okay we have one more question Dereck
always asking I'm not such a good singer
so I don't
know as as an exception I don't have a
question but I do uh feel it as a
challenge because John know dump dumped
on the Dutch and I'm Dutch
so the point you make is true most of
the the coffee shop weeds not tested at
all but I think people should understand
it's actually forbidden by law for a
coffee shop to get we tested so and
there are some coffee shops they started
about four or five years ago
basically
Illy uh so illegally having the weed
tested but they still do it because they
they want to have that service for the
for the customer so it's not that they
don't want it it's that they cannot do
it it's one so my brother actually lives
in the Netherlands and it wasn't until I
went over there and I was like oh [__]
this is how it works but it's like it's
it you know for me it was like oh maybe
you know they sell they sell weed in
other ones maybe we'll put a lab here
I'm like no they can't even test like
it's just it was just such a
mind-blowing experience to me to that
years people have been coming to these
coffee shops years you know the amount
of times I hear right now that's like if
I could get my hands on that original
skunk seed from Amsterdam cross it with
my ice cream cake and my gelato I've got
fire you know we're still looking back
at the Netherlands as these like you
know like uh like the pyramids like it's
like wow how did they build these things
like wow this is amazing but today it's
like Egypt's not even part of the global
economy is what we're doing all the rest
of these things yet we're looking back
to these things that's what I'm worried
about with the Netherlands it's like you
had this point you had this point and
you could have literally been the spot
that everything became a jump Point like
could I take give me the same don't rub
it in that oh no I'm going to rub it in
I told you I'm going to dunk on you I
told I mean do the Dutch really want
that like the Dutch like to be quiet but
but here they like to be quiet and cool
they don't necessarily want to be oh
look at us look at us we're Dutch weed
imagine just just take that's not really
their Vibe imagine if you put as much
effort into chrysanthemum uh studies as
you did cannabis we would I would have
no job I would not be here I would not
be here so you guys could do it thank
you all right let's give a round of
applause for the
panel let's hear it again for our panel
always fantastic we love Lisa hog so
much this is the international cannabis
business conference Berlin 2024