right so you think that you've gotten a
legalization and the people who hate
cannabis still hate cannabis and they
still work against cannabis and they
still want to stop it even though you
keep having common sense and if listen
if common sense and science were
accepted by politicians we would all
have fewer
problems uh but what do I know okay
we're going to move on this is the
international cannabis business
conference Berlin 2024 i' like to thank
our title sponsor the Tolman group we
you we're doing a science and technology
Forum in Slovenia September 13th and all
kinds of other stuff now to discuss the
cultivation of medical cannabis in
Germany we have an All-Star panel and it
is led by the managing director of of
black onyx Capital LLC put your hands
together and welcome Claudia deam Mor
[Applause]
[Music]
hello hello everybody good morning
so uh excited to be here I'm going to
make a brief introduction uh my name is
Claudia de la MOA kind of part of the
family now of ICBC so um I'm an
investment banker and managing director
at black Legend capital a boutique
Investment Bank based in Los Angeles
cannabis is one of the industries that
we've been focusing on for the past
almost 10 years every vertical and um
also uh Emerging Markets such as Europe
and other countries so this panel is
very interesting because it's actually
not about only cultivation I think you
know we're we're um representing here
every verticle of the industry from
cultivation to distribution to
manufacturing Pharma so I'll make a
quick quick um introduction first of all
here Kai my friend Kai he's one of the
best attor in the country so he will be
probably diving into the um you know
answer for legal legal questions and
then we have Benedict the founder of can
sativa which is the unique and only
authorized distributor in Germany
correct me if I'm wrong of um cannabis
flower can medical cannabis um
cultivated in the country so we know
there was a tender in uh in the country
and three companies won the tender and
there are the cultivators licensed cul
cators uh deman till R and Aurora and we
have actually here also philli from
demic um so Benedict as I said is from K
sativa a distributor and then we also
have Thomas from 420 Pharma manufacturer
and pharmaceutical uh company if you
guys want to introduce briefly yourself
maybe and or add something
else yeah yeah yeah I'm Kai Fran I'm La
since 2002 I'm in the industry TW since
2017 2017 I visited my first Cannabis
Conference and uh since 2019 I'm only um
Consulting CBD companies hemp companies
medical cannabis import companies and
I'm the legal adviser of the European
Industrial Hemp
Association well I am Philip managing
director of deman have been in the
pharmaceutical industry now for more
than 10 years and two and a half years
now with deman um it's a bit more than
just cultivation for the German state it
has been and it will in the future
obviously but we are really covering the
full supply chain from C to sale to say
so yeah and um I'm Benedict um
representing kaniva we're enabling
cannabis and building the leading
platform to offer the most desirable
Brands and products we import package
distribute products throughout Germany
and also into other EU EU countries um
we're also covering most parts of the
value chain excluding the
cultivation yes my name is Thomas shaton
CEO from 420 Pharma I'm in the industry
since 5 years now we founded the company
2019 and are one of the uh yeah biggest
wholesaler here across Europe in 2022 uh
the company Cur Leaf uh stepped in as an
investor in our company and we are happy
to discover whatever is in front of us
after legalization here in Germany and
happy to be on this panel here thank you
very good so let me ask like a quick
quick clarification CU I saw you were
you know kind of looking at me like okay
so uh kativa distributor now also you
importer and also exporter yes I heard
that you're uh made a new partnership
for distribution to towards Czech
Republic correct so let me ask a
question so if you understand it
correctly this is how I actually have
been studying it for several years
following your work um Can sativa
distributes the medical flow produced by
the three uh cultivation you know
companies right authorized but at the
same time deman as he said um is
actually uh covering the entire supply
chain up to delivery so where's the
mismatch there I I I think it's it's a
great question and it's also let's say a
important question right now um be due
to the new regulation because what
you've mentioned is totally correct over
the last years we on behalf of the bay
farms so the the German Authority
distributed the locally grown medical
cannabis into the pharmacies 100%
correct that's one vertical of our work
in addition to that we import um other
products we have own Brands and also
have a wholesale business line so that's
a little bit the Kiva perspective and as
of this new change and I'm very sure
that we're covering this topic today in
our our panel there will be a certain
change because there will be not only
deman but potentially further licensed
producers in the future and obviously
with this new framework this products
are not required to be pumped through
the canera system because it's not part
of this tender of this cultivation
tender and also our distribution
agreement that we also won in a in in a
tender so we are really at a point where
caner canera is still the exclusive
partner of the governmental Authority on
the distribution of domestically grown
medical cannabis but only to the extent
of the existing contract and the
existing let's say old volumes and now
uh we have this change right until 2026
correct uh so it started in
2021 the first deliveries and it's a
five years or four years contract and
the last um product I think that was
Aurora and also deman in 2022 was
connected so 20 uh uh six should be
correct given that there is no change on
this overall framework and contract
because this is also something that
needs to be elaborated and to be worked
on will there be a change on this
contract that maybe deman has with the
authorities and also we have with the
authorities and that's probably nothing
that we can disclose or discuss publicly
right now okay but let's let's talk
about uh you know this this new there's
a couple of uh new situations here right
the uh legalization of adult you
and the
liberalization of medical cannabis now
the liberalization of medical cannabis
we're talking about the lifting of the
restrictions of production for each one
of the three cultivators and at the same
time also potentially unlimited
licenses someone says even up to 100 so
let's talk about the pros and cons you
know coming from uh the us we all uh are
used to you know think limited license
Market
is better than unlimited license market
so and plus at the same time there's
also the legalization of the adult use
which obviously you know it's not really
how we're thinking about it it's the
Cannabis Club Social Clubs and
potentially if when there will be you
know commercialization of adult use
probably the license authorizations to
cultivate um adult use will be given to
the medical cannabis cultivators all
right so pros and cons yeah I mean let
me uh maybe we took we take a look back
into history so if we remember the first
ICBC in 2017 there was the tender uh
everything the procedures were starting
and uh I remember 18 19 companies were
preparing for the application for the
tender lots of Consultants lawyers
companies coming here it was like a
green Rush here by that time in in in
Berlin um and um yeah that was a big
thing uh and everyone wanted to do that
so there were these restrictions to 10
tons for four years and we were just
talking about that Wen these
restrictions in time by that place and
we would have the same situation like
now without restriction anyone would
have been able to apply for a license if
the pharmaceutical grates were fulfilled
um imagine that uh we would have 10 15
20 30 facilities already here in Germany
producing locally but that didn't happen
so the Restriction were in place uh and
probably for the market development that
was the right decision for for that time
uh but then the federal elections came
and the Liberal Party the fdp uh they
were demanding that these restrictions
should be lifted uh and V chinburg
always said Germany has to become the
export um Nation the export world record
championship for medical can
and everyone said oh that's strange
that's a brave brave calling and yeah
now it it came yeah no one really um it
was at the last moment in November no
one really expected that lifted uh that
these restrictions were lifted because
it wasn't really in the debate but um
they did a good Lobby work here
these these guys so now we have the
situation indeed there is no restriction
whatsoever not on product quantity not
on numbers of facilities uh nothing when
you can produce cannabis to
pharmaceutical standards you can produce
it in in Germany you can apply and um
you will the the um authorization will
will have to be granted to your to your
company um exactly how many companies do
you think they're going to they're going
to start applying that's the big
question because we are not in the same
situation as 171 18 um companies and
people were prepared their money was
there uh the um North American companies
they were ready for expansion Going
Global going Europe um and this attitude
is not there anymore there were several
crisises the Cannabis Market in the US
still in the in in a crisis isn't it do
you think so the the the uh
funders of uh you know this new
cultivation facility would come from
North America or not like you know
Europe or hard to tell hard to tell
because you have to keep one thing in
mind uh there's this article 21 of the
single convention mention saying
basically and in Canada applies that
saying basically the the more you
produce domestically the less you can
import cor so in the mid to long run in
the next three to five years if de and
aova taway ramp up their production from
to 60 kilo 60 tons we have imported 30
tons now so what the balance will be
from the demand uh the local demand for
for medical cannabis and the local
production we will see how that will
will unfold
so so once once uh you know domestic
production will just you know increase
and new players will come online of
course the silon Convention as you said
says that if there's enough production
then you don't have you can block the
Importer so like what would be the
consequences for example for all of this
uh producers in other countries such as
uh you know Portugal Macedonia Colombia
aiming at you know already probably
selling to Germany would I be just not
not be able to sell any more into the
country
yes quite clear you heard that but but
but but wait Kai um there is one crucial
thing when it comes to medical cannabis
from my perspective so um and five years
ago where the whole business started
here in in in Germany or in Europe
particularly um we thought okay there
are so many facilities we can buy
everywhere this is the lowest problem
this is not the bottleneck then we were
into the business and discovered wow
it's not very very easy to grow cannabis
on the medical grade month by month week
by week do Harvest all two weeks and
deliver the same product in the same
range of of parameters so it's not like
easy putting uh money on the table
buying a facility starting the grow
maybe in three years this will be the
first productive grow when you start
right now so it's not like bam and you
have the facility ready and if the the
process change and the value change are
already established I wouldn't change my
Supply just because there is a new one
because I'm so related to the quality
and the consistency of this processes so
I think um Now new suppliers in Germany
coming to the market to run growth
facilities will have a very hard
standing when it comes to the economics
at the beginning 100% I I can just
confirm that I mean we know how long it
has taken up to run the facility Well
and we're still optimizing everything
every day um so to get a GMP facility to
get the GMP certificate which you need
in the European Union in order to
produce medic cannabis it is uh quite a
long
run and maybe I I know kai you you have
this opinion from a legal perspective
just like really from the business
perspective we have established
International Supply chains we have
great products brought to the market and
we have lowcost products we have high
quality products and in general I would
say more licensed producers also
domestically could lead to further
competition which is generally good for
the patients for the whole system um
however uh if I would place my bet I
would kind of disagree I think there
will be a future for imports um and
International Supply chains and we'll
figure a way out over the next few years
how this will look like but I also agree
with with you philli that those that
have like Head Start and have existing
cultiv cultivation sites domestically
established that they will definitely
play a role in the future um and the key
question is will there be further
significant funds for those let's say up
to 100 potentially additional
cultivators and maybe to add one more
point I think the the only important
question now is the as Peter mentioned
the the column two you know the second
part of the law if that will come then
everything for this recreational Market
has to be grown in Germany obviously I
mean I think we in a good position for
that as well and then obviously more
competitors may enter the market because
it has to be grown domestically the
question is then what will be the legal
frame or regulatory framework to B
better said uh which needs to be um
accomplished is that going to be also
for uh by the way for adult use heard um
in the future potentially when
commercialization is allowed still in
indoors
GMP now due to the international
regulations if the model projects come
uh the supply for the model products
have to be cultivated in Germany uh and
if you plan now to establish your own
facility uh your own cultivation
facility you in a better position to
supply also the model projects which are
coming but to answer your question I
think it really depends if you still
need ugp we we don't know yet we know
that's the highest standard we have in
gcp probably at least GP is a standard
then e GMP maybe somewhere between food
and GMP we we don't know yet but we
obviously say Okay stick to GMP you know
what you have and you have a good
quality in that okay so and now about
the the adult use uh so how do you see
this coming I mean I'm sure that the
everybody in you know at this conference
wants to know about potential
consequences of this Cann ofes clubs
they are social clubs they're kind of
different from the ones in Spain
obviously because they're totally legal
uh 500 Max uh members we don't know
which location uh by the way the member
has to drive right to the but they can
actually carry it out I don't know what
would be the consequences for you know
uh um the medical side and also as a as
a let's say as a patient as a user would
it be cheaper or more you know uh
economic or or easier for me to to get
my cannabis as a medical patient or as a
um you know member of the of the
clubs yeah maybe I I kick it off thanks
Thomas so um first of all the only
commercial commercially addressable
Market is the medical Market as of now
so the whole can Social Club system it's
for non-commercial purposes that's
important to understand and what would
be the Dynamics from our perspective
first of all we had the rescheduling of
cannabis S A nonactic and I think all of
us here and the panel saw over the last
two weeks probably significant impact in
our sales and revenue which is great so
we see that there is a seamless easy
patient Journey that those patients get
those products get cannabis that's like
very important and the the key question
is will there be in the future people
going into self therapy through those
cannabis social clubs for example or
will those patients go to like reliable
high quality established Supply chains
and also products that's something that
we will see however my opinion is if it
is a easy patient Journey which is
possible
this commercial addressable Market is
the one that will probably have a
significant impact um and I believe that
when it comes to the recreational adult
use system we need to wait a little bit
on actually the pillar two of the um uh
yeah law um that might come over the
next few years and this will be probably
from the commercial perspective the one
uh that might have more impact on the
overall system than the the cannabis
Social Clubs right we will see what
happens sorry yeah maybe to add to your
question regarding pricing and what does
it mean for the End customer patient
consumer in the end I mean right now you
go to the pharmacy and you pay the same
price as on the black market so already
right now and as Ben said the journey is
quite simple already 7 to 10 in the
pharmacy you can get a gram of cannabis
so I think um for a social club to get
to that level and to accomplish that
quality It's a Long Way um to have
yeah enough funds to really realize that
right so well by the way do you are you
do you know how much is going to be the
cost uh the cost per gram or you know
how much they're going to have to pay
the the members of the clubs it's
differing depending on the club what
kind of of style they they are have we
we are seeing clubs that would require a
yearly fee of 3,000 4,000 we see clubs
that is a fee like 500 so this is very
very uh different but when it comes to a
market question how will this affect at
the long run um the market who will
deliver the most convenient process to a
customer SLP patient will do the run
because um even if I would be a
recreational uh uh user for example but
my customer journey is much more easy to
get it over a pharmacy because they do
delivery for example door too and the
recreational or my cannabis club is 20
kilometers away and I have to go there
um I will do this maybe one or two times
and then I will say uh I go for the
Amazon concept I just click and I get it
in front of my door so basically there
will be market for everyone recreational
medical for example if we just see we
invited a lot of rotary clubs a lot of
Lions Clubs into our facility just to
show how cannabis is produced how the
variety of medical cannabis uh is is
shown to people who use this as as a
medical treatment and they are really
apologizing after this oh we never know
that we just thought that this is just
the joint and nothing more so you see
even those kind of customer groups in
the future will grow because more and
more people are getting rid of their
fears and this big stigma of narcotic is
gone here in Germany and I think this is
the biggest Market booster in total and
at the end convenience will do the
business and run yeah convenience
actually I would like to talk about
convenience in the medical Market okay
and this uh declassification at this
point I think that maybe on a side note
this adult use my help for the stigma
thing so that more actually patients
more people you know can actually get to
you know think that I'm going to use
cannabis but the declassification so
actually in Germany um as a patient the
situation was already pretty comfortable
because online clinics all you had to do
was just the first visit right the first
visit in person with the doctor and then
everything else could be done online and
also delivered Amazon style uh home uh
prices are you know pretty good
obviously now with the de classification
what
happens uh you can do everything online
what are the you know it's not more
narcotic so they say it's going to be
easier also for prescriptions but what
does it mean uh that you know the
process is going to be easier also for
doctors and patients so first of all I
think we can all agree on that one um
the most biggest workload for us for
example was the B Farm communication and
all the documentation you have to
deliver week by week uh two two numbers
after the comma and all that stuff um
and this is gone by now immediately
which makes us a lot of easier just
doing the processes internally plus uh
the most crucial thing for the industry
is really getting rid of the stigma so
it was really categorized as a narcotic
and in the media it was dealed as the
worst narcotic ever poison poison
invented on this planet and um this is
gone now and you see a lot of doctors
also they were so scared of applying for
a narcotic prescription because the
process is not that hard to get one but
of course then you are monitored a lot
of doctors said I don't want to be
monitored and I don't want to have all
this work just for I don't know € 10 so
I'm out of it and with this gun they
have a different approach towards it
because they are not so focused anymore
with with this narcotic stuff and it's
not a last line therapy anymore so
previously as a narcotic you could only
use it as a last line therapy like
morphine and so on and so forth so now
it can be really used like eoan yeah so
this is very important actually because
it's part of the medical Market which is
a great Market because you tap into a a
huge Market potentially can be also
covered by the healthcare system so this
is the Pharma world right
uh which is kind of new for many of us
um but yeah so let's let's for example
now you just said something new that I
didn't know about the the narcotic
license uh doctors have to uh get a
narcotic license in order to not not
really a license so there are two types
of prescription there is a blue one
which is the regular one and the yellow
one which is the narcotic stuff and for
that you have to apply at B Farm you
have to send your uh diploma as a doctor
to the B then fill out a paper and then
you get a bunch of prescription send it
to your uh doctor's place and then you
can use this so you have to really apply
for that okay so how do we grow the the
market of doctors how do we grow the
numbers of doctors and therefore also
the prescription so something that I
actually have um dived into uh for the
Cannabis Medical Market is the fact that
uh you know sometimes it's not patient
consumer driven but it's doctor doctors
driven right differently from the
recreational adult use market so how do
you engage doctors in to to learn how to
prescribe to believe in it and then it's
going to actually be become a job for
the doctor because I've actually studied
this uh uh there's going to be
follow-ups and you know time required by
by the doctor and therefore he obviously
wants to get paid and then there's
liabilities to that so the training the
the the payment you know the rewards for
the doctors and the Health Care System
you know when when patients can actually
take advantage of the Health Care system
or not so uh I studied this in a in a
few countries in Europe like Italy for
example is completely Pharma so and
there's actually a certain number of
pathologies that are accepted you know
by the Health Care System then it goes
region by region of course but also
depends doctor by doctor if it's
Specialist or not a special generalist
or uh uh in a hospital so I would like
to know uh as a you know how how do you
how can patients you know get their
cannabis covered and how our clinics you
know uh benefiting from such a thing
yeah so what you're talking is a
reimbursement part uh which is still
difficult in Germany because it's still
a last line therapy in terms of
reimbursement we got to differentiate
between the narcotic and the
reimbursement part so cannabis can be
prescribed to anyone right now on a
script as as Thomas said um but you got
to pay it out of pocket if you want a
reimbursement it's a lengthy process you
got to prove that you have tried every
other therapy first and then even then
uh often um it's rejected because often
they say there's not enough evidence um
to really um do the reimbursement so I
think this doesn't change right now this
won't change very fast in the future
there are some things going on where
they try to EAS it uh for some medical
professionals um but it's a it's a
lengthy process and those patients who
want and need a reimbursement uh will
need to continue to fight for that but
with a with a price of 7 to 89 per gram
uh the self-pay don't really look for
reimbursement anymore they pay it out of
pocket voluntarily and never apply for
reimbursement so this is only a problem
for real people who really need medicine
and who really need the support of the
public health insurance and maybe just
adding some more color on how the market
looks like so in the past so let's say
last and the year before we were talking
about maybe 50% self payers 50% patients
under statu Health uh coverage now we
are probably rather talking about 60
maybe 70% self- payers so that's that's
one important impact to the market um
and we see that I mean each doctor could
prescribe cannabis I mean not dentists
not vets obviously but generally each
doctor we see I know 20 plus tele medine
providers right now that are also
offering their service um some very
bullish um and we see some especially
pain specialists that are really
focusing on cannabis as a therapy option
and because you ask how to like educate
them how to train them it's like for me
the the key topic right now is
destigmatization not a narcotic
prescription anymore it really sounds so
silly and so easy but that's like really
really a um key and door opener and then
second education and this means for
example interface to product uh
information systems and so on and
different companies have different
solutions but that those doctors really
have the chance to get transparency of
400 plus flowers in the market of I
don't know 200 150 extracts in the
market so it's getting complex there and
uh at the same same time um it's still a
quite patient driven Market especially
in the flowers market so we still have
the challenge as a company that we
cannot or very limited address patients
with marketing with information so we
always need to go to the doctor or the
pharmacist to somehow get the message
out in the market so is it going to
change anything about the marketing
advertising or at least education of the
patients with this uh the scheduling yes
before that was a criminal offense to
advertise for medical cannabis uh
paragraph 14 paragraph 5 of the narcotic
act and now it will be in the uh in in
another act but it will be only a fine
and not a criminal offense anymore so
you can do some more before so from a
business perspective you could kind of
assess what is the cost for a certain
activity but but still we are talking
about quite significant fines and
significant downsides but in the past it
was jail so I mean that was easy
decision well this is changing gradually
all over the world that's in many other
countries so that's very exciting last
question then I would like to open for
uh questions from the public from the
audience sorry uh um doin Domino's
effect or potential influence to the
rest of uh Europe what do you think in
each vertical or you know 100% this will
happen so I would even say that most
countries in Europe will be even more
bullish than Germany when it comes to
the legalization framework I would say
especially Czech Republic we we hear
more and more rumors that they will even
skip this medical part and just go all
in right from the beginning so let's see
but this was a very very big impact on
all the other countries for
sure ah there's any questions from the
[Applause]
audience check check there we go
questions questions who oh all right all
the way up there's a microphone right up
there so that my lazy ass doesn't have
to climb these stairs 16 times a day
there you go hi um my name is Trenton
Birch I come from South Africa um I'd
like to know what the panel's opinion is
on the future of outdoor cultivation um
because obviously at the moment the
farma industry is very much leading
medical cannabis but we all know that
cultivating outdoor under netting or
under tunnels or green door is uh vastly
different in terms of price do you think
there is a future for outdoor cannabis
for the medical industry from the likes
of Columbia and South Africa Etc thanks
so when once there will be recreational
Market here for sure right now in the
medical Market it's really hard to
achieve the micro values when you do
100% outdoor I'm I'm very honest to you
I visited now I think 150 growing
facilities in the Last 5 Years From
outdoor Greenhouse indoor whatever kind
of of quality and uh I have to really
admit that medical grade 100% outdoor
woo this is this is more than
challenging and if you have on the other
hands uh facilities who do the run
indoor producing decent quality to a
decent price not using radiation because
I would sense that there would be
radiation needed for for micro level
bringing down if you do 100% outdoor but
I don't know about this will be a hard
hard challenge for the medical
Market anyone else have a question
anyone closer to me
perhaps all right you've all been
thoroughly oh thank you so
much hi right guys um there's I'm
hearing a lot and I'm very interested in
the German Market actually I live here
and I help develop the business my
economic development agency of the
federal republic so right from the top
back when it was the commissioner for
foreign investment um to invest in
Germany Germany trade invest and I've
been hearing a lot from doctors about a
database that's coming out I'm not
really sure but they're going to be um
collecting it's supposed to be also
coming out do you guys know about the
status base while they're giving
practical experience how to other
doctors um about everything from
Parkinson to where where it can be used
sleep um what for whatever use this is
something that one of the pharmaceutical
groups in Germany is doing any anybody
know about that or not in particularly
because there are so many of these
projects and we as an industry we are
working very very closely together on
that when it comes to education show um
because there were so many doctors
already applying for cannabis The Last 5
Years which are very well known among
the doctor's circles so to say and we
try to make videos with them together
bringing this to educational platforms
sharing everything just to educate them
so I will be very very sure that there
will be some something like this in the
future very nearby I'll find out who but
um there is a German group working on
one of the pharmaceutical companies
right now is putting together a database
for and that will be shared all the
little qualitate circles that the German
doctors have they're they're getting
this information now so but if you it
depends really on what kind of data you
look at if you're looking really at I
mean what the German reimbursement
system when we come back to that point
Val is like phase three double blind
data uh and you won't have that from
what you described there too many
strains out that too many extracts as we
described to really get reliable medical
data which then can be used in terms of
what German doctors adere often to and
that's what we try to educate hey let's
talk about cannabis as such about TT and
the potency and then try out on how to
best um or try to find the best fit for
your patient in the end I I would like
to ask a question about that too I mean
I feel like it's a challenge because
cannabis is so different person to
person like one person
really likes OG Kush another person has
completely different effects maybe it
makes one person sleepy it keeps one
person awake how do you quantify that
how do you make it so
that I I don't even know I mean I think
in the long long run when it comes to a
data perspective um first thing that the
doctors will do will clustering diseases
and certain kind of extracts or flowers
or even turpine profiles and then you
can just put your strains which are
fitting into certain profiles into that
because even if you look at the data of
course there will be some exceptions for
that top to down as well but you can
definitely find something like okay this
strain is working for maybe 60% of the
patients for going to bed this strain is
working maybe 80% for the per or 30% you
never know and with this kind of data
you will make the the business not even
for us but for the doctors for everyone
in the industry much more easier when it
comes to this categorization because we
have to do that no no Pharmacy is
willing to to have 500 strains in their
vault and in their storage because it's
a logistical nightmare to be honest and
therefore we have to strip this down
into very very functional groups of yeah
diseases turpine canab Pro profiles and
then you go from there fantastic there's
a question up here thanks for the panel
you guys are doing a great job what role
does CBD and other minor cannabinoids
come to play in the medical Market uh in
Germany and then the second part of the
question is format uh other than fla
what other formats do you see
coming
online maybe I I kick it off here so
first of all if we are talking about the
medical cannibis Market we typically
mean THC content above
0.5% so I I would say this panel here
represents really not a the relevance of
any CBD product typical forms that we
have are flowers around 60% of the
market Revenue then another around maybe
20 25ish % is full spectrum extract and
the rest is like isolate which is mainly
dronabinol this means magistral
formulations and then there are like
very very limited finished products that
are available so I would say CBD is not
playing a relevant role as of now in the
medical market and when it comes to the
forms we are still very much at the
beginning yes but research is going on
onto that because um for examp example
in the US we have a recreational market
so we have more options to to test
products and we just find out that if
you for example do a certain kind of
timeline for single cannabinoids in a
pill or something like this working
after 1 hour after 3 hour after 5 hour
you can really steer for example the
sleeping process up to 8 hours totally
controlled and this is something we have
to learn but with the upcoming industry
in Europe the upcoming researches data
collections I think in the next years we
will have some good outcome for all of
us maybe I can add to that we saw um
companies trying to uh bring a CBD uh
sorry E-liquid wean on the market for
THC for patients but this is a very
complicated procedure so you need a c
you need a pre-market authorization you
need a c Mark approved by an expert
group and this is very hard to to
achieve or to get and compan is still
trying to do that so we'll still have to
wait for for that even for that small
simple
product so actually I have a question um
about the formulas you actually touched
into to something that I that I that I
like so you talked about the profile of
minoc cannabinoids thines formulas
pathologies um so uh now the EU
monograph if I'm not if I'm correct and
the German monograph does not
require the the the disclosing of minor
cannabinoids or terap is only THD in CBD
correct but you're actually going
further
so are you I mean uh are you when you
are you testing also for for the for the
other compon components of of the flower
the extract yes sure because we as an
industry we have to learn about our
products of course and how they work and
um yeah
cannabis is a little bit more
complicated because it's has such an
individual effect on the on the human
body and so for we have to learn that
but of course standardization of
products is one of our main goals and
therefore we have to do the research on
that so you said uh there there
shouldn't be too many types of genetics
otherwise everybody goes crazy or we
don't know how to follow have you chosen
your genetics how many my personal yeah
I mean for yes for 420 Pharma three uh I
I I selected by myself and of course we
have some more guys in the team but two
of those I selected personally were a
market hitter so what kind of
pathologist are you trying to
Target but you got to say that there's
really big demand for huge variation I
mean as you said it's a nightmare from a
supply chain perspective but you got to
see what the market wants so um there's
always quite some request to get new
product as well on the market what does
the market want so so maybe good
cannabis I hate to cutch you
actually out of time I apologize it was
I know it was just really getting good
but uh we're we are overtime let's hear
it again for the whole
panel Claudia kman Benedict Dr Goble and
Thomas shuton uh I'm sure if you want to
talk more they'll talk to you out there
this is the Berlin International
cannabis business conference 2024 we'd
like to thank the tomman group our title
sponsor we'd like to thank all of y'all
for coming out um don't forget there's a
big party tonight in the showroom and
you can get tickets for next year this
year probably and we're going to be in
slania at Lake bled for a science and
technology Forum in September