give a round of applause for this panel
and for yourselves for making it to the
last panel of the ICBC second one in
Berlin thank you very much all right our
next panel is going to go over
cultivation techniques very important
because without the farmers without the
cultivators the cannabis industry really
doesn't go anywhere so I'm going to
introduce the moderator if you follow
cannabis news online you've definitely
seen his byline and mini German and
English publications including writing
for sensi seeds for weed maps and
marijuana calm and for a little
publication called vise please give a
warm welcome for mica connote hello
hello everybody thank you for the warm
applause thank you for the warm welcome
and the panel today where our panel will
be will be dedicated to growing
techniques ever tightening regulations
and oversight related that related to
cultivation our panel of elite elite
industry scientists and growers will
discuss topics are ranging from
regenerative farming and breeding to
organic pesticides at microbiological
screening methods as they relate to more
stringent and evolving testing
requirements the ICBC invited foreign
five leading experts but I have to admit
due to unforeseeable circumstances we
are only four people today Tom could not
come to farmer Tom could not come and
say he lets his ISIL out to the audience
for the ICBC and sorry that he could not
come but still I think we have four
leading experts from the growing
industry who can give us a very unique
or very good insight into the legal
cannabis industry
in the USA and in Canada and I am proud
to introduce like people from Florida
from big companies people from the
grassroots movement people from our
grows from the science it's not it's
also not only about drawing it's also
about science and research about
cannabis drawing and I want to start
with Pete hello Pete
hi everyone thanks for having us today
Pete is a co-owner of route rx it's a
recreational marijuana dispensary with
six locations across the Rocky Mountains
in Colorado
Pete Briggs 30-plus years of growing
knowledge to his current profession from
his involvement in operating indoor and
outer cannabis grows across the country
for recreational and medical purposes he
has experience working with traditional
and alternative growing mediums and
running operations that use both natural
and artificial light in addition to the
growing side of the cannabis business
peak that Pete has deep depth
understanding of the retail aspect for
managing stores in Aspen and Vail
Colorado he brings the comfortable and
relaxed attitude to a high-pressure
industry and his his work welcoming
qualities make him an approachable
resource for all things about cannabis
and my first question Pete I'm in
Germany the regulations for growing in
medical cannabis do not allow to grow
medical cannabis in greenhouses or even
outdoor and according to Colorado
requirements can you fulfill the
standards for medical grade cannabis in
greenhouses or even outdoor and how can
you achieve that so we've been growing
in greenhouses now since 2014 and what
we have found is that in a high-tech
energy-efficient greenhouse which we now
have that these things are possible
we are regulated by several bodies in
Colorado we're regulated by the
marijuana Enforcement Division which
gives us licensing and sets fines and
fees as far as infractions of
rules in Colorado and were also
regulated by the Department of
Agriculture at a state level and were
also regulated by the Health and Safety
Department for Colorado and between
these three entities we have to adhere
to very high standards of microbial
[Music]
contamination microbial poison as far as
pesticides and those types of things and
because this is a foodstuff because
we're we're feeding people this and
people are inhaling this we're held to a
very high standard and I guess my point
being is that in the right greenhouse
environment we can achieve the same
level quality and the same standards
that you would in a warehouse in Germany
I guess we're not you folks are not able
to grow in greenhouses yet but I see
that as an evolution and at some point
in the next several years you're going
to have that opportunity in Colorado
right now because it is so competitive
there are so many growers in the market
it all gets down to cost and at some
point in time you're going to realize
that greenhouses and outdoor grows for
especially oils and extracts and that
type of thing are the only way that
you'll survive the market thank you very
much for the insight and I think I come
to : now : hello Colin Colin's
co-founder and co-inventor of the chief
growth officer and chief growth of
etcetra grow sentía he's completed his
studies in soil microbial by crow bio
triolic ecology sorry complicated work
for me
and as a research scientist of Colorado
University Colin published thousands of
peer-reviewed publications that were
focused on micro bio by micro bio
microbial mediated processes that
Nath's plant growth sorry that I have to
read that from from the document : left
his academic position at Colorado State
in the university in March 2015 and
launched Ross entia present he has a
young startup company in the AG tech
sector that develops microbe microbial
and solid it is that sustainably
increase plant yield across many crops
which in easy words is to say to say in
introverts you develop products to that
replace fertilizer and that we plays
fair of artificial fertilizing and
fertilizing in general and so my first
question is may ask you to explain that
in easy words you replace classic
fertilizers and organic nutrition and
may ask you to explain the basic
principle of it sure thanks everyone for
being here as a scientist at the
University focused on agricultural and
in soil health and microbial ecology in
general we know as scientists and we
know it's agriculture specialists that
it's critical deliver nutrients to
plants we know that's really a challenge
nutrient use efficiency in agriculture
systems as it is in can't in the
cannabis industry and we started
focusing on natural microbial
technologies that can maximize the
plant's ability to take up nutrients
maximizing nutrient use efficiency for
many nutrients so plants can naturally
maximize their health development
quality and yield so the goal of our
team we started at the University and
now we've bridged and we focus 100% on
the cannabis industry is bringing
natural microbial solutions to
cultivators so we can naturally enhance
plant quality and plant yield again
using natural processes which we think
it's important not only for cannabis but
for all agriculture segments ok thank
you and I'll come back later and to
board details now I want to introduce
Michael Michael is vice president of
conviron and he is the world leading
designer and supply of controlled
environments for
blood growth rooms in the plant research
and Adri biotech sectors and you have
installed thousands of facilities around
the world over the last last decades are
your company has installed a lot of
facility around the lis within the last
years and you are leading the expansion
into the cannabis sector of your company
so my first question to you is how do
the regulation for Germany regarding
standardization influence the design of
cannabis grow rooms in general great
thank you
first of all thanks everyone for hanging
around for this last session looking
forward to just a few more minutes with
you today one first lesson I learned is
have a longer introduction and use
bigger words in my intro so that I can
match some of these guys here what what
I wanted to just open up here with it
was the interesting aspect of the
regulations in Germany and their focus
on standardization and that that
recumbent very well because what were
the way we approach the world of growing
and growing cannabis is to provide
solutions that create environments that
really lead to standardize that comes of
plants and what we see is that the the
level of control is what really drives
the outcomes of plants so if you want
standardized results standardized
phenotypes the standardized chemical
outcomes or physical properties of the
plants you really need to zero in on
control and so that control comes from
two different aspects one is really the
brains behind the operation which means
the control system itself and also the
body of the grow system which is all the
electrical and mechanical components the
HVAC and irrigation and fertile and I
was trying to explain that to someone in
the in a situation like this a while ago
there's a professional athlete and that
athlete understood it when I said well
you need the brains that are sharp and
adaptive and
flexible and robust but you also need
the body with the muscles and the bones
that can be responsive to those controls
and so when you put together both the
brain and the body you have a system
then that will allow you to control the
growth so that you can end up with
standardized results which is really but
the German regulations are focused on
right now okay thank you very much
and Tim let me introduce you and because
you're also very involved in environment
control as well and so chair mr. Cyril
interpreter who with two successful
businesses that were handed over to
management to solely focus on changing
the way the plant the planet feeds it
grows itself so unless bio and Jeb is
focusing on patented D human IOT
solutions and other environmental
environmental technologies his goal is
making his company and Ameri
a world leading spa street a solution
provider for the cannabis industry and
as we talk in advance before we before
the panel your whole family is also
involved in the greenhouse business or
your whole family is very experienced in
the greenhouse business we have a
agriculture background and we're more
focusing on on cannabis industry now
exactly and so the cannabis you're also
experienced in other sectors so my first
question to you is what do you think the
biggest impact of tightening regulations
in this is in the industry or what you
think is the biggest impact of
tightening regulations in this industry
first of all thanks for having us here
on this panel today I think the the
tightening in regulations pushed growers
and consultants in Europe and in the
states to be more careful about energy
consumption and how they designed the
greenhouse especially water consumption
and electricity consumption it this is
now beginning to have a more of a
serious law which which needs to be
taken care of on a very high level so as
actually Michael said to standardize the
way you grow is really important that
you you use innovative ways and best
techniques to be able to achieve this
okay and when we're talking about
standardizing growing and my next
question is comes to Pete in Denver
after the regulation odor was a regular
source for trouble producer producer
said with authorities I remember that
there were a lot of reports in the
newspapers so we do not only talk about
the controlled environment we cone
between to also talk about a controlled
order neighborhood so is that also uh uh
how can you achieve that or is that as
as complicated to achieve as a
controlled environment to have the
controlled neighborhood the odor problem
that's a great question and so folks
that are working in urban areas and are
specifically have grows in urban areas
real challenge right because that
technology has just started and so what
we came up with and I'll make this a
pretty quick answer was we came up with
carbon filters and we basically designed
an implement of these carbon filters on
our own we could have gone to
manufactured carbon filters but it was
just cost prohibitive for us to do that
so we came up with designs of our own
accord and implemented those designs and
created a several carbon filter system
to go ahead and mitigate as much odor as
possible
can we get zero odor I don't know if
that's achievable with carbon I think
there is folks in the near future that
are going to come up with solutions for
odor but with carbon I don't know if
that's achievable and the other part of
that question I think is that it's about
community outreach too at the end of the
day if the
folks in your community see you as
somebody that's bad somebody that's
doing terrible things to the community
then there's almost a placebo effect of
what you're doing and and people will
say I smell cannabis they may not smell
cannabis but they'll say that they're
smelling cannabis because it's very easy
to go to a local official and say I
smell cannabis it's almost like I see a
communist so it has that effect on
people if you go out in the community
and you present yourself in a positive
manner if you embrace a community if you
have your local community as part of
your your labor solution not a challenge
but your labor solution then all of a
sudden they're spending money in the
community they're spending money that
they're making in your greenhouse or
your growth facility that long way and
that has very long legs as far as the
people seeing you in a positive light
and when people see you in a positive
light they're always willing to give you
a little bit more leeway so I would I
would say that it's a two-fold answer
there may ask you additional question
about this topic and I saw we in Germany
there were some reports about a guy
running around with a it looked like a
big big back in front of us in the face
and he was called the nozzle Sheriff is
that true is that existing in Denver
yeah the authority somebody with a with
the machine and face and he measures the
orders the existing so we do have that
in Denver we've got that actually up I
asked and also there was a greenhouse
having challenges with odor and ask them
or right outside of Aspen and there is a
machine that will actually on some
objective level and I use that it kind
of tongue-in-cheek measure the smell or
the organics in in the air but how
subjective is that okay
what is a wind blowing how hard is the
wind blowing did it rain the night
before is it not rained in five or six
days
so there's all kinds of elements to that
smell meter if you will being accurate
and again I would suggest you know doing
the best you can with mitigating the
smell itself and then also going out in
the community and being the best
neighbor you possibly can be and may I
add something people to this because if
other is a big problem in the facilities
especially in public places and Europe
we've been designing a lot of facilities
in the middle of the city in Zurich for
example in Switzerland and this is
actually a really big problem
so we dived into it a little bit and now
we have great research happening all
around the world actually there is
research on how to tap order we also use
HEPA and carbon filters they do work to
a certain extent and there is a bunch of
other natural ways of trapping order as
well order is a majek molecule and we
deal with water molecules in air so you
can also manipulate this as well so I
believe with companies like yours and
and others we're going to get to more
sufficient technologies regarding otter
trapping and I absolutely agree with
that and I would tell people that are
looking to get into the industry that
Ansel Ettore type of companies you know
there's an old saying and the the gold
mining business said it wasn't the guys
that were mining goal that made the
money it was the guy selling the picks
and shovels and I would suggest that
that is a great place for folks to get
involved is odor mitigation because
there is probably going to be some water
solutions as you alluded to there's
probably going to be some type of
ionization solutions out there in the
future so again this is an evolving
industry we are on the cutting edge of
the folks that are getting into it now
we're on the ground floor and there's
all kinds of opportunity out there
especially in places like odor
mitigation
ok thank you very much
and now my next question goes to Colin
Colin you're actually you're dedicated
your research to soil and I read some
within the last year's I read a lot of
publications and in sample retail in
some publications you can read that rock
wall or other hydroponic media are more
suitable for controlled environment what
you agree on that I'm not sure if I
agree or disagree I know that I visit
grows all over the US all through South
America all through Europe and I've
visited hundreds even thousands of
commercial grows and engage in the
industry 100% that's what I do I go
around and do discovery and learn and
try to figure out where there's value to
be made and bringing value to growers
commercial growers there's a lot of
commercial growers that are using
rockwool in Denver in you know
Washington state all over the world but
there's many many that aren't and
there's trade offs and I think you know
there's no one silver bullet solution in
agriculture there's no one silver bullet
solution in cannabis cultivation and
there's trade-offs with every decision
we make I think in some cases one can
feel that there is a more controlled
aspect to having a very inert substrate
or media like rock wool but I do think
that there are some trade-offs with
respect to interacting with the plant to
engaging the plants full phenotypic
potential and delivering to that plant
what it needs many growers and this is a
huge movement especially through the
Pacific Northwest
especially through South America and
more and more even in Europe people
understand growers understand that we
need to start reproducing soil function
and interactions with microbes and and
these effects really maximize the plant
phenotypic potential meaning not only do
we need in today's cannabis industry and
I'll speak of it generally in a global
level to maximize yield to bring value
to growers but quality comes up
everywhere we go now and yield although
it's very important quality has to
happen and you're gonna distinguish
yourself a tackle as a cultivator and
I've heard it from from growers and
consumers here in Germany through a
quality aspect
and so not only is you know these inputs
important but environments important and
energy is important all these things
that we are taught what we're talking
about on this panel are interacting to
maximize not only plant yield to bring
value to farmers but also plant quality
which is which is critical for
distinguishing yourself and in
maximizing the value of your product
thank you very much Michael Colin just
told us there are several ways to grow
cannabis on several mediums and you
build up dozens of facilities worldwide
and it's not only the medium that
differs how do the facilities differ
from each other you build up right I
think what we've seen as we travel
around the world and see different
facilities is the vast diversity of how
people approach designing their
facilities so they're looking at using
different technologies and different
design configurations so if we if we set
aside the green house side which is not
my area expect of expertise right now
but from an indoor growing facility
perspective what we see is vast
diversity in the lighting that is chosen
whether that's LED or HPS or other forms
of lighting we see people wanting to
have very distinct indoor environments
for the different stages of growth of
the plants so from clone to veg to
flowering to even drying and so want to
look at different solutions for how they
grow whether that's hydroponics
aeroponics in multiple tiers or just in
a single tier of plants and so we see
this wide range of diversity and all
these elements have to be anticipated in
the design of an indoor growing room and
so what we do is we see how these
elements come together and what we what
we really see six is we can create a
highly uniform environment so that all
the plants within that environment are
growing at the same rate and they're
maturing at the same time throughout the
room so whether it's the back corner or
the
of the room everything is maturing at
the same rate so you get that uniformity
not only of yield and and outcome but
also in the specific properties of the
plant and one of the ways that we see
that varying from room to room is how
different people handle airflow so we
look at how to direct air in different
directions to accommodate the different
growing systems that the grower is going
to choose in general we we tried we
strive for a very uniform and laminar
flow of air but often it's the way the
growing system is configured we have to
work around that as well so the
diversity of the growing techniques has
a big impact on how the rooms are
ultimately designed thank you very much
and let me just come to the next
question about growing rooms or how to
fill fulfill the standardization best
way Tim and what do you think what use
is for upcoming trends in the near
future regarding altima say out of my
automation and in the grow room there is
so much innovation happening in the in
in the world in the sector my expertise
is more airflow water usage and air
circulation actually like Michael
mentioned and how we can extract the
water that the plants are transpiring
and how we can reuse the energies inside
as in latent energy and it's it's also
as automated as automation it's now I'm
seeing that there are lots of automation
in benches there is automation in
everything now but IOT is a very
important part of the design I think
everything should collect data and you
should be able to see how well your
automation is working and the outcome
because doing the automation is
something but also
see the outcome positively it's so
important what you use for what
automation so I guess it's it's
something to do with with with idea of
the grower what what exactly they want
to achieve and then you can you can use
the automations regarding to the topic
statement when we first met today and
you had you told me a very interesting
detail I have never heard so much about
yet because I know that the humidity
humidity in the grow rooms is a big
problem and you found a way to suck out
the humidity out of the air and off yeah
so we patented kind of renew and yeah we
patented a way to basically discharge
latent energy usually the systems around
the world they convert latent energy
which is the secret energy inside the
grow chambers into sensible heat so
there's there is always an unwanted heat
inside so what we do is we don't
challenge this we just discharge it
outside with another medium we use which
is a liquid desiccant and this is this
is how we actually reduced operation
costs this is how we control total
humidity and temperature and this is how
we also recycle the water that we
capture inside the grow house and reuse
it in irrigation and of a clog nearly
closed system yes
very interesting thank you and my next
question goes to Pete a PPR also a shop
owner so how important is
standardization of the products for your
business and your customers from my shop
owners perspective a great question so
and I think we've kind of talked about
that in some of these environmental
control questions also so we are looking
to standardize all the time we are
looking to strive to that place where
every time we harvest a certain genetics
that we get the same results do we do
that every time well of course not
because everything changes almost on a
minute-to-minute basis air changes
humidity changes sunlight changes
artificial lighting changes co2 content
changes but to the best of our ability
as as much as we can with our
environmental controls with our
knowledge about growing cannabis that is
what we try to achieve where all of our
plants are growing as standard or as
close to being standard as possible
thank you very much and in that context
my next question goes to Michael Peters
told us about you may humanity in the
grow room and other critical climate
climate control and what are the the
critical design elements that must be
considered in any growing environment I
mean you designed the room so how do you
achieve that how what do you have to put
in any room right I think I left - the
answer to that question in the in the
last time I spoke so I won't repeat too
much other than of course lighting
temperature and humidity are the big
factors that need to be controlled in an
especially an indoor in any environment
of course but particularly in an indoor
environment but what I what I was wanted
to leverage that into is just following
on from Pete talking about hitting
standards in by controlling the
environment that whether it's greenhouse
or indoor one of the things that we see
especially from the in the experience in
Canada is and also in the States but
there is a lot of testing a lot of
hurdles that have that every product has
to go through and so it's not as though
there's no standardization requirements
but when as the industry becomes more
and more competitive
I think the growers are going to be
looking for more ways to standardize the
way they differentiate their product not
just passing the tests of safety and
health and making sure all the micro but
micro microbial accounts are where they
should be but also if you find a way to
different
your product from the perspective of
taste smell or experience then you want
to be able to dial that recipe into your
operation and so having that ability
whether it's your doing a green house
Rover or more particularly an indoor
grow you want to have that ability to
control the light the spectrum the
intensity to manage the humidity
properly and also to be able to control
all those other things like additive co2
and all your nutrients as well Thanks
and Colin you also know a lot about
setting after the the the the whole the
environment for the plants and there are
a lot of regulations where you where you
have your business so in how far do the
different regulations in different
states in different countries facilitate
or your business that's a pretty fun
topic and that makes my job pretty fun
as I go everywhere I go it's a new
puzzle to solve every state in the u.s.
has different regulatory pressure so to
speak if it's chemical or Crowe Beale
and it's really important for those
words to be able to to follow those I
think overall its standard there's
testing labs and and growers can can
follow that I think the the real
challenge with cultivation in general is
mitigating variability and what you want
to do and this is what's been talked
about more than anything else I think
while we're up here is consistency
repeatability and reducing variability
so you can dial in the same product time
and time again and if growers can do
that I think that's the biggest
challenge and we talk about you know you
can use a simple phenotype formula what
we're dealing with this precision
agriculture and everything should be
defined as precise as possible always
and that's a simple phenotype formula
maximizing our plant quality and yield
to the ideals that we want based on
dialing in our plant genetics over time
our environment and inputs over time and
that's critical but one thing that
people overlook pretty
bad in many cases is workflow and
turnover because people create
variability and there's a lot of costs
associated with workflow that's
underestimated and a lot of error and
variability that's introduced into
growing because of that and so not only
do we have to dial in all these
technical details in the infrastructure
and climate and repeatable inputs but we
have to have our SOPs in place and we
have to dial in how we're growing so
we're not wasting a lot of time and a
lot of money I've worked in some groves
that were very efficient that had three
growers have worked with other growers
that didn't seem very efficient that
we're about the same size that had 20
that's a huge cost and then that
variability and turnover is it's just
incredible and it creates a lot of error
with with respect to the prot the end
product over time there are any
regulation you prosper fun except that
it's legal I think we all prosper from
regulation it's important I think that
there's some regulation that the
challenge with regulations is the
regulator's aren't growers
they're typically just chemists they're
people that are following the rules and
are getting informed and sometimes
getting informed from people that aren't
that informed and so when you look at
some of these rules and regulations or
their generalities that that create a
lot of pressure and extra cost for
cultivators and I think it's important
at this stage because this plant this
crop is way more regulated than any
other food crop in the world however
it's consumed very differently than the
other food crop in the world and I
understand those pressures you talked to
the Health Department in Colorado for
example we're very concerned about
pesticide use there's a lot of pesticide
use and is regulated heavily the same
pesticides are used on a lot of food
crops that's not regulated heavily but
we aren't combusting potatoes when we
consume them we're combusting this plant
we're not extracting concentrating
potato extract where we are with this
plant and even non trace amounts of some
chemicals can concentrate into into
potentially toxic amounts and so this is
a very different beast and health and
regulators in general are treating it
very thoughtfully right now and so I
think it's important to work with
regulators and educate them to
understand where these thresholds of
true risk are versus education
opportunities to to mitigate that okay
thank you and that's quite interesting
because we don't have all that here in
Germany because we don't have production
you will we know but we don't have that
experience yet yeah and so my next
question goes to chap chap my family's
experience in agricultural or developing
and building up greenhouses so we did
not talk about feeding the plants yet
and I know that most people most
cannabis patients want to have a clean
product in how far does a clean product
and and biological organic growing fits
together with the controlled environment
is that possible to make a organic
product a hundred percent organic
product in a controlled environment the
word organic is actually it's a very
general word word I would say but it of
course it is possible we've been working
with grow owners that are shooting for
to be more organic to to use less water
to use no pesticides even to even
aquaponics is now very popular in Europe
regarding even cannabis IRA ponic
growing's you see so all of the mediums
do change with the type of growing
systems that people are trying to have
and achieve but regarding
standardization it's important what what
outcome comes from these facilities so I
think time is still needed to actually
see what's going on and I also think
that data collection is really important
regarding questions like this because
you need to prove as well
how you achieved it it's not just how
you did it but you need to be able to
show what what was your environmental
conditions how you actually got into
producing something more organic and
thanks and let's just go deeper into the
additional question how do you achieve
that how do you document that you make a
documentation about your your progress
and well we have a software that keeps
track of anything any electrical
equipment inside your facility so you
can go back a year back to any month to
any out to any day and then monitor a
single plant with it for example yeah
you can sync the plants with brief there
is there's many automations and many
systems where you can collect data from
it's up to how many sensors you have we
we usually use 35 sensors in a you know
one room and you can basically go to any
time of your girl facility and see what
your condition was was in and and prove
it to be honest so this is also
documentation is also a very very
important part of that is a planted it
is I hate it a rap but we're almost with
me hello hello I'm right here in the
front
hello I just want to live I'm hard to
notice have a very very last question
wait I saved this question until the end
and this'll slightly controversial
question and you have the most
experience from everybody here you are a
long time in the machine and thoughtful
legalization and like general question
to you is a little bit controversial but
how much regulation does cannabis need I
think it needs a lot at the end of the
day and the reason I say that is because
we want to embrace the public and we
want the public to be are our partners
in this without the public without the
guy that's your neighbor and the guy
that's across the street from you we
don't we don't succeed at this
at the end of the day we have to have
the general public say this is going to
be safe this is going to be something
that we can consume without being hurt
has to be something that is not going to
affect our children so if we embrace
standardization if we embrace regulation
that is our best way forward and I can't
stress that enough and from folks that
are going to be part of this industry it
really sets us apart it sets us apart on
so many different levels but more than
anything it makes us better at what we
do because the more regulations we have
the better we'll be at this thank you
very much thank you that was a nice
final about to say I need to have four
questions yeah we have maybe two or
three minutes we're gonna start here and
then we'll see we Conan I didn't hear
much detail about microbial or by
dynamic or alternatives to fertilizers
can you expand on that a bit
yeah and we're in brief and we can talk
more about it offline actually
microbials
are the quickest growing agriculture
segments within all industries because
we understand that microbes and
interacting microbes in soil and
substrates help maximize nutrient use
efficiency so it's critical we also know
Andy talked to a lot of growers
specifically for this industry it's
becoming very popular in the United
States I mean quickly I started my
company a couple years ago and now where
we just got product of the year in the
UK we're in over a hundred shops in the
u.s. we're in over a hundred couple
hundred shops in Europe and all through
South America because microbes have
expanded even two years ago I had to
educate everyone that's my job is
education and support like it was at the
universe is a PhD microbiologist it's
the same thing now but I'm focused on
the cannabis industry and educating
growers now it's important I think you
know plants in nature don't exist
without microbial interactions none
and so interacting and bringing those
microbial processes and interactions
back into precision agriculture I think
does a lot not only
maximize value as far as yield and
quality but to bring these interactions
that might not be present to the degree
that they need to be to maximize again
the plant's ability to express some of
these quality factors that we really see
if you add microbes into iGrow we see
the improved terpene profiles and
improved yields and so this quality
metric really goes up along with with
yield and so there's a lot of value that
we think that we can bring in general
across all agriculture segments by
incorporating microbes not replacing
fertilizers I don't think that's what
we're trying to do and I don't think
that's realistic in some soil
environments where there is a buildup of
nutrients you can actually really reduce
fertilizer inputs and replace them with
microbial solutions but in precision
agriculture you're never going to
displace completely fertilizer
applications you're going to complement
nutrients with microbe life with
microbial functionality hello my
questions for you as well I'm thinking
about using microorganisms for pest
control as well and especially since we
heard California has such great problems
with pesticides like killing one fungi
with an on the phone other fungi might
be a good idea are you searching for
that yeah we are we think that's a
really interesting solution because
there are offs from so many problems in
this industry in particular with with
chemical solutions and growers in
general are really limited to the
solutions they have to control pests and
Tesser a huge problem Russ it might
spider mites powdery mildew depending on
where you are fungal gnats there's a lot
of problems especially in mono crops and
controlled environments and if we don't
have the right solutions it's there's a
lot of value to control those and
controlling those natural is important
so we still have resources at Colorado
State University we have several 5000
square foot greenhouses in a 62 acre
farm that we grow cannabis on all to for
agricultural research purposes so we can
look for new solutions not only for a
new you know nutrient or bio stimulant
solutions but also for
control solutions so that's what you're
talking about bringing natural solutions
for four control aspects as well so we
absolutely think that's important and we
were doing that yeah one of the stigmas
are often attached to cannabis is it can
cause psychosis craziness madness I
watched a documentary blackfish what
happens when you take an orca out of its
wild natural environment for more we
take cannabis out of its natural
environment generations down the line do
you feel it could be a problem with
increased psychosis with the more cloned
chemically fed or yeah it's an unnatural
environment possibly create unnatural
plants how can I answer that I think
that that's possible I think that you
Jim genetically modify any crop that
that you can run into unexpected
outcomes and since cannabis and
especially active THC is psychotropic is
that a potential it absolutely is a
potential I would say great I think
that's it I think we're gonna leave it
right there let's hear for the panel
once again give yourselves a round of
applause for coming out that concludes
the second annual international cannabis
business conference right here in Berlin
you can still get tickets for Vancouver
which will be in June and then we are
going to be in Portland Oregon in
September so come to that as well thank
you very very much we really really
appreciate it on behalf of Alex Rogers
and everyone else at the International
cannabis business conference all feet is
a
you
[Music]
[Applause]
you