International cannabis business
conference 2024 Berlin brought to you by
the tomman group and various other
people we're good to be here we're going
to discuss developing effective medical
cannabis products which is always good
apparently the later part of the day is
the medical part of the day which is
good how are you D good to see you
fantastic how what youing no you can't
yes of
course to lead us uh the CEO and founder
of kinlock natural
LTD uh and also he's very good at
opening water bottles as you can see
very
dextrous that's fantastic and you carry
them all Wow Let's Hear It for Dwayne
[Applause]
Stewart down one more I got one for you
here we got a spot here
any all
right you're good everybody's good y
fantastic good afternoon Germany thanks
for having us here today congratulations
on your quasi legalization not
legalization it's going to be a bumpy
ride for you all um coming from Canada
we've watched the industry explode and
implode and come back a little bit so
we're here to talk a little bit today
about the foundation of a cannabis
really which I think is medical I think
that the medical products that we're
going to talk about today are a big part
of what is driven uh the history of the
you know prohibition of cannabis and the
reemergence over over the the years so
my name is Dwayne and uh we run a
company that does tping uh klock
Naturals and we also focus on medical
products through our Wellness brand and
in 2022 we won the world CBD awards for
the best CBD edible and we did that
because we wanted to put up our products
against the world and made sure they
were good and here at ICBC I'm excited
to announce uh that we've just completed
a landmark observational study with Zen
Trilla showcasing the difference between
our product CBD gummy with 50 Mig of CBD
in it versus a capsule with 50 Mig of
CBD in it and we found that we had over
300% more efficacy and over 500% more
efficacy with women and it's those kinds
of studies that have driven the interest
in this panel here today and we want to
talk a little bit about uh where we've
come from why we do it what what
everything's all about so to the panel
members take a moment and introduce
yourself uh and tell me what is the
thing that you go to Dem munch on when
you
consume when you consume when I ever
consumed I but in general I have a munch
on chocolate but that's that's that's a
known thing for they always say it's
something for women but in in your study
but there is a different the difference
between male and female you know that
sometimes Fades when especially with me
when it's about chocolate charling
you've been in the industry forever tell
us what you do at bedan sorry tell us
what you what you do at bedro can oh so
many things
um what we actually do is making
basically a raw pharmaceutical material
in very distinct five distinct
varieties that are genetically stable
that are chemically stable and that can
be used for uh that can be used to make
products out of it we don't do that
ourselves we cooperate with industry
Partners here in Europe and we have a
strict pharmaceutical focus on in that
crating again
so basically in in in that's what we do
and that's where we are coming from and
uh what we have been doing for now
almost 20 years in this way yeah and
when did you start at cannabis that's a
long time ago 32 years 32 years the real
Pioneer here want to make sure everybody
knows that Michael how are you today um
you what need did you first see in the
marketplace that inspired you to do what
you do uh so I I can't hold a candle to
that to uh 32 years um I've been in
cannabis for only about 6 years I was in
uh government senior government for a
long time before that and uh probably
should have used more cannabis than when
I was in there uh in there my um my
company remedes in Canada we make uh the
equivalent to an asthma inhaler and what
I saw was uh a need for a device that
was not only accurate but acted really
quickly um and it has purified THC or we
can customize the product in there and
and it it works really really well um
the challenge with it is is fitting that
Niche that we we saw of having something
that could work really quickly gold
standard being smoke and also um having
an accurate dosing which people want
awesome and what's your go-to
munchie sorry what's your go-to munchie
when you consume everybody's got to get
the munchies yeah um I kind of sleep
through those I think use the night fair
enough Kevin from abstract how are you
doing today great I saw the booth you
guys looked active smelled great one of
the smelling boo thank you all everybody
should
go so what role do you think technology
plays in differentiating uh product
offerings in such a competitive cannabis
Market yeah I got to I got to tip my hat
to Marcus he kind of did a a good bang
up job for me um but we uh we invested
heavily into analytics and that's what
Marcus was showing there he uh we were
able to invest in analytics it came out
to be like 100 to a thousand times more
powerful than your regular QC
instrumentation that you see in the
States today and that enables us to do
Discovery into the plant and that
enables us to see like 500 different
compounds in each sample and then when
we do that Discovery it enables us to
answer a lot of questions like what
happens when it sits on the Shelf what
makes cannabis gassy what makes it
exotic and when we answer those
questions we're able to create IP and by
extension enables us to be an R&amp;D
partner
and an innovation partner to our
customers and that enables us to in turn
make better
products and and do you find that tpin
are are playing a driving role um even
in um products that are meant to be
single
cannaboids well the Turpin is kind of
like a collo term right it's really you
know once you dig in there it's a lot
more than just tpes you got the thols
and the endals and the Esters and
everything else Under the Sun in there
and I think it's just a term to describe
the experience the flavor and Aroma of
cannabis you know what do you taste when
you are experiencing that product
awesome brender the end there how are
you excellent you know it's always going
to be at the uh tail end and wake
everybody up here how's everyone feeling
good there you go come
on brender you guys are a very research
focused um your your company produces a
CBD for inputs uh around the world um
tell us a little bit more about the
clinical trials that you do uh as a
prerequisite to product release is is
that an important part of the
development um I think you got to think
about the pathway of the product um is
it a prerequisite for all products
clinical trials no because you have uh a
pathway of of medical products that
don't need clinical trials but there are
limitations so uh if you're looking at
uh dosing levels and giving confidence
to Physicians you do need the clinical
backing and if you want to go through a
clinical prog program um you you do have
to have clinical background if you're
looking at acute pain versus chronic
pain uh faster onset versus slow set so
depending on the product form depending
on medical uh versus pharmaceutical drug
no so the medical pathway no you don't
need clinical uh trials for that but if
you want RS drugs if you want more
champions in the medical community GPS
pharmaceutical industry to get involved
then yes it is Paramount importantly to
have clinical backing and do you think
that observational studies um have a
place in that process they have carry
enough weight uh behind them for the
pharmaceutical and Medical Market versus
pure clinical Phase 1 phase two trials
if we want to if we want to attract the
pharmaceutical industry then we got to
do the full gamut and I think sometimes
within this industry I think uh there's
some myths and false assumptions that
just because it's u a natural
plant-based substance that Regulators
are going to take a bit of a break or
faster pathway um and and that's not
true because you know if you if you want
to follow the biotech and Pharma um
Pathways it's written in law and
Regulation and you have to do the full
full gamut to to get there go ahead yeah
I I want to jump in here I totally agree
with what you say the the the however I
do think cannabis is a very specific
product when and it's a natural plant
and everybody's talking about
cannabinoids as of cannabinoids as being
the main component and that needs to be
researched properly I know that doctors
and scientists are doing that quite a
lot I think however that the value lies
in the whole plant I think that the
value lies in standardization of a whole
plant have specific very specific
chemical varieties that you can actually
research and that is consistent for the
next time when the researcher come backs
and has to do other research but with
the same product so making that possible
and working towards products in the
pharmaceutical industry they have to
take one hoop
meaning they have to go off the single
compound Theory single Target single
compound Theory and they have to accept
a whole plant but a standardized whole
plant as a as a way to go I think if we
can achieve that then cannabis will will
get to the right place where it belongs
it's cannabis is not only THC if it was
that then products would already have
been long into the market but the
research should focus up whole plant
product to my mind
and add that that there's many Pathways
and and I agree cannaboid research and
isolating is just a pathway we've chosen
uh to get there and following what
Regulators want to see if you look at
the market authorization drugs it's all
from isolated products so but I agree
this is what needs to be done more
Innovation the more we study the whole
plant the more products will be out
there uh this is just the pathway that
we've chosen it's amazing watching the
Cannabis Pioneer fight the political
activist at the end there or may an
activist who you know youve got a lot of
polit politics in your background um and
it's interesting you know your comment
about if we want to attract Pharma well
do we I mean do we want to attract
patients and I think that's part of the
challenge
of if we look at the world of patients I
think currently if you see at a global
level it's about 10% of the doctors that
are willing to prescribe 90% is not yet
there and needs clinical research and I
agree we need to do clinical research on
every level but that 90% of people that
we cannot reach that can have that can
profit from Cannabis as a medicine that
is the 90% you have to reach through a
pharmaceutical approach and I couldn't
agree more uh to that than that it's
well let's talk about this a good segue
into safety um you know let's talk a
little bit about safety you know what
role does safety and quality control
play uh in the product development that
your company does and how do you support
safety and mic will start with you yeah
so a product like Irish Wayne um the the
QA and the QC on it's really it's built
like a drug product um we follow the
international I guidelines for how you'd
make a medical device like an inhaler um
so it's tested all the way through front
end back end so we make the product to
GMP criteria simply because it's it's
going to evolve that way um even though
in Canada the way the licensing works is
a little bit different globally it's
going to be a GMP product so it's going
to be a cannabis medicine this you know
we just had a great talk earlier on the
confusion of how every country country
sets up those own their own rules and
regulations um the closer we can get to
those standards those GMP standards it's
going to be easier for everybody to
understand the product and for it to
move around fa enough Kevin what do you
think yeah someone said something
earlier where when you enter the
industry or when the industry starts up
the barriers to entry are usually lower
and as it progresses and matures those
barriers get much higher and in
California you know QA and QC are huge
those things are starting to be adapted
especi they're already adapted by
majority of the Canadian LPS and the US
companies are catching up to that but
further on that you have the regulatory
packets that you have to be completely
ready for I'm sure you know all about
that and then also toxicology is a big
one that's getting a whole lot of
investment now and uh you know when you
start off in the industry you know ISO
might cut it but not anymore you have to
go to sqf 23 GMP and you have to go
through the whole gamut no brinder sure
I think safety is Paramount to give
consumers patients confidence that the
products they are consuming are safe and
reliable and the stigma still exists in
this industry as we all know and there's
industry hasn't helped itself where they
put products out there that has a lot of
band substance in it but the approach
we've taken uh to assist safety I think
it starts with your manufacturing as
been mentioned uh your toxicology and
also the safety profiles are two things
that were Paramount when we look at
novel Foods in Europe uh that they want
to see and one of the things that we
done as a company uh to your question
Dwayne was we provided our own data uh
when we uh did applications rather than
relying on third party data so all the
data in our submissions is is is from
our own um manufacturing our own
molecules to put that forward in our
facility and I think that is Paramount
if we want to build confidence uh
amongst consumers and patients uh uh and
attract more
people better can was first company that
became GMP licensed back in very early
2017 um I think the GMP should go to the
level of cultivation that's where it all
starts um actually the Dutch government
went with us in the beginning saying we
include cultivation the way you do it as
part of your GMP license later on they
said n difficult cannot be it should G
should be gcp anyway it's not possible
um however what we have been doing as a
company is we implemented GMP in our
gcp
manuals and made it gmcp as we call it
you're making up your own acronyms I
love it exactly perfect well know flow
scientific um you know our tpine company
we constantly are being asked to include
new molecules you know in different
formulations and you know we revert to
the best available safety data um and
provider don't provide them and then you
know we get complaints well your
product's more expensive we're like yeah
it's not being cut with questionable
products which we've seen from some uh
some some providers and it often it's
the effect of the marketplace especially
on the rec side or the adult use you
know trying to push the boundaries and
and gain market share and you know on
the medical side you know fortunately I
don't see that happening do you think
that wreck um pushes
medical the other way around I would say
that's that's and it's a bit of a shame
to me I would say that wreck is Rec
should be w
and medical should be medical and the
overlap between the two um it's a kind
of a little bit heartbreaking especially
when I'm I'm trying to convince doctors
I'm we as a company are trying to
convince doctors that you can use
cannabis the right way for patients and
then the doctor is pointing to the
medical world or to the recreational
world and say look what's what's
happening there and they are looking to
what is happening in Germany right now
there's there's some sort of a gray
overlap between medical and recreational
and doctors they they they shift away
from it you know they they don't want to
be they don't want to
be they want don't want to be there and
they want they want to don't want to be
mentioned that way so again I think it's
fair fair enough to say recreational
World create your own world I'm fine
with that you know no problem on that
side but don't mingle with the world of
patience to that regard you know there
is two big group that that has is in
need of cannabis for many ways don't
tell he Canada that I know
yeah I I think the medical and wreck are
very different like from my experience
in Canada when rck came in we had um
hundreds of thousands of patients with
medical documents and it plummeted and
and what we see is um when I used to be
involved in executive side in healthcare
until you convince the the person that
holds the pen that's writing the script
um you know you need to have the quality
to tie all this together between the QC
the QA the label we didn't talk about
the label like a on the medical side um
the label is so important because when a
doctor writes a script they don't
question the label they assume it's
right and and they they live in a world
where if if the cancer drug says X they
assume that's right and we need to get
to that standard on the medical side and
then the the clinical and observational
you asked a question on I think
observational work is so important and
and we have such a an interesting
opportunity because cannabis itself has
notice of compliance to use a a phma
term and it's in the industry in Canada
several places in the United States and
now coming into Europe we can do
observational work that you can't do
with an API in the drug side where you
have to go through quality safety firm
talks and everything so it'll come down
to how smart we can be in this room
about asking the right questions on the
observational work convincing the white
coats in our world this does work and I
think they're almost there um Rec is
going to create amazing opportunities
and amazing challenges at the same time
because our physicians will um Michael
will go across the street and just go
pick it out yourself I don't want to
carry the
liability um so it I think we're going
to learn a lot as we go rapidly through
this from decriminalizing and bringing
in this amazing oil that can help so
many people brid I didn't want to forget
to have you pitch your keynote tomorrow
what what are you going to be talking
about tomorrow morning uh tomorrow
morning we talking about advancing the
anoid scientific landscape what are the
challenges what's a course what are the
rewards uh what's on the horizon in
terms of innovation that's happening uh
within the industry and uh I've been
told by the organizers it's going to be
the highlight of the conference um so
it's a must attend 10: a.m. tomorrow uh
brought your own fluffers did you I was
just passing on information I've been
told Dwayne perfect speaking the truth
at the end of the panel there um Kevin
uh tpin are and flavors and Esters and
ethal as you pointed out are always
Making Waves uh in product development
in North America I'm certainly seeing
that in Canada as being one of the key
differentiators of how products are uh
made to appear different from their
competitive products what future Trends
do you foresee in cannabis product
design uh over the next few
years um well specifically in Germany
we'll see how like the medical Market
develops here I'm I'm specifically very
interested in seeing how that develops
and how the recreational Market develops
and if there is going to be a diverg
between the medical and the recreational
or if it's just going to like gray
together essentially into like people
releasing the same product in both
markets and that's what we see in
California and you know you see every
product Under the Sun is what it seems
like when you walk into a California
dispensary and I'm wondering if that's
the same thing that's going to happen
here in Germany and so that's you know
it's a lot of speculation in that
question yeah it seems in phase one that
we're not going to even see the ability
to sell or buy cannabis here Germany
phase that's going to be phase two or
pillar two as I've as I've heard this
weekend but in Canada you know we've
certainly Blended that you know your
comment Michael about it you can just go
across the street and pick it out
yourself the the challenge with that
process at least in Canada has been that
the Arbiter of what's available in wreck
um is individual people that are part of
the monopolies that actually control
distribution meaning the provincial
governments and and I hope that doesn't
happen here for Germany it be the main
thing I'd recommend they do not do um
but as far as the ability for medical to
access greater product selection that
are actually effective um I think
medical does a better job of that um
that we can have the opportunity to
produce products that that hit a very
specific outcome um you know whether
it's in in female Health uh whether it's
in relaxation stress or you know pain
control you know Charlie how do you how
do you think that's going to be unfolded
here in
Germany it's very difficult to predict
how things are going to look like what I
do know however is that if people want
to use cannabis for a specific purpose
in their
health um most of those people like to
stick to the brand or to the product
that they get I see a problem in
recreational type of production that uh
especially when it comes to flour or
flower product that it will be difficult
to maintain those products for a longer
time in the market because they will be
replaced by other types and other other
things and then it will be difficult for
that it will be difficult for that
specific group to find and to stick to a
product that is always there and
I of course when you start uh working
product into uh other products and and
it will be it might become a little bit
better um but again flour is still one
of the biggest products in the market
and is there to stay um even in Canada
with a with a wide selection of product
formats you know Edibles topicals uh you
know Vapes Etc canab flow is still you
know 70% of the market and then
pre-rolls are another you know 20% of
the market so you know there's 10 or 15%
of the market that's being used by
non-flower you know I'm I'm putting
pre-roll into that flower category um
you know and one of the things that
you've done over the years you know
Ching is if you've had to move your
business around to support regulatory
changes um you know how do regulations
affect where you operate very much
Regulatory Compliance is actually one of
the the first commitments we have in our
company um so we have been bound to the
Netherland for a long time we have been
in Canada when the rules were changing
in Canada we have been there for a bit
um but when we saw the mix of
recreational and medical arise again in
Canada things started to become diff
difficult for us let me put it that way
um in Europe we see a change now there
are more countries coming online with
regulatory friendly environments for
production and actually it's the reason
why we are moving to Denmark as we speak
um plants are moving this month so we
hope to be online in Denmark by the end
of this year um and to have more
regulatory Freedom so to speak uh we see
it's a patchwork in Europe still of
regulations and yeah we have to adapt to
those to that patwork kind of well right
now with Medical Market in in Germany
really being driven by that mag oh prep
I'm saying that right that that the the
pharmacy distribution um you know and
that really impacting the product
designs that we can put into the market
you know Michael how has that really
impacted your uh product Design Concepts
a product like ours will be a medical
device as I understand it in Germany so
it'll be treated like a drug um
countries in Europe uh Portugal United
Kingdom are a little bit different um
there's regulations around cannabis
medicine or integrated devices I I think
is it harmonizes do it'll it'll come
together and it'll be a GMP level
product so the to the comments that were
just made on the the quality assurance
and the label and and that's going to be
critical and then the regulatory aspect
of a product like ours it's going to be
highly regulated simply because it's a
device and then the quality of the API
that goes in um Germany's got a really H
great opportunity here from watching and
learning from Canada and United States
and I think the regulations um will
probably be great on the QA QC site
quality of the product will be great
it's going to be access to Market
Germany likes its rules well I I think
the quality of the product is going to
be very high we're going to see 60 70%
flour as it evolves and then there's
going to be other products come in did
you see the regulation on the screen
where the flower could only have 10% THC
was that an age gate thing or was that
meant to be across the board oh I I
don't know age okay all right phew cuz
27% cannabis in in Canada is like oh is
it that low um so I'm glad I don't think
that's going to happen here
so on the medical side as we develop
products for medical um how do you find
your motivation uh and the and the
reward and results of focusing on the
medical versus wreck how does that
impact your products and Bender may we
start with you on that yeah we we're
focused on the medical farma side and uh
you know don't do anything on the rec
side but we're Guided by the evidence
and the science so we we look at
cannaboids and see uh how they work in
the body how they work with the
receptors we we follow the science we uh
work with researchers around the world
currently we're in 30 clinical studies
globally that are utilizing our active
pharmaceutical ingredients so we're
we're Guided by the evidence we're
Guided by the science we're we're Guided
by what the researchers like the Welsh
paper say on on what these cannaboids
can do and we feel it's important to to
isolate them to study them and then
figure out how they work individually
and how they work in combination and
then put that through uh clinical
research we developing new chemical
entities also uh doing our research but
uh we're driven by the science we're
driven by the data uh terms of our
approach yeah couldn't agree more driven
by science we just opened up our own
Clinical Research Unit in the
Netherlands uh getting to a level of
scientific results uh that we are aiming
for with our own products with our own
flour basically um and getting those
results uh out there getting uh the uh
basically getting the the thumbs up from
um from the medical world on the way we
approach it is for us very rewarding
yet um I I um in addition to the science
part of it I've learned so much from the
sales data on the medical side um I got
into this thinking kind of naively that
an inhaler like we were making would be
great for people that are naive to
cannabis and what the sales data is
showing us in Canada is people that
smoke a lot of a can cannabis are
picking up an inhaler and they're doing
it because of anti-smoking laws that are
everywhere so you know most most people
that consume medical cannabis globally
are smoking it because that's the
primary format that we've had um for
years and years so I I think as it
evolves it's going to be a very
interesting product to see how people
evolve and continue to smoke because
that's the way they've taken it we know
in medical systems when you ask a
patient to stop smoking they don't and
that I'm not trying to shame anybody
about that it's the way they consume
their medicine and we're going to see
better products come along to help them
um keep their THC levels appropriate um
and and manage their their
indication you know Kevin do you find
that your consumer your your P your uh
clients are coming to you with
consumer-based demand like are you
seeing that uh uh the demand for product
development come from the the level of
the
consumer um yes more or less uh it was
interesting how you said how you're
following the science and it's very
objective whereas when we're developing
products for uh consumer Focus right
we're developing it for our clients or
is doing it for the consumer um our
science is a bit squishier as you know
it depends on the consumer's experience
and my experience of cherries is morally
different than your experience of
cherries and so when we analyze
something we you know we analyze it to
the nth degree all as many compounds we
possibly can and then we take this huge
sensory panel of many people to say like
how does that smell and taste to you
what does that experience to you and
then trying to combine these databases
together to create this robot that can
predict how something might be later and
we're using that to develop these
products at a larger scale for more
people essentially to make more custom
products for these consumers in the
marketplace you we certainly experienced
a klock wellness um consumers coming to
us you know and expressing Joy with a
given product and that really helps us
you know direct you know where we're
going to go next and certainly the sales
data is a big indicator of that we've
had products that have failed you know
products that were we think they're
great um but you know the consumer like
me you know in in a busy Marketplace me
doesn't cut it you know it's got to be
spectacular one way or the other can I
can I just quickly add to you on on that
thing I think uh think about products
too you got to think about Innovation
too uh in terms of uh uh Advanced thy
systems finished dosage forms how we
enhancing biovailability
solubility the stability uh on this
product and viability is a key one so I
think that is going to be key too and I
think targeted Delivery Systems is also
going to be key too uh as we move so
innovation's also going to push too in
terms of developing
products I think it's time for
questions for questions
[Music]
already's who has a
question okay there's one right there I
was going to say you were wrong it is
clearly not time for questions and yet
you were right was watching the clock
man I'm doing my job you're doing a good
job
hello uh we come from Morocco and we are
new to the medical uh legalization of uh
cannabis and what we see is this U uh
the medical position is to go to the
molecule while the world is looking for
the flour and we just don't understand
this schizophrenia between the consumer
that came to cannabis and heard about
cannabis and 1,000 year of reputation
and medicine is coming to it because of
the flour and now we are breaking it to
molecules and we just don't know how to
navigate to this because we are going to
extraction and the further we go into
extraction and the further we go from
the origin and we don't know whether
it's the molecule or it's the full
spectrum that is needed and in that case
if it's the full spectrum why an oil
full spectrum wouldn't be a medicine and
why a flower wouldn't be a medicine and
since we are
investing every day we get uh it's
getting foggier and F years so welcome
to cannabis the more we study the less
we understand is that welcome to
cannabis or is that welcome to like
corporate science welcome to the
regulator regulation of Canabis if I may
um what actually happened to cannabis in
general people found out that cannabis
has its medical value
and then all of a sudden we have to push
it into a system that we call
medicines and people don't understand
it
and we had lots of discussions in our
company as well where we actually say
the horse has always been behind the
cart you need to do your research first
before you bring a pharmaceutical
product to the market and guess what
cannabis is there for 60 70 80 hundred
years thousands years already in a
market where it's basically a
traditional medicine to that regard
however there's a very important thing
to cannabis because
cannabis is not cannabis always the same
you have those different products with
different molecules and then we're com
to the Turpin to the cannabinoids to
everything together there so the option
of picking out one molecule is for a
doctor and a pharmacist the most ideal
option it's the for them the best way to
work however history has shown that
whole plant for in many cases works
better but not this specific whole plant
but that whole plant so what makes that
difference this is where standardization
the chemical standardization of your
plan matter comes in I'm starting to
lecture now but I will leave it to but I
understand your question but there's
basically no real answer to it other
than look into history what happened
there brender yeah and I think that it's
an ongoing debate and we hear this all
the time um and I think there are many
Pathways and I think there's no right
answer it's just uh you know if you want
a pharmaceutical drug out there there's
a pathway to establish so what you have
to do and isolate molecules and if you
look at the uh approved Market
authorized drugs it's all dealing with
uh molecules but if you want a medical
pathway that's there too and I don't
think there's a wrong answer it's just
where your focus is and the approach
that you want to take I think maybe some
of the challenge though is that we see
is that the the scientific approach or
the pharmaceutical approach tends to
overshadow because there's more money
you know what I mean so it tends to
overshadow and they try to push the
plant magic out of the way well this is
the the tension that built one of the
reasons we did the study that we just
released yesterday to answer your
question sir is that you we believe that
broad spectrum uh is critically
important and we believe there's a
larger market for non-thc products all
of our products actually don't contain a
any THC but they do have CBG and CBN and
CBC and and CBD and tpin and what we
were able to show was that a CBD
isolated molecule without the additional
plant components was not as effective it
still worked but it wasn't as effective
so I actually take a Counterpoint that I
I actually don't think the focus on the
molecule by itself is the right path as
I think you're trying to articulate um
but it is unfortunately a path that can
be understood and brinder I think would
agree with me that that if you want you
can understand a thing you can regulate
a thing better and therefore you can
make could go forward um but that isn't
necessarily
right question up here um thank you I
want to follow up on the on the earlier
questions and and your uh great panel um
in this question belief versus proof um
as cannabis puts itself as a traditional
medicine but also very modern medical
product what modern techniques are there
to solve your problem of proving out the
the efficacy uh that traditional medical
trials can't do and maybe more
complicated modern data analytics might
be so what techniques would you see in
the future the specific technique that
we use with a company called zentella I
encourage you to look them up is they
used an AI um based algorithm that was
analyzing EEG data so we actually put an
EEG on people's heads have them consume
the product and then compare the results
between uh their pre-consumption state
their postc consumption State and the
states they achieve between the two
products over two different sessions um
and so that's a good example of taking
new technology and it's non-invasive um
and that can be observed it can be done
fairly quickly it can be done with with
some economic viability uh and is a good
use of artificial intelligence and I
know we had a great AI chat just before
this but gentlemen what else are you
seeing done as far as modern techniques
to resolve that question I think we're
looking at the efficiency how you could
do clinical processes more efficient cuz
right now you're looking at uh a billion
dollars in 10 years uh to to to do a
full trial but you know how you can do
your inv Vivo and vitro and and and uh
look at some of those signals there if
you're not getting a thing cut your
losses and and move on some of the
innovative ways that you can you can do
that work with cro work working with
iqvia and how we can do these more
efficiently uh to to move ahead but I
think the key thing for us is that if
you're not getting the signals earlier
you got to go find a new Direction and
move on and then don't fog a dead horse
the other thing I've seen that I think
works well is a joint together you know
cooperatives that have an outcome that
that benefits everyone you know you're
seeing that a little bit with the novel
Foods groups you know the novel Foods
people are getting together to say you
want this data well let's all get the
data it's going to be the same data and
then get the regulator to try to approve
that but share the cost divided by 30
instead of divided by one um I mean
that's maybe not that Innovative an idea
but in a very highly competitive
environment I think it's
rare that's a good point more
questions feels like the show all right
we're on time thank you very much thank
you very much let's hear it
again well done