Innovation and
technology which is that's on
everybody's mind right now and it's very
exciting so we're going to get into it
and to lead us in this panel uh the
founder and managing director of spells
like business I was just on this podcast
a few weeks ago and it was fantastic
let's hear it for Tom
penett and all the rest of them come out
everybody come out right now
thanks you water i' like water
all right hi everyone welcome welcome to
Innovation and technology in the
Cannabis space uh yes uh Ango thank youo
thank you for the wonderful introduction
uh we've already had him on the show
I've also had a lovely conversation with
Yogen that's uh still not been published
yet but it will be uh yeah so I think
we'll start just with a brief
introduction from each of our panelists
I'll uh you know I'll start the show so
my name is Tom Pettit I'm the co-founder
of smells light business um we run a
marketing agency we started out with
copyrighting content creation so over
the last few years obviously AI has had
a little role uh in our company and I
think chat gbt For Better or For Worse
is you know a part of our workflow these
days and it's how you integrate these
different Technologies into your service
uh to provide obviously the best outcome
for
everyone uh yeah so I mean that's me and
a nutshell ygen yes thanks Tom yeah my
name is jgen ble from uh stalls and ble
we are producing the famous volcano
Weiser and the new 20 weizer and other
devices we are located here in Germany
in toling and we are doing this now
since uh 24 years so we have quite some
experience in the field and happy to be
here at
ICBC hi there guys thank you Tom I'm
yoges I'm the CEO of Buffalo extraction
systems we help automate the processing
and extraction uh Technologies for the
Cannabis and the hemp space other than
this we come with experience in the hub
spice and essential oil Industries uh
happy to be here thank you uh Chris
Senor uh originally from New York thank
you for having me as well um three wind
Corporation we're a global Vape
distributor
uh started in
2014 and uh we've been very fortunate to
be coupled with Cel and uh here we are
great hi uh Nick terab barelli with the
paxum group we're a manufacturer of
Automated Packaging Systems we have
facilities in uh Canada the us as well
as Europe so for for about the last
eight years we've been manufacturing uh
automated solutions for the Cannabis
industry with about 300 installations uh
globally
okay great so you know obviously we have
few guests across the the value chain
which is really good from uh extraction
to devices to uh post harvesting
harvesting on that note maybe we can
start with automation because I think
that's a big one in the space and
there's a lot of innovation going on
there and maybe Nick we could start with
you I mean how are you using automation
uh in paxum I was I was hoping I was
going to be the second or the third
question but perfect um so we I mean
being here in Europe it it's actually I
mean it's been fantastic we we received
uh a very large order a couple weeks ago
in in the Netherlands uh for a large
installation that we're going to be
installing in the next few months um for
us you know it's been a a a learning
experience understanding what's
important here for the European market
uh We've installed several hundred
systems throughout Canada and the US
over the last eight years predominantly
starting in whe filling pouch filling uh
jar filling as well as pre-roll
automation
um so you know everything begins with a
project or an application and and
typically we're following the lead of
our client base and understanding what
their needs are um how much product do
they need to produce what formats and uh
the nuances of uh child safety and um
their marketing per se great great and I
mean have you noticed so you said you
just started working with some clients
here in Europe I mean some of the trends
especially when it comes to Automation
in the US I mean and also Canada have
you noticed some of that also over in
Europe or do you think we're you know
there different problems that you need
to address I think uh we are far more
similar than we are different um you
know really the delivery process of the
product whether it's a pre-roll a pouch
or a jar is incredibly similar in fact
there was a lot of booths here at the
show selling packaging and um uh you
know it's essentially the same which
makes it I I think uh the transition
much easier for an automation company
like ourselves so I think you know
really when you're starting with the
client everyone has the same uh concern
and the same needs in in Automation in
the Cannabis space um reduction of
giveaway accuracy is of the highest
importance uh how do you maintain your
margin how do you keep your margin not
give away your margin um but moving into
you know the actual styles of packaging
very very similar um and then again what
a focus of uh serialization and child
safety okay great any other question
maybe on to you cuz I know I mean
extraction has moved you know Leaps and
Bounds in in recent years and I think
you know we could probably have a whole
panel discussion just on extraction
alone but still sticking to automation I
mean how have you managed to to
integrate automation into your
extraction system so um when we look at
Automation in general I'll take a step
back here and see if you could divide it
into automation Technologies for the
extraction and processing space so this
is from C to sale when say you cultivate
a product you're growing you have the
traceability of uh the seed and the
genetics Etc from there on to uh Pick
and Pack solutions for using robots to
separate out the flower that goes into
say convection heating or cold Heating
and then gets Mill into the product
based on the client requirement uh or
goes into extraction per se and then the
use of uh new technologies like butane
that are come around the block and old
technologies that like CO2 extraction
that have been around in the other Hubb
and spice space that are being utilized
in cannabis so um that's it's been used
we've been tying up uh there's a lot of
use of uh machine learning and
artificial intelligence where there has
been use of Scara systems and recipe
Management systems that uh not only
improve patient safety better
traceability and also uh reduce uh the
waste so it's essential for Waste
Management where all of this data is
being logged and you can reduce the
waste of particular Harvest and then
reuse them and then that's a whole new
industry of what's coming out of uh the
recreational medicinal and the
neutraceutical space and cannabis so
throughout the whole space and then in
the end as Nick mentioned is use of
robots it's robots technology for
packaging Solutions Etc so automation is
not just being used from on the
extraction space but the whole value
chain has been using Automation in
different faces and the data is
essential there to be used using
blockchain or AI so that um the data is
uninterrupted not U maintained across
the board and increases safety and uh
better waste management so okay wow
there in a nutshell there so basic yes
I'd like to jump in also on automation I
know where the Vape industry has come
from back in
20024 um where everything was manually
made now automation is now a standard
for sees cell in now we're in Indonesia
with 100% Automation and it's really
been incredible to see the lack of
failures you know uh getting to the
point where the cartridge is so dialed
in um for the end user the lack of
failures and the uh reliability has
really come tenfold from where it was 10
years ago streamline the whole process
absolutely yeah yeah y I don't know if
you have anything to add on on that
front Yeah in our case automation um is
mainly happening of course in on
production facility and of course we
several steps like uh welding soldiering
fully automatized stock system is fully
automatized so of course you rely on a
lot of automatized uh processes to be
able to really have a high quality uh
output yeah that makes s that makes
sense I mean all right let's stick with
you jogen so I mean I know that you know
and also Chris especially you're
leveraging a lot of technology and you
know trying to enhance the Cannabis user
experience uh so I was just wondering
you know how do you actually you know
leverage technology and actually
integrate it into a device you know
without I guess mitigating uh or without
upsetting the sort of end user
experience yeah of course uh on the one
hand of course that the the the consumer
nowadays uh is expecting really a high
technology device and he wants also to
customize the device and at the same
time he wants to have a simple use of
the device yeah so so many times you
have device where you have like this in
our case the craft you have a one button
device you know and uh uh just a the
user uses one button hits up and when he
gets green he can can inhale and but at
the same time you need to have uh um
also uh personalization and this we are
realizing via an app you know where you
can personalize your experience yeah
depending on the on the device like with
the volcano you can even make your own
workflows you know certain temperature
for certain time and then you go up with
the temperature and you can many people
are experienc with their tpine profiles
and and doing things like that so the
the web app also allows you to uh uh uh
to get a statistic about your your usage
yeah you can also uh access a lot of
information and uh today we have for
example for for the V we have released
our first time um an over the a update
you know what you can can use we have
never done this so so far before you
know so over the a update is also uh
interesting technology where you have to
be a little bit careful that everything
works out if you roll it out for 10
thousands of people yeah but so we have
done it uh the first time and of course
then you can also add on uh uh
technology yeah in this regard so this
on the on the on the consumer side on
the on the usability side of the uh of
the devices and of course on the
construction of the devices also if you
look here to the vendan technology you
see um there's a flow meter a r uh
sophisticated flow meter built in where
we can really uh adjust uh the
temperature control uh to the draw of
the uh to draw strength of the consumer
you know and this gives uh then a really
extremely equal uh reparation because
extremely equal temperature and this uh
uh leads then to a to a very good taste
to a very good uh uh consumer uh uh
experience so I would say today
technology is all over the place you
know it's it's in your production it's
in your device it's in the device of the
consumer you know and it's it's
obviously complicated because of course
you have to have it uh let's say under
control it's the because yeah with every
device it's get getting more complicated
but yeah it's uh extremely important at
the same time there are so sophisticated
tools you can use today so it's really
great to be able to offer uh uh this
technology to the consumers no I mean
absolutely I mean I'll come to you Chris
I mean technology is great you know full
stop when it works when it doesn't
obviously it's a bit of a different
story you know and it does add levels of
complexity but obviously you're trying
to make it as simple as possible for the
end user right so Chris that was
actually great segue because for us it's
about building Brands right and when
you're building a brand like everyone in
this room when you're building your
brand and you have your oil and you
spent years perfecting your oil the
number one thing you want to do is you
want to put it in a quality device
that's going to deliver for your patient
and not only have the best experience
but be the safest as well so I think
that you know we at at three win and C
cell we've spent many years with our
technology and just driving to have the
perfect vaporizer for your for your oil
and uh we have a research lab in scel
Arizona and we actually spend even more
time on that um really dialing in your
oil to the perfect vaping experience
making sure that the resistance and the
ohms and every part of the device is
dialed into your oil because everyone's
oil is so different right um everyone
has the best oil right and and but we to
dial it into what is best about your oil
is what we we we strive for and we've
been extremely successful at that and
that's why I think that you know the Cur
Leafs and the true Leafs and the Cresco
and the largest brands in the world are
all sea Cale because we feel like they
know wow if we're going to put our name
on a on a device and we're going to sell
this device worldwide we have to have
that reliability and the trust factor in
that device because we're launching it
to millions of people actually I mean
how does it you know CU I can imagine to
make sure that you you know you provide
that good service and you're not ruining
anyone else's
brand pressure yeah pressure right and
like you know it's technology a lot of
R&amp;D must go into it I mean how does that
whole process look like you know how
much time and effort do you put into
something before you you know release it
out and feel feel that you can trust it
you know and I could speak for for Cel
and it's years you we start you know
when we have our calendar when we were
back in 2016 2017 we're all do doing uh
our things to 2025 at the time so it's
like a 10year schedule of how where we
feel like The Vaping industry is going
year after year and what's a new
innovation what's next you and for oil
like think about we went from distillate
to liquid live resin to rosin to liquid
diamonds so these are all different oils
with different consistencies and that we
have to build a device that really is
perfect within quite a short timeline
quite a short timeline as the industry
is changing incredibly you know from
country to country from state to state
with different regulations so it's a
challenge yeah to say the least say um
and Nick was also you know with paxum I
know you you're working across multiple
different verticals and and you know how
do you know which you know what will
work for the Cannabis industry and like
what new technology have you been able
to integrate sort of speed up your
process so I I think what's most
important you know when you're when you
start any application or any project
with uh a processor is sometimes less is
more and sometimes more is more right um
You need to understand their needs their
their their
production and and the Outlook of of
their future business so coming back to
you know Innovation uh things that we're
working on um like you had just
mentioned it's constantly evolving right
you need to uh read you need to do
research you need to hedge um and you
need to um at times take chances and try
to lead the market right so we've always
taken that approach um if we continue to
lead and invest in R&amp;D uh our
competition should always be trying to
chase us so right now you know a lot of
our investment has been in inspection uh
especially in pre-rolls um one of the
the I think the most interesting thing
about pre-rolls is I've never met two
people that could agree on what a good
joint is um that's Universal anywhere um
so we're starting to develop a lot of 3D
camera systems that will inspect uh
pre-rolls at at as much as 3,000
pre-rolls an hour um that could either
be hand fed or completely automated with
a pre-roll machine so we're focused on
um traceability a lot of uh printing on
bags it's incredible how much time um
and resources are spent putting labels
on your packaging so a lot of our
investment is um a real-time printing uh
direct uh connection to your Erp uh QR
printing as well traceability and then
inspection that's where we see the
future being um then on the packaging
side sure automation uh weighing filling
um and that's again coming back to
sometimes less is more and sometimes
more is more uh for us the way we look
at our relationships is that most of
these relationships last longer than
most marriages so you have to choose
well choose your partner really well um
uh because you're you're together um so
you have to start with a basis of trust
you don't want to oversell your solution
and then you also want to be able to
partner with a customer um with the
resources and the investment in human
capital training um turnover mitigation
so it's a whole you know encapsulation
of just different things but ultimately
it comes down to a partnership um and
choosing that partner well okay
yeah definitely agreed with Nick and
Chris and on the timing thing it takes a
lot of time and uh effort but how I see
technology and automation there's always
more upside than any downside to trying
technology over years and as a company
we've seen that in our systems for
instance a CO2 system where 15 years of
feedback loop has gone into it to
perfect it the way it is and we keep
investing it further
with hopes of saying heyy there's an
upside and the Cannabis industry of
jumping on it saying as it matures can
we be part of the the force of the
maturing industry and develop new
technologies that are um helping the
market grow so I think there's a lot of
timing effort and Partnerships that goes
into it important Partnerships I think
that's that's a a key key takeaway there
as well yeah and of course I think a few
of you sort of touched on data you know
and data is super important in this day
and age you can extrapolate so much data
but I feel like it can almost be
overwhelming you know and how do you
then use that data in the right manner I
mean how do you guys actually take your
data extrapolate it and actually
integrate it then into your company in a
you know productive
manner I feel like you're you have an
answer yogish no I mean the first thing
about data that there there's so much
out there yeah and there is no end to
slicing data further and trying to build
inferences which may make sense to your
business or product or may not at all
make sense and especially with the
Advent of um uh the buzzword as we speak
in every industry now artificial
intelligence machine learning but to
know their true nature and what data is
useful and what's not is very important
because many of times we've had
Consultants where you look at data in
ways where there is no positive impact
it's just an infinite Loop of an
analyzing and coming to no end so I
think I think key is to look at the data
that's relevant and then use the
existing Technologies for traceability
and for uh uh for safety and get those
automation points in place how it
applies to extraction processing is
we've had uh sensor data from time
pressure and recipes that are fed into
an automatic system and that's been most
useful in my
case nice um I don't know if anyone has
anything else to add there or I'll just
add that you know it's it's really
understanding what your client needs
sometimes you know there's too much data
and you don't need any of it I mean
ultimately at the end of the day you're
running a business right and uh one you
want to be in compliance two you or I
should say one you want to make money
two you want to be in compliance um and
and it's important to work with your
clients and understand and also coach
them uh sometimes you can just be
completely inundated with just too much
and it comes back to you know less is
more and sometimes more is more then and
then other companies you know they may
run their business um very analytically
and then others uh may have a different
approach so I think it's just purely
understanding your client base and being
able to offer offer Choice um and then
be able to take their Direction and lead
them down that path with always um the
understanding of of not overselling a
capability that you don't need because
that doesn't harness a long-term
relationship
no yeah and and just to maybe zoom out a
little bit you know and especially you
know Europe we are a little bit behind
what's going on in the US in the
Cannabis industry I say in the Cannabis
space I was wondering if you know there
are any technological Trends that's
happened over there that you can see
working really well over here in Europe
uh yeah just off the well if if I look
at like Canada yeah um or starting in
Canada we're we're Canadian based so we
had a nice Head Start about 8 years ago
when they had legalized I think the
biggest Trend that we see is uh price
compression right where the cost per
kilo was significantly higher uh same in
the United States and and it's forced
companies to have to be really uh
efficient um that they can't throw hand
labor at it you you just can't the
margins aren't there anymore I remember
early on in my career um it would be you
know overfill it it's all good we need a
gram go to 1.2 gram it's fine everyone
will be happy on on Instagram those days
are are over uh if you give away 20% of
your product every package you go out of
business um so what we've seen is is
that's changed and companies have to be
really aware that overnight the price of
this commodity can can fluctuate
tremendously right so you you you don't
want to be in a liquidity crisis um uh
because your overhead is just so high
and you have so much human labor so what
we've seen is companies are much more
Nimble um and um they're trying to
repurpose they're already you know they
valuable employees in more meaningful
roles and and we've seen that as being
almost the biggest Trend yeah we're
definitely from The Vape aspect as well
you're 100% correct the margins have
shrunk so much over the years so getting
into a new market like we're in right
now it's really going to be interesting
to see how that is diverted um but I
think that um in the US especially it's
it's not so much the race to the bottom
because you hate to always say that it's
the race to a amazing device that you
can rely on and if people can focus on
that I have to hedge that I'm in a great
device in order to carry my business
forward so although the margins are
shrinking everywhere around us I have
the reliability of a consistent vaping
experience for my
patience consistency consistency I I
would say maybe a difference also here
uh in Europe I would say is that uh
compliance uh is even more important
here in Europe than in the US in the US
it's not so much follow people are like
uh uh or our companies are always
responsible for them themselves and
there isn't so much uh from the state
side lot of Regulation only when it
comes to liability so that is you only
want to protect your liability but not
uh not much further here in Europe of
course uh compliance on the device side
especially is uh uh much more important
you know you need to have um any kind of
uh U Norms you need to follow you need
to to to have approvals you need to have
third party approvals you know this is
something what you what you need here in
in the market and um of course in our
case uh we are still the only one who
producing medical devices you know and
uh one point I want I wanted to touch
it's it's important we have here now a
new legal system that's great and we
have still the medical system um we we
don't have concentrates at the moment
yeah we we we need we will see if it
comes over time hopefully yeah but at
the moment we are relying on dry flower
also on the medical side we are reing on
dry flower and the dry flower you
purchase uh in the pharmacy at the
moment you cannot do anything with it as
a patient you need to transform it into
the roller joint or you need to make a
cookie or you can use a vaporizer what
is the only validated uh method
available and so that is very important
uh to have uh uh these kinds of
compliance these kind for appr approvals
and certifications and if it is not a
medical device you can also go go to UL
8139 a great nor for vaporizers you know
but where you can certifi uh your
devices but I think it is important here
in Europe that you show your customers
that you have some kind of third party
approval what shows the safety uh of
your device yeah now and of course like
you said it is a medically approved as
well which is really good and I think
it's a yeah yeah and and of course at
the end you you need a lot of Technology
when we have for technology to be able
to really uh have a medical device you
need for your traceability for your
whole production system you know you
need it for your clinical data you know
you need to show uh that that you have
really a clinical benefit that you have
a positive uh benefit to risk ratio yeah
you need it for your uh postmarket
surveillance to get your consumer data
bed so other client other uh are they
all satisfied do they understand
everything do understand cleaning uh uh
protocols do they understand how to use
it your manuals and all that so also
here on all levels uh uh you need uh
technology yeah well I think so
Technologies King I mean and you touched
on it and actually it's a really nice
segue to compliance and regulations
because obviously we live you know we
work in a very highly regulated uh
industry uh For Better or For Worse I
think for better but you know so
obviously that comes with its own set of
challenges uh and I was wondering if you
know and I think this can actually apply
to all of you um you know how what you
know how you actually address these
different regulations in different you
know States or countries and are you
using any digital tools uh in order to
help you know mitigate and control you
know understand that basically so uh for
us to work in Europe and we are an
American company to work in Europe
there's strict Norms around eug GMP good
manufacturing practices and that just
and and for flower it follows the who
gacp guidelines and it's electronically
available there's a a lot of tracking
that can be done on the user requirement
specification documents now so a lot of
automation has come in rooll for your
qualification of your equipment for
acceptance of your equipment the
coordination with the Auditors when they
come in to comply a facility if they are
say making pharmaceutical products so
very stringent Norms but I think they're
great because if a facility goes through
it and especially the kind of um
equipment high pressure equipment that
they're dealing with if you don't do
that you could be essentially dealing
with the high pressure a bomb there
which could blow up if you don't have
the right compliances in place so it's
it's been great how do we leverage
technology now it's everything can be
done electronically as opposed to old
days where you need physical pieces of
paper to do that and traceability has
become much easier uh with the Advent of
technology so it's been implemented it's
you cannot enter the pharmaceutical or
the API space without uh doing U GMP for
us as a equipment manufacturer okay yeah
like d mentioned that is that is the ke
obviously you have to be uh certified
and um the health of our patients is
something that we all have to be
cognizant of at all times you know to
have the healthiest device with the
least amount of heavy metals in the US U
Michigan is the top standard so across
the board in the US we just go by the
toughest standard possible yeah that
makes sense Nick I don't know if you
have anything to add there um from our
perspective you know it's really
important
to
research every new country or let's say
the US state but every new country that
you work in so for us we leverage uh we
have a manufacturing facility in uh in
Italy in SK we have Manufacturing in
Montreal as well as in uh Florida um so
here in in the in uh Europe we we very
much lean on our uh Italian engineering
force uh you know who are very
experienced in ug GMP uh CE uh in these
standards right and and no different for
when we work with our Canadian clients
in Canada um I think you know I mean we
we all live in a a Google world
everything is online um but you can't
plead ignorance you know you have to uh
take compliance seriously um it's
important and um and then again you know
working with your client base different
customers have different
expectations um different uh user
requirements uh but you need the
infrastructure the engineering
um know how to to be able to uh remain
in compliance so especially in this
industry pharmaceutical uh nutriceutical
to a certain extent um is the cost of
doing
business um I'd like to add to that and
especially with the Cannabis industry
being in a unique spot because we are
constantly intersecting with the food
and beverage industry with the Pharma
space with the uh with the neutral space
the topical space and the recreational
space so these Norms are in place
already but as as the industry grows
because of the taboo that cannabis held
before it became legal the Norms have
existed it's just about us picking them
up in each of our own companies and
being responsible enough to follow those
Norms so there's no adment of new Norms
here it's just that we pick up the right
ones when we enter a new country and GMP
authorities for the pharmaceutical space
have been kind enough that you would
have a different version of that in
South Africa versus Europe versus say
Morocco or or the us but at the end of
the day they're all the saying the same
thing
okay yeah maybe to add to this I think
it's important that also the Cannabis
sector is really compliant with with the
normal rules they are available and does
not go a direction to say okay because
it's cannabis we can make a workaround
or we can be less compliant or anything
like that I think this is uh is the
wrong the wrong approach many times it
happens it happens even to Regulators
that they're saying oh it's Canabis you
can use this device or you can use that
and even the regulator itself approaches
it differently and um so so like you see
in Australia in the moment with the we
band and they say okay we do some
medical devices with a with a two-page
uh uh uh approval there you just that's
not possible that I feel it's not
correct we must comply as as any other
industry also complies because only with
this approach we will get the acceptance
we need for a future positive
development and and more ease of access
for the consumers and patients no 100%
And I I would actually even like to add
something also when it comes to
marketing you have to be super careful
what you do and don't say you know it's
very easy to get red flagged and I think
in this day day and age of you know
cancel culture if you do one wrong thing
you can get into a lot of trouble just
by writing the wrong thing so I mean
also we use different digital tools to
ensure you know which territory what you
can and cannot say and I think that's
also very very important because you
know you talk about the software the
hardware but even when it comes to
branding you have to be really careful
you know you don't you don't uh say
something or do something wrong there
great I mean we only have a few minutes
so I was thinking maybe we could uh if
anyone has any questions from the floor
now would be a good
time yes of course anyone have
questions come
on really one question just a second
thank you
[Music]
for first of all thank you guys very
much my name is nesa and I wanted to uh
ask Chris a little more about the uh the
point about Michigan is a standard yes
because we talk a lot of these conver
ations about top down standards what are
the opportunities for a bottom up
approach for some of these kind of
successful submarkets to teach and
inform Regulators at a national
International level to help us move
forward together that's a great question
um so when we're doing our Innovation
and we're doing our technology and
making Vape devices you know everything
being uh food grade medical grade um we
just go by the top standard so as far as
the standards changing in the future I
would assume that they're going off to
the top stand standard uh to be more
compliant but the levels are so low um
that it's almost impossible to get too
much lower than where they are um but as
far as the bottom approach I'm not quite
understanding um what you're asking as
far as that goes as far as uh I mean is
yeah what I mean is if the if
the best example of a regulatory
standard comes from a a locality as
opposed to at a federal level could the
federal or International standards learn
from disclosure I'm from Michigan okay
AG could learn from that as
well yeah so I guess we can hope that
the Federal Regulation which will come
you know I think it's just a matter of
time before the US becomes federal legal
I think it it's on its way as you know
we now have 40 of the 50 states and uh
recreation's moving forward and and just
about every election there's new states
that come on board um so it's when
Federal Regulation comes in I think
they're going to have to go with the
higher standard of Michigan yeah
any other
questions no how are we doing for time
you have five
minutes wow okay how some closing
statements or maybe some favorite dance
songs um so I mean ask I know big buzz
word is AI um I know I think we have to
you know we have to address the elephant
in the room and and yogish I know that
you you sort of touched on it and I was
curious if Buffalo extractions if you
guys are have integrated AI at all into
your uh into your workflow yeah so we
we've got the data as part of our Scara
systems and recipe Management Systems as
I mentioned so for instance if there's a
particular cultivar or strain that's
been used at the seed level that could
be traced back uh to the final product
and uh the data could be used uh
artificial intelligence could be used
essentially here to fine-tune the
cultivar further when it's going into
genetics so it's it's it's Crossing its
ways with genetic engineering there is
it how is that data useful for the
genetics of that particular cultivar for
Waste Management as I mentioned and also
um if you can increase the efficacy of
the product using that data so this is
this is in the extraction space um not
sure about uh the the post-processing or
the packaging for instance in robotics
there is it also intersects with a lot
of Robotics is in how can we um say can
place Solutions is and how can we make
them faster can we make them more
efficient so I think the key words in
the Cannabis industry are efficacy
efficiency and safety where AI can be
leveraged essentially at every part of
the value chain okay interesting uh even
yeah in I would say AI or in general
what we talked about uh uh data and what
you get out of the data of course we are
trying to get uh the user data of course
if people sending the device back if
there's something happening or if we can
get access access through the through
the app and then we really know how the
how the person is using it how much is
drawing it and we can analyze this uh uh
this data uh help with with AI and then
trying to really to see also on the
regional level of course we we sold uh
over 1 million devices in more than 100
countries in the last years so so of
course we have a global presence you can
really say it's a global presence and of
course on the one side uh cannabis is
everywhere the same on the on on the
globe when uh I me the most humans are
the same all similar to but it's really
very interesting how people are using it
and what can you get out of the data
what you may not seen by yourself where
you need maybe an AI and what do you
need okay and what you can then include
in your future development
projects okay interesting uh don't know
if you guys have anything to add if
you're using um I think Nick you just
did a course right on AI oh well I mean
on the Machinery side a lot of our
investment now is um you know machines
that I mean of course self-learning um
optimization but being able to
communicate with you about preventative
maintenance um you know wear and tear on
Parts when you would require to replace
them um so that's really important um
and then yeah I was mentioning earlier
that I that we received our um our
license of Microsoft co-pilot so whoever
uh hasn't used it yet it's pretty
great fantastic let's just go to
lunch how about that cuz lunch is very
short today and so we'll take an extra
couple minutes let's hear once again for
our panel
fantastic and uh we'll be back here at 1
p.m. or 1300 hours depending on how you
do it so you got like 43 minutes eat
fast which is impossible this is Europe
take your time but'll be back at 1:00
all right we'll see you soon