all right oh good you can hear me well
thanks so much for having us I'm very
privileged to introduce this esteemed
panel of licensed distributors in
California with very diverse business
models and this group here is I think a
really solid representation of kind of
the diversity in our market here in
California but many of them also have
kind of a global vision a national
vision so I'm excited for them to get to
share that with you and on this panel
we'll really be talking about what makes
distribution work here in California and
I think that applies to most places
around the state um how we achieve kind
of an efficient market place and we'll
talk about the competitive and
collaborative landscape for cannabis
distribution so before we get into all
that love the opportunity to have you
all introduce yourselves and share a
little bit about your company good
afternoon my name is Chris Coulomb I'm
the CEO of Pacific Expeditors we are a
statewide distribution operation that
provides sales warehouse excuse me
warehousing and logistics all the way
from Oregon border to San Diego hello
Filippo recalled a and SVP of technology
and co-founder of Ryze logistics we do
third-party logistics for brands that
have their own sales team and then we
have a full service distribution branch
statewide
that also provides for our portfolio
brands that we have sales as a service
hello my name is Wesley Hein and I want
to say one thing this is without a doubt
the most comfortable panel chair I have
ever sat in and I'm glad I'm not at the
5 p.m. panel so I apologize for
slouching
I'm with mammoth distribution before I
get that and I warn Lauren I might do
this as I often answer the question not
that was asked but that I wish was asked
and I was at an earlier panel and they
said something which was if you've taken
the time energy and money to come to
this and you haven't reached out to your
Senators or your Congressman or your
elected officials
and ask them pleaded with them demanded
them to address whatever ills are faced
in your jurisdiction whether it's 280e
totally legality or whatever then you
have it backwards and that's something
that I implore you as I implore myself
to address right away and when you get
back start reaching out to those people
that's what we need as much as
distribution now for distribution
we're mammoth distribution we're a
pretty good-sized we have six licenses
one thing we do is a little different is
that instead of carrying a variety of
products we focus on just one which is
vape that's not to say that we don't
think the other categories are important
they are fun they really are it's just
with all of the changes and advocacy and
an education that is necessary in this
market of tumult we felt that we'd be
best served by just focusing on one
thing and trying to do that really well
and we carry five currently brands vape
brands all distinct our flagship brand
is called heavy hitters awesome
hey everyone my name is Michael
Steinmetz the CEO and one of the
founders of lo kana best way to describe
flow kana is we are a supply chain
company that focuses exclusively with
small farmers from the Emerald triangle
only Sun grown organic sustainable
products we have two big components to
our business one is an upstream
processing and manufacturing and then we
have a downstream distribution company
the distribution side we've got a hub in
San Diego two hubs in LA Sacramento in
the Bay Area
so about five hubs across the state and
on the upstream side of things we have a
couple aggregation hubs and kind of
densely populated areas where farmers
are we have one in southern Humboldt one
in northern Mendocino or opening a third
one in southern Mendocino as well and we
about two years ago but a the Fetzer
winery in Ukiah and we're turning it
into a centralized processing center to
provide all the services at scale for
the small farmers so they can cultivate
their product dried and cured on farm
estate cured and then we do everything
else the trimming the processing the
packaging
Manufacturing and then the downstream
distribution and that's awesome great
thank you
well let's kick off with a really kind
of open-ended first question which is
tell us tell us about the the
distribution landscape in California and
what that what that looks like and maybe
incorporate some of the ways in which
distributors work with one another and
work within the supply chain so let's
see my q would you mind picking us off
sure let's see it's really a challenging
time in California right there's about
as many distributors as there are
licensed retailers that's like a one to
one ratio
we're also emerging from a world where a
lot of distributors did or a lot of
brands because they didn't exist a
distribution network in the past have
built their own self distribution
components to their business so there's
a lot of us in the marketplace
I say it's a pretty amicable and
collaborative environment but I wish it
was more collaborative to be honest and
you know it's it's an interesting time
you know I think I think this year is
probably gonna bring about a lot of
consolidation in the industry both on
the brand side and the distribution side
it's gonna be a you know interesting to
see how it all kind of shakes out and
who the winners are that emerge but you
know as this industry matures and more
cultivation comes online the margins
compress and distribution is not a very
easy game right when you have to do it
in this regulatory landscape tons of
rules very high capex investments on the
real estate on the truck side so you
know I think what we're gonna see this
year is is you know unfortunately
probably some distributors you know
disappearing or joining forces with
other people because it's definitely not
enough room for the number of
distributors that exist today so that's
one of the things that we're working on
consciously is actually trying to come
together with a lot of distribution
companies and kind of protect the
California values and the california
brands that for so long I've been part
of this industry and finding ways to
work together more intimately well I
think it's difficult to talk about the
distribution environment in 2019 without
going back to 2017 because
notwithstanding the comment I say to
people all the time were like any other
distribution
company in any other industry in 2017 we
couldn't be like any other distribution
company because if we distribute it and
actually distributed that was called
trafficking that was very illegal so
instead what we did was we formed mutual
benefit corporations cooperatives
nonprofit we facilitated transaction
amongst members member patients of the
collective try putting that on your link
done I tried and and so we had this the
that was the downside the upside was we
had a couple of thousand potential
clients to sell to in terms of retailers
and dispensary and delivery services
then on one one 2018
boom that got cut by about 75% to just a
few hundred that type of tumult was very
difficult to navigate and as we reorient
it our business and reorder the brands
and so forth towards now this segment
started building those we got to July
1st the date all of us will remember
here the BCC told retailers ok as of
July 1 if we catch you with any
non-compliant inventory you're in
trouble
well hilarity ensued because 350 are so
licensed retailers each had a different
opinion as to what compliant inventory
was is that appropriate contrasting
color is that the lower third and so
forth and so navigating all of that and
then we almost had it again at the end
of the year with a heavy metal testing
where let's test all products for heavy
metal but let's only have a few labs
that are really up to the task
so these are the things that we dealt
with in 2018 now that we're getting to
2019 we've overcome those we now have
permanent regulations it's interesting
most people think permanent means
they're not going to change permanent in
this case means they're gonna change but
apparently a little bit more slowly
according to the BCC and that's a good
thing
so I think all of the things that that
my fellow distributor on the right said
is exactly right work we're gonna see
increased competition we're gonna see
the types of things that probably would
have expected last year but we were just
dealing with the tumult
if no other comments we can move on to
the next question which is related so
what are some of your big takeaways from
2018 really as it pertains to what makes
a winning partnership between producers
and distributors and/or retailers and
distributors so really thinking about it
from a perspective of what makes
partnerships work in this new
environment that we are all in in a new
new regulated environment with all those
changes that Westley outlined Felipe
would you like to start sure so we look
at partnership very much so that we are
in this lane of distribution and brands
can focus on their manufacturing or
their cultivation and so for us being
able to provide the services with a very
specific focus and being the most
efficient partner possible we're
flexible around the partnership so if
brands want to represent themselves
we're of the belief that nobody tells
their story better than themselves so we
allow the brands to go out and build
their sales teams and and wrap
themselves and and if they're ready to
share the story and allow us to go out
and represent them we've got sales as a
service and we'll build a team we really
get to know the brand we know what what
what drives them what their DNA is like
and and we're out on the field wearing
their gear day in and day out we have a
lot of pride in that so I think it's
just furthering Felipe's comments it's
also understanding that we have our own
very specific and respect to function
but at the same time we're all basically
standing there on the same team and so
what that means is we don't look at why
this person should be in a store and
this person should not be in a store
it's really making sure that whatever it
is that you put together as a plan is
very well defined and well executed I
think it's the main point is making sure
that everybody is relying on their core
competencies and that you
I will understand what those respective
core companies competencies are and that
also means we work together a lot so we
call each other we end up you know
working with different clients after SB
311 passed Thank You Lauren we've been
able to do distributor to distributor
transactions so it's opened up to some
of the like the local aggregators and
various regions of the state that are
further out to partner up source get
everything retail ready and then we do
the last mile delivery for them any
other big takeaways in terms of what
makes a winning partnership well we
could probably do the entire panel on
that but I think it's really
understanding and I'm building on what
Philippe it said it's mutual dependence
no matter how good a distributor is at
logistics it's out of business if it
doesn't have good products and it
doesn't make those products so brands
have a tremendous amount of leverage on
that that said if a brand has products
and it's not in a dispensary and does
not have a good footprint in those
dispensaries it's out of business so is
really looking for the areas where they
can work together and collaborate I
think the number one thing a distributor
should ask its brands is how can we do a
better job of representing your products
the number one thing the brands should
ask their distributors is what are you
hearing from dispensaries about our
products our packaging our messaging
that we can improve to make your job
easier great thank you
let's talk about what is a distributors
role in the supply chain beyond some of
the kind of logistical and functional
things that you've mentioned and kind of
around the idea of their role in terms
of creating demand is that a
distributors role to create demand or
does that fall more on the brand or is
it is it a shared effort if you could
speak to that
sure I mean I think to the point made
earlier there's there's different kinds
of relationships with the different
brands and different distributors have
different models I think you know
besides the logistics besides the sale
besides transportation warehousing that
the traditional functions you know we're
also you know this state's tax
collection agency I consider ourselves
also kind of an information hub we kind
of sit in the middle of cultivators
manufacturers retailers delivery
services we know all of those pain
points and we take it upon ourselves to
you know really help all the other
pieces of the supply chain on some of
the trade organizations that we sit on
the boards CCIA
and the others I think in general the
relationship with a distributor to
really build marketplace speaking about
ourselves we're not trying to be a large
catalogue distributor with thousands of
products we want to build an intimate
relationship with a select few of
curated you know category winning brands
and you know we try to find and
associate ourselves with brands that for
one can scale a lot of people are
struggling with scaling beyond the real
estate that they're in or with lack of
capital so we finally find the right
brands that have that ability to scale
and if they don't have in themselves we
love the brand or love the founding team
we try to help them with the capital we
try to help them with our real estate
footprint as well I think in terms of
developing the marketplace you know we
do have a very close relationship with
the brands where we actually help them
with a lot of the marketing activities
we run merchandising teams we ran brand
ambassador teams for them we have
specific campaigns that we do together
collaboratively with collaboratively
with them you know a distributors
success really depends entirely on the
brand right you're linked by the hip and
I think it's very important for that
relationship to be kind of win-win and
the distributors in our case that we are
building a lot of market share for the
brands we work with but we also leverage
a lot of their marketing campaigns that
they do I'm not sure if all the other
distributors are the same let's go say
aside from the tax collection we have
another huge responsibility is to make
sure that the products are safe for the
consumers so we're doing all of the
Quality Assurance making sure it's
labeled appropriately and in compliant
packaging
market other responsibilities and
functions that we have is to actually
give back the brands that we work with
analytics visibility to what's happening
in the marketplace so that they can make
the right decisions about what their an
excuse should be or how much inventory
to have on hand or what their the next
you know any demand based analytics that
could help them drive their businesses
success yeah one thing really worth
emphasizing is and we're very proud of
our distribution company but no at no
time ever in the history of the cannabis
industry has anybody ever walked into a
dispensary and said I would like a
mammoth distribution product what
mammoth distribution products do have I
understand their logistics is amazing
so we're there behind the scenes we know
we need to get it in we need to have the
footprint we need to educate but at the
end of the day it is the power of the
brand because you might be able to get
somebody to try something once and often
we're not able to get something in a
dispensary without the bud tenders and
the managers and the buyers trying it go
and you know what I like this and I
think other people will like it and you
can get people potentially to try
something once but if they don't come
back and ask for it then you're not
going to be able to keep it in that
dispensary and then it's gonna be very
hard to get it into other dispensaries
so it was going to go back as first and
foremost just have a great product it
has to be compliant because otherwise it
doesn't even get in retailers have
gotten very good and being very
discerning to the point of being kind of
crazy in some cases but to make sure
that they feel that it's past every
single aspect of what they consider
compliant I would just echo whatever's
what everyone else has said it's
effectively being a leveraging platform
or an enabling platform I should say so
one of the things that PACs did is we
sponsored a large consumption event and
we paid for every one of our brands to
come down or every single one of our
brands to come down and sit in front of
the consumers so we sponsored the
Emerald cup and we paid for all of our
all 21 brands that we represent to sit
there we covered the expense of that
event so that they could be there in
front of all of their consumers and get
that real-time feedback
to understand what the market really is
what the consumers are looking for the
dialog between the consumers and the
retailers and being able to do that I
think in various ways across platforms
across the state it's really that's what
we do as distributors beyond all of the
other technicalities that we have to do
it's really being a leveraging platform
great so so what advice do you have for
brands in terms of getting them ready
for distribution so I'm sure you you
know brands reach out our producers
reach out and they are looking for a
distributor and they may or may not be a
right fit for you based on whatever
criteria you have so what would you tell
brands that you look for and that you
expect before they're really ready for a
distribution partner I think I guess the
first advice would be make sure you like
your distribution partner you know at
the end of the day companies are built
with people and you got to make sure you
get along well with that organization
and your kind of value aligned and
mission the line and kind of what you're
trying to achieve you know one thing we
know for certain in this industry it's
that even though we're in this permanent
regulation phase it's gonna change and
change and change and change you're
gonna have problem after problem after
hiccup after hiccup and you have to work
through those you know we've had a lot
of challenges with packaging and
labeling and different changes and
different perspective from different
dispensaries and working through those
and I think is one of the most important
things you can do I think from a
distributor perspective picking the
right one that has this scale to really
serve you know the entire state or
specific regions if you want to divvy it
up with different people making sure
they have the right amount of capital to
continue to grow distribution is a super
capital intensive game and especially to
do it at scale at the pace that
California needs it so I think ensuring
that the distributor that you choose is
gonna be around for the long term and
you know you're working with people that
you kind of want to work with on a day
to day basis so you know two simple
rules and do your homework distributors
are different and so if you're going to
a distributor and their emphasis upon
the medicinal and yours is on the party
it might not be a good fit make sure if
you're bringing a product to them that
your packaging is compliant because if
you come in and it's got all sorts of
medical claims and so forth they're
gonna think this is going to be a lot
more work working with these people make
sure your product has been tested before
and coming in because the one thing
about distributors the distribution
model generally as a number is a sort of
a game of a lot of numbers you carry a
number of brands a number of different
SKUs that means you're dealing with a
lot of different people and competing
interests and if one tries to be the
tall blade and dominate the time it
really can make it difficult for
everything else so I think what he says
is exactly right never underestimate the
people concept somebody might like your
product but as you're leaving they're
sitting there thinking I don't want to
have to deal with this guy or this gal
that's not going to serve you well I
would recommend having a business plan a
lot of people slap a label on a package
and say this is my brand so actually you
know have some forecasting figure out
how much inventory have projections of
what you'd like to sell when you get out
to market and that will help all of us
second the packaging because the
majority of packaging that comes through
shows up the first revision they've
already ordered tons of it and we're
looking at it and it's all wrong so hire
an attorney have them look at the
packaging or get a compliance person and
then come talk to a distributor make
sure that they approve your packaging
and then the big final thing that I
would say if you want to go to market is
read the regulations or at least have
somebody that read them because a lot of
companies have not read them and we
spend a lot of time educating the
companies or the brands to work with
them yeah I would agree with what
everyone has said the other component
would be really think about what you're
getting ready to do if you are launching
a brand that's not just a brand you need
to create a message you need to create a
vision you need to communicate that out
to the market and again going back to
the enabling platform you create
marketing plans for your products you
pull your distributor into that
particularly when you're receiving some
sort of sales service from them
what we noticed on the front end when we
brought on a lot of the small legacy
farmers the small batch farmers is that
we were investing somewhere between
twenty and forty thousand dollars per
brand that we brought on just trying to
build momentum for them in the
marketplace and that takes time and
that's another thing that needs to be
understood from people you know from
brands or from entities that are trying
to create brands in the market is that
this is a heavily congested space
everybody is here attempting to sell
cannabis and you need to not only have
these differentiators and so on but you
also need to have a message that will
resonate and you have to understand that
for something to resonate it takes time
X amount of impressions for the someone
to recall that's a process so you expect
to show up to a distributor on say a
Friday and they're gonna pick up your
inventory don't expect sales on Monday
it's I mean it and that happens a lot
you know hey you guys have had my
product for three days now what's what's
going on you know what's the market
what's going you know what's the market
intelligence where's my money where's my
money yeah it's at the state the the big
thing is making sure that there's a plan
going back to some of the earlier
comments that were made you've got to
really show up with a plan you have to
understand that this is a team it's it
is a huge team of effort it is a huge
team event if you're gonna have a
marketing plan communicate that to your
distributor because they can show up and
they can be the sales team that backs up
whatever collateral media that you're
putting out there this is all
coordinated efforts and that's one of
the things that distributors have to do
we do the education we do the review we
do the compliance check we do logistics
we do hand-holding we do everything to
get something to market the best way to
see a distributor is a synthesizer and
we have to take chaos and we have to
turn it into something palatable and
adjustable on the retail side and it's
it's a process and understand that it's
something that needs to be worked
through yeah there's so many different
ways to go about this and there's only a
handful of them that are correct so so
you've all alluded to various stuff
services and value propositions that
these different business models have and
may offer there's certainly a selection
of different services depending on the
distributor a brand might go and work
with so how do we place a value on those
services as a whole or individually I
know some business models are kind of
ala carte you know and you can leverage
certain aspects of what a distributor
has to offer and others are more
comprehensive in terms of a flat rate
for kind of the whole package and so you
know I've heard rates anywhere from five
to ten percent when you're talking about
just straight transportation you know 10
to 20 percent if it's a combination of
transport and warehousing logistics and
as high as 20 25 30 percent for that
full-service warehousing logistics and
sales and brand support so how would you
say what would you say is the
appropriate value for those services and
to give people an expectation of what
how they would approach a conversation
with a distributor but also how to
evaluate one distributor from the next
based on the service that they're
getting I think that should be answered
by anyone other than me right now I
think one of the first things is is
making sure that you Felipe's point
understand the rules and then ask your
distributor if they understand the rules
there's many times where we've had to
explain the law to another distributor
and I think what you should do is find
certain points that you want to ask them
you need to do a competency test I'm
basically trusting this person - I'm
putting my my well being in this
person's hands I have done everything I
can to create a high-quality
representation of what I believe is the
best product out there and I'm going to
give you the best of what I've got how
do I know whether or not you can give me
the best that I expect you know that you
can reciprocate
and you have to be able to know that
these people are technically competent
you shouldn't have to question whether
or not they can do logistics if they
can't do logistics and that should be a
short conversation from there I think
it's really understanding there their
sales makeup you know what is it that
they can do for me on the sales front
are they gonna provide demo services and
recognizing how much of that you need to
lean on them for and how much of that
you plan to do yourself it's it's really
a negotiation you should see it as an
open negotiation saying you know I'm
gonna bring you know I the brand I'm
gonna bring my sales team and I just
need your demo but I'd say you're gonna
see price points start to get a little
bit more competitive and it's hard to
say whether or not they'll go up or down
I think with the consolidation that's
gonna happen you're gonna see some of
them go up because a lot of the
technical technically proficient
operators are gonna do are gonna remain
in those that are not proficient we're
gonna disappear and that space is gonna
get a lot more complicated as we
continue to evolve this this marketplace
there's gonna be more retail outlets
it's gonna be more delivery services and
eventually there's going to be long
hauls headed out to other states and
really at the end of the day you want to
understand how capable that team is that
you're relying on and if they are
competent you should really it's it's
actually pretty hard to explain how many
different things the distributors have
to do that really a brand doesn't see on
a daily basis but expect that when you
walk into these negotiations that number
is going to land somewhere around 20 to
25% for full service that's what you
should show up with as a budget 25
percent should be what you expect in the
middle and anything that you get below
that is a win I would say look at the
contract so after you've gotten to see
the facility meet some of the team look
over their distribution services
agreement you can tell a lot about a
company just by reading that agreement
we've actually talked about
standardizing the distribution contracts
so it's very easy for
you to read and compare distributor to
distributor so hopefully that'll happen
in the upcoming year or this year and so
that would be probably another great
thing if we can all have just like real
estate where you look at the formants in
the same place no matter which mortgage
company you worked with or which realtor
you worked with it's also important to
note that if your brand is doing a
hundred thousand dollars a month that
maybe even taking fifty percent the
person's going to be losing yet if
you're doing a couple of million dollars
a month it might be ten percent is too
much so kind of either breaking it out
so there's flat fees or there's breaks
on percentages or so forth and again a
lot of it really depends on how much
work you're asking them to do the reason
I was dodging the question a little
earlier is we have a little bit
different model and it certainly I gotta
say it's a better model or an inferior
model it's just the one we take which is
every brand that we work with we've
invested in and taken an equity position
one is because we want them to have the
resources because if we're out there
distributing and we go to them and say
it'd be great if you did XYZ we don't
want to look across the table and say
well we don't have the money go sell
some stuff and then we can do it the
second and the more important thing is
that we wanted the long term interest to
be aligned and so we want to make it
where if they're successful we're
successful
similarly if they're cut we believe as a
distributor sometimes what happens I
call this the distribution paradox for
brands a distributor goes in there
carrying your brand and the dispensary
says you know what we don't think we're
going to carry this one but we're going
to carry this other one from you well
for that salesperson there they've made
their Commission and it's really tough
on them to say no no no thank you for
that order but so forth because they're
just trying to keep that footprint and
so forth and yet from the brands point
of view you don't want the distributor
to come back oh good news bad news bad
news is they're not carrying you anymore
good news is they're carrying something
else we distribute so that's how we went
ahead and tried to address it others
have addressed it in other ways but we
look again to take make an investment in
session it just occurred to me that you
should also look at their brand
portfolio let's see how you rank amongst
the other brands that they carry does it
make sense for you to work with this
distributor do they have other brands
that would keep you know cannibalize
that piece of your business and I would
add that 20 to 25 percent numbers for a
brand new brand without any history if
you have history as stated that
obviously gives you a great deal more
leverage and negotiating power and it
also makes things a lot more cut-and-dry
for the distributor so to that end you
should really do whatever you can to see
what demand there is for your product in
the market and then start talking to
distributors again as well you don't
want to show up without a very good
understanding or at least some form of
context for your brand in the market
because we have people that show up and
they had some contracted product that
they don't really know about and don't
believe in and we just they're like okay
make this big maybe talk to somebody
else
all right well our kind of last question
and then we'll open it up for some QA
what role do you think that California
brands and distributors will have in
this kind of national and global market
that is emerging and you know what do
you think that timeline looks like now
do you personally have a vision for that
for your company or some of the brands
you work with like what's the
conversation right now around expanding
state to state the concept of interstate
commerce opening up and even even global
obviously ideally we'd want interstate
commerce to open up because we have one
of the greatest producing states in the
nation but for now since we have to work
within the confines of each state and in
the regulations California has
established by one of the best
frameworks when you look at the
regulations in the other states this one
was clearly guided by people that have
been in the industry for a long time and
we have a vision for being able to have
a platform to take your brand into
multiple
States so if you're produced here and
distributed here to provide that same
experience in another state that's
something that if you want to build a
big national brand you need so from
distribution I think we have a
responsibility to build that multi-state
platform yet stated simply California is
the largest and I think most important
cannabis market in the world it is what
Hollywood is two movies what New York
City is to publishing what Paris and
Rome is to fashion and so if you can
it's a very big an expensive and
difficult state to win but if you can
that will help you in the other states
that will help you in other countries
more than let's say having a winning
brand in Massachusetts or Florida and
then bring it in into California and so
on a pragmatic basis that means as
you're allocating if you're in multiple
states and you're allocating marketing
budgets it's worth to allocate more to
California than you might otherwise do
because it really will help in your
licensing and we see that on the basis
of just in two folds one is the number
of queries that we get from other states
people wanting to license and there was
somebody from bang earlier this morning
and people were saying we want to
license you and he said well that's
great but why do you want us and they
said because people asked for your
product in this other state and that
speaks volumes yeah I think some of the
sentiments here at California for sure
is the most important market of the
nation and you know probably the world
California also produces two-thirds of
the nation's fruits and vegetables so I
think when state white borders come down
all cultivation moves down here
manufacturing moves to California too
you don't want to be shipping biomass to
other states to be manufactured
everything will be really close to the
biomass and the way we think about
national expansion is hyper focused on
California we're building massive scale
on our upstream operations building
relationships with the farmers helping
them a lot with their accounting
services or compliance services their
legal services we've also partnered with
an amazing lab called Cascadia labs and
our facility and offering really large
bulk discounts to our farmers so finding
ways for them to stay in the ecosystem
and building that infrastructure so that
when the states do come online
or the statewide borders do go off or do
disappear we're ready for that national
expansion right in the portfolio that
we're building is a very curated set of
very desirable California brands that
have California values at heart that
want to support the sun-grown ecosystem
the small farmer ecosystem really the
people that kind of built this industry
and we feel that building that really
large portfolio here in California
putting those in the top-ranking spots
across all their categories and really
waiting for that moment
I think the Canadian public markets have
created an artificial market dynamics
where people think they can put flags in
other states and use that to raise more
money and raise more capital I think a
lot of people are going to be cut with a
lot of little small little assets in a
bunch of little locations and not really
building for the scale when the time
comes and that's what we're really
focused on I would say us goes
California so goes the rest of the world
and that's what we kind of promised a
lot of our business design on
understanding that once we get
California dialed in we can pretty well
assume that whatever structures adopted
at the federal level is probably going
to look somewhat similar to California
we are developing the precedent this is
the opportunity to establish a very
large system that allows us to prove it
to provide proof of concept to the
federal government and likely we'll have
a fair segment of it adopted at the
federal level so for our operation we
are designed to scale not only
nationally but internationally
what we did is invested heavily on our
warehouse management system on the front
end ensuring that the ability to scale
is not limited by our systems but merely
by our creativity I want to say thank
you to our panelists all members of the
cannabis distribution Association we
have Pacific Expeditors rise logistics
mammoth distribution and flow kana so I
encourage you to reach out to these
folks and do we have time for questions
we have time for one or two quick
questions all right I see you Kris here
I come on my way here I go caller are
you there thank you great panel Chris
Conrad here I'm just wondering in terms
of distribution system do we see the
same kind of
competition for shelf space in the
Cannabis introduce you like see at the
grocery stores or whatever where they're
fighting for that right at the exit and
so forth and and how does that work out
and distributor versus people trying to
go on their own and so forth I just like
to address that thank you
there's nothing preventing slotting in
the regulations so yes shelf space is
being bought and sold and traded and all
sorts of things it's extremely
competitive I also look at it like the
the almost like the pharma super forma
suitable reps that would go and hit a
doctor
you've got to think there's almost one
distributor for every retail store right
now so if I were gonna say anything that
we need to focus on in California and
2019 it's bring on more retail we have a
lot of consumers we need a lot more
retail in a really small footprint in
the stores it's not like a grocery store
though you have a lot of shelf space to
offer to begin with so the footprints
much smaller question over here it seems
like more and more distributors are sort
of building their own proprietary
technologies it seems as you said
there's a tremendous amount of expense
is already with being a distributor and
even more trying to build your own
proprietary software where do you sort
of bridge the gap between what you build
yourselves and what you buy I mean my
assumption is you want to be a
distributor now not a software company
that's an interesting question actually
and we took a very unique and different
approach from day one to actually bring
a lot of our technology in-house I think
to your point for sure people that are
doing purely distribution there's a lot
of software out there that does
warehouse management route optimization
whatever whatever you call it for us
specifically and you know I definitely
wanna speak for the for the crowd
we're very deeply connected with the our
supply chain and our partners so we have
a lot of technology and a lot of tools
for our farmers to onboard their
inventory to view their inventory to see
what products are selling in which
locations and which stores in which
regions we give them ideas of what to
grow we want to try to turn our supply
chain to being what it is today that
farmers grow whatever they want and then
we have to figure out how to sell it and
we want to basically use our data and
our tools to really inform the upstream
production
so that we're actually doing demand
production rather than whatever the
farmer wants so we built a lot of our
technology in the house you know the way
we kind of look at business and
generally at flow kana as we look at the
world and we make our own hypothesis
sometimes those hypotheses are proven
and disproven and we look ahead and try
to kind of figure out what the next
bottlenecks are right lab testing was a
huge bottleneck that we have in this
initiative a that's why we made a deep
partnership with a lab I see technology
and a lot of this software's out there
attracting multiple states and multiple
jurisdictions and multiple regulations
so we always thought that technology was
gonna be very hard for us to scale
especially how complex our model is to
really be able to depend on other people
to make the the changes that California
will require so specifically for us
because we're so deeply connected to our
farmer base all the way to our retailers
it made a lot of strategic sense for us
to build our own stuff we felt a little
bit similar tacked and a little bit
different from some of them probably
smarter people on this panel than me but
it is very hard to be a good distributor
and so we felt we should put the focus
in that the same way that I don't think
I would go to a Microsoft and ask them
to distribute cannabis so we look for
people who their sole focus is
developing amazing software and then
look to leverage and work on their
efforts and I have the opposite take so
if you work with a software company and
a product manager to design software
about something very specific it's
really challenging for them to make it
as efficient as you can if you are both
software and an operator the other
aspect related to this is a lot of the
companies that build software either
publicly traded their venture capital
funded and we've seen them decide
overnight hey we cannot provide services
to the cannabis industry so until the
federal legality changes you're at risk
if you're running on someone else's
platform that one day could say you know
what we don't want to do this anymore
you're done what do you tell your
clients in that state so we believe that
we should own our platform and build it
in regard to the brand's the small
farmer brands that have taken some
investment upfront to build that brand
do you for how do you force the
appellation rights factoring into that
and whether or not it will become easier
to support the branding for small
farmers that the when it comes to
distribution because it sounds like
there's someone said a lot of traffic
and that you know lots of players and
hard to enter it's a small farmer so the
question is what's the do you identify
there to be value in the Appalachians or
how do you see appellation rights
factoring in and perhaps I mean I guess
I have my own viewpoint easing the
ability for an emerging brand or small
farmer to be able to cut through some of
the traffic and distinguish themselves
because they have Appalachian of origin
or some other protected category that I
know people are working on that
potentially could I would say how
powerful is in Appalachian right is it
if you have a small business but you get
to call it Humboldt grown or but to see
no gold is that gives you more sway in
the marketplace yeah it's a huge I would
put every effort that you could into
creating Appalachians that's where you
can create a recognizable and unique
identifier to your brand I mean if you
look at somebody who's creating
something from Stag's Leap Vice
Rutherford and those abilities to
identify very high-end production
regions it is easily something that
creates differentiation and identifies a
certain level of value not only for the
manner in which you produce it all the
way through to the connection that a
consumer has to that particular region
I think Appalachians is a very very
valuable initiative that should be
furthered and it will definitely change
the scene of cannabis across California
I was just gonna echo echo that and also
say I think the Appalachians will be
critical to for furthering the value of
California and Emerald triangle and
regional and specific cannabis as we do
it
and into a national and global market so
it's critical Senator McGuire has a bill
that just came out last week to kind of
further clarify the point of origin for
the appellations of origin which is
great and there's a program called the
Mendocino Appalachians project which is
expanding its name I think to be the
California Appalachians project so I
would strongly recommend any anyone to
get involved with that group support
that group it's a small you know
self-funded organization that takes
donations and contributions but it's
critical for small farmers and I don't
know Mikey I thought you might want it
to say something as well yeah for sure
I'm actually very bullish on
Appalachians I think it's certainly that
the long game as lauren says I think
it's gonna be more more valuable when we
have the national market place to play
in in fact one of the slides on my deck
recently is if you look at the wine
industry nationwide 4% of the volume of
grapes come from Napa and Sonoma of the
entire wine industry yet Napa and Sonoma
wines command 54% of the revenue so
while they produce a very large little
amount of volume the revenue and the
premium that they're getting is
substantial and you know to Lauren's
point
I love the Mendocino Appalachians
project there's an incredible groups in
the Emerald triangle hcg a being one of
them mcg a ICF a there's a couple of
groups kind of trying to coalesce and
find ways to collaborate and we're
trying to figure out how to really put
forward the appellations program and
also do it in a way that the consumer
can understand but the onus is on you to
make that be something that the consumer
understands so when they walk in they
ask for it if they see it they recognize
so band together with others and yours
so if they come in they see a difference
between that and something may be grown
in a warehouse
stinky warehouse in LA County and and
let's not forget there are regions of
the state that are globally known for
being some of the best sources for
cannabis in the world exactly I hate to
cut it out this is a great great
discussion let's hear once again for
Laura Fraser all the panelists
[Applause]