yo yo yo Make Some Noise one more time
for our steam panel here ladies and
gentlemen I've got a question are y'all
having a good time
today are y'all having a good time
today that's what I'm talking about ICBC
we've got Berlin coming up we'll see you
guys there it was a beautiful day today
we'll see you at the Afterparty uh we've
got a legend in the house today uh we
like to do this to you at the ICBC and
bring you uh legendary characters and
cultural icons
uh not only in the Cannabis space but in
the artistic space uh and we have a
hip-hop Legend here today DJ mugs of
Cypress Hill House of Pain and soul
assassins so please give a big welcome
to Uno beum and DJ mugs give it up
y'all come on make some noise DJ mugs
what's up what's
up how you feel let's he it for Alex
Rogers and the entire ICBC
crew having a good day well these chairs
are very comfortable check check check
you good I'm really good how you this is
DJ mugs what's happening what's
happening Cypress Hill maybe you've
heard of them maybe you've heard of them
they've had some hits they've been on
TV you were telling me earlier this is
your 17th time in Barcelona yeah I've
been coming to Barcelona since 1988 you
know um spent a lot of time here did a
lot of Tours here did a lot of shows um
we'd be on tour and have three or four
days off so we'd come to Barcelona you
know we'd argue Sometimes some of the
guys would want to be in Amsterdam some
of the guys would be in Barcelona so
we'd split and then we'd meet up again
in Germany for the next show that's
important to spend time apart from each
other when you're on the road like that
yeah when you have like 10 grown men on
a on a bus which basically is a
one-bedroom apartment you know I can
only imagine the smell you need a little
break after when you're on there for 6
weeks right right so what what are uh
have you noticed any changes since 1988
in Barcelona has the weed gotten better
or their clubs cooler the weed's got
amazing there was a lot of [ __ ] dirt
weed out here but you you know we would
we would smuggle it in from Amsterdam
and we used to put it in the the radio
and put it in the cassette and put
coffee around it and you know anything
we can do to smuggle weed around you
know what I mean and um but the weeds
got amazing out here the clubs are
amazing you know
um it's nice to be able to just go and
get some good weed down the block and
just isn't it it's just nice to pop into
the local do you have any favorite
clubs um HQ was good you know what I
mean um couple other spots I popped into
I can't remember all the names cuz
you're cuz you're high you can't
remember all them choco HQ lalada yeah
yeah yeah G3 tpy T turp was good man
turp had some bombass weeds you know
Strain Hunters T turp Army was fire fire
fire so since 198 Cypress Hill has been
around since 1988 or is that when you
were in 783 yeah my my first group
before Cypress Hill was a group called
783 and um you know we got the picture
up there on W that was 8888 we had a
song in the movie colors we was on tour
with MC Hammer and on tour with salt and
pepper on tour with today Tony Tony Tony
so we did you know World Tour and a
bunch of big Stadium tours back then you
ever challenge Hammer to a dance off
yeah I didn't win
though did you did you dance when you
were in 7 I did the running man I was a
[ __ ] Running Man Roger Rabbit
[ __ ]
boy we did the W too remember the
W sorry I just can't imagine the soul
assassins doing the [ __ ] man we like to
have a good time you know what I mean
yeah so when it's time to party we party
when it's time to do business we do
business when you when you join Cypress
Hill was it a conscious decision to be
very canic
Centric well I actually was down with
Cyprus before 783 okay you know that was
my hood that was where we was from so
you knew all those cats growing up or
from California I met them in like 80
from California we were selling weed
together we was selling weed hustling
doing our thing you know and then um I
met These Guys from Brooklyn and they
had a they had a song out called 783
Will Rock You which was a a just a
single they was down with IC tea and I
was throwing a party and I was like do
you guys want to come and play at my
party so they came and the DJ didn't
show up and I stepped in and I became
the DJ that night and they said we have
three shows with IC tea next week you
want to do the shows with
us so I went I did the shows and then um
two weeks later we was in the studio
doing a song called mad mad world for
the movie colors okay which was my first
cold record in 1988 nice I remember that
album about a couple months later we got
we got a record deal to get we got
signed to Gein records and um album came
out in ' 89 you know and we was out we
was out and started doing world tours
and I I told the Cypress guys I was like
listen man I'm going to go figure this
music business thing out and I'm gonna
bring it all back so I would just always
come back and I learned this and I
learned this we need a logo we need a
concept we need this like the first time
they told me do you have a logo I didn't
know what the word was and what it
meant and what was your concept you know
but I I took all the knowledge I gained
and brought it back to the hood yeah
okay so marketing is is that the advice
you give the Young Musicians I always
give the young Comics at advice they
were like if you had to do i' be like
take a marketing class this was before
YouTube and all that you know what I
mean it was like handson if you didn't
know anybody back then you was [ __ ]
you know what I mean now you can just go
online and look at it all up but you
know it was you had to be in the
trenches you had to go to the parties I
learned a DJ by going to the club and
watching the DJ looking at him and I
would go home and try to do that [ __ ]
it's easier now with the computers and
the things they got DJ schools now DJ
school yeah the school of DJing yeah go
take a class I never maybe do you teach
less are you Professor mugs now n yeah
I'll teach my the homies if they want to
learn they can pull up and I'll take
care of them there you go there you go
okay so so so was was Cannabis always
part of the marketing plan for Cypress
Hill or is it just that you guys smoked
a lot of weed and you were like [ __ ] it
we're putting it on on everything well
783 was managed by Rush management which
was Russell Simmons who owned Def Jam
and I sat with Mr Bill who did the
Public Enemy records and everything and
he was like so you have a logo and I was
like what was that and then he told me
he was like what's your concept and I
was like what's a concept and he said
you know run dmc's the gangsters a rap
slick Ricks the Tory Storyteller LL CJ
is the beat boy of hip-hop what's your
concept and you know 7 A3 didn't have
one but I thought about it so when I got
back to Cypress I was like yo we got to
be the cheich and chongs of this
[ __ ] you know what I mean like
come out of like weeds our [ __ ] cuz we
smoked but everybody in weed at that
time was talking about don't smoke weed
like Dr Dre was saying I don't smoke
weed or cess cuz
brother brain damage Newan was like slow
down you know what I mean we was like
light this [ __ ]
up I remember that I remember when y'all
came out and everybody's like man these
cats are I mean cuz you know a lot of a
lot of musicians and a lot of performers
especially back in that time in the
early 90s late ' 80s early mid 90s they
all smoke weed everybody smokes weed but
everybody was super hush hush and very
discreet and you didn't let anybody know
was something you did you know but you
guys were on stage with giant bongs and
and yeah we brought the8 foot bong on
stage you know what I mean we was like
we was we was about it man and um got
you kicked off a Saturday Night Live did
it yeah I went on we went on National
Television we went on Saturday Night
Live and I was rolling my joint
backstage and about eight people ran
eight people came backstage and seen me
at you know about five minutes
increments and they was like don't like
that on stage don't like that on stage
don't like that on stage and I was like
no problem I won't I knew we had two
wasn't everybody smoking weed backstage
at no you couldn't smoke weed backstage
oh that was just the 70s that [ __ ] was
okay so I knew we had two songs so I
couldn't do it on the first song cuz we
would have got kicked out so I came on
stage and I was like New York City can I
light my joint and I lit it and they
said the phone started ringing and the
phones was ringing and when I got off
stage oh boy they let me have it they
ripped into me and I didn't give a [ __ ]
we was punk rock [ __ ] it what you you
can't fire me right then I like they
can't even prove it was a joint they
like you can't come back on Saturday
Night Live again I was like [ __ ]
Saturday Night Live too I don't give
want to come back on this [ __ ]
then Y cornballs and then um you know
here we are now now this shit's legal
right and thanks to you you guys helped
a lot first hip-hop group on High Times
yeah we was the first hip-hop group on
high times but not only that is like we
um I'm going to say this right quick too
uh when we saw you on High Times uh
that's when I learned to smoke blunts
cuz y'all were talking about it I was
like we got to try this [ __ ] out cuz in
California we didn't really have blunts
like in New York at the time the weed
wasn't that good so [ __ ] in New
York would smoke blunts to make the weed
better you know what I mean cuz we had
the good weed in Cali but the homies
didn't really had a lot of good [ __ ] out
there so you know and at that time I met
Steve Bloom from hot times and we
started doing um we started raising
money for normal the National
Organization reforming marijuana laws
and we did over 20 events for them to
raise money so they can [ __ ] pay the
pay the lawyers to go to Congress and
they could um Lobby for the legalization
of cannabis so you know back in the
early '90s we was putting in the work to
get us to where we all are today you
know what I mean yeah yeah yeah and it
didn't
um it didn't I guess it didn't keep
y'all from getting too many gigs because
some I remember in the 90s some people
would talk about weed and The
Gatekeepers and the the powers that be
be like well we we're not really going
to work with these cats cuz they talk
about weed too much but you guys were
very can entric and it didn't seem to be
a problem well the president of the but
I mean you sold records go ahead I'm
sorry yeah Tommy Mata the CEO of Sony
Music D Donnie would let us smoke in the
offices and they was like oh Cypress
Hill is in the building cuz it smelled
the whole [ __ ] 34th 34th floor but
when I would get to Arizona the cops
would be waiting for us by the stage and
like don't smoke when you go on stage
when I get to New Mexico the cops was on
stage when I get to Texas the cops was
right there waiting for us and back then
in Texas had a no Tolerance Law so if
you had one joint you was doing a year
in jail yeah you know so Nevada New
Mexico Arizona with some other [ __ ] New
York and La you get a little weed
they'll either slap you on the ass tell
you to go home or they'll take you in
for the night just to put you in the
system and spit you out the next day you
know what I mean so we went through all
that we got locked up in La a gang of
times we got locked up in New York for
weed you know some of the other states
we [ __ ] had to dip and Dodge and run
you know I remember before before the EU
was the EU you know you had to go
through checkpoints every place and
coming into coming into France all the
time on a tour bus them [ __ ] is
on you bus boy like [ __ ] with
the dogs looking for anything wow I had
Eric Bobo in my band one time get to
passport control and open up his
passport and there was a piece of hash
stuck to his [ __ ] passport he was
like oh [ __ ] I have a joke in my ACT
about that like never hide hash in your
passport it's the first place they look
and it was always that little roach in
the back of your pocket someplace that
they would find you know what I mean was
there for like a week right even if you
don't have weed check your pockets
before you get on the plane you know
before you pack your luggage
I buy new
luggage I buy new luggage and new
clothes and I still find weed still dude
I found a grandma dabs I was on a plane
I was on the plane like two years ago I
was on the plane flying to Barcelona and
I reached in my pocket for something and
I found like a grandma dabs and [ __ ] and
I was like ah I think weed got a mind of
its own it's like I'm might hide in this
other pocket he don't even know I'm here
watch this [ __ ] yeah yeah man it's just
this just how it goes when you're uh
when when cannabis is a lifestyle and
not a a hobby yeah absolutely right yeah
right right so what else are you working
on man so you do Soul assassins is
Cypress Hill doing anything yeah yeah
Cypress Hill is non-stop you know we do
over 100 shows a year Still Still yeah
still make records that's every three
days own Cannabis shops sell weed you
know Dr greenb Dr greenb my brother B
real yeah we do a lot of behind the
scenes things in cannabis you know what
I mean um just still pushing the culture
you know what I mean our whole thing has
been pushing the culture pushing the
culture being in the be be doing the
intangible things you know being behind
the scenes just still being a force to
reckon with behind everything that we're
pushing forward you know what I mean cuz
our new tour is called we legalized it
you know what I mean that's that's what
the new tour is
called right I mean you were just
talking about Nevada and Arizona and New
Mexico and they've all legalized
cannabis and I got to tell you uh it's
much easier to hang out in Arizona when
you can be high and bored yeah and not
just sober and bored you've never been
to AR going to trust me it's hot and
boring yeah they all [ __ ] they all
cuz all the [ __ ] is doing meth
over there and sitting in the house in
the air conditioner you know I got smoke
weed and be all right you be all right
who's got the who's got the best weed
besides California we already know don't
hey shut
up I rep my hood California California
but let's let's talk about in Europe
Amsterdam Spain Spain got some good [ __ ]
man I mean I smoke some good [ __ ] out
here you know what I mean Amsterdam's
always had the bomb Amsterdam's always
been you know one the spot it was always
the spot for us to come visit sure
especially 9192 you know Widow it was
there was no place else you can go
experience like the the the the Cannabis
Lounge culture like grownup cannabis
culture where you
sit your spliff have a coffee just relax
and sit back and you know and and and
enjoy yourself like that was a beautiful
thing like my first experiences of that
in the early 99s is just visiting in
Amsterdam and being able to go to the
coffee shops and was it mind-blowing
where you like we got to bring this back
to the States
100% we tried opening up a couple coffee
shops out there and we got to the final
stages of it but you know the the
Partnerships we was hook trying to hook
up with people just never panned out at
the end but we tried early on to make it
happen to be like you know everybody
went to the Bulldog back in the days
right we was like to have the the
Cypress Hill cannabis you know Cafe you
had a spot in La no we got we got
multiple spots under different names no
the the the consumption Lounge that I
have is my
studio cuz I I really I really don't
want to go smoke weed with a bunch of
Stranges I get creative when I smoke so
you come to my studio we got a [ __ ]
gym in my studio we got a theater room
we got Studios so everybody comes to my
studio we watch the games we work and
that's that's my consumption Lounge nice
uh how much is a membership where do I
sign up you just got to be the homie
just pull up come on just pull up we got
call youg we we got apartments in the
back if you want to stay there you you
know what I mean it's like heyy be
careful what you say to me come on man
be careful what you say cuz I'll come
I'll be your you need a roller you need
somebody to load bongs or what come in
and do all that I'll roll the blunts
I'll make sure that your uh your Edibles
are all topped up do you cook do you
make the Edibles are you careful with
Edibles do you [ __ ] with them I [ __ ]
with Edibles heavy I like Edibles are
you on one right now no okay I might be
a little bit I drinking coffee though
weed and coffee I haven't smoked yet but
I will after this yeah I'm going to be
higher than giraff titties after this
so what's a giraffe titty look like um I
you know it's kind of high up you got to
look I don't swing off them or
nothing how did we get to that I don't
even know how we got there I was who's
the most famous person you ever smoked
weed with oh man back in the day I got
high with Tommy Chong once I shook
Willie Nelson's hand but I never
um you say Johnny de Johnny Depp we smok
we with Johnny Depp before um Lindsay
loham
um uh um
[ __ ] uh what's um Howard Stern Howard
Stern I didn't know he smoked weed oh
yeah who was the person you were most
surprised like I mean I don't know if
you're outing any celebr every I can't
remember all the people but everybody
was like down low like yo you got any
weed yeah of course crazy motherfu
everybody smoked weed they just didn't
want they just didn't want to let
anybody know like it was it was a
[ __ ] bad thing to do back in the days
you know what I mean yeah but it wasn't
a bad thing to do it was just a bad
thing for other people to know about you
just had to be discreet yeah it was
tough to be open I I mean not for you
guys but it was because you went to jail
for it you were threatened by the cop
the hippie culture they put the clamp
down on it you know what I mean they
came and just wanted to just shut that
[ __ ] down so they did you can't have any
Enlightenment or people being against
war no you don't want that no you don't
want that at all you you don't want
people to be free thinking and open and
and and happy no we can't have it that
leads to people eating good and and
proper education and respectful and
getting along respect having love for
their fellow man that that won't do
uh-uh can't make no money off of people
getting along yeah right where's the
tension that's not good television it's
got to have conflict can't have reality
TV where everybody's in a good mood
happy and [ __ ] giving each other hugs
right hugs this week on reality TV we're
just going to hug each other and smoke
some weed give some
massages sorry that was funny to
me uh so what were we talking about
weed music weed and music they come
together those are two things in this
world that bring people together you go
to a concert you there's people at that
concert that you would never hang out
with ever in your life and you're there
together to at the Taylor Swift concert
yeah to enjoy the same thing you know
what I mean and weed like weed and
music's brought me places and brought me
to people and places that I never
thought and imagined I'd be and it
brought me to people and it's like
definitely opened the [ __ ] the [ __ ] up I
mean [ __ ] here we are at a business
conference in
Barcelona did you imagine that Christ in
1989 think about 1994 right right a weed
right back when weed business was yeah
let me get a dime yeah okay right let me
let me get a when dimes were that big
right right you could get a nickel bag
for
$4 if you knew a nickel bag would be a
with a bunch of seed $5 seeds do you
remember seeds and stems are you that
old Junior High man you get the nickel
bag and it was about [ __ ] that
goddamn like a eth but it was all
[ __ ] stems and seeds in there you
have to scoop it up pull that [ __ ] out
sco out be seed and you smoking the [ __ ]
would be popping right the smell of a
burning SE hom be like yo you ain't
going to be able to have babies if you
smoke the seeds [ __ ] it I don't got to
get my nuts cut now I could just smoke
seeds in the [ __ ] I'll be good I
don't even got to seia without
seeds cmia that's where it comes from
right well you all speak Spanish you
know
this I think most of you speak SP I
don't know how many people speak Spanish
you speak
Spanish one mugs you speak any Spanish I
talk some [ __ ] you talk some [ __ ] you
can talk some [ __ ] you can start a fight
I know all the bad
words that's how you learn yeah that's
how you learned that's how I learned
that's how you learned what do you think
the future of of cannabis and music is I
mean you know it's it's the field of
infinite possibilities with cannabis
that's interesting everybody wanted it
to go legal and here you go but once it
goes legal you get the government
involved you know what I mean and they
keep changing the here's the Target and
you shooting at the Target and they move
the [ __ ] and every time you
think you you got it in your sights
they're going to keep moving it's you
know what I mean so that's the challenge
y'all [ __ ] got to deal with if
you want to be in a legal cannabis
industry it's a struggle it's a battle
it is what it is you know what I mean
don't be a little [ __ ] um be ready the
strong Will Survive the [ __ ]
out a forward thinkers that are smart
that are making the right connections
that are getting with the right people
and the [ __ ] that are just
getting in here to get rich you ain't
going to survive and get the [ __ ] out of
here you know cuz it it will eat you up
and chew you up and spit you the [ __ ]
out and and we've seen all those dudes
by the wayside all that road kill you
know what I mean so I mean yeah but I'm
loving that it's opening up and you know
human beings that would have never
smoked and never thought about smoking
they're smoking it and they're open to
it and it's just beautiful to just see
it opening up globally it's slow it's
going to take some more time it's going
to take a lot of more work but we're on
the right path man we are we are on the
right
[Applause]
path what do you do about I was talking
to somebody uh earlier today about
legalization and regulations and and and
getting things in and I mean they're
having problems in Barcelona right now
uh a bunch of the clubs were visited by
the police uh last night nobody got shut
down but there were some inspections of
things right because they got a new
mayor the new mayor isn't as friendly
toward cannabis as ain't legal but
they're going to come shut you down for
a night grab your [ __ ] you open up the
next day you bring it back in and that's
the [ __ ] that's the peek-a-boo game
hide and go seek you know what I mean so
but I feel like there's always going to
be a certain percentage of people that
are just going to hate no matter what
like we can't expect science and common
sense to win the day if we did that we
wouldn't have racism we wouldn't have
abis prohibition if people just believed
in science and common sense so but
there's always going to be a small
amount of of people who just hate weed
no matter what [ __ ] there's
going to be a certain amount of people
that just hate themselves no matter
what so we need more love always need
more love always need more
love that's good was a good
[ __ ] be bored yo like it's like
they be bored so they just in like where
I live you could park your car and all
the work everybody who works at the
restaurants Parks their car but there's
a bunch of old ladies they're bored so
they just went around doing a petition
so nobody could just park their car no
more they they want a only 2hour limit
or you get a ticket cuz they're just
[ __ ] is bored and it's the same
[ __ ] at a board that got
nothing to do that don't want cannabis
you know legal so we need more
activities for old board people man I'm
a people are [ __ ] weird bro I don't
have F you should set up a pickle ball
court you know I will
or going him to smoke some weed right
yeah that makes sense old old Stoners
are are way cute anyway old Stoners are
way cuter than old drunks oh hell yeah
oh yeah hell yeah right Grandpa's
hitting the bong again is funny yeah
they just had the wrong influences when
they was young they needed an older
brother or sister to make him smoke weed
how old were you when you first started
smoking 14
Jesus you do you think that was too
early I mean it just was it it is it was
what it was you know what I mean it was
just we was there with the homies
kicking it and that's you did it or you
didn't kick it did you do you do you
have children yeah I got one did uh did
you talk to them about cannabis what did
you say she just grew up seeing her dad
smoking weed right I didn't hide it no I
mean can't it there's the magazine
there's a dad she don't smoke though
right my kids didn't smoke till College
I was very but since they were little
because right you can't hide it so I was
like no drugs till College get your [ __ ]
together handle your business and then
if you do that then maybe you can you
can do some drugs and then uh now
they're little Stoners 20s and they keep
me weed they ate a edible one time I
think she said she found it on accident
cuz the the maid put it in with the
chocolate and I was like man it's 5:00
in the afternoon and they're still
sleeping [ __ ] they doing in there and
then she got up and got all yeah and
started throwing up and [ __ ] and I was
like you okay and she's like man we ate
that chocolate and I was like oh [ __ ]
she's like please don't tell my mom and
I was like I got you don't trip and
you're like yeah you don't tell your mom
either because and then I think that was
itou she ain't she ain't doing none of
that
it's funny cuz my mom didn't smoke and I
was smoking as a kid now I smoke and my
daughter don't smoke that's how it goes
yeah yeah that's it's a it's a rebellion
I always I always figured my kids
weren't going to smoke I'd be like come
smoke a Jo me be like no I have to work
at the stock
market what no no child of mine's going
to have a
job you learn that from your mother
so we're you're DJing the party tonight
yes sir do you have a a playlist planned
or was it all Barry Manalo or what are
you gonna it was anybody got any
requests for
tonight George Clinton Soul assassins
what was that Willie
Nelson afro be afro beat you like the
afro beats oh yeah I love them oh yeah
the SOA y the Bachata all that [ __ ] all
that [ __ ] you going to do the running
man no
we'll get Alex we'll get Alex to do the
Running Man he'll come out and pop and
lock do the Cabbage Patch can you
Cabbage Patch too
Alex Alex is GNA do the Cabbage Patch
bust out a couple
freestyles hey more
bound does anybody have questions do you
want to take some questions I don't even
know what time is it how long have we
been
talking oh okay so we have like 10
minutes left so that was perfect so this
is when we do questions does anyone have
questions question do we cover it all
cuz I can ask more questions what's your
favorite
color black if you were any sort of tree
what would you
be cannabis
tree male or female male
nice spreading my seeds spreading your
seeds I'm glad you said it I was going
to say it but I didn't know if it would
be appropriate Alex ravage yeah awesome
mugs to to see you huge fan for a long
time seen Cypress back in Toronto um my
question is a bit specific if I ever had
a chance to meet you I always wanted to
ask you about the soul assassins album
which I love is such an epic album like
a whole story it tells like from
beginning to end how come more people
don't do that uh it just seems such a
great idea but I haven't really seen
that ever since uh to tell the story
from beginning to end like kind of like
a soap opera rap kind of thing it was
cool anyways yeah um I think I got two
parts to that I don't know why anybody
doesn't do anything you know what I mean
but my and um but my thing was I just
wanted something to be very cinematic
and and I had like I think 12 different
artists on there and I was like how can
I make this feel like a cohesive piece
of work like and bring it all together
so it didn't sound like a compilation
record or it didn't sound like a mixtape
so you sat down you felt like you was
just listening to an album by One artist
so that's the reason I put it together
like that so when you sat down you got
the experience of just you're listening
to One artist and not just a random ass
compilation or soundtrack you know what
I mean I think the challenge on that
sometimes too is in the digital age
people don't just put a record on or put
a tape on and let it play all the way
through CD in your car and it stays
there for a year right right but now
it's you know your playlist will skip
around all sorts of things so people
think they make singles right they don't
necessarily put together you know a
concept album like the soul assassins
album or what's going on from Marvin Gay
or even that sticks album about killroy
or whatever where it's like a whole
story it's everything is so uh people
don't really have the attention span
like they used to except for Alex the
stoner who listens to whole albums all
the way through and and things like that
but yeah there was another question over
here yeah over here can you hear me yes
cool all right mugs um longtime listener
first time caller uh Greg from DC uh I
just wanted to ask you what artists um
have you enjoyed working with lately uh
lately I really like um this kid named
um rasco Raz FreshCo from Canada um Rome
streets from New York Mayhem luren
um um this kid named TF from Los Angeles
which I think our album is going to be
ridiculous right now we got a bunch of
songs together and then um and I'm
working with CEO green right now oh half
the album's done the shit's amazing man
so um you know I'm having a good time
right now finding these these young
artists that are really that I'm really
inspired by and helped like giving them
my platform and giving them a platform
to go reach the world you know what I
mean cuz because money isn't my
motivation no more and fame isn't my
motivation my my motivation is just to
keep expanding the kind of music I love
to do and keep it alive and keep it
growing and help these artists you know
um reach their dreams and help help
their goals come into fruition you know
what I mean you into your OG Uncle phase
that's right where I'm at that's right
that's that's beautiful and let me ask
you this it's fun as [ __ ] we're talking
about some of the new cats but let let
me ask you who were some of your like
influences and not necessarily hip-hop
influences but like musical influences
when you were a younger cat I mean like
oh man um Jimmy Hendricks Leed Zeppelin
Bob Marley um Ram LZ um rund DMC um
Larry Smith who produced Houdini rund
DMC Public Enemy into like um Picasso
Alejandro jarasi you know people like
that like Alejandro jaroski he's a
filmmaker from oh jarasi yeah okay yeah
we were talking musicians you said
filmmaker well that's my inspiration
comes from every place there isn't a lot
of music these days that inspires me
anymore I find it outside of Music
things that inspire me you know I read a
juggling book one time and and his
advice to juggling performers was don't
be inspired by other jugglers be
inspired by different artists and then
incorporate that into your juggling
right so like my comedy show is
definitely set up like a Grateful Dead
concert it's a weird thing but I I feel
what you're saying so like jaroski any
other non-musician influences on your
music Picasso you know Picasso is in his
prime in the 60s you know what I mean a
lot of times musicians is like you done
in 30 it's like now we we I'm just
getting I'm not even in my Prime yet you
know what I mean we're just working it
out you know what I mean you don't see
you you had Killer Mike 48 years old won
three [ __ ] Grammys this [ __ ] you know
what I mean the producer of the year was
in his 40s the artist of the year was in
his 40s you know what I mean so y'all
are giving me hope right now a lot of
times the commercial music business is
always looking for the new young hot
thing you know what I mean the one good
thing about the digital age there's a
lot of bad things but the good things
about it is I can go direct to my
consumer around the world I don't have
to go through a gatekeeper through a
labor through a publicist anymore I
could just touch the people at the
fingertips you know what I mean and I
got 7 billion people right there at my
fingertips right now so D I speak
directly to them so it's definitely a
benefit for the Legacy artist in the
music business that's beautiful was
there another question yes please uh
during this day we we learned a lot of
course and a couple of times um it was
mentioned that cannabis is science but
um um it came through this interview
that cannabis is love so I have a
request can you play later your favorite
love song for us yep okay thank you that
was beautiful to the windows to the
walls from the window to the wall That's
A Love Song isn't it I said I'm like hey
what's up hello that's a that fetty W
song is definitely a love song I'm G
introduce you to my stove it's a very
sweet love song about the Trap game
trust me listen to it listen to it you
you'll hear it
hello
Mr how come you in medim
Colombia I came um four years ago with
with my friend crime Apple yes and we
made an album there I stayed for two
weeks we made a whole album in
medin um we had a good time I played a
small show in a small club with only 100
people but we didn't we didn't we didn't
um announc it it I just showed up but
I'm coming next time right yes yes yes
November you know baby
take me with you baby let's do it okay
if you tell you carry your luggage or
whatever let me know any more time for
questions oh one more for me and raspen
and then that'll do it he was first okay
okay that guy that guy and then Ian and
then that's it all right thank you um I
had a question
about uh you mentioned earlier you like
Edibles now between flower extracts and
edibles which ones you go to flower
flower team flower and a strain in
particular don't leave me hanging you're
leaving me hanging hands man you know
what I mean it just depends it depends
I'll smoke some Tas I like outdoor
sometimes when I'm in the studio outdoor
if I'm watching a movie I'll smoke
something real heavy like some OG Kush
you know what I mean but okay I keep it
light these days man now are you one of
the type of people I think there's two
kinds of people that smoke we there's
Stoners you know what I mean and um
there's people who get high like Stone's
Like a Rock you're going to get high
you're going to sit on the [ __ ] couch
and you're going to be stoned when I
smoke weed I want to go for a hike I
want to read a book I want to make music
you know what I mean I want to go to the
gym so weed affects me like that let
some people I know Should Never Smoke
Weed cuz they smoke and they're just
sitting there with their [ __ ] tongue
out and they don't get [ __ ] done just
like I got friends who drink and they
want to fight yeah but I drink and just
get happy and want to laugh so you have
to understand what your body chemistry
is you know what your goals are so
everything isn't for everybody you know
what I mean that's
and when it comes to ining anything bro
now I have some homies who always have a
bunch of different kinds of weed like
they have clean the house weed they have
sit on the couch weed they have
administrative tasks weed they have and
I understand that get high and have sex
weed Netflix CH weed the smokey pokey is
my
favorite uh can you play Dr Green Thumb
tonight yes I will thank you want the
English version or the Spanish
version
for he say Green Thumb in
espanol spell it
oh gracias okay one question for me and
then for real we got to wrap it up we're
over time
I heard that you recently released uh a
wine can you tell us a little bit about
the inspiration behind that and oh yeah
I'm um I'm a big fan of um natural wines
you know I I've always drank wine but
the first time I drank natural wines I
was you know a lot of times regular
wines might make me tired or something
but I drink a natural wine and I realize
they don't add sulfites to it you know
it doesn't last a long time but they and
um I drank a skin tone which where they
um they leave the skin on it so it was
orange and I never experienced that
before and I was like damn we drank five
bottles and I was with my friends having
a great time I wasn't tired I didn't get
a headache and I go I want to know more
about this so I got a few friends that
are really in really into wine so I was
like let's do a wine project so the
first one I did was called Holy Ghost it
was from an organic wine producer like a
fourth generation organic farm in
Germany it was a petot brought it in we
did that one and then I went up to
Northern California the last few years
with Brock is who's a big wine producer
out there who's got a winery and we did
one called notes and tones and I did a a
jazz album along with the wine so um now
I'm doing notes and tones too which is
another um skin tone orange wine um and
um I'm working on that now so I do it
for the lifestyle for the fun for the
people I meet the dinners and the
travels and the conversation you know
what I mean for me it's just it's just
it's something that I enjoy as a hobby
so you know I get to to like my life is
by Design nothing in my life happens by
accident so if I can curate my life and
what I enjoy to do and be around great
people and have good dinners and drink
[ __ ] wine that's what I do it for
amen any any final any last any last
thing you want to say before we wrap it
up no no fantastic my man I want to
thank everybody for coming out coming to
ICBC you know what I mean coming to
spanis everybody here representing the
good herb you know what I mean and
bringing this [ __ ] to the for front of
the world and you know let's take this
[ __ ] we want it to go shout out to Alex
out here and Nicole for bringing me out
here every year and being beautiful
people beautiful host you know what I
mean I want to thank y'all [ __ ]
for coming out Make some noise for
yourself thank you to this man make some
noise for my man right here
[Applause]
yo all right all right one more time
make up noise DJ vs and gu we'll see you
tonight at the after party in Berlin we
love you all Barcelona big up