all right we're gonna keep the knowledge
coming our next panel is called cannabis
deconstructed and our next speaker is a
neuroscientist with more than 20
peer-reviewed articles and publications
he is the founder and CEO of Medi
tourists please give a warm welcome for
mr. dr. Yeoh bukas is your Brook y'all
on yo-yo Cuba's your bukas thank you
very much thank you Alex and I CBC
organisers for doing this great meeting
this is my third opportunity to share
some knowledge and to challenge our
thinking at the ICBC the first time I
joined ICBC in 2016 in Vancouver I was
here last year in Berlin and it was so
good that we all decided that we should
be back here again this year and it's a
pleasure to be here my name is yacouba's
de Burgos I know it's easy to butcher it
so I go by dr. Z and my students
favorite is dr. Jay Z so without further
ado I'm gonna talk about cannabis
deconstructed and I'm gonna tell you
some of the some of the thoughts that I
have about cannabis and before we start
talking about cannabis we can start
talking instructing the human body
system that is called the
endocannabinoid system we all mammals
having the cannabinoid system even some
more primitive animals and animals and
creatures that live in the sea they also
have the endocannabinoid system the
endocannabinoid system is very complex
it is widely distributed throughout the
body so it is not just found in one
location it is essentially found in
almost every cell in our bodies and if
you look at this chart what it shows you
is cannabinoid receptors cannabinoid
receptor 1 and cannabinoid receptor 2
are distributed differently in different
organs and our bodies produces
endocannabinoids so we generate
ourselves cannabinoids
as needed and thus we sometimes need
supplement of cannabinoid that comes
exogenously as well so endocannabinoids
is a major one sahrin and amide and to
AG or a crocodile glycerol and these
endocannabinoids bind cannabinoid
receptors cannabinoid receptor 1 CB 1 is
mostly expressed in the brain also and
this is the fact of cancer tea but you
will so find cb1 receptors in liver and
the digestive system in kidneys in
bladder so it is widely expressed
throughout the body cb2 receptors are
more expressed in the organs and cells
that are related to the immune response
and it is widely distributed throughout
the body
the first boost of the endocannabinoids
and engagement of endocannabinoid system
happens with birth and with suckling it
is something that makes you hungry that
makes you eat and only after you eat you
get a boost of dopamine which gives you
the satisfaction for eating but
something makes you go eat and it's
probably the endocannabinoids because
this is one of the functions of
endocannabinoids they modulate pain and
stress immune function appetite memory
inflammation thermal regulation and
metabolism and phyto cannabinoids such
as THC for example are similar in
structure to in and amide and thus they
will bind the same receptors as does an
and amide and this interaction here is
pretty complex you can think of phyto
cannabinoids or cannabinoids binding to
the receptors in a key and a lock like
fashion however it is not that simple
and several cannabinoids for example THC
and CBD will bind the same receptor
therefore the receptor which can be
represented here by a door and the
function of the doors to be open and
closed appropriately the function of the
receptor to be activated or deactivated
appropriately and in order to engage the
sender cannabinoid system and receptors
multiple molecules have
bind to these receptors and multiple
locks exist on these receptors in order
to regulate properly the function of
these receptors now if we look at what
happens in the brain and also what
happens many places in the body this is
a simplified example with it's still
complex but when neurons are active what
happens is neurons produce a lot of
electrical positive charge that is
called depolarization that
depolarization allows for calcium to
influx and allows for the
neurotransmitter vesicles that are
chemicals that signal in our brain and
body to be released in the synapse
between two neurons
now the release of these
neurotransmitters and increased
excitation and depolarization and in
particular I'm talking here about
glutamate excitatory neurotransmitter
on-demand will then produce the
synthesis of endocannabinoids the
central cannabinoids are not stored in
the vesicles and they will cross freely
through the plasma membranes will travel
retrograde Li and will see B receptors
the C B receptor so located on neurons
but the cb2 receptors as well as cb1
receptors are also located on other type
of brain cells that are called glia
they're also very important in
information processing and brain
function so it's a system where and the
cannabinoids are synthesized on-demand
they pass through the membranes and they
activate CB receptors if there is no
control of glutamate you can have
glutamate excitotoxicity you can also
have calyx C city and cb1 receptor
activation turns off the influx of
calcium and regulates the release
neurotransmitters thereby balancing the
excitatory activity not just glutamate
no gamma amino butyric acid or GABA in
the neuronal synapses as well now in the
brain cb1 and cb2 expressed in many
different structures and you can see
that this is cb1 receptor that is
abundant in structure
such as hippocampus for example which is
responsible for learning memory and
stress but also the frontal cortex which
is responsible for executive functions
it is also expressed in the brainstem
that controls some of the vital function
interestingly the opiate receptors in
the brainstem are expressed in the part
that controls the breathing therefore it
is easy to die from opiates and have an
overdose by shutting down the breathing
centers and the cannabinoid receptors
actually located in the areas nearby in
the brainstem that control nausea and
vomiting but they are not expressed in
the breathing centers other receptor
targets so endocannabinoids do not just
bind Seabee receptors they target other
receptors and it explains the multitude
of functions and the multitude of
effects that people are seeing from
either one vital cannabinoid or the
group of vital cannabinoids in the case
of extractions and isolates of cannabis
trip v1 receptor is very important this
is your sensory afferents it's the
receptor that essentially mediates
analgesic functions or pain so
endocannabinoids target to be one
receptor they also target P power
peroxisome proliferator activated
receptor which is involved in
tumorigenesis metabolism development
self differentiation it also targets GP
r55 which is protein-coding receptor but
it's physiological function is not
completely known the whole idea is
massive and complex regulatory system
it's a homeostatic regular satori system
that has multiple targets multiple
actors and it's expressed throughout the
body so to engage them the cannabinoid
system you have stress you have trauma
you have hyperexcitability in the
tissues or in the brain you have
inflammation and the response of the
endocannabinoid system is eat make you
hungry go eat rest and sleep get drowsy
and sleep forget because it's important
forget things forgetting is an important
part of the survival if we remembered
everything we would be overloaded
mentally psychologically and also
protect the neuroprotection by
controlling neurotransmitters and also a
significant role in gastric protection
and regulation of the digestive system
thus and the cannabinoid system is
regulating our body which is teetering
constantly between excitation and
inhibition it is a finite system our
brains and bodies it's a sensitive
system but it is balanced more or less
between the interactions of the
endocannabinoids multitude of
neurotransmitters in our bodies the
endocannabinoid system again can be
modulated and we can talk about how we
can modulate on the cannabinoid system
so the first thing that comes to mind of
course is synthetic pharmaceuticals such
as synthetic THC that has been on the
market for any many years interestingly
synthetic THC that's pharmaceutical is
on schedule 2 and on schedule 3 and THC
that is natural from the plant is a
Schedule one
on substance is actually listed on three
schedules the justification is that
there are additives added into these
medications however there are no proof
that these additives are working
biological independently or making see
THC that is synthetic more effective so
we have therapeutic approaches to
modulating in the cannabinoid system of
course we can modulate the synthesis and
the degradation of endocannabinoids and
a lot of the synthesis happens through
this molecule H can modulate cb1 and cb2
is we can have supplements with
exogenous phyto cannabinoids we have to
remember that when we talk about fighter
cannabinoids and supplements we're not
just talking about smoking cannabis and
rolling joints the fastest-growing
demographic of cannabis users are baby
boomers and they are very interested in
many different preparations of how to
use cannabis and a lot of times they
don't want to necessarily smoke cannabis
reports of cannabis positively
modulating mental and physiological
processes are beyond anecdotal I always
tell this industry needs to stop saying
that this is an anecdote as an example
because when you go to any medical
meeting these anecdotes article studies
but when it comes to cannabis or
cannabis use they become anecdotes now
there's thousands of anecdotes we'll all
know that the research has been
restricted and is still restricted on
cannabis not on synthetic cannabinoids
but on cannabis and it's very limited
and therefore there may be inconclusive
evidence and you can set your own
strength and shield stringency level and
factual information that you involve in
this decision to make whether the
cannabis is effective medicine for
certain things
now let's deconstruct cannabis so we
just talked about the endocannabinoid
system and we deconstructed the system
into receptors into the endocannabinoids
and the distribution of the system
throughout the body
now let's deconstruct cannabis because
cannabis as medicine has been reported
by Chinese
shandong and is written up in the paint
our Ching which is the first book of
herbs essentially of herbal healing and
the Emperor was growing cannabis and
using it for medicinal purposes and was
really trying to understand what kind of
cannabis is being grown and what it can
be used for so all of the action and
cannabis in the plant is in the
cannabinoids and in the terpenes that
are mostly located in these very
beautiful trichomes on the plant there
is approximately three different types
of trichomes that are different by size
and these trichomes will contain these
glands will contain the cannabinoids as
well as the aromatic molecules let's
talk about something else let's talk
about some basic misconceptions that
exist
THC cannabis and what distinguishes
really hemp or industrial hemp from
medical or adult use cannabis or
recreational cannabis and I think that
distinguishes the two is THC
of course there are differences in the
way the plant itself looks but the only
real difference is the expression level
of THC so if we look at the industrial
hemp cannabis sativa cannabis ruderalis
by regulators the amount of THC it set
at 0.2% in Europe not in every countries
which one has it at 1% why who regulates
0.2 0.3 0.5 percent or 1% nature does
because you can have a certified seed
and you can have a certified plant that
is supposed to have 0.2 or below level
of THC but with certain grow condition
and maybe more some all of a sudden can
jump to 0.4 0.5 percent THC and in fact
a lot of farmers that get punished for
that they have no way of controlling it
they have done everything right they can
control the nature because the plants
are grown outdoors and naturally
industrial hemp plants actually like to
have 0.5 to 1% THC high THC cannabis is
sativa and indica and mostly hybrids now
that are in the market the highest
percentage of cannabinoids that these
plants can express is up into the
thirties percent of THC or CBD that's
simply just limited by the genetic
material and genetic mechanism of
production of these molecules so there
is a finite limit there is no plant that
can produce 65% of THC it will all get
cut off around 3035 percent now what I
really don't like is when people call
synthetic cannabinoids synthetic
marijuana or synthetic cannabis I have a
whole article written on this and I
encourage you to find it my name and if
you look up synthetic cannabinoids
synthetic Street cannabinoids or
so-called label the synthetic marijuana
is not cannabis is not marijuana it is
dangerous it should not be used it
should not be accessible and it is
widely accessible it is designed in the
lab it is designed by what I would call
evil scientists most of them are in
China and Eastern Europe it is
essentially putting chemicals together
and mixing them together to get to a
powder like form that looks like powder
and then sprinkle that powder like form
on the plant material which can be
tobacco or another material
label it a spice or cush put incense on
it and put it in all of the head shops
and the government's cannot keep track
of it because new formulations new
variations of these cannabinoids
synthetic cannabinoids that are deadly
and dangerous are coming out and they're
being released with different labels
constantly there's probably over 70
different variations of synthetic
cannabinoids that are out there they are
addictive they're dangerous and they're
deadly and they have nothing to do with
cannabis
this is hemp it grows tall and most of
the high THC cannabis at least it is
bred to be below 3 meters in height or
so
and I have to tell you that I found this
picture recently this is 1930s in
Vilnius which is the capital of
Lithuania where Lithuanians and polish
it was then under the Polish control the
city of Vilnius not only grew this
fantastic ham grew this giant hemp that
went all the way up to the four story
tall limits essentially but it was also
the first botanical and medicinal fiber
Institute that was opened in Vilnius in
Lithuania in 1930s one of the first ones
and it still maintains itself in Poznan
and has the second largest seed bank for
hemp and cannabis the the largest bank
for seeds for cannabis is in Russia so
have this in our history in Lithuania
it's not just Holland it's not just Bob
Marley before Bob Marley was born we
were already experimenting and we had a
research facility for cannabis and
textiles for cannabis in Lithuania now
cannabis consists of a diverse set of
phyto compounds some people call it and
the mere Hamish one of the professors
it's my idol pounds 1001 molecules in
cannabis
there's over 115 phyto cannabinoids a
number of terpenes about 120 by the way
analytical labs the maximum they test
for I think is steep how is about 40
plus cannabinoid spectrum or terpene
spectrum that they test for so we still
don't know a lot about these other 60 to
80 terpenes that are found in cannabis
flavonoids as well as amino acids Omega
amino acid so it's a very valuable plant
after that from many different
perspectives not just from intoxication
and the other thing that's interesting
about the plant is that this plant
doesn't produce THC and doesn't produce
the CBD actually produces acidic
cannabinoids 95 percent or so all of the
cannabinoids that are expressed in the
plant our city cannabinoids such as THC
80 HCA's non-intoxicating
so cannabis plant is actually non
intoxicating
it is heating or processing that
cannabis plant or decarboxylation
process that turns th scene THCA in t
THC CBD a into CBD and so on and th
season has the euphoric effect so THC
also is known as intoxicating agent
anti-inflammatory neuro protective
analgesic appetite stimulant antiemetic
anti-cancer is it all just good and
dandy does it work for everything and
make everybody happy no that's not the
case
cannabis is not for everybody cannabis
is not for every person it's not for
every patient cannabis can cause anxiety
can cause panic attacks can increase
heart rate there's low rate of addiction
for cannabis or cannabis dependency we
can call it as well as this hyperemesis
syndrome from high use or constant
chronic use of high THC cannabinoids its
emerging it's this coughing and vomiting
like syndrome in the morning which
usually gets fixed by taking a hot
shower
or using capsaicin from pepper which
binds to trip v1 receptors because
that's the mechanism that gets impaired
and hyperemesis syndrome so CBD is
really the therapeutic champion of
cannabinoids it actually counteracts
negative effects of THC so it can be
anti-anxiety and anti panic attacks it's
anti psychotic neuro protective anti
cancer that we can't addictions or lytic
anticonvulsant automatic analgesic it
does have negative effects fatigue and
drowsiness we also have to pay attention
to some of the latest literature from
epilepsy that suggests that both THC and
CBD could potentially be pro convulsant
in 10% of all of the studies okay so we
have to be cautious of these things so
CBD cannabidiol what it does it blocks
enzymatic breakdown of the molecule FH
which synthesizes endocannabinoids so it
increases the production and presence of
the endocannabinoids
it rapidly crosses blood-brain barrier
it's non psychoactive but I prefer to
use non intoxicating
because nicotine a psychoactive coffee
psychoactive everything is psychoactive
psychotropic is different or
intoxicating CBDs non-intoxicating
counteracts THC effects there's a lot of
evidence in human epilepsy with CBD and
lots of diverse case studies using CBD
THC and also combination of THC and CBD
and what's emerging at least from
unpublished literature is that this
ratio of THC CBD and also from existing
drugs such as sativex which is one to
one THC and CBD that this ratio of THC
CBD is also very important in different
applications now I urge you to look at
this health effects of cannabis and
cannabinoids it was published by the
National Academy of Sciences engineering
and medicine so we're the brightest
minds got together and reviewed all of
the literature that's available and this
is what they decided not me there is
conclusive or substantial evidence that
cannabis and cannabinoids cannabis in
this case is cannabis cannabinoids in
this case are synthetic pharmaceuticals
or plant-based pharmaceuticals such as
abba dialects or sativex conclusive
evidence for the treatment of chronic
pain antiemetic improvement of patient
reported multiple sclerosis spasticity
simps symptoms oral cannabinoids there
is moderate evidence that cannabis or
cannabinoids are effective for improving
short-term sleep outcomes and
individuals with sleep disturbances now
you will see that there's also a lot of
limited evidence that cannabis and
cannabinoids are effective for THC for
Tourette syndrome limited evidence that
it is effective for traumatic brain
injury brain injury intracranial
hemorrhage limited evidence that
cannabis are effective symptoms in a
fact that for improving symptoms
associated with dementia and so on so
there is definitely proof that it works
there's also inconclusive evidence and I
think again we just need more science
and more studies one thing to keep in
mind of course when we talk about
addiction is addiction is a very complex
process it's a it's intertwined with
many different things but if we look
cannabis addiction cannabis has the
highest scores which is less addictive
than caffeine according to Benowitz
ratings here so the higher the score the
less addictive is the substance and you
can see that nicotine is a lot more
addictive than marijuana and marijuana
can be less addictive than caffeine
so yesterday politician said that
cannabis should not be consumed this
coffee and I just wanted to ask why
because it causes a different
intoxicating effect but not from the
safety standpoint so from the safety
standpoint marijuana here the lower the
number on this side and the lower the
plant or a substance is on there on the
y-axis the lower it's on the y-axis the
less dependency potential there is the
lower the number on the x-axis that
means that those okay so this is the
active dose and lethal dose if it is one
to one that means that active dose
something that eliminates your pain also
kills you it's a lethal dose with
cannabis it's point zero zero one which
is thousand times of the active dose so
if one rolled joint gets you high you
need to consume about a thousand in a
matter of few minutes which is
impossible it is easier to do it with
caffeine which is only a hundred times
more of the effective dose and it is of
course a big problem with other drugs
including opiates and morphine where
only ten times the dose including
alcohol only ten times of the effective
dose is lethal from safety perspective
cannabis could be argued that it is
safer than caffeine now we have a lot of
overdoses from
benzodiazepines these are epilepsy drugs
mostly and you can see the rise in these
and there is thousands of deaths from
thousand deaths in 2000 to 2015
five to six thousand deaths from
benzodiazepines pharmaceuticals we have
very high morbidity and mortality rate
from opiates
so seventy three point eight of all
prescription overdose deaths were due to
opioid pain relievers opr it's a study
published by CDC OPR sales nonetheless
quadrupled between 99 and 2010 and it
cost insurance about seventy two point
four u.s. dollars in u.s. annually in
health care so this is a report 2011
since then I think we had a rise in
opioid epidemic and I think these
numbers would probably look even worse
at this stage now deaths from cannabis
zero reported deaths from cannabis
opiates of course are used for the
treatment of chronic pains ear pain and
I looked at one of the studies a
prominent study a Journal of pain
research in 2017 a cross-sectional study
of 2,800 approximately individuals and
they showed that about 12 48 of these
individuals 48% respondents reported
using cannabis as a substitute for
prescription drugs and the most common
cases classes of drugs substituted are
narcotics
about 36% ng Linux or benzyl taxes and
depressants this is what the patients
report themselves so it's not a very
stringent study but it is something that
is being reported self-reported by
patients and it is looking really
substantial this is not the only study
but I don't have time to go over other
pain studies there's another pain study
in Canada that showed a similar result
of people dropping opiates and switching
to cannabinoids now in the plant again
we not only have cannabinoids different
set of cannabinoids but we also have
terpenes terpenes are the aromatic
lipophilic molecules is what gives
cannabis a different smell a different
strain of cannabis smells differently
one may smell like lemon because it has
lye money
another may smell like lavender because
it has wine Elul as the terpene in the
plant these aromatic molecules they
easily cross blood-brain barrier so when
you inhale terpenes through your nose it
actually goes into your olfactory system
and crosses through the blood-brain
barrier it is not just smell it actually
has a logical and physiological effect
and if we look here D lineman E is being
used as potent anti-cancer anxiolytics
and immuno stimulation immunostimulant
beta Mersin which is found in hoppin
mango is potent anti-inflammatory alpha
pi9 is at the top cholinesterase
inhibitor or sin which acts in the same
way as Alzheimer's medications do which
are at sattell cholinesterase inhibitors
for the most part except for memantine
and line Alou has analgesic anxiolytics
and anti-inflammatory anticonvulsant
properties so these molecules are
biological and physiologically active
better carrier filling is probably one
of my favorites it has anti-inflammatory
and gastric cytoprotective activities as
well as it serves a Seabee to selective
agonist these terpenes are not just
found in cannabis and beta carrier
filling is very prominent in hops for
example it is also very prominent in
Lithuanian hemp and the products
actually that we we have here made from
Lithuanian hemp I'll tell you about them
in a minute they're loaded naturally
with better carrier filling so there are
certain strains that will have a lot of
better cure filling which is CBT
receptor agonist again it's involved in
mune system modulation and it's very
important to keep that in mind so
because of these different smells we
have what we call the anther artifact so
first you smell things and it has a
certain Association for you it's a
pleasant association it's a good memory
or maybe it's something that you should
stay away from
so first u.s. tomato of cannabis flower
especially by smell and by look but it
doesn't mean that that's going either
physiological effect that it causes
because it all depends on the components
and molecules that are found in
cannabis and their groupings now the
names are kind of interesting this has
been challenged gorilla glue I think
it's out now let's be really glue off
the market but you know what I find
really interesting and I think it hurts
the market is when fun names introduce
like purple monkey balls and I think
that that's kind of a wrong approach and
that's what makes gifts cannabis
industry a little bit of a bad rap and
that's that's a problem I think the
strains should indicate something about
the condition something about the field
least in some way associate with the
source with the location where it was
grown but not just some crazy name
because a lot of younger people would go
for it and I think it just for everybody
so cannabis entourage effect comes from
the sum total of synergistic as well as
antagonistic effects remember CBD
slightly antagonistic to THC effects
multiple targets throughout the body by
a collection of terpenes and when
terpenes and cannabinoids come together
they kind of a work in unison in one
fashion they facilitate absorption or
delivery of active ingredients the
counteract or minimize adverse side
effects and whole plant vital
cannabinoid extract compared to phyto
cannabinoid isolates will have a lot of
phyto cannabinoids and the isolate is
just a single fighter cannabinoid that
has been isolated now and the
cannabinoids and cannabinoids are not
just found in cannabis so an and amide
and all the amide are funded chocolate
you should challenge every person that
doesn't know about cannabinoids or
cannabis by telling them do you know
that you eight cannabinoids today or
last night I see no I didn't how can I
have done that I didn't do it I don't do
these things but you eat chocolate right
you love chocolate so you got some
cannabinoids in it and people are very
surprised truffles also having the
cannabinoids so we're people are crazy
about certain foods people will pay a
lot of money for truffles a lot of money
for chocolate and is it all just because
of the taste I have to wonder
so now we come to the human body in
human body processes this information in
different ways and there is a multitude
of products that go through the human
body and so let's talk about different
products and maybe I'm going to jump a
couple of slides if you don't mind we
can talk about now that we understand
different components such as isolates
such as extracts we want to reconstruct
cannabis into houses into CBD oil into
protein powder into food and everything
that cannabis has to offer so let's look
at these slides and make sure we
understand this that smoking cannabis is
probably not the best thing actually
vaporizing cannabis is better all
ingestion of cannabis you have
sublingually and swallowing you have
topical liniments of cannabis and you
also have suppositories they all have
very different effect in the use of
these cannabinoids and cannabis products
will have a very different effect on the
individual and that's important to keep
in mind another important thing to keep
in mind and warn ourselves about is
metabolism so THC gets metabolized and
it gets metabolized into 1108 Delta 9
THC and then through the secondary
metabolism it turns into Delta 9 THC 11
oleic acid this 11 Olek acid has nothing
to do with acidic cannabinoids that are
found in the plant but this 11 oeq acid
is actually a more stronger and toxicant
than THC and that's why people have
problems with edibles when they're used
to inhaling or smoking cannabis and
getting the effect from that immediately
they expect the same when they try there
first edible side the airport in Denver
and half an hour later they said well
I'm not feeling anything so let me pop a
couple more and by the time they pop a
couple more this 11 Olek acid is already
built up and it is now acting as a
double or triple intoxicant on top of
the new THC coming into your body with
additional gummy bear candies that you
consumed so that's very important to
keep in mind that the metabolism of the
body is very important so the other way
that we view cannabis is mostly we talk
about medicinal cannabis and smoking
I believe that cannabis and cannabinoids
will find their way into the food chain
they'll find their way into the plates
and micro dosing of cannabis can be
found in the feed animal feed and that
animal feed and through the whole
process it can find itself on our food
supply chain on our tables
therefore to reconstruct cannabis we
have to understand and reconstruct the
products we have to understand the state
of the under cannabinoid system
metabolic profiles psychological state
drug and drug interactions we have to
create products and then know that
recommending these products the doctors
go by start low go slow philosophy that
you have to know those who just safety
efficacy pollutants that are present
there undoubtedly third party test
results and clinical studies before
these parties can find their way into
doctors nurses health care practitioners
and be recommended either's food food
supplement or medical cannabis products
so all of these are very important now
we also have to know that there are
contraindications that cannabis again is
not for everybody
psychosis use of strains with minimal or
no THC content is recommended and
bipolar disease there's an association
between cannabis misuse and earlier
onset of bipolar eight percent of
general population is cannabis allergic
and there is a multitude of drug and
drug interactions that happen through
metabolism with cytochrome this is
something very important this is
metabolism antiepileptic drugs that is
taken from project CBD and basically
what these lines are showing that if you
combine any one of these bars any one of
these drugs with CBD the amount of that
from a suitable drug in the blood can
mostly increase in some cases it will
decrease but in many cases it will
increase and that's important to know
because you're essentially by occupying
the cytochrome p which metabolizes CBD
and gives CBD priority now does not
metabolize the pharmaceutical drugs
therefore there is a buildup of
pharmaceutical substances in the body
that can be twice three times the
concentrations can
- serious problems liver problems liver
compromise as well as other effects now
cannabis of course we have different
preparations the best way to consume
cannabis is through inhaling is
vaporization it's control temperature
cannabis flower vapor and pan can be
used for vaporization concentrate oil or
wax wax vaporization is often preferred
and that's because trichomes that
contain the cannabinoids and the
terpenes that I told you they will melt
away before the plant matter or the
leaves and the buds will burn there is
less carbon monoxide heat and there is
no smoke and somebody will say why would
you ever want to inhale cannabis let me
ask you this question where do we have
the most surface area to absorb things
into our bodies lungs the second place
is suppositories anal vaginal they
bypass the metabolism of the liver they
get absorbed directly through the lungs
into the bloodstream or into the
bloodstream through the suppositories
and there immediately into the blood
where they can cross blood-brain barrier
therefore inhaling something can be very
helpful for people that suffer from
certain conditions we also have to
understand that there are isolates that
look like powder and it will almost look
like a synthetic right but it is not it
is not a synthetic it is actually an
isolate from the plant that's what a lot
of people ask me wait a second so it's
isolate the same as synthetic
cannabinoids where you will you take and
mix things together and then you get
this powder no it's processing of the
plant is extracting the plant separating
the molecules where you can get an
isolate less such a CBD or THC isolate
some of the products are all that means
that there is non decarboxylated and
they will contain a Siddha cannabinoids
and many products are being
decarboxylated so it's important to pay
attention are these raw products or they
have been decarboxylated you're getting
a different profile of the cannabinoids
in these products there's many oils that
are being produced most of the tinctures
though but
refer to tinctures with alcohol but many
oils are being used as carriers for
either isolates or for the extracts
themselves such as olive oil coconut oil
hemp seed oil and glycerin and as well
there is form of capsules that can be
found so many different products many
different uses you have to know the test
results you have to know what is inside
the products you have to know where
they're sourced where they came from how
they were made and how they found their
way on the Shelf so for us to have
individualized cannabinoid preparations
which i think is really necessary they
have to be individualized for a certain
condition and they have to be
individualized for a certain individual
because that individual with a certain
condition may be taking different drugs
may be having a different metabolic
turnover so we need to standardize the
grows and the product to standardize the
grows the biggest challenge is you have
to have complete control of inputs that
is going into the plant and complete
control of outputs you have to scan the
plant measure the plant so that you can
capture the same output chemical output
of the plant cycle after cycle which is
a big challenge to my knowledge nobody
has done it if I am wrong please correct
me but there is no standardized output
from the the same strain grown by the
same grower the same conditions to
growth
thirty forty percent in the composition
of terpenes especially terpenes are
evolved by stress so it's a natural way
for the plant to protect itself and
terpenes and cannabinoids they fluctuate
during the girl's cycle they go up and
down so it's important to capture the
part of the cycle and the part of doubt
that is standardized what you saw in
your previous growth cycle so now you
have the standardized grow and
standardized plant now you have to
standardize the products make sure that
the products are always the same you
have to then analyze databases and here
that you trace the patients that are
using are they getting good effects or
not so analyzing databases are going to
be very important gathering that
information we have to pay attention to
liver metabolism and compromise of liver
for high levels of CBD can compromise
liver function milligrams of CBD taken
together with some of these anti
epileptic drugs warfarin for example
will increase also but a blood thinner
and also we have to think about a lot of
drugs that we're using essentially so
liberalism is very important and then
drug and drug interactions as the liver
metabolizes these is also very important
so in my opinion science anything goes
in science and you can really pave the
way of the future you can have bright
ideas you can dive in the deepest oceans
or look at the highest mountains to find
and pave the way and there is a facts
and these facts need to be taken into
consideration their industry needs
education industry needs a lot of
Education I think that the biggest
bottleneck in Germany right now is the
healthcare practitioners and medical
doctors because they do not understand
the products that are in the pharmacies
they do understand why certain strains
should be used over another certain
strain why may be low THC should be
recommended with somebody that has
inclinations or indications of psychosis
so there has to be a major D Sigma ties
ation of cannabis which can only happen
through education and of course in
medicine to reach that medical point to
standardized the can ASSU tickles and
chemistry
are different from pharmaceuticals it's
a dime change so we all have to get used
to the reality and how to interpret this
paradigm change in the existing systems
so hemp cannabis saves lives and heals
people and animals so what are you
waiting for and it's not just for you of
course most of you here know what you're
waiting for
but what are other people waiting for
what are other politicians waiting for
the facts are in front of them the
reality is in front of them wanted to
say is meetings like this are really
great because still when we were at this
meeting we came together with people
that came from different parts of the
world we met outside the meeting then we
met inside the meeting and I'm happy to
tell you that version of this meeting
dear girl is a new brand that our
company that the Taurus is launching its
Florence and if you stop by you can see
the variety of products that we produce
with hemp a CBD in the United States as
well as in Lithuania in Europe so these
meetings and Alex organizing these
meetings and all of the guys and the
ladies promoting the networking is
really valuable I'm very happy to be
here again and I think I here because we
formed the Restonic partnership and it's
also nice when you find the right people
and the right partners where you can
move things forward in the desired
fashion so these are our partners for
Florence Mehta tours and thank you very
much for your attention one more time
dr. Jay Z yes sir deep we have time
maybe for one one question question
maybe closer to me
dr. Z Z why does some people not feel
CBD immediately I've come across
right away what is it people that need
that there are they require different
dosages so III know you as a person that
asks the toughest questions in the
audience
and this is
perhaps my answer would be what are you
supposed to feel with CBD because people
are used to feeling intoxicating effect
with THC so the first few times they
they take it and there's a certain
feeling maybe I should be feeling
something like high or intoxicated but
that's not the case and if you have no
problems if you have no anxiety if you
have no pain if you have no nausea acid
reflux or gastric problems you may not
feel that effective CBD interestingly
enough the doctors in the United States
are now suggested prophylactic use of
CBD every day of about 3 to 5 milligrams
a day again for what reason
potentially to tame the the increase in
inflammation and the aging that happens
just normally in our bodies so it's a
great question I'm sorry I don't have a
definitive answer for you on the other
hand it definitely probably has to do
with metabolism
some people might metabolize it much
faster so they need higher doses and
also I had a similar question where
somebody's me on a smoked THC I can't
get high and I smoke so much of it and I
smoke a concentrated and still can't get
high and then I said well did you ever
get high and said oh yeah I had these
edibles and knocked me out and it
occurred to me that maybe the receptor
that that lady had is not properly
structured to teach see doesn't bind to
that receptor but 11 all week teetsi
acid the secondary metabolites of liver
now has a huge intoxicating effect on
the person so thank you thank you thank
you very much more time dr. Jay Z I'm
sure they'd be happy to answer more
questions hallway