this is the man who is responsible for
virtually all of the cannabis research
we wouldn't be able to do any of the
research that we're doing now if it
weren't for him he's first synthesized
and isolated the THC the CBD the CBG all
of that stuff we wouldn't know anything
about it if it weren't for him and he's
gonna come up and talk to us right now
please
everyone put your hands together and
welcome to the stage the one and only
dr. Rafael Messi lab thank you for
inviting me I'll try the LA next
half-hour to tell you about a little bit
about what went on what's going on and
what I hope will happen in the next few
years when I started research on
cannabis and that was quite a few years
ago nobody was interested as a matter of
fact when I asked for a grant I was told
a grant from NIH in the US I was told
nobody smokes marijuana in the States
and they do that in Mexico we think if
you have something more relevant kindly
let us know well they change their mind
so shortly afterwards somebody important
maybe a senator had asked him what does
Barry wanna do his son was caught
smoking pot and he wanted to know where
he destroys his mind or something and
they didn't have a single grand I didn't
know anything about marijuana so they
when they came over to Jerusalem at that
time and took the THC we had isolated
and
elucidated the structure I think they
smuggled it back because they didn't
have a license to do that and for the
next few years most of the work in THC
in the States was done with the material
that was apparently smoked
things have changed nature one of the
major scientific journals in the world
had a few reviews and this is from our
reviewer they put on the first thing a
brain from which cannabis comes out and
the reason for that is in the next slide
a few scientists at NIH and NIH does a
lot of research on cannabis nowadays
they wrote that modulating the
endocannabinoid activity may have
therapeutic potential in almost all
diseases affecting humans and they give
a lot of examples now this is a very
very strong statement I don't know if
any other biochemical system that is
involved in almost all diseases
affecting humans and while it may not be
hundred percent true it is close to the
truth and I'll try to explain why and
how this happens but let's start a few
years back in my area of the world
Assyria and we have a lot of documents
left from that time they wrote a lot of
them and stone and so on they used they
used cannabis for essentially all those
things that we use cannabis they said
that they had a name Gansey goo knew
that's the drug that takes away the bind
it's not about definition where they
thought there was the as a loop of the
same plant which was used as a medicine
apparently for neurological diseases
we're not so sure and they also use it
in their religious rites so it cannabis
as we all know has been used more or
less over the next couple of thousand
years and I'll just give another example
dr. Russell Reynolds who was the
physician of Queen Victoria in England
used to import cannabis from India
European cannabis was not good enough
for him
because she had migraines and he didn't
write that in his paper but it was
obvious because she was the only patient
he had for the relief of certain kinds
of pain I believe there is no more
useful medicine than cannabis then a lot
of research started the middle of this
century we were involved and I would
like to separate the research that has
been going on in three phases the first
one is the phytochemistry name in the
chemistry of the plant now most of the
people that are involved in cannabis are
involved in the phyto cannabinoid
research on the materials the compounds
that the plant produces but this is
these are things that we learnt the
describe try to investigate about 30
years ago since then things have been
happening
first of all the endocannabinoid
research namely research and the
compounds and the cannabinoids that we
make that all mammalians do and this was
small as completed about 10 years ago
and since then we have gone into the
third phase of cannabinoid research and
this is compounds that are more or less
the same as the compounds we produce but
they have different effects so we have a
whole system whole a lot of compounds
that are very very much involved in our
physiology and while now at the moment
most people are interested in
cannabidiol and THC chances are as it
happened to it cannabidiol where he
tried to wait for about 30 years chances
are that in a meeting like that in about
15 years of now most of the talks will
be under endogenous cannabinoids and
under cannabinoids have that have more
the same structure but have different
effects so let me try to go into the
three phases of research that I'm
speaking about those of you who haven't
forgotten their high school chemistry
these are some of the compounds that are
present in cannabis and we discovered
most of them about 50 years ago 40 years
ago and all of them mol is the same the
right hand side is exactly the same
there have been some differences may
have discovered C's with mole as the
same on the left hand side that the
changes and we have today more than
hundred compounds of this type but the
two compounds that most people have been
interested in are of course
cannabidiol and we described the
structure of cannabidiol way back 1963
and we are isolated I believe for the
first time in pure form the act of the
active compound THC and elucidated the
structure later synthesize it so these
two compounds have been of course the
center of interest and those of you who
are involved in cannabis in cannabis
whether it's in research or in the
industrial or commercial aspects deal
mostly with these two compounds but
these compounds are not natural products
the natural products are their acids the
plant makes THC acid
cannabidiol acid these are the compounds
that the plant makes we described the
many many years ago and synthesized them
but we never tested them for a simple
reason these compounds are not stable
the acids break down very easily so
there hasn't been a lot of work on the
contrary to cannot be dialed and the
reason is they are not stable so if
somebody does research on them who knows
what they are doing the research on is
that on the acid or is something that
they had the the acid has broken down so
very few people who are interested in
the acids they're just a few papers not
too many now I thought we thought in the
lab that maybe he assets are important
by themselves but they're so we had to
stabilize them and by a simple chemical
reaction we stabilized them and made a
methyl ester whether the chemist amongst
you will know what it is
we made a methyl esters of these
compounds and the methyl esters turn out
to be stable completely stable so we
could analyze we could identify the
activity of these compounds and we've
been working on cannabidiol acid it
turns out it cannot be done acid is in
those studies that we have undertaken so
far it is more potent than cannabidiol
itself so chances are that slowly to a
certain extent never fully but slowly
cannabidiol as it as it methyl ester
will parallel cannot be dialed in its
activity because in many aspects it's
much more active and this is the
structure of it those of you who
remember chemistry will say that it's
the material ester and for example we
have already published that this
cannabidiol acid if which is most stable
reduces depression-like behavior in two
models of animal depression of course we
cannot go into humans because of
regulations one has to go into animals
to a large extent and even if they are
natural product they have to be
investigated for toxicity and other
things but if we assume that most of the
things we see in animals in animal
models the parallel human models then
this compound can be dialed acid methyl
ester will show activity stronger than
CBD itself we have a publication in
press which shows that
cannabidiol methyl ester is more potent
in in pain Louis pain to a much larger
extent we have seen as a slide shows
depression we have seen a few other
things and these will be published over
the next few years maybe over the next
few months so don't be surprised in
cannabidiol methyl ester starts
replacing cannabidiol slowly as the
natural cannabidiol of importance it
does not cause the THC effects another
effect that has gained interest is the
home to harsh effect we found and it has
been of course confirmed by many many
people both in animals and in humans
that some of the effects of THC of
cannabinoids it in quite a few
cannabinoids some of the effects are
potentiated by compounds that by
themselves had no activity but they
potentiate the activity of THC and we
call this down to Roger effect and
although it doesn't one does not see
that in all effects of THC or all
effects cannabinoids
many of the effects have this entourage
effect so things become very complicated
if somebody wants to put THC as an
extract of CBD is an extract one has
also to know what are the compounds that
are present there together with these
two compounds so we can have a sample
that contains a certain percentage of
these central compounds and another one
that has the same percentage at the
other activities are somewhat different
so we shall have to develop
we shall have to develop analytical
procedures at least for most of the
compounds that are present in cannabis
in order to explain the active
and not to sell compounds with a certain
percentage another compound another
extract with the same percentage and yet
they are quite different we have to show
ultimately what are the rest of the
compounds of some of the rest of the
compounds that are around so this is
down to Rutherford and we have to take
into account and to rouse effects all
the time now okay a few words about THC
yeah most of you are aware of that has
to do with pain in nausea vomitting
sleep anxiety appetite quite a few other
things and Cathy 8 years you know has
been a found a approved by many of them
bodies in many countries in the US and
other countries and it is a approved
drug a minor drug and the reason for
that is that people prefer the extract
possibly because of the entourage effect
rather than THC itself so THC has been
on the market not a major drug I've been
told that it's sold in the u.s. between
100 and 200 million dollars which for a
major drug is nowhere there one thing
that people have not investigated very
thoroughly is depression and THC shows
significantly antidepressant effect but
the other compounds like cannot be Roman
for example show the same effect a
little bit at higher doses but they show
the same effect so we should know what's
being sold exactly whether it is THC but
it's cannabis Roman or whether it's
other things now cannabis chroming maybe
not exactly the activist THC but it
doesn't call the side effect so maybe
people will be selling cannabis Roman
because of the lack of side effects that
people in pain don't want and we have
published the THC is also pretty
important in post round
we know that post trauma patients take
cannabis in order to lower the effects
of puffs trauma we went ahead indeed a
clinical trial and found that indeed low
amounts of THC which do not cause the hi
may help postural patients we had a
group of about 12 patients a few
soldiers a few women that had been raped
a few patients that had PTSD because of
car accident and we found it in
essentially all the effects of post
trauma THC helped in the effect didn't
disappear they were easier to go around
with and the best effect wasn't sleep
post trauma patients do not sleep well
they are afraid to go to sleep because
in the middle of the night I wake up
with a trauma happening again and that's
why they are afraid to go to sleep at
they don't sleep well well we found that
with THC low doses they they sleep much
better and this is one of the reasons
post trauma patients do take cannabis
but let's go on with this
cannabidiol actions and of course I'll
start with epilepsy because it has been
approved now this is a paper you can see
that we published 1980 which is almost
40 years ago we found when initials in
collaboration with colleagues and
friends in South America we found in
animals as was previously noted in the
literature for 2000 years that cannabis
Watson epilepsy so we looked at
cannabidiol in first in animals and then
went to humans we did that and about 12
patients or 15 patients and we saw that
in most of the patients it affected
positively
the epilepsy most of them had very few
attacks a few had
much less attacks and only one was not
affected so we published that and we
thought that maybe maybe it will be used
that people will do larger trials and it
will be introduced as a drug nothing
happened for almost 30 years then pair
of parents in the u.s. discovered that
plants containing large amounts of
cannabidiol help with the epilepsy of
their children and children sometimes
have terrible epilepsies 20 attacks a
day or something and but the kappa b
dial helped and they were going to one
of the states where kind of when
cannabis was legal and maybe some of
them had known about a paper now why did
we have to wait for 30 years
thousands of children thousands of
patients could have been helped
definitely children but because of
possibly legal problems possibly of
other problems
nobody had taken up the information that
was in the literature now a once parents
saw that cannabis with a lot of
cannabidiol helps there was a pressure
on the US authorities and a big trial
was approved in the US it's very
difficult to get kind of clinical trials
with cannabis but this one was approved
because of social pressure and it turned
out to be extremely positive with
parallel what we did but it was done in
children was the need in hundreds of
children and now cannabidiol under the
name of hepa dialects is approved as a
drug in epilepsy why why was that done
thirty years ago
we we had found that cannabidiol is
active in outer immune diseases how the
immune diseases or diseases and which
the body for many reasons some of which
we don't know attacks itself and there
are a lot of outer immune disease is now
a disease which is close to the outer
immune diseases is the graft-versus-host
disease sometimes in cancer patients the
bone marrow has to be replaced and when
the bone marries replaced the body
doesn't like it and it may attack it and
the bone marrow itself may attacked
about it and the patient suffers
sometimes suffers very very much but
this is essentially how to immune
reaction so a colleague of mine dr.
Yasser hoon went ahead the collaboration
we had went ahead and started giving
pure cannabidiol to patients with
graft-versus-host disease and he was
very glad to note that yes in most of
the patients which had a relatively mild
disease then this is called the two to
four great disease 40% previously had
graft-versus-host disease when they were
taking cannabidiol this went down to 12%
those that had a real real bad disease
GVHD
which was previously 10% and a few even
died went down to about 5% so here we
have an a drug cannabidiol which can be
used in this anti-cancer treatment and
it is being developed as a drug a
company has is going ahead with the CBD
and GVHD and if I think it's now in
Phase two and chances are it will be in
phase three shortly so let's hope that
within a year or two
we shall have a drug CBD as a potent GBH
drug which there are no drugs other
drugs at a moment
now this schizophrenia now I mentioned
that because it was developed mostly in
Germany we had shown again with my good
friends in South America that it helps
in a very few patients we've published
that many years ago we had given CBD to
a young woman who had terrible
schizophrenia and it helped her over
three months and never came in Germany
decided to go head and he made a
relatively large or larger trial and he
gave it to patients that nothing was
helping them anymore schizophrenic
patients and he found that CBD was an
excellent drug he compared it to one of
the drugs that are already being used I
am if sulfide so pride and this drug
which is a good drug has side effects
now cannabidiol and the drugs are
already being used have the same
activity except that cannabidiol cause
no side effects many schizophrenic
patients don't want to take that and
histories of Renick drugs because of the
side effects chances are that
cannabidiol can be can replace these
drugs unfortunately the amounts of
cannabidiol are very high about 800
milligrams per day that's quite high but
maybe just maybe with the new drugs what
I was studying about a methyl ester we
can go down to much lower doses so these
are developing that we shall see in the
future but I hope that even now
schizophrenic patients will be
administered cannabidiol the amounts are
very high about 800 milligrams a day but
it is definitely worth it and chances
are that cannabidiol will be approved as
a drug again schizophrenia I'm not sure
that it is approved in any country at
the moment I know that in Israel it is
being discussed
we're having a meeting next week with
the heads of the Ministry of Health and
I'm trying to push
cannabidiol as a anti schizophrenic drug
this is what I was telling you about
that cannabidiol was compared to a me so
pride and it also causes some of them
it's better in some of the side effects
it causes less weight gain it causes no
changes in estrogen and testosterone and
it causes a lot of the different effect
that the unpleasant effect that the
present drug and so pride is causing so
we have probably well I believe that we
shall have cannabidiol Zante
schizophrenia drug within the next year
or two and these are some of the
symptoms that the present drug causes it
caused because muscle spasms can cause
slowness of movement tremor and some
other unpleasant types
now one thing another disease that we've
been working on is diabetes type 1 again
it is an autoimmune disease the body for
reason that we don't know attacks those
cells that produce insulin and the
patient usually that's seen in children
so diabetes type 1 is a pediatric
disease these children don't have enough
insulin and they're sick sometimes very
sick we found that the cannabidiol is
extremely helpful and in animals at
least we have not done that in humans we
don't have the permits yet we have seen
that in animals only 5% of the cells
that produce insulin remain intact those
that are given cannabidiol we see that
77% of the cells that produce insulin
remain intact so here we have a major
improvement and unfortunately although
we publish that quite a few years ago
this disease has not been for this
treatment for the disease has not been
looked to into in humans why we can't do
everything and apparently very few
people are interested although it is a
major disease and a disease from which
quite a few particularly children suffer
so any of you has enough pressure in
your countries to have an diabetes type
one clinical trial with people
cannabidiol go ahead now Oh almost all
drugs from natural products are sold not
as the drugs and themselves but as the
derivative and the reason for that are
the reasons quite a lot first of all on
the natural product the patent is not
very strong and by making a small small
derivative of chemical derivative
usually one can get more potent
compounds and compounds that are better
from in many ways for example today you
cannot buy insulin
you cannot buy penicillin as such you
can buy a derivative of penicillin in a
drugstore or let's go into cortisone
another major homo you cannot buy
cortisone in a drug store you can buy
derivatives of cortisone and these
derivatives may be sold about five or
six billion dollars a year so chances
are that cannot be died within the next
few years will be on the market is a
derivative not that cannabidiol itself
but as a derivative and here is a
derivative that we have published and a
company is developing it and this
derivative is a peril of the activity of
CBD that is somewhat more potent so
chances are that in the near future or
the distant future we shall have both
cannabidiol and
derivatives now let me go into the face
- of cannabis research and this is the
compound that we make ourselves for many
reasons and some of the reasons we
brought into the literature it was
obvious that cannabidiol acts on
something in the body such as
specifically which may be a receptor and
so a group in the u.s. found the
receptor protein in the body that THC
binds to it and it starts all the
reactions so but we don't have receptors
because there is a plant out there we
have receptors because we make compounds
that will stimulate these receptors so
we went ahead looking for compounds and
this receptor was found in all these
places that you can see called basal
ganglia all these places that have to do
with movement control and movement
coordination and cognitive function all
these things that people know happen
with THC so this receptor was obviously
important and central so we started
looking for the compounds that we make
or animals make that activated
paralleled the activity of THC and after
quite a lot of work
we found two compounds one of them we
called the nand amide and the second one
is known as 2 AG which are chemically
completely different but have the same
activity and the same the same activity
s THC you can see if you're forgotten
your chemistry did these two compounds
and an amide into AG which animals
produce and we produce completely
different chemically from THC but they
have the same physical properties there
are lipid they dissolve only in lipids
not in water they bind to the same
receptor and so on so Ananda might and
to AG have been discussed widely in the
literature there's thousands of
publications on
Anandi might and 2ag and these compounds
are central in the so called
endocannabinoid system which consists of
the receptors there two of them the two
compounds the enzymes that break down
the compound these compound Oh help us
synthesize them and of course the 18
cannabidiol so there has been a lot of
theoretical work or work that has very
little relation to marketing and so on
for a simple reason although we
discovered Ananda mite and a little bit
later to AG and nanda byte has never
never been administered to a human and
again because of mostly legal reasons
it's not toxic it's made by the body if
we compare that with let's say insulin
insulin was discovered 200 years ago and
in Canada and within six months it
became a drug within a year it became a
drug very useful drug even today people
use insulin as a drug Morris now why
Ananda might which has outstanding
medical properties never been used legal
reasons patent problems and so on so
this is strange because we know in
schizophrenia for example when
cannabidiol is administered the main
effect is that Ananda might
concentrations go up and if Ananda might
concentrations go up maybe it is Ananda
by that's helping not cannabidiol but a
nanomite indirectly there are many other
diseases that an endermite has to do so
it's unbelievable but it has never been
given to a human and now in animals it
has been looked the endocannabinoid
system and it has been found to be
involved in a huge number of
physiological effects starting from
anxiety and appetite this and so on and
so forth we can see the mood movement
stress if I were to prepare a new slide
this is a slide of two years ago I would
have
twice as many physiological things
happening so it is extremely important
and chances are that at some point an
endermite or a derivative of an
endermite will become a drug I'll give
you just two examples the
neuroprotection
we tried with a colleague vows to see
whether these compounds are involved in
Europe protection and we tried out that
person and he must I don't believe that
anybody any the a of our friends would
have volunteered to have some kind of
brain attack as we didn't pull mice and
we saw that after such a when they were
given a small attack on the brain not a
very strong one as a matter of fact
within a couple of weeks they went back
to be completely normal
we saw the two AG one of the two
endocannabinoids goes up tremendously
now he's dead because the brain being
damaged didn't know what was doing was
that some kind of a protection so we
synthesized a lot of to AG and gave to
animals and compared to animals that not
given to AG and we saw that yes the two
AG one of the endocannabinoids is a
potent protectant if we gave that to the
people to know how to look at these
things in the brain and we saw that in
the controls we had a certain amount of
damage the white part that you see those
that were given to AG the
endocannabinoid had 50% less so probably
at some point to AG will be developed as
a drug against brain damage there is no
drug at the moment quite a few people
get kind that kind of damage and there
is nothing to do with that I mean there
are no drugs available today that can
help
now one thing that has been found quite
recently again in note no South America
is that cb1 receptors are not only known
to to be of two to lower anxiety but
quite a few of the drugs that we use
today
and we are not sure of their activity or
we have wrongly assigned some of their
activity is due to the end to the
cannabinoid system and there is for
example xanax alprazolam which is an
anti-anxiety drug a well-known widely
used actually it works to the
cannabinoid receptors so this is the
case chances are that people will
develop additional drugs in this respect
now I mentioned that there are two
receptors cb1 and cb2 this activation of
the cb1 receptor causes the well-known
THC activities the high and so on
the second one the cb2 is does not cause
it is it is a protective receptor and I
know some companies in Switzerland at
least one company is developing drugs
based on the second receptor that does
not cause these side-effects which are
not of importance to pharmaceutical
company they act only in the cb2
receptor not on the cb1 receptor and
acting on in the cb2 receptor with
compound that we have made a compound
that the companies have made these cb2
receptors are involved in a huge number
of protective mechanisms in heart
problems in atherosclerosis in pain
neurodegenerative diseases again if
these companies succeed in producing
compounds and evaluating them chances
are that we shall have drugs that
are not CBD are not THC but are based on
cb2 receptors but I don't have the time
to go into that because people a long
time here are compounds that have that
are specifically acting in the CB 2 and
so this is a few words on the endogenous
cannabinoids system which is phase 2 of
research at present we are working on
phase 3 and phase 3 research is
something else entirely
I mentioned the nanda might those of you
who are chemists will see that the nanda
might is a throughout a simple compound
it is a fatty acid bound to an amino
acid we have about 20 fatty acids and
about 20 amino acids in our body
now the power body is lazy if it knows
how to make an endermite taking a fatty
acid and binding it to an amino acid why
not take the other fatty acids in the
other amino acids and make additional
compound make use of them so it won't
have to spend energy those are he has
the machinery to do that and yes we
found that this is exactly what's
happening how did we go into that we saw
that in brain injury there is a brain
injury part of the brain injury causes
effects and all kinds of transmitters
motivated so on and ultimately it causes
neuronal and cell death but and these
are the things I was telling you
previously but it also causes brain
injury can cause vasoconstriction the
blood vessels constrict this is not
healthy so the body tries to prevent
that and we saw that cannabis extract of
cannabis or can help with that and if we
take the brain or another animal and
extract it and give it it also helps
with the vasoconstriction so there is a
compound in our body which helps with
vasoconstriction and so we
in the head looking for that we didn't
know that the it has to anything that we
tend to cannabinoids we just went ahead
looking for the compounds it could be
anything and after quite a lot of work
we found that our body helps with vessel
dilation by making a third compound like
can and amide but it does not cause any
of the effects of an endermite it just
helps with a vasoconstriction it dilates
the blood vessels so this is something
that our body makes in order to prevent
vasoconstriction which is due to brain
damage if we block this system the brain
damage is much much higher so here we
have a drug a cannabinoid cannabinoid
like drug which has to do with
vasoconstriction vasodilation and again
I repeat myself all the time maybe there
will be it will be used as a drug but
this is not the only thing another thing
that happens is with bones again we this
was a research project which we didn't
think has anything to do it cannabinoids
the background of our work and bones was
that it was well known it was known that
women after the age of 50 55 when all
the hormones had changed and when all
the hormones don't work the way they did
previously women should have a lot of
osteoporosis which they do most of them
but the osteoporosis in women in a
Mediterranean region is much lower than
the osteoporosis in in the note in no
way let's say or even in the Berlin now
we thought why what's the reason and
there is a suggestion in the literature
that this is because of the olive oil
that's being used around the
Mediterranean so we looked at the olive
oil and he didn't do any
thing but maybe we said it's a
derivative so derivative in our body
makes and we were quite a lot on and
this project and ultimately we found it
yes our body makes a compound which is
closely related chemically to Ananda
mite which again is strange we didn't
expect anything like that we thought
that that's a completely different
research problem but we saw that our
body women's body of course produces the
compound closely related to an and amide
and it blocks or stoper OSIS not
completely but it blocks it very well
indeed
and doing that it helps again it is not
an endocannabinoid it is not a THC but
it is closely related so again a company
has taken up this compound which is
again a fatty acid bound to an amino
acid closely related to an an amide and
when given to mice works extremely well
well we're not mice I hope that it will
work in humans when it is given I
believe that it will then I will just
show you one slide most of the drugs
that were used again the osteoporosis
nowadays most of the drugs block the
destruction of the bones they don't
cause the bones to be built up again in
this case the compounded animals make
that we make which is closely related to
an an amide it is part of the
endocannabinoid system this compound not
only blocks the destruction of the bones
but even helps the bones grow up you can
see in this slide the first green thing
is what the bones are at the moment
after the ovaries and everything else
has been taken out of the mice in order
to parallel what happens in women after
the age of 55 there are the bones of the
animals went down and is the red thing
we see it has gone down and they have
strong and potent osteoporosis and when
we start after 40 45 days when we see
this when we start giving them the new
cannabinoid like compound we see that
the bones not only are not destructed
anymore they even go up Anna being re
remodeled again rebuilt again so here we
have a typical example of the phase 3 of
cannabinoid work namely fatty acids
bound to amino acids like in an and
amide without compounds without psycho
activity so here we have a example of
what talking about and I would like now
to summarize oh another thing that we're
actually working at the moment it's
nicotine addiction we get addicted to
many compounds too many things including
drugs opium cocaine nicotine now our
body looks at nicotine it's at any
addiction certainly also to nicotine
addiction as a disease if it's a disease
then the body will try to block the
disease how does it block it well we
didn't know but we thought that maybe
our body makes compounds that try to
block the disease I would not go into
details there it was a long story we in
this case was a group for research labs
ours came up with a suggestion a good
friend seen in the u.s. at Richmond
Virginia good friends in Canada and good
friends in Italy we sit together drink a
lot of coffee together and discuss how
to go ahead and together we went ahead
looking how does the body fight nicotine
addiction and we found that
in a certain place in the brain a
compound is formed which again is a
fatty acid bound to amino acid strangely
enough when we started we didn't have
the foggiest idea that this is going to
happen again we have an endocannabinoid
like situation and this compound blocks
an effect which is one of the models
it's called conditioned plays reference
it blocks one of the models of
prediction what is conditional Christ
reference you put a mouse in the center
on one hand you have the food with
nicotine the other hand for the in the
other side food without nicotine at the
beginning they go 50 percent here 50
percent there then slowly they get
addicted and go only to the food that
has addiction and that's caused
condition place preference and we could
block not only the model the condition
place preference but we could we could
block even then we draw symptoms when
people or mice and not give a nicotine
anymore and they are addicted they show
some kind of anxiety well that's what
happened so it was try dosing morphine
it doesn't block morphine addiction but
it blocks that we draw symptoms so if it
turns out to do the same in humans we
can maybe block we draw symptoms of
nicotine withdrawal symptoms of morphine
which is a great thing after all you
know only in the u.s. there are about 65
thousand people the diaphragm
morphine overdose so maybe we can help
many of those so just as a summary there
are three phases of cannabinoid research
one of them has to do with the plants
THC CBD possibly other compounds the
other one has to do with the
endocannabinoids which are involved in a
large number of physiological processes
and within that story the the cb2
receptors which are specific for many
diseases did not cause the side-effects
and the third one is a huge number
almost a hundred compounds that our body
makes and we know about the activity of
about five or ten in chances are they'll
see many more so cannabinoids in the
future in research in medicine certainly
in all the other commercial or
non-commercial aspect we shall be seeing
people going ahead with plant
cannabinoids the main thing that's being
done today endogenous cannabinoids which
will probably be developed within the
next few years and Ananda might like
compounds which will take a little bit
more and I want to thank many of my
collaborators quite a lot all this work
is being done with collaborators know
the lab can do everything alone these
things have to be done in collaboration
and these are collaborators in Israel a
lot of collaborators abroad we meet some
with some of them and we discuss
problems from many different sides of
science and hopefully we have succeeded
in doing some things that may be
important and maybe we'll do some things
in the future as well
thank you yes yes one more time
dr. Michelle ah
man that was what the pine solution
already maybe we have time for one here
we have time for one question one
question maybe two please be brief we
don't we're running over already so
please no stories just questions thank
you so much professor Michelle am i
making a nickel tea from Israel my
question is to but to the best of my
knowledge only THC was shown to bind cb1
and cb2 with high affinity what do you
think is the mode of action of the other
phyto cannabinoids which we may not bind
CB a cannabinoid receptors in high with
high affinity we have information about
the mode of action of cannabidiol it
does not bind to the receptors it binds
very weakly as an antagonist but not
significant it does quite a lot of other
things and it but it effects a lot of
other systems and it is strange that we
see no side effect it affects and I will
not go into the whole list of mechanisms
that are known for CB 2 it does all
these things and I'm surprised that we
don't see any side effect but the fact
is that it doesn't why does so many
things I'm not so sure
one thing that people are looking at the
moment and it may may be very basic and
this is one of the few compounds that
acts on DNA itself mostly we drug we see
effects on the symptoms here has been
found that CBD acts on DNA
it changes the activity of the specific
DNA so maybe just maybe if we there is a
disease of some kind and this is due to
DNA producing something too much
of it maybe what CBD does it goes to
that particular part of the DNA and
blocks it maybe there has been so work
in Italy which shows that it acts in
psoriasis I believe they looked into it
acts under DNA so chances are that this
is the main activity but again this is
something that people are working on at
the moment
hi a New Jersey wakati from Mehta farm
labs Canada thank you so much for that
interesting talk I'm sorry I can't can
you speak slowly and louder
okay does CBDs two different
stereoisomer have different effects in
the body CBD CBD is a compound which I
would didn't go into it which has a
mirror image there's the plus CBD in the
- CBD the natural product is the - CBD
very little work has been done on the
mirror image and the plus CBD
surprisingly some work that we did a I
think 30 years ago we found that some of
the effects of the - CBD are also seen
with the plus CBD which is unusual but
as I said since then nothing has been
done on the plus CBD the plus THC also
does not cause the side effect does not
cause the effects of THC but it has been
shown that it lowers brain damage thank
you thank you very much one more time
dr. Masur lanka that was amazing
[Applause]