appreciate it thanks to Alex and ICBC
this can be an exciting and exceptional
panel we've got a bunch of really
talented smart folks coming onto the
stage right now immediately to my right
is Emma Andrews she is the chief
commercial officer of Bev canna
Enterprises Inc just to her right is
Bert hink he is the president of rising
tide consultants next on the line there
is Neil Marotta he's the president CEO
director and founder of in diva one of
the sponsors of the boat cruise tonight
so thanks very much and to his right is
Brandan Wright mr. Wright is the CEO of
Dynel o Donnelly oh sorry
a new entrant in the edible space so
very excited to have everybody here
today and thank you all for coming to
ICBC and attending this wonderful
conference so my name is Kirk I used to
be a lawyer in the cannabis space I had
the great good fortune of representing
Owen Smith in a case there rose out of a
bust
he was baking cookies for the Vancouver
cannabis buyers Club of Canada one of
the first compassion clubs in Canada and
he unfortunately ran into problems with
the authorities because at the time not
only we're compassion clubs illegal but
the medical cannabis system did not
allow for anyone to consume cannabis in
any way other than dried flowers
essentially couldn't have derivative
products a panel like this one would
have been you know sort of a distant
dream back then in 2012 and so we we
took a challenge on behalf of the club
and Owen all the way the Supreme Court
of Canada we won at the trial court
level we went at the Court of Appeal
level and I'm pleased that we won
unanimously in the Supreme Court of
Canada and the restrictions to dried
cannabis only we're stricken and I think
that but for Owens work and the
witnesses in that case none of us would
be up here today and so I I salute him
and I note that the club continues to
operate outside of the regulatory scheme
as trying to do its best for its
patients we heard a lot earlier about
the possibilities of challenges
constitutional challenge is to come for
mr. Conroy and and in bringing access to
the full spectrum of derivative products
the medical cannabis consumers and that
work continues and it's important and
vital work and I think we need to pay
homage to it so we're here to talk about
changes that are coming in just a few
short days really there's a new
regulatory environment coming for
derivative cannabis products and we're
not talking about new products but we
are talking about new rules and many
have suggested that perhaps there are
too many rules or those rules are too
restrictive that was alluded to in the
in the prior panel and possibility of a
constitutional challenge and so we're
gonna try to divide this panel into
three topics and get through those
topics in a manner that allows us to
answer some questions towards the end if
we don't do that
grab any one of us out in the hallway
we're all happy to chat later and
throughout the day so we're gonna talk
about safety and compliance we're gonna
talk about the rollout that's coming
over the next few months of these new
products and educating consumers and
regulators and then we're gonna talk
about the challenges and opportunities
that are posed for branding and
marketing for companies in this space so
let's start with safety and compliance
in the rule set so we understand you
know what what are the rules of the road
what are the rules of the game we heard
earlier that there is a some would say
fairly low limit on the amount of THC or
CBD that can be in package good edible
products and there's also some marketing
restrictions that are in place and child
safety restrictions that are in place
and we'll start off at the far end with
Brandon give us a give a sort of a
overview of what are the rule sets what
are the biggest challenges posed as
industry moves into this space yeah
thanks Kirk so I think last panel we
heard everyone talking about the ten
milligram THC limit and obviously that's
gonna be a big one it's not gonna solve
the problem for medical consumers up
front and we're gonna have to work hard
to push back against that and see what
we can do to to make it available for
medical consumers but the one piece of
the rules that I do really like is so
far they proposed an unlimited limit on
CBD content we know that CBD is the next
big thing coming up we know that it has
tremendous medical office efficacy in
many areas and the ability to really for
unlimited product formats in that
category is really what excites us a lot
it allows for just so much more dynamic
products and so much more availability
as well we've racine recent regulations
or proposed regulations released in the
CHP product which is going to be a
combination of CBD and natural health
product of course it's still gonna
contain cannabis so it's still gonna
have to be distributed through the
provinces and through the the normal
cannabis channels but again opening up a
lot more product categories and a lot
more options this field as we heard in
the last panel is regulated at multiple
levels of government and so Byrd I'll
ask you because you do have experience
in provincial regulatory policy how are
the various provincial governments going
to help ensure that edibles for example
are a sufficient quality and have
accurate measurements THC and CBD and
are also free of chemicals and possible
contaminants such as pesticides from the
plants that are growing to make these
value-added product that's a good that's
a good question and I'm a bit of a
misfit on this panel because I come from
30 years of government regulation and
first of all running the cabinet
Secretariat for premier bill Bennett and
then I was general manager of the Liquor
Control Licensing branch for several
years in the last 30 years
consulting in liquor licensing when the
rollout of cannabis came about we got
involved with it mainly because we felt
that we saw what was going to happen is
going to be the same regulators to
regulate liquor going to be regulating
cannabis now same process a same
approach and from my perspective on this
topic is a lot of work still needs to be
done during the last several years I've
gone to a lot of cannabis conferences
and there aren't a lot of people here at
these conferences from government I
don't know if there's anybody here from
the liquor of a branch or a liquor
cannabis branch or if there's anyone
here from the cannabis distribution
branch or if they're willing to show it
or if they're willing to show it yeah
and we find that there's a null AK of
dialogue between the people in the
industry and you folks who have been in
the industry of the last umpteen years
are to cannabis what NASA is to space
you know what's going on and what we
find that there's a lack of a dialogue
you have government making rules and
when I was in government we used to have
this saying which was don't start vast
plans with half-assed ideas and we often
find that sometimes things rolled out in
government and they didn't consider all
the consequences or what we would call
the unintended consequences that's what
I'm concerned about here there needs to
be more dialogue I'm glad to see that
the industry is starting get motivated
and organized and it was on the previous
panel he's working hard to create a KERS
Association of cannabis retailers to
Lobby the government but it's way it's
going to have to go now with respect to
the issue of quality it's going to be
it's a huge issue now we had one client
who went to the government can of a
store here and bought eight products he
took him to an independent lab to have
him tested one product came back
positive for pesticides and only one
product was accurate in terms of what it
was labeled all the other the other
remaining six had the wrong THC levels
so when you bring in into the world of
edibles that's going to be a huge factor
and the other problem we have right now
on the liquor side is filling the
pipeline with product and you might have
heard that the BC government appointed
an independent review the distribution
system for liquor because the private
liquor store industry and restaurants
have been complaining that they're
gaining cross stock shortages the
product they order like a new Scotch
release or something like there are wine
release they don't get it or they want
to get half of it and I can see that
happening with edibles filling the
demand and I think the uptake for
edibles is going to be huge particularly
with older people and can they provide
the product safely quickly with a
shelf-life
to the retailer's that is accurate
terms of its chemical composition or its
quality and that to me is huge and I
would like to see more dialogue with
with industry on this point
so actually Kirk I won't jump in on two
points there first the there was a
recent study done on about 1500 people
that showed of the four million cannabis
users in Canada I would this the new
regulations and edibles and vapes and so
forth would add an additional three
million users so we are definitely gonna
see a new crowd jumping in the second
point I wanted to add was on the topic
of quality control and industry
associations more recently there was a
conference that was called the c-45
conference that was specific to
upholding the standards of production of
various things and edibles was a big
topic at that the idea behind it is a is
an industry association that advocates
for high quality products advocates for
production standards and that we
specifically recommended that they
advocate for lab testing standards that
are standard across Canada I've been lab
testing edibles now for almost four
years and it's obvious that not
everybody does it the same and that it
that's a huge problem in the industry
for consistency if we're not getting the
same testing done on one end of the
country that we are at the other we're
gonna have a problem here so the
products that are coming online are at
new products right I mean the people
make gummies people make edible products
people make cookies what's new at least
in the regular dated framework is the is
that they now are gonna have THC CBD and
other cannabinoids in them and so neo I
think let's come to you and I'll ask you
you know these consumer packaged goods
these kinds of things that are already
being sold is their utility and having
that kind of deep CPG experience come
from other realms and come into the
cannabis industry and help build that
sort of safe trusted reliable model sure
yeah we certainly think so that's been a
big part of our strategy and let's say
looking at senior management how we've
added to the team aggressively in the
last 12 to 18 months as we built out
partnerships in the edible space like
bang and and like Ruby sugar so we've
drawn on we're in London Ontario which
is a terrific market with
history not only Agriculture but also
food manufacturing and processing as
well as manufacturing of all kinds of
other products so there's a terrific
labor force London it's not a huge city
but there's over half a million people
and I would say a disproportionate
amount of skilled labour relative to the
size of the city so absolutely we're
adding in that area intentionally our VP
of operations as 25 years of experience
working with companies like Clorox and
General Mills Maple Leaf Foods B and G
our director of ops was at Nestle for
well over a decade and we continue to
draw people from other CPG companies
like Pepsi etc so that's a huge part of
addressing I think where purchase
brought up which is how do you create a
consistent quality product that you know
lives within the regs and doesn't test
negative for pesticides etc it's hugely
important circling back on safety and
this 10 milligram maximum THC per
package that's being implemented by
Health Canada Emma what do you think
that cap on the potency of your products
has in terms of defining who the
consumers are that will eventually
purchase those products at the point of
retail is it a different thing entirely
than for example in medical consumer
base and how are other jurisdictions
regulating in this area we heard from
Laurie Ajax earlier about California
what are we doing visa vie a market
that's about the same size as Canada 35
million or so people that's coming
online at about the same time as Canada
how do we stack up this is really a new
consumer category and I think anyone who
is an avid consumer in the audience
would testify to this that a 10
milligram limit may not be enough if you
are a high tolerance consumer so in
terms of your customer segmentation I
think for these infused products you
really are targeting the can a curious
the novice consumer means there's a lot
of due diligence in terms of pairing
education with your product concepts as
well I mean really advocating for safe
and responsible consumption if this is
going to be someone's first experience I
think also by nature of the product
format its non combustible it's not
smokeable so it's very approachable to a
wider segment of consumers so when we
compare this to looking down at the u.s.
marketplace in California specifically
there's a hundred milligram potency for
a beverage as an example as the upper
limit so the consumer that's drawn
towards that product is perhaps from the
legacy market or a higher tolerance
consumer there what's currently going
into the dispensaries demanding these
products and so the dispensaries in
California haven't been as open to
carrying a wide selection of the lower
potency drinks because they're thinking
the consumers not there yet but those
products at that type of potency are
really to draw in the new consumer so
it's the brand's responsibility to make
sure they're building awareness outside
of retail to drive that consumer
in-store to know that there's a product
format and a potency that's appropriate
for them so I think for Bev canna that's
really been the focus is looking at the
new consumer what are their aptitudes
and motivations and pairing products
that are ten milligrams and less so
starting at potentially a micro dose two
and a half milligrams in different
ranges and I think to you as a
manufacturer that's obviously an
advantage to get people to consume more
of your product so if you're creating
too high of a potency it doesn't really
leave a lot of room for multiple
consumption occasions potentially within
a day or potentially within any given
purchase so definitely I think this is a
new consumer category with that type of
potency limit to me the ten milligram
limit is like light beer yeah it's it's
going to me ensure the continuation of
what I call the hundred dollars on the
barbecue I have a friend she's got
Crohn's disease and every Friday she and
her husband place $100 in an envelope
and put it on the barbecue they come
home that night $100 is gone and there's
a little bag there because it helps her
where the Crohn's disease that milligram
is not enough all this is going to do is
make a lot of fat people and so let it
hurt the consumer because imagine how
many brownies are going to have to have
to get the right THC level I think it's
something that have to revisit it
reminded me also years ago the BC
government brought
a minimum drink price for alcohol and
they got protests from the legions and
veterans clubs because they set the
drink price too high they didn't consult
but so they had to go back and lower it
to get it so that you when you went into
a lesion it was cheaper I think this is
one they have to go back and rethink
yeah I'd love to add a little anecdote
to that as well so for the past when we
first entered the market about four
years ago for anyone who doesn't know my
background my last company was called
baked edibles recently purchased by
fashion brands thank you very much you
guys are fantastic but when we first
entered the market it was all high-dose
stuff all of it and everyone was in the
market was an educated consumer they
knew exactly what they were looking for
they often knew a potency they were
looking for and the majority of the
products that we sold we sold over 50
SKUs were on the higher end of the range
at some point after about a year and a
half we started introducing low dose
products because there were new
consumers entering the market who wanted
these products ultimately in the first
year our it looked like this one giant
hump of high-dose products and this is
we're talking like two hundred and four
hundred milligram brownies as our number
one selling product soon after about a
year and a half and an ultimately over
the course of the next three years as we
added these lower dose products like a 5
milligram gummy I kid you not it is
literally the opposite end of the
spectrum that's where the other giant
hump of consumers started coming in the
the middle areas were or so so but
without a doubt the the potency at the
high end was huge and there's a huge
segment of customers who are gonna be
left behind
who are gonna remain in the legacy
market as long as they can because
that's where they'll find the products
until we see a solution that's
appropriate to transitioning them into
the legal market I think you know
Connect said one thing I think i perfe
say anything everything I'm about to say
by I think it makes sense to have two
tracks one for medical and one for rec
where a medical patient chord or a
higher dose product you know I've had
family members that were dosing with are
so fighting cancer we're taking hundreds
of milligrams a day so that that's a
totally different sport it's not the
same conversation and you're completely
brand and there was this barbell you
know we've got the really high dose
let's say folks that have built up a big
tolerance and you know 10 or 20
milligrams which by the way is still the
cheapest date in town for
a novice I mean if you spend ten bucks
and buy let's say two chocolates and
you've got a total of twenty milligrams
that's a that's a that's a lot for
someone that's new to trying edibles and
I think what we don't want is to create
really bad experiences for new users
you're going to get a lot of pushback
and it's going to go right up to the
government really quickly so we tried to
at least embrace I mean you'll you'll
beat your head in complaining about
government rules you know the other
thing I would say is we're still very
thankful that were the first g7
countries have legalized recreationally
and this is still version 1.0 I mean
there there's room let's say in time to
change and allow for higher higher doses
and I think they they did underscore in
the last panel and I I note it as well
in this Ajax's discussion earlier the
California has chosen to have separate
tracks for medical and non-medical
consumers the W's consumers versus
medical consumers and it seems to me
that our federal government here is in
some respects abdicated their
responsibility to medical consumers in
this legalization 2.0 that are rolling
out derivative products and you know
it's somewhat personal to me because I
spent a lot of time litigating how this
issue and and and the brave people that
came and testified in the Smith case and
mr. Smith himself you know we did a lot
of work to ensure that patients had
accessed the derivative products period
and and it feels like some of that is
being undone with these potency limits
even though myself as a 35 year cannabis
consumer I'm not taking a 400 milligram
brownie there's just no chance that
that's ever occurring I'm the low dose
consumer despite the fact that I have
high tolerance when I'm smoking cannabis
incorrect opiate drugs for different
smoke I agree with the 10 milligrams as
a dose I don't necessarily agree with it
being limited to one package it's a
hugely undue burden on industry under
young consumers on the environment I I
think we're all on the same page there
so we do have the rules no they have
been written there was opportunity for
public comment comments were given
somewhere he did some were not heeded
that that particular one I think was was
the decision when it was made to go
conservative early
versus versus more liberal early but now
we have a rollout you know we're we're
mid-september here October 17 is
legalization 2.0 in terms of these
products being theoretically able to
come online and I know it may not feel
like things are happening quickly to
people that have been in an industry
living and breathing this but when I
talk to bureaucrats they think things
are moving at the speed of light so this
is this is a you know a real difference
between people that are living and
breathing cannabis in the industry side
and people that write rules and change
legislation for a living
industries got to be nimble let's talk a
little bit about this rollout that's
coming in the next 90 days from both the
industry and consumer perspectives Emma
you know there's this thing that that
people talk about in industry it's the
first to market ideas like you get there
first you have an opportunity to
potentially gain early market share and
dominate the category how does the
regulatory scheme that's in place
currently pose challenges to processors
and manufacturers like faff ganna
looking to get that early mover
advantage I think if anyone's aware
there's a regulation that exists that
the facility must be fully built and
established before you are in in ability
to receive your license so this really
positions people that have existing
manufacturing expertise ahead of the
curve and the ability to scale up to
commercialization and optimize your
production practices to accommodate
things like childproof lids to
accommodate applying the excise stamp to
accommodate labeling lock code and
potency per batch along your production
line these aren't easy learning curves
to go through if you haven't worked on
an existing bottling plant or an
existing manufacturing line before so
while that is
hindrance maybe to new market entrance
it's an advantage to those that have an
existing expertise within manufacturing
so you'll see a lot of early market
entrants
and that have that expertise in the
background whether that's constellation
brands whether that's the most in cores
hexo collaboration or whether that's up
and comers like volcano that are making
use of an existing manufacturing
facility based in a soyuz actually but i
think there's a big learning curve to go
through and so that's been causing some
headaches obviously as we work through
implementing things like the childproof
lip the perk package stipulations but
then also getting your facility modified
in order to meet the security
requirements for your processing license
so that early mover advantage i think is
only an advantage if you have some an
existing asset or infrastructure that
you're taking advantage of and as many
of us probably know it won't be december
until the beginning products start to
appear in market but I think this is
really a 2020 rollout so that early
mover advantage could actually be q4 of
2020 so there's still a wide open market
to to seize here so let's let's tease
that out a little bit it seems to me
that you know when we saw the transition
from in the cultivation side for example
we saw a lot of existing greenhouses
convert from green pepper production for
example to cannabis production which
gets you a little bit of an advantage
versus building a purpose-built facility
that takes a substantial amount of time
to complete it seems to me that if
you've got you know a food manufacturing
plant and you're making brownies already
and they're moderately successful maybe
you just bring in the THC and CBD and
run a couple extra shifts and and infuse
your already existing products and your
existing plant
Branden is that uh is that a feasible
path to market I'd say it's a lot more
difficult in this industry than it is in
the traditional food manufacturing for
those of you who can probably imagine
what it what the life of an entrepreneur
would look like in traditional food
manufacturing you probably start with a
farm stand you know a couple of good
products out of your home kitchen you
saw locally you scale up you scale up
you scale up and suddenly you get there
in this industry good luck
you can't sell any of that you have
have a million dollars and get an LP
what that means is it's shutting out a
tremendous number of small players who
are would be producing these otherwise
incredible products and who could be
coming into this market and it's what
it's doing is leaving folks like us with
the burden of taking on all those
products so I think we're gonna see a
real dramatically slow inclusion of
different products as it comes along
there's a lot of companies who've really
hesitated to take that risk into edibles
right off the start a lot of companies
are starting with one or two products
but without a doubt selection and
product quality and everything else it
it'll improve slowly over time as
opposed to what it would have done had
we've been able to shape this in the way
that small entrepreneurs and small were
had more we're better facilitated and to
get coming in those small entrepreneurs
to I think are forced into a different
type of business equation because they
have to license or give up a little bit
of their intellectual property and their
equity in that idea to somebody who
would take their product to market under
their own license so yeah it creates a
lot of stifling I think for those
entrepreneurs that have the hustle and
heart and that deserve a go at this
there's no commissary kitchen model
right now it's frustrating these
products and and the reality is in
health Canada made a decision to not
allow colocation with food production so
if you have an existing food production
facility you think well you know I can
run my food production and then I can
bring in another shift and I can just
infuse these products with cannabis you
simply can't do that you can't with the
cannabis ingredients so as an example
the packaging or the bottles that Bev
canna uses are made on a different side
of the operation completely divided in
separated buildings but we can blow
plastic on one side of the operation
essentially it's a transaction sold into
the other side of the operation so there
are some ways to create efficiencies but
certainly not within any of your
ingredients or the production line
itself so it literally is duplicating
all of your your production I was
sitting in a meeting with the BC food
pros Association about a year ago at
this point when the regs were first
announced and they've been holding
meetings over the course the last two or
three years and kind of bringing in
people from food and starting to think
hey guys start thinking about the
edibles it's gonna happen and in a room
full of 60 people most of whom were
involved in the food industry alone like
it was maybe me and Zen abyss from the
cannabis
side and they announced the regulations
and the dispensed mayor pardon me the
despair in that room was just palpable
it was crazy to seeing how every single
company there was thinking great we get
to use this excess capacity that we've
already built out on our cookie line on
our brownie line on our snack bar line
and then suddenly it dreams were
shattered and they realized it was an
entirely new business that they would
have to build and partner with someone
who has experience from the industry if
just the burden became imaginably high
so there are there are sort of roll out
issues on the industry side but there's
you know a positive coming to it was
Brandon referenced earlier that there's
some data suggesting that there's up to
3 million new consumers that are waiting
to enter this space and become cannabis
consumers but that stay away from
consuming cannabis currently because
they don't want to smoke or babe Neil
what do you think this suggests both is
in terms of the need for education of
those new consumers but also the
cultural shifts that's happening when
millions of new people begin to consume
cannabinoids right what is hugely
important so we're very proactive about
publishing things on our website and
through social media doing people advice
about I don't know what start low and go
slow means we've sort of started saying
try some and then wait til tomorrow
there's no reason for anyone to have a
bad experience unless they have no
coaching on on how to go about trying
inaudible and that just relates I think
primarily to milligrams and what you're
dosing partly what you're eating as well
you know a chocolate like kicking a
little differently you know given the
the cocoa butter is a great conduit
versus let's say gel cap or another
product so the education goes a long way
but what we've tried to do also in the
spirit of that education is not just
bring a marriage of say chocolate and
distillate that's nice but we partnered
with bang intentionally through our
joint venture in Canada where we the
exclusive right to produce and sell
those products across the country and
export from Canada because that's a
cannabis brand and so there's brand
value there important brand value but
all and trust but also this is not a
science experiment these products
already exist in the market in
California they've moved into Nevada now
in Florida so to us that's the essence
of global branding where someone can go
buy a bank chocolate let's say the honey
pot in Toronto or one of the
dispensaries in Vancouver and it it will
be the same chocolate in the same recipe
if you went to you know met men in
Venice Beach or something let's say or
in San Diego or San Francisco that
you'll find the same products might be a
little different dosing will absolutely
be different packaging
they'll be French on it in Canada for
starters but that's you know to us that
is a hugely important the same thing
with Ruby
you know the cannabis sugar installs
that they make are sold in Washington
State now it's a much younger company
than bang but interesting disruptive
product that our cannabis brands and
cannabis products to begin with I think
one of the most important pieces of
education to is actually the feedback
loop for the consumer so products that
are made with water-soluble technology
means that there's a quicker onset so
the consumers better able to regulate
their experience dose and outcomes based
on that quicker feedback loop than
something that's a fat based edible that
might be a homemade brownie where you
know we've all had those experiences in
the past where it's so variable
depending on your own endocannabinoids
system depending on the dose that you
ate depending on what part of the
brownie tray it was from so this
homogeneity
that's required as part of our
regulations requires a technology
advantage like a water soluble extract
so that gives you that quicker feedback
loop so the consumer has more
instantaneous awareness about what their
experience is about to be and will be
over the subsequent few hours so you may
not have to wait till the next morning
right you might have that feedback or
should have that feedback within let's
say less than 15 minutes is kind of the
the common standard with water soluble
extracts so Burt you know there's this
pent up demand we're hearing about for
these different varieties of products
and legalization 2.0 is scheduled to
come online October 17 these products
will be legal technically for commercial
sale at that point of course you can
make them at home currently now if you
want to but they'll be legal for sale on
October 17 does that mean we have
products on the shelves on October 18 or
is there some obstacles in the way to
actually seeing products and if so when
do you expect that to actually roll out
you can go to your store and buy a
cannabis infused chocolate
I think it'll go the same way as the
retail cannabis stores have gone the
slow rollout adding it on when we got
into licensing retail stores we were
surprised how long the application
process takes we did last fall but a
year ago now we did an application for
one of our liquor clients for a liquor
store liquor hi sorry a pub up on Main
Street and this is an experienced
licensee and his application was about
half an inch 3/4 of an inch thick for a
liquor primary license during the same
time this gentleman decided to get into
the world of cannabis so we put in a
cannabis retail store application and it
was 15 inches high same person same
business but as 15 inches that
application took a long time to get to
the process and we've had people that we
were working with about a year ago who
are still waiting now somewhat is the
fault of the applicants but it's a very
slow process going through the
government what we're finding is that
there's not enough stores out there now
to even serve the demand for cannabis
now a lot of people between the
provincial regulations and the municipal
x' municipalities are really delayed I
think with the coming out of edibles I
think will be a slow process to get them
into the stores and again what the
process right now is going to do is give
a huge advantage to the BC government
cannabis tours or the government
cannabis stores over the private stores
and I also of comes back to my supply
issue the second thing I think it'll do
is prop up the black market even further
it's such a disincentive to the consumer
because most people that we talked to
are really anxious to get into edibles
they don't want to vape they don't want
to smoke but they would consume inedible
and I think there's a huge demand for it
but I don't think that the pipeline's
gonna be full right at the beginning and
but yet I think it's fascinating I look
at what's going on in kettles similar to
what happened in craft beer and now
refreshment beverages and the liquor
stores we've got a plethora of
beverages and liquor stores with it and
you know Mike's Hard Lemonade came along
and then after that there's an explosion
of refreshment beverages I think the
same thing will happen with edibles I
think would be a really innovative
creative stuff that that innovation and
that creativity hopefully will translate
into a wide variety of products that
consumers appreciate and can come back
to but but you did mention Burt that
there's this sort of elephant in the
room which is the fact that these
products aren't really new they're all
for sale currently in Canada right now
in the legacy marketplace it's not easy
to market your products it's not easy to
brand your products when you do it
legally you've got sort of big stop
signs and small small brand elements you
go into your local liquor store and the
craft beer industry has a wide variety
of really interesting packaging options
available to them some that might even
be attractive to children you know
placed right at child level on the on
the stores on the shelves in the store
so I'm a with those tight restrictions
on branding and marketing what
opportunities are there for brands to
carve out consumer awareness so that
people come and say well actually that
products available at the at the legal
dispensary so I've been working in
product development for over a decade
now in the natural products industry
prior to working in cannabis and I'm
trained as a nutritionist as well so
this might be a little bit of a bias but
I think with as much restriction as
there is on packaging when a consumer
approaches the Shelf there's very
limited touch points for them to make
their product decision based off of so
one of the things I think is really
going to shine especially in the the
onset of this category perhaps before
regulations change is how clean are your
ingredients so if a consumer is able to
you know be appealed by maybe the color
of the package or that the method of
consumption itself they're interested in
beverages to pick up that package what
they're basing their decision off of is
potency for sure price of course but
then what's in that product so as
they're artificial colors is there
artificial sweeteners is there
sweeteners in general
so for Viviano we've been really looking
at clean ingredient label minimal
ingredients no added sugars no
artificial colors so nothing that would
cause for concern alarm everything
that's all-natural so I think that's a
huge opportunity for brands and
manufacturers is to formulate with a
higher quality standard so that there's
nothing offensive making somebody put
that product back on shelf and then
ultimately I think efficacy is a big
part of the marketing play if your
product delivers on the occasion that
you're seeking I'm so something that's a
little bit euphoric as an example or
something that helps you relax and
unwind at the end of the day these
occasion based types of outcomes I think
that's a big appeal in terms of somebody
reapeat purchasing or recommending that
product or referring that product to
others in their network so in some cases
this comes back to grassroots marketing
initiatives word-of-mouth and in other
cases it comes back to the fundamentals
of product development which is what you
what are your ingredients and what's
your quality standard when you're
formulating I think that's the huge
opportunity here especially at the
beginning of this category
I think another big key of consumer
repetition on branding is just that
repetition with so few touch points the
store is the place where they see your
brand first if you're not on the shelf
they will replace you with the product
next to you so I think in the early
rollouts we saw a lot of companies who
brought products to market early they
had that first mover advantage but they
couldn't hold it because their products
didn't remain on the shelf so I know
we're producing a like a high volume
strategy of always trying to be there no
matter which brand we're producing for
and I think it's really important that
the consumer can go in see your product
and buy it over and over and over and
over if it's the only place they're ever
gonna see your product I'm excited about
outdoor grow coming online cuz I think
that will help keep these products in
supply because the input amount that
you're using is so minimal if you're
using you know refinement and
purification and your extraction process
but hopefully we won't see the same
supply issues as these categories come
online but I think that's a great point
is the replicate ability of seeing these
brands and the visibility in the market
strongly agree with the green labeling
as well we're going with natural fruit
purees from Okanagan peaches and so
forth so we've got just about two or
three minutes left I did want to save a
little bit of time for questions let's
let's go to some questions I'd ask that
you just
ask the question ask it as succinctly as
possible and then in the answers let's
try to also be a succinct as possible
get through as many as we can the next
day those are nice words let's hear for
the panel one more time gravity is the
soul of wit we'll go here then we'll go
there and that'll be it really it was
really interesting so the very beginning
of the panel you hit on on quality and
testing of these products and to me this
is a really interesting issue I thought
it was really interesting that you can
test stuff that's on the shelf and get
you know very different answers as to
what's in there so what do you think the
solution to that problem is are we gonna
go to some standardized or validate
validated testing process for this I can
jump in on there and yeah I think you
have something to add as well too there
is a variance that's actually allowed on
the label so depending on the potency
that you're claiming there's a different
variance at different breaks along that
potency spectrum so what this means is a
manufacturer could produce the label in
advance just for you know efficacy and
efficiency in there costing strategy as
long as their label is testing within
that variant suspect they can release it
into the market but I think the due
diligence is for the manufacturer to
label based on the batch so when you get
your testing data back to label it not
just according to the variance that's
allowed but the actual values that were
achieved for that batch and that
transparency ultimately I think is going
to shine through in the eyes at the
consumer even if the retailer then has
to do a little bit of explaining you
know why is this batch a little bit
different than the last batch but I
think that's the ultimate implication
for manufacturers and processors is to
label on a per batch basis to overcome
that variance
yeah there's very little times when the
customer a kid gets over the feeling of
dishonesty and especially when you're
paying who knows how many dollars per
ten milligrams each
every milligram that's not in there is
someone is hitting someone's wallet but
the other answer there of course is
industry associations and coming from
within industry to standardized testing
across the provinces there's no push for
it from government right now because
they've already handed out these testing
licenses to the labs and they assume
that the labs are doing it at a high
quality level and they may well be the
difference is that they're not doing it
standardized with standardized processes
across the level we know a lab that was
taking an entire brownie breaking off a
corner of it blend
that and getting a result that's not a
homogeneous sample it's not a
representative sample and so we were
hoping that not all labs in Canada are
doing that but at the same time we need
everyone to be on the same page I want
to say something I think that we in the
industry and we come from all sides
makers investors entrepreneurs I think
we have a responsibility to find an
international agency to develop testing
standards I'm in many countries in my
investments and I'm working on
laboratories in some of the European
ones and we don't have high enough
testing standards and I think if we were
the ones to propose them and maybe go to
the United Nations to have them help us
with these standards that could be
accepted internationally I think we'd
put ourselves in a much better place so
that's my thinking I actually disagree
with the we don't have high enough
standards I just don't think that
they're consistent enough I think in
Canada with the highest standards in the
world for testing especially on food
products I think it i think that i think
that's agreed we need to lead in this
category it certainly speaks to the need
for coming together and ushering in
legalization 3.0 which hopefully will
see the fall of the international drug
control treaties and more coordinated
effort across jurisdictions so thank you
all for your attention
thanks to ICBC for having us and already
you know guy thank you Kirk
let's hear for Kirk and all the fabulous
panelists that was great very
informative