to discuss emerging International
markets we have a crack team and the
panel will be moderated by the president
and CEO of hello cannabis let's welcome
Stephen Furby
hey everybody
um as angawa stated I my bad we were
actually close friends I'm sorry buddy
my name is Stephen verbique I'm from
Canada I founded a company called hello
cannabis back about eight years ago we
started in tissue culture and genetics
merged with a different LP and
concurrently I was working as a medical
clinic we branched off into recreational
we opened up the very first recreational
store in the G20 nation and uh just for
my own credibility I'll say that there's
very few people in the world I can say
that they have sold over 50 million
dollars worth of legal cannabis and and
I'm one of them that is a claim to not
fame but a claim to a reality that we
are actually people that do it and this
is why I believe that this is one of the
most important panels here because we
are seeing everybody talking about
Concepts and ideas on how to bring out
legalization we have been a part of this
I'm one of the co-authors and
contributors for the Cannabis act in
Canada and the very first continuing
medical education course where there
were six co-authors for it myself being
one of them so doctors can literally
earn credits in Canada for medical
cannabis and I'm one of the contributing
authors authors for this so myself and
every single person on this panel I know
them all very personally as well for
many years we are people that are
actually doing it and we have seen this
from concept where we're going back over
a decade I'm part of the Legacy market
so we have seen this from Black Market
Legacy Market all the way to a gray
Market to a legal market and battled
everything including the governments
including the doctors and all of the
problems and gaps that I have been
hearing all across the world I've now
spoken in I believe 16 different
countries they are all identical and I'm
telling you that every single person in
this panel
is somebody that has lived through this
and is still doing it right now to this
day and our resources that can help we
are here to be able to help countries
that are legalizing we have been through
this already and we are sources of
people we are resources that are
actually doing it and this is something
that unfortunately is not happening in
many areas it is still just talk it is
still just conversations and you even
saw the largest market which is Germany
is still talk
they're still figuring it out right and
I've been speaking in Berlin for seven
years now where it was still raw raw raw
legal legal legal league seven years
later we're still figuring it out
so we were people that have figured it
out in countries that have figured it
out and we've battled and we are still
battling a wild industry um to this day
so that is my story and I urge you to
listen to these people they each have a
different specialty and they're close
friends and colleagues that I
collaborate with around the world and we
are truly here to help people we get
more joy out of being able to contribute
and collaborate with different countries
and of course self-fulfilling prophecy
here as well we also have careers and we
like getting paid but we bring value
that is the point here we're not just
taking shareholders money we we are
Revenue generating companies and our
goal is to be able to help you generate
revenue and not just be fluff and talk
and burning money every single day which
is what the vast majority of this entire
industry is so this panel is different I
assure you without further Ado this is
uh my very close friend doctor this is
JC
please come
and next we have Karm is a wonderful
lady who is part of New Zealand
she is the only legal producer in New
Zealand and ready and able to export so
are we in Canada but we will share is
this fine
and this gentleman I've known for many
years this is Kai he is a legal expert
in cannabis practicing in Germany and
represents many different cannabis
companies specifically in Germany and
and another close friend of mine Nema we
met in Zurich many years ago and in fact
actually one of his uh his business
partners is from my hometown in Canada
as well and this gentleman is part of
the pilot project in Switzerland where
he is one of the only people that is
able to produce and sell cannabis and
cannabis extracts to the pilot project
so again
yeah we are people doing it we are
active we are Revenue generating we are
real companies real people operating
real things and I I think I've said the
word real enough but I want to reinforce
that it's real last time I'll say that
so the focus of this panel is
well tell you what
I spoke uh very broadly about each of
you would you like to elaborate further
about what you do individually and then
we will have a round table discussion
and I do believe that in open Forum here
because we are resources
please ask us questions and get our
contacts we we love doing this
please tell us more about yourself
so hi guys I'm John I'm from Malta and
in Malta I am a licensed physician and
prescriber and I support doctors with
two things educating doctors to become
prescribers and better with private
supporting them with Tech Medical Tech
data Tech which is supporting doctors in
all areas of medicine but especially
cannabis medicine and Innovative Fields
Malta has had medical cannabis now for
five years and since then it's been a
lot of battles a lot of work some things
have worked some things haven't and the
best part about being here and speaking
to you is to see the enthusiasm and to
help of enthusiasm and make it to the
other side with success and hopefully
avoiding some of the pitfalls and some
of the bullets that we've had to take in
our own respective countries and lessons
we've learned we have lots of bullets in
us it's it's not an easy industry I can
promise that so when you find anybody
that has been in this industry for
longer than five years it's a lifetime
right we say dog years like it's so cute
when people say like oh I've been in the
Cannabis industry for a long time it's
like how how long and they're like like
two three years and they're like
crazy like how long have you were like
12.
and yeah I had hair before by the way
uh Kiara everyone my
and I think I get the prize for coming
from the furthest away uh so I'm here
from New Zealand
Helios is a medicines company we are New
Zealand's largest producer of medicinal
cannabis as Stephen said we're the only
New Zealand grown New Zealand made
producer who is in Market
we were the first to achieve our GMP
license back in 2021 uh we've been in
market for two years in New Zealand
catering for patients in New Zealand
first that was one of our real goals at
Helios was to look after our own
patients first as you heard we're
ramping up for export now we're a
vertically integrated company so we have
our own highly controlled indoor
cultivation
we have our own extraction facility we
make our own finished products we have
our own GMP analytical testing labs and
our own r d space we also have a number
of collaborations across New Zealand
with research and development
Partnerships into universities and I
think one of the things that I can
probably share is a different
perspective here on how medical can be
done and done really well it's not all
perfect that one I will definitely say
but one thing that we do see in New
Zealand which is a bit different to what
I'm seeing in Europe is really strong
government support
so we have support and funding for our r
d programs we have support and funding
for our export plans part of the reason
that I'm here today to be able to tell
you all about what we're doing in New
Zealand and we also as a small country
not quite as small as Slovenia but just
five million people we're able to really
interact and talk with our Ministry of
Health with our politicians and with our
government departments and I think that
Slovenia could really learn and and do
that as well with being able to have
those conversations just like the ones
we're having here today
fantastic
yeah thank you my name is I'm a lawyer
from Germany I'm a lawyer since 2003 and
as Germany legalized medical cannabis in
2017 also the first CBD products came up
and no one really now knew how to
regulate them or how to treat them and
then I started to Deep dive into these
regulations I started to block and this
block was read by prohibition Partners
prohibition Partners was read by mjbiz
daily and was invited to the U.S to
Canada and since 2019 I'm only
representing and Consulting medical
cannabis import companies CBD companies
hemp companies
and of course we were we are preparing
for recreational reform here in in
Germany and I'm also the legal advisor
of the international of the European
Industrial Hemp Association the iHeart
we are preparing four different
applications for Noble food
um food products and I'm Advisory Board
member of the international cannabis
Association and the board member of law
enforcement against Germany okay okay
okay
education
give it up for Kai
if you want legal representation and any
connectors in the Cannabis industry I
urge you to find a good lawyer I would
not be sitting here today if I didn't
have representation from a good lawyer
in fact actually Eric Foster was a
partner at Dentons in Canada and was one
of the people that actually helped train
Peter who is now head of the the
European
cannabis area here and if it was not for
me meeting Eric Foster of Dentons and
somehow someway impressing him which is
baffling still because he's kind of a
big deal just like Kai
they make introductions and they pick
their battles and there's a lot of
cannabis clients that are out there all
hunting but a good lawyer is somebody
that I urge you to Cozy up with and he's
handsome too
that's my sales pitch for you pal
Nema it's all you buddy hi everyone
first of all I just want to say thank
you for the warm welcome that I had here
in Slovenia really nice country it looks
like Switzerland over here so I feel
like home
um I've been a friend of the plant for
20 years
I've been in this business for seven
years I have a law background but not as
many as he does
um started the first company with CBD
with my brother Swiss him care so we're
family owned business we started with 40
000 Swiss Francs
um Build It Up made millions of Revenue
made a lot of money then went to
Medicinal cannabis which is Charlie's
lab my other company a laboratory then
we lost a lot of money
um and then we applied for the Swiss
pilot trials which started this year and
we officially are allowed to sell THC
from first of January 24th so I'm really
excited about that
[Music]
so as I said the resumes on this table
are pretty significant
and I'd like to reiterate as well um
Slovenia is like a second home to me my
first 11 University was actually
Slovenian and I lived here for a couple
months and I'm For Hire I would love to
be a part of this country officially
um that's my sales pitch for myself
I'm not kidding so uh let me know if I
can help in cannabis and Slovenia and I
I will come running very quickly I love
it here like what the like
we're in a Disney movie right now guys
so um let's let's talk about some themes
that I've noticed that were consistent
here today and I assure you they're
consistent across the entire world
and one of them is uh on just focusing
on the medical side
we we find that there is a big roadblock
with access to medical cannabis and the
first step is of course physician
awareness Physicians are a unique breed
and what I've noticed is that Physicians
are a unique breed across the entire
world with very similar similarities
good one
um I'll work on my vocabulary too sorry
uh with without physician education it's
lost and like Sylvania has had medical
cannabis legal for what six years
how many prescriptions are active here
like that's crazy
right
I I want to jump out the window hearing
that like that's crazy
and the reason that there's no
prescriptions is because there's no
Physicians prescribing right but they
could
why are they not
makes no sense the reason is because
it's lack of Education
right they're not Googling how it worked
in Canada in Reading when they have
spent their how many years getting a
license that could be in Jeopardy by
prescribing a narcotic
so the first step is destigmatizing it
right I'm on cannabis right now
like I'm stoned
and I promise I could write a Calculus
exam I'm not intoxicated
and my job is to destigmatize cannabis
around the world I've got an interesting
personal story but I'm a moderator and I
won't take the sunshine here
but the Physicians need to be educated
and they're a unique breed in order to
educate them you have to be face to face
or be another physician they're I find
it is very difficult to be able to break
through to Physicians
so I'm saying all these things to lead
into a doctor that's sitting beside me
that specializes in Tech and specializes
in educating doctors and allowing them
to be able to prescribe more effectively
allowing them to be able to titrate to
be able to find out what cannabinoid
profiles work what levels of THC what
levels of different different elements
of the plant what levels of either
combustion or non-combustion what
delivery mechanisms he has developed
Tech that is very similar to the tech
that we developed in Canada but he is
taking it to another level to make the
prescribing process easier
and I believe that this is the Forefront
to be able to help Slovenia here because
if there are no prescriptions
you've been legal for six years
so this gentleman is somebody that can
provide the tools to be able to help
educate Physicians so that they can
prescribe better more effectively more
confidently
and it's coming from a physician
so reach out to this guy
thank you Stephen thank you for the
introduction yeah in Malta
the experience of having six years now
of medical cannabis and the same metric
is is a problem the the number of
Physicians and that metric affects the
accessibility because if there are not
many Physicians it's difficult to get
access and when you think about
accessibility and physician education
you get down to to a barrier and the
the problem is the barrier and the
solution is a bridge to that barrier and
first you need to look at the difference
between legalization and normalization
so in 2010-18 when motor legalized
medical cannabis there was a legal
channel for doctors to to write a
prescription and uh just like any other
prescriptions they have
um a legal access but any prescription
made by a doctor
anywhere carries
await that weight is the warrant this is
why we allow doctors to prescribe
substances for people to use
um in in our mainstream societies and
when I educate doctors and I teach
prescribers about how to go about adding
cannabis to
to their Arsenal to the therapeutic
Arsenal ultimately there are two things
which arise it's about the scientific
and
the educational part let's say and the
liability
liability of a doctor
writing a medication which can go really
either way just like any other therapy
it's uh it's a risk benefit analysis
and that risk benefit is something that
every doctor has in his mind before he
makes decision the decision I will
prescribe this medicine
so that's what's really been lacking in
many countries around the world
legalization is only a half measure the
next measure is to get that into
mainstream medical
prescribing mainstream mainstream
medical doctors
um and we have a lot of scientists
earlier on today we had we had some
brilliant panelists and some brilliant
speakers talking about the science of
the endocannabinoid system
with medicine is an applied science
someone needs to get
those trials that's those studies and
apply them into what we call in medicine
clinical practice guidelines guidelines
that the medical boards and the medical
faculties across the world can agree
that this is a standard of care in
medicine why is this important that
leads me to the next Point liability
in malpractice how do we how do we
decide where whether a doctor was in the
right or in the wrong
it's something we we call a standard of
care and in animal malpractice Suite
you'll have City have um
a panel a peer a panel of peers experts
peers so if we had to look at the
pediatrician and explore a case and you
have to decide whether this pediatrician
acted
well or badly with any medicine you're
going to have a group of expert peers
deciding whether that use of the
medicine that prescription was up to the
best standard of care possible
and this expert peer review these groups
are the doctors associations that we
know of the GPS the pediatricians the
geriatricians
and unfortunately when we talk about
cannabis these people have been left out
by the industry in general and I think
that is one of the biggest pain points
that I would like to communicate here we
we often look at the Mavericks in this
industry the pioneering cannabis doctors
who are are doing it all they're they're
doing amazing work but they're that
doctor in that part of the country
that's one guy
and that's not enough to support an
industry that will never be enough to
support a medical industry
which needs mainstream support and
doctors need mainstream support and we
need to have a bridge connecting
producers connecting policy makers
legislators
to the doctors and to the patients to
the waiting rooms of clinicians who
they're not cannabis doctors and they
never will be but they have cockroached
their doctors doctors and they've been
approached by an industry of cannabis
medicine Innovative medicine Innovative
natural medicine which more and more
patients now are are being very very
passionate about so that's definitely an
important point I'd like to communicate
off the bat about about how to go about
starting physician education and
building them a framework for successful
medical cannabis industry in any country
nailed it and this is the thank you
and uh I'll see if I can Circle back so
we can speak a little bit more about the
technology that he's using it's it's a
fantastic platform and it drives a lot
of the data from our clinics as well
like currently hello cannabis has 7 000
patients that we have all individually
prescribed and they've purchased
cannabis this is not anecdotal evidence
like this is real like we literally save
lives my my company hello cannabis is a
suffix for goodbye opioids I'm an opioid
Survivor from a tragic injury in a
wheelchair six months I have not taken a
painkiller or a pill for 11 years
and if I go to a pain clinic they're
giving me heroin I still do it every
single year they will prescribe me
heroin I will be a junkie I was a heroin
addict by hour four taking enough
medication to shoot up intravenously I
was taking it in a pill but I was taking
enough in a pill to shoot up three times
every four hours 24 hours a day seven
days a week for three months I get
goosebumps still talking about it I very
rarely speak about it publicly I was a
[ __ ] heroin addict
flat out I just wasn't using a needle I
quit cold turkey after two months and
I've I have flatlined twice
and once was because of withdrawal
so like this this data works it's real
and bridging this Gap to these
Physicians is critically important and
if I I can Bridge into this because this
is exactly what Carmen I were talking
about out front which I found very
fascinating right now there are no
Physicians prescribing here
and my job originally my business
partner is a doctor and I own like as an
entrepreneur
long story short I was I was connected
with a lot of different surgeons and I
managed money so I knew rich people most
of them are doctors and surgeons and
they saw my recovery
so I was able to bridge that gap of
trust where they said like yo this guy's
a derivatives Trader like he's on the
cover of an investment magazine he is
not a stoner
and the little did they know that I was
on cannabis managing their money every
day and I was damn good at my job so I
already had that trust
and then I had another physician to do
it so we started this medical clinic
and I urge anybody that is opening up a
cannabis company here you're going to be
screwed if you do not have a clinic that
you were working with or starting on
your own that focuses on destigmatizing
cannabis in educating Physicians so it's
not just one
you get all of the different groups and
pound it I was knocking on doors every
day we have 78 Physicians that refer
patients to hello cannabis now I have
shook hands with literally every one of
them
this is important
it's the only way to do it you have to
get in front of these people and if you
are going to become a cultivator
you need distribution you need Revenue
I'm a businessman right
it's it's growing it it's it's not like
the Field of Dreams if you build it they
will come if you grow it it will sell
Canada has sold 17 of everything we've
grown
name a commodity
name any industry that can survive if
you sell 17 of all of your production
imagine if all of the coffee Growers
only sold 17 of the beans you're
bankrupty are one
right like you need distribution and
right now the distribution is through
medical channels and in order to get
that medical Channel open you need
people like this and you need this is
free advice you are going to be screwed
if you do not have doctors that are
prescribing because you won't have
patience which means you won't have
Revenue
which the only way you're going to
survive is burning shareholders money
that's it and getting more money to burn
so it's very important and this is
something that Karma's doing over in New
Zealand and it's very special that they
have a government that supports us and
she can speak with respect to how the
medical program is working there and how
they are able to prescribe and the pain
points that they faced
in place since September 2021 it came
into place on the 30th of September and
Helios launched our first product on the
4th of October just four days later
um one of the things that I wanted to
share is that our medicinal cannabis
scheme covers CBD and THC so it covers
all cannabinoids and any doctor in New
Zealand can prescribe for any condition
and I think that
um by having CBD under that prescribing
Laura look at that in two ways compared
to what I see here in Europe in some
cases I think it's Overkill that you
need a doctor to prescribe CBD
but in other cases the rules are very
clear unlike here in Europe where CBD is
a medicine and it is prescribed by
doctors and that has actually been a
route where doctors have been able to
get
to understand cannabis a little bit
better by starting with prescribing CBD
before moving on to prescribe maybe a
balanced product before moving on to
thinking about THC so it's been a an
easy route in for some of our GPS
but we've had to really focus on
education so Helios even before the
scheme came into place we held medical
conferences medcan we had experts from
around the world come so Professor Mike
Barnes from the UK some of you may have
heard of him we had him come to New
Zealand and do some education programs
for us we go to two doctors conferences
every year and in October we're going to
have a couple of events where doctors
are coming along to hillius to see what
we do
the reason I bring that up is that that
is probably the biggest game changer
we've seen around breaking down stigma
is actually having doctors and
politicians come to our site
and see how we make medicinal cannabis
even the most
um
skeptical let's be polite skeptical
politicians when they've come to Helios
and they've come into our facility and
we've dressed up all in our white gowns
and our hear Nets and our shoe covers
and we've gone into the cultivation
facility
have changed their minds about cannabis
and about what that cannabis as a
medicine as we go into this facility one
of our politicians who was dead against
cannabis said to me but Carmen it's so
clean
right I said yes we're making medicines
build it she said but yes it's so clean
yes we're making medicine we're making
medicines and so I think that in her
mind the view of cannabis as a medicine
was very different I think she thought
we were growing in a shed with foil on
the windows and you know it was super
dodgy and so being being able to come
and see the Precision to look along the
plants and see that every single one is
the same height to go into the
extraction facility and have our
extraction manager explain in detail how
we pull out the cannabinoids from the
plant and how we do that the same way
every single time has been a really big
way that we've been able to break down
some of the stigma for politicians or
for doctors and really understand that
what we are making as a medicine so
that's one of the the insights I wanted
to share with this audience today
[Music]
what I love about that story is uh in
New Zealand they were actually able to
get the doctors to come to them it
wasn't so easy in Canada
but it's very true the stigma right
there like they think about cannabis the
only thing that they've seen is on
television when they're watching cops
and they see somebody breaking kicking
open a door and in the basement or in
like an attic with mold and foil and
black black tape covering everything
like they think that that's how medicine
is made that it's it's baffling when
people walk into a real cultivation
facility for the first time particularly
doctors and precisely that they're like
this is very cleanly yeah you can eat
off the floor it's GMP like what we make
medicine man like like this is a
surprise like it's it's very very very
surprising how their mind and the stigma
even after legalization in Canada in
Canada is still there years later until
they actually see it with the first hand
or until they actually hear a real
success story from somebody that's
eloquent not just like y'all look I'm in
a lot of pain and like I just smoke weed
and I feel better like they're not going
to give any credibility to that but if
they're hearing it from another
physician or they're seeing it firsthand
it starts swaying and and it's it's
still in Canada we do tours all the time
and that shock and awe is still there
with Physicians being like
this it's harmless right like how the
hell do you walk into a cultivation room
and think like this kills people
there's literally zero deaths because of
this plan
like zero I like I've died twice because
of something like heroin
cannabis is zero like this is this is
this is real truth here
so I I I'd like to uh find a much easier
Bridge
um uh to a legal perspective in Germany
and it's uh it's eluding me right now
I've been pretty smooth with the
transitions
but uh what what I what I really think I
should really talk about here is in
Germany right now right now it's only
medically
and Recreation as you heard Peter
speaking earlier it's still very much up
in air and we've been speaking in Berlin
for six seven years now where people
thought it was like six months away from
stores opening and people running in and
buying weed and smoking on the streets
it's it's not the case
um and slovenia's I highly recommend
going through the medical platform first
and we can help avoid the pitfalls of
transitioning from medical to
recreational because there's a need for
both absolutely
and I'd like Kai to be able to explain
what what he saw in the medical Market
in Germany and hopefully he can be able
to add some color and context on how
this can benefit Slovenia and the
Balkans in general in Europe in general
because I do believe that the medical
Market in Germany is set up not to fail
it's set up to succeed it's just still
very new and
the doors have not not enough doors have
been knocked on yet so to speak but uh I
think the German Medical Market is
actually better than Canada's
um it's just not
um sophisticated or I should not use
that word with Germans sorry
um it's not uh fleshed out and efficient
enough yet just because it's still in
more or less trial stage Canada's been
operating for a while but uh if we had
the rules like Germany
um I think we would be able to help a
lot more people and be able to grow and
sell this product a lot more and that
health and revenue is actually a
synergetic thing and that's coming from
a businessman that's a an opioid
Survivor that puts Health First and the
money was a byproduct and like I said I
was not kidding when I say my company
has sold over 50 million dollars worth
of cannabis and the whole ethos is
Health goodbye opioids hell of cannabis
so what did you see in the medical
Market in Germany and how can how can
they more or less learn from what
Germany has done because it's still slow
yeah yeah for sure for sure so we
started 2014 with 1 000 patients they
had an exception and could obtain
cannabis from the pharmacies and then
there was this one case uh where this
patient grew his own on cannabis on his
balcony was prohibited he got a criminal
offense and he fought this thing and in
the end he um at the highest
administrative Court he was admitted to
grow his cannabis on the balcony the
German government obviously didn't like
it that all patients can grow their
cannabis on their balconies so they set
up a whole new law the Cannabis as
medicine Act that came into force in
2017 so we started with 1 000 patients
and now we have we don't count the
patients that's the problem we only call
the prescriptions count the
prescriptions uh which are reimbursed
from the public health insurance
insurances
um so but probably we have to 200 250
000 patients right now the market volume
is we don't have exact figures on that
as well because we have a lot of
self-paying patients which don't
reimburse which don't apply for
reimbursement at the health insurances
the market size is probably between 300
and 400 million somewhere between that
so it's a tiny Market it's not a very
big Market but still very fancy
conditions here
and that's the uh the the the thing we
imported 25 tons of dried flowers last
year 10 tons were delivered to to
pharmacies and you don't see any real
growth increase in dried flowers for
public health insurers anymore so the
the future of the market definitely is
the self-payer market
where people
obtain cannabis from from our
prescriptions and don't even think about
reimbursement or imply apply to apply
for that and
that is a
the future of the market for for sure
and maybe one of the or The only
positive aspect about the new draft
which the federal health Ministry
represented two weeks ago or three weeks
ago is that cannabis is removed from the
narcotic act yes so it's not a narcotic
anymore it's a zoo generous it's a
product it's a commodity Zoe generous
you can say even stricter regulated and
controlled than before but it's not a
narcotic anymore
and that's the future maybe that helps
for doctors as well for education
purposes so it doesn't have the stigma
of a narcotic anymore but
um somewhere between an all commodity
and the medicine we have to figure that
out exactly if science progresses
Etc
and
um then as you said it if you prescribe
a narcotic The Physician has obliged to
do a risk benefit analysis uh how big is
the risk that the patient gets addicted
and that the situation gets even worse
and these analysis
um is the Physicians don't have to do
that anymore so they can prescribe it
and please pay attention on that if you
set up the medical regime
um any indication is possible for
cannabis and it's not shouldn't be
restricted to like in Portugal to seven
indications
or like in the UK where you can
prescribe cannabis only for very few
conditions make it open cannabis has the
potential to to help anyone and yeah the
future definitely is in the episode
prayer Market absolutely thank you very
much so
I'll I'll highlight a few key points in
uh in the German Market the
reimbursement program is something that
is astonishing
um they they have a very strong
reimbursement program in Canada we have
what's called ohip it's like insurance
coverage cannabis is not only not
included in this this is the best part
we have what's called an excise stamp
it's like a syntax so things like
cigarettes they have a special rapper
with a special stamp where you have to
pay an extra big tax because it's bad
for you
our cannabis medicine
has an excise stamp on it medicine
that is still even we are by far the
most fleshed out and sophisticated of
the G20 Nations for cannabis and we have
been lobbying and I've been sitting on
boards and sitting on the Canadian
cannabis Council I'm a member of the
Canadian Chamber of Commerce like one of
the lead cannabis advisors there
and if anybody has a story
of who qualifies for medical cannabis
and it's real medical efficacy it's it's
me and just with my own company we have
7 000 patients never mind the half
million others that are using this
product and we get taxed as a syntax on
it
it's nuts whereas in Germany they are
offering reimbursement for it and I urge
policy makers here in Slovenia to
understand that this is a real medicine
it's irrefutable the only reason that
it's still like that in Canada is
because of bureaucracy and the Genies
out of the bottle and they're very much
enjoying the the monetary tax benefits
out of that excise stamp
right like trust me I like I I watch
Netflix mini series of corruption I'd
laugh saying that was [ __ ] Tuesday
morning for me
like it's it's it's dark it's it's
really really dark and we're very young
and the knowledge and experience that
we've had weighs like a very very very
heavy heavy weight on us and so I got to
commend Germany for being able to follow
this reimbursement program for real
medicine that really works there's no
denying this this is not anecdotal
evidence
it's not anecdotal anymore it's not me
standing up seven years ago saying I am
not mentally disabled I'm a competent
person that is on cannabis right now and
I am a sophisticated professional take
my word for it and that's how it started
this is now no longer anecdotal or me
talking on a Podium this is irrefutable
medical data
real so it does require reimbursement I
am unfamiliar with the ins and outs of
the medical program here in Slovenia is
there reimbursement
super do that with cannabis too
perfect perfect now let's educate The
Physician so we can help people and get
them off of much worse narcotics and
have them reimburse for medicine that
works please let us help because the
combination of all of these experts here
will ideally put together in my opinion
a perfect system
methodically doing it's a lot harder but
but you get it
speak of somebody that's doing it
there's a transition of the day
Nema is one of the gentlemen that is
doing it and we've met around the world
at different conferences I I'm telling
you this this man has a brain that's not
from planet Earth
and you're right he's also humbled but
he's a sharp one and he specializes in
in extraction he specializes in
distribution and clearly he's part of a
major pilot program in a very
sophisticated country such as
Switzerland and
Nema can you please explain how the
medical program was originally working
and now you were part of the
recreational pilot program
so the medical cannabis in Switzerland
has been legal for many years
and since last year it's become much
easier for doctors to prescribe
before it was only for if I recall
I didn't do it
hello
for four indications basically
if you're just before dying you can take
cannabis so uh that changed which is
also good but also in in Switzerland
there's a lack of education for doctors
I just went to a doctor my doctor
wanting him to prescribe me medical
cannabis and he wanted to send me to a
psychiatrist so where will I get my
cannabis not from them you see a theme
here right it's to come full circle this
is the biggest theme that's why you said
sophisticated country I
um so the pilot trails are recreational
there's nothing to do with medicinal
cannabis
um maybe to explain a bit about the
trials
we have 26 cantons in in Switzerland and
you can have a pilot project in one
Canton
you can have up to 5 000 participants in
that pilot project you have to be over
18.
and you have to smoke cannabis or
consume cannabis so if you don't consume
cannabis you cannot take part in the
trial
yeah
um
the products range from hash oil Vapes
flowers for now Edibles will come as
well
maximum of 20 THC
again there
I don't know where that came from so all
the data we collect above below above 20
percent with we won't collect that it's
only up to 25 20 THC
they want also ratios like 2010 with CBD
one one so these are the the varieties
that are grown and was actually quite
challenging to make a hash with 20 but
it's possible it's always simple
but it's possible
um
to get these pilot projects it's uh it's
a long way it's a lot of energy a little
bit of money you need a research team
ours is from the eth from Zurich
and you need a topic what are you
researching so the differences of for
example differences of consumption
cannabis in the city and in the
in the
um not in the City Country thank you
thank you so that that's something
um
that that costs money obviously then you
have to if you are producing with plants
you have to have a certification which
is normally jacp
you definitely need a a track and Trace
system in place that's very important
for the government
and that's more or less for the
production of the plant side then
extracted is extracted there's no law
how you need to extract or or you can do
it as you wish basically you just need
to have that so if you say you will
extract a hundred kilos at 18
THC then you can calculate how much
distillate you have and you need to
apply that put that in your application
how many plans how much you extract how
much a distillate you have
Etc
then for the the products which we
specialize in in Charlie's lab are Vapes
and oils
so uh the oils do not need any novel
food or any approval so THC is okay in
oils but not in CBD
also question mark
um but I'm not complaining just showing
makes no sense
um
you don't need a GMP in the lab
but you need traceability that's that's
very important
it took us two years to get this pilot
project
I I think every other country will
legalize before Switzerland we're just
very very slow
um
but I think we will get there the
legalization process is already started
um they're just many entities that have
to
give their opinion police Ministry of
Health some consumer protecting
associations
Etc but I'm sure we will get there one
day and just just stay positive and
promote this plant
I think that's the right way to go that
would be my advice to you just stay
positive
and uh Lobby no just kidding
loving does work to some degree
um but uh
it's not a fun process either so I I I'm
really uh grateful again to be in this
lovely country
um we are open for work here me
particularly I'll reiterate that again
you want to post your resume yeah yeah
to Pro I'm like I'm in we get it
let's hear it again for the panel one
more time
we have time for one question
does anyone have one
oh right here we go
[Music]
Hey guys does this work uh California
breeder and plant tissue culture
scientist here so I've been in the
trenches uh for uh six years so you know
know how it is uh you really need to uh
recognize the black markets uh presence
worldwide when we're talking about this
can you guys room rock or uh comment on
some of the regulatory form medical
needing to be or or like the bureaucracy
needing to be smooth enough that if
someone has access to to their plug you
know they're illegal and then the legal
why they're going to go to the medical
and uh what advantage do you does the
medical bring why doesn't need to be
cheaper better you know like what are
your comments on that
great great question and it's coming
from a tissue culture and like basically
uh seed junkie as well that's been
traveling around so respect on that in
Canada is very similar to California
with the dichotomy between the illicit
market and the legal Market
um I I'd love to jump in and finish that
but please yeah I think I think that's a
really good question when you look at
the situation in Europe and the
bureaucracy and and as the legally the
legal experts have told us it's a lot
about the conventions and a lot about
um in Switzerland we're seeing pilot
projects so scientific studies now in
business we say you know show me the
money in science we say show me the data
now does it work
um and we've already discussed today
there's a lot of Studies have been
looking into how recreational Cannabis
or cannabis has caused harm but we
haven't really had funding in showing
why
in a context where a patient can choose
to keep getting the the illicit Market
why should they choose to go to the
medical market right it and needs to
work
and we need to show data that that it
works and that data is showing patients
getting better
um my opinion is this is where Tech
comes in and this is where we need to
have med tech to be able to show that
our patients are getting better this is
why uh advocacy coming from the medical
aspect is so strong you don't you don't
want to believe me look look at look at
this patient speak to this patient he'll
tell you his life story he'll tell you
about his child in PD who went to a
pediatric doctor and used cannabis
medicine he'll tell you about his mother
who used cannabis medicine with her
geriatrician and when we have that data
we'll be able to show and give
motivation for why people should choose
medical over illicit because we need
like you very well said we need to
remember that we're not in a vacuum here
uh the illicit Market is still with us
and it still offers an option and we
need to be better than that and show for
it so what he's reiterating is that the
the medical efficacy is real and as
people become more educated the
stigma of going to an illicit Market or
not to speak from a business standpoint
because I I know both sides I've
straddled them like I said I'm a Dutch
guy from Vancouver like BC Bud right
like it was like we basically supplied
all of North America with cannabis until
California kind of opened up and then
they became the American supplier what
will get people going to Medical instead
of the illicit Market is a system like
in Germany where there's reimbursement
free weed that right that's good
incentive
right and the other in Canada we at
least have we have tax write-offs for it
we have grants for medical devices
things like any
non-combustion medical device so the
incentive
um we can actually now replicate the
distribution right I haven't we're
launching an online pharmacy for my 7
000 patients same day delivery it's just
like amazon.com except everything is is
wheat
and it's shopping online you buy it it's
with your credit card and boom the same
day it's coming there like find a plug
that's going to do that I got it I will
crush them and that's the whole point
you got to be able to compete on price
compete on quality and the fastest way
to compete on price on the medical
Market is to re have the government
reimburse them we don't have that
privilege in Canada so we have to beat
them on ease of access quality and price
can I jump in here as well one of the
things that we discussed is a panel
before we came up is that an adult use
and a medical Market can exist really
well together
and that
um you know from Cannabis as a medicine
perspective we are giving cannabis as a
medicine to someone who is sick whether
mentally or physically in many cases
those people are immunocompromised and
so the the consistency being able to
deliver something that is free of
pesticides free of heavy metals it has
it's the same strain every time that has
the same profile every time but also
that has that wrap around medical
support I think is really key price is
always going to come into it but for me
when we're talking about cannabis as a
medicine it's all of those things that
are really really important and someone
who maybe is using cannabis medicinally
but not as part of a medicinal Market
um just one other thing to share there
is that in New Zealand we're able to
bring strains from the illicit Market
into the legal Market we have a route to
be able to do that through our medicinal
cannabis scheme in a declaration process
where there are no questions asked
around where the strain came from and
there's some really interesting strains
coming from the black market where
people as green fairies have been really
focused on medical outcomes
and then now we're able to bring those
into a medical setting also with wrap
around Healthcare support from their
doctor from their Pharmacy for someone
who really needs that help
that was fantastic let's hear it again
for the whole panel again unfortunately
we are out of time I know it was very uh
very interesting but I'm sure everyone
can continue their conversations in the
salon in the hallway and everything this
has been the international cannabis
business conference Slovenia Science and
Technology Forum we'd like to thank the
good people of bled and the good people
of Slovenia for coming up we'd also
um thank you I'd like to thank all our
panelists all the translators all the
audio visual people everyone here the
the hotel weekly balance is great don't
forget I cannot stress this enough
the shuttle leaves at 8 45 the first
shuttle leaves at 8 45 wear your pass
we're going to go up to the castle and
party with magnifico
also uh if you haven't had a chance
please make a donation to help the flood
victims in Slovenia you can go to the
Lions Club booth in the exhibitor
hallway and we will see you in Barcelona
and Berlin thank you all so very much
have a wonderful
[Music]