emerging cannabis legal markets and to
lead us in this the founder and CEO for
the Hyde advisory and Investments
Incorporated the one and only David
H thank
you well what an amazing time to be in
the Cannabis
industry the global cannabis sector is
finally showing signs of accelerating
growth after many years of slow what we
might call grinding progress I see a few
Grinders uh out in the audience today
I'm one too partial legalization in
Germany developments in the United
States progress in key European and
Global jurisdictions on medical and
wreck pilots and market growth in
countries like Australia Germany Israel
followed by UK Poland Brazil and more
are the catalysts for this new found and
long awaited
momentum we're on the precipice it seems
to me of something
big um you know now more than ever the
topic of emerging cannabis markets is a
really hot
commodity but what is an Emerging Market
what lessons can be learned from the
growth of other more mature markets what
are some of the key Emerging Markets we
brought together a diverse group of
leading Minds from different parts of
the Cannabis sector globally to discuss
our topic today I'm David Hyde CEO of
Hyde advisory and Investments Hai is a
boutique Canadian based advisory firm
brokering m&amp;a and Strategic investment
deals across the global cannabis space
successfully closing 12 deals in
2023 Rob perro to my left is a respected
Advocate and thought leader within the
indigenous cannabis industry with
extensive experience navigating both
regulatory challenges and Market
opportunities he represents
organizations working towards the
international expansion and empowerment
of indigenous Le cannabis
Enterprises next to him is cooh Yamada
Co is the founder and CEO of ceki group
the first Japanese vertically integrated
medical cannabis company cohes
subsidiary company ceki Plant Factory
Thailand has made significant strives in
cultivating pharmaceutical grade medical
cannabis in Bangkok
Thailand next to him Zach George is the
CEO of Canadian publicly listed licensed
producer snd L sndl is one of Canada's
Premier vertically integrated cannabis
Enterprises Zach is a seasoned executive
and entrepreneur with a diverse 20-year
investment and executive leadership
background next to him Patty Holmes has
over 15 years experience in the
pharmaceutical industry with a
particular focus on medicinal cannabis
she co-founded one of Australia's first
publicly listed medicinal cannabis
companies and is now working as a
consultant in the novel therapeutic
space Patty is Al also the executive
officer of the medicinal cannabis
industry Association where she plays an
integral role in supporting and
advocating for the industry so that's
our crew for today so if everyone's
buckled in let's go for a ride on
Emerging
Markets I'm going to start if I can
Patty at the end with yourself I'm going
to put this question to you about the
market in Australia Australia was picked
as one of the fastest growing medical
cannabis markets in
2023 why did it grow so fast in your
opinion and what are the implications
for other emerging cannabis
markets I think it was really
interesting that Australia was selected
as one of the fastest growing markets
because it's so hard to get uh
transparent data on actually what is
happening in the market so um so that's
very interesting I think one of the
reasons that Australia has been so
successful is that we have um a very
good reputation for
uh drug development and uh
pharmaceutical
industry um experience and it's
recognized with all the other main
Regulators in the US and the um EU so
there's quite a few Mutual recognition
programs that we've been able to tap
into and I also think because we do so
much drug Discovery and um development
that when the our regulator the TGA went
to uh establish the prescribing Pathways
and the product access Pathways they
were very clever in that we already
already had a special access scheme uh
for unregistered medicine but we didn't
have the issue where in so many other
countries that GPS weren't able to
prescribe so they didn't limit as long
as the person was medically registered
be the person a GP or a specialist they
were both able to prescribe medicinal
cannabis and they also weren't specific
about the indications that you could
prescribe for so as long as the doctor
could clinically justify the indication
our approval our um regulator was happy
with that and then with the product
access Pathways I mean Australia is very
far from the rest of the world and so I
think um the way that when it was first
regul uh regulated there was obviously
no industry in Australia so they made um
import Pathways very um not easily
navigated but there was a pathway there
was an established pathway and it was
well defined so I think the combination
of having product accessible and
prescribers willing to prescribe really
helped us with the understanding of our
regulator that's great Patty thanks very
much and really I think highlights
really why Australia has become one of
the medical cannabis powerhouses in
terms of its growth and some of the key
facets there Zach turning to you as the
first G20 Nation to legalize
recreational Cannabis Canada's a great
case study for emerging markets in
Canada there have been challenges
related to product Supply over supply
retail saturation regulatory challenges
and so forth what should other Emerging
Markets consider in developing long-term
sustainability in a nent
market thanks David so you can come at
this from a couple angles um certainly
uh there's a lot to learn from in terms
of the Canadian case study first and
foremost when you compare it to one of
the larger and more mature markets um in
the US um Canada is an example of what
can occur when you have a national
market for flow so um there are some
signs and indications um at the physical
plant level um and in terms of costs and
the commodity risk that is inherent in
the space
that will certainly rear its head as we
get to Interstate Commerce um across the
us sometime in the future uh when it
when it the other factors that are very
relevant to Europe you know I think that
the the rampant over
licensing um which drove material over
Supply in Canada uh and the lack of
enforcement Believe It or Not which has
put the government in a position where
they are the um the largest creditor to
the industry in Canada
um is a real problem in fact the uh the
current state of aers when it comes to
excise tax in Canada um has become so
large that it's it's actually larger
than my estimate of what the wholesale
Market um would represent in Germany for
the entire year this year um so
seriously problematic um Canadian LPS
and participants in this industry have
gone through a lot of trauma in The Last
5 Years which which impacts memory um
but put a positive spin on it as well um
what you're seeing now is that the uh
like like any uh commodity Market uh
you're seeing branded product uh mean
much less to the consumer at retail uh
we we manage a portfolio of over about
190 um retail doors across Canada uh so
we can observe last year alone over 10
million consumer transactions and we see
an extreme willingness to switch so
brand awareness is still coming um in
our Market uh we have uh we have biomass
trading uh both domestically and
internationally below the marginal cost
of production so in many ways um the
pain that Canada has experienced um is
uring to the benefit of European markets
like Germany um that are accessing um
that that biomass and flour at quite
reasonable prices in some cases I was
speaking with an operator yesterday who
um surprisingly told me that they had
paid more for a lot of Spanish origin
outdoor grown flower than they had um a
lot of higher quality indoor you know
grown in Canada just to put things in
perspective that that's incredible and I
and I think one of the threads that's
starting to emerge already in with our
panelist responses is the important of
data you know so we'll definitely I
think you'll see that as a thread that
comes through more and more as we go
through the panel discussions here today
moving to something totally different
another part of the world in fact Co the
East and Southeast Asian markets such as
Thailand Japan Malaysia are making
significant strides with their medical
cannabis laws Thailand has gone under
much attention recently and was been
discussed earlier today in some of these
panels as an emerging market with what
we might call Tricky and evolving
regulations if there are indeed
regulations that that could be tricky
and evolving can you demystify
Thailand's cannabis regulations and
market for the audience okay thank you
David um medical cannabis has been Regal
in Thailand since 2018 and
decriminalization in
2022 took things step further Mak it
making it no longer a crime to grow and
trade marijuana and H products So
currently there are more than uh 5,000
dispensaries all over the Thailand
however a new uh government is planning
to ban the recreational economy so
under the new coming regulations Growers
and dispensaries will need to comply
with gscp and transform from
dispensaries to into clinics where
cannabis can only be prescribed by
licensed doctors with currently anybody
can sell cannabis uh products to
customers I expect further uh
registration that we both Safeguard and
Foster the growth of the medical
cannabis industry in Thailand to deliver
the safe and quality uh cannabis
products to the
patients excellent cooh thanks very much
and we're going to come on to the
Japanese Market a little bit later which
is another very interesting Market but
just coming to Rob to kind of finish the
first round of questions for the
panelists Rob comes in it from a little
bit of a different Outlook of course Rob
what are the biggest challenges
indigenous Le cannabis companies have in
expanding to International markets and
how can representative organizations
like the one you represent support them
yeah uh first thanks for being here I'm
grateful to be here um it's it's a
loaded question I think there's a little
context that has to be provided um you
know we're here as icia the indigenous
cannabis industry Association on behalf
of uh tribes that have signed resolution
of support for our trade Association to
activate tribes in the in the Cannabis
and hemp industry uh there's 574
independent Sovereign nations in the US
right now and there's indigenous Nations
across the world uh safety is Paramount
for our communities
um testing reg regulatory bodies we can
do all those things within the
jurisdictions of our own governments uh
so there's a massive opportunity for
tribes and they're activating there's
approximately 100 operating right now in
the US um First Nations we know are
operating as well and there's Sovereign
markets and there's open markets there's
a lot of comp complexity to the market
and also a lot of opportunity and for us
on the world stage it's about expressing
that we're open for business uh that we
are looking for partners um and really
ADV as well to elevate that this plant
really is a medicine and we have our own
uh sort of safety crisis Happening by
not uh moving this legislation forward
on a world
stage that's great Rob thanks very much
and I I think it's just so intriguing to
think about the the indigenous groups
and their involvement in the industry I
know in Canada it took some time to
develop but it has developed and it is
developing quite well now but you think
about other countries that might not be
an indigenous population but you you
think about other markets with the rasa
fari for example in Jama or Barbados
where there are religious or cultural
reasons why different groups have access
cannabis in different ways and there's a
lot of historical context to this as
well so I think in most markets Emerging
Markets you'll have interest groups or
other groups that need to be thought
about and navigated not to mention of
course the Legacy markets that occur in
each of the
jurisdictions um back across to you paty
again other side of the world here for a
few minutes how is the Australian
government assisting Australian cannabis
companies broadly speaking but more
specifically um in evaluating potential
export markets from
Australia um the government's been very
proactive in assisting companies in the
Cannabis space um a great example is we
have a booth here um the mcia has a
booth here at ICBC this is our third
year and we partner with global Victoria
which is one of our state governments
and so they fund the the booth and the
um everything that's required for the
booth and we bring a delegation every
year of Australian companies so that
they can interact with their
contemporaries around the world to build
those business Pathways the other thing
that um the different um departments
like we do a lot with the Department of
Health but also the Department of
Agriculture because this is a plant at
the end of the day and the Department of
Agriculture has actually given us a
$250,000 grant for for the MCI to
explore export opportunities and Export
markets for Australian companies so what
that means is that our scope of work is
to go around and see what are the short
medium and long-term prospects for our
medicinal cannabis products in Australia
to go to markets overseas and because
we're only a medicinal Market we can
only export to countries that have
federally legal Medical cannabis markets
um so we cannot go we none of our
product can be diverted to adult use or
wreck markets so the um so the
Department of Agriculture has been very
supportive in assisting us to find
markets for the Australian manufacturers
of products that's great insights Patty
and I mean it it kind of comes back to
the idea of how plugged in is the
government how supportive is the
government in in Emerging Markets are
there um funding um you know allocations
allowed whether it be research Etc that
new on that topic yeah in Australia we
have a very good tax uh R&amp;D incentive
for any medical um uh clinical
development work that's gone that
happens in Australia there's a 48% tax
rebate so for every dollar spent you get
48 cents back on the dollar so there are
many of the pharmaceutical companies
that use Australia for their um contract
research
organizations great great intell Patty
thank you very much for that Zach coming
to you many Canadian companies are
exploring entrance into the United
States Market what emerging
opportunities are you looking at in the
states and do you think they'll face
similar challenges as seen in Canada and
a second part to this question just to
keep it tricky for you is sndl pursuing
opportunities in the United States or
additional Global
markets yeah I think in our case we've
gone through such a dramatic
transformation in the last three years
that people aren't aware Ware of our
current business model so in terms of uh
Canadian participants I think there's
the there's the narrative um and what's
being spoken about versus reality um so
there are very few Canadian participants
that have the wherewithal or the capital
resources to successfully enter the
market um we've seen a number of us
Brands um be brought up and experience
varying levels of success in Canada we
may one day um see the reverse happen
happen um you know there's always the
possibility that that a Tim Horton or
other classic Canadian brand could do
well
internationally um in our case we made a
decision early on um that as a NASDAQ
listed company that's prohibited from
engaging in plant touching activities in
the US that we would gain exposure
through credit so we deployed over $500
million CAD um into a series of secured
um credit positions in the US against
top msos and a few of those as they've
experienced um Financial wos are being
restructured and we will end up as
either super majority or 100% owners of
those businesses down the
road great Insight Zach thanks very much
for that um cooh we'll come to you on
Japan as I mentioned earlier Japan is
currently active on the medical cannabis
regulatory front can you provide an
update um on the laws in future
medicinal Market in in Japan thank you
David um in December 23 Japan passed RMA
can Reform Bill which is expected to be
fully implemented by the end of
2024 the new regulations are very clear
only prescribed medicines like epids
that have been approved by the Japanese
FDA are legal while smoking cannabis
remains illegal for even for medical use
so I think this legalization is still
the good opportunity for the Japanese
people to know the medical benefit and
efficacy of cannabis While most of the
Japanese people think cannabis is still
just Dr since we have been brainwashed
by uh you know propaganda for after
World War II so uh this represents a
significant opportunity for biotech
companies specializing in the Canino
medicine particularly those are already
in phase two or phase three of clinical
Char and already approved by Foreign
fdas in the Western World this crucial
because development of new medicines
from scratch can often take more than 10
to 15 years this Advantage is especially
remarkable considering the Japanese s
FDA policy of requiring approval even
for Dr that have already been approved
by forign
fds introducing Canabis uh can medicine
that already an advantage stage has the
potential to speed the introduction and
use of canid based medicine to patients
in Japan this approach can provide quick
access to effective uh treatments
leveraging this uh ground work rate by
extensive research and testing already
complet completed in the other countries
I'm very keen to develop cannaboid
medicine in partnership with Western
companies particularly often drugs for
epilepsy D syndrome and Parkinson's
disease which doesn't have effective uh
effective treatment so far great cooh
thanks very much and it's that that
Japanese Market is pretty intriguing and
again though we get the idea that
different markets are going to take
different shapes the Japanese Market
will be a pharmaceutically driven Market
in a similar vein let say to New Zealand
or to UK to a degree would that be
correct yeah right uh Japan will be uh
the big one of the biggest eom medicine
Market if Japanese people wants to take
any kind of know substances for medical
use there's only option you know the
pharmaceutical medicines yeah right very
clear for sure and then you look at
other other markets and they're more
hybrid markets you might even call them
preck markets if you wanted to coin uh
you know a term for them so I think when
you're looking at emerging markets and
deciding as a business where you want to
go or how you want to partner up or
where your product mix today and
tomorrow May fit looking at the
orientation of the regulatory scheme in
those markets is really really critical
and obviously Japan will be a intriguing
Market with a pharmaceutical bent if you
will um Rob coming across to yourself
how does tribal sovereignty and autonomy
autonomy un uniquely positioned
indigenous cannabis businesses in
navigating the complex legal landscape
of the Cannabis industry especially
concerning global
trade yeah um there's just a lot in the
US is you know it's a [ __ ] show um so um
as we're all collecting data here data
points are what we need uh in Indian
Country to move policy within our own uh
reservation boundaries uh these are 574
Sovereign Nations so they're independent
and they have their own ideals they have
their own Geographic locations so kind
of starting there um and making sure
that you know the house is in order
before you're you know moving in another
Direction um so I think on this world
stage as as why we're here there's
traditional plant medicine rights that
our communities have innately since time
Memorial and I think as far as what we
can bring to the table on a world stage
is that perspective and that sort of
lobbying interest of having indigenous
Nations at the table advocating for this
plant medicine so I think that's one
opportunity where the indigenous uh
value is is looming large and it's
moving rather quickly I think the other
aspect of that is talking to friends in
Canada talking about building capacity
for the tribes talking about developing
not just um you know an industry but
also a Workforce for economic
development for sustainable uh Legacy of
benefits for these communities is
critically important to the indigenous
community and that's one of the you know
reasons we're here as well we feel
Europe is further ahead than we are
right now us is sort of sitting in a
very static phase states are all you
know checkerboard across across the
country so we're also learning watching
and Gathering as much information as we
can and really looking for partners who
can provide an objective view to what
the global market looks like compared to
the fodder that we're receiving in the
US thanks Robin before we leave you
maybe say a couple of words about like
free trade zones with respect to
indigenous groups and things it's a very
broad topic but a couple of words from
you would be great on that subject sure
you know Sovereign Nations have the
ability to establish free trade zones
for import export with reduced duties
and customs fees uh these SE are all
opportunities that tribal Nations have
as ferally ferally recognized Nations
they also have the the ability to get
DEA licenses as well for uh just
self-regulating and and moving medicine
uh at a higher level so uh these are all
areas and and advantages that tribes
have that because of lack of capacity
and legal backbone instructure and fear
of repercussion they've failed to move
in these directions aggressively but
they are getting more bold now as
they've gotten organized and started to
pool resources
excellent Rob thanks very much for
sharing that I think it's a really
important subject and you educated me on
it before the panel and I was I did some
extra reading it was very very
intriguing um questions to Patty across
to yourself here um and maybe this is a
good one for folks in the audience to
who are looking to kind of choose
markets and and plan their next
strategic moves What markets in your
view Patty hold the greatest potential
for Australian cannabis companies
besides their home
Market well since we can only export to
federally legal pharmaceutical markets
we're kind of limited as to where we can
go um so the things that we look for in
when we're um exploring potential export
markets are um what is the regulatory
pathway um and if there is some sort of
um Beach head or some sort of um
collaboration that the mcia can
spearhead on behalf of the company is
for a um product
registration um so we so we look at what
the regulatory pathways are obviously
the size of the country what their
framework is and uh what the what the
logistical um expertise and Regulatory
expertise are required um in order to
get there some of the markets we export
quite a bit to Germany um from Australia
um we send some to the UK
and we're also um I think Poland is
another Market that some of the
Australian companies will really look at
great great insights Patty thanks very
much and again the importance of that
understanding the regulatory environment
the orientation of the regs
pharmaceutical or potentially not quite
so heavy that direction is so key to
choosing these markets right and I think
one of the other markets that's going to
be really interesting and I think Paul
from little green farmer a fellow Aussie
who spoke earlier today is the French
market so you know they're doing their
trial you know I believe the trial is
wrapped up um they're going to figure
out what sort of framework um they'll do
it the French way of course um but yeah
watching that market and seeing how for
their trial obviously they had um they
had to import product because they're
not making any locally so there's going
to be an an export from Australia import
into France pathway that's going to be
established by that trial
great Patty thanks very much so let's
put move across to Zach for a quick
question on kind of um what advice that
you would give to new cannabis companies
looking to gain market
share Glo global market
share it's it's a broad and complex
question thank you for that one um I
just just as Patty had uh referenced I
think understanding the regulatory
framework in each given Market is really
critical um it it could be as much as
70% or more of the battle at the end of
the day and uh what we've seen in Canada
um there was certainly a very high level
of exuberance uh as we went into a wreck
legal or adult use uh Marketplace just
over 5 years ago it drew in um uh
entrepreneurs of all ilks some with um
long-standing uh Business and
Professional backgrounds some who are
willing to risk
um everything that they had saved um to
uh get into that market while many would
regard this plant as somewhat magic um
this industry these businesses um do
submit to the laws of gravity um
understanding the entire supply chain in
the markets in which you either are
operating or are looking to operate is
critical understanding where the
economics fall where bottlenecks are
where risk really lies I think is
critical to success uh and and also not
trying to be all things to all people
what what we recognized in Canada was if
if if the adult use Market was designed
in in such a manner that the um the only
point of contact effectively between the
consumer and THC products was going to
be at retail that if you if you wanted
to own the consumer relationship having
a very strong presence Downstream in
retail was going to be critical um and
we moved aggressively in that direction
that's great Insight Zach thanks very
much and again so helpful to get ins
sites from from individuals and
companies that have navigated some of
these choppy Waters and can bring us a
bit of bit of help as we look at
emerging markets and how to decipher
choosing directions Etc cooh a question
across to yourself we'll get a couple
more questions here then we'll go out
for audience questions as well um how
long do you think it will be before we
see this kind of long awaited um
stabilization on the regulatory front in
Thailand well uh actually I don't no and
I don't think the some people uh saying
that uh the the cannabis plant will go
back to be a narcotic plant but I don't
think it might not happen and everybody
hope so and this new regulation when it
will be
installed I really don't
know PE you know
that he he's my he's a tie grower and is
one of the best you know that everyone's
waiting for that
gold the best genetic supper in Jan you
know that I don't think anybody knows
that that's great cooh thanks very much
for sharing that one one final question
Rob to yourself I think we have a little
bit of time for questions because we
were nipped for about five minutes by
the our previous friends on the previous
panel with the evolving legal landscape
and increasing Market opportunities what
future directions do you envision for
the indigenous cannabis industry both
domestically and
internationally well to become friends
with Zach and and figure out how to you
know be pragmatic about what launches
look like but also figure out ways to
access capital and there's some things
that are built into Indian country that
just don't work uh you know we we were
given gaming um in the US and uh able to
regulate that through IGA but we're also
told that we can't use any of those
profits towards cannabis um so right so
there's to get around that um but I
think it really is about problem solving
and when I talk about you know capacity
building and tribal governments um our
tribal governments are in charge of
every facet of government you know and
that includes business so creating an
economic development committee to create
a business development committee to move
towards a cannabis operation while
they're making sure their housing and
health care and legal is all taken care
of this is a lot for a tribe to manage
so trusted partners are something that
we have been trying to vet since our
organization's been around for 3 years
because there have been a lot of Bad
actors out in Indian Country doing bad
things for years and years and years
just around cannabis not talking about
other things but specifically for this
um we are positioned with 70% of the
existing landbase left in the United
States we have sovereignty we have
self-determination we can self-regulate
as an independent nation so in my
opinion that's a that's a massive
Advantage excellent Robin I'm not going
to argue with you thanks very much for
that so I think we've got a few minutes
for questions we'll hand across yeah
let's hear for the
panel who's got a
question anyone got a qu oh Bo has a
question Bo always has good questions
it's Bo Woodley everybody all right here
I go I'm on my
way hey this is very interesting guys so
thanks for your contributions to this um
to this conference um in the United
States and elsewhere um medical cannabis
is usually viewed as a springboard into
adult use and so for those like in
Australia or Japan you've got medical
now well limited Medical in Japan do you
think that in in the future that will
serve as a springboard to full adult use
legalization PTI Co would you like to
have a go with that one yeah I'll have a
crack um hi B nice to see you again um I
I think when you when we're talking
about medicinal cannabis as we all know
there's so many there's such a wide
array of indications that it can be used
for and there's also
um the different formats so I think the
anything that's in a more for
pharmaceutical format such as the soft
gels or the tinctures or even the pasel
the
gummies I don't think that will lead uh
that will segue from medicinal into
adult use what we're currently seeing in
Australia um due to the due to a number
of factors you know the falling price to
Consumer um the ease of actually getting
a prescription now because there's more
doctors that are willing to prescribe um
there are some uh uh patients there are
people who are using illicit product who
are now switching to LIT product because
access is easier and the quality of the
product is better
I don't when I think of um medicinal use
verse um recreational use I think about
the intent behind the use of the product
so I look at someone who's um buying
illicit product to help them go to sleep
at night or help quell their anxiety so
it's not about the um the type of
product they're taking it's about their
intention to use so I think if we bear
in mind that people people use cannabis
and medicinal cannabis for different
purposes I don't think in Australia
we're going to have a great shift
towards adult use in my opinion it's at
least five possibly 10 years away any
other thoughts from panelists on the
question all right fantastic let's hear
it once again for our panel way to come
in and get her done this is the
international cannabis business
conference in
Berlin day two shout out to the tomman
group