all right what's up Barcelona how you
doing yes I see you guys have been
outside already I see all right well I
have an excellent panel here today uh
we're going to be talking about research
advancements and some of the emerging
research that's been going on with these
awesome panelists who all let them
introduce themselves uh why don't we
start with you thank you very much thank
you very much everyone for coming thank
you very much for the organization to
invite me to this amazing event my name
is Al sign I'm from Spain I'm based in
Barcelona so if you need any
recommendations later you can hit me up
no problem um so my background is in
Psychology and Neuroscience and I've
been working for the Cannabis industry
for the last 10 years I'm a Clinical and
Behavioral scientist I've been doing uh
research on how cannabis affects the
brain and how H the therapeutic
potential of cannabis can actually work
on humans so um through my work in the
Academia and the work on the industry uh
we trying to find if cannabis is
actually uh helping patients to treat
their diseases to trade this their
symptoms uh for this I work for 10 year
for eight years in Greenhouse company
that had a medical branch and I was
doing research from biomedical to
clinical like from initro studies to
human studies also with animal studies
and for the last two years I'm working
as a
consultant ER in a company that is
called the Bron group from the UK and we
help uh companies to put their products
on the market mostly vaporizers from the
nicotine cannabis and Pharma industry so
I think I'm really looking forward for
this conversation I think it's going to
be a really good one uh let him
introduce himself now awesome thank you
R good morning good afternoon uh I'm
very happy to be here I want to thank
the organization for the invitation to
be in this panel my name is whw I'm
founder and CEO of parab we had a
company based in Portugal and Spain uh
we have a mix of distribution of uh
laboratory analytical land process
instrumentation for uh initially for
many years for over 30 years on the
pharmaceutical industry and with the uh
starting legalization of medical Canabis
production and processing in Portugal in
2018 we were brought to this uh to this
uh to this field extraction it has been
always uh one of our main topics in our
business either Manufacturing Systems
either Distributing more
higher capacity systems too
uh but over these years by request of
our customers somehow we expanded also
for the Post Harvest so bucking trimming
and so on so we can say that from the
moment you cut you harvest your plant uh
we have been
present one of our big concerns it has
always been because in Europe until now
it has been medical Canabis so we have
to follow EU GMP guidelines to make sure
that Solutions were compliant with these
guidelines and also to optimize the
processes most especially on extraction
and on
purification where we see that the
knowledge uh that uh there is four
Canabis doesn't allow yet to take this
processes many of processes on
extraction purification to the most
efficient level to the most uh efficient
and also according to the guidelines
consistent products with purities
and basically to assure that the product
is a safe product for uh the consumers
and the medical Canabis very cool
Justin all right good to see everybody
here my name is Justin tombi I am uh
here on behalf of the tomman group um as
we sort of lead efforts to up upgrade
research and development activities here
in the Cannabis industry both in Europe
and globally to more Professional
Standards uh I'm from Oregon originally
um my background is cannabis I grew up
in the culture I've been involved in
sort of every stage of the industry's
development from premedical to Medical
to recreational to hemp at scale um I
helped found and uh lead a uh hemp
breeding company by the name of fonics
where we did genomic cross indexing of
phenotypes and genotypes to different
cannabinoid profiles and then different
cultivation methodologies and produce
lines and varieties um of hemp for
different
application um I've also uh had a
background at one point in a a R&amp;D Tech
incubator for non-thermal plasma
technology so I know the value of good
uh R&amp;D good data management and good
practice and methodology a lot of which
has been missing in cannabis research
over the years because of various biases
and and lack of basic supporting context
and information uh so our goal here is
to kind of elevate the conversation
about what uh makes good research in the
Cannabis space and how we can get there
and I'm looking forward to this
conversation awesome and then my friend
from
Slovenia uh hello everybody I'm badish
I'm coming from Slovenia I am a founder
and uh project manager of research
nature in
Institute uh we are actually supporting
uh Slovenian and international patients
with the quality control of their
products now for last N9 years I
think uh and uh later on this was the
first part uh we also starting to
organize uh education for uh doctors and
nurses uh because uh we realize that uh
if doctors are not educated cannabis
will never be a part of the medical
system so I think it's the most
important uh issue and I hope that
industry will uh you know accept that
and maybe
support uh more research like the Pharma
industry do uh but cannabis is very
special and
uh field so I hope that industry will uh
see that it's really necessary other
things that we are
doing uh because I was also in jail
because of cannabis we started to make
this legalization or regulation process
in Slovenia which in last uh 2 three
years also with help of the tman group
made the big leaps in Slovenia and I
hope uh that uh we will be the next
country following uh Germany soon all
right very cool Round of Applause for
our our panelists we're going to get
this thing started and thank you and my
name is Alex revich I'm from Canada
started in uh 2013 in the legal industry
which uh 10 years in the legal industry
feels like a 100 years sometimes and
been helping with ICBC since the first
one in Berlin hopefully we'll see you
there and excited to be talking with
these great panelists about research and
the first thing we want to talk about is
why is the research so important I mean
we touched on it a little bit and maybe
we'll start with you since you kind of
touched on it you know why is research
so important why why do we need to even
be doing this
uh of course the research is most
important that uh the professionals get
enough usable data to bring the Cannabis
into mainstream medicine uh actually
cannabis is the most research plant on
the planet with over 150,000 published
uh
studies uh but still uh the the doctors
or the professionals they don't have any
uh protocols they don't have actually
any any uh base to prescribe cannabis at
least in
Slovenia uh cannabis in last 70 years
was mentioned just in a bad connotation
not as a medicine and I think this 70-
year old propaganda uh still ongoing uh
made the big damage and this is what we
want to turn
over other thoughts why why else is
research so important any other thoughts
uh um so I think research uh is always
important in that it generates um
knowledge and data that can be used um
in practical application but it's
dependent on the methodology of the
research right so uh you can conduct
studies with sort of narrow scope and um
kind of preset biases about what your
outcomes are likely to be or you can
also conduct research without necessary
context and those are going to um
predispose your results um
to uh to limited application so one of
the things that's happening now is is
we're looking at sort of a wider range
of how we can um Carry research out uh
that uh certainly wasn't allowed before
in
and I think that um the the outcome of
having more data available is that then
there's more spec specificity and more
Effectiveness in application and whether
that's medical right and whether we're
talking about the use of um uh
cannaboids as agones for CBN one and two
receptors that uh reduce cell
proliferation and tumor formation for
glioblastoma right that's very specific
but then which cannabinoids and which
ratios um in which clinical settings are
going to be most effective well okay
have we addressed that or if we're
talking about the use of uh you know
cannabis fibers in electroforesis for
substrates for super capacitors and
energy storage um these are really
different but the um the the level of um
background contextual information the
openness to different outcomes and the
methodology
used um will definitely influence what
the the result is and that's what we
really want is we want good results to
guide good decisionmaking so we have to
have high quality research to do that
yeah that's a good point and we were
backstage we were talking about the
importance around education uh we hear
doctors all the time saying oh there's
not enough research and we don't know
enough research well you know how do
they get this research because there is
a lot of research out there but
sometimes they don't really make too
much of an effort to go out of their way
and maybe it's cuz the Pharma companies
are are so in their faith with all their
research you know what can we do better
to make sure that the doctors are are
learning about this research because
it's so important Alberto or ruie want
to touch on that well first point is we
have to research because research gives
you knowledge but it's also the way you
do this research uh if we want doctors
to start prescribing Canabis we have to
do research with the statistical
relevance I'm not saying that ideally
this would be like far away you know
with clinical studies and so on but this
takes many years and tens hundreds of
millions but the studies have to have uh
statistical relevance then with this
data is absolutely necessary as to start
educating the
doctors uh and there is I think not one
magical solution for everything
different countries have different
realities maybe even legal requirements
but but it's absolutely necessary to
create I
think uh courses is not just making like
a congress I I talking about Portugal
where I come there is one or two
meetings per year about medical cannabis
in which doctors are invited but after
these two meetings doctors go home and
they forget either if there isn't a
specialization few weeks ideally some
months specialization training that
doctors can
attend there will never be doctors that
will be really willing or a big number
of doctors that is really willing to
start describing Canabis this is a main
issue we need specialization courses on
Canabis how long it will depend but it's
not with meetings congresses you need
this TR this uh this
discourses now depending and again with
the with Portuguese
reality we should strive to have the
doctor's Association
blessing uh because without this doctor
assession blessing there will be Yeah by
just by happening there will be a
doctors start
describing being
evangelized understanding the benefits
of the medical Canabis but to have a
major major impact then it comes with
lobing also it depends what is take over
maybe sometimes it's government in
Portugal is not so much the government
but exactly this Medical Association
that they have to give the blessing to
these courses so that then the doctors
wi without fear of any lawsuit or
liability that they can start
prescribing Canabis no fear that's a
good point Alberto what do you think
yeah to me it's quite clear that we need
uh research to understand exactly how
cannabis affects the body and and the
therapeutic potential of of this plant
we need to know exactly if these
treatments are safe and we also need to
investigate the efficacy of these
treatments and obviously we need to
train the doctors so they can understand
when they can prescribe this but the
evidence that we are creating at the
moment is only clinical evidence and
clinical evidence cost a lot of money
and a clinical trial cost millions of of
euros and not everybody is able to spend
that money to create that evidence that
doctors may need uh in the other hand we
also have what is called the real world
evidence that these types of studies are
observational studies that can still be
run by doctors so we can train the
doctors to collect the feedback data
from the patients and use that data to
create that evidence to understand how
cannabis can really help to certain
medical conditions and that knowledge
will come back to the doctors to
understand how it works so we not we
don't only need to uh train the doctors
on how they can uh use cannabis for the
patients but we also have to train them
to collect data so we can um make the
evidence larger we can we can create
more evidence so we know exactly how
gabis works great Point Justin yeah I
just wanted to add real quickly to what
Alberto was saying a real world example
um John Hopkins University is launching
um in this year a study of a large
cohort of 10,000 uh patients who are
engaging uh uh what they call um from a
cannabis naive position so their first
time to begin using uh cannabis
medically um and they're they're working
with a nonprofit out of Colorado called
The Realm for caring ing uh they got a
$10 million Grant from the federal
government and they're tracking the um
uh variety of different health
indicators and metrics um over minimum
of the first year frequent uh check-ins
to begin with later afterwards they're
looking at uh they're looking at dosage
they're looking at cannaboid ratios
they're looking across these wide range
of um again health indicators to create
kind of a database um about a bunch of
different therapeutic uses and then that
would be an aggregate form of data that
back to Alberto's Point could be
utilized um to um better inform and
train doctors about um how cannabis use
and all these different contexts affects
you know interactions with other drugs
different Health outcomes things like
that so having the um the research and
the data on one side and then having
that accessible to the healthc Care
Professionals it's really important
agreed have a thought I just want to add
something you know uh until the kind and
endocr system will not be the part of
curriculum in the schools and
universities we have done nothing we are
just throwing a little bit of water into
big fire and uh there will be no success
you know that's the point and if we
start to educate those people today it
will be available in 10 years when we
have first generation of you know
informed uh
Physicians mhm that's excellent point
Thank you applaud that for sure um just
wanted to touch on uh therapeutic
benefits of these canabo you know in
Canada we have a lot of uh CBG CBN
products that get in a lot of talk and
uh I hate when people say it's a new
canabo they're not new canabo these
canabo have been there the whole time we
just never really knew anything about
them but uh it's creating a lot of
excitement like my my mom is taking CBN
gummy and I was joking with you that she
used to yell at me that cannabis is
ruining my life and now she's taking it
and she's telling her friends about it
uh we're starting to see a lot of these
cool new therapeutic uh canabo Without
Really any of the research and I wanted
to see from the the panelist what other
exciting things are you seeing on the
research side that you're excited about
on the therapeutic advancements uh
anything You' like to talk about
anything specific that you're excited
about uh with that you want to start
yeah from my side well I'm I'm really
looking forward for the data of what I
was talking before of the real world
evidence uh like the job
Hopkins study that is been done and also
and there is a program in the UK that is
called 2021 that they also collecting a
lot of feedback from patients I think
that's what's going to change everything
once we know exactly what works and for
what and for which medical conditions
from the real experience of the patients
I'm really looking forward for that and
in the other hand uh well one of the
studies that I'm going to start soon is
also the psycho pharmacology of minor
cannabinoids to see how
cbdb can affect the the the brain H CBC
CBN CBG but from from a clinical
perspective it would be kind of a
clinical trial to see the
psychopharmacology of minor cannabinoids
so it's something that I'm also looking
forward for that and in general what I
want to see is more research on minor
cannabinoids and well done research
because what uh there's not enough funds
to do all these things we I think it
would be also interesting to get H
public funds to do these things because
otherwise the only ones that could do
this research would be the
pharmaceutical industry and the
pharmaceutical industry I think it plays
a role here and it can be important
because obviously they they they put in
resources to do research but we have to
find also other ways to do research that
can benefit to also smaller companies
and obviously the
Academia cool
that's this is not much my area but some
the things I'm going and seeing and
reading it was very interesting seeing
some uh studies recent researchers in um
autism treatment with
cbdv and diabetes even although it's not
a critical disease so much as the others
with jcv but we are talking here about
the research for the patients but and
you're talking about minor
cannabinoids and by minor then when it
comes to get them available let's say
ntracts becomes really expensive and
complicated to get this and so
increasing the price of these
cannabinoids and there has been lots of
research and nowadays is not even uh so
uncommon to find flowers buds with
plants producing High contents thcv so
thcv for instance is not anymore a minor
for those strains this is other research
happening that at the end will be very
relevant then for the application of
these cannabinoids for the Therapeutics
that doctors and researchers like
Alberto are are finding for these
cannabinoids yeah for sure and uh you
know we're seeing you want add anything
to that
uh uh in terms of therapeutic
applications yeah I'll just put a brief
plug in for something that's um a huge
problem for us in the US uh due to some
irresponsibility on the pharmaceutical
Industries part and um the
ineffectiveness of regulators we have a
huge opioid dependency issue um in the
US and um the impact um is significant
can't be understated there has been
research done uh showing the benefits of
cannabis use for um adjunct treatments
um for opioid dependency and in uh show
Market significantly uh statistically
significant increases in efficacy of
treatment north of 20% increase in the
Cannabis user cohort as well as um uh
decreased rates of recidivism so that's
an area I'd like to just highlight say
it's a powerful way that cannabis can
help and something I'd like to see more
research in for sure uh you know in the
Cannabis case I think the Pharma
industry and Main
mainstream uh research industry let's
put it that way they actually don't know
how to do it you know because they are
mostly you looking for molecules for
certain condition or disease but with
cannabis is other way around you have to
adjust to your endoc canab system and so
on so I think this is also the reason
why uh you know now you uh uh year
before uh was thcv now is CBN then is
CBG all those minor cannaboids but we
never look into the whole picture and
how the Cannabis effect to end the canab
system actually and when we figure this
out it will be way easier yeah no
excellent point and uh you know
something we were also talking back
stage is around the importance around
quality and Innovation and Technology uh
your research is only as good as the
quality of what you're researching I
mean there was an example in Canada
where someone was doing some research
and they found that the Cannabis wasn't
effective like people were not getting
good results and I said wait where are
you getting the Cannabis from and I
won't mention the company name but the
company product is terrible and then
it's like of course they're not getting
good results they're getting like hey
you know this isn't cannabis so uh we
were talking backstage about some of the
Innovations whether in plant production
or whether in extraction uh in re
research methodologies maybe we can just
talk about something and then we're
going to open it up to questions if
anyone has any questions uh get ready
for them uh but talk about some
breakthroughs you're seeing in in your
own perspective areas uh that you are
excited about that can actually help the
research side because without the
product quality it doesn't matter the
research that's being done so who who
wants to start us off maybe Justin with
the plants like you know what's some of
the research being done on the plants so
that the research on the patients is
benefited yeah well it all starts with
the plants right um so obviously from my
background we um we start looking at you
know genotypes and and then uh
cultivating specific varieties that can
predispose plants to producing more or
less of certain cannabinoids right so if
we want to emphasize tcva as one of the
minors and the production of that we
start looking at it genetically but it's
not just um a genetic expression right
um we have also all of the environmental
or abiotic epigenetic influences that
change um how the plant create secondary
metabolites so um that means that you
can change the light uh the color
frequency intensity of the light and
that changes the um relative ratios of
different kinds of canono um that are
produced so UVB light tends to drive um
THC and CBD production there's been
research that illustrates that whereas
certain kinds of LED lighting um with a
more full uh spectrum and lower
intensity has been shown to get the
ratio of
CBG uh to THD production down closer to
1:2 um as opposed to 1 to 16 so that's
an example of where you use something
like light spectrum to to impact what
the plant's producing which will then um
relate to a feed stock product um for
the um ultimately the patient um I also
think in terms of it's important to say
on the whole value chain beginning from
plant all the way up um if you want good
medicine for people um you have to treat
the whole process with respect you can't
just be profit um driven in this you
can't look at the lowest cost inputs and
have no mindfulness about what chemicals
you are using in the soil the plants or
the extraction processes which solvents
might be left behind you really have to
come at this from respecting ultimately
the the value of the life of the
ecosystem the plant itself and then the
the patient that's ultimately going to
use that um so we always ask advocate
for highest standards of uh of practice
in cultivation Organics biodynamics
regenerative and you can kind of Follow
that up and that might be a place where
it's good for me to pass this over to
ruie because I believe um you know he he
and I have had conversations speaking to
the the importance of upholding those
same kind of Standards when it comes to
extraction and processing yeah that's
very important for sure R some thoughts
one of the main issues with extraction
is that if you start to eat a bad flour
low potency flour you always get also
extracts that are not very poent and
with more
impurities uh if you want high quality
extracts without going in over steps
many steps of purification in which you
will end up also losing compounds that
are of interest you would have to work
always with high potency high quality
flour nowadays based on CO2 extraction
but in different conditions of standard
super critical conditions you are able
independently of the potency of flower
it can be 5% potency can be 25% potency
you will always get extracts let's say a
full spectrum oil as first extract with
potency is always over 80 to 85 so these
are methodos in which conditions of
solvent is very very selective to
cannabinoids this is why you always get
the hypothesis even starting with plants
with low pocy this is quite important
because at the same time using these
Technologies you can also maintain high
levels of
trines people always speak about full
spectrum oil but what's a full spectrum
oil a full spectrum oil is an oil on an
extract in which the chemistry of the
extract is very similar to the chemistry
of the flow so uh the ratios of
cannabinoids are the same on extra Clan
flour the ratios of tpin are the same in
the extra in flow and the ratio between
total canab noise and total tpin are the
same if many extraction techniques will
not keep this ratio so saying that you
have an full spectrum oil many times
it's just marketing is not a true full
spectrum oil this kind of new
technologies you get real full spectrum
oils it also makes life easier when you
move them to distillates or even to
isolate because in these techniques you
can opt to take the tpin or % of the P
Sal making life of in terms of
purification and reification of the
extract quite easier yeah this is a big
impact that's a good point and you know
we like to joke that garbage in garbage
out they expect to just take some
garbage product throw it in there and
Magic is going to come out well if it
was garbage before it's not there's no
magic formula that takes some garbage
old stale cannabis and turns it into to
fire as we we like to joke about it so
that's a good point there is even also
coming not to extraction but for
production there are also developments
this applies more for indoor facilities
indoor facilities usually uh is seen
that a way to produce Canabis with less
contamination microbiological bioburden
uh bioburden issues less uh microbes
less bacteria less mold nevertheless
even indoor things can go wrong and
typically as this facilities age you end
up having an increased number of
contaminations there are also so
nowadays new technologies that allow you
to so by working Contin continuously
24hour 7 to kill eliminate 98% of
pathogens and it's in the air in surface
wall ceilings but most especially on
surface of your flower so these will
have you end up with a flower that is
far less
contaminated will not require treatments
like irradiation that always affect
quality of flour
dries it up kills the Tes we seen it any
last thoughts Justin before we open up
for questions just wanted to tag really
quickly on the whole meta picture of um
indoor cultivation uh versus greenhouse
and outdoor as there is this sort of
view Paradigm that in order to quality
control and increase um uh Purity and
security there's a drive to put things
in indoor conditions for cultivation um
and it's a it's a question worth really
evaluating in the long term whether this
makes sense I pose this for everybody to
consider and take home with them um the
energy intensity and cultivation the if
we're talking about things in terms of a
a CO2 footprint or an energy consumption
or environmental impact of indoor
systems and cultivation needs to really
be looked at and in terms of what we
look at for um Purity and uh whether
there are biological contaminants
microbial contaminants part of that is a
misunderstanding the thought that um all
microbes need to be controlled is is a
misunderstanding pathogens uh occur in
the absence of beneficial microorganisms
and really understanding how to
cultivate uh uh beneficial strong
healthy robust uh micro uh ecosystems in
the soil and on the plant then actually
as a cultivator you can eliminate a lot
of the potential for pathogens the same
thing in your processing uh uh practices
for curing and all that so I want to
just push back a little bit against the
assumption that you need to create
laboratory like aseptic conditions to
grow and process your uh cannabis in
order to have a high quality High Purity
healthy product um and I think in the
larger context we need to examine those
assumptions um that's that's a good
point and uh you know I think I think
along that lines it's around the
consistency we want to have consistency
so it's always the same I mean when we
make our edibles people think of Edibles
as Recreational Products but really
they're an excellent meter dose way of
using cannabinoids you know smoking a
joint and then doing research is a very
difficult thing because it's always so
different but having some meter dose and
also I work with a company called
zentella which we were talking about
before where they have an EEG headband
that measures brain waves and tells you
when did you get high how high did you
get and for how long these are the types
of things that are going to
revolutionize uh that so uh just want to
open it up to some uh quite first round
of applause for our panelists very very
insightful I see question back over
there s got five minutes for
questions hey guys thank you so much for
sharing your knowledge I could geek out
with you guys for a while I'm maxico
yeah we could for sure CEO at abstracts
Justin you uh did a great job mentioning
narrow broad scopes with John Hopkins
and although this one's going wider I I
appreciate them also having a narrow
focus with that study ruy I believe you
mentioned some of our research possibly
on uh with Western Washington on um the
uh study is done with Tarpin and autism
and Alberta I totally agree with you
that minor canabo need not only more
research behaviorally but also
toxicology um with abstracts we've
invested significant resources into
researching cannabis Aroma compounds
putting out a lot of Publications on the
science of exotic THS Esters flavorant
everything that affects the Cannabis
experience and so there's a lot of talk
here about cannaboids and how they
affect experience but as Ry you
mentioned our resar SE arch with Western
Washington these play a bigger part in
here I would argue some of these more
smaller volatile compounds we're
discovering have a broader impact in the
experience and so what can we do
together to help Foster more research we
got a great re we got a great
relationship with John Hopkins as a good
example but they don't always include us
in everything that they're doing and so
how do we start chemotyping these and
including more of the aroma complexes
the Cannabis chemistry that is really
defining the experience of these
products so that it's not subjectively
tailored towards cannaboids alone and
secondarily if we have time love to just
listen Maybe what's your most favorite
research on the horizon that you guys
are most excited
about thank you let's start with the one
and I don't know we'll see if there's no
more questions then we'll we'll hit that
second question but uh maybe with this
first question go ahead
Justin um it's a great question um the
role of tpan terpenoids um as an example
of these aromatics is um it's becoming
better appreciated but it's still not
well understood there's been um
alternative classification systems uh
for genotyping proposed on uh on terpine
synthesis Pathways um which is an
interesting sort of way to look at the
plant um I don't know that there is a um
I don't know that there's a like a
silver bullet kind of approach to how do
we generate more um research on um the
role of turpins but I think it has to be
addressed um from initially maybe a
therapeutic perspective right um and so
in order to do that we also have to have
a better understanding of the TP tpine
profiles and ratios um of the source
material that's being used
therapeutically right so we have a very
limited sort of understanding already uh
having to do with the canabo profile of
what's being used um as a medical
cannabis product um in most cases people
aren't really paying attention into the
ratios and um and the contents at
anything but a superficial level so um
making sure that that becomes part of
the
conversation um that you have an
informed patient consumer and then that
goes to the practitioner and I think
that maybe drives research um uh maybe
it's the other way around but um I think
part of it is just educating people um
about uh the role um and you can look at
them in abstract right you can look at
fractionated isolated tpin um where
they're derived from you can look at how
they act isolation but really what we're
looking at is a synergistic hold in the
relationship so I would say you start
with um making that more of a
conversation at that entry level yeah
agreed I don't know if we have any more
time I think we're out of time uh we
don't uh sorry I wish we could sit here
all day talk with these panelists with
questions but inos here I'm very strict
let's hear it again for the whole panel
that was very informative