and here to lead us in our next panel
where we will discuss emerging
opportunities in Europe's biotech and
pharmaceutical
Industries uh all the way from Germany
one of my favorite people on the planet
a longtime Canabis activist and a great
person and the founder of the MJ
Universe let's hear it for Lisa
hog thank you thank you everybody um and
thank you for being here on this panel
uh it's a pleasure for me uh to be the
moderator um to these super interesting
topics uh cannabis is a highly complex
uh ingredient uh that we as we've
learned I think um we all understand
that there are different industry that
are highly interested in the topic and
so especially for the biotech um life
science and pharmaceutical Industries is
something that is becoming more and more
relevant and that is also becoming more
and more interesting um for uh number of
reasons and it's my pleasure um to have
here um today Sabine
suak kovich yeah did I pronounce it
correctly um Chief quality and
Commercial officer at Argent um biofarma
um she's uh has a specialization um with
her company on the manufacturing of
non-sterile liquids including cannabis
based uh medicines with a spec specific
M EU GMP license and she has 10 plus
years of experience um in a highly
regulated and complex uh compliance
context and navigating complex ecosystem
um so then we have um Danielle bernin
from or berin yeah from president at
Laur Crest um they are a us-based uh us
GMP based um certified cannaboid
manufacturer and um she's here today to
look at Global expansion with her
Venture and also um to help bring her
Mission across the globe to give access
to safe plan-based medicines um and then
uh is I have mariaa Dr maretta chesa
here here she's Chief Regulatory Affairs
officer at pharmer Hamp um I had the
pleasure to have her on another panel
years ago um so it's great to have a
familiar face um on one of my panels
again she graduated at the faculty of
Pharma uh with a PhD in uh um Eco
technology here in Slovenia I think and
um she has been a scientist uh for
Slovenia and other um uh EU projects and
has been involved on different levels
for different um segments and in 2018
she joined Pharma hemp for the with the
specialization on Cosmetics food
supplements and medicinal products so as
you can see we all have API uh
Specialists here on this uh panel so um
I wanted to start with you U Maya um you
you work at pharmahemp um it's a u based
company that offers a variety of CBD
products um you have also established
our r&amp;t department what is your
experience so so far regarding R&amp;D
projects and uh canab noise U
applications and um
formulations hello everyone good
afternoon yes that is correct um in
pharmahemp we have our own R&amp;D
department and we are also registered as
a research organization since
2018 um in total we have now five re
researchers working on different types
of R&amp;D projects and briefly I will
explain them and I will read a few of
them just to be sure not to misspell
them so the first project that was
co-founded by the EU was new generation
of hemp extracts for natural Cosmetics
which lasted for two years since
2018 then we had two projects which were
performed in collaboration with mik Meda
Miko Meda is a Slovenian company that
produces medicinal mushrooms so the
first one was first food supplement
standardized to Arin a that lasted years
since 2020 and the second project was
sustainable production of standardized
food supplements from herian fungus this
one started in 2021 and lasted for two
years as well the last project is safety
evaluation of cannabid dials and
implications for public health and
consumers behavior shortly can save this
one is co-funded by Aris which is
Slovenian research agency and I will
just briefly represent some results and
the project um in this project uh in
total four different research
organizations are collaborating namely
National Institute of biology faculty of
Pharmacy and school of Economics from
University of lublana and pharmahemp is
an industrial partner in this project
which is I think I mentioned co-funded
by Aris so Slovenian research agency the
project has started in 2021 and it will
end by the end of this year
um we already have published results
from uh National Institute of biology
which uh showed that the Pharma hemp
studied isolated CBD and hemp extract
were both found non- genotoxic and also
the researchers confirmed that no DNA
damage was observed within the performed
Comet essay so another part of uh this
project is uh currently ongoing it's
performed by the school of economics
and they are uh uh basically examining
the public perception towards the use of
CBD different types of products in
Slovenia they're also trying to assess
the actual exposure to CBD products uh
from different consumer groups so this
is something that we are looking forward
to see uh and the results hopefully will
be with us in the next few months thank
you um Sabina already mentioned your GMP
EU GMP license can you maybe tell us a
little bit more about that and um maybe
a little bit um uh what you're uh what
you're doing in this regard with the
manufacturing of
cannabis of course thank you good
afternoon everyone uh so at Argent barma
Argent barma in Slovenia is the at this
point of time the only manufacturing
facility that has an eug GMP certificate
issued by the health authorities of
Slovenia so the agency for medicinal
products and medical devices uh we have
a license to manufacture non-sterile
liquids uh for uh investig as
investigational medicinal product we are
aiming to also have a regular license
for regular medicinal products however
the Slovenian regulatory framework
doesn't allow us to upgrade our uh
certification in that sense because the
comment from the health authority is uh
usually that there is no legislation for
cannabis based products not even
medicinal products so that we need to
stay as investigational as a result uh
we are producing different medicinal
products that are our intellectual
property so our medicines or we can also
do custom based uh medicinal product
with custom range of different ratios of
CBD THC and others that we can then
Supply to other countries and other
markets where this is actually allowed
for further uh
treatment and not only this as uh maret
mentioned for Pharma Hamp also Argent
barma is also licensed for the from the
Ministry of Health to conduct research
on different cannabinoids uh what we
actually exploit in a sense that we also
support research with uh other
facilities institutional uh institutions
in Slovenia like nation National
Institute of biology with whom we worked
really closely but but also uh we do
research on our own products to
facilitate different clinical trials
what we as a company have sponsored in
different countries like in Australia uh
aiming to finish also in Israel and also
in the United States to show uh that our
products are true medicines and uh to in
the future to get them registered so
you're venturing into the global
pharmaceutical industry from Slovenia
basically for sure for sure um maybe
what kind of um other cannaboids are you
looking into other than THC and CBD so
uh firstly we were also in investigating
the CBG so um Professor Tamar Al we have
cooperated with her in the formulation
was prepared from my colleagues from the
R&amp;D Department that were supplying it to
the National Institute where they were
actually investigating the positive
outcomes on the glioblastoma so we are
open for uh every opportunity that comes
for different combinations that we can
then enforce but for now we are mostly
concentrated in uh CBD uh CBG THC and
also the full spectrum extract that we
have been now for more than one year
supplying to the ukat so the medical
center of lublana we are also closely
working with the Pediatric Clinic
unfortunately we were not able to
prepare a medicine like like an oil that
would be then prescribed directly for
patients but we are supplying the API so
the raw extract that is then uh further
processed in the pharmacy thank you very
much um Daniel let's move move over to
you um how is Laurel Crest participating
in medicinal uh studies and R&amp;D of
cannabinoid medicine and for which
products which products do you think are
particularly interesting to
investigate thank you for having me good
afterno afternoon um so Laurel Crest is
a primarily an ingredient producer in
the United States so we are actually
producing CBG isolates CBD uh full
spectrum extracts and working with
different um countries which is part of
the reason that I'm here but all over
the world and researchers on
formulations that are going into
pre-clinical trials or for instance
something we're currently working on in
Japan is
uh people who failed the GW
Pharmaceutical trials are going into a
trial with a full spectrum extract that
we're providing and going to see how
that that works in a clinical study and
so we're also providing the platform um
which is less formal than what we're
talking about here and like to the
medical Market but a a platform to
basically analyze data and at least be
able to
offer what's happening for these
patients that didn't have success with
the pure isolate and the difference
between that and a full spectrum product
so expanding opportunities in that way
and then also full control of the
ingredients going into these
formulations and I think an exciting
expansion is tpin um and so also working
with some of the leading tpine
researchers and and doing combinations
of Turpin to see how that improves uh
the efficacy of different formulas wow
that's super interesting
so uh let's talk a little bit uh about
the public perception of cannabis um and
also in um how this uh interacts with
research and development ma um public
perception is uh varying very much from
person to person from individual
experience from many levels um how do
you address misconceptions and concerns
about canabo based therapies and what
role does public education and also like
uh to a certain extent registration of
specific Health claims or looking to
register for uh specific medical
indications play in this
discussion yeah we've talked about the
health claims actually a few years ago
now uh it is true that we've uh applied
for the authorization of a health claim
related to CBD uh to which could be
stated somehow like CBD reduces the
stress induced anxiety uh but of course
the authorities have not responded yet
in any way up until now so we have no no
answer from EC and FSA on this topic but
that's the same for novel food right
yeah novel food is relatively the same I
mean we've heard before that aha is very
successful in their toxicity studies on
on in clinical trial basically uh at the
moment at farahan we put this project on
whole because of the the really high
investment you probably all know that
clinical trials are very very expensive
and we've got we've received the same
request from ifsa like everybody else
who got validated in the EC that is
performed the additional animal testing
along with the one that we already did
plus clinical trials so it's really a
big thing that will or not happen we'll
see yeah but but don't you think it's
strange that a lot of people are using
CBD products and it's actually publicly
available as a food supplement in many
cases and we know about certain risks
and it's still so much so many barriers
in there whereas it would be easy thing
to just put some R risk thresholds or
find some individual regulation is that
also something that you're lobbying like
when you're or that you're when when
you're addressing concerns for cannabis
yeah it's it's hard to actually comment
this but you can see that that reality
here and not only in Slovenia but I
think the whole Europe is that everybody
sells CBDs food supplements and the
authorities are actually not really
responding I mean they do there are some
cases available on rapex system I think
notification system is in in Europe and
you can see there are some notifications
that there was a re re removal of the
food supplement containing CBD because
of the I don't know the excess of THC
and something like this but uh when you
see the the market is still flooded with
this kind of products so you know one is
theory and the other as as Cosmetics
that are like just declared as Cosmetics
um SA let's jump over to you maybe you
can walk us a little bit through the
regulatory landscape here in Slovenia
and um when it comes to the treatment
with cannabis and what should change
here in or what should be improved or um
changed and uh yeah how is the
experience here different with in your
experience in other markets okay uh so
um as maretta said we have a lot of
products on the shelves that are um
Cosmetics but are used as food
supplements yeah
this is uh yeah this is some kind of
let's say how you avoid some regulatory
obstacles but this products let's say
primarily are not intended for treatment
so usually for treatment of different
symptoms or uh diseases medicinal
products are used so as I mentioned
before what is also an obstacle for us
as a GMP license manufacturing site is
that we don't have any concrete
regulatory framework when it comes to
cannabis based medicinal products uh
this is also I mean um it's very
limiting how to bring products to the
Slovenian market and not only how to
bring products to Slovenian Market if I
if we produce it as a company for other
markets is also a difficulty to export
them so uh the thing is that in Slovenia
cannabis-based treatments are usually
allowed as magistral medicines meaning
that the pharmacy can order a
so active pharmaceutical ingredients
these are ingredients cannabinoids of
any sort that need to be uh manufactured
in an eug GMP facility so in a facility
that is producing according to the
guidelines for medicinal products so not
nutraceuticals this really needs to be
pointed out and these apis are then
supplied to the pharmacy and Pharmacy
according to the prescription of the
prescribing doctor prepares a
formulation
these formulations are in Slovenia also
in the health insurance system so this
um this ratios need to be approved also
by the sector of the pH Pharm
pharmacists of Slovenia uh and these are
the only ones that are also reimbursed
that the doctors can prescribe uh so
this is very limiting because we don't
uh we as patients for instance don't
have many options into getting the
medicine that you want uh and also it's
limiting for the industry in a sense
that we can produce different medicinal
products that can be offered that will
ease the life of the doctors of the
pharmacies and so on but since there is
no regulation we cannot work anything
through we uh I can share an experience
that we have at Argent biofarma that the
pharmacy actually approached us the
pharmacy that they wanted us to produce
the oils from for them because um I'm
not sure how many you have experience
with full spectrum cannabis extract but
these are very viscous and very hard to
work with uh and you need to have let's
say uh a bit of experience to work with
them to dissolve them and so on and also
not to compromise the quality of the
extract because we still want the canab
nids to be there and we went together to
the agency to ask for the permission and
constantly we get a no because there is
no legislation
and then we are constantly in circles
and it's a shame because in Slovenia I
believe we have a lot of knowhow from
different companies we have a lot of
comp uh um a lot of uh how they say a
lot of uh openness yeah and
collaboration with different uh
institutions with healthc Care
Professionals between us in the business
so business to business we have with
different markets and instead of us
being a set we are waiting for others to
have a trend and then we follow and we
have also very good experience at Argent
we are supplying our medicines to
Ireland Following also on the last
question in Ireland you have a medicinal
cannabis Access program that they uh
have published three different
indications for which the doctors can
prescribe the medicinal cannabis
medicine so our the product needs to go
through an evaluation at the health
authority so not everyone and every
company that produces something can get
there so you need to show your quality
consistency that you are an eug GMP
certified site and then this product is
also fully reimbursed by the health
authority and the doctors can prescribe
them and there are several products that
you can pick from so that you can also
treat the patient and this is really
limiting in Slovenia and it's high time
that we move forward in this sense it's
holding also back economic potential for
sure for sure
um so Danielle let's jump back over to
you um where do you see the great
greatest expansion potential um and for
cannabis and plant-based medicine
research and how do you think this will
affect the long uh in the long term also
the consumers and uh patients maybe also
in addition to that yeah um so I'm
coming from a slightly different
perspective um than the more medical
route in the sense that um
it's like the thing that still keeps it
very inspiring is that these products
change lives and they're very uh it's
still kind of a word of mouth industry
strangely where your speech this morning
is very moving where parents find that
this really helps and then they tell
another parent and then it becomes a
larger circle of people who believe in
the medicine because they see that it is
really working and it's changing the
lives of the people that they love and
so uh how do you bring that patient it's
not really a patient Network as much as
it is like a community of people who
really want to see these accessible to
more people who are experiencing
whatever hardship or disease state or
you know mental stress whatever it is
for the people around them and so using
these patient groups or these Community
groups to collect data around
formulations that can be maybe
formulated in a medical setting or
formulated like at Laurel Crest you know
where we're working with uh doctors to
create the formulations based on their
research and applying it to a community
group that wants to also be a part of
the advocacy and so the data is less
formal than a than a expensive clinical
trial but it's still data that's showing
that these things work and you can kind
of it depends on the group that you're
working with but you can cross into you
know like or rings and different kinds
of ways to measure how this is treating
or improving something or maybe not
working so that you can improve the
formulation and so it's like I think
that these all of the work that we're
doing is super important to continue to
get the message out there that this uh
is a safe alternative to some of the
pharmaceutical ingredient you know some
of the pharmaceutical things that are
prescribed all the time that are ruining
people's lives um and so that's kind of
that's where Laurel Crest sits there
because we're we're really not in the
United States we do not have to have the
level of compliance that you do in in
Europe but
we're working towards that to
participate in the World Market FDA is
going more against it recently and
they're also looking to standardize more
right like I I mean we are built for
compliance so we are hoping we would
love the FDA to say something and and do
anything it would be very helpful to
Laurel Crest and companies like us that
are built to to Really stay within the
regulatory like escalation of the market
yeah but I think it's interesting to see
if you compare like for the audience to
compare the last two answers yeah like
from from the ladies you can see how
this is the conundrum that we are in
yeah at the one hand you just have the
consumers who are really who want the
products who are pushing for initiative
who are taking the governments to courts
and then you have the government and the
government they don't want to react
because they're scared of making
something wrong but you have the experts
there who could help build those
Frameworks and these ecosystems so it's
something uh interesting I think that
just comes out of that those two answers
because it shows the contrast yeah true
so uh Marita let's jump back over to you
um what about the future do you already
have new plans for R&amp;D projects sure
like always yes it is true we are all
constantly developing new new products
new
technologies and for sure I can mention
one Milestone that happened just
recently we signed a memorandum of
cooperation with the tnl company uh tnl
company is a South Korean based company
that produces various types of polymer
based Technologies uh which are
basically final products like cosmetics
and medicinal products um so together
with tnl we are developing at the moment
new type of patches that will be infused
with
CBD and uh uh the thing is that the
operational date of the production
facility which will be in maribor is
planned for the second half of 2025 so
by then hopefully we'll start producing
the Innovative CBD patches which will be
very beneficial for the treatment of
acne yes interesting um and What markets
are new are you going into zabina are
new and exciting for you uh so the most
exciting Market would be Slovenia of
course but but we will still need to
wait a little
bit uh yeah so we are um exploring as I
mentioned Ireland and we would also
expand our portfolio in the Irish Market
because Ireland is now also looking into
adding pain as an indication for
treatment with cannabis based medicinal
product we are also present in the UK uh
for the treatment of epilepsy so
refractory epilepsy what uh we are now
also planning to broaden our portfolio
with one of our also Flagship products
uh but for the treatment of Parkinson
disease so we are actually planning to
now cooperate with one Clinic that has
200 patients so that we could also see
the benefits in the treatment of
symptoms that are uh connected with the
Parkinson's uh um also non-u Market
markets are really interesting
especially Brazil what we all know so
Brazil also did some changes in the
legislation whereas you cannot just
bring a canes based product into the
market it needs to go through a sanitary
authorization which is something similar
as a traditional herbal medicine in EU
we have been present in Australia but we
not sure whether we would stay there we
would mostly like also to focus in the
US I think there is a big potential so
we are working very closely with the FDA
to also um go over some bridges there
and to bring the products there so
unfortunately Slovenia has a big
interest of ours but we don't see
anything happening in the near future so
we are exploring other markets globally
that's super interesting um also for for
the states like especially for the
medicines part there not so much if you
really look at it like from the
standardized like National available
kind of things maybe you can also tell
us a little bit for because it's your
home Market um about uh and um how you
looking to get more access there on a
national safe and compliant level and um
how what kind of international markets
are exciting for you yeah the US is a
confusing Market um because there is so
much gray space in in the Market at the
moment and until the FDA says something
publicly it seems like it'll remain and
then also with elections coming up there
is no farm bill um no new farm bill and
so that kind
of maintains the status quo of a lot of
gray space and so uh the
majority of our work is really in the
therapeutic molecules and so we see that
continue to be added into different
formulations worldwide so that's
expanding throughout the US it's being
added into cannabis in the regulated
market state to state where you're
complementing THC with CBG and CBC and
CBN for different uh effect-based
products so we're seeing a lot of
expansion there um and then our largest
expansion this year is a distribution
center in Japan and so working really
closely with a patient Network there who
advocated really strongly to raise there
was recently laws Japan that we're going
to change the uh THC limits to one part
per million they've now advocated for 10
parts per million which is just a little
bit better uh but this patient Network
we've been actually working with for
five years providing product to this
group and so they're really working with
them to Advocate to continue to be able
to serve that group of people and so
that's an exciting project that's kind
of becoming more realized as the
regulations are changing and the
Japanese group um this patient group is
uh being more vocal about their rights
to to Super interesting especially
because Japanese uh the Japanese Market
are super anti anti- THC yeah so I mean
it all is anti- THC um they are allowing
this one formulation to come in to see
but it's almost like honestly it's
almost like they made a mistake and said
we're going to do do you know what I
mean oops Yeah but I mean and that's
what's interesting think about all the
markets and learning today about more
about EU GMP and what it would take for
Laurel Crest to become EU and GMP what
that really means like you're everywhere
that I go I feel like I'm learning
something else and also no one's really
sure what's going to happen and so we're
expanding as we can you know we've been
we've shipped product into uh Ghana um
South
America um just opening things as it
becomes available and yeah thank you um
so I think um goo yeah how many do we
still have time for Quest you can talk
all you want we have 40 minutes left
14 questions oh okay yeah I don't know
like uh doubt it gives us a little bit
like I didn't expect to be uh over that
early I didn't have a Time on so great
yeah let's hear let's hear for them
they're doing
[Applause]
great um yeah then maybe we keep the
discussion five more minutes on stage
and then um question yeah and then two
questions yeah okay um so let's keep the
discussion a little bit more on stage
but it just I think it's super
interesting to see like all your
different experiences and what uh what
you're doing on a local level and how
we're all doing our jobs to bring the
puzzle pieces together um maybe a
question to all of you what do you think
should be done and could be done also by
us by Regulators or maybe also by
getting patient engaged and those kind
of initiative what should be what should
happen more that uh in order to get a
more harmonized um framework maybe
Sabina St with you what should what
should change there in that
regard good
question so uh firstly what um so I
worked in a regular uh pharmaceutical
industry so I have been uh in qu
for more than 10 years and I came to
Argent biofarma entering a
pharmaceutical industry connected with
cannabis so for me if you are a GMP uh
manufacturer and if you produce medicine
you produce medicine you know it's
effective you know it's safe uh
compliant and you just give it and when
I started my colleagues that are also
here were constantly telling me Sabina
it's not that easy how it's not easy we
have their opioids it's easy you give
them you distribute them and so on and I
noticed that the biggest obstacle is
education so people don't know a lot a
lot about it um the problem then second
education I mean also um from the Health
Care system to the Regulatory and then
also to patients consumers that are
mixing also food supplements treatments
THC with CBD and so on and I think this
is the biggest obstacle that we have uh
and this is our let's say responsibility
in a sense we um I can say in my company
we really work closely with doctors with
institutions with clinics for this
purpose to educate also we educate our
business partners because a lot of times
we get a lot of offers that are
connected with CBD THC and then we also
need to educate the difference of
medicinal product food supplement uh
treatment daily intake for supplementing
food and so on so I think this is uh the
first thing where we should start is
with the
education Danielle what do you think it
should be um done more like especially
because you talked about the US and the
different uh markets and I know you have
the same situation like we do here with
the hhc Delta 8 Delta 10 that are maybe
often times also used um in a medic
medicinal context but are only available
as a commercial product without the
proper help by the for for Education as
you say is important but um uh let's uh
what do you think should be better I
mean I do think that in the US
specifically it would be really helpful
if the FDA would come out and say
something so that at least manufacturing
had to meet certain standards um for
Laurel Crest for example we're a GMP
facility we're our infrastructure is
built to go up into pharmaceutical if we
needed to but we are doing that out of
like a desire to be a leader in the
industry not because we have to and so
we're self-regulating based on our
ethics not on any regulatory body that's
telling us that we need to be making the
products in an environment that you
would want any you know medicine to come
out of um and so that would be great and
then also just Community forums I mean
like this like your network Empower
women's cannabis you know is it's really
important for everyone to be
communicating and also linked in the
collective movement towards normalizing
hemp and cannabis or this amazing
magical plant that we are brings us
together and not having it be so much
about like how much money you're going
to make all the time because we have
seen that that also is isn't really a
lasting
motivator you know um so yeah I think
that the continued community and
conversation is one thing that's super
important and then more more regulation
in the US would be really nice because
we could guarantee that even if you are
making hhc or d8 or all of these
different products that have kind of
poured out of CBD isolate in the in the
last years
to kind of the the farm bill allowed a a
big definition of what hemp is and what
is derived from
hemp it would be great if those were all
being made in facilities that were safe
um but across the globe more like that
is maybe you can add to that Maya like
because you are active in with uh
ingredients in different uh standards of
identity what should be the thing that
should happen on the European level but
also on a global scale so we can get
more harmonized and standardized also
Frameworks where we as entrepreneurs can
then
act um it's hard to get a global picture
or to harmonize everything I think we've
discussed this earlier with the with the
within one of the topics but I would
relate to to Sabina um and I think that
the education is a very very um
important thing here one is we need to
educate the doctors because I think
there's still lack of knowledge when it
comes to cannabis based
therapies uh one fact is for example
that on medicinal school at the
University of lublana the program still
doesn't contain any kind of uh uh
cannabinoids or cannabis based therapy
so people that basically finish the
medical school have no knowledge about
the already existing medicines that are
possibly to be prescribed in Slovenia
and I think this is a big issue um
another is the education of the people
so of the patients to enable them to use
safely and effectively anything that's
related to cannabinoids because people
are still using a lot of garage stuff
which I think is very bad and this is
something that needs to be changed with
an ongoing communication with a clear
communication for example at faham we
took some steps to to try to at least uh
raise awareness um I've participated in
an interview on Med overnet which is a
well-known platform in IIA then we had
an open for where people could
anonymously ask any kind of questions
that are related to cannabinoids and Med
cannabis therapies and our scientific uh
advisor Professor Stosich was there to
uh respond to all of those questions
they are still there it was about 50
questions from basically everyone and I
think this is the way that everybody
should do it and in this manner we will
come to to Better World yeah I have one
other thing is um because I was touring
Pharma hemp and they have an amazing uh
testing facility which I'm sure that you
do too with hlc's and all these things
but standardization of testing is
probably the biggest hurdle to the US
market at the moment you can get a test
on your product and you get it back from
four different labs and it's for
different completely different tests and
so something that is standardizing how
reading these ingredients would be from
a worldwide perspective really helpful
yeah I think uh but if you look at the
picture of these developments especially
surrounding CBD I don't know in Europe
to me at least it feels a little bit
like we're in a still standand
especially with all the food regulations
and the novel food application and back
in
2019 I think it was when it was decided
that CBD is not a drug
basically there you could already see
some movement against these recreational
users or lifestyle users but still it's
just like there's a roadblock and
there's no solution to it and there is
also No Sol no willingness to release
this roadblock and I think um it would
be a possibility to create more
harmonized rules because we have like
different rules for CBD in the
Netherlands in Germany in France some
have special things yeah and it's not so
difficult that we can use the science
and data I bet you have security
thresholds or don't
you all right um so let's open the FL
for questions yes yes let let's he for
the panel one more time we're going to
start here we're going to go
there check
check yeah hello can you hear me is it
working
yeah louder uh I have one question you
in one moment uh Danielle mentioned in
uh Japan and their
regulations uh do you maybe have some
insights about their um regulations
about the CBD and the source of CBD
because now it's really funny that they
accept CBD only if it's sourced if it's
extracted from the uh not from the
leaves not from the flower just from the
stalk and
root is there do do you maybe have some
info about that is is is it going in
some different direction it I mean just
like maybe two days
ago it is starting to go in another
Direction and it was acknowledged that
that is Antiquated definition but that
definition is going back to I mean it's
it's a it's a very very old definition
of hemp and related to fiber and so it
just never changed for many many years
and with these new regulations it seems
they're not going to require those
statements anymore anymore um which
obviously if you were importing into
Japan and making those statements we
know that it
was not true um and so that
uh I do feel like there is a shift in
Japan and at the same time the parts per
million the THC parts per million is
extremely limiting and extremely
difficult to accomplish and
also analyze analyze yeah and so part of
the testing like the I mean depending on
what lab you go to you could get the
thing that you want or not and there's
no standard there so do you think it's
like a form of uh prohibition through
overregulation
uh I don't think that I don't think that
the country is comfortable with THC in
any at all like it's very uncomfortable
with it and so yes and it's not 100%
different and there's kind of like this
portal through this patient group where
they're not wanting to also hurt their
citizens so I don't know it's changing
every day I get like a WhatsApp text
being like hey this is the new this is
the new thought so I think that it's
really it's it's kind of a dynamic
situation and they're not planning to
say anything def definite and for a
couple more months so it could continue
to shift but the an the analization of
10 parts per million as a limit for THC
is is going to be very difficult to
consistently achieve By Any Lab but it's
in it's an interesting aspect we have
the same situation in Germany I'm on the
German Board of the industry Association
and German industry Association I was
for a long term also responsible for the
CBD part and we had a couple of cases
where there were CBD products um with
full spectrum extract cosmetics and they
said you're going against the single
convention on narcotics this is clearly
your drug dealers and they did creams
for putting on your skin so clearly
they're not drug dealers and uh so those
kind of situations evolved but in my
opinion those are rooted in the single
convention in in a outdated and wrong
definition because you just mentioned
the stalks um those of you who know the
plant know that there are little
tricomes even to the smallest level or
on the sugar leaves and all those kind
of things so I am personally lobbying to
change the definition and to get the
update in the single convention for
these definitions because they're just
not right it's just technically wrong
do we have more
questions yes um thank you very much and
uh I have a some question my name is IIA
Resnik I'm a psychiatrist and director
of International Association of
cannabinoid medicine several years ago
we made some research what is wrong with
CBD oil it was it had been published uh
uh where we collected the samples from
the 20s pharmacies where the and OTC
sources where the CBD oil uh had been
sold and we we made assessment in Len um
laboratory using hlc in order to compare
what doesn't uh indicated on the label
and what is real content we found that
more than 50% of the labels were faked H
more than 50% contained even more
concentration majority less but some uh
samples had there low more concentration
that it had been indicated so we suppose
that no control really plowed to this
area so how we can calculate it using in
my clinical practice in clinical
practice in Germany other countries
where the OTC no nobody checked it
really please may I
respond um I suppose this was taken from
Slovenian
pharmacies if I may ask
meaning dogies like d droger
Market in Slovenia was it in Israel or
where did you take
them where ah from Israel ahuh Germany
was it with the one with the CBD LMA ah
I misunderstood this okay um so firstly
um hlc even though it's um high
performance liquid chromatography
it can show varying results if the
method is not uh qualified and validated
so if we have oils in different matrixes
and different matrixes and different
ingredients inside and if this is not
brought to the highest level this can
also be uh a reason that the results
are not as what is uh on the label we
had also an experience when the
Institute YF Stefan took one of our
extracts in oil and their results were
drastically different from the result of
our laboratory that has a validated
method so just saying that when you use
an hlc doesn't mean that the result is
something that you can rely on and this
is also when uh my colleague here Daniel
mentioned that you can have hlc uh
analysis in four different Laboratories
and you get four different results me as
a pharmacist I will get a heart attack
because this is U we cannot just rely
and say this is a hlc and it's good
enough so I'm sure that this would be
the biggest reason for the uh difference
in the uh results I I personally would
ask what kind of method was used whether
this method is prepared to be um used
for the analysis of different matrixes
yeah but I I know the uh the research um
Dr reik is referencing but it's um it
has a publication to it actually but it
just shows that within the non-medical
part there is so much fluctuation in the
product and that that's I think the
point that uh is most important that
there is a varying quality of product
with a lot of tainting and lot of
additional things you shouldn't be in
there yeah have for one one more
question one more question yeah one
observation I would like to congratulate
ladies on this panel because you are
very Hands-On and excellent thank you
thank you thank
you yes I'm a big appla do we have one
more question or I don't know but I
think we're out of time I'm
sorry we're we're supposed to stop at
4:30 it's like 4:33 so Alex gets on my
case if we run too
late another round of applause for the
panelists thank you ladies thank you for
being so
[Applause]
wonderful all right all right the energy
is good everybody's excited