um in this uh today's panel discussion
on the birgin and cannabis Industries in
Europe versus North America where the
Landscapes are rapidly evolving and uh
in a cybernetic relations as nearly half
of US states Embrace adult youth
legalization and medicinal cannabis
continues to flourish our attention now
turns to Europe Germany in particular
where the industry is still in its
infancy but rhyming with potential so if
you ever wondered what it takes uh for
the US um cannabis companies to conquer
the European market stick around for um
as we discuss the essential Market entry
um requisites for navigating Europe's uh
green Frontiers so today on the panel
here um I have the pleasure to have
Jamie Pearson um International Market
Pioneer and founder of the New Holland
group Jamie is a highly respected leader
in the Cannabis industry known as the
Wonder Woman um for her operational
success leadership and Global
relationships she founded in leads New
Holland group a Consulting um firm
offering Services ranging from
International Business Development to
financial turnarounds and previously
also served as president and CEO of uh
Bank in um and expanding into multiple
states and countries through licensing
deals so welcome Jamie thank
you happy to be here then we have here
um aru de Cordova um CEO and founder of
teil arur uh is the CEO and founder um
he's a lead a leading provider of
non-ionizing thermal solutions for mic
microbiological pathog gain reduction in
agriculture and cannabis products and he
has expensive experience in regulated
market and a background in
Pharmaceuticals energy finance and other
brings a Global Perspective for the
Cannabis industry focusing on strategic
Direction and Global Partnerships for
seil and then last but not least we have
kyri nman um a lawyer from Germany from
kfn plus he's a highly knowledgeable
legal expert in the Cannabis industry
offering comprehensive support for
contract drafting to Regulatory
Compliance he operates internationally
and navigating the evolving uh legal
landscape um while he also has his blog
cannabis. Leal um and he's also um
effective lobbyist and working with many
associations uh in Germany and
Beyond so Kai let's start with you
straight away uh cannabis is legalized
in Germany and the industry is
impatiently waiting for the final
passing of the law what is the status of
legalization in Germany and what stage
are we at and what are some of the
biggest roadblocks on a global and local
level yeah yeah we we are not done yet
don't think that so um it's almost like
a classical uh drama in five acts and I
will give you an overview of of that so
the journey began the drama began in
November 21 we had Federal elections and
a new government was in place a new the
traffic light Coalition and they
announced in November 21 that cannabis
will be legalized and the the uh
distribution by distribution of cannabis
in specialized stores in dispensaries
that was the aim in November 21 uh then
the increasing moment came in October uh
in October 22 uh and there was a paper
published by the Federal Ministry of
Health um saying okay this is our plan
to enroll a commercial route for
cannabis distribution in Germany um
everyone said oh yeah German is really
legalizing commercial route great um and
then uh the third uh the third Act was
uh in April
23 uh the federal minister of health and
the federal minister of Agriculture
saying okay uh the commercial route
doesn't work uh we have legal problems
uh single convention EU framework Etc uh
it's not possible we have to uh do it
the other way uh and then they presented
again a paper saying uh okay uh you are
only allowed to possess 25 G of cannabis
uh we are planning to introduce cannabis
cultivation associations no cannabis
Social Clubs so no cons consumation on
the premises uh but cannabis cultivation
Association for Collective hom grown and
uh the home grow of option for three
plants at at at home uh so U that was of
of course a big step back and uh it was
probably completely over regulated uh so
that was a big disappointment at at that
point of time uh and then we saw the
first draft in U in October in in August
last year in 23 uh and it was so heavily
restricted so
prohibitionist a drama nothing left over
from from the initial plans uh and um
then the the act started uh by uh even
these reduced plans were attacked from
all sides from uh police uh um
associations from uh physician
associations Etc uh and it was not clear
if these draft will enter bunak at all
uh and then uh the Ukraine war came uh
and uh the uh tax problems uh came and
it was scheduled for November it was
postponed and then um it was scheduled
for December postponed for January
postponed and then in February 3 weeks
ago the law passed bunak and now we in
the situation that the bundesrat the
federal Council has to approve that law
as well he can't really prevent it but
he can appeal to a mediation committee
and if that is done if they appeal next
Friday for the mediation committee uh
the law can't enter into Force at 1st of
April and when it will enter into Force
course is completely open and this would
be the last Act of this classical drama
the catastrophe no change at all so you
think 1 of April is off the table it's
50/50 it's 50/50 many people are working
on that right now uh the um the resist
resistance came from the federal states
because they saying oh my God we have to
implement new administrative procedures
and we have to look through old criminal
files maybe we have to release some
prisoners oh we are completely
overwhelmed please stop that law and
this is the the problem right now but
are the people overthinking or is it
realistic concern that they have at this
moment for the changes that are
outstanding I I mean the the the green
party was always in favor of
legalization they um bought the first
bill in 2015 to bunak the Cannabis
Control Act uh and now it seems that the
minist the green ministers from the
federal states are opposing just this
law it would be political suicide for
the green party if it's in the end the F
of the green party if the law doesn't
come into enter into Force so I agree so
uh Jamie with that in the back of your
uh or with the back of our minds uh what
advice would you give American brands
who hire your group uh the New Holland
group for entering into you Europe what
are some vital aspects that they have to
consider when I worked at bang uh for
those of you that know bang chocolate I
ran that company for seven years and one
of the things I did was when I started
the company we were in California uh
when I left we were in seven states
Canada and I brought the CBD division
into Europe so my experience sort of
boots on the ground is navigating the
complexities of the legal Market
whatever is happening legally things
change on a dime you have to be able to
Pivot quickly and know how to do things
for example you don't want to buy
100,000 packages to get a cheaper rate
knowing that the government could on a
dime change something and then that
whole batch of packaging becomes
obsolete so I put the legal framework
more in the boots on the ground
operational um strategy and what I would
say to that what Kai just explained is
that you you've got a political sea you
know football going back and forth It's
a seesaw we don't know what's going to
happen Friday is D-Day um what I've been
telling my clients is Germany is
Pharma in in the words of Ceda Schubert
those of you who know her full stop
Pharma so if you want to come in and be
a brand you're really early it's there
there's no Brands right now and even in
the social model if it passes is Brands
aren't really a thing however if you're
an American brand and you have
credibility and people know you because
like everywhere um cannabis American
cannabis is in high demand especially
cannabis from
California uh so if you have a brand
with tremendous credibility as we've
witnessed with cookies that came over
here and has been able to open stores
and um and I don't want to open that can
of worms but um there is a path and
there's a path for doing um B to C so
approaching your consumer directly
rather than going the traditional B2B
route um and then going the farmer route
so you want to make sure that you are
building your brand through the
traditional medical um channels now one
thing I want to say and then you know
I'll I'll let someone else speak here
but I think when you're talking about
brands in Europe you you really just
have to think about
um the European market compared to the
North American Market which is kind of
was the title of our panel in America
medical you have to put air quotes
around it because it was really just a
workaround so we could put the plant in
people's hands in Europe medical
actually means medical it's a doctor
prescription it's Health sometimes
health insurance if you can jump through
those Hoops you get the medicine at a
pharmacy you're not going to a
dispensary so all of you in Europe know
that but for my American Compadres
especially the new ones that are here
medical cannabis in Europe looks nothing
like medical cannabis in America so I
think that what we're seeing is that
those medical laws will probably loosen
and it'll be easier for people and
patients to get their hands on cannabis
but it's probably not going to be
anytime soon like what we see in the
recreational states in the
US thank you so uh AR um as an American
company operating in the North American
cannabis market for more than eight
years uh or um how do how long ago did
you begin to prepare to enter for the
European market and what steps did you
take and what were the most difficult
challenges also coming here with an
American perspective uh to
Europe thank Thank you
Lisa I come back to Europe with a view
from my previous chapter when I lived in
Europe and I was country manager of
Astra now Astra zenica and when I left
Astra I didn't think I was going to go
be going back into the Pharma business
and so I returned back to the United
States acquired this company
seal and we were in the recreational
market for all intents and purposes as
as Jamie mentioned medical cannabis in
the United States was really just a
pathway to get to
recreational uh here in Europe
microphone up high we need your
microphone up by your mouth okay here in
Europe uh it is as Jamie said very much
of a pharmaceutical market and so I look
back to those days at Astra when we had
reps detailing doctors educating doctors
solving distribution problems uh for
pharmacies so uh we had to you know go
back to the old Playbook and so we
re-entered or we entered the European
market a few years ago you know it's a
GMP market and our equipment is is
qualified for GMP certification I was in
a customers facility yesterday in
Portugal and I can tell you there's not
a single North American facility that
looks like this facility I saw yesterday
in Portugal and then it is it is clean
GMP the processes is professional and
so I think the jury I mean the pathway
as Jamie said is very clear it is Pharma
it's going to stay Pharma Recreation is
not on the horizon here there's probably
a little room for brands in the
traditional sense uh in the European
market for years to come uh but we're
very excited and I look forward to being
back in the Pharma business in Europe I
will say OIC is a brand and it's a
Pharma brand so there is a ability to
Brand Pharma but we're so early it's
it's not not time for that
yet but do you see also many differences
on how business is done here like in
comparison to the states differ how
business is done
here the the United States uh you know
it's a go- go market I mean you have
Legacy Growers you have institutional
investors here it's much more of a
steady slow organic growth I don't think
there's going to be seismic changes uh
like you might see in the United States
and Chloe hit it uh this morning the
earlier panel that we're all now waiting
for the DEA to endorse or not endorse uh
the rescheduling of of cannabis from
narcotic I'd say that the Germans may
have beat us to the punch but the jury's
out till next Friday but it's going to
be very
steadied growth I don't see any
hyperbolic growth that you saw in the
United States which is arguably a $30
billion market now uh I don't have a
hard number for Europe but it is a
fraction of that but we have Bitcoin so
we're all
okay so Jimmy back to you um like more
also from a commercial strategy point of
view um what has changed about uh your
view of the European cannabis industry
since the German and Dutch W or maybe
even since you started entering yeah yes
so I I entered the European market in
2016 um it's hard hard to believe yeah
in dog years was does that make me a
hundred um
and that market we were so hopeful and
every year it's kind of cannabis you
know we always say and then cannabis
happened um you just get kicked in the
teeth you know you think you're going to
make big progress and you really don't
and I don't want to be Debbie Downer but
but what's changed for me as I realize
um I actually think the European can AB
Market is doing it right in comparison
with the American Market because we have
so many problems with uh the illicit
Market um I I don't believe that it
should be a situation where you've got
people in prison for this plant and then
what you do is you legalize it but then
you create a new set of criminals quote
unquote um which are the people that
open or have elicit dispensaries so in
2018 for example in California uh we had
3,000 dispensaries it goes wreck there's
only 300 legal dispensaries the next day
all 3,000 stayed open now you've got
2,700 new criminals instead of lowering
the bar and letting the people that were
operating you know enter the legal
market and I I am hoping that in Europe
which has a robust illicit Market
everybody uses cannabis um that there's
a pathway to not create new criminals
and I think that part of the
delays thank
you I think part of the delays are about
the lawmakers are not
jockeying um Us Versus Them which is the
problem we have in the US it's Democrats
versus Republicans well if they if they
do the bill then we're not going to
approve it and all that kind of stuff
here very thoughtful you've got a
parliamentary process you've got
coalitions that are all putting their
stakeholders and their policies in place
and and bringing the concerns that they
have to the table and I think one of the
big concerns is criminal justice and I
think part of that is what is causing
some of this delay and I'm I'm grateful
for that I'm grateful that there is eug
GMP so the the medicine is coming out of
clean facility
because I can tell you I have
toured probably near a thousand grows in
my life and um and some of the best ones
are here in Europe for sure so I think
the Europeans might not be getting it
right all the way but I think they're
getting a lot of it right maybe uh just
out of the regular question here Kai can
you give a little comment on social
justice in Germany and how this is
developing and this discussion is
developing and with
amnesty so social social justice yeah
that is exactly the point where these U
Ministry ministers from the federal
states are complaining because they
would have to go through 100,000 cases
uh to see if they have to be ricated
these convictions and uh we have too
little staff we can't we can't do that
let's skip that let's skip that and then
we will consent to the to the to the
bill that's uh so much to social justice
awareness of politicians in Germany
thank you so um AR um like in Germany we
have talked about that market we have
roughly sometime between something
between 20 to 30 tons of medicinal
cannabis flour Imports in 2023 so far
reported um in some individual states in
the US you have hundreds of tons Alone
um so is Europe uh even on the mark uh
on the radar of um American companies
so I'm going to give an an example of uh
just one state and this is really the
opportunity that Europe has I'm going to
use scale so if Germany last last year
was 30 tons approximately of of flour
most of it
imported uh one State
Michigan consumed 160 tons of flour one
state so you you amplify that and if you
want to use that as a benchmark to what
the European market could look like you
know greater population
the opportunity is enormous even if it
just stays medical the opportunity is
enormous so we're all here in early days
and all that groundwork is being done on
the regulatory front uh Germany leading
the way but I think it's going to be
very interesting with the European
Parliament elections coming up uh what
the European Parliament does and I'm
going to ask our German colleagues a
return question how do you see the
European Parliament uh you know how this
playing out in the European Parliament
not just in
Germany on a European level that's a
good question um but it's like I don't
know we all don't have a grass bubble
that we can look into that's a little
bit the problem but hopefully um and uh
I hope many of you are also working on
that within the countries that we come
together and that we really lobby as a
European industry because that is
something that uh we have been missing
in Germany we had our first industry
Association in 2019 and the thing that
we all need to do do more and also more
jointly is to really Lobby on a European
level especially with the European
elections coming up
soon sorry yeah yeah no it's fine we
just continue with the questions here
because we're also we have an echo yeah
yeah we have an echo up here like
sometimes we
like um so uh Kai we have a the
rescheduling in or the reeval valuation
of the laws in Germany Does this does
not only have impact on the um
recreational part but also on the
medical part and on the hemp sector um
what do you expect for the future of
these areas um and also in yeah regard
to Global development and upcoming
European election yeah sure so uh once
again if the law if they appeal to the
um mediation committee next week uh the
law won't pass at the 1st of April when
it will pass then is completely unclear
it maybe fails at all but if it um
enters into Force at the 1 of April
cannabis will be rescheduled and not
part of the narcotic act anymore it will
be a regular commodity highly regulated
though but a regular commodity that's
one advantage of
course and as a regular commodity as a
regular medicine you don't need a a
narcotic prescription anymore you don't
have to obey these safety regulations
anymore or lesser documentation um
obligations Etc so that was would be a
big a big Advantage uh and um it would
access easy the access for medical
patients as as well in Germany because
then the stigma is gone and you can uh
prescribe cannabis for back pain
basically it's no problem then anymore
and uh every the medical import
companies of course they hope for this
they hope for this
boost and that patients numbers will
will Wise by by that I I just want to
add the the German law will benefit the
patients more prescribing doctors in
Germany the change the rescheduling if
the rescheduling occurs in the United
States it will have very little impact
on patients it'll have a huge impact on
the Growers because of the tax
implications 28e it's an Arcane IRS rule
but they be be able to depreciate
but that rescheduling plays out
differently in the
markets thank you for that addition um
so maybe can can I uh add something and
uh the the most surprising development
showed up in November uh as they um um
published the mandments to the law which
is now coming into force is that all
restrictions on medical medical cannabis
cultivation will be lifted so everyone
who wants to produce who wants to
cultivate cannabis medical cannabis
according to pharmaceutical grade will
be can can do so uh and um we have three
domestical licenses already in place by
deman Aurora and tillay and they are
only allowed to produce 10 tons in um
four years lifted they are only allowed
to produce three strains lifted uh and
every company there's no restrictions on
the number of companies so if you want
to grow medical cannabis in Germany you
can do that with the with the new law uh
and then you have to think of the single
Convention of article 21 which is
basically saying uh the more you produce
domestically the less you can import so
this has the potential to change the
whole scene uh and in the long to in the
short in the mid to long run you
probably will have to produce cannabis
medical cannabis in Germany if you want
to distribute it in in Germany so you
take a close look on on that how that
will unfold very
important okay thank you so um the final
question to all of your panelists maybe
starting with you Jamie um what will be
the biggest surprise in Europe in the
next 12
month well it won't be a surprise to me
um but I think what will be surprising
to the government is that the efforts to
decriminalize the lifting of the limits
is going to create an environment where
cannabis is ubiquitous and it's going to
be very difficult for the police to
start enforcing and I think what you're
going to have is a free for-all
and they're going to underestimate the
entrepreneurial Spirit around cannabis
and so you're going to have I think an
illicit Market explode that they're
going to have a very difficult time
controlling because if you're a police
officer uh in Spain for example because
there's no borders you go over to
Germany you buy something that's adult
use you bring it over it's
decriminalized here you can have it it's
going to be May him it's going to be
chaos that's what I
predict I
agree I'm going to go with the short
term and see what happens a week from
tomorrow in
Germany not 12 months because I think
what happens in Germany is a bell
weather for the EU Parliament and and
the tone it's going to have implications
for Spain uh as uh Carla mentioned in
the earlier panel and it's going to
provide if it passes political cover for
politicians or in the United States if
the DEA passes it it'll give political
cover then for our politicians our
dysfunctional political government in
the United States to possibly change the
tone in Washington they're not going to
do
that they're not going to do that
they're not going to change their tone
yeah but that's something very critical
that I think is we are heading in that
direction where we have a cou all
different countries all finding
different regulations it's no harmonized
Market many bottlenecks
and that's something uh we as an
industry also need to try to avoid and
create more harmonized regulations
across Europe and not only for
individual
countries Kai what's your biggest
surprise next
Friday no they will be a lot of
surprises coming up over the year I I
guess as it has been the last two years
as we try to legalize or decriminalize
or whatever with cannabis in Germany um
but um As It Seems there is a developing
a sort of European Standard for for
legalization if you look at Malta if you
look at Luxemburg if you look at Germany
and the Czech Republic announced
something similar so this cannabis
cultivation model with 500 um members
maximum uh and this three plant at home
seems to develop to a European Standard
which uh um a member State can easily
adopt and apply without getting into
conflict with the EU commission and we
will see that with Czech Republic as
well probably uh and then we will have
the EU elections for the EU Parliament
uh in in summertime in June uh and there
are already working groups of um MPS in
the European Parliament working on
cannabis reform uh on a European level
the EU framework decision from 2004 we
know that the Shang acree uh all having
regulations on cannabis in place which
makes the legalization so difficult
right now um and I think if the new
Parliament comes in after the summer
break we may see some surprises there
and some initiatives to reform these
legal framework on the EU level I'm I'm
pretty sure that will happen do you
think some of those surprises will be
positive uh yeah yeah yeah because uh
the framework decision from 2004 is
under the uh old legal framework of the
U of the Nitsa framework and uh it's
politically not
really um legitimate legitimate it
wasn't decided by the parliament it was
an off record decision so to say uh and
it's not uh viable for uh for preventing
legalization anymore but it's in place
so you have to deal with that and if you
change that you can go further than
cannabis cultivation associations and
and decommunization you can then think
of the commercial route and all the
tools which are in place on the single
convention level with interc agreements
Etc well I think the other big surprise
that we know is coming is these pilot
programs we don't know what that's going
to look like necessarily but we know
with some certainty who the players are
going to be that are going to come in
with money yeah but those discussions
are just starting so at the pilot
projects of course yeah they announced
that they will if the law passes next
week they will immediately start working
on the pilot project um and uh
for the pilot projects you have to
cultivate cannabis as well in Germany so
it's maybe not a bad idea to start a
cannabis cultivation in Germany to be
prepared for model B for the model
projects and for the for the next steps
five six seven years ahead yeah maybe
just as a little comment to the audience
also like the pillar two is for
evaluating the commercial part so you
can already do an now scientific
research and uh research in those kind
of areas so that's also something that
be done way more but um we're going to
open the floor for questions now maybe
Misha your uh your main surprise of uh
the next 12 months what is
yours uh I also have to wait till next
Friday I would say and uh another
surprise is uh what Jamie just mentioned
uh there will be no legal
Supply or legal possession in the
beginning and what we never discussed so
far is uh that pharmacies they don't pay
taxes
they pay taxes but they pay less taxes
and if you look at the pricing right now
and this is also my first question that
may may go out to Kai maybe when I look
at the pricing of Pharmacy right now do
you think uh they will be like uh in
competition because it's also in
competition with shops and clubs because
it's also as we heard very easy to have
a prescription very soon all the
restrictions fall and when I look at the
pricing in pharmacy it starts at 550
right now and it's becoming cheaper do
you think they'll have there'll be in
competition with the clubs and the uh
and the shops which will
come yeah
um if I would be allowed to uh have a
proper hom grow um I probably wouldn't
take uh prescriptions anymore um you
know that it's a big it's a huge
potential for for hom grow in in Germany
uh in every municipality in every County
you have at least three hops selling uh
stuff and accessories for the last third
three four centuries so it's already
there and it will it will boom
definitely if you can do it legally many
many people will try that and uh but if
you look at the demand uh we were
talking about that with B last night the
hup study assumes 400 to 600 tons Bo
Whitney says no it's 900 tons uh
probably 1,000 tons uh so uh if you
really uh go if if you if if the the the
the usual um
Stoner transforms or switches switches
to the medical Market there's enough
potential for for everyone so no real
competition I
guess uh I'm gassa kashu the founder of
can Portugal it's an expo on hen
cannabis in Lisbon and I have a question
to to uh nman because you told a couple
of times that uh the new laws of German
uh implies this uh protection of your
own Market and my question is and
considering that most of the a lot of
the product that is um medicinal
cannabis that is produced in Portugal
goes to Germany uh how come in this
European Union free um C culation of
goods uh how come Germany can close um
its borders and protect
themselves because I think it's the
opposite uh idea that we have of the
European Union that's a very good
question very good point it's not solved
yet because there are two different
regimes we have the EU law and we have
the single convention and medical
cannabis is traded according to the
rules of the single convention and these
are overly or superseding uh the uh the
principle of the free movement of of
goods uh this is a conflict and maybe it
if someone starts to uh to uh appeal
against these rules uh maybe he will be
successful if you take it to court it's
a good
question we have to see I'm going to
translate that for the Americans in the
audience what you basically have is the
same situation here that we have there
it's federally illegal by EU standards
so if the the member states if Germany
as a member state of the EU passes the
law for the benefit of its citizens they
can grow they can do whatever they want
in within the borders of Germany that
where the law gets broken is when the
when it's Crossing Borders when the EU
law is broken is when it's Crossing
Borders so you have this conflict
between the the oversight of the Fed
heads of the EU and what's going on at
the state level or the member state
level and so it's not a freely tradable
commodity medical cannabis it's highly
regulated it's according to the single
convention and you have to comply with
the single convention rules
first there was another question back
there yes hi Jason Shard uh founder of
Pat Global and modern extractor I've got
a bit of a two-tiered question for Kai
um from everything I've read regarding
medical cannabis and the new changing of
the cannabis laws in Germany it seems
like it's really opening the doors for
flow but uh beyond that what are the uh
what are the options for creating
consumer packaged Goods finished
products uh Vapes and any of that kind
of stuff and then also how do you
fulfill um is it going to be possible to
fulfill that from within the EU and
outside of Germany eventually in your
opinion yeah you have to comply with the
monogra S monographies in Place which is
for dried flowers and for um extract and
if you if these if your products comply
with these uh monographs you are fine
you can sell it but we won't see um uh
medical weaping devices they are not
there yet no one has an authorization
yet for the European market uh but
companies are working on that so yeah
and we would need to have more and new
and modern monographies for for for new
products which would have to be drafted
and you yeah the industry should take
care of that what I predict is that
you'll see um kind of like the social
club model here which I know they're not
the same but what happened is cannabis
is not legal here but you have these
quote unquote private clubs and they're
not supposed to be selling cannabis but
they all do because it becomes an enfor
ment issue and Kai's talking about the
government's already complaining oh
we've got to go through 100,000 uh they
aren't going to fund enforcement that's
the general rule of what happens is the
law gets passed and then they don't have
they don't consider or they don't think
about we're going to need to actually
put some money in budgets for
enforcement so then you're just going to
have people flouting the law which means
then you're going to have people putting
the flower in branded packages and it's
not going to be allowed but they're
going to do it anyway that's my
prediction oh maybe Kai you can tell a
little bit about the products available
in the Social Clubs and in the pillar
to uh yeah in Social Clubs it's only uh
flowers and uh resin no extracts
solventless extracts sorry solventless
solventless extracts solventless
extract yeah they are
forbidden and no Edibles of course uh
but uh life was in so if it's with
pressure and no no solvent it's it's
okay and um in the model project uh they
will try to uh um uh that the Edibles
will be possible uh under strict um uh
evaluation uh if that is really as
harmful as they expect to be it now it
is not but yeah they ads will come there
yeah so in the second pillar there is
some potential for more commercial
products because that's the focus of the
pillar so um our time is over let's give
a warm Applause uh to the
panelists thank you everybody for
attending this
panel fantastic thank you so much